I'm gonna lose a jacket it's a little
bit warm
alright afternoon Jeremy Rasmussen from
ABBA code I'm the chief technology
officer we're a local cybersecurity
company
I also in the adjunct faculty at USF
have been teaching classes there since
2000 on cryptography network security
ethical hacking mobile and wireless
forensics and so forth started the white
Hatter's Club back in 2005 to do capture
the flag competition and so forth so
pleasure to be here with this afternoon
insane and mainframe is my talk topic
today like took that from obviously
Futurama that I don't know if you ever
saw that episode where bender and fry
going to the bank and then I think
benders old buddy there robs a bank gets
them framed for it they end up having to
go to robot rehabilitation hospital
where fry is like I'm not a robot and
they're like obviously you're crazy
and so they make him eventually believe
that he's a robot but hopefully it's not
going to be that way for you the gist of
this talk is a lot of people are moving
into cloud who's who's either or who's
moving who's on office 365 Rd who's like
moving to office 365 or you know ok and
who's thought about it right so you're
already kind of they're halfway I mean
if you're if you're in office 365 you're
already on Azure because I adjure is the
basis for office 365 who's doing who's
like who's doing some Amazon stuff
anybody Amazon anybody Azure anybody
going to Amazon or Azure ok so basically
everybody right but then you know if I
asked you to tell me all the security
implications of that how does badger or
how does Amazon or any of those handle
security for let's just say they're
virtual machines might not know the
answer so when I start out looking at
this I was like I have a 715 page and
not kidding you 715 page document from
Microsoft on this and I'm like this is I
mean this is staggering this is just too
much so and that's how everybody feels
when they start looking at everything
it's just like too much so the gist of
this talk is to boy that all down into a
tldr
30 minute talk and this is going to give
you the summary of how asher is trying
to do security then you know it's to
motivate you to do some self study on
your own to go off and you know take a
look and dig down in deep
into this stuff but I think this is
going to get you started if you don't
even know where to start so the the
cognitive distance dissonance there that
Frye has is is kind of what
so here's we're going to talk about
today so first of all I'm just gonna
give you some cloud background if you
don't know where to start we're gonna
help you get started and I'm going to
tell you how Asher does identity access
management how they do encryption and
file management how they do
virtualization firewalls networking and
so forth and then how to kind of get a
handle on all that with logging
monitoring security scanning that kind
of thing the stuff that we do as a
managed services company all right so
the cognitive dissonance I think for
cloud actually is you know relevant to
what we're talking about for insane of
the mainframe I was thinking about this
you know by the way does anybody know
what this picture is from anybody
anybody like where what building used to
be in the physics used to be in physics
not anymore they moved it this is this
is a giant Foucault pendulum that they
move from the physics building to is a
the interdisciplinary Sciences Building
but it's pretty cool if you ever get a
chance to go over there and see that
it's really neat to see but back in the
60s all the way up till the you know 80s
we had just mainframes right there
you actually the way you secured a
mainframe was by locking the door to the
server room right
you know we had dumb terminals that
connected into this thing from the 80s
to the 2000s then we kind of went the
other direction the pendulum swung over
and we had distributed systems we had
more technological and electronic means
to protect those systems and now I see
it as kind of swinging back over to this
mainframe idea again where the cloud is
your mainframe now even though it's a
really a distributed system of you know
millions of computers but it looks like
a single system to you and of course
electronic means and protections to you
know that's what we're gonna go over
today is what those protections are
available so why is just without look in
this slide I already stole my own
thunder why would you move to the cloud
what we're the benefits of that yeah you
don't have his number it's not my cloud
and somebody else's thing all right
exactly what else
scalable cheaper in some cases maybe
maybe not you gotta pay for everything
in the class availability absolutely
99.9% uptime SLA is right it's
supposedly greener you know there's a
lot of things that are cool about cloud
right that's why everybody's kind of
going that route but what's what is
cloud scary well you're putting all your
eggs in one basket right you're you when
you store your data you know Microsoft
has 27 data centers on you know
throughout the world when you store your
data actually where does it get stored
I don't know not sure about that and you
will have a hard time actually knowing
where it gets stored and who has access
or is it in a country that route demands
backdoor access like the United States
probably you know to the government
right where's your where's your standing
or right yeah where's your context for
it for legal standing oh I hear and see
it's in their Terms of Service you just
got read that not where you want it to
be you know and also you've got to
consider if they have 27 data centers
and a million-plus servers out there and
they're all running Intel processors
that got hit by there that are affected
by meltdown inspector Wow somebody could
come up with like this killer virus or
something that we could take down the
whole thing right so there's some
definitely some some drawbacks or
scariness to operating out of the cloud
but Azure I don't know why you know why
I sure I could have done AWS Rackspace
or whatever it's just that I didn't know
much about it I set out to learn more
about it and like I said there was you
know so much to learn and I didn't know
where to start so I just decided I'll
start looking into this Microsoft is
considered the top cloud provider only
because they count everybody on office
365 as part of their cloud
I think AWS probably cell is actually
more pure cloud than then Azure does but
more than Microsoft does but
nevertheless they're very good they're
very involved in all aspects of software
as a service delivery platform as a
service delivery infrastructure as a
service delivery and we'll go into that
and then it what does what does that
mean for you what
your responsibilities begin and end on
security in those different models also
what I found out from starting to get in
this they have a lot of interest in
supporting AI and machine learning stuff
so if that's something that's of
interest scalable systems to support
machine learning scalable systems to
support blockchain technology they have
a lot of dedicated environments for that
so how's it right now they've already
sold 17 billion dollars of clout a year
and now they're talking about selling 20
billion dollars of cloud a year if I had
some extra cash sitting around a
probably invest in Microsoft and I'm not
at Microsoft pimp I'm just saying you
know they're doing well all of our
customers that we talked to most of them
are moving into Azure office 365 so and
their CEO is very you know cloud focused
as I was doing my research some of the
cool things that even know about Azure
is it'll su like run Linux containers
with docker integration so they're
they're not forcing you to go Microsoft
on everything they don't you don't have
to do Windows and net and all that if
you want to you can build your stuff in
JavaScript Python whatever and and they
integrate with you know iOS Android all
kinds of they they want to be they want
the whole enchilada right so they're
willing to open up and play with
everybody else's technologies and so
they interface with everything whenever
you're talking about delivering cloud
services is you know it's it's a complex
and difficult task and so you want to
decompose that into sort of like a stack
of services with each layer doing some
kind of job and so it's also important
to know who is actually running things
for you know the organization that
you're signing up to do business with
and because you know each layer affects
the other layers and in a crash at one
layer could you know have an outage and
every other Larry you really kind of got
to know who you're working with so in
Microsoft the gfs global foundation
services group is one who actually runs
their data centers and there are million
servers at the physical layer their STB
server and tools business group is who
does the platform layer that's all the
cloud delivery infrastructure and then
you and us all of us are the people that
kind of you know run the applications
and data that sit on top of that so this
kind of the money slide right here
this came from
several different documents and places
that I gleaned you know stuff together
to try to figure out all right what is
what it actually are they responsible
for and what am I responsible for in
terms of security so does everybody know
about the different levels of software
service infrastructure platform is
service if you don't know about that it
just means how much stuff your provider
is giving you versus how much stuff
you're doing yourself so if you're
running your own thing on-premises
you're responsible for everything right
you've got to configure the whole data
center you've got a you know provision
it run all the operating systems
provision those do all your identity
management and so forth if you're going
with what they call infrastructure as a
service they're going to give you the
physical hosts and hardware and stuff
underneath your network all that's
abstracted to you you won't see any of
it but you're responsible for everything
from the operating system up so you've
got to configure that and you're
responsible for the security of all that
if you're running Microsoft's platform
as a service they're actually going to
also give you they're actually going to
provision all the operating systems in
the VMS and it's a shared responsibility
on network application and so forth and
then if you're running their software as
a service so you just have a hosted app
there then they're giving you everything
underneath that and the only thing
you're responsible for is the app but
still there is some there are some
security implications of configuring
your own app on their cloud so if you
don't know where to start
on something like how do I know if
they're secure or not well there's a
cloud security alliance CSA and they
developed eight a list of security
controls they call the cloud control
matrix ECM and it's all about you know
how you should do audits I should set up
personnel operations security
architecture and so forth so anybody
that you're doing business with that is
claiming to be secure in the cloud
should have some reference to the cloud
security alliance CCM so Microsoft has
like a 75 page document that shows how
they comply with that matrix it also
actually maps to all their ISO 27000 and
to controls or 27001 by the way anybody
know what ISO 27001 is it's an Internet
all standard for security controls that
you should have in any business process
or business infrastructure IT
infrastructure you have to pay for those
iso documents so actually went to USF
and got them to buy a set of the ISO
27000 documents so they own those now so
if you're a student or faculty or you
just want to go in there and use your
reference materials you can check those
out and and for free instead of having
to pay iso money for the standard just
throw that out there but yeah they have
they have a whole document showing how
they comply with those controls and
here's what they claim to do so first of
all they're saying well we've built
security into our our own internal you
know code base through code audits
mandatory background checks for our
developers mandatory security dev
training this is not this is not hasn't
always been the case I remember I talked
to anybody remember Howard Schmidt who
is the chief information and a security
officer of the White House and before
that he was CEO of Microsoft and I asked
him like straight up hey in the early
days did Microsoft really give a you
know what about security and he's like
now um he was he was straight up they
didn't care until like Linux started
eating their lunch on some stuff right
so until it became like a a money issue
for the company they didn't really start
putting any money into it into security
so at that point this is probably about
2000 or so they had their trustworthy
computing initiatives I don't know if
you remember that it's a long time ago
they had like a coding holiday we're
like we're gonna stop writing code
everybody to stop were to train
everybody how to do secure coding now
before we do anything else I mean they
need to do it right because 90% of all
operating systems
you know deployed out there are Windows
or in a Microsoft base so all
vulnerabilities and exploits are
targeted for them and so they need to be
really good at what they do
that isn't mean they're perfect at least
they have the controls in place to try
to make their software development
lifecycle better in terms of security
operations what do they do they claim
that they do regular pen testing in the
environment they have intrusion
detection they have DDoS controls how do
you how do you to get hit by DDoS what
do you have to do about that distributed
servus what's your let's what's the
countermeasure for that huh well
professional service to do what you have
to you have to have flex some capacity
to move all the the network off to
somewhere else
scrub it for DDoS and then move it back
to the right place I mean so you have to
they must have a lot of internal
infrastructure or either that are using
some kind of third party to do that so
they've thought about this and you know
for availability reasons they have all
this stuff in place the data centers are
amazing if you go out there and look up
like Microsoft data centers some of them
really cool they have their modular
they're like like a farm it looks like a
trailer park honestly though the
configure trailer they'll have all the
conservers all the cooling and power
conditioning racks you know raised floor
or cabling fiber and all that stuff and
then they're just you know it's modular
and it's put just keep adding more
trailers to the to the trailer park some
of them are actually buildings and stuff
like that but some of them are you know
they're very very cool they've got
millions of servers very strong physical
security availability you know rows and
rows and rows of batteries and battery
backup and generators and like if they
ever went down you know if there's ever
a power outage in that area probably the
hospital gets restored number one and
then the data center at number two right
there they're on a priority restoration
schedule so you know they can deliver
this you know big time availability
uptime in terms of secure networking
their city they have they claim to have
you know network access controls in
terms of firewalls route control forced
tunneling secure access cross premises
connectivity via VPN load balancing you
know force name resolution either to the
azure DNS system or bring your own DNS
so they've got all that in place for
monitoring they have threat detection
incident response going on
you know round-the-clock always so
they're kind of doing you know you don't
hear much about Microsoft failing on
security at the at the platform or at
the infrastructure level so what's our
part of the responsibility where they
offer us in terms of tools and controls
for controlling security and the cloud
so let's look at identity access
management first
this is probably their like the big
selling point for them right there
single sign-on it's considered to be you
know by people to do such evaluations
cope injure Kol puts them at the front
of their you know SSO the nice thing is
you know they've decided to work and
play with everybody else so you can do
single sign-on when you get on to your
instance you're not only on to office
365 we also can get to Dropbox Google
app google apps and thousands of other
things through OAuth and other different
sam'l and different types of you know
federated identity they also have you
know they've tried to make it so you
have easy integration with your on-prem
stuff so if you're running everybody's
probably familiar with running active
directory in windows on-premises so it
should be a simple matter you know
almost like a wizard click a few buttons
here they say the claim for clicks and
five minutes to get stuff like
transferred and synced up to the cloud
it's not that easy really but but they
claim that and you can you can like you
start it for free everything in the
cloud is just like a drug dealer right
they give you a taste for free and then
once they get you hooked yeah they're
gonna make you pay basic you will give
you the SLA up times and then premium
there's two or three levels of premium
that will give you multi-factor
authentication and some other features
but I just want to compare so anybody is
familiar with with standard Windows
Active Directory on-premises you've got
these different services such as domain
lightweight Directory Federation
certificate rights management that run
on through protocols such as Kerberos
everybody even familiar with Kerberos
it's honestly name for the three-headed
dog of Hades right thank you you log
into an authentication server you get a
ticket granting ticket which it gives
you a validation to get a ticket for a
service and then you present that ticket
for a service it's you know they've
tried to bring that over to something
called a juror ad because on premises
you know we're designed for full control
here we're trying to control everything
when you're in a cloud we're not
controlling physical we're not
controlling infrastructure the only
thing we really care about is Identity
Management so and for Windows
eighty Active Directory all we care
about is Federation which means getting
to other stuff and our own identity
management in Active Directory
so the fallout from this unfortunately
is that if you developed an app you
can't just take an Active Directory
integrated app from on-premises and
forklift it easily in the cloud you kind
of have to rebuild it for the cloud for
a sure ad and that's unfortunate but
that's the reality so talking about some
of the api's they use for controlling
things in the cloud
Microsoft graft is a new way graph is a
new way of of controlling access
controls for what they call crud create
read update and delete it used to be
something called as your ad graph API
this is probably a drawback of some of
the Microsoft stuff they're trying to
move so fast this sometimes they come
out with something they do it for a
couple of years and then they pull it
back and they replace it with something
else so like as soon as you developed as
one standard and get used to it they're
like yeah we don't have that standard
anymore we're gonna we're gonna move you
from Azure ad graph API to Microsoft
graph anybody run into this before so
you have to be very agile in your
development to keep up with how agile
they are in their development but crud
is gonna give you you know allow you to
create a new user this is just some
typical things you might do get their
properties update the properties check
the group membership actually show you
how that all works with an example
alright so here's how you would
configure if you're an app you simply
create a service principle in a tenant
tenant is the same thing on any cloud
right in tenant is your your instance so
it's the same you know if you're running
on AWS or Rackspace or Salesforce com
whatever you're gonna have a tenant
that's your instance so a tenant is your
instance in Azure and then your service
principle is really your object that
talks about what is what you're
providing for the application it's gonna
have an identifier and a key or a secret
they'll also have a little database of
user data that will tell what like maybe
for role based access control reasons
what you know what the role is and data
for the app so then to get started
you give that Apple URL an address to
get to it they just browse in through
their web browser to the URL it
redirects them to the azure active
directory login page so you log in with
your user ID and password or and/or
multi-factor authentication then it uses
a token signed by the azure ad which
goes for validation so they make sure
it's it's legit and signed by the
certificate authority then the app
checks the idea against the app database
and you know maybe either using the
secret from the from the object or some
security top context settings from your
database it lets you do get to the thing
you want to get to the nice thing is we
never passed the password right we did
all this with a token that's the beauty
of single sign-in you know anybody use
like LastPass or any of these tools you
got like 80 different things you got to
get to everyone has a different password
you know whole the holy grail of
computing is single sign-on we only sign
in one time and then I pass the token to
everything I want to get to that's what
they're trying to do all right so that's
identity access management
what about controls on files and
encryption where they offer their well
as I mentioned before I think
multi-factor authentication is super
important when wherever we do a pen test
or whatever you know the easiest way in
is somebody write either you know call
them up and ask them for their password
which it might give you half the time or
cinema phishing email it looks just like
their domain and they go to login and
you grab their credentials multi-factor
authentication obviously now you're
sending them a text message or just or
they're having a click on something on
their you know an Authenticator on their
mobile device or whatever that makes it
a lot harder to just steal credentials
so I highly highly recommend that if you
don't have that implemented for
everything across the board you should
turn that on and as your supports that
everywhere you should try to restrict
access based on you know need-to-know
and least privilege whenever anybody
comes in your organization you should
give them the least amount of privileges
they could do to you know do their job
and no more role-based accent access
control through you know groups very
familiar in Windows is a standard part
of azure
a juror actually has dish disk
encryption what do you think it uses for
disk encryption what do use on premises
BitLocker what are you using the cloud
BitLocker same thing so what do you use
for Linux for disk encryption damned
crypt what are using cloud damn grip
yeah the same thing so it's virtual but
it's the same thing it's really the same
type of thing BitLocker DM crypt are
used for for disk encryption in Azure
and they actually have a tool called the
azure key vault that helps you control
all your BitLocker keys and DM crypt
keys and even has some features like key
audit so you might like to you know get
rid of all keys after people leave the
organization or roll them over or after
some certain amount of time you can do
audits on that and update all that
information through the key vault it's
also got something called pause which is
a high assurance workstation so there's
like certain things you're doing for
admin reasons you might not want to just
do those on a regular workstation with
lower security privileges because again
you've got the whole credential theft
thing so many systems we do we set up
you know it's easy to set up a responder
you know do a little bit of cache
poisoning or get you know force traffic
to your system that's you know they
don't have any way to resolve NetBIOS
names things like that and you can steal
credentials or you can do pass the hash
or pass the ticket attacks or you know
somehow get a keystroke logger on there
it makes a lot harder with pause because
it's high assurance workstation with
more protections to hard and lockdown
keep people from be able to do those
types of credential stealing attacks a
real nice thing about Azure is it's a
sequel database transparent data
encryption now this should be you know
this this in this day and age how you
are not encrypting your database is
beyond me I mean Equifax
yeah I mean when people are getting into
your system and they're able to get to
plaintext data it's just incredible that
how that happens but on through a sequel
database TDE transparent data encryption
it helps you know lock down the data and
also have some tools in there for
backups even encrypting backups
transaction log files and so forth so
it's all built in everything in Azure is
is SSL TLS encrypted
so site to site VPN point to site VPN
anything you go anything going as
storage is encrypted and anything within
the infrastructure of asher is encrypted
if you have a dedicated high-speed win
like link like express route all that's
encrypted any contacts through
connecting up to an api a rest api is
all done over https so every single
thing in there is data in transit
encryption and then you know you can
even do file level encryption for data
at rest so it's got it's got lots of
encryption everywhere as I was
researching this I thought I'd tell you
this little late-breaking news
tidbit I didn't know about this it used
to be that when people could you noted
as your search they could actually bring
up you know key you know look for key
words and documents it would bring up
documents or partial partial findings
from documents and you could infer based
on their search results what the
contents of the document were right they
took that away now now everything's
encrypted with AES 256-bit and role
based access control so if you try to
search on something you're just not
you're not even be able to bring up
results from stuff that you don't have
access to at all so anybody who's
running a sure if you've if you've done
your indexing prior to January 24th you
don't have this yet but you should just
make sure you do if you run your you
should re index to make sure you get
that encryption and it can't be turned
off it's controlled by a Microsoft
alright so the you know everybody I
don't know one of the difficult things
for my students in classes I don't know
why their junior and seniors and IT and
I have the simplest assignment I think
which is install a virtual machine like
install virtualbox and Kali Linux and
get that running and I have to do help
session after help session to get them
because just so hard they just don't
understand it how to you know there's
some it's evidently fraught with lots of
difficulty for some people but so they
don't even understand it very basics but
virtualization is you have a host OS and
you've got some virtualization software
that runs a hypervisor which is what
enforces security protections between
the host and the guest and you run a
guest opera
system inside the virtual machine
alright that's about it so how does
Microsoft do all that well there's three
things they do they have protection for
the virtual machines themselves they
have isolation of processes and then
they have network security
so VMs in general like I said you have
your host OS hypervisor and guest OS the
VMS never have access to any Roth you
know read/write privileges on physical
software right that's protected that's
actually firewalled by the software by
by default at the app app as your
firewall hypervisor or whatever we want
to call it firewall it will block all
traffic from the VM to physical ports
and only let them get to virtual ports
that are locked down the things that
will let it do is like maybe go to DHCP
so it can get a local address or maybe
go out to the internet or maybe talk to
other VMs in a cluster but absolutely
everything on the back end
Asscher router subnets management back
in that's all blocked by default there's
absolutely no way to get to it
there's also memory and process
separation enforcement so anybody
remember the early days of VMware and
security enhanced Linux SSE Linux we're
all about trying to do process
enforcement I remember I worked on a
project with NSA way back in the day
called net top where they're trying to
run different virtual machines of
multiple levels of security you know
secret top secret and different flavors
of coalition networks all in one box and
it was using SELinux with a modified
VMware hypervisor to try to block you
know cut cut and paste from one
classification level to another and
things like that well this is all you
know standard for virtualization now now
I assume like we we know that they're
using a virtualized version of BitLocker
I don't I didn't really look at this and
does anybody know the answer this they
use a virtualized version of BitLocker
for their virtual disk encryption in a
cloud do they use hyper-v for their
hypervisor security or have they come up
with something completely new I don't
know the answer my guess is since they
don't mention it probably using VMware
just guessing but they also do
separation through you know private IP
addresses natin firewalls actually
there's far walls everywhere think about
this all right you got your physical
layer then you've got your host OS layer
then you have your hypervisor and you've
got your VM and you've got the operating
system that's the guest inside of the VM
they've got you've got firewalls on all
those every single place so the native
level your as your service fabric has
firewalls and keeps you in protect
storage and VPN at the host level
there's a you know a firewall that
protects the operator operating system
in that runs the hypervisor for the
hosts
when you go to the like the Windows when
you go to the azure storefront or
whatever you call that and download your
your operating systems your windows OSS
those all come with you know Windows
host based operating system turn on by
default when you try to get storage
everything is is blocked by a front-end
firewall server when you do VPN there's
a VPN firewall server so there's far
Wells everywhere in Azure so you would
think with all these firewalls it's
gonna slow stuff down right you know
every single place you're getting your
packets checked but you know they have
this you know fabric that's
interconnected they have high-speed
networking you know so everything's you
know try to they try to speed it up with
you know with high speed equipment all
right so we've got Identity Management
which is you know big deal basically
letting you Fed rate your on-prem with
your cloud and federated with other
outside services like Dropbox Google
Apps
you've got your encryption your file
control you've got your access control
you've got your VMs under control now
how do I make sure it's all running
correctly well I would like to have some
way to monitor it lock it down
assess it scan it right so here's what
they have for that they have something
called ohms first of all which is their
operations management suite so it's
really a collection of tools that lets
you do log analytics automation unless
you spin up vm's it helps you watch
things what I like about it is you can
even use it for some on-premises
operations so you just put an agent on
any Windows or Linux box on your on-prem
or in your data center and it will send
data to the log analytics for central
analysis along with it your cloud-based
stuff right all in one place
helps with backups site recovery and all
that stuff here's what actually owns
looks like if you log in I'm sorry it's
hard this is not that great of graphics
but you can see yeah you can't see I'm
even standing right by it I can't read
it but I'll tell you what it says it
tells you that there was X number of
systems to try to connect out to an own
command and control malware site that
there's X number of systems that aren't
properly provisioned for some patch so
there's some in addition to the health
and network status stuff that Azure
delivers it also gives you some security
stuff in addition it's got something
called
Security Center
and this is basically you can set up a
security policy for all of your VMs and
then you go check them all once think
how how powerful that is if you're
running say enterprise with mm you know
endpoints and you know 100 servers or
whatever all at a glance a couple of
buttons pressed out of policy to all of
them and then a couple more buttons
audit all of them and see how they're
doing so it's as simple as login to the
portal go to setup with security policy
go to a policy components section you're
gonna see the default policy that it
rolls out when you first deploy the VM
and then you can just turn on off on or
off stuff and hit save when you're done
here's all the stuff you can do here's
all policies you can set so you can set
it up for automatic Windows updates or
Linux distribution package you know
package updates you can look for sister
system miss configurations within the VM
you can make sure to have antivirus
installed this is just like just like on
Windows 10 on your desktop if you go and
you don't have any antivirus it's gonna
be like hey you really should have
something turned on and then you install
like AVG and it's like hey you really
should have something else turned on
besides that a lot of these things
actually is Microsoft trying to sell you
stuff right because they're gonna
they're gonna say oh you need this so go
pay us some more money and get it out of
the App Store disk encryption they want
you to turn that on you'll be BitLocker
for all your VIP vm's
security groups for our wall then we
have that turn on I told you some of
these couldn't things are turned on by
default
I'm sequel auditing and obviously if
you're running a database you should
have that turn on I can't imagine why
you would have that not turn on other
than I don't know negligence telling you
should have some kind of vulnerability
scanning setup and encryption this whole
thing with the just-in-time access
that's really you know by creating a
network security group rule you select
the ports on the VM which to which you
know inbound traffic should be locked
down things like that so this is all the
stuff they're selling you should have
and then you run a scan through there if
you click if you click on the prevention
tab in the Security Center it takes you
to something looks like this so it shows
you all at a glance okay here's how many
compliant here
non-compliant there's seven with high
severity those ones you got to look at
first and remediate right so it's pretty
powerful that's good
but full disclosure I'm not necessarily
an IT operations guy I start out in
software development start getting to
crypto boxes teaching classes auditing
so I like to break an audit stuff I'm
not necessarily running stuff so as an
auditor I wanted to know what could I do
to audit all that as a third party
obviously you know for vulnerability
assessment reason pen testing reasons
I'd like to see how somebody's doing
with their as your security so this is
kind of another slot slide I'm proud of
because I have figured out how to
actually run nessus with Azure does it
sounds like who uses Nessus
vulnerability scanner like half the
people right but if you try to use neces
to scan cloud configurations it's not
straightforward you have to do some
finagling much I didn't decide not to
show this in real time because real time
demos are always fraught with danger and
fail so I'm just going to show you some
screenshots and talk about it actually
but here's here's what happens number
one you go to the the azure portal and
you have to you click on Azure Active
Directory and now you can't read this
and this is hard to see and then you go
to app registrations and you click on
that and you create a new app so
remember we showed that demo earlier
which is it's just it's really an
instance what they call a service a
service object it's gonna have a name
and and some secret well when you click
on that thing when you create it and I'm
so sorry you can't see this it comes up
with two fields one that says
application ID and one that says object
ID the one you want for necess is the
application ID now when you go into
nessus it tells you it wants something
called a client ID don't know what that
is I think back in the day
a droid used to call that saying a
client ID but now calls an application
ID if you don't use the right one if you
try to use the object ID it's not going
to work all right so what Nessa
asked for calling it a client idea
they're really asking for application so
you create that you can call it anything
call it junk give it a URL junk calm and
and you want to copy the application ID
then you go into settings and you have
to click on require permissions is also
very important and I didn't I really
didn't find this in necessarily any
necess
you want to click on require permissions
and then you click on add in Windows
Azure service management API so you've
got to do this to give basically the
object API access from the outside in to
be able to scan your network but by the
way what I'm describing is I have you
know instance if necessary in my data
center and I use that to scanner scan
things and so I'm giving it access
through an API key or whatever to get
into Azure and scan this this cloud
instance you could actually do all this
in Azure itself there's a in the app as
your app store there's a necess tool and
it's like to bring your own license just
provision it with your license and you
can do it from right inside nessus but
i'm not going to show you that I'm
showing you the way I did it I would say
this is similar to how you do AWS
scanning tool to I just did some of that
recently you have to set up an app a key
asset a separate secret key for AWS to
be able to scan you can't just log in
with your user ID and password all right
be careful with those what you've done
is created this API key that has admin
root level privileges so I'd say after
you've done your scan throw that thing
away disable it deprecated don't use it
anymore once it's not in use or not
needed alright so let's take a look oh
you can't see that but it says make sure
you get application ID not object ID all
right so here's actually Nessus i don't
know if the tenable guys are here today
or not i saw actually saw something out
there but if you go into necess and you
start a new scan you select audit your
cloud infrastructure and that brings you
to a dialog that says you have choice
between an
Rackspace Salesforce or Azure so I'm
going to select a sure then I'm going to
put in my credentials here and the key
thing application idea right here even
though it says client ID whatever that
is then you have to sell it what you
want what compliance standard you want
to scan to so they have some choices
here they have an ad for best practices
one they've got one specifically for
websites they have one specifically for
database whatever you want to scan for
select your compliance thing and put it
in there and then you scan and boom you
get some results now I didn't really set
up a real instance it was just it was I
mean it didn't have a lot of data or
anything in it so most these warnings
are hey you know this certificate
doesn't exist and there's no virtual
machines that exist so I don't know
we're really scanning here but if I did
have some VMs in there you would
probably have some you know some fails
mornings most of the things have to do
with have you have you correctly
provision the VM in terms of security
settings you have strong passwords do
you have monitoring and logging turned
on and stuff like that so if you anybody
notice in a security information event
management anybody run us them a lot of
a security office enter sims are super
powerful we're partnered with you a lot
of them logarithm hailing in vaults
Blanca you radar things like that what
it does is it takes all of your your
like firewall data network IDs data
server data and puts it all into a
correlation engine and runs these rules
on it you know some of these have like
150,000 rules out of the box there
they're constantly updated with the
threat feed and it helps you see how
secure you are so you can actually use a
sim to not only monitor your VMs you
know what's going on inside those but
also monitor the health and status of
your pasture environment and all these
sims have a plugin for specifically for
office 365 and Azure cloud stuff as well
as Google Apps and you know AWS and so
forth so the beauty of that is that you
can
and you know they've got all these rules
pre-built and integrates free firewall
it's updated with an Intel feed you
don't have to actually write all the
rules yourself if you don't want to
there's some ulama you might like to
customize but key point is you don't
wanna monitor all about yourself right I
would recommend obviously selfishly
speaking go with the managed service
like ours because sim is very noisy it's
like a little kid it always wants your
attention here's my example I gave
everybody if you buy this there's
company hope they're not here friends of
ours good buddies but they bought us sim
first time we ever went in there we log
into the console and they had 90,000
unattended alerts so it's like you
bought this product you're paying 30,000
a year for it and nobody's ever watching
it or it's it's noisy and gives you so
many alerts that you can't take it stop
you know and then you just start start
ignoring all those alerts at your own
peril so best to go get somebody who
will go through all the alerts triage
them or escalate them according to some
incident response protocol and take care
of that for you to take it off your
plate otherwise you're gonna buy this
nice tool that's gonna do nothing for
you so it's about it I mean finally
speaking you know I think we know cloud
isn't perfect a sure Microsoft I don't
know if you can read this this is a
story from last year they had an azure
outage caught us caused by a fire
suppression gas lease release I know in
the earlier speakers who is speaking
about Zillow said he had a fire
suppression vulnerability I wonder if
that's related at all just guessing but
anyways they were down or they had
glitches for like seven hours so if you
put your eggs all in that one basket in
you're down for seven hours you're
probably sad oh yeah let's see this
little trailer server farm I was telling
you about so I mean it's not perfect and
but the nice thing is you know and they
also charge you for everything anything
you want it's going to charge you more
they're gonna you know if you want to
add DLP hey we'll do that for you but it
cost you but the nice thing is there's a
lot of nice centralized security
features for Identity Management for
file encryption
for auditing logging and for getting
control of your security environment all
in one place and you can take advantage
of that so as I say pimp in my own self
again
you know let's manage the security
partner take care of that for you
because it's not something you want on
your plate
absolutely so hope you're smarter about
as your security now take a few
questions if anybody has he wow you're
enlightened that's awesome you're
completely enlightened well then as
[Music]
exactly any Azure security questions
yeah all right any questions about
cryptography no whatever you want to ask
me good changes in permissions where
they log sit yeah they're centralized
logging within securities with the
Security Center so
question question is about sins so
security information event management
solutions you take a port mirror off
your firewall and you feed it into the
sim you also put an agent or pull logs
from Windows systems or Linux boxes
critical servers like file servers
database server web server DNS and
everything like that you also put an
agent or pull logs off of all of your
critical infrastructure like router
switches and so forth all those events
get poured into one aggregation server
so thousands of events per second maybe
even per second depending on how large
the environment is then thus in this the
brains of the sin is that it runs these
correlation rules algorithms
continuously over everything and
determines if something looks like an
intrusion is happening if there's some
security alert that needs to be taken
care of a lot of times they're false
positives or there's something we've
seen before it's just a matter of
understanding the environment and
triaging it but a lot of times those
things have to be taken care of
immediately and spring into action so oh
this guy's connecting out to me a
command-and-control site we know he's
infected with malware let's shut that
box down or let's put a rule up in the
firewall to block it so there's some
simple things you can do for incident
response right off the bat last question
yeah now you can I think I believe you
can direct that not to not to the
centralized logging in the cloud you can
put you can move that to wherever you
want it to go I believe so yep and a lot
of these sims actually have an agent
that they use with them - for example
alienvault in the past has used awesome
open-source sim they're actually talking
about we just talked to their
development people there on the on a
roadmap to create a new agent so you
have to look out there and see what kind
of log pushing agents there are
available and how you how those work
alright thanks a lot guys
[Applause]