okay
is this what I speak into this yeah yeah
if it you don't wanna eat it huh no I
can use it I don't know if you
introduced me you're okay
good afternoon good afternoon everyone
thanks for joining
we have Julien vivent he's an expert in
all sorts of applications security he
works with Mozilla and he keeps the
Firefox at cloud services at Mozilla
safe
he has also authored a book on securing
DevOps and so we look forward to hearing
his interesting presentation welcome
thank you everyone I have never given a
talk before with that kind of microphone
so I feel like a stand-up comedian and I
try not to make too many jokes but this
is kind of cool so this talk is about
modern web applications security I'm
gonna talk about the kind of problems
that we've seen at Mozilla over the
years securing websites and web services
all over the place and how you work
around that and what kind of security
you can put in place on your websites so
I've been introduced already but very
quickly I run the operations security
teams on Firefox so we take care of all
of the Firefox back-end services the
stuff that you use to log into your
Firefox accounts or synchronize your
bookmarks or receive web push
notifications
I'm a developers I started mostly as a
sysadmin
did a bunch of development I think I'm
more some sort of deaf psych ops like
DevOps DevOps tech whatever you want to
call it nowadays I also authored a book
that's called securing DevOps so we
talked about DevOps a bit in the book
and we talked about security a lot that
actually covers like this is kind of the
400 pages version of these talk so if
you want the long version go check this
out and and with that what I really want
to focus on today is at first the kind
of issues that we see on modern websites
and and we're going to take a random
target but one that obviously would not
offend anybody and fortune fortune
everybody hates fortune it's fantastic
it's easy to beat on it fortune
is terrible you know not only because of
the content that gets posted on there
but also because of its web security and
I mean try to zoom in here a little bit
if we can get this a little bigger I
should be fine so this is the grading of
fortune according to Observatory that
Mozilla or which is a website we run
that scans your website and will give it
a grade depending on various security
controls that you have put in place
fortune gets an F and it gets an F
because it doesn't have a content
security policy it doesn't have sub
resource integrity it has no TLS at all
no HTTP at all it has a whole bunch of
issues and you might saying well that's
a grade okay so maybe it doesn't really
matter but we'll discuss later on that
yes actually it does matter in having a
good grade will help you in your
security
so for Jan well you wouldn't expect them
to be awesome and security after all
it's only Commons and GD content that
goes on there so let's look at some
other websites and this is united calm
all right you would expect them to have
a little higher budget for their web
security and they get a D they have no
content security policy they have no
protection on their session cookies I
think up until recently that was one of
the site that was passing problem to
Firefox because they had rc4 enabled on
their cell and they that was actually
prioritized at the very top and I would
break some of our efforts to modernize
HTTPS so another one that's really bad
and really shouldn't because they have
money here newyorktimes.com
that's a pretty big newspaper a lot of
people read this with all people trust
the data that come from new york times
you would think their web security is
pretty important and still they get addy
so we're seeing a trend here is that
overall we really suck at web
application security and so this is data
that April King my colleague at Mozilla
who runs the observatory collects and
she published that's every year or twice
a year and 90% that's the stance that
she posted this week
90% of websites can on the observatory
get an F
90% well it's to better a year ago it
was two years ago it was 97% so we're
getting slowly better at it but really
really slowly
very few websites get an A+ that's not
easy so fine maybe you shouldn't be
aiming for A+ but you could at least get
a B and I'll talk about what it takes to
actually get there
so does this matter that's just grades
right do we care after all to get an A+
on a website like we're here to run a
business not to get a good grade on some
random visit our website right well this
is data that comes from buck crab and
buck routes as you may know provides a
platform to operate your bug bounty
right and they have a lot of customers
they run over 600 programs so that's 600
corporations that uses buck route to to
offer bounties on their websites or
their web application security and
that's a data for last year they paid
out more than 6 million dollars to bug
bounty researchers who found actual
vulnerabilities on their customers
websites right so those issues are
issues that thankfully were not
exploited for any sort of malicious
activity but were reported to bugcrowd
to the companies that run the bug bounty
program and could be fixed before they
were actually exploited
I don't think Equifax has a bug bounty
program or maybe they do now but that
will probably have save their asses so
this thing matter right I mean we run we
have one of the oldest bug bounty
program at Mozilla we run it both on
what we call the client side so for
Firefox itself and for the the web
application side and we pay a ton of
money every year to researchers who come
to us and say well I found some random
application bypass on some random
application that you guys forgot about
and we give them a few thousand bucks
and it's pretty much the only way for us
to keep an eye on everything that we run
because we have I think to date
something like 400 websites that that we
run day-to-day that people rely on some
of them are obviously more important
than other if you're addons.mozilla.org
and you're delivering Firefox add-ons to
order Firefox you
security is pretty important and then we
have stuff like is Windows XP dead yet
calm right I mean that's just one page
with a dashboard on it
no one cares but it still counts as a
website the problem we have and that's a
problem we faced at Mozilla where we try
to be pretty good at web security any of
you buddy else faces as well including
Equifax I'm gonna beat on them quite a
bit because I don't like them is that
modern web applications are ridiculously
complex and this is a funny tweet that
was posted a couple of months ago here
we see a react engineer deploying a
contact form you've seen this right I
mean you have your dev team coming to
you saying hey I'm gonna push that
nodejs application on our AWS account
next week could you do a quick review
and you open it is like a gazillion
dependencies for thousand lines of code
like what does this thing do oh it's a
dashboard for the finance department I'm
like what what how am I supposed to
review this thing is ridiculously
complex and it's not getting any simpler
so securing them often feels like you
know it's a losing battle you can't do
anything about it but with some efforts
and some well-trained developers and
some good practices we can get there and
this is
accounts that Firefox comm right and we
worked with these teams so you can look
at a bunch of the website that we run
and they all get the A+ now because we
worked with them very very closely to
get Compton security policy in place to
improve their HTTPS to improve their
dependency management and it's a lot of
work it takes teams of people to do it
and we learned a few things while doing
that and what we learn is actually is
that you can get most of it done by
following these six areas these are the
six areas that pretty matter of to your
web applications security today and I'm
gonna talk about each one of these so
it's gonna be a fun 40 minutes some of
that stuff is old and and I'm hoping
that probably a third of the content
here will not be used to you hoping
because I know that web application
security is hard and our heads are just
you know not big enough to keep it all
in one place so it's possible you learn
a bunch of stuff
so let's start with content injection
and here I'm talking about cross-site
scripting attacks exercise so that's
pretty much a number one attack vector
from modern and old web applications
pretty much since the sámi worm and that
was in 2005 and who remembers the Samy
worm I did so I'm going to be explaining
what it is again so in 2005 this
researcher that's a journalist it's not
the guy who found it but I forget his
name yes and what he found is that you
could inject a little chunk of
JavaScript on the comments of a MySpace
page and when he when someone else was a
myspace account will visit that page the
JavaScript would execute in their
browser we have access to their session
and could post itself to their own page
therefore replicating itself to the page
of the victim and that was quite a
little fun experiment really the the
researcher didn't try to make any money
out of this or anything but that blew up
out of proportion and within just a few
hours it had replicated itself all over
myspace and taken over hundreds of
thousands of pages and if obviously
everybody freaked out that was just a
very simple cross-site scripting attack
and we know about this we knew about it
before 2005 but since 2005 we know it's
an actual problem so basically a
cross-site scripting attack is a
security exploit which allows an
attacker to inject content into which
inject client-side code into a website
that get executed on the victims
computer and bypasses all the access
controls and can be used in person in
the Mexican etc that's from MDN Mozilla
developer Network web pages has good
page numbers and if you've never seen
one this is basically what it looks like
that little snippet of code at the top
that just injects text JavaScript and
what's between the braces here is your
JavaScript code and here's an alert
exercise that would print the string XSS
whenever it's executed
you put that unit down into your page
you have that little alert pop-up from
JavaScript show up this is everybody
knows this we've seen it a million times
when we test test and XSS on a new page
that's the string everybody uses so this
is fairly standard stuff so obviously
because we won't know about this it's
fixed right this is bug bounty data from
2016 and 2017 at Mozilla the categorized
by type of vulnerability application
logic disclosure impersonation CSRF
application with configuration
authentication etc etc the one on the
left is XSS it is about ten times more
prevalent across our application than
any other type of your nobility we know
about it this is taken 11 years 12 years
after the sami worm and we still suck at
it so the remedy here and the reason we
push so much on content security policy
is because by setting this HTTP header
on your web applications you're telling
the browser to not execute any sort of
inline JavaScript so if someone injects
JavaScript in choose a comment of a page
and it's not part of a loaded script
that's part of the application is
something like that the browser would
say nope not not running this right so
obviously this policy here is the simple
simplest possible version of a content
security policy and if you have a 10
year old PHP application that loads code
all over the place and as inline Styles
and inline scripts and everything it's
gonna be a bit more work to get your CSP
to work but to give you an example we
used to have probably one or two XSS
vulnerability is a month on
addons.mozilla.org we invested a lot of
time on putting CSP in place and we I
don't think we've had a single XSS since
that was a year and a half ago we used
to pay money for these bounties we used
to have developers have to go fix their
code they used to have to track down all
of the possible injection vectors now we
just put CSP in place and we know it's
an old app and we could probably do
better and we use sanitation frameworks
and whatnot
but CSP really really helped us kill
that attack vector entirely
if you're a better for developer this is
basically how you put it in a go
application and I could even go you
could do the same thing in Java PHP
Python whatever but essentially in you
have your middleware that handles HTTP
responses and you inject a response
header with content security policy and
in the string that we present your
policy so d for SOC star and object
source none and I'm not going to get
into the details of what the keywords
inside of a CSP mean because I will take
the whole 40 minutes but what you should
know is this if you're starting a new
project or if your dev team is starting
a new project have them use this policy
just as a starting point and add stuff
to it as they implement more features
and they basically will not add any work
to them they're not any more pressure on
the development pipeline but it will add
a whole lot of protection to their web
application when they ship it so do it
from the start it's a lot easier oh one
thing that is worth noting is that CSP
does not get cached so you need to
return it with every HTTP response right
it's not like just yes or the other
things that get cached in the browser
CSP must be returned all the time so
accepting user generated content header
cartman Yelp critic so if you run an
application of website a web service
that accepts user content any type of
user content could be just comment on
the blog could be images that they can
upload in their profile it could be I
don't know maybe you have a healthcare
portal and you accept invoices in PDF
format whatever what you need to know is
that pretty much any sort of file format
or input format can be used to inject
malicious content if you think you can
sanitize a JPEG image sufficiently then
go look at the all of the JPEG
injections that were published over the
years
if you accept images in SVG format well
that's great because SVG is a scripting
language so you can pretty much put
everything you want in an SVG image it's
really really hard it in really hard to
accept user content and reflect it on
your main domain security it's almost
impossible to do so that's basically to
take away here do not reflect content on
your main domain what that means is that
if you accept an image from your users
for their profile page when you return
that image if it is served from your
main domain example.com where everything
else is and you have your sessions
cookies on example.com and everything
and that that image has a malicious
payload in it then it can access
everything that's on example.com
including session cookies locker storage
everything the security of a web
application depends on the security of
its main origin so if it's example.com
and your cookies are there anything that
runs inside example.com can compromise
that security so the way we do this is
every time we accept User Content and we
know we're gonna have to display it
somehow then we put it on a separate
domain and you might have seen Facebook
user content com Twitter user content
com this this sort of domains that are
not Twitter comm of facebook.com and
what they do is they serve the image to
the main site and the site will load it
as an iframe or as an external resource
and by doing so the browser will say
well fine I'm loading all of that
content from all over the place but it
doesn't have access to anything that
belongs to the main origin it doesn't
have access to session cookies it
doesn't have access to local storage
none of that so the the important part
here is if you have a commenting system
that you're hosting yourself for example
have it served through a separate domain
load it from an iframe into your main
domain and you wouldn't have you won't
have to worry about injections that's
that's actually really really hard to
implement like that takes weeks of work
with dev teams because you need to catch
that early if you have to go back to an
application before it goes to prod to
tell them hey all of your user-generated
content would have to go to a separate
domain they're going to freak out at you
talking up from experience here because
we've done that and they don't like it
but it is pretty much the only way yeah
I mean Facebook uses FB CDN dotnet
that's yeah basically how everyone's
does it there's no other way to sanitize
User Content
so speaking of cookies and it's
interesting when I learned web
application security decade and a half
ago cookies were important and people
were talking a lot about cookie security
and then and we cannot stop talking
about cookie security and assume yeah
you know everything's okay and people
don't really talk about cookie security
so much anymore because we assume it's
secure and then I joined Mozilla and I
realized we're like tons of people are
still working in the browser on cookie
security was still a problem and we were
still seeing a lot of issues on it so
what are the issues the main one is
people store cookies session cookies for
example for the web application
completely insecurity so they will let
for example the cookies be read by
JavaScript why a session cookie if you
think about it is really just that
little random string the browser is
going to send back every time it sends a
request to say hey I'm still Ascenta
cated but JavaScript on the page doesn't
need to access that why would it
manipulate the session cookie there's no
reason for that it's pretty between the
browser and the and the server so why
let your session cookie be manipulated
from JavaScript no reason so said HTTP
only on your session cookies and the
browser will say fine it's this shitty
piane javascript cannot touch it don't
send them in clear text so everything
should be HTTP nowadays but if it isn't
at least make sure your session cookies
have the secure flag on it so that the
browser will only send them back over
HTTP not HTTP expires them you know you
don't want someone to manage to get an
XSS on your user studio session cookie
and be able to still use it a year from
now like that's ridiculous expiry
session cookies renew them regularity
you don't need to do it every 30 seconds
but at least have a reasonable
expiration here and the interesting one
that we're going to dig into a little
bit more
is use the same straight attribute so
wait what's nice I never heard of that
one so same site
who knows what a CSRF a tank is yeah
this is gonna be fun
so same site prevents CSRF attacks and
I'm gonna explain how that works so you
have your browser here and the browser
accesses facebook.com everyone's you
know what user is authenticated user has
a session cookie
anyway sings great and then the browser
goes to your bad side dotnet right
doesn't really know it's a malicious
site maybe it's a legitimate site that
got hacked right and bad site dotnet we
have it in a nice HTML an image
essentially that points to facebook.com
slash delete
slash image slash to the browser says
okay fine
I need to send a get request choose that
URL so sends a get request to
facebook.com what the browser doesn't
know is that sending a get request to
that URL actually deletes image too so
bad side dotnet forced the browser to
delete an image on facebook.com
that's a cross-site request forgery yeah
like you look it's like what how is that
even possible well that's how the web
works and and the funny thing about this
is that bad side net tells the browser
to send the request the brother is like
oh I have to send a request to
facebook.com
let me also add all of my session
cookies to that request because you know
it's a request to facebook.com so you're
sending an authenticated request that
was triggered by a third party site
cross-site request forgery and this is
where same site cookies become
interesting because you can set on your
session cookie the same site attribute
and say same side equals strict and when
you do that the browser will only send
the session cookies if the request comes
from facebook.com if it goes on bad side
dotnet and bad side of net says hey send
a request your Facebook the browser will
say sure I will but I cannot send those
cookies because your bad side dotnet
asking me to send a request and so I'm
gonna exclude all of the stuff that's
protected by some site
so it's a bit tricky but it's very
important and if you talk to your web
des and you ask them how do you prevent
CSRF today they're probably gonna tell
you we trust the web framework that we
use Django flask whatever you use PHP or
whatnot is that sort of thing I don't
know I haven't done PHP in 10 years
people laughing probably means yes yes
that's what runs our production and
those web frameworks usually implement
CSRF token CF tokens are complicated
that requires to do each max they're
appending the S to deploy people mess
them up all the time and same site
essentially is a better way to do cos I
have token so you're a bit on the
leading edge of things here because same
site is not deployed everywhere but it's
something to keep an eye on next time
you you're asked to review a web app
that has here's our problem all right
our stuff let's do something a little
more fun who knows about have I been
poned calm yeah you want one of my
favorite site in the world so great
great site you should check it regularly
Troy hunt is a fantastic person he has
been doing a whole lot of work just
collecting hacked accounts and putting
that for free on the on the public
Internet and he's just really helpful
when it comes to understanding exactly
how widespread accounts theft is and
what we've learned from have I been
poned is that collecting user name and
passwords from your users and storing
them in your database is a terrible idea
you're gonna it up that for sure
you're going to it up at some point
like let me tell you a story a few years
ago Mozilla developer Network MTN is a
django application right and and because
we musta died everything we do is
open-source and in order to help
contributors who didn't have all that
accounts and whatnot
participate in the development of mdn we
used to give them a sanitized dump of
the database I'm gonna give you five
seconds to figure out what happens next
the sanitization job didn't work well
and one day we gave them an unsanitized
dump of the database was a bunch of
password hashes so we regulated like
what why do we have 50,000 password
hashes on the internet so that was that
was sad it was a bad week for me we
stopped publishing that database dump
and we want everybody to change their
passwords and make sure that those
passwords were not reused on other sites
but basically we learned that we
probably shouldn't ask our web
application developers to store
passwords because those databases are
going to leak at some point so now the
questions we asked the most of the time
when we do risk assessments for new
projects is what happens when the
database ends up on Twitter they always
say why the hell we put the database on
Twitter it's like well it's not exactly
up to you it's just gonna end up on
Twitter at some point so the best way to
do this and it is essentially to let
somebody else or Santa Kate users for
you
there are largely enough authentication
IDC providers out there that you can
just pick the one you like Google
Microsoft Yahoo paper github Amazon they
all provide identities and what is
really really good about using those is
that first of all for you you don't have
to store passwords anymore you don't
have to spend a whole week figuring out
which hash function in which size of
salt is best suited to that new 20:18 no
js' application you're building just
connect to an identity provider
and you won't have any password in your
database but the other thing is you
allow your users to use two-factor
authentication and I don't know if
you've tried implementing 2fa in your
web app and managing tokens and managing
TOTP or u2f for one it's really hard
we're doing it right now for Firefox
accounts and we're working through all
of the failure scenario and the the one
that is the most difficult for us to to
implement is how do we deal with users
who just lose their tokens and and once
you regain access to their account you
need the support team for that you need
in Google and Microsoft and Facebook
they have support teams who can answer
use a request and Ascenta Kate them with
whatever the driver license or whatnot
we don't have that so it's really really
hard to do it yourself so what's gonna
happen is you support username and
password authentication and you'll never
support 2fa which is a terrible idea
the other thing is fraud detection is
really hard and I was at the ending my
conference last month where the folks
that run the account management system
at Google we're talking about protecting
user accounts and the amount of energy
in engineering and and just pure money
that they invest into fraud detection is
ridiculous it's probably your entire
security budget so you're not going to
do it as well as they do it's better to
let them do it
and finally users they already have too
many passwords I saw a little cartoon on
the internet the other day there was a
surgeon opening someone scale saying we
need to raise a pressure on this
person's brain I'm gonna remove two
dozen passwords it's true like we all
have files with with dozens of passwords
from websites we haven't connected to in
the last three years but we need to keep
it around in case we need it it's really
hard to do so identity providers solve
that problem and you should use them all
right switching gear again
one of my favorite topic dependency
management Equifax you probably know how
Equifax got hacked but just to remind
everybody here they were hosting a web
application open to the internet that
had a venerable version of Apache struts
Apache strands will use framework for
any sort of Java Web Apps and they had
forgot to patched it this is they had an
old version of it and the attackers
garden used the publicly available
exploit probably for it yes no ID I
forget we I don't do Java so I just
looked at exactly what the issue was
basically but I I didn't look into the
details of how they got in but if you
look Equifax Apache stress you'd find
the entire write-up of what the issue
was and probably hide was exploded but
basically what the important part is is
that they had a dependency code that
they had not written themselves that was
important in their web application and
that was Apache struts and they had they
are not updated that dependency to the
latest version now probably 90% of the
code that we use in any sort of modern
web application comes from third parties
today the the joke about the the web
devs who are shipping a contact form in
react well really the majority of that
code is framework whether it's the react
framework or any sort of JavaScript
dependencies that gets imported like if
you look at any sort of modern web app
let's say node.js for example will have
a package.json file will contain
probably five dependencies in there and
you think oh that's just five
dependencies create but you need to
expand that tree because those
dependencies have dependencies of
dependencies and when you do the entire
shrink-wrap operation of flattening that
into the actual list of dependencies
that are used is going to be hundreds of
them this email I don't know if you can
read it but I read it for you they were
sent to me by a
developer of firefox accounts three days
ago
little hole a manifestation is published
to npm called conventional changelog
1.2.0 on february 12 the module will
minecraft cryptocurrency when invoked
from require context we use this module
in many of our repositories now mind you
is talking about accounts that firefox
dot-com the stuff that people logs into
to access their accounts right so I'm
freaking out
server environments should not be
affected by this NPM issue I'm no longer
freaking out we use NPM shrink-wrap and
pin versions of packages good however
John is double checking to make sure
everything is okay etc we've added email
and I'm glad because one of our dev
actually sent us an email saying hey we
have a package that is potentially if
your net worth I probably use all over
the place now these guys are more
paranoid about security than I am
because they know they around an
accounting system user accounting system
so they're pretty security focused but
we have another probably fifty or sixty
nodejs applications that may be using
that dependency and we have no idea if
they're Vernor abort if they have a
conversion or if they're currently
mining cryptocurrencies on production
hardware so one of the guy in my team
went to actually wrote some scripts and
in thankfully everything we write is on
github so we went to all of our github
organizations and and verified that we
don't use a venerable version of the
package but that's something we have to
do regularity I think last year who is
he saying I think we had five NPM
venerable fraudulent NPM packages last
year alone and that's just for nodejs
then we have Python applications you can
look at how go works etc etc it's really
difficult so you need tooling in your
web application this is a dashboard
that's created by requires dot IO that's
for Python application it will
essentially run against your source code
and look at your dependencies and tell
you if some of them are known to be
renewable and it will alert you
there are other services that do this as
well
no GSS greenkeeper dot io that actually
just sends you a pull request with your
dated version you just have to let your
CI environment run merge it and you're
good to go
we use PI of the IO a lot sneak dot IO
is a new service if you do if you do
Java
it supports Madden if you do Ruby
supposed ruby gem Pippin NPM so that's
another one I think it's still free for
principals projects and also once you
look into dependency management some
could add securing the supply chain
you'll find it in the different names
that it's it's something a lot of people
are worried about nowadays the slides
are online by the way um you should just
look at my Twitter account and just wit
them alright let's talk about HTTP a bit
this is bad SSL calm is a site that just
had bad SSL all over the place on
purpose so we can test things HTTPS is
not just important because it shows you
a little pretty green lock nowadays it's
important because any sort of complex
web application feature that you
developer want to use will require HTTPS
the browser's are actually we're
disabling a whole bunch of JavaScript
features in Firefox and the chrome team
is doing the same thing if it's not on
HTTP a lot of stuff you can't do anymore
so you need to be able to set up HTTPS
all over the place everywhere this
example here is an alert message at
Firefox displays when a user enters
their password so it's a password field
in a form on a page that isn't HTTP and
it would actually tell the user this
connection is not secure logins entered
here could be compromised when we
deployed this last year we had
application developers and website
owners scream at us because we're
freaking out their users because we're
harming their businesses and in claiming
that their web sites were insecure when
in fact they were perfectly secured
because all of the servers were secured
and everything and like how you
sending passwords in clear-text on the
internet what the hell are you even
arguing about but we did have people who
did not understand what was going on
here so it is critically important that
we make HTTPS the default they make it
really easy and I think this is
something that security team probably
understand better and can help a lot
with make it really easy for any
developer to get an HTTPS certificate on
their test environment on their staging
environment pre-production production
whatever make it trivial and the way you
can do that is obviously you can
automate it with let's encrypt so I'm
not going to get into the details of
this because you all know what it's
encrypt is and what it does basically
run a script on your machine and it will
go get a certificate for you when you it
automatically fantastic you can make
that a little more complicated if you're
running in AWS Google Cloud is your you
can use your DNS if you don't want you
have your server be on the public
Internet as you probably you can have a
server that is behind VPN not accessible
from the public internet and can still
get the let's encrypt certificate
because the challenge doesn't require
you to open your web server to the
Internet you can use a challenge for the
certificate using your DNS records so
you can do a whole lot of stuff with
automation and let's encrypt for your
test environment you dead of
environmental stuff that you don't want
to expose to the public Internet and
once you have HTTPS you should test it
so again we're back on the observatory
there's a tab on that page unless you
test the quality of your HTTP with the
TLS observatory and if you want a good
configuration to run on your server you
can go to your configuration generator
there is config sample for Apache nginx
like the if and once it uses that it's
your proxy everybody's here these
eccentric cetera it's it's just copy
paste at that point all right so I fried
everyone's brains with sort of the fancy
new stuff let's talk about some old
stuff a little bit and I think everyone
here would be familiar hopefully would
be familiar with the basics of testing
your application and I'm going to talk a
little bit about the benefits and
drawbacks of these four approaches the
first one of course
web application for nobility scanning so
I'm fortunate enough to have the lead
developer of ZAP in my team Simon
Bennett's so we do use that quite a bit
and obviously we get the benefit of the
entire wasp ecosystem so it's a great
tool but there are the tools that zap
you know other problems that that
doesn't solve them I'm going to talk a
bit about fuzzing and static code
analysis but also relying on external
researchers because I think it's very
important so that if you don't know it
it's it's a GUI it can be run on the
command line but it's an application
that we've crawled your application your
website and and look at all of the pages
and find issues with it it's really
really good for more traditional
applications it's not as good with the
new stuff for example reactives is a
thing called the virtual Dom that is
really hard to parse and that doesn't
really understand it well but you should
at least try it it Auto supports web
api's if you have a REST API and you
publish in an open API document that
describes your API is that can scan that
so there's a whole lot you can do with
this out of we're on a capture the flag
challenge at our last mozilla all-hands
in december and it was fun because we
had a bunch of people come in who were
used to web application security but i
never really used that and discovered me
included actually discovered a whole lot
of features that I didn't know existed
in zap that really made it easier to
poke at these web applications to go
discover dark corners of the app and the
app wasn't an old 20 year old PHP app it
was a recent nodejs app called the wasps
juice shop if you haven't looked at that
it's a really cool CTF capture-the-flag
application and that was a really great
tool to to browse that application and
start poking at its dark corners and
funny issues and one of the thing that
we do a lot is we run zap as a proxy so
we essentially tell you know the browser
to go through this app to go to the
target website and that would inspect
everything that transits through that
connection so even if you have a really
modern web
you know something crazy or like a super
old JavaScript or Java app and there's
really no way to inspect that directly
you can still use your browser to
interact with that application and zap
to inspect the content as it goes
through you can also do fancy things
like fuzzing in zap so for example
you're you're capturing a request that
has an argument in the URL you can
select the document and say all right we
place that with a whole bunch of random
utf-8 and see if that blows up the
app and that's useful if you're in like
in more of a pen testing mode where
you're trying to really break your
application you can do interesting
things with it static code analysis I
think is more something that developers
should use it's it forces in my mind
more in the category of writing good
code and cleaning up your code and the
same way you will write a Python
application and and pass it through your
unit tests or passes through flake eight
to make sure it's well formatted and
everything it's useful to have a static
code analysis look for issues in the
code you wrote so here the issue we
found this is called bend it it's a
static code analysis tool for Python and
it looks at the source code of an
application called kinto and it says for
example here we're using I don't know if
we see it here we're using the input
method right here and in Python - you
can put Python in that variable and it
will get executed as Python code which
is pretty cool use the name sure let me
write a Python script as my username and
that gets run on the machine
the study code analyzer will catch this
whereas it maybe it's unlikely that zap
will try to inject a Python script
inside of a username like it's it's a
little more instrumented right you need
to know what you're doing in Python 3
this isn't an issue they fix the input
method but it is still a as one and in
person to study could analysis is also
something that developers will
understand better than security people
because you need to understand the code
you need to understand the specificities
of the language who wrote the code with
so there are a lot of really fine
details about how your application is
built that are difficult for security
folks to work through so but a good tool
at the very least you should ask your
dev team what do they think of these
tools run it against their application
and take an hour with them and say hey I
just run this thing I just want to go
through it with you and see if you think
those are issues and if we should put
this tool in our continuous integration
platform to run it regularly and maybe
they'd find a whole bunch of false
positives and not like it maybe they'd
find it useful right but at least you
can ask them in and and have them
participate in that process
so I mentioned DevOps we didn't talk
around about DevOps but we do a lot of
fun integration of our tests in
continuous integration what we don't
want is to have to go scan production
apps that have been deployed as a months
ago in order to find issues so what we
do is our devs will build their
applications in github and run all the
unit tests in circle CI or Travis CI
whatever CI they like to use and we'll
put a test code or our scanning code
directly in that CI environment so every
pull request will go through some amount
of testing you can do that with zap we
have the thing where we could it the
does that baseline scan because it
really does like basic tests here and
you pull down a docker container is that
too darker weekly and you run that
directly in your C environment against
an instance of your application running
locally and we'll find issues like all
of the issues we talked about now here
we have missing X browser XSS protection
so no content security policy but
there's an anti CSRF token so the stuff
we talked about how you secure your
cookies are you put your CSP in place
etc you can test for it continuously by
putting your testing tool directly in CI
environments
and to close on something a little bit
lighter is I really think everyone
should consider opening a bug bounty
program these are the payouts that we
give our researchers and if you find a
remote code execution on a critical site
so that's going to be one of the main
site that we run you'll get 5000 bucks
you'll get your name on the Hall of Fame
and and probably a published report and
all that stuff we have a lot of junior
developers junior security people who
who come to a bug bounty program with
with a very limited understanding of web
application security and use a program
to ramp up so part of the cost for us is
triaging all of these low quality
security issues from from reporters who
do not have the experience yet so sure
there is a cost and it's I wouldn't
start a bug bounty program like for
example if you're running 50 websites
and you know they're insecure and you're
the only person doing security probably
don't put all of them in your scope like
day one because you're gonna get so many
reports that triaging enemy is going to
kill you but you can ramp it up slowly
putting one website at a time and and
make sure that you are polite to
researchers and that you pay them
because they like that too
the other thing I recommend and I give a
version of this talk to two web
developers at some point and they were
more interested in this but and I know
you guys will know this already but I
mean do get external teams to review
your web apps give them the source code
give them we did one we do that
regularity this is with on Firefox
accounts with secure 53 a German company
that does fantastic web apps like work
we gave them the source code they came
back with a list of 20 issues nobody
would have thought about and and that's
really really valuable obviously costs
more money but I think it's really worth
the effort like sometimes in my mind if
you're looking at your budget for the
year and you have to choose between
hiring a new security person or
investing that amount of money into
you external tests you may want to
consider external tests because you're
not gonna get a single pen tester who
can do the same quality of work that an
external firm is gonna do that's not
gonna work so you might want to consider
that when you build your budget I'm
going to keep on this don't host your
stuff yourself if you can avoid it
use Heroku AWS Google planet etc it's
better so some resources on this we have
a pretty big page on web application
security on the Mozilla wiki we have a
security checklist that we give to all
of our teams it's in markdown format so
they can just copy and paste it and
github issues against on the wiki the
slides online the closing starts is
don't be Equifax stay out of the news
secure your websites thank you