all right so everybody we're going to
get started my name is Melissa dark and
I'm a professor here at Purdue
University Jerry asked me if I would do
a fireside chat and so when I envisioned
this I envisioned Diana and Tim and Neil
and I sitting down here amongst you and
and we would be fireside chatting with
you but I'm told that's not possible I
asked yesterday but for videotaping
purposes that can't be done so I'm gonna
start you know I'm gonna ad-lib here
real quick thought what can I do I'm
gonna start with a few questions set the
tone about fireside chats okay so who
gave the first fireside chat FDR gave
the first fireside chat that's correct
when was the first fireside chat
delivered the day after a tornado
warning no I looked I thought wouldn't
that be so ironic if there was a tornado
warning in the United States
I checked only in the United States
Dickey so when was it it was 1933 and
there was a tornado warning on March
14th 1933 in Nashville Tennessee closest
one okay and this one is Reagan's first
State of the Union address since I had
Reagan on the last slide I thought I'd
carry that through so there were a total
of 30 fireside chats and this question
is asking you what was the theme of the
first and the last number one and number
the bank crisis and the fifth war loan
drive that's correct so with the the
focus of our fireside chat here is deep
ok
the cybersecurity labor market and
demand and supply and this is a bonus
question that has a prize with it and
the question is not up here what is the
average length of a fireside chat I'll
take the first five answers closest
person big 30 minutes to set it's okay
any other answers 2020 645 going 35 was
29 and a half minutes 29 and a half
minutes to done right it's good to see
you and I say that because I have a
dissertation defense at today at noon
I'm the major professor for a young man
who's going to defend his dissertation
today so I thought that was another
important aspect so I'm really thrilled
to be joined by three of my colleagues
Tim I'm only meeting in person for the
first time today Diana Baur Lee so diana
is currently associate dean for research
and external relations at the george
washington school of human resources
education and human development
I've known Diana for a long time and
she's got a wealth of experience I think
looking at what has changed in about 20
years in in the supply chain of
supplying cybersecurity professionals
Neil ziering lead technical director at
the National Security Agency been there
29 years if I remember correctly and
all 29 years in government service so I
asked Neal to talk to us a little bit
about what he has observed in labor
demand changing over that period of time
and Tim Sewell currently at Eli Lilly
formerly at Mayo Clinic and I forgot the
other place lucky Martin Martin so we've
got from the demand side some
interesting perspectives both from the
the government and from the private
sector so before I open up with my first
question you all see the same statistics
that I see Oh 1.8 million people needed
in the global cyber security workforce
by 2022 and sometimes you you put those
numbers up in there they're shocking
maybe even almost paralyzing you know
what what do we do what do we do and
having been involved with the serious
program here in cybersecurity education
at Purdue for a long time for almost 20
years we are still only producing a
trickle you know so sometimes I think
it's it's just a matter of more and then
I say no it isn't it's a matter of more
of the right thing you know
hmm so I want to open with what are your
perspectives on and I'll start with Neal
and then go to Tim what are your
perspectives on more more of the right
thing okay I don't know if this is my
god yeah so uh I think it's partly a
matter of more but it's not exactly the
same mix of people that we wished to
hire that was sort of wanting to pull
into the cybersecurity profession than
it would have been say 5 or 10 years ago
right I think at least in my perception
watching that from the government side
there was a lot more emphasis on
what I might flippantly call boxes and
processes you know hiring people who
could build boxes for us and hiring
people who would run what we might think
of as security compliance processes you
know your creditors and testers not that
those people aren't needed we still need
people to do that although the
experiences we're asking there's a
little different but we need a lot more
folks in the areas of things like threat
analysis application security design and
characterization and people at what I
might characterize is the intersection
of cybersecurity policy and law that's
sort of a growth area in my perception
so and I've other notes of things I'll
work in later okay let's go to you I
would I think it's it's a question of
more of what and I think there's
especially in kind of post post primary
education there's an emphasis on some
really technical skills which are
important but if if you can't speak in
the language of business then you're
less useful in a in a corporate setting
at least security is a boardroom
conversation now we have we have that
conversation with our board of directors
at every quarterly meeting we have it
with our Executive Committee on a
regular basis and if all you can do is
speak about security in terms of math
and firewalls
you can't tie that back to the risk of
the business those critical operational
processes then you're you're less useful
to the corporate side of the equation so
I think there's there's got to be that
blend between the hard technical skills
and then that business acumen so I'm
going to turn it to Diana now and I'm
gonna say okay if it's if it's more and
more of certain things what's your
perspective on the United States
currently has about 260 schools
recognized as centers of academic
excellence in cyber security
research institutions for your schools
to your schools you know how is our
system marshaling its resources to be
responsive how can it be more agile
where do we get stuck so we have about
260 CA es but we have 4500 institutions
of higher education in the United States
so we still have a long ways to go even
if we just look at at that balance
because the reality is that it's not
just CA es that we're looking to to
develop the cyber security workforce so
we have a long way to go even when we
look inside the CA es and we look inside
the institutions that are developing
students they're primarily based in
computer science Computer Engineering IT
places where curricula is very heavily
focused on the computing aspects of the
challenge but also where the curriculum
is so full that it's difficult to add in
some of these other elements that we
need where we've heard business policy
law business acumen communications and
all of that and so we really have to
think a bit more broadly and
holistically about how to implement and
develop programs that will allow us to
strike the right balance and we've we've
been working on some initiatives to help
us to do that but we really have to
think a bit more broadly about how to
effectively balance the development of
technical skills and also the
development of the business acumen and
the communication skills that will allow
our cybersecurity professionals to be
able to function within their
organization ok so I want to stop for
just a minute because I'm supposed to be
doing a fireside chat and not a panel
and I want to go ahead and fire and
invite some of you to yes please I am
inviting you to make her for yes
can you hear me
yeah I'm Fred sheol consultant thank you
very much
Nashville I I totally agree with
everything I heard on the panel I'm very
excited that I think you guys are
getting this story right I've done work
in academia in business and I take
exception with the number about you know
we need a million new cybersecurity
professionals or something like that I
did drill down and contacted people in
government about that and the number
really refers to jobs that have some
component of cybersecurity acumen needed
to do the job which I'd kind of agree
with but I think that we really have to
get this idea across that let's say you
look at a typical large company how many
people are involved in cybersecurity is
like 0.2% or something like that
so let's say we increase it to 0.25
percent is that going to have any effect
no I think we need to develop more
programs to train the other people in
the company and not just do the boring
annual awareness training and several of
the speakers here talk about that so my
question is is there any hope for
getting the concepts of cybersecurity
into the boardroom into the senior
management so that when there's this
dialogue between the 0.2% and the rest
of the people progress can be made more
effectively okay great question initial
responses yes absolutely in fact the
program that that you all were talking
about earlier where we're spreading
across that Purdue even looking across
different schools is is a testament to
that but but I would take issue with the
point two percent in my mind everyone is
doing some cybersecurity related work in
the organization and it's just a
question of what role are they playing
and how are they participating in the
process because when we look at it that
way it is a more effective way of
convincing academic institutions that we
need to spread cybersecurity across the
curriculum and enable those institutions
to to target and position the pieces of
content where they need to but to make
the argument that everyone has some role
to play and that we just have to figure
out how to effectively
teach it you know I'm gonna try to add
saline to that from a specifically sort
of government or intelligence defense
viewpoint and that is that that we hire
a lot of folks who aren't you know
primarily cybersecurity and intelligence
analysts financial analysts people like
that but because cyber facility
cyberspace is so deeply integrated in
our businesses and society's missions
these days all of those folks need to
have some cyber knowledge cybersecurity
or defensive knowledge as part of their
education right if I come to Purdue to
hire a person whose expertise is in
Middle Eastern area studies and I would
like them to have a little leavening of
cyber knowledge in there because that's
the way the world's working these days
so there's both growth in the person who
is a cyber security professional first
and foremost whole variety of classes
and in many many other specialties
across our businesses and agencies just
like Fred and say in there I think
that's a puzzle for educators how to
work that in in curricula that are
already pretty full yeah and I want to
pick up on that in just a minute but I
wanted to see first Tim if you had a
comment and then I know we've got
another gentleman here yeah I would say
like I mentioned our our board does get
it maybe maybe we're lucky maybe we're
unlucky because they really do seem to
get it I chase it back to the to the
target range right for you where you had
a lot of senior executives lose their
jobs that had nothing to do with
cybersecurity
at that moment it became everybody's
responsibility from company president to
the the guy in the mailroom who's still
got an email account and gets those same
phishing messages that everybody else in
the company receives I would love to see
more cyber curriculum baked into every
academic discipline much the same way
you see computer skills built into every
discipline today I mean you can't go
study mineral sciences without a
computer degree computing class so
why not it's the security piece of that
same tool that you're gonna use no
matter what discipline that you're
pursuing okay thanks turn to you hello
I'm Brett Miller from the University of
Michigan and we're do engineer friends
my question is do you think there are
any lessons in the way that you meet a
labor shortage in a technologically
changing environment such as say the
Industrial Revolution good question good
question how you addressed a labor
shortage in a period of revolution did
it fair summary very carefully I do
think that there are similarities and
you know this is something that that a
colleague of mine out at the University
of Washington and I have struggled with
because I think that if we just look at
the way that higher education is
structured and we use that as a
mechanism for understanding the shift in
the way that the labor market works the
current way that higher ed is structured
really isn't serving us well in a field
like cybersecurity because inherently an
our structure are these silos that we
have spent a great deal of time
constructing intentionally purposefully
because we felt that it was the right
way to get the depth of knowledge that
we needed in engineering or computer
science or English or whatever it is and
the reality is that this field that
siloed structure is actually hindering
our ability to do the kinds of content
across the curriculum problem-based
education that we really need to be more
efficient in the way that we educate our
cybersecurity professionals so in some
ways there's a mismatch in the current
state of the labor market the current
state of the field in the current state
of the structure of higher ed that we
need in order to get our people into
into that labor system take a slightly
different angle
think that that the the person asking
the question is right we have to have I
think a diversity of sources to build up
a labor force to support this sort of
cyber revolution that we're living in
higher education and sort of the
traditional academic pipeline of getting
a bachelor's and getting a masters it is
one of those sources far from the only
one a huge one for us for example at NSA
we call military conversions people who
serve time in uniform and then after
separation or retirements or no yeah you
did that come in back as civilians but
they bring different experience
different viewpoints different training
with them that's an important source and
they're there are many others but I'll
stop talking about them now because
Dickey is looking impatient over there
yeah that's good I think you're missing
the point of the the answer to that I
think the point is that if you look at
all of the cyber that we do people are
the long pull and everything they're
slow at it so automation and artificial
intelligence they're going to take a lot
of those jobs that we need these people
to do and we can save the people for the
things that where you really need the
innovative attempt at doing things so as
soon as we get smart enough to figure
out the rules of what automation can do
that's going to save you some of those
people and it's oh yeah you can't part
away this but the other thing I think we
need to talk about is we're talking
about we need a million people they
aren't all of one size and you've really
got to look at the roles they're gonna
play and who's gonna provide the
training for what roles a little bit on
the automation comment because if we
automate the wrong thing we just do the
wrong things faster I think until we
until we start understanding more about
our threats and our adversaries and and
ultimately we as a field start to look
more like our threats and adversaries
and that's a meth back to the basic
diversity going back a little bit how do
you address any resource shortage you
look for alternative supplies I think
we've got a whole population that's
missing I'll just kind of stereotype the
room it's about
let's say 9 to 1 ratio of men to women
I think we've excluded half the
population from helping us solve this
problem and I think that's a challenge
that we have to address far earlier in
the cycle than in college this is this
is a grade-school problem my daughter's
in 2nd grade and she already is getting
challenged by the boys in her class
because she likes math and that's just
crazy to me she's in second grade so I
think there's some systemic challenges
we have if we really want to start
looking at how we address the the
resource and the pipeline challenge in
cyber man I anybody who's got the answer
to that one
I'm gonna ask you to come up and I'm
gonna let you have the mic right in
front of this young lady all right so so
what's happened is that women have taken
a lot of the jobs that men used to fill
in the medical field and so we've had
that shift all of my doctors are women
now when I was your age all my doctors
were men and so we've had that shift all
over the place and that that's what's
happening so okay time is the answer
okay yes you may
all right if I could comment I think we
have a marketing problem we don't have a
technology problem when I talk a lot
about women and SEM I've been an
electrical engineer in the industry for
20 years when I asked my colleagues what
I should talk about about cybersecurity
they say talk about how great the
technology is and relate it to gaming
neither of those things is interesting
to me it's intellectually interesting
but I care about technology for what it
does to help humanity to solve problems
if you look at where the women go in
engineering its environmental and its
biomechanical because you see a direct
connection to how you help people to the
Medical comment you are helping people
cyber security protects people but we
have hackathons and we talk about how
much we can break stuff how many points
we can earn being competitive about
breaking in and we don't talk about how
understanding how to break in helps me
protect people so that they don't get
hurt and if we can position to women how
creativity and ingenuity and
collaboration is part of cybersecurity
you will have an entirely different
experience with your audience her
comment made me remember that Robert
Frost was the first poet laureate in the
United States educated in metaphor you
are not fit to be let loose in the world
so maybe we need to think about our
metaphors what we communicate to people
about what cybersecurity is yeah you've
been waiting patiently thank you I
actually had a comment about something
Diana had said you had said that the
computer science curriculums were really
full agree with this like there are so
many other courses outside of computer
science that I'd like to take to tie
into it and just if there would be a way
to like find more room to have more
other stuff in it like I would
I think we should stop there because
this is a hard problem
it is a hard problem so let's talk about
this a little bit yeah I mean it you
know whenever I have these conversations
with my industry and government friends
I remind them that it's not a simple
matter of a faculty member making a
decision that we should include content
and therefore let it be that there is a
structure there are accreditation bodies
and accreditation requirements that have
to be in programs that that say what
courses and and content needs to be in
programs and so it's very difficult to
get outside of that one of the things
that we are doing collectively the big
we is we are now in the period of a
trial accreditation process that abet
which is the the body that accredits the
schools and colleges of engineering in
cyber sciences the idea being that there
can be this other degree program that
will allow for the flexibility to
include the kind of content that we need
in computing but also in cybersecurity
programs and so that that accreditation
process is based on a project that I've
spent the last couple of years working
on which is to develop the first set of
global cybersecurity curricular
guidelines on behalf of the ACM and the
I Triple E and so what we tried to do
was to outline a framework that would
provide both the depth of content but
also the flexibility within the
curriculum to allow for institutions to
to be able to address those issues so
your your point your comment wherever
you went is well take it there I staff
just ask permission from this gentleman
to cut in line and I think it was
granted checking yes he knows what
happens if he says no so I want to just
add to this as someone who has for years
tried to get my colleagues here to have
something about security privacy those
issues into the curriculum for all
students to have
and it's still a matter of electives at
the undergraduate level because we are
also driven by demand and although we
here know the demand for people who are
trained in this area what is the
department focusing on right now
well it's big data it's data analysis
data science and huge push there there's
a new program they just established a
new University Center that is one of the
two areas along with AI that is the
majority area all of our incoming
students want to take and in large part
it's because the companies that our
corporate partners that are hiring our
students that's what they want it's
whatever the latest buzzword is it's not
a matter of saying everybody should have
cybersecurity if every one of our
corporate partners were to say to the
faculty there must be a course in data
security in computing security network
security whatever you want to call it
for not only every CS student but
everybody on campus if all the companies
came back and started saying that then
maybe we would have something I have
tried repeatedly to get courses or even
a major started in this area and then
shot down because I've been told there
isn't money in it
there isn't enough demand and so that is
a collective problem that we also are
going to have to address as
understanding the priorities if the
focus is on the new hot items to make
money and startups and to be competitive
rather than in puree you know this is
the whole problem with security right
what is its role then we aren't going to
have the advances at the university so
if if you want to expand on that feel
free but but that's that's from in the
trenches that's been the experience here
amen we're doing the same thing staff we
we at GW are now we are launching a big
data Science Institute and it's moving
and so it's the the new sexy term
whatever it is but we have to work with
and I tell our industry partners all the
time our industry and government
partners those of you who are hiring we
need you to speak to the Provost's and
the presidents and the the folks at the
academic institutions that are making
the decisions about what happens with
curricula because they won't listen to
us they expect us to advocate for
our fields so we need you to come and
say this is who we want to hire two
thoughts which was to ask everybody here
if you have the opportunity to lean into
this conversation
lean in because we do need you okay but
but then my second thought was maybe we
don't need 260 universities doing
cybersecurity education partly maybe we
don't even need a thousand let's say we
could you know triple that number we
could get a thousand of the 4,500 you
know maybe we don't eat a thousand doing
it partly maybe we need a small number
maybe we did a national cyber security
Academy maybe we need something that is
concentrated and immersive and deep and
selective and maybe we need both and you
need depth and that's part of what the
CAE ARS are about right institutions
that can take someone all the way to a
PhD level in their education but as
several the speakers have pointed out
you need folks who have their specialty
might be you know business management
but they have some cybersecurity and
yeah data Sciences is sort of the hot
buzzword right now we're hiring people
in that you know almost every
organization I'm in we'd expect the data
scientists to have had at least some
exposure at a college level to security
before they come into NSA to be a data
scientist and I think there are a lot of
corporations where that would be true as
well certainly a lot of our big industry
partners they just expect that it's
become so important that you don't even
say it anymore you just look for it yeah
so you're right we do and and thank you
for reminding us of that and we'll try
to do better at it okay Tim you know
when we hire a research chemist we
assume that their curriculum included a
course on ethics and how to how to use
that knowledge well and how not to
create chemical weapons in a laboratory
environment
that has not proven to be the case in
technology fields we are lacking that
what what I think we see from a business
perspective as a basic assumption that
we teach people how not to do evil in
this field is it seems to be missing in
computer science and other technology
disciplines so I don't know where that
gap is and I will continue to trumpet it
at my organization's about the need for
we need dedicated security at the
collegiate level but I do think there's
a an ownership of that issue that's
that's larger than a single organization
so we've drifted a little bit but I get
I found funny increasingly unhelpful to
talk about a strategic workforce problem
monolithically one reason is we don't
want Nestle to key off Dickies point we
don't want more cyber folks we want
better cyber folks and one of the
responses to getting you know the
strategic workforce problem for cyber
command or for cyber warriors who we
took a bunch of two-year associate's
degrees gave him a CISSP crash course
and call them cyber warriors but really
they're cyber grunts or infantry and we
do need a bunch of grunts but we all
seen a bunch of generals and we we do
need a bunch of blue-collar cyber jobs
and we need a bunch of white-collar
cyber jobs but moreover I think even
since I have kids as well I think we
need a cyber literacy baseline just like
we need civics so as we increasingly
depend upon technology this has to be
woven into some form of baseline
literacy cyber literacy which isn't jobs
specialization or even a graduate or a
collegiate level but moreover we want on
top of that that every major has the fit
for purpose subset of the cyber spectrum
woven into them so if they are an
executive if they are an entrepreneur if
they are developer what's that subset of
that spectrum of cyber security that
would make them good receivers of people
so I might major in cyber security as a
career but all my developers are
interact with should minor in cyber
security velopment resilience ruggedness
etc so one of the questions after this
monologue is how do we that want to see
better include
want to see earlier inclusion how do we
talk differently so it's not this
monolithic fuzzy thing that doesn't go
anywhere because I'm what I'm most
concerned about lately is the strategic
workforce problem in medical to get
qualified security people into hospitals
in rural areas is directly competing
with our command or directly competing
with financial services so we don't even
just have a single pipeline problem we
have to decide as a nation where do we
want to place the emphasis the
scholarship programs the loan
forgiveness such that we are pushing
folks toward the areas we strategically
need most help not just the one who's
loudest or has the most taxpayer funding
so there were there were a number of
issues that you raised in your monologue
so I'll address apologize okay and they
were all great points I'll just just a
couple of them one I think in terms of
thinking about the general literacy and
and looking trying to push down one of
the things that we have to to reconcile
is the way that we talk about this we
often move into a we need to get more
people in the cyber security workforce
well immediately that turns off a whole
segment of the population that says I
don't want to be a cyber security
professional so we have to use language
that is more inclusive and and treat
this as a general literacy issue I know
that when my kids graduated out of their
high schools at Fairfax County in
Virginia one of the things that they had
to take in order to it was a graduation
requirement was they had to take
business and personal finance zero
credits no grade pass/fail but every
single student that graduates from that
high school system must pass a basic
course in business and personal finance
not because everybody's going to be a
financial analyst but because in order
to survive in society you need to know
how to to manage your money right they
all took a field trip to business
finance park or whatever it was called
Junior Achievement finance Park we need
to do things like that on the literacy
side for cyber security so that everyone
function in a digitally enabled society
and so that's separate that's a
completely separate conversation than
preparing people to go into the
workforce on the workforce side the only
point that all a reference and then I'll
turn over to my colleagues is when we
start to discuss these issues or when we
hear about these issues being discussed
on the hill and where the money is going
part of the reason why there is such an
emphasis and I can say this because I'm
I don't work for the government I work
for a university so one of the reasons
why there's so much emphasis on the
grunts or the the blue collar workforce
is because it is very popular to send
money to community colleges because
every congressional district in the
nation has a community college system so
everyone gets money and it's less about
the specific needs of the workforce than
it is about the political needs of the
members and that's that's the reality so
we have to figure out how to work around
those issues or to leverage that to to
move us to where we need to be but we
can't lose sight of the fact that there
are multiple things happening in the
name of preparing the cyber security
workforce I want to hit a different
point that I really liked in your
comments if we want cyber security to be
sort of the the part of the knowledge
base of people in different specialties
in business sky your intelligence
analyst your lawyer etc then you're
right we need it a tailored sort of I
don't know if you call it an Edition or
element of of the educational experience
for those folks and it can't be the same
right that the knowledge needed by an
attorney is not the same as the
knowledge needed by communications
specialists and I think that it's going
to be incumbent on this community that
the cybersecurity community to to work
with these other fields especially the
ones that are willing I hope too and
then for the in a sense the job market
government industry to come back and say
well this is what I expect of my
communications professional of my you
know Budget and Finance person
Exedra that's gonna be a big job but I
think if we really want that vision of a
sort of cyber savvy workforce to be
realized we're gonna have to do that and
this community is the hub I think of
that it's it's never fun to talk about
sticks it's always more fun to talk
about carrots but if you look at at
least in the white-collar environment
today if you interview for a job and you
can't operate PowerPoint you are at a
strong disadvantage for achieving that
job and I think we're gonna start moving
these basic cyber behaviors and in the
same way if you can't identify a
phishing email or if you can't identify
a potentially malicious link you're
going to start to be disadvantaged in in
hiring and in promotion conversations
because we are starting to just expect
those behaviors out of our workforce
interesting I will turn it over you sir
I'm Ryan oaken's a security architect at
Eli Lilly and one of the big debates
that you hear across information
security are where does your seaso kind
of line up do you fall under IT do you
fall under risk you found are legal is
that the same identity crisis that we
have with higher education on where does
the information security program fall
whether it's in computer science or
would we benefit more by either I think
Neal you're starting to hit on this of
putting more curriculum within business
or within an English major to let you
teach them technical writing
capabilities you would highly increase
the job opportunities I think to just
get some level of cybersecurity
formalized training on their resumes as
they're leaving higher education are
there any efforts underway to do that
and also I think there would be a lot of
commercial and private company partners
that be willing to help with curriculum
in those various areas to support
educational courses to do that I'll be
very quick because I know you want to
colleague n to come and join your
colleagues thing my strong belief is
that the US educational system is big
enough that we need a variety right and
I look at a lot of CAE application CAE
are applications
and they do have variety today but it's
not sufficient yet
right you should have some cybersecurity
programs that are their center of
gravity is more towards the school of
business or towards the school of
engineering or computer science or
perhaps I don't think we've seen these
yet but maybe in the law school
we need that variety and that's going to
be a long project to get it you don't
have to don't feel compelled I've got an
easy answer for this one I okay but
interdisciplinary programs like Sirius
play a key role in that because that's
where you can easily create that
intersection of fields my boss RC so see
so she likes to talk about innovation
occurring at the intersection of fields
and in cyber in particular it's critical
that sort of the easier example these
days is back to fishing psychology
majors have a lot to contribute to this
field of study but a a program in
computer science and cybersecurity is
not going to attract a lot of psychology
majors so these these kinds of
interdisciplinary approaches are in my
opinion the key to achieving some of
those objectives again I will say we
folks at universities we need you
because there was a time when
interdisciplinary education was popular
and encouraged at Purdue University and
I don't feel I'm living in that era
anymore I feel that I am living in an
era that very much rewards disciplines
to colleges the budget model Swartz
doing things across colleges and across
the fields so we need your voice and
just just to add to that because I don't
think Purdue's all I know produce not
alone than that what has happened is
because interdisciplinary is still a
very nice word that college is like but
what I think has happened is their
disciplines with a course somewhere else
and we're labeling that as
interdisciplinary so that we can get the
best of both worlds and that's not what
you mean that's not what you need that's
not what the field needs but we need you
to come and help us make that those
arguments
help you yeah so Jim Jim Passat recently
retired director of aviation security
for the Boeing Commercial Airplanes
company um when I listened to this
conversation what I hear is a
conversation about how to sell what we
have today and I think maybe we should
look at the conversation about how do we
change the environment and I'll give you
an example back in the 90s the Boeing
Company realized that if we did not
improve the accident rate that within 20
to 25 years we would have a fatal
accident a day in the aviation system
and when you look at the cause of
accidents
it was perfectly good pilots flying
perfectly good airplanes into the ground
and killing people and when you dug into
what was the root cause it was because
of the decision making environment in
the cockpit now the aviation industry
the first thing that had to happen is
you had to get key stakeholders who
could change it
see Airlines the manufacturers and the
regulator and get them to agree that we
had a problem that had to be fixed and
then come together and be very open to
understand how do we change the
environment so that we could eliminate
the accidents and when's the last time
you've read about an accident in
aviation because they changed the
process the decision-making environment
I think maybe the conversation needs to
change how do we change the environment
in our country so that instead of having
to opt into a 401k we have to opt out
because people are less likely to opt
out than they are opt in is there are
there lessons here that we can learn
that we can then use to change the tide
in the direction of things in studying
having having corporation having to opt
in so I'd be interested in your thoughts
we'll do next year serious symposiums
back down in Washington DC well give
Senators and Representatives and
staffers an opportunity to come in and
talk with us fireside chat one quick
comment on that because I want to try to
tie it back to work force if we're going
to change the cyber environment and
there are many ways that we could do
that I think it's going to be the the
research community has to help lead the
way on that right I don't think you're
gonna get it out of the folks in the
trenches because in my experience
they're so busy fighting fires that it's
very difficult for them to kind of look
up and and see a long-term vision for a
different sort of cyber environment
that's I think that's got to start here
in in the research community and then
try to drive it through partnerships and
allies out into the sort of broader
community Thank You Melissa just kind of
want to and thank you for that
I think the leaning forward comment that
you made about staying engaged in the
dialogue Dickey your comment about why
do we have female doctors now more than
we have male doctors and I think the the
comment that was made by the young lady
about how do we articulate cyber
profession in in the words that are
understood by a greater diversity it's
very important we had a 11th grader
keynote the nice K through 12 conference
an 11th grader we started his own
corporation as LLC now you know let's
say his dad's a cyber security
professional etcetera etc so he has the
pedigree right but his complaint and why
he started as LLC is because kids in the
fifth sixth and seventh grade don't know
what a cyber security professional is
and there's no one taking to be a cyber
security professional the comment was oh
I don't even want to do that well we
don't know what that means
so I think we need to lean forward at
the lower level in the K through 12
space and lean forward in the things
that we've talked about of how do we
change I like the comment that was made
about the Industrial Revolution how do
we strategically start thinking we're
have been tactically thinking for way
too long how do we take the energy and
it is energy to set aside the time to
continue a strategic dialogue in
parallel with the tactical problem we
have to solve a can't abandon that but
how do we do in parallel a strategic
national conversation that changes the
paradigm I all of us have these stories
my 8th my 8 year old granddaughter
doesn't know anything but an iPad and an
iPhone and and in those technologies but
have we taught them to be a good cyber
citizen I would say no when I was a
little kid living on 9th Street Hill mom
and dad said you don't go next door and
go into somebody's refrigerator and get
something to drink ok that's that's
being a good citizen we haven't taught
that in the cyber world and I think we
need to think about strategically how to
do that and and make it so that when
when we give that eight-year-old a
device they know that there's nothing
sacred on facebook and that you can't
believe that stuff anymore you got to do
your own fact-checking on on information
so I agree that we need to lean forward
we need to keep the dialogue going
phenomenal dialogue in all these panels
phenomenal stuff thank you serious for
holding this I think we just need to
figure out a way to continue the
dialogue throughout the industry thank
you Thanks raise it up okay Tim left
laughed at glass thoughts I'm actually
I'm really intrigued marked by your by
your thought I think that's a strategic
change not just in in cyber that's
really a change in how society functions
we we have tried to take many of our
physical world processes and you know
speaking in from the business
environment the easiest thing to do with
technology is to accelerate what I do
today but I don't actually get the
benefit
it's a transformative technology unless
I change what I do today to achieve the
same or better outcome I think it's an
interesting interesting way to think
about cybersecurity how do we change the
conversation from what are we doing to
how do we achieve that better outcome
Thanks so many good topics in this
conversation I think I want to go back
to something that someone said earlier
about automation I think that is gonna
have some effect on the workforce
you know you many companies is recently
is six seven years ago actually used to
hire people to go apply patches and now
you know who do that right so you
automated systems apply the patches and
human beings go troubleshoot the ones
that didn't work I think overall we're
going to start seeing that across both
the people who are full cyber security
professionals people who just need a bit
of cyber savvy it's how do we enable the
the technology to make us more powerful
right sort of along lines of how do we
reach that that vision for better ways
to achieve the desired outcomes and and
I think that's going to change the
workforce composition that we're looking
for in the future the metaphor I like to
use is I want a person who knows how to
do X but is especially good at teaching
a machine learning algorithm to do X
faster than and more completely unique
and just a metaphor you mentioned those
but I think that's going to change what
we ask of students and of the people
that we hire I would just ask that you
remember that we're talking about a
whole ecosystem here we need students to
come into the system but we also need
faculty to teach the students when
they're in this system and one of the
things that we often forget about when
we're having these kinds of
conversations is the fact that at the
University at the post-secondary level
we have a very serious problem in terms
of faculty members who are able to
actually teach and get the students into
into the workplace and so as we look
for solutions as you lean in as Melissa
says and you're leaning in on getting
those young kids interested getting
those middle high school-age kids
prepared getting the curriculum
developed remember that you also have to
have some time to emphasize preparing
the people who will actually teach these
individuals at all levels because
without that none of these programs will
have a chance of making it thank you
I wore my fire sight scarf for you all
today recognize that last question how
did every fireside chat in the TV turned
off fireworks star-spangled banner so
thanks for being here thanks for
participating any announcements for
lunch all right thank you
[Applause]
you