good afternoon everybody and welcome
back to the final sessions of the 19th
annual serious security symposium our
next speakers our tandem of speakers are
going to talk in an initiative here in
the state which I'm I'm proud and
pleased to say that I'm attached to some
what I this last year was invited to by
a part of governor Holcomb's Executive
Council in cybersecurity and amongst
that was then assigned to several
committees and one of those committees
is headed by by Doug and Charisse and so
in that conversation was the initiative
that maybe you guys should come talk
about this so well this is an indian
initiative there i believe that there
are lessons that could be learned not
just at the state level but also at
company levels and other organizations
that could be duplicated so it's my
great pleasure to introduce our Treece
Mosley who is the cybersecurity program
director for the state of Indiana and
Doug Rapp who is the president of the
cyber leadership Alliance in Indiana
[Applause]
thank you all very much okay I think I'm
double as a woman you don't realize you
forget that you might be miked and so
then you wear dresses and it's not very
easy to put me so I'm glad for the
backup okay can you guys all hear me
thank you very much Joel for having me
here today I've heard nothing but
fantastic things about this organization
obviously well established and and when
kind of looking at the models when I
took the position actually a year ago
now as the cybersecurity director for
the state and looking at how we as
Indiana or want to approach
cybersecurity holistically I definitely
realized a couple of things we are not
always good as a state to recognize the
significant amount of talent in our own
backyard with programs with the people
who are passionate about this topic
people who have actually come up with
Fanta
solutions for this topic but may only be
known in one area one group and so as I
was looking at other states who were
struggling with the same kind of thing
and then talking to such a great number
of people here in Indiana and throughout
I mean I'm our council is made up of 250
members
that's not trying to beat any record
it's just I want it depth in addition to
breath a lot of times when you hear a
governor government councils and you can
raise your hand actually I'll make
people do something because it's after
lunch and if you're like me if I'm not
like doing something or having to listen
then I'm usually on my phone or starting
to think about what's for dinner so so
how many of you when you hear
governments committee government council
you think of a bunch of high people high
up people to talk about an issue but not
really get anything done right I know me
too
I mean I've been a part of those fresh
and frustrating type of councils where I
believe in the cause I think everybody
around the table truly does believe in
the cause as well and but you know a lot
of times we have policy people we have
academics we have people who know it in
theory and either we we then miss the
operations people on that so they come
up with great policies that really can't
actually be done or it's the other way
around you have a bunch of people who
are operations people who come up and
say we need these are the solutions we
need but we don't have executive buy-in
at a policy level and so then things get
stalemated and don't get done on that
and - so when I was given the
responsibility of leading the charge
with Governor Holcomb's Council on
cybersecurity I wanted that to be
different I wanted it to be both which
meant to grow but it meant to grow to
make sure that the right people were on
the council at the right place and
giving just the time that they need a
give to be effective and add to the add
to the discussion so when I want to be
conscious of time so that can wow my
private partner over here also a council
member to be part of it
I do appreciate Joel being on the
council and yes absolutely anybody who
says they want to be on the council I'm
like are you sure because you're gonna
get emails and then you have to attend
meetings and then you're gonna have to
do stuff so it's not gonna be a council
where you just show up and you know say
that you were there and then you know
get then that's really where all it goes
so when I looked at states as many of
you probably have also looked in cross
state paths they a lot of states I
recognized do really well in certain
areas within cybersecurity whether it's
workforce development cyber incident
responses the academic institutions
private you know private sector
collaborations or state policy I
recognized that they were all moving a
little bit inch by inch towards the big
notion of cybersecurity that many of you
have been talking about today but really
how can we move together and bring the
lowest common denominators you know the
local governments the small businesses
the people who actually really need to
know about it
as we were talking somebody had brought
it up earlier how do we make it a
business conversation and not just an IT
conversation how do we make it relevant
to the local government person or the
operations person and not just sisto's
because as all of you know sis's are
only at certain companies a lot of them
actually do not have those they don't
have an IT division they don't even have
a cybersecurity person even if they do
have an IT division so how can we
provide those type of resources but
still be respectful of the nuances of
the sector's the regulations and and
really have the right subject matter
experts providing the true implement to
be able to implement true solutions to
the problem so what we developed with
the Executive Council on cybersecurity
is really a full ecosystem we have
governor Holcomb started at July of last
year and just in the last six months
this council has done more than I'm
grateful because of the volunteers on
the council then I haven't come across
any other government entity and I know
Doug can has we talked about that too
because of the type of value that people
bring to
table and so what it is is that we've
divided up into verticals of critical
infrastructures that we wanted to focus
on in year one granted there are others
that are missing on this but we wanted
to kind of test out test out things
first and then we realized that there
were things cyber hygiene items
emergency services public awareness
training cyber sharing policy that would
go across the sector's so why would we
have why would we have just one person
represents everything in that area why
not gather somebody for example in
public awareness of training our chair
there is the executive director of
Hoosier Prussia sociation somebody who
understands what they're trying to
convey to the media from the media's
perspective coupled with a co-chair that
is the four year veteran of public
relations and marketing so somebody who
is trained on how to get information out
and I say that because a lot of what
we're talking about is public awareness
right it's education it's how do we
really get it to be valuable to the
regular person who's not an IT person
and so when you talk about cyber stats
they really kind of turn it off and
unfortunately how do we kind of cross
that another one that would be example
and probably relevant to a lot of people
here is the workforce development team
so when I put together that team I
needed it to be effective right away
because because is it a concern it's not
only concerned from how do we establish
and from the state's perspective one of
the the proposals that the team is
putting forth for the governor is to
make nice the standard across the board
for Indiana and the expectation how do
we do that right and so we need to do
that K through 12 as well as higher
education as well as looking at
workforce development programs so we
have our department of workforce
development sharing that but it isn't
just enough to have department workforce
development which typically would have
been the person leading that effort
they're co-chair is Department of
Education because a lot of times we find
I have found that in a lot of these
discussions they get so far and some
great ideas but they're not able to
actually go forward because they now
need another half or another section
that they
and I have brought early on and so we
kind of almost had to start all over and
how frustrating is that and in a
situation such as the the needs and the
the concerns that that evolve around
cybersecurity were already behind the
curve and and so having to not only
realize that and we're I'm very lucky to
work for a governor and leadership at
the state that recognizes that it isn't
going to be a one entity solution the
state of Indiana cannot solve the state
of Indiana cybersecurity problem we
would be we would be wrong to even try
the state of Indiana needs to work with
all the other people such as our private
sector partners our educators our
federal partners our local governments
we need to work together and and be okay
that other people have significant and
great solutions and let them go and run
with it and be empowered with it and
then we just have a central framework in
which we can help and feed off each
other for efficiency for their sake as
well as for the state of Indiana because
at the end of the day the end user is
you and it's me and it's our kids and
it's the people who are coming to
Indiana as a business it's people who
are coming to Indiana to work for
Indiana so so the ecosystem approach is
is what well other people in other
states are now calling the progressive
model of Indiana which I'm taking is a
great positive a lot of them are looking
to see how we how we get this moving
real quick one of the ways that we're
getting this moving it into Joel's point
you don't have to go to committee
meetings and so on but these meetings
and the the committees are all tasked
with actual things that they have to do
so it isn't that merger service is an
exercise group or people you know
presidents and CEOs and CIOs of energy
or health care are coming together to
talk about cybersecurity because then I
just really made that one government
council assumption 20 of them what it is
is every single one of them has and has
done it already had created research
created executive summaries from theirs
perspectives from there such a matter
expertise we have hundreds of years
within each of these groups that are
providing
expertise and resources and and
templates and things they've done for
their fortune 500 companies that are
like strip our name off of it and go
give that to the local government small
business because they realize that they
are being the weakest link are their
weakest link as well so it strengthens
that our posture as well and so each of
the groups are doing research each of
the groups are creating deliverables
actual deliverables of trainings of
programs of proposals for things that
they feel the state of Indiana needs or
their sector needs we have 70
deliverables coming out of this council
in six months and probably about half of
them will be completed by September of
this year and the goal is that we
provide the governor portfolio of those
deliverables and actually start
implementing and sharing that
information out with everybody those
underserved populations and figuring out
how we move that to the next level and
then the the next section of that is
proposal of how we go and make this
better
whether that's working with other states
in our region whether that's furthering
and deepening our partnerships with with
companies like CLA obviously academic
institutions like Purdue Ivy Tech IU and
so that that is the goal of this so it
isn't and I'm very happy to say a group
of people who are just talking it's a
group people who actually really because
they've shown interest and committed to
this I've really kind of had their feet
to the fire saying all right you said
you're gonna bring something to this so
what are you bringing that can benefit
everyone whether it's in your sector or
across the sector's or for your group so
so in addition to the plans of the
deliverables of the more the 70 items in
implementation so they're answering the
hard questions right now they're in that
phase right now how much is it gonna
cost what resources are out there now is
there a policy that's going to be needed
what look how can higher institution or
higher higher ed help how can we start
integrating these type of discussions
like what was being discussed earlier
into the younger the younger crowd so
that it becomes the normalcy and not
what we're trying to you know pull out
of people
so so that that's kind of basically the
big one I know that and I'm very lucky
that Purdue's a partner with me and the
council on developing a scorecard for
the council and for the state of Indiana
I am a big believer in not just creating
Korea and deliverable but I personally
need to be able to look my leadership
and be able to provide statistics to the
governor and say these items did this
for these people and so how do we
measure that
looking at other states talking to other
institutions no state has been able to
actually measure their effectiveness of
a governing type of council body and
volunteer group the way that we are and
be able to show that that they actually
did something moved it along I'm outside
of the one area but across the board for
all the state of Indiana for all the
underserved that's what we're looking to
do with that scorecard so I appreciate
Perdue very much in helping with that I
think that's about it right now we can
oh I know we're gonna leave a few
minutes to take questions I'm sure
people have some questions with regards
to what's coming of the council but with
that I think a hallmark of what the
council does and a big portion of my own
philosophy is that I'm not I'm only as
good as the partners that I have and the
people that that I work with and so with
that came real emphasis from a state
perspective to make sure that we have a
strong strong private partners on the
council and and be okay that they go and
do great things and not try to stifle
that and if anything try to grow that
and try to figure out how to facilitate
that growth without always needing to
have and I say that because I know that
there are other states and even Indiana
has played that role before where I'm
not necessarily in this one but where it
has to have the Indiana seal on it it
has to have somebody's name on it and
and I'm not really I'm not a believer of
that I really just want people to go
forth and and work together and be able
to work within a framework so we're not
having 10 parallel efforts which was
what was happening before the as all of
you probably already know so with that
is a perfect example of a partner on the
council from the private side of it so
he can speak to those initiatives on
that end thanks for trees can you hear
me
great so I have to say that
beginning with beginning a while ago
with the state of India under Mike Pence
when he first kind of came up with this
this concept and then carried on by
governor Holcomb that I was a little bit
nervous about the concept of a large
cyber security council nested within
government all right
so having spent 34 years in government
myself I understood how how effective
government can be sometimes but I was
very encouraged when when she Treece was
appointed the director of it let me say
that there's nobody in the state of
Indiana or beyond they could have pulled
off what 'shit Reese has done at the
state level building a team and a true
team a public-private partnership and
that's kind of a you know catchphrase
these days but a true public/private
partnership where you know the state
doesn't have veto authority you know
they actually listen to their
subcommittees 250 people over 20
subcommittees 70 deliverables in six
months and these are actionable things
have been in the business for a while
and these are things that are actionable
they are things that are getting done so
I'd like to thank seat Reese as a
representative of all our state
leadership for for the council and for
being such a great partner
[Applause]
she trees and I have a have a long
history I was in uniform for a long time
and in my career with military in a
National Guard as an AGR I would say I
was a civil military specialist and I
worked on disaster planning at
contingency operations and he had the
great fortune of having cybersecurity
dropped in my literally dropped in my
lap I always tell this story about
major-general I'm Barger who's a
phenomenal leader and a great man of
personal mentor who went out to DC and
the hot topic was cyber forces out there
and he came back to a state that were a
bunch of knuckle draggers like myself
infantry guys and artillery guys and in
combat arms and he looked at his staff
and he said I want me some of that cyber
security so that's almost a direct quote
and the the operations officer the state
operations officer at the time my boss
he came back to the office scratching
his head and a man let who's led more
National Guard officer who's led more
troops in combat since the Korean War
this guy led 6,000 troops in Afghanistan
from all over the world and he came back
and he said I have no clue what so he
brought all of us in he said hey you
know the boss wants to do for structure
bid for some cyber security forces and
it's like anybody know anything about
cyber security I went I do because I saw
I saw what was happening out there along
the sort of the story is that we started
down a path where with a single workshop
where we brought in people like Reese at
the time her boss Caroline Mays medley
who was a pioneer in in in utilities and
security and utilities and we brought in
private sector people work security
ponder ins Kenny group we brought in
state and local Nationals and just
started meeting really and just started
talking about things like hey you know
what's going to happen if there's an
earthquake and all these high-speed
pipelines get severed you know what's
going to happen when when the fuel runs
out and we can't power our computers
that are now powering everything else we
started having those conversations and
we've evolved from
that into probably the most effective
and best partnership that I've ever been
involved in a true statewide team so so
again the cyber leadership Alliance we
are a 501 C 6 we are industry
organization we represent the members of
our organization it's very easy to
become a member it takes an MoU there's
no fee so but we represent about twenty
five billion dollars worth very interest
in the state of Indiana through our nd
NSSO form some of you attend those
forums are here in the room
the Indiana so forum gives security
professionals a trusted environment
where they can have very candid
conversations about their architecture
about solutions about vendors without
the influence of of those vendors or
other outside interests so that's run by
Ally and Ravenna who assists so for car
auctions one of the smartest men I know
and he is he is fanatical about
protecting that group and ensuring that
they we have that entrusted environment
so so we are really a voice for the
industry and by the way we want to work
ourselves out of a job so we hope some
day I'm call myself get friends call
themselves cyber evangelist I call
myself a cyber optimist I look out
across a route like this and I see some
of the most amazing people that I know
great minds
great leaders people that are in the
trenches every day and I have hope that
we're going to make the world a safer
place and that we're going to solve some
of these incredibly complex problems so
so I'd like to consider myself a cyber
optimist I also lied to suit Reese I
told her you just bring one slide I'll
bring one slide but I can't help myself
I'm gonna cheerleader for the state of
Indiana
so Secretary of Commerce a few years ago
commissioned a study a cyber economic
development plan for the cyber security
industry part of that was a series of
town halls where we went around across
the state of Indiana solicited input
from from everybody we did did about in
Evansville we talked to sis's we talked
to you politicians we talked to you
economic development people we talked to
anybody who would show up at the meeting
that thought they had an interest
academia we talked to them all and we
conducted a survey and you'll be happy
to know that the number one greatest
asset according to this survey is
Indiana's academic institutions so
throughout that innovation
entrepreneurship also was up there so
the innovation that's coming up training
exercises with the facilities like we
have I don't see the uniforms anymore
but Muscatatuck and the cyber-physical
range down there so so Indiana has
amazing assets that that we we don't
brag on enough and I'm glad we serious
has afforded me this opportunity to get
up here and brag so now I want you all
to notice that I've just committed a
mortal sin I'm showing the CIO from
Indiana University at a per - group we
are all inclusive so so these these
statistics a little bit old and actually
the department education and the
subcommittee for workforce development
is actually updating these but at the
time that this was done there were 31
colleges and universities offering
curriculum or cybersecurity education
here in the state six cybersecurity
centers of our cybersecurity research
centers and seven cybersecurity centers
of excellence I think the latest one was
Ivy Tech with a two-year CAE so what we
realized is that we we've got something
here while other people struggle with
workforce and certainly Indiana
struggles with workforce - we have an
educational pipeline that we can we can
leverage so I doubt you'll find many
other states other than states like
California that have more educational
institutions that are teaching
cybersecurity content I'll brag about a
couple more things that are going here
the innovation that's coming out of out
of our community these are just a few of
them and I'll get criticized for not
putting everything somebody that I
forgot overlooked or there just wasn't
room enough on the slide University of
Southern Indiana with the Southwest
Indiana ice ow it's a partnership
between that University and and
businesses down there primarily the
utility providers citizens Energy Group
where they have industry people working
with their students in the Sauk the
indiana i sac I don't think Ted stalls
here today but originated by
concept by Hans Vargas who just left
unfortunately through Ted stalled to one
Neely Nixon who was here he's back here
somewhere there's an extension in a
partnership at Purdue an extension of
IOT to service smaller small governments
and in schools
Indiana University the omni sock which
was recently just long launched in the
globalnoc and then the scatter tuck
urban training center which is a
military facility it was a it's an
entire town that at one time when when
we were a different country we
institutionalized people there that had
physical or mental disabilities so it
was a total enclosed town that now has
been turned into a training venue which
includes dark fiber running to working
facilities power generation plants water
treatment plants buildings jails
stadiums they even have a camel true
story um this is where Indiana's been
and where they've they've gone so some
of the great things that have taken
place here that I just don't think
people realize is we'll start down at
the bottom of the past critics which was
a sniper physical exercise kind of
really the culmination point of a lot of
things that that have happened in that
public-private partnership with the
state not that there were obviously
there are many other people that were
doing groundbreaking work in
cybersecurity but really the hallmark of
the public/private partnership critics
was conceived in a bank vault office of
Brook security a private industry with
in conjunction with cyber leadership
Alliance the Indiana National Guard was
there a few other people that were there
when we just finally kind of got fed up
and said you know somebody needs to do
something about infrastructure and start
thinking about what that evolved into
was was a world-class exercise cyber
physical exercise that had state and
state local federal partners all the way
I mean it was pretty incredible where we
actually did we've run in the six
largest water utilities in the state of
Indiana or the six major water utilities
the state of Indiana
and we had there we had their operators
try and detect and and defend against or
at least detect a hack into a working
industry standard SCADA system in a any
functional water treatment plan and to
the point we had role players out there
created hammering effect bicycling the
pumps and actually had a pump that came
out of the ground that was being water
it was pretty amazing it was an amazing
event so that was kind of a hallmark
hallmark event for us that I think
spurred a lot of our relationships that
birth by fire working through that
exercise and in all the working through
all the political stuff and there's Nick
right there so everything so speaking of
speaking of the indie and I said Nick
was a huge part of them so but we formed
relationships there that we took with us
to the different entities and agencies
that we've gone to whether public or
private and we kept those alive and
that's really how we're able to create a
successful public/private partnership
cyber defense summit was conducted here
between Indiana University Purdue
University and Muscatatuck urban
training center we brought in almost all
the service academies many of the
military assets DHS S&T others brought
them here and really kind of highlighted
what was going on yeah it was our first
first at-bat really starting to promote
Indiana cyber cyber security state of
the state which was a concept we brought
in six experts from different verticals
that were important to the state and in
the in the Statehouse we briefed elected
and appointed officials on what the
state what those industry experts felt
the state of the state was in those
particular those areas so we began the
process of educating legislators and
educating leaders what's going on today
I talked a little about the Indiana
Cisco forum so I want I won't beat that
to death the Israel cyber tech
delegation annually we form a delegation
that goes over and meets with our
partners in Israel we were pretty
impressed with the fact that their
points in thirty five times their weight
in cyber security and we like to think
that innovation is is born out of
research it's it's born out of companies
that are doing things and in the case of
Israel it's going out into said
city so so we're very interested and had
great partnerships with them and we
continue to to go over and meet with
them secure the hill we do that that's
coming up we actually go out and talk to
our legislators out in DC well you even
go in so far as been asked to testify in
front of subcommittees on public-private
partnerships in workforce development
cybersecurity Executive Council we've
already talked about cybersecurity Town
Hall's we're continuing that tradition
to go around and talk to and get people
motivated and interested in
cybersecurity around the state of
Indiana geographically you know anytime
there's a State Capitol everybody else
who is not the state capitol thinks that
everything result revolves around the
State Capitol last year or the year we
did this the first year we did this we
made a point of not doing a
cybersecurity Town Hall in Indianapolis
we actually just did it in all the
outlying areas so in the future the
Indiana secure technology consortium as
a group is a group of interested people
that are coming together to form a
catalyst for security in the Internet of
Things Indiana has made a mark in
technology what we're concerned about is
like technology in the tech culture we
want to rush headlong into technology
and we want to grasp those things with
with a focus on getting to market as
quickly as possible and that doesn't set
conditions for security very well so
we're interested in getting ahead of IOT
and the IOT craze and ensuring that and
partnering with industry in Indiana that
are in the manufacturing space to build
security in from the ground level the
Indiana cyber security focal point just
I would say very briefly that Indiana is
considering creating a venue to
consolidate some of the expertise in
cyber security around the Capitol
workforce development initiative talk a
little bit about that in partnership
with Purdue Indiana University and other
interested partners ideally Department
workforce development mapping a
progressive pipeline of talent to
incentivize them in the right places to
go to Indiana schools to stay in Indiana
to live work and be educated here and
cybertek Midwest so we are
in talks with has anybody been to
cybertek in Israel or in Singapore Rome
Panama any of those places
so cybertek Indiana's is hopefully
working through the final the final
terms of bringing cyber cyber tech here
for the next three years some cyber tech
the Midwest it'll be their only event
that they hold in the United States so
we certainly invite you all back for
that and then what
and the last thing is I'm calling the
SMB sock and that is an initiative that
we're working with serious on right now
to roll out cybersecurity tools to our
most our most vulnerable sectors of
society women's shelters food pantries
those types of areas that if they were
to suffer a breach or an attack that
they would it would instantly put them
out of business and portions you know
the people doing great works you know we
have an obligation to protect to protect
them
so so that's a lot of stuff I've just
thrown at you so I encourage you to stop
by and talk to me I'm in the back and
got the cool pins so glad so myself in
the trees thank you very much for
allowing us to present here today and
just brag on Indiana and the great stuff
that we're doing we truly are the cyber
crossroads of the United States
[Applause]
you