all right Joel Joel neglected to mention
at the beginning that if you hear the
tornado sirens we go to the basement of
this building which is a little more
entertaining in some way well it's more
comfortable than the basement over at
the Union doesn't have as many
interesting nooks and crannies as over
at the Union serious has a twenty-year
history and along that history we've had
many different organizations who have
been in our partner program some have
left for various administrative reasons
sometimes its changeover of strategic
direction but we always welcome them
back and any guys because they're
friends they're supporters and we're all
fighting for the same things our next
speaker is someone who represented a
national agency that was part of our
strategic partnership program for a
number of years in the early 2000s so he
was a member of the board some of the
pictures that we were showing the other
day he he was in one of them at one of
the poster competitions helping to judge
some of the posters at that time and so
we thought it was really a good idea to
invite mark back given his position now
I wanted to mention here NRO
how many of you know what the NRO is
okay probably about a quarter so let me
just say there are a number of
intelligence agencies that are part of
the US government and the National
Reconnaissance Organization is involved
in geospatial intelligence so in that
word salad basically the idea is that if
we are going to conduct any kind of
intelligence operations or military
operations it's a good idea to know what
is on what is the landscape what is the
area what is there what has been moved
there what's been moving in the area and
that's effectively one of the missions
of the NRO
which is to manage various assets that
observe what's going on in the landscape
to analyze it and to send those results
to various agencies and organizations
that need that information in a timely
fashion so it's a very vital part of the
intelligence community not well known
but they have a lot of interesting
security problems particularly in
communications marc has been with the
NRO for 25 years he has a career of 37
years in the Intelligence Agency
first as with the CIA and then
eventually getting into this position
directing security at NRO a wealth of
experience in a very demanding area so
we thought he could bring some of that
information here not only to tell you
about some of the challenges but to
project forward with what he sees as
some of the interesting problems in the
future so please join me in welcoming
somebody who's working on the frontlines
in a very interesting way and a real
friend of serious mark Spangler staff
before you before you get out of here I
wanted to kind of thank you and I want
to give you a a commemorative coin from
the in a row if I can find which it's in
thank you
for the long relationship we've had and
then I wanted to give you an anniversary
present since it's your anniversary
I hope it's not another bottle
bobblehead anyway on behalf of the folks
at the in a row and our our cyber
lawyers out there all the work that you
and in the center does we appreciate the
partnership over the years and hopefully
that will bring you much joy when it's
full yes thank you
[Applause]
Thank You staff thank you serious for
the invite this year I did I'm gonna
kind of present kind of a maybe a
light-hearted maybe sometimes serious
look at some of the challenges in
today's cyber battle space and I'm gonna
try something new so bear with me we're
gonna do a audience participation so I
know how this goes with animal acts to
Giri I'm gonna need your your assistance
would you pass these out to four people
that you know at well people you know
alright Jerry would you ask them to go
ahead and open those right now all at
once
all right we'll start up here what is
what what was your gift Jerry what did
you do all right who's got another one
got back here oh we got some bugs in
there well and what does your your tab
say nice anybody else you got some bugs
- nice nice and lastly you are most
popular in your company right now
right so maybe yeah so just kind of a
light-hearted example of Jerry was used
to distribute spear phishing attacks for
you guys
the problem is Jerry why did you do that
to these people now question is why did
you open it because it was from Jerry
did you trust him no you didn't trust
him
yeah but you but you were inquisitive to
see what was in there right so a little
bit of today's discussion is going to
talk about kind of the human condition
because part of our IT system the large
part of it is that biological element
sitting in front of the keyboard and we
could have all the protections in the
world but if we don't attack that
element of the system will continue as
we have for the last couple of years on
users defeating our well-planned
security architecture because they just
have to they have to open the present
there's there could be something good in
it and I guess if you under if you
realize that the FBI had to put this on
their online fraud page to say said that
you still cannot
in the lottery that you haven't bought a
ticket for okay I don't know why they
had to say that but apparently that
still works anyway so what about this
we've heard a lot of discussions about
the upcoming cyber war a lot about cyber
Pearl Harbor was mentioned about two
decades ago by the SEC def and then
cyber 9/11 when it when it comes if you
ask Sony if you asked Target if you
asked Equifax
they would probably argue that it's
already here and I know that my folks go
to work every day with the war footing
that we're in the battle already those
folks that talk about the upcoming are a
little bit late to the game we're
already fighting the war and so
understanding kind of that mindset about
being a battle space commander
understanding what your your battle
space looks like is imperative to
managing it and surviving whether you're
doing DoD or whether you're a
pharmaceutical company or a tractor
company there are adversaries out there
and they came to work today and will get
bonuses for getting your data and if you
don't understand that then you'll have
to move over to the column of victim so
we want to talk a little bit about that
and maybe prevent ourselves from landing
in the the victim column without a fight
so today I'm going to go ahead and talk
about these six areas know your user
know your AOR anybody familiar with that
area responsibility that's our battle
space and how it's changing today in
today's environment know where your data
is know what type of data it is where it
is sensitivity of that data it is now
very challenging so you don't sometimes
you don't even know what country your
is it with certainly distributed cloud
services hard to tell where your data
might be and then we're going to look at
the adversaries look at who's out there
what their motivations are and try to
put on the hat or the hoodie because all
hackers wear hoodies right and then look
at some best practices so I'm gonna walk
through this story with these two folks
Flo and Joe named them whoever you want
but we're gonna look at those those
biological elements of our system and
whether you're the sysadmin or you're
just an employee or you're the CSO of an
organization you really need to
understand who they are right if I have
people who live in a cyber battle space
where they're on the phone all day with
the credit company trying to get their
their credit back there not a asset to
my organization that day that's lost
productivity and so that I need to be
concerned about where those folks live
in order to make sure that they're safe
and so some of our education has been
targeted not just inside the workplace
but when they leave the workplace before
they before they go home and they stop
at the gas station or they do a
point-of-sale on the way home they need
to be understand some of the adversaries
are waiting for them outside the
building as well so we're gonna look at
the battlespace anybody recognize this
this battle space may be the history
folks in the room so if you can't
articulate to the seaso or the c-suite
what's inside and what's outside what's
your responsibility and what's outside
your control and you probably don't have
any right
be spending corporate money on that if
you can't articulate this then you need
to go back and do your homework because
we have run into a lot of organizations
that are very enamored with fancy tools
and they go out and write big checks but
they don't know where to put them in
their architecture they don't know where
they're best used or even if they need
that tool but the slides and the sales
pitch was very good you need to know
where your where your points and an
adversary might attack you much like a
fire inspector knows where the source of
ignition started you should be able to
look at your architecture and notice the
top 10 places an adversary would first
be encountered where your IP space meets
an adversaries IP space and we call this
intelligence preparation of the
battlespace we're going to use a lot of
let's say we're fighting terms but as I
said earlier we are in this battle and I
don't intend to go quietly so important
here to know where your allies are and
where your troops are what their sizes
are what their capabilities are where
your adversary is so you can deploy
countermeasures appropriately if you're
you have sensors on your network but
they're deployed because the engineering
people are in this building and this is
where they wanted to put the sensors
because it was raining out and they
didn't want to go across campus it would
be important to understand that you have
a topography of your network and
understand where placement of those
sensors is important you could waste a
lot of money and think you're watching
the adversary when you have your sensors
in the wrong spot
so I don't know if anybody has I was
given some folks an example of this over
the course of the the conference I went
into a group and I was excited because
the group one of the elements in the
group was a mapping branch and I said
well this is great I'm finally gonna get
this essay of our battlespace and so
first meeting with them I sat down I I
kind of gave a little bit of a history
of where their branch was we had funded
for two or three years and I was excited
to see their product so I said where
where's the map they said well we we do
mapping I said yeah where is the map I
want to see the map and they referred me
to a spreadsheet full of IP addresses
and so I pulled it up looked at it I
said I can't make any intelligence
decisions off of this data in this
format is no context it lacks the kind
of the so whoa where are these devices
in relationship to the adversary where
they relate in relationship to the core
parts of my network that that I don't
want anybody to be able to get access to
they gave me a phone book of the county
and I wanted to ran McNally
and so when we start mapping we need to
understand that just because I run tools
like AI T PI R ed CL some other other
other tools doesn't mean you're doing
the job you have to that gives you raw
data sort of like dick you would tell
you the you'll get you're getting raw
data but you haven't converted it into
intelligence yet right so having mapping
and understanding your your battle space
is are two different things
so without this these are the items that
you need to understand through that that
process you have to understand what
you're missing essential functions are
for your organization
we'll use the one that's I guess most
popular in discussion this week which
was get the beer out if you're running a
Brewing Company well your mission
essential function is get the beer out
and it doesn't really matter if you were
under cyberattack if if you had a flu
that took out half of your workers or if
one of your conveyors broke down at the
end of the day with through all of that
storm if you didn't get the beer out you
aren't achieving your mission essential
functions and so if your organization
hasn't sat down and mapped those out
what those core mission essential
functions are that's really kind of an
elementary first step because I don't
know how to deploy countermeasures
around kind of an amorphous blob unless
I have a clear picture of what your
mission essential functions are because
then I can do critical path analysis and
identify the systems that support that I
need to make sure that when I'm doing
that critical path analysis I expand the
aperture open up enough to understand
that if this is a mission-critical
facility and I turn off the fire alarm
the fire marshal will do my job for me
he will evacuate the building and
interrupt your mission essential
function if I if you need cooling for
your server room and I turn off your
chilled water the the heat alarm will do
my job for me I don't actually have to
come into your facility I don't have to
booger with your I can interrupt your
mission essential functions in that way
and so when you look at what your
mission critical function or mission
essential systems are you need to
understand the extent of dependency on
systems that may fall outside of the
traditional look that we look at for
servers and routers and
part of that is identifying those
critical assets that have to happen if
you identify critical path and you've
identified that I only have one server
and it is critical to those operations
does it have redundant power supplies
does it does it have a redundant do I
have a failover in case that that that
inevitable crash does happen so
basically doing some resiliency analysis
on that on that critical path and then
Utah you talk a look about the the
critical path and see where in that
critical path your adversary would have
access and so you're looking for
exposure am I is my mission essential
function exposed to an adversary where
they could interrupt interrupt its
execution and then looking at the
battlespace you should be able to pull
some stats because that's the beauty of
IT we can really set the settings to
collect any number of things doing it
wisely is an art not to collect
everything because collecting everything
means you collect nothing nobody has
enough time to read that and you can't
make sense but you have to understand
what Krita what what is critical so if I
had this battlespace map and I
understood that I get 30 hits on that
particular interface down on the left
corner but I get none over here I now
understand where the adversary is
targeting me and so I can move resources
there to defend against it do I have is
it passive monitoring at that point is
it in line blocking tackling so I can
match my defenses to where what
attacks I'm seeing in the network and
then your Intel sources if you're
relegated to sitting inside watching
lights blink and alarms flash you're
you're trying to fight this battle with
with one hand tied behind your back the
importance is to kind of get out and
take that that strategic look at the
battlespace and try to get a look at
what your adversary is doing in that
space is your adversary attacking other
vendors in your same group have you
talked to the sis's or the CEOs at other
organizations in your in your same line
of business what do they see
are you pulling down the commercial
indications of compromise that come off
of some of the Intel sources because
there's a plethora of information out
there about understanding adversarial
tradecraft and if you don't understand
that it's hard to assemble the right
protection strategy for your
organization so let's go on to take a
look at more of our duo here so what is
their battle space look like everybody
probably touched one of those or is
touching one of those devices right now
it's an access point right so if it's
connected to your network now you have a
kind of a distributed way of ingesting
things into your network it's also a
point where your users are we going to
be targeted and we're going to talk a
little bit more specifically about
understanding what your personal battle
space looks like anybody recognize any
of the any of the blocks up here so
these are on our today's battle space
our data is our data is at target our
data is at Equifax or maybe not at
Equifax in other places I was telling
somebody yesterday when I was a victim
of this one or a BlueCross BlueShield
they signed me up for credit monitoring
and so I followed the procedures I
called the folks up and what was the
first thing they asked me they asked me
the very data that they had stolen
that did that got stolen and I'm you
know the little light bulb went off in
my head going so you want me to trust
you again with the same data that you
had stolen and it's not just these
companies it's also the credit
monitoring companies that have been
attacked as well so kind of a personal
decision on whether you're gonna use one
of these services or not but understand
that those large volumes are really
honey pots for an aggressor because
where are you going to go to collect
millions of profiles you're going to go
large companies that have large data and
you need to be aware of that as simple
as the gas pump if you're using your
corporate card gonna disable your small
business because you know you impede
your your drivers from getting their
product to market because their card
gets skimmed back in what's a historical
we had some issues with toll fraud small
companies they get whacked from toll
fraud and have $50,000 bill last month
from the phone company because they got
they got their their phone system taken
over there the phone company's not
particularly sympathetic when they said
all your calls went to Venezuela they
said do you have any do you have any
corporate business with Venezuela well
then why did you allow your switch to
talk to them as well so same as same
kind of vernacular that we need to use
with some of our
our corporate systems I don't think
anybody up here has not been affected
because in some of these cases this of
this
I think the Equifax one was half the
people in the United States
anybody have Yahoo and impacted by the
yahoo account yeah so uh that that was a
billion a billion people that that were
effect
so this is the this is the battlespace
we're living in so it's really a
constant flow of these data breaches
that are going on and we have to
understand that that's not going to just
affect our employees at work but it's
also going to infect their productivity
at home and so part of that is not
bringing bad behaviors like opening
stuff you get from Jerry with a trust
model but they have to understand what
they're getting into and what liability
they have when they open that a lot of
companies have gone to spear fishing
training they send out a spear fishing
test message every every month and if an
employee clicks on it they need to go
and take some refresher training I don't
know if any of your companies do that
but right now
spear fishing is the number one concern
that we have for employees circumventing
our protections and so let's look at
that battlespace a little bit more I'm
going to kind of reach back to you know
last year you heard Greg - he'll talk
about - his law about one year one human
year equals 25 years of computer life so
you really have to look at your company
and decide are you flying the Wright
Flyer are you in a raptor if your
company isn't keeping up then they're
probably leaning towards the victim the
column because those systems get patched
and upgraded and most of those are
critical flaws that the the
manufacturers are pointing up and
and in patching and if your folks aren't
patching their systems their targets
right targets you're not making the
adversary work hard for it and so what
we want to do is make it hard raise
their cost to exploit you so that they
go on to somebody else
it's like putting the lights around your
house and that you make them go to the
neighbor's house if you keep your
patches up inherently hackers are lazy
and they want the the ripe fruit and
they don't want to have to work hard for
it dedicated resources and a lot of
manpower they're going to get into your
network the vast majority people are
will go on to somebody else and then
planning part of this is planning if
you're not planning for a data breach or
system failure you're not doing your
company any good
you need to white card this at least
with the with the board to understand
what their responsibilities are what
they would do in when it does happen
because it's gonna be when it's not
going to be if and the time you want to
be scratching your head wondering what
the process is is not the time you have
a very large breach you want your legal
folks involved and you want to have a
good understanding of what each of their
responsibilities are to ensure that
corporately they've provided due
diligence and due care for that data if
your company's not keeping their systems
patched they're not watching for the
adversary it's hard to demonstrate at
the end of the day when a data breach
goes out and loses a bunch of customer
data that corporately they've done due
diligence and do care so right now I
think the tide is shifted I saw last
week where when Under Armor got got
hacked and some data taken it wasn't it
wasn't so much focused on the attack but
on Under Armour's response they
responded within like four days of the
breach and they had very aggressive
action and kind of were commended about
their response
time and their and their ability to
recover and I think as we see this this
concern evolve we're gonna see less
concern about what did a breach happen
because most folks are going to have one
and it's going to be on what did your
company do responsibly to first prep
their their networks and then also did
they do display due diligence and due
care in customer information so
identification of those I was surprised
last night I talked to a couple
companies that I would have guessed
would have segmented their networks
already that customers don't need to be
on the same domain as your secret sauce
I was shocked to find out that they
weren't they had just one amorphous blob
of a network and they weren't segmented
anecdotally I looked at the sony Sony
hack and I had heard that the the
decisive decision came very early that
from their si so to sever that business
unit announce that their company got a
contract right they immediately become a
target so they can see a spike they can
see a spike in attacks right after the
public announcement so your adversary is
watching they're seeing who gets in the
Federal Register on federal contracts
but they are watching corporate mergers
he said one of the more nefarious ones
is that when his company is going to
purchase another small company they can
count on that other small company
network being penetrated prior to them
taking over and pulling them into their
nest what they found is once the merger
is agreed upon
spending locally on patching and keeping
that that network up-to-date goes down
and they become a larger target for
folks that want to get into your
corporate network they'll get a foothold
into another network that you will
incorporate into yours so if your
company is doing a lot of acquisitions
of smaller companies be very weary of of
how you go about incorporating those
folks into your network if you have a
business unit that just will not comply
with keeping their standards up I have
seen very effective use of Doh painting
them off from the rest of the company
and letting them fend for themselves
because you do have a responsibility to
the enterprise and if you have one
business unit that you just can't get
the the leadership to adhere to some of
those core principles so keeping their
systems up you need to make some
decisive decisions about not continuing
to send them nagging emails you need to
make an action to prevent the rest of
the network from being drawn down to
that level
so who's hacking you so what about
attribution I'm going to talk a little
bit about where these attacks are coming
from you know in no particular order
this is just kind of a sample map but if
our adversary if we're gonna we're gonna
get attacked from an IP and say Finland
is that you know what if they took out
one of our critical infrastructure
systems what if they took out the the
Northeast power grid from a DDoS attack
originating from Finland are we going to
war if they take out a weapon system I
mean that's really a debate right now is
how do you respond in kind in the kind
of the traditional the traditional
measured response on a cyber attack
really hasn't been resolved and
attribution doesn't come immediately if
somebody sent a missile we could
understand where it was launched from we
could understand who build it and we
could immediately respond cyber is a
much different animal and how do we
respond in kind and that's a that's a
dilemma and I think that certainly
everybody here is going to be involved
in as we have more and more let's say
assertive attacks and one that we're
gonna debate especially if we see
attacks on critical infrastructure or
civilian targets and things like that
that how do you respond Jo got any
suggestions
probably both so in this map I think
what we've seen is that more
sophisticated folks you can't really
tell where they're coming from because
they're using somebody else's they're
using somebody else's system to do that
that's kind of a smart approach if
you're lazy then you're going to be
probably coming out of this northern
region right here and attacking directly
and we'll talk a little bit about some
of those some of those attacks so what
about reducing the attack surface kind
of wanted to open up the discussion into
what could you do corporately to reduce
your attack surface we had and a little
discussion earlier with a company and
they they reduced they they quit doing
BYOD they said corporately we made a
decision that our our attack surface had
to be smaller in order to manage it
managing those devices is difficult and
it opens your company up now depending
on your business and your criticality
it's a it's a corporate decision on how
much risk you want to take I kind of
gave the example I was I was monitoring
somebody it was my brother worked for a
manufacturing company and he was logging
into his corporate industrial control
system remotely and I kind of watched
him through that process of logging in
and he did user ID and password he
pulled out his RSA key fob put in the I
was like okay well I thought you made
soup in that company and he said what we
do and so I watched further and I asked
him what the
system was doing and it was doing
hardware authentication it wanted to
know that this was the device that had
been issued to him and then it was doing
configuration verification that nothing
had been modified on the device before
it led him in and then once it was done
knowing that he was who he was supposed
to be that was a device he was supposed
to have it was still loaded with the the
load that they had loaded it it patched
him so it brought his patches up to the
corporate level before it even made it
on to their network and though so he
went on to show me kind of the very very
high speed production that was going on
and I said well that seemed very
sensitive why would they allow you to do
that remotely and he said well you you
think it looks like the high speed
production system it's I'm on a proxy
looking at the system it would be
foolish to allow anybody remotely to
make these changes from outside the
company and I said wow that was pretty
good that was a decade ago and that was
protecting soup so you know it made me
feel warm that there are companies out
there that that that do take corporate
or their mission essential functions
seriously and put in place mechanisms to
protect that I wish that transferred
across mint domains that are I'd say
more critical than sue all right so
let's look specifically at some target
opportunities here how about this guy
anybody know him see your threat to your
network is he I don't know
all right so if I came in in the morning
and somebody said overnight we lost a
thousand safes of information it
disappeared from the company we can't
find it that everybody would stop
working and we would find that but I
would imagine that if in your company
you lost one laptop couldn't find it the
same response isn't there it's just a
laptop but I think in some cases we
think about all of this storage kind of
flippantly because it's just become
commonplace and I can probably steal
most of your intellectual property off
of a pen and this comes down to kind of
this network hygiene right are you
managing your devices down to the user
level appropriately where you can't get
data off of your network easily this one
especially this will clean out most
companies and if you don't manage that's
a huge liability any disgruntled
employees in here I didn't think so but
corporately if you have a network that
you haven't taken those productions
against you are opening your
organization up to huge liabilities both
from data going out and special data
coming back in
so let's talk a little bit about all
that data that's going out so the data
going out let's talk about data breaches
we've been talking a little bit about it
but let's go to this line right here 100
and last year according to the the
fundament study that produces this every
year this was last year's total 141
dollars per record well this is this is
fine if you if you just lose one record
but you lose a million customer files
with this information
suddenly the cost of doing business that
year is going up and and maybe your
bonuses at stake this year because most
companies can't take that out of
hide-and so you're gonna see a pop up of
insurance in the marketplace to protect
against breach I think I talked to
somebody over the course of the
conference that that said their company
does use insurance carrier to kind of
transfer to the but that cost of
insurance is certainly going to have to
be incorporated and if you can prevent
this by low-cost control of some of that
those exfiltration techniques two-factor
or two-person integrity at some of those
critical junctures where you have data
leaving I was kind of relating that I
was I was carpooling on one time with
some ladies and they worked at a medical
testing facility and they probably
didn't understand why I was asking
because they worked in billing but I was
asking him about USBs it something long
came on the radio that that spurred that
conversation and they described their
facility as having probably 2000 people
working in it and they said there was
only one person in the company that had
the authority to remove certain data
from the from the network with a USB or
burner and they said they asked me well
why would anybody want to do that be
because that's where the the information
is protected and why would we want to
take that protected data and move it
somewhere onto a media that's not
protected and so if you looked in your
company and how you do you're missing
essential functions you really have to
understand how much of that convenience
you're going to prescribe before you've
tipped the scale and you're really
fighting a losing battle with trying to
protect the flow of your data off of
your network anyway if this is broken
down on breaches by sector business
sector so any mathematicians in the room
Viki yeah so if you add this up and that
figure from the last page you get in the
factor of like twenty three billion
dollars that's a lot of cost to
corporate productivity doing cleanup you
don't buy anything for that that's just
sponsoring identity monitoring for
clients that you've you've lost their
data for press you know working with
your attorneys on liability proving that
you did due diligence so if this is the
discussion that you have in your C suite
this is why you need to be a active
member of that discussion because this
is what will will buy you some a seat at
that table because if you can show the
organization that you're not a liability
that you're not just there to spend
their money that you're actually there
to save them money in the long run that
that makes you a partner and not you
don't because security doesn't become a
liability to them it were a added cost
so let's look a little bit at the the
breaches of the causes of the breaches
so these are the hoodies this is Joe we
talked about Joe this is him he's
causing these problems he system error
so through whether it's disinterest lack
of training if you could take a 28%
almost 30 percent of the concern away by
reinforcing user education to person
integrity about preventing those those
losses this would be a big big win for
your organization's
sure we're gonna do a whole lot about
preventing but I think in the in the
case of remote access to your network so
if you're really looking at those points
of exposure you can you can drop this
one as well remember we're not looking
for the perfect because if you go into
this with the the understanding that
there will be a breach and it's just a
matter of time you need to educate your
folks on what they're gonna do when it
does happen and if you can get them to
that point of acknowledgment the further
discussions are that will go much better
on let's wait card this let's walk
through it a couple times and then what
I found is business unit leaders are
very they're very complementary a month
or two into this process that they know
that here in the radio so-and-so guy
breach this morning and they know oh I
know exactly what we would do when that
happens because it will eventually
happen to them alright so let's go a
little bit deeper on what what this
actually is gonna look like on your on
your cell phone
anybody get this one this morning
anybody want to get rid of their student
loan I get one of these calls almost
every single day it's a new federal
program it's got to be trustworthy right
yeah cuz the only the Fed does you know
acronyms like do e stuff like that
anyway this sounds really good missing
anybody familiar with that term mission
phishing SMS fishing this is a an attack
surface any from them and anybody know
what the the abbreviation for the 419
scam is it's a quiz there may be a prize
419 anybody got one in the back what is
it that's right let's give him a prize
yeah so what he said was it was the
Nigerian statute against fraud and so
this nickname the Nigerian advance fee
scheme they're not really interested I
almost get one of these every single
time I list something on Craigslist I
get an immediate response that says I'm
really excited in your item I would like
to purchase it I unfortunately I cannot
come to your your location and I will
have to have a shipper arrange they're
not really interested in your item
they're not really interested in the
cost they're looking for that 2 or $300
extra that they're going to give you for
the inconvenience of working with their
shipper they're looking for that
advanced fee part I like to play with
those folks sometimes I don't know about
you guys but it's actually become a
sport spam baiting or scam baiting I had
one on the line for about a half an hour
the other day he was calling from
somewhere probably Pakistan or India he
was going to get refund me $199 because
I had overpaid the
purchase of a service maintenance
contract on my laptop
anybody got in this one yeah so he he
told me in order to process this refund
I need you to do this on this I need you
to go to the site I was like this sounds
exciting 200 bucks so I'm typing away on
the keyboard
appearing to sound in the receiver like
I'm I'm doing the the link I said this
thing it's not working and then he you
know talked me through some other stuff
like well hit the Windows key and I said
well what do you mean by window is it
the one with the flag on it I don't
understand what you mean my keyboard
doesn't have that he got very frustrated
but he was obviously using a
knowledgebase right so like a helpdesk
he had a knowledgebase I could tell he
was looking up what operating system I
had I was just making something up and
he was giving me with a prescription it
told him to tell me right and then he
was basically trying to enable remote
desktop after about 30 minutes you know
I just I got kind of tired and I told
him it I had to go and and I said I I
don't really appreciate you call and
taking Peter and he was kind of arrogant
he said I said he said well this is what
I do to make a living and I said well
does it work and he goes all day long
yeah it it said that that does and they
do prey on people my my own father he
got taken by somebody appearing to be
from Google Gmail and and they loaded a
crypto blocker or Locker on him and he
ended up having to go to the Geek Squad
to get it cleaned up but it's
unfortunate that there are a lot of
people that are out there being preyed
upon one of those kind of the more
insidious ones is kind of up next I
don't know if this will this audio clip
will work let's see
all right well I'm gonna just describe
it to you if anybody has anybody got in
the IRS call oh okay good good
terrible right it apparently it's worded
in such a way that it has some words in
there that really kind of trigger things
within you and I so who ever crafted
kind of the dialogue it and it's in I'm
the one that I received was in a mecca
knife was like a recorded voice really
couldn't tell that it was a foreign
person calling you but they're talking
about you know and then apparently a
preyed on thousands of unsuspecting
folks that don't want to have any
problem with the IRS and so as long as
it keeps working but these are the same
people that work in your building right
these are the same students and
grandparents that you all work with and
have and so they're all part of your
workforce and they're a part of the
people who will be distracted and I've
had I have employees maybe weekly that
click on things they should redirects
spam it's just part of that human
condition that we need to factor in to
our our our management on that on the
battlespace Oh which one
nice nice nice yeah a lot of times you
can't get them they'll they'll hang up
before the the recording but you can't
I got a most of it on on this one all
right so I have now there we go
all right so let's go a little bit more
tactical do you have a problem with this
in this area the skimmers yeah so I'm
not sure how long the the skimmer items
are really cheap i I think I looked one
up the other day and I could get the
whole setup for like 20 bucks and it was
I mean that's pretty good
not that I would ever do that but the
some of the more expensive ones are our
police in in the Northern Virginia area
said if you find one like they're there
their advice is shake it they basically
run up and shake the heck out of it and
if it comes off leave immediately
because they have had some issues where
the the adversary would come and try to
retrieve their device and and there
would be in some ensuing problem so but
these are tough I mean tough to this one
especially and this one down here this
model looks almost exactly right so what
we've seen in our areas security tape so
I guess for a while until the adversary
by some security tape that that's their
countermeasure so how does this does
that concern your company I think we
talked a little bit about yeah if you're
you're delivering products and your
driver gets the the corporate card
skimmed it's gonna impede their business
also if I'm on the phone all day trying
to get mine reset it's going to impact
my productivity
the next one I get the the discussion
here is a little bit more of a concern
because a lot of these we've been
talking about for decades right so
there's another quiz question there may
be a bug or another treat available so
what was last year's most used password
the high schooler yes number two last
year that's it it's one two three four
five six
yeah winner winner anyway how does that
happen
right you start asking the critical path
the critical path analysis stuff and say
why why why does that how if we're if
we're really computer security folks how
could we allow that to happen
who's managing those networks that allow
users to enter passwords like that and
apparently a lot of us work in places
that don't they allow users to get away
with passwords that way that's I mean
that's fundamental and we're we're
missing the gap I don't know and so
that's a that's more of a troubling
troubling fact part of this is hygiene
too we didn't talk a lot about hygiene
of networks but what I found is a lot of
the stuff even on the DoD scorecard and
some of the other score carding efforts
are talked about just basic network
hygiene are you keeping your networks
up-to-date as far as patching are you
configuring and keeping configuration
control of your network devices for
instance if you identify that you've
done a really good job of dividing your
you know you're defining your battle
space you have two main areas that your
network goes to the out
the internet for primary and redundant
and you've really interrogated the
settings on your firewall do you lock
those configurations so that if any
change those firewalls immediate little
alerts in your sock because what I found
is most people aren't doing that they
don't use the tools that are available
that will identify those critical items
in your protection architecture and lock
them down because as we saw from that
other other slide human error
so many times I have good intentions
sysadmin folks get inside and they
change something and we've had you know
we've certainly had seen examples of
very critical interfaces were bypassed
and no one knew about it for significant
amounts of time because we're just not
instrumenting them as we should they're
not instrumented as critical nodes in
our network and so that goes back to the
network hygiene if part of the computers
are the CS program here at at Purdue I
don't know if they stress that or not
but once you build it you gotta maintain
it right you can't just walk away
deliver it to the customer and walk away
there isn't something inherent in the
liability that you created something and
you need to nurture it or it dies and
and what I've seen is networks where
engineering folks will deploy and then
walk away and they there is no money
left for keeping the system up or
maintained and so that's kind of the the
Coalition of the Willing need to kind of
bond together and say we're not gonna
we're not going to behave that way
anymore
because it'd be become a liability to
our organizations if we don't maintain
those systems
all right so let's look at some of these
educate your family your laptop sitting
around at home got a teenager pops it
open to look up something goes to some
site get your corporate network infected
that never happens the safeguard your
devices especially when you're traveling
if you're traveling to an area that has
a very let's say aggressive government
that you could probably consider your
device compromised so don't take your
corporate laptop there okay bye-bye of a
cheap throwaway and once you're done
don't throw it away all this review your
statements goes along with kind of the
review your logs you got to have if
you're if you're doing logging and
auditing of your networks you have to
have knowledge of the people who
actually know what they're looking at
the worst part is finding a network
where there are logging they're
producing logs
no one's trained and look at them no one
knows what they say and so the worst
thing would be finding something months
and months and months old that was a
problem and then this issue of answering
that those social networking calls I
don't know if the phone company or where
that industry is going to police itself
but as you saw from that earlier slide
that was just in one day all of those
out of the area calls that I got those
were all in one day
all right so let's look ahead see what
we got coming up
data breaches they're gonna continue the
on my prediction is more of those it's
not going to be much about if you got
breach but how you acted after the
breach were you prepared and so if this
is kind of the the foot stomper convince
your folks that it's it's going to
happen we just need to have our our plan
in place when it does having a very kind
of order of battle this is what this is
what Bill Sallie and Tom do on the day
that we discover we have a breach this
is who we're gonna call a lot of
companies let's say they they get
completely inundated and they have a
whole business sector that's that's been
polluted and they're gonna have to do a
hard rebuild I don't know about you but
that's gonna put a stress on most
businesses how are you gonna get four or
five hundred clients and if you have to
replace servers routers and other
devices on the network do you have a
acquisition process in place to do that
rapidly I read a cleanup story about a
one at the Pentagon took two weeks to
reconstitute the network and they
considered that as success how many
business could sustain being off for two
weeks not many so beyond alert you got
fishing at work and at home
I don't know as as as many times are
many tools as you put in place you're
always going to get those spear phishing
attacks with payload into somebody's
inbox some tools are better than others
some are crafted in such a way that
they've been able to bypass you need to
understand who the target is at your
organization spear phishing anybody
heard of whaling yeah so you need to
know who the whales are in your
organization we have a list of the most
most targeted people in our organization
for spear fishing
and we talk to them and we have security
officers talk to them to make sure that
they're understand they've been a target
and they will get these messages too if
any do get to their mailboxes before we
quarantined them and deleted them they
need to understand that they have a
responsibility aren't part of the
security architecture social engineering
it's still my favorite because it only
seems to work if you haven't seen some
of the go to the FBI page and look it's
disturbing and kind of entertaining at
the same time people want to believe
stuff like they want to you know a
million dollars or something like that
and inherently you can get them and you
can manipulate them if there's just a
glimmer of hope and you know I read a
study one time in the past couple weeks
about why some of those scams are so
blatant right have you noticed that some
of the the scams the the wording is so
blatantly false you know the context of
the of the language used is just so
outrageous that nobody in their right
mind would believe that and so there's
one contention that that that's why
they're crafted that way they're done
that on purpose because they don't want
to waste their time on you folks they
want to waste their they want to cut the
group down to the most gullible people
in the society right so that's why
they're crafted in such a way to kind of
exclude the folks taking a first glance
at it still going to continue because it
works identity theft
certainly up your decision we talked
about monitoring that's it's kind of a
personal decision
voicemail that's kind of the social
social engineering
the and some of them are just you can
make a living just validating it's a
it's a working phone number right so
you're the mirror you picking up the
phone give them and say okay that's
check that's an active line and somebody
answers it not a machine not a Google
number whatever and so that's a that's a
data point yep No
right right yeah in fact I I actually
seen that on my phone I get the same
first six digits and they they call
every day and they still remind me that
a federal grant has washed away my
student loan if I'd only click on this
email skimmers I'm kind of on the fence
on this because with the advent of the
chips everybody chipped down on their
cards or we still got some legacy ones
out most most people now have the new
chipped cards I'm not sure how that's
gonna work and factored into skimming
because that's it's it's a little it's
up the game a little bit so I'm sure
that some somebody smart will figure out
how to how to circumvent that so that's
kind of on the fence io T's right now I
think I talked about this a lot I think
we're gonna see a little rise in
malicious activity just kind of the
proof of concept can I can I mess with
this because people like to mess with us
right as you saw in that there was a
clown on there there's always some clown
out there who's gonna mess with you and
then privacy I think you heard yesterday
from Michelle her her old boss you know
when that that quote was the privacy is
gone get over it well you know when that
was right 20 years ago and it hasn't
gotten any better
right and it was if it was gone then I
don't know where it is now it's it's
your yeah I think certainly it's
generational and depending on where
you're coming from it's it's sort of
privacy's in the eye of the beholder I
think his staff had had said it's really
dependent on on what your you know your
background has been
all right let's go to
so these are kind of the the kind of
alley behind that I'd kind of recommend
looking at that you'd really do have to
understand your users what they're
trying to do on your network where they
go if you're a company that will kind of
just foot stomp this if your company
doesn't have any business dealing with
will you just use Venezuela again do you
have any corporate business in Venezuela
well then why would you allow your
network to talk to IPS in Venezuela I
mean it's an old concept of geo blocking
but when we use this a long time ago
with toe fraud it kind of makes sense go
on and why would why would our network
be talking to i PS in Kazakhstan I have
business there and I don't have any
business there right so if you're if
you're a company that has of the luxury
of having a fairly defined market you
can do some things to limit your
exposure and understanding your space
you need to make sure that you could
articulate that you really don't have
any any any right to be spending
corporate dollars if you can't
articulate the kind of the return on
investment you're going to get from it
so you're gonna be seen it's kind of
crossed that line between a security guy
who's a liability and he's gonna cost me
money - one that's aiding the mission
essential function making sure it is
protected and can always produce revenue
then you're gonna put a different hat on
manage your data when possible
personally who knows where your data is
but you all ultimately have a have an
understanding of what your tolerance is
for how much exposure you want stay
aware the adversary you're going to need
to keep up on what the adversary is
doing both to your employees at home and
are you being targeted if you're if you
do a merger and acquisition
really need to understand what an
adversary sees it's an opportunity to
get into your network and then we foot
stomp the five a lot this one is it's
going to happen to you you better plan
for failure this one is it's hard to
understand because people seem to live
in this denial phase that no we're
spending enough money this won't happen
to us it's it's gonna happen either it's
gonna be a small-scale or it's gonna be
large-scale but either way it's gonna
cost you and then you got to stay
vigilant because after all this this
cyber war that we talked about for many
decades we're actually fighting it every
day so welcome to the fight and that's
probably all I have to to leave you with
unless there's any questions yes
[Music]
it does it does a factor in those as
well those and those ancillary costs
it's a it's a good study if you haven't
seen it I would recommend taking a look
through it because it it does talk about
different sectors respond differently to
breaches I think right now if you're in
a financial instable than they are in
say if your core of target or or Under
Armour seen a little bit differently by
customers any other questions
no I'm going to turn it back to - Joel
thank you
[Applause]
you