okay the cold weather must have chased a
few people away today so go ahead get
started
professor payer is not gonna make it
he's travelling again this week so he's
not gonna be able to be in class today
but it's my pleasure to introduce Mitch
Parker and Mitch is the executive
director for information security and
compliance at IU Health and Indianapolis
so he's currently working on
redeveloping information security
program at IU Health and regularly works
in lots of non technology and technology
areas so he's been a speaker a lot of
conferences and a lot of a lot of
workshops if you're familiar with hims
he's he's big in the hims organization
and as a speaker there and he's been
also a proponent of the Internet of
medical things so I think you'll enjoy
his talk today
he's holds a bachelor's degree in
computer science from Bloomsburg and MS
and information technology from LaSalle
and his MBA from Temple so he's well
traveled and so all with adding further
dill introduced Mitch thank you very
much and yes well traveled up and down
Broad Street and Philadelphia I'd like
to put it as a salad temple or a couple
only a couple miles from each other so
what I'm going to talk about today is
lessons learned from the retro computing
community and purpose of what I'm doing
today is to show that successful retro
computing projects in groups which
currently exist they follow patterns
that we can use to help a lot of low
resource at industrial organizations
that really need the secure their
devices so I am from the Philadelphia
area a little bit of background on that
is that in the Philadelphia area
probably the most famous computer
flameout of the early 90s was a company
called Commodore computers based in
Westchester Pennsylvania and famous for
at one time being a multi-billion dollar
company and getting sold off for parts
in 1994 so Who am I
Gary talked about in the executive
director of information security
compliance at IU Health I have been a
CISO for over nine years both at IU
Health and at Temple University Health
System I've got over 30 years using
computers despite my youth I started out
with a Commodore 64 back in 1984 I still
have one of them set up obviously not
the original one which has probably some
landfill somewhere but I also have my
candy 102 my candy 200 mi tan DW
to which I actually occasionally take
out in use and I taught myself computers
by taking my old computers apart and
putting them back together again then I
went through a lot of Commodore trs-80
Tandy and PC clone hardware that way I
mean a lot since I got married and had
kids a lot of hardware has been given
away so what is retrocomputing for those
of you who don't know it's the use of a
lot of older classic computer and
hardware hardware and software now and
the vast majority of platforms as covers
are from the 1980s and 90s and the most
represented platforms you gotta have out
there and again this is a no particular
order or preference for those of you in
the room that may have one I have no I
have no interest in reenact in the BBS
flame wars of the 80s so yeah yeah the
Apple 2 family which includes the Apple
2 2 2 + 2 e 2 C + 2 GS and I can tell
you I've met was incredibly incredibly
nice guy and will tell you everything
about the Apple 2 to this day you have
the Commodore 64 128 you have the
Commodore Amiga and it's descendants and
clones the Atari home computers and the
ST sorry for aus - eggs for leading out
the TT when I wrote this deck you have
the Sinclair spectrum and his clones I
put this as specific significance
because this computer was so easy to
build that a large number of them were
actually rebuilt in the Soviet bloc by
former Soviet by the for Soviet bloc
countries themselves so literally
there's one case where people actually
rebuilt the spectrum using literally
household parts and things that cobbled
together out of scrap metal in Romania
back in the 80s which isn't pretty
incredible and of course you got to
mention - Tandy trs-80 portables and
desktops and of course - Tandy model 100
series which was the first real computer
you would call laptop and part of that
was written by a Microsoft engineer
named Bill Gates and of course you got
to mention the TI 99 for a series first
16-bit home computer so why these
computers are very simple and very easy
to use and fix the Sinclair spectrum I
mentioned before used a processor called
the za
from a company called zilog which at one
time was part of exxon and there are so
many of these processors on the market
that to this day you can still find that
part all over the place and there's
significantly less complex than modern
computers I sometimes call it
deceptively complex but you can really
get to know the platform really well and
many compute community members in the IT
community grew up with them and entire
communities have sprung up around this
so I will bring up the first and most
popular ones IRC Internet Relay Chat and
also back in the 80s before there was
IRC and the internet was popular and
well not in universities you had
CompuServe you had a little company in
Virginia called quantum link that grew
to become America online you had PC
Pursuit and yet a bunch of other 80s
online services many of which charged a
lot of money and of course the most
infamous one for hackers the Versa dial
a kad dial 300 baud you could take seven
Apple cat modems drop them in an apple -
and boom instant chat line back when
your average computer had about 64k of
RAM this was ridiculously popular and
you had often had several them in the
same city there were - I was aware of in
Chicago - in Philadelphia and at least
one in New York City and I would say out
of the hacker community this is probably
most famous / infamous take your pick
online social community and a lot of
them were quote-unquote linked
nationally back before long-distance was
free long distance cost a lot of money
and so there used to be services called
out dials you used to be able to use to
link services together in different
cities
so people link their D dials in places
like Canada Chicago New York all over
the place to talk and yes it's still
emulated and running to this day I'm
honest I'm a member of a Facebook page
for D dial and still haven't logged into
that one detail system in Florida but
it's there so what's my community
experience this is not an excuse for all
the hours I spent on IRC or D dial I
learned computer insecurity in the early
1990s pre-internet being popped
heck I will tell you that back when 900
numbers are popular the local internet
service provider actually offered a 900
number as an option to called it once a
month in a pager bill and I learned
pre-internet at the end of the BBS a
year at during the transition to the
internet I learned a lot from working
and participating a lot with friends and
acquaintances as they worked and towards
the end I started writing documentation
testing and connecting others with
resources they needed and sharing
hardware with those who develops I
remember one day driving 40 miles into
South Jersey to pick up a Commodore 128
D for a friend in Scranton Pennsylvania
neither one because I was gonna be up
there later that day why cuz it was 60
bucks and the guy wouldn't ship so what
makes this community unique they've
worked their way through innumerable
challenges to keep hardware and software
running far beyond its useful expected
lifetime and they've managed to do so
despite some of the most onerous
rightholders withholding information or
not even knowing where it really is so
I'm gonna give one very important case
in point when Commodore went under in
1994 and was pretty much sold off for
parts a number of companies bought said
parts and what happened is there was a
lot of legal fights over the rights to
some of that Commodore intellectual
property some of which got so intense
that I could name at least one executive
of a company that had a lot of ex
Commodore employees that when he does
case studies for his class at Temple
University will not even mention the
Commodore name out of fear of some sort
of legal repercussion and also they've
done so without major corporations
funding them so there's an interesting
case I actually sent this deck to be
reviewed by Trevor Dickenson this man in
particular multi millionaire
entrepreneur happens like Commodore
Amiga is a lot so there was no new
amigas being made so he funded a couple
of you so and literally he spent several
million dollars of his own money paid an
engineering company to make him an Amiga
and he sold him something he sold
several thousand of money internets so
he's done an incredible job you did an
operating system pay developers to write
the operating system
very rare exception matter of fact he's
dealing when I could find everything is
almost completely bootstrapped and
self-funded and it's pretty incredible
so what makes it unique this is a
do-it-yourself
punk rock hacker ethos community so
these are the original hackers from back
in the day and many of these community
members are still active in corporate IT
although you'd never know it unless you
really asked them and they do it for
themselves there's no corporate
interests in there remember this is
do-it-yourself and they actually kind of
shun corporate interests and a big part
of reason why is some corporations and
rights holders have been very hostile to
the retro computing community and I'll
be honest about something for those of
you from said large corporations viewing
this video right now you don't know who
these people are that are asking you
about this information from some of your
twenty plus year old IP some of them now
are decision makers and executives at
large companies and when you blow them
off or give them curt answers it will
negatively reflect on your business and
I'm not saying that to be bad I'm saying
that because bad customer service leads
to some issues like I said you don't
know what these people do for their day
jobs I can name several very highly
placed IT executives that are active in
the retro computing community including
one that holds several patents for
things we use every day so why am I
doing this realistic reason because many
of the solutions out there and
implementations are people are taking
cybersecurity implementations that are
point solutions and saying they address
and assess risk this is a big problem
and as I see so I see that as being a
big issue because you can't buy
something out of a catalogue or
something from a company that's going to
magically fix all your problems it's
just never gonna happen that way and you
can't assess and address this risk if
you don't know what it really is or what
it means and you don't know what it
means unless you understand the whole
system and these people really
understand systems and they understand
them well and this community does a
better job of understanding systems and
assessing risk in any community I know
we've forgotten a lot and we will forget
more than most
people have ever learned and we can
learn a lot from them and apply it to
modern technologies so case in point I'm
gonna talk about industrial devices and
industrial device security there's a
number of companies out there that have
products such as industrial robots
medical devices SCADA systems standing
for supervisory control acquisition data
acquisition or control systems with
twenty to thirty year lifecycle
realistically that's what they plan and
budget for and in many cases this
equipment was already built on obsolete
hot hardware and software so I'll give a
real-life example of this 22 years ago I
worked as an intern in a company doing
PLC development and ladder logic we were
putting forty six a--'s in the
industrial robots in 1996 at 1996 the
processor to use was the penny and were
Petty and Pro we were already a couple
generations behind why because it was
the only equipment back then he could
rack mounts and he can't expect this
equipment to be upgraded like a PC on
Patch Tuesday oh and I forgot to mention
that this Hardware metla ran Windows 3.1
with on top of ms-dos 6 - so it was very
obsolete already and with the emphasis
now on quantitative management which I
got a big exposure to and I got my MBA
there's often expectations of every
device out there send performance data
for analysis including the devices that
were never meant to do so ie the PC from
1996 running running a robot out there
somewhere and in addition another
business trend there's been an emphasis
and centralizing management and
operations of companies into what they
call Centers of Excellence rough
translation there's been a lot of
mergers and acquisitions over the past
20 years perfect example of that is
General Electric another example I could
give is IBM and the real translation for
those of us in the room that work with
technology is they want to run the
actual production sites as lean as
possible with as few people as possible
to reduce the number of people actually
there and reduce costs using centralized
monitoring which means they want to
network everything
coupled with that the number of people
in the workforce who built or maintained
these systems is slowly dwindling due to
retirement or certain or attrition
outside of the bump we got from y2k when
pretty much give you new COBOL you were
worth six figures we're seeing a lot of
retirements coupled with the fact that
especially in the case of the US
government a very large amount of the
workforce in the US government that was
under the old Civil Service Retirement
System were given payouts to leave
because of the old defined Ben pension
benefit the government had iBM is doing
really well
why because they run their own schools
to train people on this stuff very few
companies out there actually run their
own schools to train people and I can
mean to IBM and a security company
outside of Detroit Michigan and that and
a lot of this industrial equipment is
being networked and in many cases the
original information used to build a
system it's gone why this a major risk
I'll give you three wanna cry Petya and
not Petya
there are a host of other active threats
out there such as Mirai and the various
huge amounts of worms out there
attacking your arm based devices or x86
to base devices every day and a major
propagation fact where vulnerabilities
is when you don't address or assess risk
vault or vulnerabilities correctly when
I talk to executives about what the
major cause of data breaches is I tell
them the systems aren't maintained first
time I ever get had to give a
presentation to the c-suite at my
current organization I was doing prep
with one of the executives before and
she sent me two data breaches I didn't
cover in my prep deck both of them I had
covered in five minutes after doing
research because I literally took a look
at it they didn't patch they didn't
catch got up in front of 30 executives
and basically said you've got a patch in
maintain your systems and you'll take
care of 90% of your problems we do this
and after a few months they got them to
believe me and buy into that but again
that's what it comes down to and when
you sit there and tell them you give
them these huge data breaches such as
OPM
what 25 million records breached and the
reason why it wasn't because you didn't
have someone wasn't wearing the latest
and greatest latest in greatest security
software they're running a three year
old version of Oracle forms that had not
received security updates and was not
going to receive security updates and
this is not Oracle's fault Oracle told
the government this is old and obsolete
software you need to replace it which is
why the old OPM administrator is now
looking for a job so another piece when
I did my research for this powe is that
you literally will have these devices
show up a network they're available to
entire corporations not to a branch
office not to a defined segment you'll
literally find somebody you figured out
how to do a serial to Ethernet adapter
or a next thing you know you've got an
industrial robot showing up on your
corporate network and when these devices
were being designed
they were just figuring out how
networking and these technologies works
so even securing them is a major
challenge and this sounds similar to the
challenges the retro computing community
faces so we're going to go over to
following changes they've following
challenges they've addressed
collaboration and communication focus
social communities lost poor or
incomplete documentation reverse
engineering of hardware and software and
again working around bugs years and
after effect building Newell to building
new tools addressing tasks at hand
emphasis on preserving the experience
and putting solutions in place to
preserve security so then we're going to
go over how we cannot apply these
lessons to to our businesses so we can
better protect ourselves so there's any
community any or the group that
leverages collaboration communication
it's the retro computing community there
are mailing lists IRC channels BBS's
over telnet though I don't think anyone
I know is doing dial-up BBS's anymore
they are I'd be surprised and bulletin
boards that you use for communication
there's always someone at the other end
always willing to answer questions or
research and there's no real hierarchy
it's a meritocracy built on delivering
information or products and there's an
informal expectation that you will
contribute or help
in some way shape or form there's also a
very strong conference community with
this group that has an emphasis on
presenting these findings or new
developments so biggest one I'm gonna
give is vintage computer festival which
hosts events in the East Coast Midwest
West Coast and I believe they have they
have them in San Francisco and Seattle
now I have to check with having
compliments on that who does a lot of
work for him but again this is great I
tell you one the best retrocomputing
enthusiasts I know is actually goes to
all these events he's based out of
Chicago you have hackers on planet Earth
which every year in New York City at set
I think at the hotel Pennsylvania it's
run by 2600 magazine and they do a lot
of work they actually have a
retrocomputing table set up by the
finished computer Federation you will
see a lot of them at Def Con and black
hats many of them go here I can tell you
at a conversation I first got to Indiana
with somebody about someone they knew
from Def Con 20 years ago
there's the Commodore Amiga conventions
was yes they still exist the Apple and
Atari ST conventions I believe there's
an apple convention in st. Louis that
gets several hundred people a year and
the local user groups and yes there is
one here in Indiana
I think they meet about half hour north
of my house and I'm down in Carmel and
the summary is people want to share
information freely in this community and
they're gonna do so so one other
critical aspect you can't overlook is
focus so these days social media is
marked by mayhem and trolling and quite
frankly just general chaos as the as the
events of Twitter today show us
but these communities they are very
focused on addressing task at hand while
the 2016 presidential election was quite
frankly incredibly divisive on social
media you'd never know it from these
groups so groups like Club 100 which
tandy laptops website mailing lists the
Commodore 64 and 128 grew up on Facebook
and the IRC channels are very intolerant
of political discussion of trolling and
they will not hesitate to boot you if
you bring every star amber got those
conversations
and this is what I use and it was so bad
constant trolling that's kind of what
killed Usenet and they're very focused I
mean you have a mix of ages backgrounds
geographies and ethnicities who
participate in these forms especially
the Commodore ones where most of the
people are actually from Western and
Eastern Europe but again you never know
about the political issues in Europe if
you were on the IRC and you also have a
very large district or ship number of US
Armed Services veterans because reason
why very simple many of the people who
learn computing back in the 80s in the
70s they got their start in the Army
because back with computers cost as much
as a new car you wanted access to one
have you enlisted you had access very
simple but the truth is they leave it at
the door and when addressing issues and
challenges and there are many lessons to
be learned here from this and I'm gonna
actually suffix this with especially for
the information security community and
they all can have the viewpoints they do
right wing left wing or whatever they
can still work together no matter any of
their differences and they still get
work done and they can tell you from
personal experience you get both ends of
the spectrum and I've never had an issue
and when people have brought them up
they've been asked to leave so you get
brings us to lost poor and incomplete
documentation this is the biggest
challenge a lot of people face because
many of these systems lack any kind of
proper documentation and if they did
have it it's most likely gone by now
except for the great work Google didn't
pretty much preserving Usenet from the
70s and 80s and putting it available
online as part of Google News quite
frankly if Google hadn't done that a
huge amount of history for Commodore
computers would have gone by the wayside
or being permanently lost so big props
to Google on that so what's left is
still on paper or of electronic still in
the original disk or tape formats so
what's happens
community members post what they need on
a website or forum other communities
will research and
give what they have they'll put it up on
a website they'll put it up on Dropbox
door we're gonna put it up on a BBS to
download and these people will go to
flea markets ham fests vintage computer
festival local groups or hacker
conventions to purchase this equipment
or documentation and they'll scan it in
they'll post that they have it I mean
there's somebody I know
literally he'll pick up old computing
magazines scan him put them in PDF post
where he's got him and people download
them and in this particular case this is
very interesting or some software in the
Amiga community that was thought to be
lost they contacted the original author
brought him back into the community he
got a new release of software out of it
guy's name was Jim drew I believe and
they will contact original authors and
companies and sometimes this brings them
back into the community and again the
other way of seeing us a lot has been
with Nintendo games people will contact
the original authors of Nintendo games
and what's happened is you've seen a lot
of roms of what were once thought to be
lost games downloadable on the Internet
and they will make best efforts to
reconstruct what they don't have and
they will often collaborate to piece
together info like amateur archaeologist
it's actually pretty cool to watch and
they will fill in the blanks and put
together documentation in a standard
format and yes they will build equipment
to read the old formats I'll give a
perfect example it's a little something
called cryo flux you can get off the
it's a disk drive you can get off the
internet designed to do low-level disk
reads of three and a half five and a
quarter and eight inch disks yes they
did at one time make eight inch discs
and what this does is because standard
disc readers weren't capable of reading
past some of the errors this reads
magnetic flux patterns that's dedication
and what's the end result collaborative
communities working together to rebuild
relevant documentation and while it's
not perfect it's a start and in some I
should have put many cases it's the
improvement over the original
documentation why because you have to
because a lot of people reverse engineer
it and when documentation isn't enough
you have to
how it really works and you were dealing
with situations where 99% at a time
except for the rare cases I talked about
before you're not going to have access
to source code or the developers
therefore these people will reverse
engineer and document using emulators
and virtualized environments to
determine exactly how systems work this
means they will take the extra time to
disassemble code libraries and determine
exactly what lines of code executed
where sound like malware research
perfect example I can give of this of
determining how something works under
very specific corner cases was a game
for a Super Nintendo called Speedy
Gonzales based off of the old Warner
Brothers character so what happened is
is the programmers that built this game
were incredibly ridiculously talented to
the point where they were able to get
more performance out of four megahertz
than they should have and they used some
dirty tricks and the hardware to do it
so someone that wrote one of the Super
Nintendo emulators and I read this an
ARS technica five years ago literally
figured out how to game operate it
because there was a glitch caused by how
this one programmer programmed in Speedy
Gonzales in level six and what he did he
figured out exactly what the glitch was
reverse-engineered it published the
results of his emulator and got an
article on ARS technica out of it which
meant that a lot of people out there got
to see firsthand what this man did and
it was absolutely brilliant and this is
the kind of dedication and this is the
kind of people you need disassembling
malware why because they know how it
works and they can get those corner
cases working and a lot of the malware
we're seeing these days uses similar
techniques to what the video game
programmers used in the 80s everything
old becomes new again and some of the
more motivated ones will document ships
using logic analyzers and other tools
custom builds the determine exactly had
our Hardware operates and they will
document what they have and share it
part of the reason why a lot of this
hardware it's dying the there's only a
finite number of Commodore 64's or
Commodore Amiga that were made
unfortunately both of those computers
used a lot of
some ships as common or had their own
ship foundry they were able to do this
and what happened is they didn't exactly
put out good documentation those chips
unlike the woz who documented everything
he could about the Apple too and made
sure everyone had it and I'm sure if it
wasn't out there on the internet he'd
pay for it to be out there these days
these people are going out there reverse
engineering what these chips did so they
can make sure the emulators can emulate
them because the hardware is dying which
means software can't run anymore
you have to be able to do it it's very
important it also gives you additional
knowledge of how the systems work and
where the risks really are or in a case
of some of the more brilliant video game
programmers how to make us how to make a
Super Nintendo applet real-time video
and as part of your documentation would
reverse engineering process you will
find often very hard to reproduce bugs
and they will find something that took
you years to discover however
there's several ciao there's several
challenges here much like Speedy
Gonzales would have talked about earlier
in a Super Nintendo
people for I knew about this bug and use
it to their advantage or as I like to
refer to it as many of the demo coders
who programmed demos for a Commodore 64
and Amiga who were infamous for that and
if you try and fix it in hardware or
software you have a chance of breaking
existing systems we see a lot of that
today Microsoft had that problem years
ago before they put the side-by-side
libraries and windows and which we used
to call DLL hell and if you fix it you
need to be able to operate in both a
broken and fixed state emulators do this
a lot as did Windows with its
quote/unquote shims which are really
popular before Windows 10 and the most
popular solution for when you find these
bugs is integrate the solution into an
emulator with an option to turn it on or
off so I know when you a he does that
qemu which emulates x86 computers DOSBox
vice or mommy code fix fix only to
programs that need it and offer it as an
option or patch the media community is
really good about that and there's a
broad-based solution you document the
living heck out of it and communicate
that everyone you know
so when you talk about building new
tools most of the original development
environments they show their age order
unusable on modern computers because a
lot of development environments use some
of the same hooks you use to make demos
run there's a lot of new technologies to
take advantage of so what a lot of
people do is they develop their own
tools on newer platforms that can either
interface with the emulators or actual
devices via the interfaces kind of like
what people used to do a Palm Pilot
development 20 years ago and it allows
you to speed up your development by
action by using modern tools and it
allows you to debug issues more
thoroughly by again using some of the
modern tools you're gonna be a lot more
productive using some of the GNU the
buggers and you were some of the stuff
from 30 years ago and you have to have
that emphasis on addressing the tasks at
hand you look at a fight in the finite
number of hours in a day you can
actually do something and these are
people doing this in their spare time
and they're folk they focused their
successful projects around a limited
scope that addresses the tasks at hand
and while it take them might take a
while to complete the development is
very usually transparent and open and in
many cases can be downloaded via github
however they address to get they address
the key issues and the focus is on
preserving and reproducing the user
experience in his original and manner as
possible there's not about making a
modern experience because people
wouldn't use it it's not authentic you
have to keep it original univis emulated
you preserve it you go out of your way
to not changes and if there's new
features you integrate them in such a
way that integrates with the old
environment and more importantly can be
turned off so I can think of all the
modifications for a trs-80 one model 100
and 102 you can turn them all off and
return back to your stock hardware
whenever you'd like and there's new
hardware and software features don't in
it don't make them part of the core user
experience keep them away make it
something someone has to turn on because
you don't want to ruin that experience
and also people forget muscle memory and
user experience and if you mess with
that you mess with someone's workflow
you're gonna have a pretty major issue
which is major a big reason why a lot of
software projects fail a lot of upgrades
fail that's because you change
someone's workflow so drastically they
don't know what to do and remember
you're dealing with poor documentation
most of the time so you have to preserve
an experience now there's new hardware
you keep the cost down and the hardware
as common as possible and like woz did
with the Apple 2 you publish everything
you make it so you can open up a book in
whoa look here's the hardware block
Tiger of everything I ever did document
everything about how to install it and
you use common low cost hardware
solutions that anyone can implement or
as I could do a tour substitute here
Raspberry Pi which for $35 has taken the
hobbyist world by storm because it could
be used for Darner everything and is
used for darn near everything in retro
computing and always be available as a
resource always be available I can tell
you one computing community in
particular that was emphatic about
self-selecting developers was a
Commodore Amiga community if you didn't
respond to bug requests or put out new
versions of your software to fix bugs
you didn't have a lot of users they have
to work because they would users would
basically say don't use the software he
doesn't know what he's doing he doesn't
respond the customer service requests
and I found this bug it's crashing and
he hasn't fixed it big emphasis on good
customer service in that community so
you got to put solutions in place to
preserve security so what this means is
you got to make sure the entire
environment is appropriately secured and
if you know how do you how do you
environment operates you can assess and
address risk and the retro computing
community will often with emulators
describe what turnin options will do and
more importantly what not to do and they
emphasize keeping your personal
information safe and off of devices you
develop on sounds familiar
so how does this relate to modern
company I just talked about a bunch of
things that have gone on over the past
thirty years here's the first way I'm
going to bring this home for you we are
losing information more now than ever so
I'm gonna bring up the example of the
iPhone I have a thunder phille iPhone
here that up until iOS 11 was able to
run 32-bit applications it now only runs
64-bit application
so think of all the 32-bit applications
out there that no longer run because
apple iOS will not run them and from
what I understand there is no emulator
yet for apple iOS that I'll do 32 bits
we generate petabytes of information a
year and I'm sure that there's you could
probably use exabyte at this point for
the amount of information we generate
and barely any of it despite the best
efforts of companies like Google and
Microsoft is kept in a format we can use
we didn't know we have and we need to
collaborate to know critical information
about what we own and almost every
company out there has something very old
and obsolete that is absolutely critical
to their business you're not alone
everyone's got something 20 or 30 years
old and it you shut off would cause a
serious disruption to your revenue
I don't care of your Apple Microsoft IBM
or Purdue you have something and I will
tell you message from management here
your peers are most likely already
collaborating and they haven't told you
yet and I will tell you in terms of some
of the managers I've dealt with over the
past 20 years an IT there in some cases
there's a fear of repercussions because
some managers emphasize not talking to
outsiders and realistically if you're an
app boat
you should be providing the blocking and
tackling for these four people to
preserve your critical assets and reduce
risk and don't be scared of potential
impact from lawyers reverse engineering
how a 20 year old device works or that
looks like to explain the people the
Digital Millennium Copyright Act has
section 1201 for a reason you are
allowed to reverse-engineer something
you own for the purposes of
interoperability so as long as you do
that tell the lawyers that you should be
ok and nothing is so critical that you
have to absolutely hide it and the
lessons learned from this corporations
and team members need to collaborate on
shared vulnerabilities why everybody has
done and possess on the period we need
to work together to address them it's
about reducing risk not corporate
advantage and what do we learn from
wanna cry Petra and
Pecha what good is corporate advantage
if you don't have a network what good
it's no good so what you want to do is
you want to empower your key team
members to collaborate with their peers
and you want to instead of trying to
hide it
we're trying to hide the fact you've got
some legacy system someplace you
facilitate it I couldn't have a major
major supplier to one of the Big Three
automakers that actually facilitates it
who and this was 20 years ago why
because most of robots that assemble
auto that assemble autos at the time
were running backs not openvms VAX an
operating system that quite frankly is
older than I am and he came on eight
inch disks so because of that you had a
major auto company out there that was
openly collaborating they had staff
doing that why because those 27 year old
robots at the time they shut down
there's a lot of people that weren't
really buying new cars and you want to
provide legal protection for them to do
so so that they can reduce risk and they
can share this information without fear
of repercussions you want them joining
information sharing an advisory centers
such as the National Health Science ACK
or in the case of Purdue the research
education and networking I sac red eye
SEC and you want to facilitate the
shared forums and discussion areas to
discuss how to resolve a lot of these
issues and give them time and resources
to reverse engineer what you've got if
you have to change the acquisition rules
so be it
this is your business eBay flea markets
and Bitcoin or work the risks if it
involves keeping something safe and
secure on your network and I can tell
you in particular the supplier to the me
to one of the big three auto
manufacturers I mentioned had three
staff members their job was to go on
ebay into the vintage computer forum and
buy all the deck hardware that can get
their hands on they would literally get
lists from their IT department what to
buy and they would their job was to go
on eBay and buy it and also don't do
this in isolation have them gather its
information and knowledge as part of the
yearly risk assessments and include
addressing discovered risks as part of
the risk management plan
because you have to do so from the point
of view of addressing the risk in real
life use cases and don't get caught up
in these point solutions that say hey do
you put this on you network you'll
preserve all your legacy devices why
can't you well it's not gonna do it and
you have because the reason the real
reason we have all of the legislation
out there on the information security
why we have HIPPA why we have high tech
is because and why we have the rules in
finance and why the FFIEC has the rules
they do is because you have to know what
you have address what you have and treat
these resources like they have the 20 or
30 year lifecycle they do you have to
mitigate risk and you have to make sure
your use cases address present and
future conditions translation if they
decide that they're gonna run a skeleton
crew at your factory and they're going
to monitor everything over the internet
from Kalamazoo Michigan they need to be
able to do so and do so securely and you
got to address these risks with common
solutions so level set for a lot of
people here don't put this off because
it doesn't meet someone's criteria for
an ideal solution oftentimes an IT we
get into this mindset of we have to get
the perfect solution out there it has to
do everything that doesn't work that way
you don't have something to secure your
systems now and you're at risk and the
reason why you're at risk is because
you've you're sitting there in analysis
paralysis and you like many other
companies you don't have a butter to put
all new solutions in and you shouldn't
try to play keep up with the Joneses so
translation many of the magazines you
read out there many of the publications
they make their money off of advertising
revenue trying to get you to buy the
latest and greatest products you
shouldn't fall into that trap you want
to keep the solutions common low cost
and easily replaceable or fixable in
case of failure so in other words you
collaborate with others I'm building and
maintaining them and keep them simple
and add it away so if you don't think
that something like this works take a
look at the Open Compute Project where
you have some of the largest cloud
services and application providers on
the internet collaborating on server
designs twenty years ago it would have
been unthinkable it also would have been
a major dent in the revenue stream with
a lot of former multi-billion dollar
companies and I want to emphasize that
former multi
billion-dollar companies the companies
you deal with now for server technology
and compute technology are not most
likely not going to be here in 20 years
and the forum you recognize outside of
maybe IBM and even then half of what was
IBM 20 years ago now belongs to Lenovo
hewlett-packard 20 years ago there were
four other companies that were part of
hewlett-packard
the Hewlett Packard Enterprise I believe
the new one ZTE there was also agile
--nt and about two other companies that
got spun off so change is inevitable and
you have to make sure you're as open as
possible and flexible as possible as
simple as possible because 20 years from
now those companies are most likely not
going to exist so keep things as simple
keep it matter to weigh and collaborate
and documents so how does this actually
benefit you you actually address your
risks based on your use cases and you
put solutions in place that actually are
provably secure in a combination with
network based security such as
segmentation a light amount manage
multiple sites securely so think of some
benefits I listed here such as central
medical device or clinical engineering
command centers that's something you're
hearing a lot about these days why
because a couple of major hospitals
pulled it off executives see that and go
ooh I want that because it helps me
increase my revenue so you have to be
prepared and you think about centralized
SCADA management for industrial devices
think of the fact that there's a lot of
factories out there but the people that
actually know how to maintain that
equipment are few and far between so you
put the monitoring equipment where the
people are at and you literally run VPN
connections from where the people are at
to those machines keep keep a tech or
two on site to fix the stuff when the
when it breaks but again you're have
people monitoring industrial equipment
three states away and when I did my
research to his presentation I went to
guy named Bill heard he's a Hoosier
he should be mentioned as much as SWA's
niak is why because he's designed the
Commodore 128 he designed the computer
that in the mid-80s had three processors
in it that was doing work that quite
frankly no one else in the market was
doing
and he comes to me when I talked about
the silver email he goes to me he goes
you know Mitch we put this equipment out
there we were just figuring out how it
worked so now we have equipment designed
when people were figuring out how
networking works heck even with micro
processors work and you're putting it on
the Internet so it's the equivalent of
putting a jet engine and Model T in so
in many cases so that's part of the
reason we have to be so careful in
assessing our risk and we have to do so
in a way to preserve the experience
because there's no way in heck you're
gonna make something running a processor
from 1979 like the 68000 you're not
gonna make it run a modern user
interface it's not wearing a networking
stack you got to think differently and
keep that user experience and keep any
changes out of the way you don't
introduce new challenges of not needed
and more importantly you make us that a
person that's been operating that
machine for the past 30 years is able to
do so without major changes or else
you're gonna have some employee
engagement issues so I wish I had the
old Commodore demo thing I could have
put up here but I wanna do thanks to
Bill herd designer of the Commodore 128
in +4 and fellow Hoosier John Haeger hi
Ken petit and Stephen Adolph of club 100
having complaints of the vintage
computer Federation Alex or Bella's from
Blackstone Law Group and 2600 magazine
and the crew from Pouncy 64 on IRC EF
nets so thank you all very much
well before to any questions
everyone was applauding it working what
do you see
technologically it's gonna relieve some
of those problems that are just kind of
like piling on right now if anything I
think you have to have a good risk
management plan I'm very familiar with
the man who spoke here actually talked
to one of his friends on a regular basis
from Eskenazi so we actually collaborate
with them pretty extensively so just a
little bit of level setting in
backgrounds ultimately you have to
extend your risk management program the
medical devices and you are gonna have
to put these devices off in your own
little worlds a lot of medical devices
out there again I can name devices from
multi-billion dollar companies that have
networking abilities because somebody
figured out how to make a serial to
Ethernet ships at work you have to keep
all of that in mind you have to assess
your risk properly you also have to
realize that there's no way I can expect
the company to update these devices
after five years it's just not gonna
happen
half the time they're kidding get the
built they can't even get the builds
building a software working directly
which is why I mentioned it today in
retrocomputing literally if I were to
tell you I want to build a pomalyst 3.5
application today I wouldn't know where
to start because even getting the
software needed to build it running on a
modern operating system would be a
challenge that's the problem you have a
medical device security is because a lot
of this hardware and software that has a
stated 10-year life cycle you're not
patching it on Patch Tuesday and why the
heck should it be visible in to anyone
for any purpose other than what it needs
and according to HIPAA Security Rule it
shouldn't be this full only be there for
the purpose that's needed for so yes
we're gonna see you a medical device
security that people are going to figure
out the hard way don't have to segment
this stuff off from the rest of your
network and they're gonna have to keep
it isolated and know their data flows
which is ultimately be a mat a HIPAA
Security Rule in the first place and I
applaud the work that man is doing at
Eskenazi
it's I'm just curious with your passion
in the retro computing area obviously
you're very passionate about having been
able to apply that in your day job
I haven't been able to apply it at IU
Health but I will tell you in previous
jobs I've run into hardware and software
that has been so old no one else has
known how to operate it I have been able
to use serial ports and actually
configure one which is lost arts I have
actually had to do it for a fire alarm
system my whole job because a fire alarm
system was sending out serial ports and
sending out signals out of what's called
an odd baud rates and getting anyone to
understand serial port as anything other
9600 baud is a bit of a challenge these
days so yes I have applied this
repeatedly at my job just not an IU
Health so any other questions from the
audience there thank you
you