I
so we've been talking all along about
the importance of of cybersecurity
information privacy and the like and
here is an area where this applies where
consequences are frightening ly real
although this is more about simulation
but nonetheless one of our faculty who
works in nuclear engineering engineering
here honey is going to tell you about
the research he's been doing with ELISA
Bertino and take it away
I want now this is definitely a great
turnout they didn't realize it was that
it's gonna be that big but so hopefully
I don't say anything embarrassing thank
you for inviting me to to talk to you
about the cybersecurity but in reality
I'm not really going to talk about
cybersecurity at all I'm going to talk
about the engineering side so I
personally don't have computer science
background and I stopped doing
programming maybe 15 years ago so the
goal here is to think anytime you design
an engineering system there will be some
vulnerabilities the more complex system
because some new vulnerabilities you may
know about from experience or you may
discover them from simulation so the
idea is if you know that could that be
used or exploited by a cyber attack okay
so how the cyber attack is started
that's not really part of the scope of
this work okay so you can think of us as
a second line of defense after the
information type security measures have
been compromised
okay so nuclear reactors I'm not really
gonna give you examples of accidents
that could happen here and the idea is
not to scare anybody but this is the
message here is that this is an example
of an industrial control system and
information about it it's not really
hidden there's a lot of interest in
nuclear reactors and other types of
reactors like chemical plants fossil
plans water treatment etc that are very
common to to the world landscape so
there's a lot of expertise on these
systems overseas and we pretty much know
how to run them and simulate them
so for these class of systems where not
much is hidden is it possible for the
attackers to learn the vulnerabilities
and then use them to device some or
launch some attack and at that point
what would what would you do okay so
some other systems that have a lot of
proprietary information and a lot is not
really in the public domain it will be
very difficult to launch these types of
attacks
okay so my opening lines here is the
safety and security obviously are very
important for for a GE GE and the part
of nuclear the Department of Energy
nuclear engineering to protect the
population that's the general statement
and in the last 10 years or so there are
a lot of efforts directed to modernizing
the reactor control systems which were
traditionally very analog type but this
is similar to many other industries as
well so with more digitization on the
way and also more new new nuclear
reactors that are going to start with
being digitized from the start then
there's obviously a concern about
somebody preaching the the data and then
trying to launch something that's
malicious to the reactor okay so that's
that's the question that we're posing
here security breaches lead to safety
related accidents how the breach happens
that's not the topic here but once once
it started can they initiate some
malicious behavior for the reactor so
some other follow-up questions that we
also think about is the reactor state
can it be falsified by computer virus or
attack a rogue code attacking the
control system and if that's how do you
introduce that that's one of the
questions that are out there that I'm
not gonna try to really address I just
have a couple slides on it but that's
not really the pull of the research and
if the virus can be introduced into the
control system how can you initiate an
event that the operator won't notice
okay and so what kind of accidents can
occur and then if you ensure these types
of events
well the physics on its own cause
director to be safe a lot of these
systems are designed to be inherently
safe so if something goes wrong the
system can recover on its own so that's
one of the questions we have to pose if
some brute force attack causes a reactor
to try to increase in power suddenly for
example will the physics be able to
protect it and what if it was more
calculated and
is introduced in a more stealth way can
the physics still save you or you have
to do something and question
there's also another related can this
happen on a systematic basis and until
it gets you outside this boundary of
safe operation okay so the ultimate goal
of of this research is mainly thinking
about how to design a methodology that
can detect if the control system is
being compromised so when I started this
work I got a chance to meet with Lisa
Bertino she's the one that really got me
inspired to work on this and she
introduced me to this this interesting
article which really combines a lot of
different methods that are currently
being used for industrial control
systems the idea is if we have a model
for how the system behaves then we have
an idea about how it should perform
under normal operations if it deviates
from these normal operations then
something that's the rationale in
general for model-based defences so
we're asking for funding right so we
have to show that we're doing something
different so the approach that we're
taking is that for the class of
industrial control systems that are very
well understood and there's so much
knowledge in the open domain it's
possible to learn learn the reactor
state from the public domain or even on
online in using machine learning type
approach and after that you can try to
develop an attack okay and I'll give you
an example then if we have a few more
few minutes so if that's the case we
have to think of a different way or
different philosophy to protect these
systems and as again I stress that this
is to the class of systems that are very
well understood and very common and to
usually part of the a critical
infrastructure for many countries so the
main message obviously were safe there's
nothing going on everything is great so
as I said since we're already being
filmed here so this is second line of
defense okay if something goes wrong
then what what would you do so obviously
there's a lot of things in place already
and there's not imminent danger to to
this facility especially in the nuclear
field I can't speak about other fields
so give you a few seconds to read this
quickly it's so extremely robust
cybersecurity program that had been
installed over the past 10 years alright
so the official facts systems are safe
industry cybersecurity programs have
been implemented since 2008 and there's
a lot of coordination between the
government industry as well so there is
no reason to jump off your seat and
worry about this ok so the goal of this
definitely is not to give you some ideas
on how their actors can be can be
attacked or give you detailed recipes of
how to do it because in either way it's
it's not it's a lose-lose situation any
way you look at it so really think about
this as a way to serve us to provoke
your thought and think about how that
applies to your own system ok so as part
of the research we'll have to come up
with some recipes of how an attacker
would try to let's say just cause a
meltdown for example or cause what's
called a low CAX and a loss-of-coolant
accident but the goal is not really to
to share that with you but just say if
this happens is there a mathematical
approach that can be used to detect it
and you can apply this to your own
fields ok so the way we're using the
word cyber attack or using it very
loosely because obviously in in critical
infrastructures like nuclear reactors we
want to air-gap everything so we're not
really assuming that the attack is
coming from from the internet or from
from the cyberspace but it's mostly
probably gonna be something like Stuxnet
from an insider so again this is not
something that we are touching on how
how to how to do we're relying on
computer experts to help with that line
of defense ok
so in our context cyberattack is still
employed to note any type of intrusion
either direct virus by a USB hacking
on-site or some of these crazy
techniques that I've just heard about
like that extra filtration or maybe
social engineering
so all those could be ways to to ensure
the attack and you guys know that very
very well so this is obviously the
motivation how this topic became very
public news the one started with the
Stuxnet attack so there's no reason to
go over that so the idea is that we're
looking at scatter system anything
supervisory control in that acquisition
it's something that collects a lot of
data from sensors and then sends some
commands okay open up a valve close the
valve turn a pump on off etc okay so
this is an example for scatter system
for a nuclear power plant so this is
something where the energy is being
produced this is something what the
energy is being exchanged to generate
some steam and then eventually you turn
it into a turbine so as you can see
there are a lot of sensors throughout
the entire system okay and because the
system is very complex when you change
something somewhere it will have an
impact or footprint somewhere else
okay and the idea of model-based
defenses is if you can model that then
you can see how things are correlated so
if the attacker just is brute force in
introducing a brute force attack you can
easily detect that something is not
working correctly but the premise of our
research here is that the attacker has
the same schematic as this because this
is something in the open literature now
you'll be amazed by how many PhD theses
that were able to produce the operation
of reactor very very accurately we're
usually within a percent you know for
power distribution etcetera so it's it's
amazing amazing how these models have
evolved over the years
alright so the link to the computer sign
of thing is science of things is the
PLC's and and also used to send the
commands so the ultimate goal of this
research is to take these data analytics
techniques that will develop and put
them as a chip on on the PLC so it can
detect whether the traffic is being
compromised or not and issue some
corrective corrective actions and that's
the link to work
the computer science experts okay so the
just if I want to outline everything
that said so far with enough resources
persistent we're assuming that the data
can be hijacked and by data here I mean
the data that are being collected
routinely during operation okay so flow
rate measurements temperature
measurements flux measurements etc a lot
of levels like in any type of the type
of chemical plants there are usually a
lot of levels like different species
that you have to monitor if those level
deviate from certain range then you know
something is wrong so those are the data
we're assuming that the operator that
will be falsified and the operator won't
be able to see them with these data
hijack the adversary the main scientist
equipped with technical know-how on the
safety systems can potentially inflict
some some damage so this is again it's a
very key point to your key assumption
that we're assuming there is a lot of
technical know-how on the subject
elsewhere and we're looking for smart
ways to see if the system is being
manipulated
okay the assumptions were making the
information protection measures have
already been bypassed which is a big
assumption obviously there's a lot of
research on that but as I said you can
think of this as another line of defense
and the rogue data used to control the
system that are displayed to the
operator can be falsified that's also
another hurdle and so and it's an
example for a nuclear reactor some
examples like in core instrumentations
flow rate measurements levels water
levels etcetera etcetera and then
finally the control system will take
some commands so it has to send commands
to different units to take an action so
I'm assuming that this also can be done
on manipulated biases so in a reactor
for example we have something called
control rods that go insert it in the
core to slow down the chain reaction so
we're assuming that those also can can
can be manipulated and in current
designs most of these decisions are now
being digitized okay we're trying to
stay away from analog because they were
coming more obsolete so there's some
voices now that are saying maybe we
should stay analog to get away from this
problem you know so
all right so what is not available in
the public domain sufficiently accurate
models for commercial us actors do exist
in their acted in the public domain and
more importantly the accidents that
happen in any type of reactor have to be
reported okay all incidents that happen
have to be reported even if minor
instance so there's a daily report and
that engineers on site have to file
within RC Nuclear Regulatory Commission
and that comes online so you can access
it and as I said there are a lot of PhD
students that have modeled the systems
over the years and the information is
available you can always get it and
extensive literature exists on the types
of accidents that are there there are
still some proprietary details there's a
lot of correlations that empirical
usually correlations that appear and but
they're usually if an expert knows the
system they may not know then the values
of the parameters but they know the
general dependence of the model so the
premise here is that those unknown
parameters can be determined from online
monitoring and what's available to the
attacker the prop as I said the
proprietary details can be acquired
either somebody steals the data works in
a company or so meets people conferences
usually you know you have a good pretty
good idea about the ranges for this data
so you know most machine learning
schemes work very well if you have an
initial good guess of what the data are
so in principle those can be learned and
then the machine learning techniques
that the defender will use to find
patterns correlations etc those are all
public domain also and the attacker have
access to most of these technology as
well okay so I think I probably need to
keep the time check okay okay so the the
basic idea right now according to my
understanding when you try to detect
that there's an attack is the concept of
templates or templates matching for
viruses so you have some signatures for
the incoming attack and you always match
against that
so we actually do something similar from
a very high level I could see that there
it's very similar in nuclear industry
because what we do is we have a list of
accidents possible accidents that could
happen some smart people sat down and
thought of how things can go wrong and
then the vendor for this type of reactor
has to show how the reactor will respond
to these site types of accidents and if
you can convince the regulatory body
then that's a check you're good but
there's always a lot of in between cases
that could happen and an example for an
accident that of of this in between
conditions is the Three Mile Island that
happened in the late seventies so the
idea is if you have access to all these
records it's possible to come up with a
scenario that will not appear as a
design what's called the design basis
design basis access okay so we
definitely don't want to do this
template based approach so the idea is
instead of creating signatures for the
incoming traffic's we're thinking about
creating signatures for the entity that
we're trying to protect okay so you put
the burden basically on on the attacker
every reactor has been operating
differently if you just think about the
load follow of any type typical plant
and that's that's gonna vary from one
plant to the other so the way the
composition of the fuel and the system
will change the history of the the flow
rates the steam and water levels and
different components and system that all
will be different if specially if you
recorded over time so the idea is is it
possible to generate signatures for the
system itself rather than for the
incoming traffic so this way you're
putting the burden on the on the
attacker okay so I stress that the
attacker have access to all the machine
learning technology that's out there so
some of the initial ideas that came
about and in this field is you know you
use outlier anomaly detection techniques
but people quickly showed that you can
always falsify your data to be within
the range that doesn't trigger these
techniques then there's a lot of other
work that looks at correlation type
signatures as I said I showed you the
SCADA system
for all the measurements and they're all
correlated so you can use very rigorous
correlation techniques to look at how if
this guy goes up this has to go down and
some relative weights and proportions
you can detect that with simulation so
the attacker can also do that a lot of
dimension electric-type reduction
techniques like principal component
analysis SVD etc that instead of looking
at the entire domain you can look at
some first-order type behavior but I
argue that again the attacker can can do
this on the cloud so the threat scenario
is that we are thinking of I'll give it
to you from a very high level again no
details here if this is for example some
time dependence and this is some
response we're looking at let's say
we're looking at the water level and in
the steam generator for example that
takes the water heated water from the
from the core and produces steam so this
is what it should be looking like let's
say in response to some some event so
we're looking at two types of accidents
here you could have some initiating
event like as I said there are some
design basis accidents that we look for
like if a pipe breaks for example what
happens so that's an initiating event
then maybe we should expect the
temperature to rise according to that
shape okay so if something happens like
that that's maybe when the attacker will
start putting his signal after the
accident has initiated or they can
initiate the accident themselves by
turning down a valve partially or
closing it completely and let the system
respond on on its own so I look at the
types of accidents that can be initiated
there's these two different ways either
we initiate something you wait for
something normal to initiate and then
you change the reactor behavior after
that or you are the one who initiates
the the incident so I think you can skip
those two
so I want to give you an example here
this is an example for the time
dependence of the system okay so what we
typically do is we we have a lot of
measurements inside the core that give
us an idea about the power if the power
is going up and we want to keep it
constant then we have to insert some
control rods to keep the power down and
this is described by this set of
differential equations those
differential equations are well known
okay but the parameters that appear in
these equations are not they are going
to be specific to the system that you
are working with okay so the idea is if
the they have measurements for the P for
exampie here is the power level or the
flux level if you can wait line wait for
a long period of time like let's say
several months and just come take note
of all these data then you can learn all
the parameters that are in this system
via machine line okay so the basic
algorithm in this case is that you have
if n is the current time step and you
want to estimate the power for next time
step you collect the flux monitors at
both N and n plus 1 you estimate the
reactivity reactivity tells you if there
actor wants to increase in power or
decrease in power naturally by the
physics feedback and then you solve
these equations and there are standard
methods for for doing that it's called
ipk predictor corrector type methods and
then if their activity does not match
what comes from the simulation then you
take an issuing a command ok of this
simulation tells you the reactor wants
to go up but the measurements is they're
saying it's trying to go down then you
take a command to to make them
consistent okay so we took an example of
just a reactor in the in the literature
and the equations this is all the
equations that are associated with that
model and we developed some inverse
approach to to look for these parameters
ok assuming that we can track the
reactor break behavior for a few weeks
ok and this is what we see this is the
flux and that the operator will be able
to see okay you can keep it within the
range
of nolo behavior everything oscillates
due to noise and in these measurements
and while the real flux could be going
up raising the power by 20% which is
outside the normal range that's allowed
for these systems so this could be
happening just during normal operation
and if you can just increase the my
reactor power 10% more than what's
normally doing it will shut down maybe a
few months early and that will cause a
lot of losses financial losses okay so
our current work really is focused on
the first year of the current project is
on looking at these model-based defenses
if the engineers have access to these
models that describe industrial control
systems that are very well understood
could just a lie in wait period long
enough can allow you to learn the system
and if that's the case then we argue
that you should look for another
approach to to find signatures okay so I
think that's that's everything I have
motivated persistent and per series can
always learn the system if it's it's
already in the public domain and they
can change the reactor state to stay
outside the envelope safe operation so
we should be looking for more
sophisticated defense techniques and
again this is I don't think this is
special to nuclear power I don't know
about the physics of other systems but I
can guess and so I'm like to use this
opportunity to connect with people in
other engineering fields especially that
work with systems there are and open
wide literature and very good
description these systems out there in
the public domain and share some ideas
of what you would think we should be
doing to protect these systems thank you
you