after a short delay with fun setup of
video displays after it is my pleasure
to introduce Lotfi bend owed money I
hope I didn't butcher your name he's a
lecturer at Iowa State working in
different areas of secure software
development and he has traveled quite a
bit and come through a whole bunch of
different countries which was
interesting to read including the
Fraunhofer Institute for secure
information technology in Germany which
was very nice trade his research focuses
on empirical research in secure software
development development of secure
systems using an agile approach and
cyber easily connected vehicles and I'm
very interested to hear what he has to
say about what do you think so please
take it away thank you it is so what I
said
my name is Latvia Bennett man I'm with
Iowa State University I travelled quite
the word I think I went through three
continents so far and I am here so I I
came here to share with you my passion
for empirical research and hopefully
some probably of you will be I would
appreciate that so in this talk I'm
going to give examples from my research
on four roles that empirical research
can play in software security so the
first thing probably who actually did
not take course on soft on security so
far so all of you took course on
software security and one question that
you had it probably when it comes to
threat modeling is that we have I think
probably so far 60 method for threat
modeling you could see by this kind of
study by colleagues they did it at the
time and we got it from there slide when
I was at foreign however said so the
number of citations
or uses of this threat modeling approach
you have fault tree analysis you have
attack tree you have the MSS Dale Mike
refers tried misuse cases and for
default tree analysis you see for the
citation this is 2014 more than 1000
paper actually either they work it with
the approach extended and so on or
actually they apply it or probably they
cited somehow so we have a big number
and the question when you go to to work
with this in real context with this
method your first question which one I
am going to use obviously this simple
answer is it depends but that's good
that we have many methods that probably
also would help us to identify all the
potential threats might be however we
hear all the time about new threats that
comes to follow to the world I'll give
him an example this is one attack that
we got it about two years ago and this
is what we named it use of malicious
dependency in this kind of attack that
we identified you deploy your
application let's say to the cloud
specially to Nadia's
you use specific dependency but it's
possible that in one of the dependency
that you used it she changes the
behavior of another dependency that you
are using and that's potentially you did
not you do not realize that so that's a
new at least we were not aware about it
so simply how this is works
so you call for example for not years
you have the async library in your code
and the code the dependency that you are
using it's probably going only to give
you to change the colors for your
formatting for your HTML but in this
code there is few lines extra requires a
sink
it saves the method map in
variable this is JavaScript so you could
do it then there is a definition of the
map function and in this redefinition
there is a leak of the events so you
have the events that sink get which you
are using they will be leapt because you
have this leak method and then the
behavior continue because you call again
to apply the previous method so with
this redefinition of function now the
map that you are using is not the map of
the sink but actually in the new map
from the other dependency that you are
using if you did a review of the code
your sink is great it's not change it
you are fine but because the other
dependency changed the behavior so you
have this attack so my bottom line the
bottom line here is we have different
method let's say one of the cases for
software security we have different
method for threat modeling but we are
still discovering attacks more more and
more and more we discover attacks the
classic way for cyber security you have
problems we come with a set of solutions
we prove that these are solution our
grades --great and probably we develop
software and so on this is method one
there is another method so we've seen
with that for threat models with direct
60 times and we are still not did not
reach probably satisfactory situation a
second approach that would be collect
practical wisdom from expert you will be
graduating like the previous one like
myself and do you want you go to the
industry and you have real problems
there you gain experience what if we go
for all these kind of things that we
have we go to one of the things we go to
this experts we go to the facts experts
data and try to learn from there from
this wisdom so empirical research method
they are not in you they have been there
for social science they have been there
for education for medicine
so we have the qualitative study
probably you are aware about this so for
example the interviews the case study
this is for medical for example
observation so people they work you
observe how they do and you try to
derive rules there or common patterns
you have the mapping study mapping study
implies that there are study the top
talk about topic like now for example
let's say blockage chain and you want to
check what is this stage what are the
aspect that are studied in block chain
the other category for empirical
research is the quantitative study where
you have a quantification here like data
analytics you have probably
questionnaires and surveys you might
have experiment so you run things on
code and you bring data comment pattern
there are also four papers you do
systematic literature review you have a
criterion you wanna see how for example
mature specific field based on specific
criteria that you come up with so we
have a set of empirical research methods
those here set of this common one that
we use in software security and this
they have been used for other Sciences
we could use them also for software
security so I said I'm gonna share with
you four rows and the first role that
empirical research could play with
software security it could help us with
improve the maturity of the models the
techniques and processes that we use to
engineer secure software let's take the
case of risk estimation so for risk
estimation the common formula that we
use is the risk exposure equal to
impacts multiplied by likelihood so you
get the impact then you get the
likelihood thus will define your risk
exposure so the likelihood it's kind of
the attack potential how likely the
attack could happen multiplied by the
frequency how often is going to happen
let's say you could use this
you might come with different way but
this is kind of common so I would take
here for the connected car we have now
most of the cars they are connected
somehow you have Bluetooth you have
different devices and I'm going to say
what are the different threats that I
have and how likely how likely the
threats can happen and what is the
unpacked so you come and someone is
going the attack is going to flash the
firmware or here I would say this is the
likelihood the unpacked is low probably
probably not you might not agree with me
and the likelihood is no is low let's
say inject brake message the likelihood
this is probably is going to be possible
the impact is still probably I would say
probably low but there is another one
take control the likelihood is going to
be likely low and the unpacked is high
this is my perception you might agree
with it you might not I could give you
an argument ation that's my
argumentation for why I would say this
is low or high or I would show you why I
came to this conclusion so we bring this
this is Robert so he was here years ago
he's graduated from here and you work it
on this paper together so and we ask
what is the risks exposure of a threat
take control of a car so let's assume
that Raj says this is high risk I can't
say no this is low risk how did we come
up to this conclusion low or high and
the first question if two peoples they
come especially to experts they come to
you and you are working on let's say for
to develop something and one says this
is high one thing one says this is low
who should you believe so question who
should you believe this is actually the
one who is going to make the decision
this is that's what this comes to him so
and I heard a jump I would say if one
says it was high and one says low
go talk to each other and come with me
with the response something that makes
us so far it doesn't make sense
so let's we have as risks as I talked it
before for threat modeling we have many
methods and that's great because we have
different perspective on things
we have also for risk estimation
different methods so the OS they came
with their own factors for estimation
rescue estimation ISO 1840 1845 they
have also their own factors there among
other things in that standard the nest
830 they have also their own estimation
risk and the octave too they have their
own estimation method let's assume are
used for example the octave and karate
used a nist SP 830 everyone used his own
factors the factor that are defined in
this document for the estimation of risk
so now we know that we have already two
different ways to do estimation so we
have them here so I use the motifs the
means the opportunity what is the
motivation what are the means and what
are what is the opportunity to to do
that from the other side we've seen the
capability what are the resources
available from hardware from the scripts
and so on that you could use to perform
specific attacks and also the entrance
for doing that or not and the question
comes now whether you believe right or
you believe Lotfi now here you are going
to come to the point which factor should
I use we know that we are using
different methods and the question which
factor should I use we need to use the
same factor probably so we can get to an
agreement right so whom should you
believe comes to which estimate should
you use right so let's have now two two
estimation two threats
we're not going to use only one the
first one is remote update of ECU
firmware and here we have the likelihood
we have the impact the likelihood rod
says 13 I would say 30 how did we come
up with Vietnam
so we said low high and very high then
we we make scale if it's lower than zero
if it's higher than four then because
you have a set of factors you compute
these numbers so you do summation we're
gonna see that so we come with different
numbers we come with different
estimation low and high likelihood for
the falsification of speedometer reading
we come also for two different number 50
at 23:59 23 right he says this is really
very high and I will say this is medium
now the question is who to believe right
so we have an error in this estimation
and the common thing here I brought this
kind of from physics from physics the
document old document you have two ways
for to analyze your error you have one
is you use historical data you have
historical data and you gonna use that
to analyze what is your error and you
have the uncertainty approach where are
you going to measure the bound where the
true value lie and this it implies that
if you have an agreement then this is
most likely the true value if the
experts they agree for this case on
something on specific value for the risk
I would say that this is actually the
risk if they disagree then there is
something that is wrong the first
approach actually we do not we cannot
apply it because we do not have
historical data the day that we have
historical data that's probably the best
way to go because you have better
probably better foundation so we come to
the estimation and the uncertainty in
general its measured using the standard
deviation the regular mathematical
standard deviation thing we have here
for the simple case this is the simple
one where you have Z this is the
summation for factor X I then the the
the standard deviation for Z so you have
the square root of the summation for the
for the Delta X I square so if we get to
Delta Z that is a small small
uncertainty then there is an agreement
right since we said if this variation is
a small then people they agree if there
is a big variation then people they
disagree so a big uncertainty applied
disagreement it's a common thing that we
use it for other aspect for the
estimation of uncertainty so we got that
that's the approach now we jump which
factor we are going to use and let's say
here we had at some point a debate and
we said attacker capability is the
ability to access system resources to
exercise of threats this is actually
it's a good factor that has really it
impacts the risk estimation and we
should use it so we say you cannot use
the scripts you cannot use specific
hardware's you cannot use the
opportunity that you have unless you
have specific capability so and you have
a specific capability now we have to
come up with the likelihood for this
capability so you have now the
likelihood of the capability is how
likely potential attacker can have this
capability and you could have specific
factors for the estimation of likelihood
for capabilities such as how many
persons they have they are around to
estimate in that in that moment for
example to check the opportunity so we
identify for these attacks two simple
attacker capability one is local access
and one is remote access you might say
well remote access he can access my
Bluetooth or he can access we can access
it remotely using v2v or whatever so you
can go in details so we specify two
access capability one local access when
remote access and we give again the same
threats so this is not V this is right
so how likely is it to have remote
update office you a firmware so we say
for the local access if I have local
access to the car and I can plug it plug
my code in the obd2 probably I have
waste scripts and this is 27 percent is
likely and they would say 30 percent is
likely we come to the second thing that
we say falsification falsification of
speedometer reading but say if I have
local access it is very high I could do
it so and I would say yeah it's high but
still it's 30
but for remote access if I have remote
access it's gonna be more difficult so
it's 10 and they would say yes it's
going to be more difficult and risk is
low it's 15 so you have much work to do
and probably more hurdles to to do that
tag we see here that 27 and 30 they are
not far 50 and 30 they are not far if we
compare them to the previous value where
we have let's say 50 and we have 10 so
for the previous one we have different
exposure risk estimation exposure
estimation of the risk exposure and here
we have close one so we came and we
formulated this so a sense attacker
capability this is a condition to use
specific means and opportunity then you
have the set of factors that you have
for each a threat you identify the
capability that you have capability K
here and you want to identify the the P
so this is the potential of attack so
you have the factors but multiplied by
your likelihood for having that
capability then you come for your
potential attack it's going to be the
maximum of the potential of attacks
given the different capability so you're
going to get the maximum for all of them
for all the potential capability that
you have and the risk is going to be the
impact for that threat multiplied by the
attack potential multiplied by the
occurrence so this is kind of how we
compute
we compute the the attack so we came now
we had the idea on how to measure how to
identify this uncertainty we came with
one factor that we believe this is
should have an impact and actually it
had an impact in our opinion but still
we are too and whether the numbers that
we got they are arbitrary numbers
because we are excited about it or that
was kind of truth
so we can with hypothesis the
uncertainty in the attack potential when
considering attacker capability one is
equal to the uncertainty in the attack
potential when not considering the
attacker capability we said let's
consider now we have hypothesis and this
hypothesis says that the uncertainty
when we do not use the attacker
capability is the same as the put attack
potential when we consider when when we
consider the attack capability is equal
to the one when we do not consider the
attack ability so and the goal is to
prove that this is false whether we can
prove that this is false or not so if we
prove that this is false it implies that
attacker capability it has a value in
the risk estimation and we should
consider it as one of the factors so if
we cannot prove the opposite then we
cannot conclude based on this statement
right so we took the example of seven
threats for connected vehicles and we
send the information to expert that we
know they work on cyber security or they
have exposure to knowledge about attacks
to two cars connected cars we did that
in November 2013 so we did this example
so seven threats we got response from
nine expert the data it was complete and
at the date it was in 2013 so what we
found here is that the average
considering the attacker kept
of the uncertainty for the seventh rats
was 2.23 and the average were not
considering attacker capability was 5.20
so the 5.20 that uncertainty is as you
can see is higher than 2.23 but we can
see the value are different but whether
this difference is meaningful or not we
have to go to the inference with from
statistics and based on the t-test this
is 99 percent they are different and the
effect size another metric that we use
for statistics the effect size is 2
which is more than threshold we use 33
so this difference is of practical value
so since so we did it with two cases to
two studies like this so this is one we
had another one in the paper so
considering that occur capability with
this evidence is reduces the uncertainty
in the risk estimation so my suggestion
if you are going to do risk estimation
one of the things that you start looking
for is to see the attackers what are the
capability of the attackers from there
you start you should consider that as
one of the items that you use obviously
whether the hardware is available
whether the scripts are available
although we did not prove whether that
that's correct or not so you could might
consider them but the tagger community
should be the one is there others
probably that needs probably more
studies to do so that's one roll so one
roll is that we have a set of methods
and a set of techniques and software
security and a Pyrrhic research it helps
to mature these methods and these models
strugle going to the expert and bringing
some data there that would help to
improve them so that's good for what we
learn about method what we did for for
research but campus
helped me to address my everyday problem
I am in the company and they work on
software security can this empirical
research help me to work on my own
problems and they're all here the second
role which is also very classic is that
it allows to identify recommendation for
solving problems we take your example of
a study that we did it at IBM and this
is related to DevOps so at IBM they have
a system for business analytics
application and they develop projects
that for the business analytics so you
could see how things complicated
different infrastructure they have for
the analytics they have two tools here
software prediction Watson analytics or
SPSS they have their IBM information
server and a lot of things that they
could use to develop a new application
for business analytics based on the
demands the classic approach for
developing application is that you do
development you packages you make a
package then you get kind of a release
letters and that everything is in that
package and it's worth pushing to the
production and you get a set of
signature so you could push it to the
operation and the goal here is that if
we're gonna have a problems it's already
so we have we did a good analysis of
when before to push it to the production
and it's worth to push it and probably
they will be risk but we studied them in
advance so this happens in the release
letter so this is good have development
we have operation but very security a
tendency we have been working on agile
and this is kind of great but we finish
our zile on the end of the development
now we need to push it there are two
different processes if we combine the
development and the operation not Kjar
or not to combine them but
surely to connect them then we're going
to have an added value so from developed
from operation you could have feedback
and from development you could have you
could have collaboration one thing easy
thing is when you develop an application
and for security perspective you
probably gonna study it or prepare it
based on your development environment
but you know what you need it you need
it for the operation environment if you
have a problems you want them to go fast
to the development and come back to the
operations so we need that feedback loop
that would improve the way that how we
manage software based on a study and see
a technology so they did what are the
obstacle that are stopping company from
adopting this paradigm of having the
development and operation strong
communication there and at the top one
was security or compliance concerns and
this is with 28% difficult to justify
from an ROI standpoint 27% organization
complexity 27 so you have different
factors but the top is actually the
security and compliance concern if they
solve that then that helps to to do it
but actually what was the case for also
for this kind of application at IBM they
have a problem for security concerns and
the question that we have here is what
are the security aspect that should be
considered when automating the
development process the development and
deployment process remember we have a
development process you can hear you can
have continuous integration but when it
comes to the deployment those are
separate you have release notice there
so and the goal is that you can push
things from the development that can go
to the deployment in smooth way and the
question for that we post here is what
are the security aspect that we have and
we have that
there and we need to consider when
thinking about the Java process so we
studied their five projects one it was
automated already and for that our
manual processes and we interviewed nine
participants they were from the testing
developers on security project
management we had variation of roles so
we didn't we interviewed this this
participant so we have an interview then
the classic way for interviewing so you
have the interview you prepare you
select your participant you execute
semi-structured you have the interviews
you transcribe your interviews then out
of this transcription you quote them to
get meaningful information useful to
answer the question so once you have
those codes you have data extraction
then you classify them so to get the
aspect that you need and obviously you
will analyze the results so that you got
so one with when we did this analysis we
notified first item probably is not
related to security but it's related to
the manual process why they would go to
the to the DevOps so one of the criteria
is the lack of qualified personnel so
you might have you want to push to the
operation but the guy who is going to do
specific tests he is already on vacation
and you have probably to wait so if you
have manual then you might have lack of
qualified personnel at the time that you
need it and for example someone is
qualified and but he is on vacation you
have to wait there is the problem of
difficult collaboration so this is
mentioned 5 times in these interviews or
5 items that are related to difficult
collaboration there is the lack of good
documentation so we had also three items
that were mentioned
for the lack of documentation frequent a
human errors there is a lot of a lot of
errors when you have manual process and
obviously if you have error and you have
a process then if you expect your
application to be up it's not up on time
there is a lot of manual tests five
items related to manual tests this is
also problem for manual process there is
a lengthy deployment at some point they
wait one week until the first day of
full process is suited to have the
application up which is very long
especially if you want tomorrow to use
the application the customer what's the
more you use the application the
application is ready come on guys can I
use it now we are still working on the
deployment so lantee deployment three
times it was raised so you have a
problem now you probably cannot go and
justify your return on investment but
from security perspective this is our
main question what are the aspects that
we need to consider the first major
thing here is separation of duty we did
before study for the literature and
separation is use it was mentioned but
it was not really dominant for this
application
it was dominant that the interviewers
one of the main concern that they have
is separation of duty so the developer
should not be the one actually that
takes care of the operation or should
not be the one that takes care of the
security review the enforcement of
access control policy so if I am I am a
developers I might have access to the
database so I could fix my codes
depending on everything there but I
should not have access to those records
in operation right I shouldn't be
allowed so I can write with some data
specific ones to fix my code to write
the code but the operation one I
shouldn't so if there is a connection
between development and operation that
aspect of enforcement of access policy
should be there especially for this case
access through to data
the second the third aspect was the
manual security tests so we do lot of
pennies they do lot of penetration
testing things are manual if you want to
go for the automation you have problems
you have many manual tests that are not
automated they have also then made one
of the main concern is the audit when
they have applications before they push
them the production they go through the
audit and now they should consider the
audit - they have security guidelines so
they want to consider that these
security guidelines how they are applied
they should be in the automation process
automated process - how to manage
security issues and mitigation when
vulnerability they discover Berner
ability now how the process when you
have the development and operation
connected how things will work there is
also the security team they are
participating in the manual process and
there was a concern if you have an
automation for the four devil process
someone probably is going to push things
from development straight forward to put
to the operation and the security team
they will not be aware about that and
there was concern about about that so
those are several seven concerns that we
identified we're going to have a look
here for their separation of duty so you
could see here we have development team
we have basically the integration and
testing team a central team and we have
production team so you have the
application development of the
application they do lab tests and from
lab tests they go and they prepare their
packages once they prepare their
packages they give it to the integration
testing central team the IT ITC they
perform the tests then if they have so
they confirm the environment everything
is going to run on the product on their
environment and they push it to the
development again so
this is now it's ready so you could do
your testing user testing for the
development they do the tests they could
fix bugs if there are any issues so they
look there if everything there then they
provide the release sign-off so they
could push it to the production once
they have that release sign-off the I
t's the ITC they got the package they
got the release so they could push it to
the production they give it to the next
third team so the third team they could
work with the pushing things to the
production but they have also to get
that change management change management
request signed off so we see to the
minimum here big three three teams that
they work and separation of duty they
don't want someone who does development
to probably participate in the code that
is in the test environment if he is
going to do anything there then that
might compromise the numeric compromise
the other package so obviously we can
talk a lot about this separation of duty
and how things can go wrong but
basically this is this is the idea they
also identified for best practices for
the transformation to DevOps that based
on their experience from the first
project you need good documentation and
you need the logging so from development
activity you do good logging from
pushing to the test you have a good
blogging to push into production you
have a good logging in case of a
problems you can go back to identify if
you have anything that you need to do
you need strong collaboration and
communications so they have it all ready
for manual process they have hard time
for collaboration but if you want to
work on the verbs secure DevOps you need
strong collaboration and communication
the third obvious is the automation of
process and the fourth item
is the enforcement of separation of duty
so it's best practice to have an
enforcement of separation of duty so we
have now two roles we've seen from the
empirical research the first role is it
helps to mature the methods and the
techniques that we have for software
security the second role we could have
from practical point of view to study
problems and come up with the
recommendation from the expert so you go
to more people you bring that wisdom and
that wisdom you could use it so IBM the
last communication I have I think
probably two weeks ago they said that
they got those recommendation and they
implemented them for the other project
which is it was good useful for them so
the third rule this is a talk when I be
M this is IBM Germany so this is where I
was before so the role 3 is that we have
a lot of accepted truth and our
self-evident statement when we started
security there's a lot of several
professors that they have weight and
they come up with a statement and as a
student we got those statement and we
believe that those are truths and some
people they come later on with something
that we like it probably it's well
written and we use those are accepted
truth empirical research would allow
also to verify these accepted truth well
this is what we believe this correct and
we accept it as it is can we prove it
whether it's a true or actually it's not
so I give here example so our the first
role I give more detailed application
the second one also more detailed
example here for example there is one
one through with that probably when we
talk about the time to fix security
vulnerability whether this is a
cross-site scripting sequel injection or
authentication or whatever we would jump
and we say code complexity this is the
factor that is the most important that
what we should consider when we do the
estimation of the time to fix security
availability the answer actually is not
so we did a study in this study
it's on 2004 at SAT and we found I think
more than 50 factor and the one probably
one of the most important is the skills
of the developer how how good have they
have skills their skills to identify
these these vulnerability so that's also
very important so not only that you have
the the code complexity but but also the
skills and the experience of these of
the developers the type of vulnerability
and so on so this through that code
complexity this is the main factor that
you should consider for when saying that
you are going to fix this value fix this
variability in three days or in two
hours
you should also consider who actually is
going to do that how much experience
does he have or she has so the second
one is when we talk about agile
development we talk often that there is
a mismatch with software security and
this is kind of something people they
have it there is a mismatch we have
software security you need threat
modeling you need risk in InDesign and
you need implementation if you have a
change then your design is not correct
then you have to do things again from
scratch because for agile you are going
to iterate often so we might go with
this simplistic idea and jump there so
we did kind an analysis of the
literature what are the literature that
they are talking about how to apply
agile and software security and we come
that there are items that there are
problems that needs to be solved and
there are items that actually it's okay
the practices companies the users
already so because they avoid these
these problems or they have solved these
problems the third item is code
vulnerability vulnerability at the code
level they are the main software
security flaws so this is here we have
study four-for-one software's and card
but I refer here to the I Triple E cyber
security report top ten flaws and in
this report they would say the same
based on study that they got code from
big company there are as many
vulnerability at the design level
authentication authorization as you
would have also encode so it's not that
the code vulnerability that are most
frequent they are actually probably from
academia and so on people they report
this but the the design flaws they are
also very important from a publication
or from when we talk to colleagues on
dev ops or sector fobs
we report that the collaboration problem
between the developers and the operation
and actually the automation of the
process those are the main concerns
we've seen now for the study that I
showed that probably for the case of
ambient separation of duty is one of the
main concern it notified more than these
so this are kind of truth that we jump
we have on the talk that we say
collaboration automation this is really
what you need to solve and you could
have Dex that's a sec DevOps know for
the case of IBM it was the main thing is
the access control and separation of
duty those are the two items among the
top that they need to solve going if we
consider malware whether this is
software security or not we had also
studied in 2016 we got 1000 recent
malware and we try to see whether they
access the files they access the
registry they change the file system
they change the registry are they access
the network or not
so for each we give it about two minutes
to check whether this true or not this
is kind of also it's believed that when
you have malware they are going to
change the file system they are going to
change
the registry and they are going to use
the network and we found for most in
general so they did not exhibit this
behavior at least the recent one they
are not exhibiting this behavior they
are slow column they do not give you
much opportunity as it was before to
identify that they are behaving so we
have three now roles and the four role
is actually now what about if I have new
problems if I have new problems I could
jump myself and I could solve it but
empirical research they could help you
to explore techniques for solving the
problem so we take the case of
incremental development on software
security for the case of software's and
card this is an open source for
e-commerce so it's one of the main one
main open source for e-commerce used and
we took that the software and we studied
the vulnerability was that different
aspect from security perspective one of
the things that we did we did the
interview for the security lead so we
want to learn from him security aspect
that he has with a fourth and card so
that would help because this is
incremental incremental development - so
we got few first few remarks here that
needs to be considered when we talk
about incremental development the
changes of the security requirement of
the payment the payment current district
implies for their case complete
assessment for every two years there are
new version for the PA DSS this is for
the banking and the the payment for
every two years there is a new version
for every two years they stop the
development they spend about two months
to do the evaluation so that two months
is kind of 10% which is timely time lost
code the changes may imply security and
party security mechanism if you do
go change you might have your
authentication authorization broken and
that happens from time to time so you
have to be careful when you do code code
code changes if they change even the
framework that they use for the
application for example because the u.s.
PHP if they use a new version of the
framework or other label that they could
use this might imply that their security
mechanism they are not valid anymore and
they have several cases so they change
the framework not their own code and
some security mechanisms they don't work
the way that they need to based on so
his hunt over the code and for 50
comment change change that they
commented on because whenever they got
to change first thing is the main
developers they discussed the impact on
security or the impact of the change on
security they found that for every 50
comments one of them it concerns
security they have to be careful about
it if they do not its security broken so
those comments that we have we can see
that the change code changes they
potentially have impact on the security
of the software and they have to be
careful about it so we have a case now
what is the solution to give to work
with that problem so one simple solution
like the PA DSS is to do full
reassessment every two years you need to
do full reassessment you go to the code
review especially the money on manual
one penetration testing you have to do
them fool again there are solution
actually practical one practical one for
the for their case the first thing is
when they have a change they discuss the
impact of the change on the software
security so they have an evaluation
there in another company that we studied
so they do peer review of the changes
they have before at the end of each
sprint
everyone gets his code they sit together
and everyone gives through another
developers that they trust to go and
they to check what is the impact of the
code changes that they did on their
security and whether they have the near
ability there or not
that case was in Germany so hearing us
had one so far one company and we went
through them and what they do for
example they scan the code for keywords
so if you are using specific libraries
for cryptography and so on they would
scan this the code for those keywords
for the method that you have for the
label that you have if you touch these
things then you have security aspect
someone needs to verify so keywords this
is another approach another one is that
the developers they are the comment when
they do change
they are the comment there and they say
there is a potential impact of security
of this portion of code that implies the
code needs to be reviewed by security
expert so or actually they potentially
that is one of the solution is to add
the notation to the software so to say
that this related to authentication this
related to authorization once you have
this anotation
you could scan it and you know this is
authentication you have to be careful
about these methods so this kind of
existing now solution but this is from
people who deal with the problems how
actually they deal with it and the goal
at some point is to come up with a way
that should work practical way that
should work the default ways you do
reassessment for reassessment right so
this is one aspect that we are working
on before going further so it's nice we
have one almost now on time so we have
empirical research we could use them for
we have four roles we specified for
software security but there are
imitation for that and the limitation
for empirical study we call them threats
to validity threats to validity specific
way in which the study might be wrong so
things might go might be what we are
reporting is wrong if you refer on the
first study that I showed we talked
about the t-test but we also give the
effect size that's implies that this is
practical value from statistics this is
correct it's so possible that the study
you forget to do that or that probably
that value is not it's not good so you
cannot have conclusive results if you
choose also you have study then you did
not go through the participant that
represents the domain then you do not
have a good picture you if you say that
you have a good picture that's not true
but if you say that you have perspective
or specific people for specific case
then that would applies my questioning
here is how to assess the validity of an
empirical study I was gonna answer it
he's gonna get this book how to assess
the validity of empirical study
try you you benchmark it you bench those
different empirical studies about the
results of what happened from doing them
against real world situations you do
benchmarking against so this is the
first one and this is you identify your
question right how did how to find out
the theory and the practice you you have
to go back to reality and say okay the
empirical study really achieved a
success we were looking at go it has it
depends upon how you define success when
the empirical studies versus the normal
processes you used before I'm gonna give
here it's a good question so if you hear
I'm saying assess the validity if you
say success then implies that you apply
your own particular research again and
you check whether it's valid or not
that's the replication so if you have an
empirical study now how you assess what
are the limitation of this study if I
reform it how you assess that this
studied has a limitation specific
limitation in the study did you qualify
what you're looking at before you
started how did you say we're looking
we're focusing on these things which one
probably
I'm gonna make this question sir but
it's just a reflection on it we would
know that mathematical perspective is
something and when it comes to empirical
research you could prove that but here
it's different
would it be okay here if I did not say
that the effect size is though if I said
that the effect size was let's say is
0-2 would that be okay can I have a
conclusive result here can I claim this
result I cannot
that's from statistical perspective I
cannot conclude that so that's an
example so empirical research they are
not so one get it so we have a study
here about threat to validity when
chapter in the book so whoever wants to
get good answer can get this as a gift
for today so you have a lot of criteria
that you go to analyze your work and
your result and how you did things to
know what are the limitation of your
study empirical research all the time
they have limitation so far so whenever
we say things it's not as complete as if
you write to prove all the proofs also
you have Assumption right so with this I
would say that when we talk about
science or at least our hard science we
talk that we have causality and we have
repeatability we can repeat things but
when we talk about empirical research we
talk about observation on general of
patterns this is what we get and but we
have observation we have patterns it's
better than we do not have anything
right if better than we have only
opinions that that we use so but
observation should have to identify
causality and repeatability so if we
have a lot of patterns then we increase
our knowledge
potentially we can come to two causality
and we can come to to science so this is
the last slide for my presentation I
hope I convinced you about the value of
empirical research for software security
so I showed four rules here that we
worked on there are probably other roles
that empirical research could help with
and we could have better way for to
develop secure software so thank you
[Applause]
you