okay all right so I work for a company
called digital silence we're a Denver
Colorado based security consulting firm
I'm basically a senior security
assessment manager and co-founder there
used to work for a company called Gotham
digital science they have an office in
London so you might have heard them all
cease work for a defense contractor
called og systems probably haven't heard
of them basically little about me about
me I'm a red teamer
researcher knew dad was pretty cool I'm
a pretty interesting LinkedIn handle
it's Emma zero eight zero six seven but
yeah enough of that so this is a talk
about well it's mainly about attacking a
turtlenecks 2010 but before we go into
that we should probably go over just
kind of like how it would see that when
X itself works so what is 82 dot 1 X
it's an authentication protocol welcome
everyone and it's used to protect local
area networks and also Wireless local
area networks with rudimentary
authentication at the finest exchange
between three parties the supplicant
which is the client device that you're
connecting to the network the
Authenticator which is a network device
such as a switch that's providing access
to the network and you also have the
authentication server which the host
that's running triple-a software such as
Radiesse that is going to make all ten
occasion decisions you know what can and
cannot be able to access the network
that's usually sitting deeper inside the
network but communicates with the
Authenticator um you can think of the
Authenticator which once again is just
switch as a sort of gatekeeper or
security guard the supplicants gonna
connect to it provide it with
credentials and as well as identity the
Authenticator is going to afford these
credentials to the authentication server
but the finna cater itself actually
doesn't have any decision-making power
that's actually that's a role that's
assigned to the authentication server
once the authentication server receives
these credentials it's gonna validate
them and then make a final decision as
to whether or not this device can access
the network and the Authenticator is I'm
going to carry out that decision it into
an exit typically of four step sequence
so it's gonna start out with
initialization that initiation
negotiation which is basically a pina
goshi ation and finally we want to
authentication
ports have two states so if you have a
port that's protected by 802 that one X
you can either be authorized in which
traffic is unrestricted you can send
anything you want through that port or
unauthorized so it's unauthorized which
default State
traffic is restricted to only a 22.1 X
traffic
so he mentioned the first step of this
process is initialization initialization
basically what's happening is that the
supplicants gonna connect to the switch
port which is gonna start out as
disabled the Authenticator Sutekh gonna
detect this new connection and able to
switch port in the unauthorized state
and they're gonna move on to initiation
and basically what initiation means it
means you're initiating the
authentication process there either the
supplicant or the Authenticator can
start this if the supplicant starting
it's gonna start by sending the equal
start frame the Authenticator is gonna
respond with an EAP request at any frame
which is basically asking the supplicant
who are you so it's gonna basically
asking for its username the supplicants
gonna send a response at any frame we're
just gonna continue an identifier such
as a username and that's can be received
by the Authenticator which is going to
encapsulate it into something that the
radius server or the the authentication
server can understand it's gonna forward
it to the authentication server at that
point we transition to step 3
EAP negotiation so a long story short
able to tow an X is basically an
encapsulation of EAP extensible
authentication protocol for use on on
wired networks and also as we said in
some case on wireless networks so you
know there are many ways of implementing
EAP we're gonna talk a little a little
bit about that later but basically at
this stage what's gonna happen is that
the supplicant the authentication server
we're gonna haggle for a bit until they
decide on a basically both agree upon an
EAP method that they're both comfortable
with once that happens you move on to
step four which is authentication and we
mentioned that ap is kind of like you
can implement it a number of different
ways so the specific details about how
step four is gonna play out or depending
on the EAP method that we chose in the
last step however the important things
to remember here is that this process is
always going to result in either at EAP
success or AP failure message as you may
guess the AP success means that the
authentication attempt succeeded if we
have an EAP failure it means that have
failed so you know it's gonna happen
forget the EAP success messages the
port's gonna be set to unauthorized and
all traffic can flow through freely so
we've been talking a lot about EAP so we
should probably go over what that what
that's all about - if he stands for
extensible authentication protocol it's
really more of an aesthetic ation
framework it's not really a protocol
because it only defines message formats
and individual
aap implementations are known as EAP
methods so you can kind of think of it
as a black box box for performing
authentication you know that if you give
it a specific set of inputs you're gonna
get a 6 into the output switch either
you're gonna get on ten occasion success
or an authentication failure plus some
other stuff but the actual details are
really just kind of you know boiled down
to the specific implementation some
notable implementations or methods yet
PMD five big spoiler alert it's really
bad if you peep
it's another spoiler it's uh it's not
quite as bad but it's still pretty bad I
know it's just so but it looks delicious
so I just have to throw it in here
eap-tls
you know so traditionally you pee TLS is
one of these EP methods that has been
thought to be a lot better than the
other ones we just mentioned actually
that's true it's probably one of the the
more secure ones there wasn't released
some research released at Def Con last
year by a couple guys from sense post
I'm not sorry last month should I say
where they kind of kind of nuked that
assumption to some degree so yeah that's
that that kind of paradigms you know
changing a little bit but anyways that's
the AP I guess the next thing we got to
do before kind of gets the stuff where
the meat of what we're talking about
today is talk about just go over like a
brief history of wired for security and
essentially why we're doing this
research in the first place so the 802
double-neck standard came about in 2001
and the first version that was called a
toe to toe when X 2001 and it was
created to provide authentication for
local area networks fast forward you
know three years to 2004 and we have a
to doubt when X 2004 which added a whole
bunch of new stuff with a primary
intention of extending 82 no one
actually could use it over wireless
environments as well a year after that
in 2005 there's a researcher named Steve
Riley your demonstrator you could
actually bypass key to 1x 2004 by
inserting a hub directly between the sub
lock and the switch so essentially like
you have the switch and the the
workstation drivers connect into it you
put a hub on it you can snip traffic
which is pretty cool because it's a
passive bypass you could also interact
with network and limited agree you can
inject PDP packets although with Riley's
movement age DVD with TCP injection it
causes a race condition things starts
breaks he you couldn't really do that um
that was fixed in 2006 though which you
know basically like six years later and
and
so essentially two things happen in 2006
2006 I'm gonna say 2011 two really
interesting things happen in 2011 you
know the first thing that happened was
AB from Granville security create a tool
called Marvin implemented in Java it the
major breakthrough with Marvin was the
fact that you no longer had to rely on a
hub to bypass a 2.1 X instead you could
place a rogue device directly between a
sub look in the switch you'd have to
network interfaces and you'd plug one
into the the switch and one into the the
workstation you know the supplicant
device and you just bridge traffic use a
Linux bridge to kind of forward traffic
between these two interfaces and that
would allow you to passively you know
just kind of sit there on the network
and inspect traffic and additionally you
couldn't with with absent plantation you
could get full interaction with the
network using packet injection
later that year this look one those
cases where two researchers kind of came
up with like something very similar and
we're working in parallel didn't even
know it all the duct wall at least
something is only two not one X 2004
bypass that also use a transparent
bridge you know to kind of introduce the
the rogue device between the supplicant
switch but the cool thing about duct
walls implementation is it didn't
actually need packet injection because
he just used IP tables to create a
source NAT so that all traffic
originating from the rogue device it
would appear to be coming from the
supplicant so that was a much simpler
implementation it was all done in bash
you know and comparatively it took it
had a lot less that you could there's a
lot less setup so that's kind of like
the when people think of you know how to
bypass you did 2.1 X 2004 this is
usually what they think of we're gonna
go over that a little more later 2017
and hack in Paris so actually very
recently Valera in the grand period a
tool called Fenrir which works similarly
to duct walls tool but implements the
nabbing in python using escapee
because by this point duck host was
pretty old wasn't very you know it
wasn't maintained at the moment and
relied on you know kernel patches that
no longer existed so LeGrande kind of
fixed that you know threw it into a
module design with support for responder
and all kinds of other stuff so I think
whenever you're starting a new resource
project it's you know not only useful to
kind of try to understand the existing
work out there but also to see if you
can implement it yourself and even
improve upon it if there ways that that
you can so that a might let's look at
duck walls you know classic 82 that 1x
bypassed a little more closely
you mentioned use a transparent bridge
to silently introduce the road device
between the supplicant Authenticator and
network interactions achieved using IP
tables you to create a source net so the
traffic originating from the from the
road device appears to be coming from
the sub looking interesting problem that
the duct will had to face is you know
when you think about the situation in
the end if you're trying to bypass a 2 T
dot 1 X in in most cases you're going to
be an environment where you're not
supposed to be there this is the kind of
thing you have to do on a red team
assessment when you've broken into a
building and you actually need to like
plant something so presumably you're not
gonna have a lot of time to stick around
and and fiddle with this stuff you need
something that you can you can plug in
leave behind and then later have a way
of connecting back to this device
getting access to it and doing
everything else you need so it's
important to have a way of accessing
this device from or you know essentially
remotely so Dunkel has an answer to this
and we'll go into like a little why
we're going to why you had to do this a
little bit later but duxelles answer to
this well he did two things the first
thing he did was he uses destination
adding to create a hidden SSH service
that essentially you could you could
access you know from a very specific IP
address with a very specific you know
route set up you know etc if you were on
the internal network but also because
you can't guarantee the ability to
connect to a devices behind like nnat
and fire one all this stuff you also
implemented it so that you could you
could set up so that you have a outgoing
SSH tunnel that would allow you to
essentially it would give you a reverse
shell essentially that you can connect
back to the device and do this over you
know port 22 but you could do it over
anything really the other problem that
Dunkel had to face which is which was
kind of interesting to me is that when
duck walk created his original tool the
Linux kernel at the time would not
forward eople packets over a bridge and
and presumably for security reasons and
you know that's kind of what we're doing
to do this bypass in the first place so
what he did and what pretty much all
existing tools do to solve this problem
is to patch the Linux kernel so that you
know essentially there's you changed
some stuff and suddenly a Linux kernel
kernel will forward packets over the
bridge so you know existing tools either
do it that way or they rely on
high-level libraries such as KP we've
mentioned the Grands tool that does that
there's some
with these with these approaches you
know basically relying on Colonel
patches can become unwieldy you know
actually and the fact that they're no
publicly available Colonel patches
anymore that do this is testament to
that you know you figure what it's like
to try to maintain a patch that modifies
something from what the Colonel's
supposed to be doing you need to keep
updating that patch as the Linux kernel
continues to be updated over time you
know and and and people move on from
these tools so essentially if your tool
like you know if you're lying on a
kernel patch and you know development
the kernel suddenly starts to go this
way and something that existed in one
file now is in two or isn't somewhere
else the patch is gonna break and you
know your your tools and longer gonna
work
and the problem is relying on
higher-level tools that's escapee is
that it can actually make the bridge
kind of slow under heavy loads you won't
notice it at first but you know it will
you know in circumstances where you have
a high volume traffic create a
bottleneck and a bottleneck is a really
good way to get caught because you know
not only do you have the security guys
who knows this plague but now you have
like users complaining that their
network is slow and and then here come
the network admins looking for the
bottleneck and they find a little
sketchy box to plug into the network
that's a problem so fortunately The
Situation's actually dramatically
improved since duck well originally made
this his tool that did this as a 2012
ETL bridging is actually you can
actually enable it in the Linux kernels
not on by default but you can interact
with something called a profile system
which you can kind of think of it as
like a API for the Linux kernel for
changing configs on-the-fly it's
basically two files you modify the bots
that the values and the files to do that
but you can actually enable it using the
cross file system and what this means is
you don't have to rely on patching
anymore so I added that to my
implementation of this and just use the
profs file system so you don't have to
do pass the kernel anymore the other
thing they added was support for side
channel interaction we mentioned when
duck will created his original bypass he
had to figure out how to provide the
attacker with access to the rogue device
from a remote location this was back in
2011 stellar modems were pretty
unsophisticated they were slow they're
really expensive you couldn't just go
down to you know whatever your local
Ektron store and buy like a USB LTE
modem or you know that that wasn't like
really something that was available in
the commodity market so the solution you
know his solution was to create the
hiddenness
save service and rely on SSH there are
drawbacks to this approach though which
you know now that you know a few years
later we can actually mitigate you know
the the first problem is that it relies
on the assumption that egress filtering
is something that can be bypassed which
it's not always going to be something
you can rely on if you'd be outgoing
connection the other the other issue is
that relying on pushing traffic through
the target network is going to create
another opportunity for detection so the
updated implementation of this ID is
essentially Eliza I modified some of the
firewall rules in the original scripts
to give it to work so now you can add a
side channel interface whether a modem
you know some kind of like you know RF
device or whatever it does really matter
but you can you can actually control the
whole thing through a side channel
interface and not have to rely on going
through the target Network and maintain
control over your device so I'm just
gonna demo this really fast and I know
you can't see it on my own but my screen
is really really small for some reason
so if I mess this up please forgive me
okay so what you're gonna see here can
you guys see my mouse okay cool Wow the
mouse is totally different okay so in
the in the bottom right we have the
Authenticator the switch top right we
have the supplicant on the left we have
the attacker if you see this little
Ethernet cable that the yellow one on
the right that is connected to the
supplicant and that little green light
or should be green anyways blue green in
a second you can actually see it that
little green light right there
indicates that the that something is
currently both connected to the to that
port and you'll think it's currently
authenticated what you see here is this
device is paying out to the outer
network it's something outside the
network specifically Google's DNS server
and the reason why we're doing that is
just to show that this thing has
connectivity when we connect the rogue
device you're gonna notice that this
stops because it's gonna lose
connectivity briefly by the way if this
light turns off like you just see that
little green light turns yellow it means
authentication is currently in progress
if it turns off and stays off it means
that either nothing is connected to the
port or thinks that nothing is connect
to the port or authentication is failing
we trip port security has been
completely disabled so all right let me
actually try to run through this
whoa I feel like I'm playing helicopter
you know that little arcade game yeah
okay there we go so we're gonna run this
command and it's gonna create our bridge
and you see that we've lost connectivity
here from the supplicants perspective
but now that we create our bridge you
can actually this turned yellow because
the supplicants real authenticating
through our rogue device and now you
know we've real ten acade in the light
screen again so that's the that gives us
our passive bypass if you want the
active bypass you have to add the source
netting so you just run a second command
all those little flags that have data
and then you can actually sniff that
when you're in the passive bypass mode
we're gonna run the the active bypass by
reading source net and I'm gonna just
kind of fast-forward this little bit to
save time but once instead of doing that
you can actually interact with the
network so just demonstrated that works
it's gonna do a port scan bless you of
hosting the internal network you see it
works so that's that alright so all
these traditional a 2.1 x bypasses you
know the hub based one the injection
based one the bridge based bypasses they
all take advantage of the same
fundamental security issues that affect
it a 2.1 X 2004 and that is the protocol
does not provide encryption and the
protocol does not support authentication
on a packet by packet basis which is
kind of why it's Adamic 2010 was
developed it's the latest revision of
the protocol and it uses Mac sec to
provide layer 2 encryption on a hop by
hop basis and pack up iPad integrity
checks so this is pretty cool because
not only does the hop by hop encryption
help you protect against the bridge
based attacks but it also allows network
administrator's which means to inspect
data in transit because remember the
encryption is going hop-by-hop so if you
you know in between hops you can still
look at traffic the editor directly does
in protocol works in three stages
begin with authentication and master key
distribution and we have the session key
agreement and we move on to the such a
secure stage so the authentication stage
is basically just it in all intense
purposes it's pretty much a tenant when
X as we as we described for previously
you know you start have your initiation
your initialization your negotiation you
pick an AP method that works with
whatever you're doing and then you
perform
indication and if it's successful you
move on to stage two we have the session
create key ribbon which actually isn't
totally relevant to the bypass believe
it or not but we're gonna do later but
yeah simply during the session curry
agreement the important things that
happened here is that the the session
Keys get installed
well first you stop was the supplicant
can actually support max ik in the first
place and then you installed a you know
that relevant session keys on it and
then if all that succeeds you move on to
stage three was the session secure and
at this point everything is protected by
max sec or should i say like the lyric
encryption products spec and this is
ultimately we're trying to end up so i
think whenever you're trying to approach
like a challenge in terms of you know
finding way to attack a new technology
of some kind it's useful to look for
parallels between this you know this new
technology and also things that have
been either exploited or bypassed or or
compromised in the past so with that in
mind this particular clause and in the
in the I Triple E standard for a 2.1 X
2010 actually kind of stuck out of me
it's in Section 6.6 and you know
basically with this what this Clause is
alluding to is it there parallels
between the role that max Tech is
playing and the roles that similar
encryption kind of things are playing
with in 802 dot 11 which is you know
what used to implement wireless
communication and you know what kind of
took out of me is they must probably be
talking about WPA
and indeed there are parallels between
Max ik and WPA although perhaps not the
ones that they were intending to lose
you but you know when you think about
WPA it came out in 2003 that's when II
had WPA 1 they provided it also provided
hop-by-hop layer 2 encryption from the
access points of the station station
base station being your you know
whatever device you connect to the
wireless network
it was also providing authentication
using so WPA provides an authentication
using either EAP or pre-shared key as a
fallback or alternative you know there's
a major like kind of paradigm shift that
happened in the offensive security
community when WPA was released
excluding the being a whole slew of like
tkip based attacks which kind of ended
up getting mitigated by wpa2 at least
for a pretty long time injection based
attacks were no longer possible do the
layer 2 encryption that the strong layer
2 encryption being provided by WPA so
this kind of led to a focus
because you couldn't do the same style
of injections based attacks that worked
against web so you kind of had to do a
focus shift and focus on attacking the
authentication mechanism and in fact if
you look at the traditional ways that
you would breach a WPA Network you know
the first ifs of PSK network you have
the WPA handshake capture and subsequent
dictionary attack and that's attacking
at that occasion mechanism you also have
the row of AP attacks against vici AP
madness so you know fast forward a bit
to 2010 82 82 that one acts 2010's
released its providing hop-by-hop layer
2 encryption using Mac's hack this time
between either device to the switch or
from two switches you know from one
source to another but it also is
providing authentication using EAP or
PSK as a fallback or alternative which
comes here I'm going with this you know
with this bridge and injection based
attacks that used to work against
earlier versions of ADA 2x no longer
work so I guess the first thing that
kind of comes to mind is to try
attacking the authentication mechanism
and you know my this is pure conjecture
but I would assume that some dictionary
it would be at least worth exploring
some kind of dictionary attack against
the PSK variation I haven't really
really fully delved into doing that yet
so I can't really tell you one way or
the other but the other one that that's
kind of obvious is to you know try
attacks against weak EAP implementations
just the main takeaway of what we're
going to talk about to kind of
understand what we mean by attacks
against weak EAP no plantations we're
just gonna go over some attacks that
work within a wireless environment what
EAP is used or weak forms of EAP are
used you see this diagram here this is a
diagram of the EAP peep authentication
process
eep eep eep is an EAP method it's very
very closely related very similar to EPT
TLS which EPT CLS makes a little more
sense within an ADA 2.1 X 2010
environment so but they're close enough
together that you understand one you can
understand the other but the way eep eep
eep works is that you know first the
supplicant which is can the left which
in this case is a wireless device is
going to make an authentication request
it's going to make authentication
request to the authentication server the
authentication server it's going to
respond with an x.509 certificate and
the role that's x.509 certificate is to
prove to the supplicant that it is who
it says it is you know before before
this happens the supplicant really has
no idea what it's connecting to so the
the the fennec asian server has to prove
it
we trust it now the supplicant at this
point can choose to either accept or
reject a certificate if accepts the
certificate it means that it trusts the
authentication server it trusts who it
says it is and it feels safe indicate to
it if it rejects it this whole thing is
called off and and nothing further
happens so provided the the certificates
accepted and the onus has kind of placed
on the supplicant in some in a lot of
cases the user to accept or deny this
but if it's accepted you're gonna have
we're gonna move from the outer
authentication to the internal
dedication which is you know the next
stage of what we're showing here in
which a secure tunnel is established
between the supplicant and the
authentication server and then what
happens through that secure tunnel part
happens is that the actual like that the
meet of the authentication process you
know where we actually typing your
password and neck it's you know convert
it into a hash of that that gets sent to
the authentication server that happens
through that secure tunnel that we've
established the reason for that is
because and we'll talk about this more
toward the end of it with earlier
versions of earlier VAP methods that
didn't use a secure tunnel like that you
can actually sniff this whole process
offline so there are some issues with
this process Brad and Tony Woodson Josh
right back in 2008 they actually
demonstrated that you can use the rogue
access point attack to force the
supplicant to authenticate with the
robot than a casing server by rogue
access point attack what we mean is
there's a style of attack different
variations of one of the rogue ap attack
but the the I guess like the most
fundamental form that's kind of easy to
understand is the evil twin attack in
which essentially you create a clone of
the of the target access point with the
same network name as so long as you can
provide a better connection to these
client devices here they'll connect to
you and their couple ways of doing that
either
you know higher signal strength or
better single signal or simply by
spamming this one with the
authentication packets once you do that
you've essentially established a man in
the middle and remember that until this
whole process succeeds this essentially
is operating as an open network because
you need to authenticate before the WPA
protections kick in so what they figured
out was that you forced these devices to
connect to you and then you run your own
authentication server in the background
and they'll tena Kate with you and you
can capture in this case an MS chapter
to challenge and response which are
hashes that you can crack to obtain
credentials
did I make sense to everyone because
it's pretty fundamental so I just want
to make sure are we good at that
anyone not good at that okay awesome
right so to make this worse right like
what they also you know the thing is
like a few people so uses well okay so
we mentioned that yep Emily EAP complete
be implemented in any number of ways
right I mean there there's a ton of EAP
methods out there likewise when we talk
about the internal dedication that
happens through the secure tunnel over
here there are a number of ways you can
implement that mschap e2 is probably the
most widely used for EEP EEP EEP and EAP
TLS also one of the stronger ones I mean
what's cool - MS Chaffee - is it
actually does provide mutual
authentication which is which is pretty
interesting the problem is it's also
vulnerable to cryptographic weakness as
discovered back in 2012 by Moxie
Marlinspike and David Holton and
essentially what they figured out is
that the EMAs cheffy - challenge and
response is what you capture in order to
crack and and obtain passwords demos
traffic - challenger response can be
kind of converted to ntlm v1 which as
you may know can itself be reduced to a
single 56 bits of das encryption which
can be cracked really fast
this was back you know like six years
ago they were able to demonstrate that
you could crack and essentially had
passwords of arbitrary length within 24
hours 100% success rate using an FPGA
based crackling rig that they built now
granted you know back you know they're
rigged with a bill was $100,000 FPGA
based cracking rig so it was kind of
expensive however they did make it
public so they you know they kind of
knew the argument that well most people
couldn't have access to this so they
essentially said well you can use ours I
know actually I had the pleasure of
speaking with mr. Holten last summer and
he was telling me that the the that
hundred thousand dollar cracking rig
that or that bed cracking where they
built back to 2012 that cost him about a
hundred thousand dollars to build now
would probably cost anywhere between ten
and twenty thousand dollars to build so
that actually is a number that's much
more approachable in terms of what would
be affordable to like you know a
mid-grade
you know like criminal enterprise or at
least something you could find someone
to crack these hashes for you
so like it it's actually far more within
reach of that because the hard
to do this has gotten cheaper anyway
it's back to $82 next 2010 and why are
we talking about this stuff in the first
place okay so the main takeaway about 82
dot 1x 2010 from attackers perspective
is that it uses a ap to authenticate to
places to the network and that's all
well and good but it's remembered too
it's important remember that EAP is only
as secure as the EAP method used and if
we look at the the EAP methods that are
supported by attitude when X 2010
basically the only requirements are that
it supports the mutual authentication
that supports derivation of key is there
at least 128 bits in length and it's
able to generate an MS Cave at least 64
octaves and there plenty of commonly
seen week EAP methods that meet these
requirements including EPP EPP TLS so I
think you see where I'm going with this
so it makes sense now that you know we
should be able to use a similar attack
that what we used to defeat weak EAP
methods on the wireless environment
within a wired environment and I know
this slide says defeating Mac's accusing
rogue gateway attacks we're actually not
doing that where it should say defeating
a throw in X 2010 using rogue gateway
attacks because like you know what we're
about to do we're not actually going to
approach Mexico at all we're going to
avoid having to deal with Mac SEC by
attacking a sonication mechanism which
it's kind of sleazy but it it works so
the goal of a rogue gateway attack is to
force the supplicant to authenticate
with the attackers device and this is
happening our wired network once this
happens you capture has just cracked
them an authenticate directly with the
network the challenge here is gonna be
that you know we're no longer working
with wireless we can't just pluck
devices out of the sky and get them to
connect to us we have to be a little
more clever in terms of find work or not
as the case may be in terms of actually
getting this to happen but you can't use
the traditional row VIP attack good work
in a wireless environment with that said
you know if we look at 82 that - 2004
the bypasses that effect that they take
kind of man the middle style approach
you see we're inserting the device
directly between the Authenticator and
the supplicant in this case we can't
really do that so we're going to be
basically coming up with a way of
stealing credentials so we can attend to
keep directly with the switch so let's
talk about how we build a road device to
do that basically the platform that I
used was an intel milk running through
our 28 because for our 28 has support
for mac sack which is pretty cool you
know you'd want to give a two or three
interfaces a slide channel interface you
can control it an upstream interface
that's connected to the switch a fire
interface that's connected to the
supplicant i threw in a transparent
bridge they're just good it's useful to
have low it's not looking to be
applicable in this case but more on why
we have this let me apply this other
things but we need a way of diverting
traffic to the road device so if you
look at these these train tracks you
know we can imagine right you know
there's like a switch here and and when
the switches in the a position the
trains going to go directly into this
this this train station right here and
once in the B position it's gonna bypass
the train station entirely you can do
the same style of thing on with an
Ethernet wit Network you can buy a
little mechanical a B Ethernet splitters
off of Amazon for like five bucks each
they're wonderful you can take them
apart and do things to them but
essentially you click the a button on
one of these things and traffic will
flow into this little thing on the back
and out through the a port you click the
B button and it will switch it so the
traffic will be you know the two ports
that are connected here will be the the
kind of primary one back here and the B
port so a it goes one way B goes the
other way it's a mechanical
implementation you know it's not
affected by the the protections that
mitigate the bridging that we used
earlier the problem is it doesn't really
switch itself you know you can you can
buy one that switches itself but like
they're like a thousand bucks
so it's either just a build one but we
need a way of manipulating the push
twist you I recently tried using relays
but that led to like some pretty crazy
impedance issues because I'm not an
electrical engineer which probably
explains why if you buy a relay based
one online they're really expensive but
the I think that the more easily
reproducible option is to use solenoids
much anyways what I did basically the
solenoid is it's a linear it it's a
linear it basically creates linear
motion essentially you have a coil
that's wrapped around a rod and you know
when you run electricity through the
coil you either get like a like a like a
pushing motion if it's a push solenoid
or a pulling motion if it's a pull
solenoid so we essentially use push
solenoids to manipulate the switches and
allow us to switch this remotely and we
can control the solenoids with an
Arduino so like the final design of a
road device is actually gonna look like
this
it's what we saw before except now we
have a physical ABS footer on each side
so two of them and you know the one of
the left here is placed between the the
switch and our upstream interface now on
the right here is a place between the
finer face and the supplicant and what's
in the a position if you know the
splitters are bypassing the RO device
entirely we set up a land tap a passive
tap which essentially has a one
directional you know traffic can flow
out of it but not in if you look up a
throwing star land tap you'll see
exactly I'm talking about but we placed
that here when it's in bypass mode so we
can still sniff traffic and we just kind
of that gives us ability to listen to
traffic from drove device so if we if we
put the switches and you know if we if
we run the command to put the switches
in the B position now traffic is routed
directly to the device which puts our
device directly between the supplicant
and the switch so you can kind of go
back and forth like that so you know
with this voice how do we implement the
attack but what we do is we first you
know once we've started out in bypass
mode obviously but when we want to
perform the attack we bring down the
upstream interface the bridge interface
because we're not really using it and
and and leave the finder face up and we
start host EPA PD or listening on the
finer on the fire to face and we put
these these mechanical switches both in
mode B so what that's gonna do is that
it's gonna connect the switch the
Authenticator to this this network
interface which is not currently up from
the switches perspective nothing is
connected to it and you know from the
what the other one is going to be
basically from the supplicants
perspective the supplicant is going to
be connected to this fie interface which
is running this authentication server
and then we essentially force the
supplicant to authenticate we tell it to
really negate by sending it below I
actually did it was I sent a equal start
frame to hostapd which then sends the
request identity frame to the supplicant
but that forces authentication and at
that point it proceeds very much like
the attack against weak EVP methods that
we just talked about you know they've
indicates with you you crack the hashes
and you're done then at that point you
can just authenticate with the network
to
Klee you do this like late at night when
no one's in the office people probably
won't notice so to do that we leave
these splitters in the beep position you
bring you know you leave the bridge down
you bring down the finer face you bring
up the upstream interface with static IP
address that matches the one used by the
sublet can spoof the supplicants MAC
address then use the correct credentials
to authenticate directly with the switch
and then you're on the network so just
to demonstrate this really fast same
stuff as before although you see here we
have our like our little Frankenstein
device you can do this in a much smaller
package but just you know if you're
building something for the first time
it's used it's useful to have like large
parts to work with and also it for
demonstrative purposes it's easier we
have our four solenoids there that are
manipulating the splitters which we've
taken apart and integrated them into our
little board there it's not really
little but and it's controlled by the
surgeon we know down there but it same
deal and we're gonna run this command
and it's gonna implement the real
gateway tech and you can see these
things lighting up and you can see that
the solenoids kind of kicking in and
they're flipping those switches so that
our supplicant device is connected
directly to the switch or and I'm sorry
subway device is connected directly to
our Rogue rogue device and you see there
we're able to capture the hashes and you
could just use those to authenticate so
yep that's the attack gonna do it you
know it still sometimes we get to a
quick detour to some other stuff that
kind of worked on in conjunction with
this we're gonna talk quickly about Mac
filtering and Mac application
authentication bypass so a fun fact not
all devices support 8 a 2.1 X and that's
surprising right but not all the devices
for a 2.1 X and when this happens in a
lot of cases organizations need to be
able to deploy these device anyway so a
lot of like historically a lot of
multifunction printers IP cameras
peripheral devices like that they don't
have the same kind of attitude on the
next support that that you'd see with
you know things that could be more
centrally managed so this happens you
don't always have the option to just not
deploy this device
you still need to hook it up to the
network some house when this happens you
to create what's known as a port
security exception and you know
essentially port security exception
you're changing your typical port
security policies what this usually
means that you're disabling 802 dot 1x
on the port used by this device and
usually replacing it with natural Turing
or some other weak form of access
control and historically these have been
very prevalent due to widespread lack of
a tonight when I support by these by
these devices as we talked about it's
also presented historically it's kind of
been viewed as pretty low-hanging fruit
by attackers because it's um it's much
easier to try to actually to just find a
device that has been given a port
security exception and spoof of MAC
address then to actually have to bypass
a 22.1 X using a bridge or hub it's it's
much easier as much faster it's much you
know so that's kind of one of the first
things you'd look for rather than
actually trying to bypass from an actual
bypass the thing is though port security
exceptions are slowly dying slowly I
mean we're not there yet but it's low
there they are slowly dying the reason
for this is that 802 that when X support
by peripheral device manufacturers has
increased dramatically
legacy hardware's currently being phased
out and replaced by you know devices
actually do support it a 2.1 X you know
if you go online and look at like Newegg
or does any site that sells you know
enterprise like printers for example if
you go and look for different models
available pretty much every minute major
from manufacturer out there has it like
at least one brand that supports 802 dot
1x and falls within a price range that
could be you know within the purchasing
power of you know even like you know a
lot of small businesses let alone let
alone like an enterprise organization so
what this means is that as like the old
legacy hardware breaks it's gonna it's
probably gonna get replaced or will be
replaced over time with these 802 dot
nice capable models which sounds like a
good thing because you know it is making
these port security exceptions less
prevalent and it's and really it's it's
really becoming not quite the
low-hanging fruit that it used to be and
this is only kind of getting better
accepted improve adoption of either John
tax did not necessarily implies strong
poor security for all devices for a
couple of reasons the first reason and
and you know I can't really fault him
for this but heito 2.1 X 2010 support
it's not really reality after peripheral
devices it's only just starting to take
off
with everything else you know like the
you know like the top maybe like maybe
like you know two three four or five
biggest manufacturers of enterprise
networking hardware have max set capable
models but they're all like you know
they they're all toward the higher end
of what you can purchase you know so you
know even if it's and also it's
complicated to implement so essentially
like it's 2010 it's only just trying to
take off in general and you know it's
it's it's something that enters a
peripheral devices they're not even
close so they're all using essentially
that means they're all using a device to
does before and as we saw you can bypass
that pretty pretty easily using bridges
injections etc but suppose you don't
want to do that well the other
interesting thing is that you know it it
kind of if you think about it you can
expect adoption for security ap methods
to be significantly lower on peripheral
devices than for centrally manageable
devices such as domain joint devices and
the reason for that is that you know
adoption of secure AP methods is already
pretty low across the board so you know
an adoption of security PAP methods can
expect it to being lower for peripheral
devices that you can manage from
centralized location so what this means
is that you do have the option of using
the road gateway attack against 802 that
when X 2004 if you want to leverage it
against these devices I would play out
much the same way that the attack that
we just saw but instead of you having
the the switches you actually could just
if you're using the rogue gateway attack
against $82 X 2004 you don't need the
added hardware capabilities you can just
connect the Authenticator and the
supplicant to your upstream and finer
phases respectively and then use that
bridge the bridge base that approach
that we talked about to kind of you know
sit there silently in the middle looking
at traffic and then when you want to
perform the row gateway attack and
actually steal credentials you you as
before you bring down the upstream
interface bring down the bridge and
start a hostapd listening on the finer
face that will get the supplicant holden
authenticate with you and you able to
capture credentials that way or actually
you can track to get credentials so
that'll help you out in cases where the
you know these peripheral devices are
using eep-eep eep-eep it's it LS
something like that where you actually
have to use them at the middle attack
get hashes but actually interestingly
enough a lot of peripheral devices use
EAP md5 you know and and the reason for
this is so md5 it's a much older much
much older AP method it's not really
that secure but the thing is it's very
easy to set up and configure and still
better than Mac filtering so if you need
to set up a 2.1 X on your printer and a
pinch you can pretty much just use EAP
md5 and you know it's probably gonna
work and you're not gonna have to fight
with it too much and you can still say
that yes I think we were deploying 82
networks 802 dot 1x on everything we
have EAP md5 running on all the printers
but you know who cares right
so the way ap md5 works it's going to
start out with an EAP request identity
frame coming from the authentication
server that's it's asking the supplicant
to provide its username the supplicants
then going to I respond with an EAP
response at any of our it's gonna
provide that username the authentication
service I'm gonna do something
interesting it's going to basically
generate a random string characters and
it's gonna send these off to the send us
RAM string of characters the supplicant
as an EAP response at
ap challenges at request and it's gonna
send that to the to the sub looking the
supplicants can receive this random
string of characters concatenate it with
its username and password to make one
long string that's I'm gonna put through
the md5 hash function that the output of
the md5 hash function is then going to
get sent off to the authentication
server as an EAP response I'm
challenge-response and the
authentication server is then going to
do the exact same thing it's going to
take the supplicants fat you know
password username and also the the
challenge string that generated earlier
and put it through the the md5 hash
function itself and if the output of the
hash function is equivalent to the
challenge response to receive from the
supplicant then the authentication
server is going to issue an
authentication success and the
supplicants can be able to connect the
network otherwise it fails and it can't
so the problem with this
this was another once again this is this
was Brad Antonia Woodson Josh right if
you pointed this out
back in 2008 is this entire process is
happening over plain text which is
really bad because if you can snip
this this process you can capture the
username the the challenge and the
challenge response then use a dictionary
attack where you successively trot
successively try passwords to get those
all to line up and then you can use that
to obtain a password using the captured
data actually and actually that you
don't necessarily have to use a
dictionary attack anymore in 2012 fan
Belu and and taozi
they figured out how to you that you
could actually doesn't length recovery
taxes to be this long even more so
without of mind if we leverage what we
know about how to attack EAP md5 and
boat and EAP 2004 and kind of combine
them you know here's how we would
essentially be able to go from this or
you know from this should i say to being
able to passively significant n chose
and let me kind of go where back to the
slide we're at now you first set up the
bridge you use the bridge based approach
to place the road device between the
supplicant Authenticator and then at
this point you could just start sniffing
traffic you're then wait for the
supplicant ill attend a gate and then
snip the EAP md5 challenge in the EAP
md5 response as well as the username
when this happens you then crack the
credentials and connect to the network
as we talked about before the major
drawback to this approach is that we
have to wait for the supplicant URI
authenticate with the switch actually
this is not gonna happen unless the
supplicant I was unplugged realistically
disabling a virtual network interface
usually is not enough to make this
happen we could use mechanical splitters
as we did earlier to kind of like you
know disconnected and then reconnect it
remotely but you know the less overhead
the better so the alternative is to
actually use something that I've dubbed
the forestry authentication attack in
which we know how we talked about really
the first two steps of the EAP
authentication process are as follows
the supplicants going to Sony
authenticated equal star frame and then
the Authenticator is going to respond to
that with an EAP requested any frame we
talked about that how that's optional
and and this the fact that the first
step is optional has security
implications right you know presumably
the reason why it's optional is that the
Authenticator needs a way of getting the
Authenticator to re-authenticate
the problem is the supplicant has no way
of verifying if the incoming EAP
requested any frame has been sent in
response
an equal start frame so what this means
that we can force real dedication by
setting an equal start frame to the
Authenticator as if it came from the sub
working using max do you think miss
proofing the result is the Authenticator
will send any AP requests on any frame
to the actual supplicant kick-starting
the real indication process and when
this happens both the Authenticator and
supplicant believe that the other party
has initiated the real authentication
attempt so it's kind of blind there and
I'll be done like two minutes or so so
just to kind of demonstrate this here's
this thing in action it we're just
sending we're just spamming equal start
frames using escapee as forcing real
authentication so our revised approach
to to attacking AP md5 insistence
introduced the rogue device into the
network between the Authenticator and
the supplicant start the transparent
bridge and pass they sniff traffic then
you finally you forced a real dedication
by setting this proof people start for
him to the thinner care that forces real
dedication and then we capture and crack
the EAP challenge and a pond5 response
and then could just credentials it's a
very fast attack when this happens like
you just run it and we've already got
those hazards that we can then crack
alright proposed mitigation I don't
actually know and it's probably might be
way around this but the first thing
comes to mind is introduced safety bits
the EP requested any frame I guess you
can read the blog post you want know
more about that but just some closing
thoughts so just to go over what we've
you know that the main contributions
that we've got over today the first is
the row gateway attack which can be used
to bypass a 2.1 X 2010 in cases where we
KP methods are used and does that by
tackling the authentication process
itself rather than dealing with max sec
we've introduced updated and improved
existing attitude we've basically
updated improve the existing edited out
when X 2004 bypassed techniques and
packaged them and are really easy to use
and install tool called silent bridge
and also we've introduced the EAP
md5 force real dedication attack which
you know it's kind of simple but it
makes that you know the process of
attacking a PMD 5 a lot easier a lot
faster some key takeaways for Security's
still a very positive thing do not stop
using it just because of any of this
stuff that I'm talking about today but
it's not a substitute for later pros to
network security by any means you know
deploying into not 1x
doesn't absolve anyone from patch
management responsibilities but I'm
by stating the obvious here the other
key takeaways you know the benefits
provided by ATC 1x can be undermined due
to essentially the benefits provided by
eighty to the 1x 2010 can be undermined
in a lot of cases do the continued use
of VAP as an authentication mechanism
and you know not only actually it's
interesting if you guys following the
research that was released at Def Con
this year but there was some you really
attacks that released by a couple guys
from sense post that kind of further
make this you know actually probably
blend itself nicely to this so I haven't
looked into it yet but yeah that's you
you're still healing with the APS the
authentication opt indication mechanism
and you so you can still attack it in
the same ways you traditionally attack
the AP also improved you know and I
support by peripheral devices is largely
undermined by lack of support for 802
that was 2010 and lo adoptions for trace
for strongly ap methods if you want like
more in-depth information than what we
saw there's a white paper and blog that
you can see if that URL there and also
if you want to play around with this
stuff there's a tool on github and I've
got the URL for that there thank you