all right let's do it okay so we're
gonna talk about a title of that talk is
catch me if you can
if thermal butter us do you guys serious
yeah at the mics on yeah
is that better yeah you guys see me can
you guys see me yeah oh yeah cool all
right so it's part of our talk is catch
me if you can
ephemeral vulnerabilities in bug
brownies so my name is Michael Turner
arcus I'm CEO of asset note formerly I
was with spider labs in a g-pack I spoke
in a bunch of conferences so maybe
you'll see me from there mostly mobile
security I'm the organizer of a couple
of meetups and a conference in Australia
which is much less organized than 44 con
much more but yeah go Tuscon thanks man
oh sure so I'm the CTO of acid note I
used to work as a senior security
analyst at Bishop Fox I'm a part of a
hacker one top 50 and I'm the co-founder
of hackers helping hackers so you wanna
give a quick spiel for hackers helping
absolutely it's a really good charity
so Nathan and I co-founded a charity in
Australia where what we do is we take
money from a bunch of sponsors within
the InfoSec space and we redistribute it
to two hackers that actually need help
in education and getting into this
industry so students who have just
basically you know got into a point
where they have no idea how to break
into the industry we take them send them
to conferences pay for their flights and
accommodation and train them up
throughout a year so if you want to
check that out definitely do it and hit
us up if you want at any point cool all
right so what are ephemeral
vulnerabilities so put simply ephemeral
vulnerabilities vulnerabilities that
exist in an application system for a
short period of time right usually a
matter of hours or days so
straightforward yeah so why do they
exist why is this a problem
how common are they and what is the
impact and is this a real thing or we
just a couple of Ozzie wankers trying to
come up with fancy names the answer to
that hopefully is no well you you can be
the judge of that
ok just to set the scene take a step
back
let's start with bug bounties so a few
years ago there was a shift that
introduced a new form of security
assessment on a large scale bug bounties
but Benny platforms you know like
bugcrowd hacker one packaged up to this
sort of the internal bug bounty model
and prioritize it for many companies who
had it and in a lot of cases probably
wouldn't have run a bounty before and
the bug bounty model and and more
specifically the reward based economic
model that underpins it has kind of
shifted the behavior in the way that
people are testing applications if you
aren't successful you don't get paid
that's the kind of the approach and if
you approach bounties like a pen test
you won't be successful yeah at the very
least not on on any real scale and I
think and I think jobs will agree with
me it's absolutely fair to say that most
of the innovative techniques and tools
in web application space in recent years
have been borne out of the bug bounty
space so pennies not paying taxes yeah
so I'm essentially bounties are not pen
tests they differ in so many ways in a
pen test that's normally point in time
it's usually you know one to two weeks
it's tightly scoped it's typically a
static scope so you have a list of IP
ranges or subdomains that you were
explicitly allowed to go after and
nothing beyond that you pentest new
projects and then it's business as usual
it's performed in some sort of test
slash non production environment
something that's imply the QA or
something that's not actually having it
doesn't replicate the pure production
environment the standards and
methodology is you know it's driven on
it's focused on coverage and it usually
is compliance driven a lot of pen tests
are quite frankly done for a checkbox
alternatively on the flip side you've
got bug bounties where it's kind of the
opposite its ongoing it's typically
broader scope so there are although
there are limits it's evolving so every
time you're testing it things have
changed and and it's not point in time
your scope that you're going after has
changed from what it was yesterday and
then the day after and the day after day
after it's evolving very quickly and as
we hopefully demonstrate sometimes
involving on an hourly basis yes and in
bug bounties is performed in production
which is kind of scary for a lot of
people but I really do think that's the
best way to do security testing when
you're looking at something at that
scale and to find all the act
bugs its results-driven only pay and get
paid on results have to be first to get
that result and and this one's actually
super important because in my opinion I
think that bounties have you see a lot
more innovation and bounties because of
the fact that it is result driven people
aren't going to be making tools that
aren't going to be making them money in
bounties it that's a waste of their time
bounty hunters who do it full-time like
myself for some time Nathan and so forth
many other bounty hunters that do it
full-time you you can't invest your time
in creating tools and software if you're
not going to get a return from it
because that is your income and usually
it's security driven it's not as much of
a compliance focus so if you want to be
successful in about dspace you can't
just approach it like a pen test you
have to approach it like a competition
and you are competing with everyone else
to find new bugs that are actually but
actually have a security impact before
anyone else does and and in in this
sense when it comes to competition I
think it's super healthy because that is
what actually breeds the innovation in
our in our bug bounty industry so if
you're not first you don't get paid no
actual security impact don't get paid X
technology stopped you sucks to be you
you don't get paid for us if we're
spending time doing computer stuff
instead of drinking beer we want to be
paid for it essentially so getting paid
yeah so over to me yeah sure alright so
yeah we like getting paid to find bugs
but to get paid on any kind of decent
scale that replaces sitting on a data
center floor for eight hours a day you
need to take a different approach so you
need to cover all of the possible scope
if you miss something you're missing an
opportunity for a payer you need to be
fast there's no prizes for second place
in the bounty world if you're if you're
second that's great but it's a jus sucks
to be you it needs to be continuous if
you're not looking at things constantly
you will miss opportunities to be paid
you know everything the modern
application environments and and modern
tack surfaces are constantly evolving
and if you're not looking at this stuff
continuously you're going to miss those
opportunities
you need to adapt to how organizations
are actually developing their
applications and deploying the
infrastructure in the real world so all
of the protections that are in place
whatever technology is that they're
using you have to adapt to that as
opposed to just doing what you've always
done you need to keep up with it so yeah
automating it with an approach with that
sort of approach but down those sort of
principles the next challenge was to
scale so we built a tool that will
automatically find new assets in a given
scope check for bugs on a continuous
basis this is a tool that would
eventually form the genesis of astronaut
but that's another story come see us
later if you want to find out and by
continuous we mean performing all the
recon and security checks at least every
hour this works extremely well bugs were
found money was made alcohol was
consumed it's great but one of the
interesting things that came out of
building this tool is that shifting to a
more of a continuous security process
opposed to a point in time presented a
whole bunch of new opportunities that
started to emerge from that so shifting
the approach to a security assessment
from a point in time into a more
continuous approach ends up morphing
into into much more of a monitor and
respond approach and I can totally
testify against this I used to be a
tester he used to go through the
application find every app application
as a part of the scope go through each
one and take a look but but today it's
the other way around I want to now be
notified of what the things I should be
looking at what are the indicators what
are the things that are on this huge
scope that do deserve my time I want to
reduce the amount of time taken to find
a really good bugs so this this numb
this hand ended up having a number of
benefits it adapts to the organisation
and how they actually develop
applications so if I get notifications
about a new sub domain that this
organization is released you know in the
last hour or so I might be able to tell
depending on the previous subdomains and
so forth what they're working on or
what's new or what has changed you can
find bugs quickly and you can find all
instances of that bug across an
organization so if you have a really
good idea of where all of your assets
are located and you have some sort of
way of testing
a particular thing across all these
assets then that's actually you know not
only can that be used to test for
remediation like regressions but it can
also be used to test across a huge scope
very quickly to find quick results and
ultimately it leads to the ability to
find ephemeral vulnerabilities there's
no money left on the table so this photo
I put in a slide this is this is how
you'll often find sharks this is in the
taxi on the way from the airport here
and he really embodies this monitor and
respond approach any time there's a ping
from from our tools it's like straight
on the laptop doesn't matter where you
are so yeah so just to yeah I can do
this much cool so just to to kind of
visualize what we're talking about with
the thermal vulnerabilities and this
whole idea of continuous assessment to
take this kind of timeline right there's
an organization you know they've got
they do a bunch of vulnerability
assessments you know different points in
time you do a bunch of pen tests
different points in time you know and
along that scale you know things are
changing things are being developed and
then sort of in between is where you had
these sorts of ephemeral vulnerabilities
that you get because you're looking at
it all the way along the timeline as
opposed to just the points in time so
recourses of ephemeral vulnerabilities
so ephemeral vulnerabilities as a
concept isn't necessarily a unique or
new idea right and any bug can be
ephemeral that said if Fermin
vulnerabilities are in our experience at
least becoming more prevalent and you
can't really pinpoint a single root
cause based on looking for these bugs
but based on looking for these bugs
across a number of programs and
organizations there are actually a
number of elements that seem to be
driving this increased prevalence of
these sorts of issues so these elements
include cloud first architecture rapid
development deploy cycles like you know
devops is is you know becoming more of
the norm board attack surfaces so you
know having lots of externally facing
assets and large organizations that have
somewhat complicated internal structures
so I have multiple subsidiaries often in
different countries different
teams with that that have either
development capability or budget to get
things developed you know can can be
good indicators of you know where you're
gonna find the firm or fun abilities but
really ephemeral bugs are really just
mostly down to the pace of change
complexity and scale securing systems
that are constantly changing across a
large and complex attack service it's
hard right I mean we're gonna show you
some bugs today and you look at that and
think wow that's that's crazy but you
know these are very large organizations
it's really hard to do this at scale and
and even just keeping on top of what
assets you have on the Internet at any
kind of scale is a difficult challenge
even for very well-funded
teams let alone monitoring for security
issues at that scale and pace mistakes
happen people screw up you know
happens basically so the impact right
that's that's what matters the most
about all of this and the impact of
ephemeral vulnerabilities is usually
quite quite huge
the defining characteristic in is that
it happens in a short period of time
that their life but ephemeral
vulnerabilities is a short pier time of
their life that means that the impact of
these bugs vary because of the type of
honorable any type of vulnerability can
be ephemeral now that being said the
impact of these bugs tend to be pretty
high because they're short-lived in
nature and generally reflective of an
issue that shouldn't have been there in
the first place when they fix quickly
now like I hope that I can really
reiterate how important this is once I
show the bugs that we found because
these bugs definitely are critical and
they're definitely bugs that were only
there for short periods of time
companies don't tend to fix things that
have no real impact that quickly so to
help illustrate this we have some
examples and we've submitted and
submitted them to multiple bounty
programs they're all being paid quite a
bit of money that that's been resolved
for quite some time so we can talk about
them today we've got three examples to
show you two of them we can disclose
completely the company as well one of
them is slightly redacted these these
funds get paid out very well so
ephemeral issues are definitely things
that I think bug bounty hunters should
be looking for and before we go through
them I think it's worth pointing out
that all these companies that we've
worked with we're an absolute pleasure
to work with
we ended up resolving these issues quite
quite swiftly and we didn't have any
complications throughout so the first
bug the first bug I want to talk about
is evaluating AB script on uber so for
quite some time we knew about a
subdomain called exact target web - -
web.com and it always returned something
like this and I've seen this page a
thousand times and I've always been like
it's a Java Script expressjs application
but nothing seems to be on it I've done
heaps of content discovery work and I
still can't find anything so do I forget
about this asset well it was forgotten
and it was with them until we detected a
change and once we detected a change
it actually looks something like this
one day and that's a pretty dodgy
looking application already and if you
take a look at it it's got this iPhone
it's got this little message and all the
all the details that you know this this
whole thing is like alright I want to
send a message to someone and
personalize it so that's that's what I
picked up from looking at this page
initially this was served on the index
page instead of that that 404 not found
that I showed you earlier so now that we
we found this new functionality we have
to figure out where to go next
we tried interacting with the UI tried
making API calls while listening for
requests but it didn't work all the
requests failed a return an empty JSON
response so we then reverse the
JavaScript we recreated a legitimate API
call and finally swapped out all the
goober uu IDs which is essentially like
a unique ID that identifies you on the
uber platform with our own uu IDs
instead of the ones that were provided
on the front page that I showed earlier
and that worked and that that actually
led to something super awesome so I
won't explain what it led to
so the API was working and there was no
output received when running the the
example am script shown on the front
page of the app that example am script
well actually so let's learn how script
and you might be asking yourself like
what what the hell is a script what wTF
is a script so am script is actually a
part of Salesforce's marketing cloud
and they provide AM script as a
scripting language that they can embed
marketing content within emails SMS is
anything that needs to be dynamic so
what what can an script actually do
turns out it can do quite a lot so if
you take a look here there's quite a lot
of things you'd expect in basically any
scripting language
they've got HTTP functions encryption
functions data related functions all
sorts of things so let's try and use
Apps Script to to create I use the HTTP
functions within am script to see if we
get a call out just to confirm whether
or not this is actually a vulnerability
we need to care about so this was the
the syntax in AB script to make a HTTP
request to an arbitrary URL and it
worked we've got a response saying that
you know this you know this AB script
has been evaluated and we've got the
result of that which is basically a full
full response srf here you've got that
it's actually coming from ExactTarget
Inc now that was really interesting when
I saw this because that meant that the
script that I was sending through and
where it was getting evaluated it was
actually just getting evaluated on exact
target service not an uber service so
we've proved that we can execute our
script through the bar but it's being
executed on exact targets service and
and that's where it gets interesting is
like where do we how do we go further
and we found out that Salesforce
marketing cloud allows you to pull data
from a number of sources using something
called data extensions so daughter
extensions are like database tables that
can be accessed through AM scripts data
extension extension functions so this is
the app script that we saw returned by
the application itself it looks
something like this
it sets a first name by doing a lookup
in a daughter extension and then prints
that first name out when personalizing
the message so as you can see it does
like a lookup in that little data
extension called driver underscore
partners so even though this answered
query did not work it had enough
information for us that we could use it
to create our own am script that could
pull down data from the driver partners
data extension
so this was the final proof of concept
this proof of concept trust me was very
hard to write AB script I didn't even
know it existed until I found this bug
but this proof of concept is actually
quite simple it looks at the data
extension called driver underscore
partners and it does a search it does a
search for every one which has the first
name shoves based off that it assigns
some variables and then it finally
prints them out and to our surprise we
gave this a shot and it actually you
know it worked we got a list of users
that were registered on uber and a lot
of their details as long as their first
thing was jobs it printed it out so
essentially this one bug that you know
one day it was just a four or four with
no content whatsoever and then the next
day it turned into something this
critical you know that's because we were
testing the day before and then the day
after like we're continuously testing
we're finding these bugs in the gaps
where there's development cycles but
there's no security testing done there's
a lot of development happening because
as thousands of engineers pushing out
code to the cloud but there's still no
oversight on what's being pushed out at
all times or or even just nothing to
catch the gotchas like simple network
access control mistakes that often leads
to very critical vulnerabilities and
there's in this being a burrow right
they would be doing some kind of
security in development probably but at
the end of it like we spoke about before
with pen tests they'll probably be doing
a pen test before they deploy and then
you know doing sort of regular pen tests
but this was being actively developed
and this is why we saw it like it was
just as you saw it was nothing there and
then we were just monitoring it and it
changed so they it's sort of
demonstrating you about the value of
like looking and things continuously
okay cool so this is the one that was
rejected hopefully I do not ask you up
here but we'll see so breaking into
large US ecommerce companies ci so if we
set up large US ecommerce company into
our automated monitoring systems and
overnight it found the host HTTP Jenkins
TFS webhook dot e commerce company comm
and it was found to be running publicly
facing Jenkins's so it was overnight we
got out having breakfast showing the
morning looking at sort of Jenkins
machine
had a cursory kind of look but it
requires authentication and no really
serious bugs were found at the time but
you know we're going on going about our
business in the afternoon drinking you
know as we do and casually checking it
out and notice that they replace Jenkins
with the concourse C I a plication but
had not removed the DNS records for the
Jenkins - TFS webhook at blood comp so
most accounts registered on their
concourse CI were accessible without any
authentication and this was a very
recent change that was detected for the
asset within a couple of hours so so
again like this is the time that kind of
time scales were looking at and when you
continuously monitoring stuff and
continue looking at things you know you
start to be able to work at these time
scales and something to mention here is
that like the fact that they were
changing from Jenkins to concourse and
the fact that we found that there was no
authentication required I would dare say
that if I check that same concourse see
I am like a week's time they might have
actually set up authentication properly
I think what had happened is that we
found them in the act of changing C is
completely and they were working on that
but we had gotten to them before they
even implemented authentication cool so
once we logged in where I was view the
CI pipeline's here's some of the
examples here hopefully if anybody
recognizes anything don't say anything
please see a bunch of CI pipelines and
so in order to react with the server we
downloaded the fly CLI tool which you
can get from that URL to start
interacting with with the CI and this
allowed us most importantly to read the
config of existing builds and get access
to the docker registry so we logged in
using flying that's the command there
and yeah so pretty straightforward and
then the most critical vulnerability was
being able to read the config of
existing builds and that contained the
credentials to the docker registry which
hopefully all redacted they're just
checking bit nervous pretty emphatic not
to mention their name
so then we can log into the doctor
registry using those credentials that we
just found and get all these doctor
images pretty straight
yep and then using docker we decided to
pull down the payments resource and then
run the following commands started
exploring the container a little bit and
we found the mango mango file and in the
main dock go file it contained these
your cloud secret keys that were
hard-coded into the source which is here
hopefully redacted yes good we did
double-check but you know we've been
drinking for a bit so um so we were able
we're Australian come on like give us a
break how we were able to confirm that
the keys works using the following
command so log into Azure the keys were
actually valid keys and returned the
list of assets and we'd proven the keys
work and which is a critical
vulnerability obviously getting keys to
their is your environment and at this
point no further exploitation was
required and will pay fourteen thousand
dollars for the bugs so pretty great
good bug and the final one I think this
one's actually quite quite quite a cool
one actually it's also the reason why I
quit my job so it one of them one of the
reasons why why I quit my job in January
last year I was considering quitting my
job and going full-time to run a startup
and this was the bug that convinced me
that said look alright ephemeral issues
are valid continuous security is a valid
thing and I need to explore further so
it's about an exposed get repository on
slack that led to all of this source
code and the secrets being leaked so
just to set the scene 10th December 2016
we set up our automated monitoring
systems and we look at everything which
has an SSL cert related to slack and we
look at every you know we look at
reverse who has started to find domains
that are owned by slack - very simple
reconnaissance methods to find domains
that are owned by slack we add them all
into our own top automation systems and
these domains in particular looks
something like slack - reader comm slack
- files
calm and slack or calm to give you some
examples by using passive DNS data
sources our systems collected thousands
of subdomains but there weren't any
vulnerabilities that were picked up
immediately in December through
automation we kept on testing these some
things that we picked up we tested them
every hour of every day from 10th of
December until we finally found the
vulnerability that led to the critical
bottom so 14th of January 2017 for a
short period of time a git Reaper is
exposed which contains the source code
for slack's entire web application this
source code was 1.6 gigs it had over 300
secrets hard-coded within the source
code this is how it looked like QA 30
lakh - reader com / get / config now
what was interesting is that it wasn't
just QA 30 that was exhibiting this
behavior on 14th of January it was
actually around 10 to 15 different QA
subdomains that were ordered and numbers
like QA 20 to 30 that were exposing this
vulnerability and it seems as if what
had happened is someone who was doing
DevOps or setting up a new staging
application for slack's main web app had
cloned it to the web route but forgotten
about the git repo in the web root so
14th of January we we use this tool to
pull down this entire git repo it cloned
it successfully in its entirety and at
the time slacks config dot PHP file
contained the credentials from multiple
services including Dropbox Zendesk
Salesforce Google OAuth
twily a screen hero stripe Twitter or
Amazon AWS Braintree github asana help
Scout box wunderlist and possibly more
that's all there were 300 those days so
there were a lot of credentials there
and I feel really really sad for whoever
had to rotate all yeah we reported this
bug to slack why hack one as soon as we
confirm the findings and slack we were
very quick within hours to remove the
git repo from the library you'd hope so
so 23rd of January 2018 this issue's
result and we worked with them and they
responded fairly quickly helped sort it
out
of course they would but it's like
rotated all the credentials and fix the
issue and I I definitely don't envy the
guys who had to do that we were awarded
$10,000 for this Fogg Hikawa and this is
some of the sauce credit line that's how
so there's some of the keys in the
Sasuke just straight-out hard cut yeah
cool so some more examples one going it
won't go into as much depth but video
game company company runs a program that
for a time was paying out really well
for subdomain takers this obviously led
to people focusing on discovering
subdomain takeovers and after a while
this company got sick of paying out a
bunch of money for all these takeovers
and wrote a tool that would
automatically detect and fix subdomain
take of issues it's just great tool does
have did an awesome job at finding and
fixing these issues automatically I
believe it's open source right really
great tool except our continuous monie
tools were out we're finding the
subdomain takeovers faster than their
tool was fixing it by about a few hours
so like it's great that they did it but
you know again the kind of continuous
security monitoring it and getting that
speed you can pick those issues before
before they're fixed same video game
company so remember the photo of our
jobs in the taxi this is this bug so
when we landed yesterday in London we
reviewed our tools and notice that this
company had exposed a gitlab signup page
that may have allowed anyone to signup
to their internal get lab instance I say
may have because it was introduced found
and then fixed by the company while
we're on the flight over here so we so
we kind of missed it but even though
it's a long-ass flight from Australia
and it really is a long-ass flight um
that it was still only exposed for less
than 24 hours so had we not been on a
flight over here we probably would have
picked that up and hopefully that you
know we would have been able to make
some money from that but you know you
can sort of see now with like continuous
security assessment you can find and
capitalize on those issues so what can
you do about ephemeral vulnerabilities
so if federal bugs are mostly down to
pace of change complexity and scale
securing systems that are constantly
changing across large and complex
attacks services
is hard your automation really is the
key to helping mitigate these issues
there are many things that you can do on
the prevent side so you know baking
better automated security checks into
your development and deployment
processes but in reality doing that
effectively a scale is going to be quite
difficult and probably not going to stop
all the the issues realistically like
happens I use other kinds of
companies they were talking there they
spend lots of money on security
they have talented developers and you
know it's tough that's not to say that
you shouldn't try doing this and and
that's definitely good practice you
should be trying to do so from the
prevent side but really the more
realistic approach at scale is to
essentially minimize the level exposure
from these ephemeral vulnerabilities so
essentially you want to make them even
more ephemeral so having a strong handle
on your only facing assets is the first
step and critical to to helping to stop
these issues if you don't know what
you're trying to protect you won't be
able to protect them pretty fundamental
and then from there monitoring all your
assets for these types of issues
continuously so you can identify and
respond quickly as you identify them in
part and you know they pop up I don't
know it might seem a little bit like
whack-a-mole security but for ephemeral
issues on a large attack surface it's
often the most realistic approach to
minimizing the exposure and that's the
end any questions
[Music]