all right well welcome to track two
ladies and gentlemen
sorry for the delay on on the startup
and just when I get started with my talk
I have another apology to offer 20
minutes ago I RM my slides it's one of
those days where yes command-line
doesn't help you
you couldn't controls edit so these
slides that you see have been put
together in the last 17 minutes and then
I then I ran down however however the
demos work and we will be just note
padding and demoing the talk so at least
I've got everything working which is
good I hope the VM doesn't evaporate
while we while I present and and make me
look like a complete monkey all right
without much further ado let's let's get
this show going so my name is Sami Lucia
I apologize for screwing up the slides
what we going to talk about in this next
hour is basically my own research on arm
shellcode this is some part of it might
be new some part of it might be
repetitive but repetitive but this is
stuff that I have been playing around I
got it working and presentable enough
and this is the first time I'm giving
this talk off to a great start with the
slides being bought I will publish the
sides tomorrow for sure the code will be
uploaded on github it's just a bunch of
arm assembly files so with this being
said and done let me just give you an
idea about the gender I just start off
with a little bit of background about
arm shellcode which might be about 90
seconds long and then I'll talk about
the three areas that I have been working
on arm shellcode the first stage
I was working was on cache coherency but
this problem has been solved before in
several other in several other
techniques so what I'm going to focus
upon today is shellcode where space is
tight and you have really limited space
and some polyglot tricks that I've been
working upon why because I love
polyglots as you may have known from my
previous work I love to confuse file
formats I love to confuse instructions I
love to confuse scripts and I love to
confuse people so we're gonna see some
polyglot tricks the demos are all
working ok the first the first portion
of this talk will be about how to handle
shellcode when space is really tight ok
before that the the background stuff on
shellcode is kind of interesting it's
somewhat like rolling the clock back to
2008 10 years ago where x86 shellcode
was just maturing you had additions
contributed to the Metasploit framework
you had shellcode archives people are
cutting and pasting code and sometimes
they would backdoor themselves if the
kiddies don't know what they're doing
there was that fantastic Apache exploit
which actually added a backdoor route
into your own system things in the arm
space are like that there's not too much
work being done or not too much work
done in the shellcode space you can kind
of get by with the limited shellcode
that's available but the limited
shellcode I mean the classic exactly by
in shell reverse shell little bit of
stagers there is an arm meterpreter semi
working the challenge with arm shellcode
is it's not like the ARM architecture
especially MV 6 and 7 is not like intel
intel gives you a lot of luxury
you get unaligned memory access for fun
and profit you get cash synchronization
automatically done so you can have
self-modifying shellcode you can have
encoders and then decode the shellcode
on-the-fly
all that fun stuff works as is on Intel
not so much in arm things will work
things may not work things work on an b7
they don't work on our b6 and some
variants of our b7 don't work with
encoded or self-modifying shellcode so
there's a plethora of complexity when it
comes to running on shellcode on actual
hardware it'll run in QEMU but not not
on actual hardware so the overall goal
for all my shellcode research is try to
keep the shellcode nan modifying nan
self-modifying if we could modify the
shellcode in inflight then polymorphism
and all those tricks will be very easy
you just do shake at a guy or something
like that
so all this work is without having cells
modifying shellcode yeah so first thing
we're going to see is how do we go about
dealing with shellcode in tight spaces
the most common approach as we know from
the x86 world has been the egg hunter
and egg Hunter stuff has been around for
a long long time you kind of split up
your attack shellcode in two different
memory regions the memory region that is
delivered with the part of the memory
corruption exploit like a stack or flow
or a format string bug the shellcode
contained is very very compact it's like
a small string the egg hunter
code does nothing but searches all your
process memory pages up and down and it
looks for a pattern the pattern is
typically a four byte value of your
choice and this four byte value is
checked twice because first time the
four byte value can occur in different
places so if these two eggs appear
consecutive
then we can say that okay the rest of
the shellcode follows the egg so if
you're exploiting a web server you may
send the overflow in the URL and you may
send the large payload as a part of the
post content the URL may trigger a stack
overflow the shellcode may be lying on
the heap you need a way to somehow find
out where the shellcode is on the heap
because the other area where data is
loaded is not predictable and that's why
the egg hunter is important cause I will
go and scan through memory for
occurrences of these two eggs once it
finds them at any given location it will
Jen jump to the shellcode following it I
had animations and everything for this
trust but they're all gone so I wrote I
have to use the thousand words instead
of a single picture to deliver this
message right so the the main the main
workhorse component of the egg hunter is
a loop you're looking at page boundaries
now it may so happen that in your
virtual memory space some pages may not
be mapped so how do you get around it if
you try to like load memory from that
page you might sing for yourself so we
can't test memory pages from user space
virtual addresses you've got to go to
the kernel to test the memory pages and
the best way to do it is via Sisco so
you choose a syscall which doesn't kill
you don't choose exit or anything like
that because your code will aim but if
you choose a syscall which takes a
memory pointer and performs some non
destructive operation on it like check
for access or check for permissions or
something like that and if that memory
page is valid the syscall will return
you some value if it is not valid it
will say ìno mem or some other error but
it won't kill your code so every time
you check a page boundary go make a cyst
call if it is valid then scan through
the page for the egg if not go to the
next page boundaries
can through the page and so on and so
forth so this is how the this is how the
whole egg hunter used to work by
repeatedly checking each page boundary
with a Cisco and there were choices of
syscall spoon amanda escapes paper with
when they were building the Metasploit
2.0 framework they did a lot of work on
shell code and published some excellent
work so i am kind of standing on the
shoulders of giants over here i have not
really reinvented the egg hunter but
kind of adapted it to modern day
exploitation where i have run into
limitations with exploiting are my OT
hardware devices so the common problems
with the egg hunter the first major
common problem is data execution
prevention like let's say you have your
memory corruption layout where the egg
hunter is on the stack memory and the
real shell code is in the heap with data
see different prevention both these
memory regions are non-executable we
have a solution for that the solution is
rob chains we all know what rob chains
know they're they're these magic trick
stringy thingies and they will turn
stack memory or any memory that you
choose into executable memory I am NOT
going to drive into I'm Rob chains over
here I'll spare you the agony we will
straight away go to the application of
rock Rob chains but what Rob chains
won't solve everything for us let us
consider the same case where your code
is split across two regions your memory
corruption is in the stack your option
is in the stack when you apply the Rob
chain you need to be able to specify
which memory region you want to rwx or
you might allocate new memory and then
copy the code over there for fancy stuff
you need space but then we are out of
space over here so we have to have some
trick where even after the Rob chained
the memory region
where our shellcode resides must also be
turned executable so if the Rob chained
can help you apply our W X to the stack
and your shellcode is in the heap
somehow we also want the heap memory
containing a shellcode to be executable
for this I came up with a slightly
clever trick at best calling it the M
protect egg hunter
the trick is really simple remember I
told you about the syscall that is used
to test the memory pages well this is
the SIS called not only do you test the
memory pages but if it exists RW exited
everything so you kind of you know
painting the memory pages as you go
along and if you do it long enough a
large part of your virtual address space
might be just RW xed by the end of the
shellcode so this is a quick little demo
I will show you how this game works
right my cheat sheet
okay
so I'll show you two
Sorry Sorry
I'll show you two demos let me push up
the phones and see make it make it
legible
I have two programs over here to test
the stuff there is the first demo
program is called egg break and the
other is called egg victim let me show
the egg victim first so egg victim is
actually a really simple simple stunt
you have assimilated the shell code
being loaded in the heap with some
really really ugly string copy code just
allocating a variable and loading the
shell code and the egg over here is hack
hack repeated twice can you read this
all the way at the back or do you want
me to push up the fonts a little more
okay I can't see you all the way at the
back you oh good oh good very good
excellent it's just my eyesight is bad
not yours and then here you have the
here you have the classic stack overflow
function so when we overflow this this
code we're going to get memory
corruption of the stack whether
shellcode is in the heat and we need to
do something to jump to the code right
let me show you the first two the first
two attempts
so I have two attack vectors already
loaded I will show you the attack script
for the first one so the first one is
your classic stack overflow because the
memory is not executable we have to have
a rope chain so here's my impro tech
drop chain and once I also the buffer
I will invoke em protect and after em
protect I will then jump to the egg
hunter
the egg hunter will then go and find out
the shellcode that exists in the heap it
ends with this egg called hack this is
what it's going to search and then once
it finds it it's gonna transfer control
to it so this is the attack that we're
going to try out first let me show you
the attack the other program that I'm
gonna demo it on is called egg break
which is basically the same
vulnerability but instead of shell code
I have got I got breakpoints loaded over
here so we'll halt and we'll be able to
check the memory okay I'm going to run
this in the debugger first we will run
this we just run this sake first classic
overflow good enough you're going to
crash it we're going to get control of
the program counter we get control of
the stack memory and if we look at the
memory layout we notice that whoops if
we look at the memory layout from the
crash we notice that the stack is
readwrite and the heap is readwrite
there is no executable privileges
given to us we control them we control
the registers so yes we do have a
program counter in our control now when
we run the rob chain what we're going to
see is the stack memory is going to
become executable the heap will still
not be executable because M protec just
protects at one region and then we will
invoke the egg hunter and see how the
memory pages are marked executable and
and we will will then move to the other
demo so let me run this again this time
with just the Rob chained so here I'm
invoking the the the program with the
Rob chained as a payload we still get a
crash those of you in my class will
recognize PC equal to 48 48 48 48 is my
preferred crash point but at the moment
if we look at the process memory we do
notice that M protect has done its work
and applied rwx to the stack so the
stack is in our control thanks to the
memory corruption bug the heap is not
yet in our control like if you look at
the heap if I dumped the memory at the
heap
so here's my here's my egg sitting in
the heap this is the hack hack I will
dump it as a string so here is the egg
sitting over here at address 1 1 0 0 8
and if I check the page permissions of
that address it is still read right it
is not executable so if you jump here
you will spectacularly fail now let me
show the egg Hunter code so here's the
egg hunter shell code I'm going to be
publishing it the 800 code right now is
60 bytes long which is not ideally very
compact but is as compact as it could
make it with my limited knowledge of arm
assembly but I'm sure there's some
optimizations possible so here we start
with the main loop we invoke the M
protect sis call every time this is the
page sizes and this is the rwx
permissions and every time you invoke M
protect if it fails with a no ma'am that
means there is no page existing then you
kind of subtract it subtract 12 from it
go back to the loop increment it to the
next address the moment you exit this is
called loop you will be having a valid
page and from this valid page onwards
you can test whether the egg exists
twice and if the egg exists twice then
you simply jump to the code following
the egg I am NOT going to go into the
details of the arm assembly but that's
at a high level what it does now we will
switch over to let me look at the cheat
sheet again
so yeah now we're going to invoke the
we're gonna invoke the egg Hunter chain
not crash we're going to run egg break
again if everything works we will get
control to our shell code in the heap
and halt at the breakpoints so we run
the final shell code I mean the final
egg Hunter code and notice that we are
now crashing at these BK PT instructions
these are the breakpoints that we have
thrown in the contrast isn't very
favorable on the projector but these two
words that have highlighted they say
these are the letters hak hak which is
the egg so it went over there let me
show you the memory first so if I do a
if I do the attack string at one one
zero zero eight this is the pointer to
one one zero zero eight and we're
crashing at one one zero one zero so the
string at one one zero zero eight is
here's your egg hack hack and this is
the breakpoint sequence let's look at
the memory privileges now here's what
the egg hunter has done so after you
execute the hunter from the stack it
started at the top of the process memory
and started painting all the pages rwx
out of you excited of UX until it hit
the heap by this time the heap is
already executable now we can
straightaway jump to our shell code and
make it work so the last demo will be
the same one with the real shell code
exactly loaded into the heap and this
should give us
and you have a share okay so this is
half a successful talk right the second
half let's see how it goes all right
the only few points about the egg hunter
is it could have been a little shorter
but I wanted to make sure that there are
no null bites in the shell code and it
should run as is without much without
much modification again I will publish
this code on github just after I get the
slides and all working by the I mean by
tomorrow you should have all the stuff
and much better slides published okay so
with that done let us talk about the
polyglot stuff so here we saw the egg
hunter work with this trick with M
protect now let's look at the polyglot
now before we get into the arm polyglot
shellcode I want to preface this by
saying this is not like polymorphic
shellcode it's very different it's not
like I'm transforming the shellcode
arbitrarily to something else
there is no steganography nothing of the
sort going on but this is a polyglot
this is a polyglot technique with
instruction sets now a lot of work with
polyglot instructions has been done
before you can mix architectures like
x86 and PowerPC and SPARC and all and
there have been universal shell code
starters code that runs on x86 on spar
on PowerPC and automatically switches
you to the architecture independent of
prior knowledge of what your targets
gonna be this trick is somewhat like
that
but it's a it's a polyglot with in arm
itself now one of one of the common
things you're going to do as a shellcode
writer whenever you're dealing with a
shellcode is remember that arm always
has fixed with instructions 32 bits in
our mode but arm also has a smaller
subset of popularly known instruct used
instructions called the thumb mode where
a thumb is half the size of the arm not
really my thumb is much smaller but if I
had a very short time then thumb is the
size the half the size of that right I'm
sorry I just have jokes too a few not
proper slides so one of the things we
want as a shell co-author to do is we
want to write the shell code and compact
thumb mode for two purposes a it saves
size it's compact B we're free of bad
characters we don't have null bytes you
don't have problematic things tripping
us up and the commonly is known of the
commonly used instructions are still
available in thumb mode and that helps
us a lot so when you write shell code
the first thing you want to do is you
want to switch from arm mode to thumb
mode and this is usually a to buy trick
you add r1 equal to PC plus one branch
to r1 boom you are in thumb mode and
then the rest of the shell code follows
the thumb mode so this is what I'd been
teaching in class and sure enough three
years of teaching in class somebody is
gonna pipe up right right oh wait but I
can signature this the moment I hear the
word IDs or signatures and any any crap
like that I go deaf and I go mad like
this is ridiculous like we are doing
InfoSec for 20 years and all we depend
upon his very signatures and updates for
security something fundamentally wrong
here anyway I will not get into my rant
about signatures but whenever I see
signatures I am really motivated to
defeat them and not defeat them by just
obvious creating it I am going to
you feed them in style with a technique
that okay like yeah signature this here
here's a whole new class of approach and
good luck so exhilarating this that was
my motivation for stable sploit yeah I'm
going to put JavaScript attacks as
pixels on an image now tell me whether
this code is bad or good you know all
this technology depends upon is trying
to figure out the intent behind a piece
of data is it going to do bad or is
it able to do good now if I
transform the bad stuff into what looks
really good then you can't tell good and
bad apart and that's that's why all
these technologies fail so somebody
wrote yarra rules to detect this arm
thumb switch and catch him so of course
you have to go one up I have to go one
up so I I i did this technique the
second case was pointed to me by travis
Goodspeed that and sure enough there are
some processors especially cortex-m
processors which are pure thumb
processors so if i have a vulnerability
and i don't know which processor it's
running on it's running on an ARM
processor or it's running on a thumb
only processor i should be able to hit
it with the same shellcode which means
that you have one shell code which can
run the same way whether it started in
arm mode or whether it started in thumb
mode and this is where the polyglot
stunt comes in handy we will have a
series of instructions which will end up
landing you into thumb mode and then you
can put your regular shellcode at the
end of it thumb mode is the least common
denominator
every ARM processor will switch to thumb
but if it's an m' cortex-m then there's
only thumb mode available and another
goal for me was to write it for the
lowest common denominator of
architecture so no thumb to no wide
thumbs thumb to is like 32-bit thumb
mode is kind of counter intuitive it's
like two thumbs 16 plus 16 so
I started the research on this purely
upon impulse and intuition and then of
course it takes you then have to involve
some background knowledge of
instructions and such and a little bit
of lateral thinking and this with this I
will present to you my techniques on
universal mode half time thank you very
much
Universal Mode shellcode so basically
what the universal mode shellcode will
do is no matter how you start it it will
always land up in some mode it's like a
cat you throw it from the roof it lands
feet feet down I should come up with a
nice name maybe you can choose a name
for me and tweet it out I will adopt it
before a publisher to github so the rest
of the shell code is simple you can like
at the end of this series of
instructions you can tack on whatever
you want reverse shell exactly shell
whatever it is so I have a demo on this
I will show you the the construction of
the polyglot code for which I had all
the arm encoding slides which you know
where they are now gone burned but here
so what we need for the polyglot code is
first we need a very deep understanding
of how instruction encoding works on arm
and thumb mode fortunately these are
fixed with instructions arm is 32 bits
thumb is 16 bits a single arm
instruction can therefore be split into
two thumb instructions now we need to be
able to choose carefully what these what
the 32 bit value is which results into
two non-destructive thump instructions
for us
they shouldn't trip up our shellcode
what do we consider
destructive branches are destructive
loading from the memory is destructive
if you don't know the register you
loading from you might say fold yourself
writing back to the memory is
destructive some push pops not push
pause but load multiple store multiples
can be destructive so we want to avoid
all of those and then use only a few
thumb instructions to do the job for us
the benefit that our mode gives you
which is often overlooked in shellcode
is the power of conditional instructions
every armed instruction the first the
most significant four bits of an armed
instruction are conditional flags and if
a condition exists you can trigger the
instruction if the condition does not
exist the instruction becomes a lot and
simply falls through so what we want to
do is we want to lay out a series of
steps which will execute or fall through
depending upon instructions in our mode
but then when you cut them all up as
thumb mode they just fall through all of
them without disturbing us and it's it's
a it's a nice exercise which requires
luck and perseverance with this let me
give you the demo now large part of this
demo is going to be with notepad and I'm
sorry about that again I follow J's okay
so let's start with really really simple
shell code we'll do like an armed thumb
switch which is the basically the most
simplest of them all so here is code to
do an armed thumb switch and we push it
up a bit to make it clear this is
whenever you start your code let's say
you're starting in arm mode this
- these two instructions will switch you
to thumb mode and then these
instructions I haven't really added real
shellcode at the end of it but I'm just
setting our seven equal to eleven just
as a proof of concept and then breaking
so at the end of this code execution
you'll get our seven equals eleven now
let's see how this works I'm going to
single step through these instructions
so here are your instructions you have
the arm to thumb switch and the rest of
it is in thumb mode if we single step
the first notice that our mode of
execution is our mode the thumb flag is
off the second one the moment we do the
second one our thumb flag becomes on so
the switch has happened and now you'll
move seven into you move eleven into our
seven and crash so the end your crash
has our seven equal to 11 this is the
regular version all right now let's see
what happens when we when we object dump
this so I'm going to object dump
disassemble this code into both arm and
thumb mode so
the arm mode I mean this is the regular
disassembly where you see the switch and
it goes on if I force disassemble this
in thumb mode supposing the processor
started in thumb mode then you see how
this 32 bit value e 2 8 F 1 0 0 1 now
becomes 2 thumb instructions right over
here the first thumb instruction is kind
of okay it shifts the register doesn't
kill us the second one is a branch
that's going to ruin you the third one
over here so this BX instruction becomes
a monster it becomes like this vector
floating point instruction there's this
gonna kill us
all the BX instructions if we look at
the encoding have the second operand all
bits are set to high so this is always
BFF and if you now cut this word up into
thumb mode then all instructions FF
becomes something number two or
something crazy or something that'll
kill us so now as you as you play with
these instructions you're going to see
some restrictions being applied on
certain bit fields and we then go to
choose these bit fields carefully if I
run this in thumb mode it's going to die
so I do I do one test case and I will
show you what this test case is the test
case is Universal mode 1 dot this now
instead of two instructions ad + BX have
turned them into four instructions so
now I want to use the conditional bits
the top 16 bits should be a valid thumb
instruction the bottom 16 bits should be
a valid thumb instruction the top 16
bits in an arm instruction are
conditional bits and the opcode the
bottom 16 bits are registers and
operands I can choose the registers and
operands easily but the opcodes are kind
of tricky
I need the opcode so I'm going to use
the condition bits
to tweak the top four bits to be able to
get a valid instruction so and I'm using
a pair of instructions the conditions
are now complimentary so if you see that
ad has now become an ad if not equals
and a diffi quills one of them is always
going to trigger no matter what the
condition is
and the second one the branch became
move pc comma r1 move if not equals and
move if equals again one of them is
always going to trigger so it's either
going to be AC or BD in terms of
execution or what the conditions have
done is it's given me the power to craft
two valid AM instructions with these
bits let me show you how this works so
I'm going to object dump this normally
this is in regular arm mode so here are
four arm instructions and when we object
dump this in thumb mode yeah when we
object on this in thumb mode I will draw
parallels
so here's the object dump in armoire on
this side so this single instruction
here has now become these two
instructions over here so the add
instruction the add not equals now
becomes two arithmetic shift right
instructions the second add instruction
becomes an arithmetic shift right and a
logical shift left this is achieved by
tweaking these highlighted bytes thanks
to the conditional execution the problem
is with these move instructions we still
have I mean these are valid
thump instructions but these are thumb
two instructions these are wide and
instruction I don't want thumb two
because then that restricts me only to
our mv7 so let me show you how the
encoding goes this is this is where the
slides would have greatly helped so
here's the encoding if you if you look
at this add instruction it splits up
into the first four bytes our
conditional flags then the immediate
mode is 0 0 1 then the add part is from
this 0 1 0 0 that decodes to add the S
is the status update RS is the source
register so source register is hex is 16
which is a program counter the
destination register is 1 which is our 1
and this is the operand which is decimal
9 now this same instruction the single
instruction when you split it into two
thumbs you have an arithmetic shift
right so these these bits these 0 0 1 0
0 that are highlighted they become the
first 5 bits of the second instruction
which is arithmetic
shift right then this is like a full
shift 32 bits so it's equivalent to zero
the disassembler shows you 32 for some
reason and this is a shift our one with
our one itself so this one zero zero
nine becomes an arithmetic shift right
instruction the other one the one two 8f
the top half of this instruction up to
here that becomes another arithmetic
shift right instruction down there so
this is how you're going to cleverly
split it by controlling the condition
bits and the registers to be able to get
you to valid thumb instructions they
will mock up the registers but they
won't destroy the code execution you
want to lose something let's lose a
registers value that's okay and the
other one also becomes into two thumbs
similarly so then I kind of went ahead
with my wits with some more choices this
is going to give you this demo bit over
here so then you can try and play with
you can try and play with different
conditionals so I have ad CS and add CC
so Kerry said Kerry clear move Kerry
said Kerry clear so each of these
conditional Flags these are 60 these are
four bits so they can they can have 16
possible values and they will result in
two different one so I kept on trying
the first ones become end and the moves
also become NW I was trying to get rid
of this this high F over here and
finally I have Universal mode 3 which is
the winner
basically this end W will work as well
except that this will run only on arm v7
architectures this is non-destructive
this works quite well if you want to go
to on v6 or below then we cannot afford
to have wide thumb instructions and this
brings me to the last iteration of the
universe
shell called stub which is universal mod
3 so here I could not do the branch by
move PC comma some register so I had to
literally pull push a register and pop
it back into the program counter so the
register I'm using is r4 which will hold
the next PC relative address our 4 is
being pushed on the stack and being
popped into program counter now in our
mode you have something called a
register list this curly braces thingy
is a bit field containing which
registers are to be pushed or popped and
this is the last 16 bits of the
instruction so we have to choose
registers so that there are no null
bytes and they they don't conflict with
us the order of the registers is also
important you can only have registers
which are numerically increasing so with
a lot of tweaking I figured out that I
can push four values on the stack but
pop only three and that's good enough
and this is somehow if I pop the fourth
one then I got instructions which are
not very happy in thumb mode so this is
a lot of back-and-forth going on had to
play around with it so you have add you
have the move so I transfer the stack
pointer into r3 because I got to restore
it back otherwise my stack is going to
be completely screwed and then I push
the r3 and restore it back into the
stack push the r4 restore it into PC and
again you have these complimentary
conditions so again you have one three
five or two four or six happening this
is going to drop you into thumb mode no
matter what the architecture is and no
matter what mode you're starting in let
me show you the object dump then I will
have a small demo to prove that this
stunt works and then hopefully I survive
this talk as
oh wait yes did I do the whole thing
with that thing in the middle yes I did
nurse so I'll walk you through the
object dump in our mode so here's your
stub in our mode so our four is program
counter plus relative offset our three
stack pointer then you push them and pop
them back into our push our three or
four pop them into SPP see I had to have
r1 + r8 to avoid null bytes in the
resulting thump instructions and at the
end of this you should be into thumb
mode and this code should execute
normally let me force disassemble this
we force disassemble this into thumb
mode if you go to thumb mode it looks
quite different
so in thumb mode a single add
instruction over here is now transformed
into and and add then the next one is
also hand and move the third one is to
adds the the fourth one now becomes add
and move the fifth one
so the pushes become LS LS and subs I
also have the the encoding for the
pushes that I'm going to show you so
here is how the push instruction is
encoded to give you an example so pushes
these are data transfer instructions so
they are kind of complex the condition
bits are the first four bits then these
indicate 100 over here I mean 1 0 0
means it's load store instructions the
the P is for push or no sorry what is a
P for P is for something I forgot what
it is for you is up or down this is the
forward or reverse s is update the
status flag the bang is if you want to
write back to the base register and this
bit is load or store so if it's zero it
is store if it's 1 it is load so
basically these bits translate to push
that is store with the stack pointer and
this these bits and imply pop that is
load with the stack pointer so stack
pointer is this is the base
register which is the stack pointer are
at 13 yeah this is our 13 is a stack
pointer and this bit field is a 16-bit
register list the the bit field starts
from the least significant bit so if a
bit is on that corresponding register
will be populated so this is going to be
r1 r3 r4 + r8 this r8 had to be there
otherwise has a null byte that was
creeping up and that was damaging the
instruction and this other one is just
pop I am only popping three and these
they get decoded to a shift instruction
and a subtract instruction the other one
the pop gets transformed to an add
instruction and a subtract instruction
so there you have to play a lot with
this encoding stuff and then once you
get it right hopefully this stuff should
work okay so as far as the demo goes I
have a test case
so has a universal test arm dot s this
is basically just starting off in our
mode these instructions will drop you to
thumb mode which is kind of obvious
because that's what they are I have just
placed them as arbitrary shell code for
a test but let me show you the thumb
test which will be more interesting so
what I'm going to do is in this test I
will forcibly switch to thermode and
then invoke these same instructions but
the code is compiled as code 16 which is
this will be forcibly assembled as thumb
mode and just laying these out as as
literals now what it should do is all
these little should switch you to thumb
mode while being in thumb mode keep you
in thumb mode sorry and then you will X
or R 2 and set R 7 equal to 11 okay bro
gdb Universal test thumb break start so
here we will switch to thumb mode after
the first two instructions say step 2
and so after a step 2 we are now in
thumb mode and the add CS move CS and
the pushes have now been transformed to
a series of and add moves and all these
so if I keep let's let me skip four
instructions at a time so step through
four instruction at a time so the first
four went through no problem the next
four will go through and the last four
will go through there's this more
yeah the last four are now remaining
over here so if this is non-destructive
all good now we are at or our proof of
concept code we're still in some mode
and if we if we finish up we will get
the register - which is zeroed out and
our seven is set to Allah so you start
in our mode you drop two thermode you
start in thumb mode you stay in thumb
mode the code doesn't change now this is
a I mean this is like one iteration or
one turn out of the of the code sequence
you can use your imagination you can use
your fluency with assembly conditional
execution and play with op codes and get
like a large set of polyglot sequences
to then drop you into thumb mode so to
the Yara rule-makers a signature that so
this kind of brings it to the end again
I apologize for the slides they will be
published tomorrow and the code will be
pushed on github you can play with it if
you find any additional stuff this is I
know this room has more arm experts and
me who played with a lot of stuff please
let me know it would be great to improve
the shell code and collaborate or you
can fork it or merge it back it'll be
it'll be a pleasure to work with you on
this ideas are most welcome I will be
tweeting tomorrow and the slides are up
so with this thank you very much thanks
for putting up with my semi broken talk
and enjoy 44 corn and there's a bus full
of gin waiting outside
[Applause]
[Music]