we use the sacrament meeting so I have
no idea how to do how to join a meeting
[Music]
that's the rule
hi we need somebody to take minutes just
record actions and somebody to be the
jabber scribe for the 6-8 people that
are currently in the jabber room at
least to our remote any volunteers
obviously we can't start until we get
those volunteers and yo points out that
our agenda has shrunk so we have about
20 minutes free time so we can just sit
here waiting for two people of our
volunteer for nearly half an hour if
that's what it takes
thank you Matt
is that someone know who shoots and the
blue sheets are going around
yes thanks oh come on it's only the
first session of the week you can't all
be burnt out on volunteering for a
minute I know you
right so it's one of the stressor people
have to leave we want to get their input
here updates if somebody please
volunteer to take the minutes well you
can take the minutes and then leave and
then we'll be stuck again right Thank
You Robin
yep okay thank you Robin everybody yes
okay close the doors let's get sorted
okay welcome to the acne session here at
IDF 105 in Montreal mm-hmm I'm sure
you've seen this but this is the first
time you've seen it this week so it
hasn't changed much on the agenda today
obvious gender bashing administrivia
that's the streets going around and
finding scribes and mayor takers and the
note well which we have already seen
then we're going to do in status update
I'm gonna get update on telephony with
no slides from John and we had planned
to have a presentation about TLS LPN but
since neither Rowland nor Jacob are in
or in Montreal and they haven't sent
slides jacob is
the jabber room so yeah we'll include it
in their plate unless Jacob wants to hop
in from remote and then start allegation
Acme integration from Alexi about email
and you know then two things from
Kathleen any agenda bashing ok on to
status so we have new versions of the
telephony and the s/mime drafts the star
delegation was allowed to expire but
okay but we might be reviving it now and
I've seen that I wrote that twice yeah
[Music]
acne AP and the TLS LPN or in is G
processing there we need a revision of
TLS al PN which should be this week
anyone want to jump to the mic and say
something about that Jacob yes so to
summarize with acne IPD I mean it's
ready to go
I've just been holding to because I
wanted to batch together that document
with TLS you know because they're so
interrelated my kind of my remaining
points on on a opiate novelist and I
think there's one outstanding one from a
group so we can close that one plus the
minor ones I added weekend advances that
was Roman didn't he speak moments Rab
matthew miller echoing for Jacob he does
believe ruin will get to this week and
he'll bug him when he gets back vacation
today cool
so also acne star is an ITF last call
which is why start allegation is and now
revitalizing and CA is best is G
processing so it's now in the RFC
attackers queue hopefully we'll get an
RFC by next ITF so this is just to
finesse together the exact word and back
to the third bullet acne uh pls a that's
actually still with me we have not
advanced that you the whole is G okay
anything else about the updates good so
next are the presentations and looking
back at the agenda first up is John with
telephony update
oh and no slides so you don't get last
year so it's not like we have something
particularly new to present at this
point
that's hardly because actually changes
that we're still contemplating these
faster president at this point our thing
is that have yeah versions pendency
these are decisions that were still kind
of rolling over in the storica group I
just be an example of one of these we
have this thing that's in Mersin TP from
six that's called JWT constraints and
this gets really into no we were just up
in aster uses these certain and
passports right passports
basic idea negative constrains Jones you
just took the mic no it's Mike
the switch maybe yeah okay that's a
switch
oh look at the hand that's pretty fancy
I can hear the sound of my own voice so
yeah like I said this is kind of in the
weeds of stir but like we have these
passports that are getting signed by
these certificates and these are j2 80
based tokens and so we have this concept
in RC 82 26 of having a JWT constraints
element and what this means on the cert
is basically it can dictate which JDO ET
claims you're allowed to insert into one
of these tokens and it kind of occurred
to us it might be handy actually have
the token authority be able to issue
those constraints when you know someone
is trying to get a passport I trying to
get a certificate back mean so as a
consequence of that we're still kind of
mulling that there's a particular use
case for it that's associated with our
rich call display draft our CD but our
CD is kind of still in flux at the
moment once I think we know where we're
gonna land on that we'll be able to
decide whether we want this JWT
constraints actually be part of the ATC
that we have developed here in the Acme
working group or not and so you know
that that's pending otherwise I think
these graphs are in pretty good shape at
this point and so yeah well we'll be
back with that we may do that like later
this week just bang this out and put a
new version into the repository the
issue is stir is like in you know 40
minutes and so we kind of want to see
what's gonna happen there and then then
we'll make a decision about that so
that's where we are any questions
comments thoughts well I just think that
great if after this term meeting you can
send a message to the list saying where
we are on this okay okay thank you so
next one who
the delegation is Diego in the room yes
good okay this is this is a draft that
was created some time ago just a little
bit of history it was created some time
ago was a semi we split my request of
the of the group we played the original
star mechanism into star only which is
about the request and the way in which
searching the identity owner could
delegate they use it because thinking of
the scenario of typical scenario of a
CDN the idea that we split 80 at the
document into to start this went on its
way and is close to be published and the
case of the delegation was part of
another of another document that
originally the group asked us to to go
to sec dispatch to see whether this is
something that belongs to what may or it
was something that to be considering
another in another group they point the
conclusion from sex dispatch was to
bounce us back here so here well here we
we came some time ago the draft was
adopted and let's interrupt a little bit
about the story because we will talk
about why it was expired basically it
rose about an identity owner that
receives a request for delegation
typically think of a CDN node that wants
to use the certificate for for the
identity owner without exposing private
keys or whatever so what the entity
owner does is precisely request for that
for a four star
certificate a temporaries at the
temporary certificate using Acme and the
NDC the name delegation client pulls the
certificates a temporary certificates
and use it allowing the the identity
owner to revoke them immediately without
sending a revocation but just stopping
the the serving Yule this is this is
basically the the idea is that well
there is a request that goes with the
see Assad that has to go from the NDC up
to the I do that is the one that makes
the request and and since he at the URL
for pulling the certificates the private
keys never left
never leave the be NBC no the any any
private material from the identity on
research force is only that the identity
owner express as willingness of via of
the certificate being generated the
reason this is something that we discuss
or challenges why is important just
another I say this precisely because
typically and NDC and an idea or are
living in different domains and their
relationships is not precisely an
internal is not well state goes we is
true as do office aid is that it has
been expired because and this is our
fault and only or fault of the others
that were much more focus on the main
star draft trying to align with it and
we let the time past simply and we
frankly we failed in making the usual
cosmetic update just changing names in
numbers on a date as well but we have
formally inspired we had not abandon it
and are buying ongoing discussion with
you currently documented use cases that
one is a steer precisely the other one
is the CDN interconnection in which they
are explicitly mentioned the this well
what we are trying to do it most
precisely to understand which other day
the specific requirements
well and that's true respect again so
this is something that we will solve as
soon as we can mr. Sirk delegation
definitely you know we have no real
story about how to do like shortly stuff
with anencephaly I think there is an
overlap I know one constraint that is
unusual for a starship obligation is we
want to be able to narrow the namespace
of these locations was used something
like yeah an accomplishment that you
support that G's is in the list of the
things that we have to consider
possessing few different categories of
identifiers and figuring out how to do
encompassing no no it should be I mean
it should be doable I believe it should
be doable right now if you look at the
at the document is not precisely good
okay so there are some open questions is
right now zero zero is an adopted zero
zero version the message flow we are
reasonably happy with us with it but
well whoever is willing to have a look
at it and tell us and tell us what he or
she thinks it would be really really
appreciated now there are a few things
that we have in mind one is about the
composition patterns with the other how
we combine the flow for delegation with
the flow for the agree star requirements
once that the ACMA star flow is skia
second is precisely the naming
interactions were John was mentioning
it's about how you narrow or within the
weather than the the way in which you
interact with the identify mapping
system DNS is what we have in mind what
probably others how this is the CSR the
CSR that goes from the NDC up to the
idea is validated
I'm going whether we need them more
detail on that and something that has
appeared in interaction with the CDN
guys is whether we need to make to have
a way of publishing and making available
which is a CSR template that is
suspected to be used by the baby NDC so
that that's a few reflections initial
reflections about about the different
the couple of use cases one is steel and
possess so it is a abstraction from DNS
in that it would be wider in terms of a
generic naming Authority and making
because star delegation considers DNS
specific things that we should have to
make optional or bring some mapping in
the case of a CD an idea is that suppose
the the is that there is a upstream CDN
that is delegating some access to a
downstream CDN so it is how would you
expose the requirements for the
delegation in this in this in the the
requirements for the delegation of the
identity in the content allocation
requests and well there are some
concerns at these theories Vivian is not
limited is not you may have a chain of
here key of delegations and how these
affect something that is such to a
couple of identities and how this
propagates is something that we have to
elaborate the little bits because
personally I don't like the idea of a
proxy of proxy of a proxy of a proxy and
this is another discussion with the CDN
hi guys and as far as I can tell this is
the zone we are where I'm going you will
see a zero one very soon and I hope it
will be a little bit more than a
cosmetic
update okay thank you
questions we're really running ahead of
schedule this planning on me how many
people are planning on reading the spec
all right quarter of the room that's
pretty good rameneh do how many are plan
to implement this they come and then
they will just be a CBN I guess at least
that's their scroller yeah so I'd like
to hear from some reasoning I'm with
this and make sure that we're actually
in their needs and they're such people
exist initially put on ice well by what
they could lose possessory I mean John
is saying that they this is a speedy
guys in the city and I would make
segments or I'll ask them because I
wanna meet them all right next
okay so next in the agenda oh and this
time it is the fourth tab
Hey so there's a couple use cases were
looking at and primarily around
certificate enrollment for devices for
hardware endpoints and we think Acme can
be used to solve a lot of those problems
these cases we recognize and one of the
things that will help with the second
main bullet here is Acme can actually be
used for issuance of soft mint
certificates this isn't really clear and
obvious from the draft but it's actually
technically allowed from the drafts are
going to go through that and when we use
acne for issuing a soft mint certificate
it will just optimize issuing of large
volumes of certificates for clients and
devices and some of the use cases were
looking at for a hardware endpoints
integration on est integration with
brewski integration with t p-- and
integration with TP risky that the thing
about EFT Brisky t panting briskly is
these specifications define how the
endpoint connects to the server but none
of them specify how the server connects
to the back end CA whether that server
be eni's tra order that server B at each
server the integration between the
server and the CA is out of scope
there's a couple of related drafts so
recapping cathing have drafts here and
we have had some and these drafts cover
client enrollment and device one first
if could use an acme and we have some
pretty many discussions about alignment
to these three drafts I went to the site
meeting scheduled so anybody who's
interested in using acne for issuing
client and device certificates please
attend the site meeting so lots of them
inserts for product remanded if you read
if you read the draft in detail a key
mandates that the identifier in the CSR
must match it and for in the new order
request and the identifier and the
authorization object must be used when
fulfilling HTTP or Tina's challenges
Arachne does not mandate is that the
identify new order request matches to
identifier in an authorization object so
what this means for a CA if I ca
implementing a controls to do so
an acting server could issue
certificates for a subdomain
if declined to only fulfills a challenge
for the parent domain so this is
actually technically allowed by the Acme
draft of ran through this is Richard
this way Richards on the co-authors and
we think this is an interesting use case
if an ACME C is willing to allow a
policy like this and so what that would
mean is that an ACME client could prove
ownership fulfill a challenge for a
parent domain and then issue a larger
number of client certificates or
subdomains of that parent domain which
is a nice optimization it reduces all
DNS of traffic and challenges so what
this culture looks like for supplemental
pre-authorization and on the left hand
side with the standard floor for
pre-authorization of parent domain and
declined post the new authorization
endpoint and if you run through the
steps there it's straight out yacking
standard and the client just proves
ownership a for parents to me in the
example that given this domain calm and
there's nothing the draft that precludes
step two happening and step two you is
the client issues a new order request
for a subdomain of that previously
challenged fulfilled parent domain and
the Acme server can fulfill that order
an issue a certificate because there was
no text in the Acme draft to prevent
that use case and from talking to
Richard that is deliberate ever trying
to devise certificate integrations est
which risky diverges defines the
protocol the client used to mollify
exchanging pkc as ten and seven payloads
with a nice tra and teeth and
deliberately bridges and defines a
protocol where clients can roll over a
teep server and by exchanging because he
is ten and because he is seven payloads
and what draft we have actually neither
das to draft specify how the t p--
server should integrate over the CA or
how the e or EST or a sorry the EST or a
integrated to see either a theft auto's
culpable drafts so what this draft we
have here does illustrate so Acme can be
used as a glue to integrate between the
est array and an acme server RT p--
server and acne and
not well this book may not be strictly
true no changes our party is TT for
acting specifications we think that the
teach standard is actually under
specified at the moment and the teach
standard doesn't really deal with how
the tip server should react and how the
client should react if the tip server is
not able to fulfill that because he is
10 requests straight away there's no
back off mechanism doesn't all the retry
mechanism so he believed the tip is
currently under specified and the
subdomain proposal is a nice
optimization it reduces to round trips
that would be required if you're using
Acme for certificate issuance sort of
the for client use case is the only one
I've documented here is the use tqi
opinion these culturals were taken
straight from the draft on the left-hand
side to step on the pre-authorization of
the parent domain
it's all very standard than the example
of given as pre-authorization of
domain.com and on the right hand side
home showing his de client interaction
with the east tra and the client just
sends a standard D is T central DRA DRA
replies were to attend to or to retry
after and this is the bit that's missing
from t p-- there's no retry after an t
p-- and the east tra then turns around
and placed a acme order and what you
will notice here is on the left hand
side the pre-authorization involves an
interaction with dns but for actual
certissue ins there's no interaction
with TS there's no authorization
challenges required and for issuing a
certificate should be faster and should
be more scalable and once the acme
server is issued the certificate to the
RA and after the client that we trained
for this has expired the client should
also simply unroll and retry and then
the RA can just issue the search
straight to the client then so that's it
really short presentation and pretty
simply use cases for interesting use
cases so the two main things won't stock
what as one is to solve the menus case
of interest to acne series and if it is
is it what formely documenting because
it's currently allowed by the acme
traffic but it's not immediately obvious
and our de client and device use cases
of interest to any other implementers so
a version of this presentation is going
to be given that
amuse in you sessions as well and we
have the side meeting on Wednesday
mornings so anybody who's just please
come to the second meeting mr. morning
that's it Wednesday morning sir
Kathleen Moriarty I do think this is
worth documenting just from talking to
people who are looking at implementing
when they see that these gaps exist they
can feel that it's not ready right even
though you can do these things so I do
think this is worthwhile develop does it
definitely yes I mean so know the years
that we were discussing were talking
about the delegations precisely whether
it would be it would throw words people
say subdomains and we were like to
simplify
[Music]
ranked rants levy Google so the value in
the subdomain just working is valuable
in that it aligns with public see Asians
I don't want to suggest that hacking is
only intended for public CAS but it is a
nice side effect which is that a public
CA has to follow baseline requirements
of recurrence and this is an existing
pattern that many CAS using can use so
there's value in documenting it the only
caveat I throw out there is that in a
world of increased automation which is a
desirable world of reduced life time for
certificates across the board in the
industry and again I'm only speaking
about public certificates or private
ticket it's not is this maybe profiled
out in a future point rank which is
there there's value in actually having
the domain authentication bound to the
specific domain so it's possible and I
say this on the order of many years you
know that this gets profile out in terms
of public see days but I don't think
that precludes documenting it now as
this one's with public practice this can
be used for a number of interesting use
cases when you're using acting with some
of these other use cases so that's just
a caveat that I put out there is that it
may be that in the future Acme
implementations being used for public
CAS don't use this feature and so any
documentation it would be useful to at
least keep in mind that we made profiler
sure
okay so anybody specifically interested
in the client entice these cases please
attend the site meeting on Wednesday
Thanks okay and that brings us to Alexey
this was really planned for 11:00 and as
I said our agenda is shrinking right
this time
I only updated one of the documents
which is s/mime I think this is getting
closer to being done
next slide so just don't mind people
what this is trying to do this is
basically to be able to issue ex-prime
certificates for and user for email
addresses the way it works is that the
challenge is sent in an email in the
subject of email that can be verified as
coming from their Akhmatova
email client is a document client itself
or it can invoke Hockman client you know
maybe it's a special media type can be
music might be able to do this manually
then the responses sent with the
response part and then Acme server can
issue a certificate voice my abuse so I
sort of had a lot of you know open
issues in the document about how you
verify that email is challenging mail is
coming from a cui server how you
verified response and there was also
some questions about specific email
details about format and I was trying to
balance about between making it very
simple to implement for email clients
but also trying to make it usable for
wide variety of existing email clients
and existing libraries so this time I
drill down more into email format for
challenges and responses
mostly syntactic elements I did some
tests about putting long strings and
subjects and how they will be encoded by
existing email clients or web services
and yeah basically because of polling
length limits in our email specs it's
likely that subject line is going to be
folded it means that encoded-word
specification has to be used so I
initially didn't want to use it but I
think it's unavoidable so basically IRC
twenty to thirty one needs to be used
but this is unlimited to utf-8 Oh us a
sketch char sets so we don't want people
to require to implement various other
things and then yeah similar thing for
responses and then basically there was a
man in this discussion about how do you
actually verify that email challenge is
coming from Acme server and tradition
two ways of doing this an email is a the
dekum signing because the challenge
itself in the subject so you want to
sign that it's coming from from address
associated with the Acme server assigned
the subject and few other header fields
or you can use as mine signing with the
responses is more difficult because you
don't want to use s mine for responses
because the whole point of this is to
get a smile too difficult to be able to
do that among other things so for
responses is probably just Hakeem
signing and make sure that SPF and de
mark and various other things in use
work right next slide
yeah I got a couple of questions last
week
I'm sorry I didn't reply to email all
those later
hopefully today one question was the
document currently says the responses
need to use re colon space prefix and
suggestion was to allow any prefix not a
big deal I the way purist and me says
the only client that generates non re
prefixes old version of Outlook that
should be banished from the surface of
the earth if there are other clients
doing this I'm curious to know but you
know at the end of the day this is not a
big deal it's the change is going to be
whether you compare the whole string but
see you compare suffix of itself I mean
in computer terms it makes no huge motor
difference the other question was I was
struggling a bit with you know how
simple the structure of challenge and
response e-mails can be original I just
said it's it's to explain messages where
for the challenge the challenge itself
is on the subject of email so text plan
is just explanatory note for response is
risk response itself actually contains
the response part so I was trying to
balance whether you know do you want to
require Acme clients to be full email
clients you know to allow multi-part mix
or maybe allow you know nice HTML text
to be included explaining what you do
with this challenge how you can handle
it manually if you your client doesn't
support like me as my automatically but
you know the user can be instructed how
to do this still open to suggestions one
suggestion was also to use spam like
encoding inside to explain so like sort
of for certificates and various other
objects
yeah again depending on your API in your
client libraries that might be
convenient I personally prefer to tag
challenges and responses and you as
extra media types which allows to invoke
external applications automatically and
it's slightly easier for email clients
to to key off to do automatic action but
again this is the grand scheme of things
it doesn't matter but we just need to
make a choice and move on
think next slide so this is a list of
mal standing issues I dealt with
challenge verification I need to do a
bit more work on response verification
and again there is still a little bit of
open issue about structure of their
challenges and responses so more
feedback from the mailing list would be
useful I think probably one more
revision and this can go to Alice Cole
and then we can I can try to ping
various people who who can provide more
feedback on you know the structure of
the message and ok so not as a chair but
if someone who gets a lot of
international mail I see aw all the time
so going back to the prefixes slide I
think maybe just to use the subject line
being a suffix is the best yeah a lot of
ITF right yes I see Ari : aw : or e :
you know I know if this is that old
outlook maybe it's just old outlook but
ok ok ask the audience who's going to
implement this
has will thinking about mr. Dale can't
go more from the ACLU so there's
different parts of implementation right
so one part about being mail user agent
implementers who would be willing to do
this if there was a site that's willing
to do it yeah so if there's a CA that's
willing to do this then yeah we'll have
this to a million thank you
okay Kathleen you're up okay
so from the last meeting I split out the
the one draft I had into two so the
basis of this one is just to set a few
new challenge types for user
authentication focus and that could be
for code signing certificates operating
within a process where you establish an
account first with the CA and then you
get credentials to use for that
pre-authorization challenge and so I'm
proposing one time password key pairs
like a phyto account be set up or other
certificates be issued for that
pre-authorization so what happens with a
code signing certificate is the request
goes in and there is a challenge sent
back in for eg certificates - typically
to administrators within within the
account and this would be used for that
authorization so I did get some email
and private conversations after the last
talk and not what not I think crickets
on the list right but I did get a bunch
in private so I don't know if people are
ready to do this yet or if they like or
so so this is the first time I have
these three in there last I was just
trying to see who is interested so I
actually did get some interest is anyone
in the room here interested in adding
these challenge types okay I do have
other people okay so at least one and I
do have other people interested which is
okay at least to
three okay and I do have other people
that were interested and I don't know if
any of you are the ones means there was
somebody I didn't know that had
contacted me I mean should I just will
have to sit a while longer and see if
interest grows people not ready for it
they don't like it okay thank you
all right so that's at least four and
with the interest of four is that
implementors yes okay so all right and I
have other people is why I'm standing up
here
all right so okay all right good thank
you
so please send comments and feedback
okay by the way it's Thomas for snotty
under the that was nothing the job of
expressing interest thank you Mary um
this is the first great excellent thank
you yeah I'd appreciate any feedback or
if there are types that I missed that
should be incorporated as well I didn't
put too much time into this because I
wanted to get interest look cool alright
next one so I split out these two drafts
after a message from Richard Barnes and
some conversations with Owen and we have
to sort out like what we should do with
all of these drafts I just want to go to
the next slide so when I talk about this
work people just see the let's encrypt
work and the RFC
eight five five five and they get lots
of I've gotten lots of questions that of
things I think Owen head said this
things that you can do with acne but
it's not clear from the draft and then
people are hesitant to go forward
because they think it has to fit in with
the realm of what let's encrypt does so
this would be informational I think we
have to sort out maybe in the Wednesday
meeting what Doc's go where or here
ideally but what's useful are there
other questions that need to be answered
that other people are getting like I get
ones like okay where can you store the
keys and it's orthogonal right so you
could use pkcs 11 but it doesn't say it
anywhere in RFC a five five five I know
I know
John John's face yeah yes it should be
obvious but apparently it's not right
and then there was long mailing list
discussions on things like comparing it
to esthe but that wasn't captured and
you have to go back and read a mailing
list so I've gotten lots of questions on
that and then being able to use a
challenge type for a different type of
certificate you know you just have to
change the the CSR and it has a
different cert type but that's not
obvious either so yeah some of this
might be silly
is it worth documenting and improving
this or as an informational draft or not
what do people think I'm happy but this
I didn't put a lot of time into yet I
there so it can be much improved but I
think the more we want people to
implement encryption on PKI
as an infrastructure as a default the
more we can do to reduce obstacles to
that adoption the better so favor
Seldon explain crypto to sympathy for
anyone okay great so comments and
feedbacks to improve it would be
appreciated yeah I mean this is like
interesting material I think rc-- seems
like an odd way to do it they're gonna
have an import questions that people are
going to have it's like a fax kind of
it's more needed here also remember what
a little sort of sad about the material
in here this you're like why not ask
that seems like like I think you did
what he sidestepped those questions in
the working group and like I'm sort of
watch into it like like I find another
you sure explain why did you perform I
end up were to go be be or sad and like
I don't think you had that funny yeah so
it was answered on the mailing list in
detail but people who aren't feeling
following mailing list aren't seeing
that so it's just stuff that I've been
asked yes I've read the draft segment
there's some useful stuff in here some
stuff that yeah maybe
history but I don't see why this needs
to be an emergency it all it doesn't
need the consensus is the IETF it
doesn't need permanent archive ability I
think this would make a fine blog post
or a series of blog posts that doesn't
okay so something being found I think is
is the importance like I have some
working groups where I go back to
documents and I have to pull out a draft
that's been expired and you know this
goes back over a decade where I have
ones that I do that for that's the fun
thing that logs expire they can
disappear without notice and in RFC Camp
a site can go away these are these are
archived so archival value no hats so a
few years ago and I fused probably about
2/10 and I that is a canoe group had
this exact roadmap or FC that documented
so that is published and I don't think
is there a way to know that though
there is some value in this my opinion
but I don't know it's a lot of value
alright so if there's some place where
it's not gonna just disappear like just
some random blog post I've had blogs
disappear questions I'm gonna add one
for him do we know whether anyone's
reading it or using it I can't say using
it but if we implement the web analytics
on the idea that's just say individual
here I did not read the draft is
clickability
I mean this is just answering general
questions like so it's all over the map
right now
French aha fortunately I want to say
that when I read this draft I think that
it is useful for me to understand the
history of how to use these kind of
things as a new guys for this area yeah
it's really useful and I personally
think about the question of whether it's
to the PRC or the kind of way to publish
it
I think because I think that maybe this
drafter you have talked about or you
described about something about how to
use eme and together with the Brisky oh
yes the other kind of technology to
provide a whole process of the device or
the of the users auto provision right so
I think these kind of things is not just
some guidance it's just like Roman
nation maybe saw applicability document
or some kind of thing so I think this
makes sense to be a document standard to
clarify how to use it a different kind
of time technology combined together
right I think that is useful so the last
question inside is that I'm wondering
whether this document has included a
part of the
the certificated provision for the
networked device for exam or whether we
to talk about about the revelation with
the I Triple E a to the arrow to thought
a to talk about they are it's kind of
certificate how would you say I say I
need to probation unit yet so I was
aiming it at informational I you think
from the feedback I'm getting I'm happy
to aerate this again as a draft even if
it's not a working group draft and we
can figure out where it gets published
as it iterates so if you want to help
add that information please share and
and we'll get it incorporated and we'll
see how this develops if it develops
into you know something more or not
maybe gets published a different way but
I'll iterate it in a draft for now the
drafts are cheap so a lot of times I've
seen RFC's called use cases maybe not
overviews yeah that's not popular though
so you expand acne Navy you're expanding
the scope it right you use cases more
well I don't I don't know I can see the
value to having you know here's the
possible ways you can do this where you
put it as you say as long as it's
persistent right that's my worry for me
Alexei Melnikov I suggest the Working
Girl if there is enough interest
adopters as a work item with
understanding it might not be published
as an arty and just do it as a working
your process and then you figure out
what to do with it later on whether it's
you know wiki blog post you know RFC or
not you know content so when I'm fine
with that because then even the the
draft will always be there even if it
doesn't get published so we have that
stickiness of that because the archival
properties hi I mean Susan you had a
perfectly consistent with it being usual
individual traffic like what you
potentially dock you for like working
group work it's not playing RC even like
other groups do it yeah okay
Virginia I mean I think it's for
whatever the word enough wants to do so
they're interested yes and if anyone
send me feedback I will update it
regardless of its status so I'm happy to
grow this or let it die based on
feedback tears are you ready to have the
working group think decide now or you
want to do another drafter it doesn't
matter to me I mean I'll continue to
work on it based on feedback but what do
you guys think you're the chairs well I
think that the first question would be
how many people have read the draft well
enough to fill a table to restaurant
yeah tomorrow yeah so um I don't see
really a good case for asking whether
people want to want to adopt this now so
encourage people to read this and
perhaps next time or on the mailing list
we can decide whether this ought to be a
the workman draft that's discussed in
the working group or an individual drugs
that is discussed in the working group
so either way
I don't think there's any decision that
were that we can make right now all
right thank you
that's most of what we have on our
agenda except for their way forward and
open mic also known as any other
business so about this way forward thing
the way it looks from here is that we're
discussing a lot of very poorly read
probably reviewed drafts that well
there's not a lot of interest and for
many of them the people who are might
want to implement them are not in the
room not in the not in the list and
there's somebody that comes to Acme to
write the draft because some other group
needs it and the rest of the group
doesn't really engage in Mack he doesn't
come to the meetings and the question is
do we really need a working group to do
that I mean is this either is there any
advantage of having an active working
group when what we're doing here isn't
of interest to the people in the room to
the people on the mailing list except
for that one or two people coming from
another group to do some acting work for
their group so the question is do we
want to be always be closing this
working group or doing one team or do
you think that there's any actual work
that the working group is going to do
rather than just sitting here reading
our email well somebody from another
group comes to the mic and tell us what
what they need so this really has to go
in the mic we could probably put this
group on kind of glide path supposing
seem like we've got a couple of kinds
there seems to be reaching a natural
ending point I think there's not there
shouldn't be a real great need for this
group to stay open long term unless he
needs to make tweaks to acne
I think defining you identifier testify
challenge types can be done in different
groups and extended by the IRS Jews need
to find always be closing
[Music]
Kathleen Moriarty I I think there's
value in at least getting the client
pieces forward just to round it out and
have acne more full and and presented
out externally as more than just for web
certificates right so I'm sure that
anything that we've already accepted
should move forward and we done that but
we could go into the kind of closing
State where we're not taking any new
stuff because as long as we stay open
people are going to come and have this
new little extension that they want to
we're never gonna we're gonna be like
the old pickax we have some drafts in
flight that are adopted we have some
drafts that are not yet adopted what
we've talked about is there any body of
work that has not come a draft warm to
the working group that we would want to
put in the table that would necessitate
us continuing the work so I guess I'm
asking another evening is everything
it's or all the traps that we would
think about kind of advancing they all
the tables there's something else I said
hi this is entrenar own from my
historical perspective and you mentioned
pickax like it took like 18 years to
close it if you have something that's
open it's about PKI it will stay open
into the closest so if you've got things
and you think you're good to go and
close it start on another working group
it doesn't take that much time so we
charter do whatever I mean there's all
kinds of ways to do this I think you're
things that me are good if there are
things that come along that are like
additional explanations we have SEC
dispatched if it's clearly bad evident
the ATS can sponsor or not it's
Aleksey monocle whatever you do just
don't close the meaning list I think you
want to keep the men in this town so
people can at least ask questions and
bring ideas then you can redirect them
elsewhere
mail is including the pickax one are
open forever of course so any other
business we've got a lot of your life
back and we may not see you in Singapore
and you do need the blue sheets back if
you haven't signed them do so now