in this session we've got a variety of
different topics are we starting talking
about securing ipv6 neighbor discovery
and we've got Thomas shuffler all the
way from Berlin that's talked about his
work so this is better
hello everybody I'm Thomas Schaffer I'm
here from Germany Berlin and I'm going
to present you some student work which
we had done in collaboration with the
University of Potsdam and what we were
looking at was how can we secure a
different way to secure neighbor
discovery in access networks then what
had been proposed previously and what is
being implemented or proposed in several
other aspects and we were actually
trying to work this out by using an SDN
approach where we actually build an
application which collects all the
neighbor discovery messages from from
the network so this is the outline of
the program well actually many of the
comments I got from the reviews actually
triggered me to go a little bit back in
history and and talk about what paper
discovery and ICMP issue is actually
aren't how they can be exported I know
I'll focus on what we did so IP v6 is
kind of still the new protocol 20 years
old now and ICMP
is one of the big change changes in
protocol in regards to what had been
there in ipv4 and which is now May
different from what we had before so we
can say this Auto configuration and
router discovery we have a different
address resolution process then we had
an IP before and we now have all kinds
of other options which we have in order
to do something like multicast discovery
etc so all these changes actually led to
a very new protocol fairly different
protocol and what we had in ipv4 and
this actually sort of now opens up
several possibilities to actually
exploit these kind of things and the
maybe the most obvious change was a PDA
address auto-configuration which changed
the way IP addresses are assigned to us
I mean we now have DHCP in all the
networks so made for the end-user may
not feel so different one from the end
user perspective but at least the
protocols are very very different so the
assumption in ipv6 is basically that you
do some sort of address also
configuration and even if you are going
to use IP if you if you haven't use DHCP
is actually sort of store reliant on
some of the the mechanisms here so by
default all the hosts do stateless
address auto-configuration and in order
to configure address there's a way to
maybe take some data from an identifier
like a MAC address and and make this
into a relatively six address and what
you then do is you do so-called
duplicate address detection which lets
you know that this address is actually
unique on the network and as I said you
can also use the HTTP v6 but not as as
widespread as it is in ipv4 and a lot of
people don't ever actually implement it
and even if you implemented it means
that you still have to do some of the
first steps in the application process
so how does it
work so basically what you do is you
have a period six addresses now have
something called a lifetime which may
surprise people that it you have
actually now sort of tentative addresses
and preferred addresses and expired
addresses and when you do generate a new
address you actually set it and do to
prove it in the in the state of being
tentative and you need to make sure
through the process of duplicated
address detection it is address it's
actually being unique on a networking
you can actually use it so how this is
works use sin of solicitation message to
network where you set your source
address to the unspecified address and
then this gets sent out to the local
network and if you don't ever expect to
get a response back from this because
sort of that's your way to say oh you're
sure that this address is actually
unique on a network so that's how it
should work
that's how most most of the times you
what you see in the network but it's
actually now possible to to attack these
kind of protocol so it's very very easy
to do this so and you can actually dust
somebody just by replying to these kind
of messages on the network and other
attacks are possible as well so how does
this thing actually work so if somebody
just sort of some prankster or some some
attacker actually sort of just monitors
what's going on what's being sent out to
the network and and just replies to this
and and what happens then is that your
host says oh sorry
I just got an answer back I can't use
his address and it may pick another one
depending on the implementation but then
again you do the same thing again and
again and you actually does the the host
from actually being active on under
network that's just one example of what
can happen in ipv6 never discoveries
other attacks as well
so what did people think about it so
they said oh well we have this nice
thing called IPSec so we just secured
our neighbor exhale
messages or neighbor protocol messages
basic and then solve the problem solved
the trouble is this doesn't really work
because in order to set up an security
Association you somehow have to have a
valid IP address which you don't have
because you are in the process of
configuring one so this would actually
require that you have previously
configured manual security Association
on your devices in order to join the
network so kind of a chicken and egg
problem here then people real assets we
need something else and they secure
neighbor discovery protocol which is a
nice idea I like it very much
unfortunately nobody sort of either
implemented it or even if they
implemented it we've found that there
are some potential vulnerabilities
against it just by sending or arbitrary
messages you can actually cause and
release also resource exhaustion attack
and so I think that's probably the point
where people set the odds dump all over
then anymore and we don't implement it
so how do we actually be as our research
group actually cut you cut you this be
sort of monitored all these activities
we're very closely in a timeframe from
15 years ago or something like this and
we actually found and that's I don't
know if it's known by everybody there's
there's actually good X attack toolkit
out there so if you ever wanted to play
this yourself and find out what what's
possible on on these these protocols and
what what kind of attacks out there just
actually did seek to occurred here so
it's actually being developed by a guy
in Berlin as well so I met this guy and
he's a very very nice guy but sort of
very interested in how
to break ipv6 people came up with all
kinds of changes to the protocols we now
implemented something like route or
advertisement guards and silicon on your
access switches etc so kind of the
problem sent seemed to come or gone out
of focus and and nobody really cares
anymore what we did is we in a couple
years ago we started looking at ipv6
support in IDs and specifically in snort
and the developers they said yes we are
ipv6 comfortable but this meant a we're
only looking at layer 3 in not looking
at specific protocols they didn't even
have a way to distinguish an ipv6 ICMP
message from an ipv4 ICMP message
message so we did some implementations
there to allow this distinction and so
we looked at some of this in order to
detect any P attacks in IDS's but then
found it's maybe one way to do it but
there's may be others and instead of
using IDs we could actually use an SDN
switch to do very much of the same thing
so we could monitor or links and monitor
what's going on and linked and
potentially DSS also cheaper to deploy
and maintain but once we do this we can
actually go a little bit further and say
oh well now we can also filter not only
monitor or you can also put stuff on the
network on the Sdn controller which
allows us to give more control over
what's actually going on in the network
so we build NDP proxy or an intelligent
selective proxy it's under
discriminative lis proxying messages
it's just as if there's a certain data
metal net we implement this in the Rio
framework in piping and what we do is we
monitor the network and whenever we see
a duplicate address detection message
then we take this as the authentication
hook for our data model so this
generates a host cache entry in our
controller and this allows us then to
sort of distinguish between what we
should forward or drop on on our
networks other than this this is normal
oh no scripts which for ipv4 and we
additionally also implemented through
our advertisement cards so actually our
controller is the one who's who is
sending out our attachments and if
somebody else-- us that we just blocked
this what we also did is we didn't want
to have every kind of traffic or NDP
traffic hitting the controller because
this would potentially cause some
performance issues so we managed this by
using different priorities for our flow
rules so we have a catch-all rule which
has the lowest priority if somebody is
known mecca's now and we have these
flows to take a priority over them then
we filter ipv6 messages it's such and
then we have NDP traffic which we catch
and if you know this guide and sort of
this flow was actually taking priority
over this so we should only ever see the
first NDP package for certain flow and
and all the subsequent messages should
be switched directly from on the switch
so the idea was to have to simply deploy
so that we don't need to change any kind
of if anything in the implementations or
any protocols and have this running so
here you see a big picture of our
architecture I'm not going too much into
this
just some particularly of REO is
actually this we need it to only have a
single thread trying so we need to make
this so that it's actually something of
this coin going to be called in parallel
so how do we learn learn the host on the
network so we as I said we use the
typical recitation Massachusetts
whenever we see some body using a
and specified source addressed and we
take this as a hint it might be a new
host on a network
and whenever we see a second one then we
block this this could lead potentially
to the case that if somebody is moving
from one port to the other with his
machine that he himself blocking himself
but we we just take this chance and sort
of in after a certain computer world
time period we actually drop these
entries from the cache so it shouldn't
be blocked forever it shouldn't be just
blocked for a certain specific time
period so and then so if we have our
cache board our never cashed and we use
it's never cashier in order to validate
packets going between these entities and
whenever we have a full active
communication going on between some
entities then we actually install flow
in in in Sdn switch so when regular
traffic should be actually also being
able to cause these these flow entries
and the idea is that when we have some
bio direction or communication going on
we actually have these going over the
flows and we implement it as such that
sort of whenever there's a new packet
being triggered and we have a timeout
period for them for the flow rules and
they should be stay active as suit as
long as there is active communication
between the networks between the
entities on a network so after a certain
time period these flow rules may timeout
if somebody's failing to send any new
traffic or if somebody's maybe being
removed from the network we'd not
immediately remove these we remove two
flow rules from the switch but we not
immediately remove the hosts cache
entries they will get purged after a
certain time period but this is for
longer than it is usually for a day idle
time out on the floor flow rule so you
tested us in basically
of it in mini night but also some of it
on some real open flow hardware so the
basic functionality of onboarding ipv6
horse is quite quite easy to implement
and and works as intended the main
challenge really is in maintaining this
host cache because we don't we can't
guarantee that we see all all the
packets going on in the network and we
don't can I mean the trying to keep it
is if you have some host maybe shutting
down or maybe going to sleep and not
answering our pro packets when we trying
to figure out if this hose is still
active on the network we also did test
some performance issues with this
because sort of if basically now we are
in the packet path and and whenever we
need to process something then
potentially take some time and we find
out did it take some time which is
mainly due to the fact that we have a
non optimized host cache data structure
the trouble here is that been in the
norm of economics which can just sort of
key on the mac address here we now have
to check megatron's against different
and potentially multiple ipv6 addresses
so we have to go through the whole cache
and this is done in tight and so it's
not yet production ready but sort of
that's and but these times are only true
or these these these these times here in
milliseconds or for just first ICMP
packet being processed by the switch
whatever we got they got these things
it's the flows installed and all
subsequent like it will be much more
faster so what's our current limitations
we are model of sort of assumes that we
have one host per switch port that or
our host doing actually doing duplicate
address detection and the control sees
all those messages and currently it only
works with a single switch Network which
need to be extended what sort of main
challenge already hinted is really what
happens if a horse is have an idea
sleeping if or if house may change their
mega trusses what they are doing -
working out so that's actually something
what we we found is that sort of it's
actually is you feel it's a very good
idea to use as the end to do this kind
of things the trouble is that sort of as
Ethernet and IP are not very very well
integrated with each other so maybe it's
time to change something like this and
that we say oh well yes and I assume
that switch isn't supposed to be a layer
2 device but it never really was a pure
layer 2 device so there's some
interaction between these these layers
and maybe it's time to get this but a
bit more integrated in order to also
issue some some security and reliability
in networks and we see this already
being implemented in something like well
I find managed Wi-Fi networks where you
have the same or similar situation and
here we have mostly proprietary
controller models and I would rather
love to have something which is more
open and more standardized so that we
can actually use it in whatever we want
to do it so yeah thing is we want to
like support extend our work to work
with multiple switches and maybe use a
different framework maybe move away from
open flow and use p4 but that's still
not yet decided so if you want to have a
look at our code it's you are right on
the on the slide so you can go to a git
repository where you can download this
stuff and if you want to contact me here
on my contact details so if there are
any question I'm happy to answer
so we probably have time for one quick
question well the next presenter sets up
I am curious whether you does your code
assume no packet loss for the bad
packets yeah basically you're gonna have
a bad time okay yeah yeah because also
there's a yeah yeah I've seen people do
that in production of quotations and
it's fallen over for them because for
example I mean if you're in Wired maybe
you're okay yeah it's a it's the target
is wired Network so yeah if you're on
Wi-Fi like no I am we were actually
actively targeting wild wild networks
because I feel like that's that's like
neglected area so nobody really does
does so for excess networks I don't see
anybody doing it I mean we see a lot of
activities you see like a lot of
activity knee in Wi-Fi space but for for
just ordinary switch Ethernet networks
it's everybody assumes it's just there
and you're right I mean it's a there's a
whole lot of assumption here and the
question is really should we maybe
change some of the assumptions because
sort of and it is transparent switching
approach for Ethernet is head I mean has
its merits it's working but it's also
introducing a lot of troubles which may
or may not have if he had a much better
integration and finding out who we
actually aren't and yeah and basically
using git dodges a basically just that's
the only thing we could use without
changing any protocols it's yes maybe
chat more on the break thanks for your
talk so up next we have Sylvester not us
from Ericsson research he says he's
working with traffic man
for twenty years and he's interested in
finding practical scenarios where fast
and precise control of resource sharing
is needed among a high number of flows
so I think if you've got practical
problems like that perhaps find him in
the break let's take it this time silver
sir presenting our paper to both score
statements fairness and multiple time
scales paper together with my university
colleagues you can find all our papers
on our home page so our goal is to
extend fairness to multiple time scales
so first of all we want to define some
kind of mood temperature fairness we
want to be all done existing frameworks
namely two frameworks one is the per
packet value base cover stateless member
the other is another paper of mine not
with the same also as it is called moody
time scale bandit profile and we also
want to provide efficient and versatile
in implementation and versatile meaning
that we want to provide fine fine gain
fairness on multiple time scales that is
independent of traffic mixes and
resource bandwidth and I also want to
demonstrate some advantages and some
motivation for this as an example
motivation is T is from a paper getting
a scheme to instantly serve up flows for
improved performance by maintaining
fairness between other participant flows
remains an open significant design
problem to be investigated and we think
that we take a step forward in in that
direction sorry
so overview of course stateless resource
sharing with the example of per packet
value base course agency so sharing its
it's a framework which allows a wide
variety of detailed and flexible
policies I will I will go to some of the
details of these policies and enforces
the policies for all traffic mixes and
scales with the number of flows there
are two components packet marking and
the edge and resource node everywhere
else mainly in the core which does a
command scheduling so packet marking at
the edge and codes the policies into
value marked on each and every packet
and there's a packet marker per flow
flow being the unit where we have
resource sharing policies and based on
that packet marking the resource node
doesn't know about policies flows it
doesn't have to have separate keys it
only does its behavior based on packet
marking and packet marking only and we
have very fast and simple
implementations we actually had a paper
one year and two years ago in a inr we
about reduce resources of
implementations but this paper is not
about resource and implementation and we
reveal in this paper use our resources
implementation from last year so
betrayed measurements and timescales
botrytis derived measure there are all
these great packet arrivals and these
can be translated to bitrate and it
which way it always has a timescale
associated so it's a some kind of volume
divided by some cut some time some kind
of time and there are some natural
timescales like OTT one second session
duration may be one minute ten minutes
and for example amounts is mostly cap is
also a kind of like a bit rate limit
over the month so you can see that some
examples for the packet rival says if if
in a normal TT more packet arrives and
the RTT bit rate will be larger or there
can be a session bit rate there can be
bit rates averaged over pages which are
larger than a session and then then
these betrays will be smaller than the
session that's right so why does that
make sense that makes sense because we
can have fairness and multiple times
here so then do we measure a bit rate we
can measure betrayed only when the
source is active to describe for example
the performance of the source but we can
also measure betrayed during both active
and inactive period to judge fairness of
resource sharing so what can be a fan as
goal a multiple time scale is to to
balance the the bitrate measurements
among these multiple time scales and for
example to allow higher share on shorter
time scales for flows below their fair
share or longer time scales so there's
an example there if we have the same
fairness on each and every time so one
to one sharing then there is the blue
flow and blue flow is is having the same
same resource all right like the yellow
and it takes quite amount of time to
download that loser but if you take into
account that on a longer time scale
the blue food didn't have any
transmission you can allow a higher
share on the shortest time scale so he
said you cannot oh this one to five
share and steal on the longer time scale
the resource sharing remains one-to-one
and assuming that the yellow user is
downloading alone so the yellow users
download time won't change why why the
blue users stupid will be improved quite
much and there's there is one more thing
is this this is this was true for our
previous paper but we also aim at smooth
transition at at relations between the
rates measured at different time scale
so we don't want to have sudden rate
changes when the relation between rates
changes I will go to more more more the
details later there are much more
novelties compared to the previous table
but first a short introduction to be a
backpack if you are you marking like
versatility so we define in the per
pocket value framework we define
policies throughput value functions and
these are for a single time scale they
provide a very fine-grained control
which is independent of traffic mix and
resource bandwidth so these these meet
our requirements for a single time scale
and if you have a traffic mix if you
have a resource bandwidth then that will
always result in something we call
condition threshold value and condition
threshold value is a horizontal line on
this value function curves and if you
take the intersection of the stupid
value functions and the condition
threshold values then you will get the
stupid targets at all of the all of the
congestion levels I have three examples
here high congestion medium condition
low condition and the high congestion
there
there are several traffic classes here
but the interesting ones are the gold in
the silver so in in case of high
congestion you'd like out such to get
wise this route of silver flows in case
of low congestion we would like to have
God flows get four times the super soap
and and what is in-between is medium
congestion when silver flies over the
reach ten miles per second then those
flaws can't just can't get can't just
get the fall times but it gets the rest
so it gets something between two times
and
four times so the rationale behind is to
have some kind of for example mini
movers you put Target and Auntie
aluminum so you could put target is met
for the lower priority flow we shouldn't
prioritize the higher priority flow that
much and this is again an illustration
of the Versa type policies we can have
with this framework and and again we
just set based on these curves we
redefine packet marking so how can we
have packet barking based on a secret
value curve we have incoming packets we
measure the rate somehow so these are
the rate based packet marking policies
so we we measure for example rate 48 and
then we determine a uniform random rate
between 0 and that rate take the value
of the stupid value function at that
point and mark that packet value on the
packet and just by having that marking
and maximizing the transmitted packet
value in the core we've realized a
resource sharing target sum on this so
there are other papers about how this
how this happens but it's important to
understand this this kind of thing for
understanding this paper so but for this
video single rate measurement a single
time scale but if you want to have
multiple time scales we need read to
measure bit rates and multiple time
scales and we actually introduce two
different rate measurement algorithms we
have token bucket base rate measurement
organ for the RTT time scale only
because we think that the token bucket
based rate measurement models the first
reboot and our fair share of the lot are
not quite well it's a single part token
bucket it's rate change changes when the
bucket becomes empty or full details are
in the paper and the the other rate
measurement we used for longer time
scales is it is a sliding window based
rate measurement so the rate is
basically the amount of bits arrived in
the last time scale interval divided by
the by the length of the time scale and
it's actually an efficient efficient
approximation of that OGG and TDM tv-ma
and an interesting thing is about this
rate instrument organs if you if you
think about them is that learn
transmissions thoughts if you if you
would all timescales
increasing and and have the rate
measurement organs when the transmission
starts the
the bit rate on the smallest time scale
is always larger than the bit rate on
the next time scale and sense you can
see an example there are like time scale
ones like five subtank that and first
the the once one second rate measurement
reaches the since we put down the five
second and 10 seconds and and the slicer
version and the transmission stops so
for new clothes arriving to the system
they will have pretty big bit rate
measurements or no time scales but they
will still have moderate rate
measurements along with time scales so
how can we then define throughput on
multiple time scales instead of having a
single supa trial function per flow type
we introduce once we put value function
per time scale per flow type so for a
single kind of flow instead of having
one such function you're having for such
functions and all of these have a time
scale associated so so what does it mean
we first defined dominant time scale so
dominant time scale is then for example
time scale R is the dominant when the
rate measurement at that time scale is
the largest and if there are more than
one than the longest time scale applies
and as an example have two fluids of the
same flow type one has dominant time
scale one the other tournaments go
forward so one has just arrived the
other has a long history in the system
and we say that multi time scale
research airing is such that they should
share the bottleneck according to TV f4
and TV as one so it is as if they would
be different flow flow types in the
single time scale framework so if you if
you look at it then the the new flow is
the is the blue one it should have much
higher so you could share and the old
old flow the green one but we also aim
smooth transitions when the relation
between our eyes change so if there is
an oscillation between which is the
dominant time scale we don't want to
have an oscillation in the resource
sharing so how do you achieve it there
is something in our previous paper
called mu times given the profile and it
has a few go presidencies and the future
chemicals associated with each of these
and this can market given the preference
if there are enough tokens at all of
these buckets and in theory we could
quantize smooth times get through it
value function to an MTS be VP but is
not practical because we would have
thousands of token buckets but we can
use that to approximate what happens we
can we can look at multi times get
bandwidth profile as an indirect measure
mental operation rate on each time scale
and limiting token buckets would would
determine the measurement again I can't
go through all of the details there but
if you look at the look at what happens
is that the transition between the
street value function will happen at the
rate measurements at the different time
scales and by using that we can have an
efficient packet marking based on these
repeat value functions so you can
measure bit rate for all of the time
scales at these bit rates you can
determine the distance between the
street value function and that will
result the blue region of difference we
could write functions and similarly to
the single x kilogram you can have a
uniform random number determine the
right region for for determining your
packet value so you can choose between
region 1 2 3 & 4
based on relations between your random
number and the measured bit rates and
determine your your packet value
accordingly and it's actually a pretty
fast algorithm so what can be achieved
with this we did some simulations to
understand what happens in the system
it's a pretty complex system can we
achieve some kind of gains can be indeed
boost new flares things like that so we
use an s3 we use the same core scheduler
like in our previous organ with a
millisecond delay target we had several
flows one flow consists of either a
single DC TCP connection or for for
cubic TCP connect on Josh connections
which means faster slow start for for
the cubic flowers we have thermally
second one second five second and ten
seconds this time skills and tvf for was
gold and silver as in the single
timescale t VF
and in each and every time scale we we
double the share so and timescale:1 we
should have twice the share five time
scale five we should have doubled the
share time scale one four times the
share and time scale that in a second
eight times the share of the long time
ten second average stupid
so some simulation scenarios we had
first greedy flows of the same traffic
class and DC TCP the blue flow was in
the system for longer time than the
longest time scale and then the yellow
flower light arrives to the system the
left-hand side curve is the is with the
multi time scale PPV and the right hand
side curve is the reference so in the
reference you can see that with the old
framework we knew it converges to the
fair share pretty fast we we have one
second average throughput here so it's
it's basically converges within one
second but what happens with the multi
time scale is that when the when a new
flow arrives it is boosted first then
there are some oscillations and then
they converge to the fair share and how
can you how can we visualize it or
understand it me even more is to is to
measure two things one is the one is we
call the flow time averages and there is
the five five second time being the
average so the flow time average is the
total amount of buys the flow has
downloaded divided by the total amount
of time the flow has spent in the system
why the fisa five second time window
average is basically looking back back
back at the last five seconds and and
see what was the average stupider
including periods when the flavor wasn't
even there and what you can see I
highlighted some cases with the cubic
multi timescale vs. there are friends so
what you can see there is that the flow
time averaged one this is a relative
curve and one is the is the equal share
it's it's not any more than the furture
so the flow time averaged has a high
boost at the beginning and actually the
five second average fair share of the
flow which is almost the the equal share
in one second which means that in one
second the flow can download as as much
data as his equal share in the last
second including the four seconds when
he wasn't yet there but after a period
you can say see that it will go to the
equal sharing site it will converge to
equal sharing with flows it's a flow is
in the system for a long time it will
have equal share with other flows I will
show show this slide first so in this
example there are continuous arrivals to
tiny flows arrive to the system every 10
second and you can see that the number
of flows is of course increases say the
the per flow equal bandwidth decreases
but for each of the new flowers there
are temporarily boosted each and every
case independently of the number of
flows and then they all converge to two
to the equal share as we desired and
there's another example here this is a
very simple adaptive streaming model its
inserts some kind of dialog to the
system every 10 second and there is a an
initial time an initial download and we
show how much time does it take to
download one second verse of video data
and because the MTS the multi timescale
resource sharing boosts the initial
pause there is a much faster startup so
the time display is much less and also
every time it yes it's basically a lot
about one side and it also feels a play
after but for most foster stage it it
defines and implements mu times E and s
for far enough place so so this is this
initial results really promising so we
have some kind of multi times get
fairness which works there are
significant performance gain so
advantage for new clothes for the
starting phase and there is also better
long time fairness for flows we don't
know if behavior but there is a quite
amount of future work we are not quite
sure how it can be used what how is it
useful so what is the for example what
is the practical number of times has to
be to reach real advantages for the
users how shall this be dimensioned how
shall we design the move to time scale
sleep its value functions we use the
simplest example week
imagine does it make sense different to
use different kind of policies in this
TV s word for the Piraeus timescales and
and what what we can find which can be
redundant like further so we're still
running a little bit behind but we've
got time for one question mm-hmm
questions
yes I'll ask one quick one so are you
thinking about this mainly in the
context of like data center networks and
data center workloads or would you see
it in other types of networks our main
focus is really access network and
broadband users so it's it's not in data
center it's it's more about smaller even
smaller times guys but it's for example
for residential access and fair sharing
over over congested access things all
right let's thank the presenter one last
time Satya are you there can you unmute
yourself Hey yeah I'm sure can you hear
me okay yeah yeah we can see you too
[Music]
okay so your Center let me know when to
advance the slides so for our last talk
we've got Satya Kumaran money from
University of Wisconsin and he's made
presenting some work on managing time in
the Internet hello everyone I'm Satya
I'm from the University of
wisconsin-madison and thanks to visa
processing delays I'm currently in
center Daylight Time which is an hour
behind
Montreal and today I'm going to be
talking about our work in examining how
current local time is reported by
devices on the Internet
next slide please can we go to the next
slide please
I think you skipped a slide yeah yeah so
Internet time synchronization is useful
for a variety of applications and these
mechanisms synchronize clocks on devices
to a common time scales such as UTC to
make time more comprehensible people
facing applications need to translate
time from UTC to current local time and
writing code to do this translation is
notoriously difficult because several
factors such as the daylight saving time
rules and changes to these rules need to
be considered further several edge cases
need to be handled as well for example
the island nation of Samoa skipped an
entire day in December 2011 because they
wanted to be on the tail the same time
as Australia their closest trading
partner on the other side of the
International Dateline next like this so
time zones originally alternated in the
late 19th century in order to improve
coordination in railway and Telegraph
networks and the daylight saving time
was introduced in 1918 in the u.s. in
hopes of saving energy during the first
world war and modern applications such
as calendars need to handle and know
about time zones and the time zone
database is a critical asset that
contains data and code that helps
applications do this handling and this
database was created by Arthur David
Olsen in the early 1980s next like this
so this time zone database consists of
definition of time zones and the
daylight saving time rules for every
time zone and it contains both
historical and current data so in this
small snippet we have here we have bore
a definition of a time zone and also the
addition of DST phones
so we've skipped a few lines here to
save space and tidy so on top and we
have the time zone definition for the
New York Times here and it says until
1883 New York was behind GMT by 4:00
hour and 56 minutes and did not follow
any daylight saving time and until 1967
New York was behind GMT by 5 hours and
had its own rules for observing daylight
saving times and right now the daylight
saving time in New York is same as the
rest of the US and below that we have
the DST rules currently in effect in the
u.s. from 2007 the rule says that
daylight savings start in March on the
second Sunday where clocks are advanced
by 1 R and end in November on the first
Sunday so information like this is
organized as text files in a typical
unique style and bundled with code and
reference implementations for C API
functions to handle time zones and
usually programs in the database next
slide please
so this database was placed in the
public domain by Olson in 2009 and hence
this is not owned by any entity the
database is currently hosted by IAE and
the process to update the database is
defined in RFC
six five five seven so the database is
maintained by a community of volunteers
and all decisions are finalized and
published by a primary maintainer the
current primary maintainer for the
database a spa legged of UCLA the
current version of this database has
three hundred and forty eight times
owned records for various time zones
across the internet oh sorry across the
world and this database is used by
almost all major operating systems such
as various flavors of Linux Android iOS
and various programming libraries
by TZ and Jorah time etc next slide
please so the actual rules for the time
zones and observing daylight saving time
is decided by the local corresponding
local government authorities and this
and this information and changes to such
rules are published either officially or
through the media and when such share
changes or updates are known the time
zone database community discusses such
changes the official time zone mailing
list and once the changes are finalized
a new release is prepared by the
maintainer and published at a known
location then it is up to the consumers
of this database to push these updates
to their end users which are typically
done through operating system updates
and any delay in this process has the
potential to cause major disruptions for
example in 2015 due to ongoing elections
the government of turkey decided to
delay the end of daylight saving time
and announced this change only three
weeks in advance to the actual date of
effect so what finally happened is the
update to the database being pushed was
delayed and the iOS update bundling
these changes reached the end users only
three days before the date of change so
what happened was a huge confusion on
what time of day it was
so given the wide use of the database
and huge impact the update process has
you are motivated to understand the
evolution of the database and the update
and maintenance processes next slide
please
yeah and for this analysis we use source
files from all 214 releases of the
database that span over 26 years they
also download the entire mailing list
archive
and perform text search on the archive
to identify problems and anomalies with
the database which will later discuss in
this talk to perform this analysis we
built a Python based processor tool that
can compare consecutive releases to
detect effective changes in zone and DST
rules and this tool is also capable of
identifying correction updates that is
updates that make changes to previous
updates so in total this tool identifies
about 2200 h2 zone and DST runs with 400
of those labeled as correction updates
next slide please
so based on this - what we do is we take
these updates and then classify them
into either making changes to time zones
or to DST rules and since we can extract
the release dates of this other updates
from the mailing list we also see
whether these updates make changes to
time stamps in the past or in the future
and from the charts on the right we can
see that make the majority of the
updates have to deal with the DST rules
so this shows the huge impact daylight
saving time has on managing time on the
internet and also an interesting fact is
even though the database does not make
any claims for the accuracy of historic
data before 1970 a majority of the
effort goes into improving the
historical accuracy of the database and
since we can also extract the release
states of this updates we assess the
timeliness of these updates and from our
assessment we see that about 80
percentage of the updates are published
within 100 days from their actual date
of effect and of that 20% of the odd
updates are published within
fifteen days or less from the date of
next slide please
then we also look at the community by
assessing the mailing list archives and
we see that over a span of 30 years we
have about 19 thousand emails in total
from 1,800 unique contributors from the
histogram on the right we see an
increasing trend in the number of emails
and contributors after 2012 particularly
after the adoption by I am and this
trend is correlated with an increasing
amount of the database particularly
after the adoption of mobile and smart
devices ingesting information from such
a large number of contributors is a
potential concern from a management
perspective next slide please
so earlier we saw that so most of the
updates deal with DST rule changes so
then we wanted to listen up both these
changes why do we see so many changes
Stevens our hypothesis is that DST rules
are often the changes to DST rules and
often administrative reasons that are
correlated with major events such as
Wohlers
policy changes or major I mean even sex
a travel to evaluate this hypothesis we
analyzed the sorry
also to evaluate this hypothesis we take
the most recent version of the data base
and count the number of updates made to
each time zone or DST rule we generate a
histogram of these changes which are
made by the government entities and then
we group these time zones by country and
then we look at the history of the
country
question so in this example shown here
so we see the histogram of rule changes
for North America and as we hypothesized
after eliminating all noise we see that
a huge number of changes correspond to
major events such as the world war and
policy updates such as the uniform time
Act or the aisle embargo that was in
effect during the energy crisis in the
u.s. so in addition to proving our
hypothesis this also shows that that the
time zone database provides a unique
perspective on world historical events
we see similar results from time zones
belonging to other countries which is
not shown here for space constraints
next slide please
so next we try to identify the problems
and anomalies that are related to the
database updates our intention here is
to highlight the importance and the
impact of these database updates so as
mentioned earlier about 19 percentage of
the updates are flagged as correction
updates by our tool so these are updates
that make changes to previous updates
and we see that most of these
Corrections arise due to incomplete
information being released by
authorities such as authorities just
announcing the start of a new DST policy
without an end date which later need to
be updated but some of those corruption
updates also related to errors that are
actually made in the database these
errors highlight the problems in the
informal update process that has ingest
data from a large number of contributors
and sometimes we see that even correct
database updates making unintended or
causing unintended bugs and other
software systems for example a provision
to include a negative
a time offset in the database broke
several software systems such as open
JDK the Qt framework etc another issue
that we noticed in the database are the
updates is the disruptions caused by
delayed updates which we saw earlier
next slide please
so based on our analysis we have come up
with a set of recommendations which are
intended to improve the security and
integrity of the overall system our
intention here is not to impugn any
individuals who are indeed contributed
significant time and energy in the
upkeep of the database rather our goal
here is to expand perspectives and to
start discussions about this critical
asset and as such we do not provide any
implementation for our accommodation
because these recommendations could be
implemented using standard open-source
tools and other commutations are
intentionally high level we believe that
the details should be fleshed out within
the dzt community next slide please
so our first recommendation is to codify
the overall update process by
introducing more formalization such as
standard release tools standard
documentation ticketing system to track
each and every update and most
importantly a test suite to ensure
correctness of the database we recommend
that these updates are treated in the
same way as Linux kernel patches and
then the overall update process is
extensively extensively really relies on
the primary maintainer or coordinator of
the database so for immortalized
motivated attacker or a government
entity it might be possible to introduce
unwanted updates into the database
through impersonation of the contributor
are the primary maintainer so we
recommend stronger cryptographic
measures to improve security and we also
believe that introducing more
formalization will also help in this
regard by introducing more transparency
and finally we also recommend an
independent third party audit of this
database which could be contacted
periodically and could test the database
from the perspective of end-users from
different time zones next slide please
so in summary we examine how the time
zone database is used by devices
connected on the internet and how it has
evolved we also look at the maintenance
and the update processes and we see that
daylight saving time has a huge impact
on the update process and we also see a
huge amount of effort gone into
maintaining the historical accuracy of
the database based on our observations
we come up with a set of proposals that
will aimed at enhancing the security and
integrity of the database our goal here
is to draw more attention and resources
towards improving this critical asset
next slide please
thank you let's thank the presenter
it's a lot of time for question hello
you mentioned the necessity of having
safeguards against malicious leads of
the database you mentioned a lot of
changes that were actually fixes for
previous changes but did you notice any
actual malicious update in the last 26
years so we have not seen any malicious
updates
but you've seen errors that were cast or
arrested where unintentionally caused
but we do believe there is a weak link
and this could potentially be exploited
by malicious actors yeah my concern was
it's may not be necessary to add new
process new rules new security for
something that may never happen but we
do believe there is a possibility for an
attack due to the informal update
process that is involved and as we've
seen any delay or unintel entrie could
cause mass confusion
totally uncertainty of time so this
could potentially be used by any
malicious actor hi Kunz you recommend it
if using tests as this is not code what
are you testing and how are you going to
so the database actually contains data
and also code
so there are this compiler that compiles
all this data to binary files that are
later used by system utilities so test
could test that code and also it could
test the validity of the entries itself
the whole point of this talk was on the
data know that code which is just a
sample
anyway is that those concerned about
being incorrect right so that's not be
so yeah so finally what this data
accomplishes is for every time zone it
gives you the effective offset from UTC
so the tests could actually make sure
all these offsets are indeed correct so
that could be out the whole point is
this is the database of those offsets
are so what are you testing again check
right so so some of the time zones could
be selected where the test could
manually checked for offsets we could
the test could pick certain time zones
for example the central Daylight Time
where the offset is well known and then
make sure the data is indeed consistent
with that so randomly
time zones across the world can be
picked and then could be checked for
consistency so your test is a separate
database of timezone data of which you
test your time zone database against
yeah maybe in a limited scenario yes one
last quick question
Anjaneya I just have to say thank you
for doing this work excuse me my dogs is
kind of leaving me um but this work is I
think super useful because it shines
light on hidden parts of the internet
that we take for granted and I disagree
with the first person here the Mike who
said if there's been no attack why do we
need to worry about this I think we need
to worry about this because it is a
weakling and I think you're exactly on
the right track with that in terms of
figuring out what tests to you here I
think that's completely reasonable to do
that design elsewhere but I think it is
important that we do some testing and I
completely agree with the general
recommendations that you have my
question to you is do you have any
particular areas in the IETF
that could look at this or is this
something that you have to toss over to
the TCD debe community and hope that
they come up with the process is there
something with the idea yeah I think the
RFC six five five seven that describes
the update process could be looked at
again because some of the processes are
left at the discussion of the user and
for example something like using PGP
signatures to sign the database is left
the text just mentions that the
signature should be used not must be
used so some of these security measures
could be made mandatory and then the
Archie could be looked at so that is
something that I ATF can do thank you
all right
think thanks for taking some time out of
your breaks guys let's thank the
presenter one last time thanks for
sticking around and if the presenters
for the next session want to come and
test their laptops and meet their
session chair just come up here
[Music]