[Music]
this is Jeff Dunham
I suppose all right good afternoon
everybody
I hope you are here for say FRG right
please take your seats
finish your conversations
which I didn't ask okay so see FRG is
part of IR T f so we abide by the same
rules but as i TS oh not well applies I
hope that's not the first time you've
seen it this week I think we have Java
scrub we have no takers you might notice
that we have just use this one so we
have a new co-chair Nick Sullivan
sitting next to me can is absent we also
have C FRG secretary now which is tennis
valve who's going to help us waste time
keeping today very quickly document
status we managed to publish two
documents since Prague
we have rekeying still in our editors
queue our argon too is getting really
really close to being in irst review and
being approved spec to Kenny still need
to have a look at this in the list of
active documents you can see we who
actually cook have accepted quite a lot
of documents we have eight documents at
the moment so quite a lot of work but
some of them in early stages you know
luckily we're not going to publish them
all at the same time chairs rely heavily
on crypto review panel which was formed
in September 2016 the purpose of crypto
review panel is to reviewed to help
review documents Foshee frg whether
they're just beginning their lifecycle
or are in research group last call as
well as helping security area and an
independent stream to get reviews of of
crypto algorithms there were lots of
very good reviews done chairs will be
relying on crypto panel to calc with
reviewing packs admissions in order to
do that we just you know chairs just
realized that the term of existing
members already extended by one year
would have ended in September so
extended until the end of the year also
we are reopening nominations so we are
looking for new new candidates so if you
know somebody who will be good or
whether they have more academic
experience or even in industry and
protocol use experience we are looking
for both please submit nominations by
September 1st to see FRG chairs and self
nominations are very welcome
so don't be shy one of the main sort of
big tasks that we started last time a
spec selection process we have eight
submissions submission nominations ended
in June we got preliminary information
from all submitters the aim is to
hopefully find more than 0 but recommend
or more packs to see FRG recommended
documents
Stanislav is helping out with organizing
the process and he will have a talk at
the end about the current status the
current submissions if people have
suggestions for chairs how to which kind
of questions to ask to help us decide
please contact us either at cfd chairs
or talk to us privately and on that I
think we are starting yes my apologies
we're two minutes late but we'll start
with the first presentation
this is about the hpk draft which is the
current slightly suboptimal name hybrid
public key encryption in that it is the
encryption that combines an asymmetric
operation public key operation with IAD
so this is now graphed IRT f c/f RG h PK
we submitted 0-0 just before the draft
of the main after having a successful
adoption call so let's so made a couple
changes between the the last individual
version in this one that we're kind of
cleanup oriented um sorry I love them
the monitor here is not working so the
main change in this draft was to kind of
clean up the logic we had a diagram like
this in the last deck and we presented
this in Prague that had a lot more boxes
and basically we've pulled all of the
logic into this encryption context
creation function which gets a bunch of
parameters from a setup function
depending on what mode you're in
and then generates a context and some
key announced that you'll use for
encryption operations based on that that
context Thanks so in the earlier draft
in the individual at zero zero we only
had the one mode where you just encrypt
to a public key and zero one we added
these other modes where you can encrypt
or you can encrypt to a public key and
also authenticate that the sender has a
given symmetric secret of PSK or that
the sender has a given private key on
this earth mode one of the things that
this consolidation gave us was that we
can now have a mode where the sender can
prove both of those things they can
prove both that they hold a given
symmetric secret at PSK and that they
hold a given any symmetric private key I
don't know how much you said is I don't
think there's an immediate use case for
that but it just seemed like for the
sake of completeness we have the
capability of why not just add the mode
one of the questions here I'll get to in
a second is whether we think that's
worth it so that that's the major
technical change in draft 0/0 of this
draft otherwise it's it's pretty much
the same as as the earlier versions
since the last IETF we have now two
implementations I've done one and go and
Dave Cridland has done one in Python
these kind of do orthogonal there are
good at orthogonal things so Davis is
really nice because the pseudo code and
it's in the spec is kind of Python
looking and Dave's is in pseudo code is
in Python and huge very closely to the
the pseudo code that's in the draft so
it's very easy to understand that way
I've my go implementation is a little
bit more completeness oriented so it
covers all the cipher suites that are in
the draft right now and as of yesterday
include psych as a kind of a
demonstration proof case that we can
integrate a post quantum count because
one of the things we did in zero zero
one was like it changed from a th
orientation to a camera orientation with
this idea that we could use post quantum
chemist air and you know we have at
least kind of empirical code based
validation that that's possible I've
been had this reviewed by anyone it may
be using it completely in securely but
it at least like compiles and runs and
passes tests and it was actually a
pretty small patch like once we had the
framework for this set up it was really
just that that little bit of glue code
to get the post problem can patched in
so I think it's kind of a promising sign
for the ability of this construction to
evolve forward into a post quantum world
there was some discussion on the mailing
list and during the adoption hall about
some other things one might ask for out
of this this construction and I think
that we discussed in the list and I
think that we kind of got some pretty
good consensus on not addressing some of
these things right now so forward
secrecy is kind of not a sensible thing
to address here that's kind of a
property of the key that you are
encrypting to so we're going to build a
construction here for encrypting to a
public key and then forward secrecy
properties depend on how you rotate that
public key and things like that so it is
we're building up something here that
you can then embed into other systems
that provide things like forward secrecy
MLS for example will provide foreign
secrecy in PCs properties
k-ci resistance honestly I'm not you
know the I don't feel like I deeply
understand this but I some other folks
who can help be honest on this I think
the the the all of the words in this
this bullet here makes sense if you have
a one-round can
based protocol we can't resist that
style of attack um you need something
like digital signatures from from the
sender to make that possible and I think
the feeling right now is it doesn't make
sense to add in that extra machinery to
get that property again if you need that
property you can add it in higher layers
higher layers than this I'm finally post
quantum um I don't think it makes sense
to put that in the spec right now as I
as I said in the last slide we kind of
demonstrated that it works so it's good
to have that validation it's possible
but I don't think it makes sense like to
find cipher suites that are post partum
cams right now because we just we don't
have anything that's kind of ready for
to have a code point quite yet so that's
kind of the state of the art where the
frame a couple questions for the working
group because you know now that we've
got it adopted we can start thinking
about how do we get it to the state of
completion dan you have question Dan
Harkins if the sender reused his key
pair and then the D H K M then the
context would produce the same secret in
the same nonce right no because there's
an ephemeral key pair that's generated
in D H Kim case there's a ephemeral
keeper that's generated that is fed into
the context that generates the key and
the nonce so that each encryption fresh
entropy it's impossible to do static
static in the D hm
Chris you're not in can you better than
Mike maybe that's okay nodding is this
one okay yeah I don't there is no mode
where everything is static yeah yeah so
think about now like what do we need to
do to get to completion here I think the
major question in my mind here is is
this draft I'm trying to do too much
there's all these modes we talked about
how you authenticate the sender in these
various ways we've got we talked about
how you do multiple encryptions off with
a single context generation I think the
feeling of the authors with those that
those things were useful we had kind of
demonstrated use cases from some of the
prior art with Nicole and things like
that where people were using doing
making uses that have
same general shape so it made sense to
cover those in this talk but I could
understand if you've wanted to slim this
down and and have a more straightforward
doctor review and do analysis on so
people have lots of comments on that we
lengthen the jabber room Tania lang it
depends on how they define ephemeral as
one time Moshe Schwartz tongue yeah I
think that's I think it in the sense in
which we mean ephemeral here is that the
the key pair has generated for the
purpose of the single encryption so it
really is one-time use Adam Adam Langley
so if you're worried about doing too
much I think the example of noise might
be useful if you've seen noise to say a
framework for to party communication
protocols which has generated like noise
Explorer which generates like formal
proofs of many many of these things and
tells you exactly what properties you
get and so forth like that I think was
useful and demonstrated that you know
you could do something worthwhile with
an over general system so if you go
there I think like being general is good
but this is the ITF and obviously
they've been plenty of protocols they've
been over general and that hasn't
produced any positive effects so when
you say go there what do you mean I mean
if you start add you've got four modes
now I'm sure there were others in your
mind and and so forth so it I guess I'm
saying like look at some of noise
Explorer as as I think a high point of
what you can do with a more general
framework and if you don't want to you
don't do all that then like trim stuff
away this you mean yeah I think analysis
was the the other big thing we're
waiting on here I think the INRIA team
at least are looking to do like a single
composed analysis of this much like you
did a single compose notes on TLS from
which the verification modes kind of
falls out of special cases I think this
is still a slow enough target that
that's a reasonable thing to do
the logic is fairly well consolidated
and so I think I think if this is kind
of our thuggin all approaches to the
noise compositional approach in the
noisy explore approach but I think this
is still reasonably
simply composed to make that sort of
serving else as possible of course I
don't do the analysis and so I can't let
speak authoritative look at that yeah
yeah Riyadh Wahby if you were removing
things what would you remove like you
say are we doing too much there are four
options if you had your druthers would
you remove any of them I think the
simplest the the thing that would could
would be removed that would make the
most impact is the modes in which the
sender's are authenticated with an
asymmetric key because this requires
this authen cap off the cap thing which
is only like I don't know if that really
extends to any non d.h Kem's and we just
kind of define it that hoc for kemp's
now that I mean that is if you look for
if you're looking for like a feature
parity with the Box API I think that is
that feature exists there so there's
some benefits of having it there but it
does introduce some additional
complexity into the spec and you know
it's more more optional things to keep
around as one more thought would it be
reasonable to consider removing the
unauthenticated case there arguably
there's no reason to use it on
authenticated so I don't not sure it
would streamline things much that's here
that was what I was suspecting so yeah I
mean it might streamline things if you
are going to remove focusing on only the
PSK case or only the authentic a
symmetric case right if you were going
to do one of those then you could cut
out awesome stuff related to the
unauthenticated case but if you're going
to have both of those and you're gonna
have some optional stuff on both sides
then the the unauthenticated case kind
of remove it emerges as a special case
so yeah I'm not sure that's simplify so
I appreciate the the the instinct Thanks
yeah hi Giselle if this were a working
group I would say like we would really
want to take out things we didn't have a
work use case for as a research group on
may be less inclined to that but I think
probably if we can trim stuff out it
would be better both for the amount of
work involved in improving it but as you
say some some things may just fall out
and it may be a non-issue but it kind of
helps to have glasses more yeah I
appreciate that I mean personally my
feeling is that we've got a reasonably
consolidated set of logic the thing that
honestly makes me question of the aspect
of the I question knows does the the
both know where we have both a PSK and
an asymmetric keeper because that's not
there's nothing in the art that does
that right now so it's not clear there's
a case well although it may be used
writing still writing my MLS slides
there might be an application for that
in MLS but it's not anything like the
open source software now so that that
thing that I'm it's least clear that
there's a use for but at the same time
it's basically zero cost because all the
machinery is there for the the other two
notes so so my inclination is going to
keep things as they are but I'm open to
arguments of people are really concerned
about complexity here otherwise I think
Karthik and company and welcome other
analysis or think Karthik is ready to
kind of proceed ahead with doing
verification on on the full construction
okay
last issue I had which naming came up on
list and people didn't like HP key a so
I figured you know I got a couple
minutes left give people a chance to sit
last chance to come up to Pine
alternative names this is this was the
best we that the authors came up with
and so my proposals like let's call it h
PK or let's call it cashier and let's
consider the question done I would
propose we stick with hhp ke but if
someone wants to stand up for the
alternate there be my guess yeah I love
cashews I don't they care for this name
let's just stick with the HP key
anything it provided me an expansion
we're on okay that's all I got
go down the italics
Stanislav smush laughs Crypt approach
and this is a very short overview about
MGM mode which has been standardized in
Russia s an ad mode in 2019 the
description became available two years
ago and the motivation for the
development was such that have known
security issues face gtam and GTM was
not so widespread so it we have a chance
to make something you know but the
designers were late to see the contest
so it was not nominated this is only an
informative talk without any plans for
adoption at least now so the scheme is
on the slide basically an encryption
process is counter mode and the
authentication process is kinda like
Gmail from GCM but with a new secret
value for each new block of data and
with separate counters with separate
nonces and with additional operations at
the end of the process so if we consider
the function properties that are
satisfied for GCM who may say that
except for one except for the sixth one
they are inspired for MGM mmm and with
the sixth one it is how satisfied
because if we have our knowns
beforehand then we
make these recommendations for austa
gated data so the difference is that for
GCM we doesn't mean we don't need a
nonce to go with the data and for MGM we
do so there are some protections against
lengthen extension next X is mixing in
thanks it end of the process and
protection against predictable
collisions of counters do two separate
initial values of counters and different
processes of increment so and if we have
a very brief overview of attacks on G
same when we see that for all these
kinds of attacks on G same let me see
that MGM have has some countermeasures
to protect against the encryption of
things here and there in this even
process usage of separate and distant a
secret values for each block during a
special operation to control fate
Saarinen like attacks we have some
security bound obtained and the present
in this paper shows this light and the
last light very shot comparison without
a ad modes it can be seen that but for
GCM it is right that none of the modes
is better for in for all properties so
there is a subset a certain subset of
properties for which MGM can be
preferred so it can be used for some
certain applications when its properties
are desired that's all and there are
some backup lights so that you can use
if you want some additional operation
one very minor detail GCM also has the
interesting property that you could
ah floor Cisco Systems GCM also has the
additional property that you can
actually implement it so that you can
start encrypting before you know the age
of the additional data even how long the
initial data is a very minor detail but
yeah it's there so instinctive recommend
so in fact yes the same in fact has a
lot of good control properties and not
all of them are enumerated in this light
and if you'd like any comments about how
some of them are or are not satisfied
for mjm I'd be happy to comment so seems
like it has some real advantages over
GCM so why are you so which makes me
that it would be better well in some
respect to using a SGC I mean say TLS
right dislike so why are you not asking
for reduction so I'd like to announce
here that I'm not the design MGM so I
was the guy who was who conducted some
part of gnosis of it so I can't comment
all design ideas of it well the idea was
to take all the best from the same but
to fight its weak points but of course
you know it's slower if to talk about
[Music]
implementations without communism but if
you implement this in parallel you can
address each block one by one at the
same time in parallel mode hello
my question is really about the security
comparison to AAS GCM none of the
attacks you cited actually the
probability what many attacks you cited
break break break free speed security of
a mistress yet they're the the forgery
probability is exactly what it says on
the slides and looks like MGM is
actually slightly
works from the answer so less efficient
and there are what are the properties
you're gaining with MGM over ASG cm so
thank you very much for patient yes in
fact in addition to the control measures
against certain attacks
on GGN MGM also has better guilty bounds
if we consider synthesis they are on
this back up slide so you can see that
for some typical values of length and
number of blocks
I'm gem is better and also in some
positions when some forbidden actions
like non 3 use happen it has a little
less impactor security so of course the
comparison of the modes can be on the
back tables but if we see that in season
two bounds see for which cases MGM looks
better
we may see some applications when it can
be preferred but I have nothing against
it in fact it's just an information
about modes that is slower in some sense
but that has some stronger security
parameters in other sense but and I
would add that for example for fidelity
MGM has a little weaker form of the
security maturity bounds because of the
fact that it has to deal with that
additional bit just played to counters
for encryption and for authentication so
this presentation was not about given
all the details of gem and I think I am
I don't have any time left but I'll be
happy to comment etcetera
yeah so but on your package slide it
looks like this and the backup slide you
have GCM preferring anything
so what for community betters and you
seem a little and for simplicity
MGM is much better please refer to the
slides
thank you so hello everyone I am so
corny so up and it is my first idea TF
and I'm grateful to give a presentation
here the today I would talk about
pairing friendly curbs so first of all I
give a brief overview of this
presentation so pairing based
cryptography which I will explain later
is getting widely used and the security
evaluation of pairing friendly curves
which realize pairing web-based
cryptography has been changed due to the
attack proposed in 2016 so introducing
secure / secure pairing friendly curves
the after this attack are required so
the the - so the this program the goal
of our draft is to show the latest
security evaluation of well-known
pairing friendly curves and to show the
pyramid new new parameters for pairing
friend records with each security level
namely 128-bit or higher so
our draft is strongly related to the
existing existing energy items the
area's signature scheme is one of the
examples of pairing based cryptography
and behavior signature scheme you uses
the hashing true pairing friendly curves
specified enhancing to elliptic curves
so thankfully this drop drafts refer
referring to to our drafts so let me
explain the parent with more details
about pairing based cryptography pairing
based cryptography is a kind of elliptic
curve cryptography the main difference
is it utilized the special map called
pairing so and thanks to the property of
pairing the the cryptography with more
more functionality can be can be
realized and getting widely used here
are the examples of standards in
implementations of parent based
cryptography for example so so we can
see you can see you can see in CDA a
specified by TCG Fido and CC C and Intel
SGX CID for the remote remote we wrote
anonymous attestation which realizes the
attestation in privacy-preserving manner
another example is pls signatures which
real of which enable signature
aggregation and realizes the compression
of certificates the signature of
certificate chain or the signatures of
blockchain and so on
more addition the potential potential
schemes are proposed in the research
paper and can be realized in the future
so like standard elliptic curves the
parent based cryptography requires
underlying elliptic curves that is the
elliptic curve cryptography like sed sa
easy th and is EDD sa require you
require underlying elliptic curves
defined by NIST safety and CFR G
similarly parent based cryptography like
BLS signatures required pairing friendly
curves and likelike elliptic curve
cryptography the security of pairing
friendly preparing based cryptography is
estimated by the security of parenting
friendly curves so let me explain what
pairing is so so this this slide
contains the the equations but but they
appears in only tooth right so okay so
pairing a also known as the Polly near
map is a map from the group g1 and g2 on
to the group GT which satisfies this
equation in general g1 a group g1 and g2
is a subgroup of elliptic curve groups
and GT is submerged creative group of
finite field so there are various
pairing proposed
and optimal egg pairing is is considered
to be most efficient and popular to
compute pairings absently pairing
friendly curbs are introduced example of
pairing friend records include being
krob pls curve and so on so and BLS
curve varies in their embedded degrees
so and the parent render occurs varied
in their key lengths which determines
the security strengths so we called the
parent friend curves like so by their
car family and key lengths such as the
m25 4v n 2 2 2 5 6 and so on
so how how can we evaluate the security
or pairing frontier curves as shown in
the previous slide pairing the parent
friend records contains three groups G 1
and G 2 is chosen by the elliptic curve
groups they are based on a CD LP
elliptic curve discrete logarithm
problem
by contrast
GT is chosen by a multiplicative group
of all finite field so they are alike
they rely on finite field discrete
logarithm problem so so we have to
consider up so in in the general
standard elliptic curve cryptography we
can only consider gg1
but in parent preparing based
cryptography we have to consider both g1
and g2 and GT and the difficult
computational the complexity of a CD LP
is known as sub exponents of
exponentiation and but the complexity of
GT is known as sub exponential so we
have to consider the difficulty of GT in
12 in 2016 the the algorithm to solve FF
DLP was proposed so so at first at first
there okay so so due to the attack the
security level of all pairing friend
recurves has fallen so so we have to
consider the new security evaluation of
pairing friendly curves for example
after this algorithm being 2 5 6 6 which
regarded as 128-bit secure so far fallen
to the 100 bits of security now so so
introducing new sickness new parameter
for 1 128 security level is required
so in our draft we select the parameters
for each level low security in terms of
the
security and also the efficiency to it
since when implemented and how wide they
they are used now based based on the
this evaluation we are in our draft well
the one hand 128 bits of security and
256 bits of security are introduced so
so so my our our opinion is these two
security level sufficient so so we are
wondering what what what 192 bits of
security parameters are should be
defined so candidate curve is BLS 24 for
family and several papers for this
security level are proposed but no
implementation are published so far so
our question is how can we treat one 192
bit parameters to answer the question
here I give one fact in you us seen NSS
which the persecutor parameters for
asymmetric cryptography are said to be
192 bits of security but on the other
hand the status statistics says that the
theorist servers the safety in the tiara
servers supports to 250 256 bits of
security rather than one
ninety-two security so so based on them
our consideration is we we can we can
select on the 128-bit of security and to
256 security so here is the history of
our draft we after the initial
submission we gave we so many comments
are posted in the mailing list and
revised according to them so so if you
interested in we we proceed our process
that old yeah we'll take one question
and after that yeah really quick we're
behind Riyadh Wahby sorry real quick um
so the I emailed you about this but
maybe it's a question for the wider
audience one of the major applications
of paring base crypto as was mentioned
the slides are for pairing based
arguments snarks BLS 12 3 D 1 is
designed for that purpose none of the
other pairing friendly curves being
proposed aren't well known but the bien
curves are but let's ignore those
they're too low security so the question
is is it worthwhile to also define 192
bit or 256 bit argument friendly pairing
friendly curves it may be no because
already the provers work in Starks is
preposterous ly bad and so like 192 or
200 pieces acure 'ti is like
unbelievably slow so it is not not my
our our go to speech by variety many
curves so so we have to consider the the
the yes the the multiple parameters are
good but so so many parameters are not
not for implement a turn implementers to
implement because they are confused
which curve to be implemented yeah
that's totally fair like I said I'm not
aware of any applications that really
need that highest security but it's
something to consider because you know
it may be that in two years everyone
wants to do it and then oh no we need to
add a curve so for example if no one as
far as I know no one is actually using
BLS 48 5 anyone that's just like some
curve that you know we run on our
laptops to bench market or something
right so I don't know maybe there's a
VLS 48 587 that is you know that would
be reasonable to use with with hearing
based arguments in which case maybe it
would be worthwhile to uh standardize
that instead of 581 I don't know I like
I said I don't actually know if people
are using 581 and I wouldn't suggest
that we get rid of it if they are but if
they aren't let's let's keep this on the
mailing let's move this to the mailing
list really quick ok there apparently
there is another option which is optimal
TNF SCO pairings on elliptic curves with
composite embedding degree and there's a
link to a paper I knows interested great
let's discuss that nonetheless
last question I just wanted to thank you
for bringing this work to the CFR G I
think it's very important we have a use
case for where we're interested in
identity based cryptography and we're
going to need to some standardized
curves and so I'd like to see let's go
forward ok and before we move forward if
it's good to to see if anybody else here
in the room has applications of parent
risk cryptography that they need to so
rather than a hum if someone has an
application please raise your hand
okay so not many but a few
[Music]
the next presentation is going to be
remote and need to be in the control of
the slides but rightly open you want we
can't hear you
to present again we'll see if it works
no it's a struggle we we can smoke
presentations we'll give you another
chance later on better yes okay
good old leave the page open the page
again that's the trick great we can hear
you we can hear you and just let us know
when to advance the slides okay let go
so thanks a lot for allowing me to
present my work I'm a little para I'm in
Paris right now I'm a postdoc at an area
and what I'm going to talk about is this
paper that I authored which was
published at dusk to the conference for
symmetric crypto and its consequences
regarding to RFC's so I'm going to tell
you what the results presented in this
paper is and why it is inconsistent with
the claims of the designers of said
algorithms next slide so I'm going to go
quickly over the general context of this
work well what are standards but
obviously I'm going to spend too much
time on that and what are s-boxes then
I'm going to talk specifically about the
sbox of these two algorithms and finally
tell you why I don't like this S box
next slide next slide so the lifetime of
an algorithm can be represented in this
way next slide so you have these three
faces the design the analysis and the
deployment I'm not going to remind you
what the actors are I believe you're all
familiar with them next slide so when we
design a new algorithm we come up with a
scope statement and we write down its
specification and much more importantly
we make choices during the design and we
justify them so we explain them and we
justify them in the specification and we
also do a first security analysis
next slide so we put this all in a
publication and then the public so the
general general academic community we
try and break said algorithms next slide
if we managed we put it in the trash if
not next slide
eventually the algorithm the algorithms
are trusted and they are standardized
and then they will be implemented in
actual products until a new attack is
found hopefully not but perhaps this is
the ideal world and indeed it actually
happens in this way in many cases but
not always next slide
sometimes we have an algorithm which is
designed by unknowns which is
standardized right away and we don't
have the publication with all the
explanation of all the design choices in
this context and as you can see there is
no trust anymore on these slides next
slide the problem we have in this case
is that there could be hidden defects in
the algorithm since for the analysis we
can not leverage all this public
information all this explanation about
the design choices etc we could overlook
some aspect of the design and miss a
flaw but the flow could be intentional
or not it could be a perfectly honest
mistake that we still cannot see because
we don't have this information next
slide an sbox is a very popular
component of symmetric algorithms it's
usually the only nonlinear one so an
sbox is a small nonlinear function which
is so small that you can specify it
using its lookup table so typical size
are four or eight each and they can be
designed in very different ways so this
is a survey I'm majoring my PhD there
are many different structures I'm not
going to go over them
next slide how do we justify the choice
of an sbox
we can just look at what the designers
of the alias' did so this page you can
see was taken from the document with
your URL I put in my slide it was
written by the AES designers and as you
can see they have first appeared design
goal so they want their s box to be
invertible etc
then they explain the motivation for the
specific solution they chose so it
turned out there was a paper explaining
that the inverse was very nice so they
went with that they also identified the
possible issue with this approach which
is that the ad break expression could be
too simple and this could be an issue so
they found a way to remedy that and then
finally they described the process they
use to choose the actual sbox of the
cipher the one they actually used so
this is how it should be done and how it
is often done this is not how it was
done for these two algorithms slide
these two algorithms
it's the hash functions three bug and
the block cipher quiz Nicci hash
function and the block cipher both are
standards in Russia both are RFC's
although not from the CFR G the chair's
insisted on that they are from the
independent stream they were designed by
the TC 26 along with the company and the
TC 26 is a committee which is supervised
by the FSB what matters to me for now is
that both of these algorithms use the
same a t-test box which they denoted by
slide over time so first this algorithm
these algorithms were published by the
ghost so the Russian standardizing
agency and as RFC's after that next
slide we looked at them with my then
colleagues from Luxembourg and we found
two decompositions of this S box so we
found two ways of writing it which was
very puzzling for us we found the first
one and then we found the second one
which was completely different so the
conclusion of these two papers was that
this S box was very mysterious and there
was more to it than we could find after
that next slide
it was standardized tree bug was
certified standardized by ISO after that
I found the final decompositions that's
the one in the paper I mentioned on my
very first slide the this is the final
decomposition because
it explains the other two the first to
the competitions are just side effects
of this one and it's much simpler so at
that point problem solved that's how
they beat the sbox or so I thought
next slide the discussions are still
ongoing at ISO so they were supposed to
standardize whose net cheek but they
decided instead postpone the decision
for six months until they had the time
to figure out the consequences of my
work and next slide they would have to
take a decision in September so I
mentioned I saw a lot here because
actually there were like a side channel
as you will see next slide so why do I
not like said sbox slide that's what we
know about them this is all the
information that was provided by their
designers the lookup table it's all you
need if you want to implement the
ciphers or the Alameda cipher or the
hash function but if you want to
evaluated security it's not sufficient
next slide
however during discussions that I saw
the designers of three began whose
Nietzsche did provide them some
information at ISO it's behind closed
doors but this information was leaked so
I have put the URLs on my slides and in
these documents you can read what is on
the slide namely that the sbox PI was
obtained by so the random search no
secret structure was enforced during its
construction this is wrong what I have
proved in this paper at dusk was that Pi
was actually described by these very
simple equations so these the designers
defend themselves now saying basically
what is written on the second block at
the same time it is obvious that for any
transformation a lot of representations
are possible
basically what they say is that yes Pi
has the structure it is impossible to
deny you can just check it however had
they picked the next day's box in the
generation process I would have found
another structure in it this is wrong
next slide
to see why it's wrong we need to come up
with a sensible definition of simplicity
that we can still evaluate so that's
exactly what we did there are about two
to the 1684 8-bit permutations so in any
given language you're going to need at
least one thousand six hundred eighty
four bits be able to represent all of
them and most of them will have a very
long representation the number of those
boxes with a short representation is at
most the number of bit strings of this
length next slide and this is an
implementation of Pi it's C not super
readable C but perfectly compatible C
and it's only 1155 bits long next slide
in fact we invited the code golf
community at Stack Exchange to come up
with the best implementations they could
find so the shortest and one of them
found by one odds-on is only 624 bits
long next slide the probability that for
a random s box is the one that you have
obtained by a random search is that
simple
meaning that it can be implemented by
your program is short is that most two
to the minus 1,000 and that's assuming
all bit strings correspond to the
umbrella C to the amd64 bit code
implementing a permutation it's not it's
wrong it's a very it's not a tight
estimate at all it's an upper bound and
this upper bound on the probability is 2
to the minus 1,000 which I hope you will
agree is very low next slide so where do
we go from here slide this statement by
the designers that they had not enforced
any structure in their algorithm cannot
be reconciled with the shortness of
their implementation of the
implementation of the rest box it is not
possible to generate an S box at random
and obtain in the output something with
this simple structure
by chance the probability is so low that
it's young negligible we're happy with
256 bits of security here we have 1,000
next slide I think what this means is
that the designers have provided
misleading information for the
cryptographers who wanted to analyze
their design at first they said nothing
which is not the best practice and then
at ISO they provided wrong information
next slide I don't need to tell you how
hard it is to do the security analysis
of an algorithm even if we have all the
data in the world from the designers and
all the goodwill from the designers if
we have not just an absence of
information but wrong information it's
even more difficult and there is I can't
think of any good reason to complete
gate further the task of external
cryptographers next slide that's why I
think the designers of these algorithms
cannot be trusted these algorithms
cannot be trusted and why I believe they
should be deprecated I don't think we
want to have Arabs RFPs for those and
that's it for me thank you
okay any questions I agree we should
stop using them but really encourage
people to find out how they go I assume
that the some jiggering going on and I
really be interested to see how it could
be exploited which will be the next part
but we don't need to see the exploit in
order to stop using it we'll cut the
line here okay
your veneer so I guess you don't want me
to write using this check for TLS ting
okay
every person is saying that either is
standardizing it and they are making the
decision in September suppose they do
who needs to use this what does it mean
that is the PI server is standardizing
it I encourage you to watch a talk given
by a tool Louis at real world crypto
this year where he talks about the
impact of an Isis realization in this
case he was worried about Simon inspect
the ciphers from the NSA but a nice
Western realization can have more
consequences in the sense that it could
be enforceable in some cases to use
these algorithms like to force people to
use these algorithms if I'm not mistaken
but I thought explains it well in this
real real world crypto presentation it's
on YouTube I am a little concerned about
the things you've raised here but I also
feel like we've heard this story in the
1970s when Marty Hellman said hey
there's something funny with these des s
boxes don't know what it is but it
doesn't feels right there's a cemetry in
there and then it turned out that that
symmetry was put there to defeat
differential cryptanalysis it just
wasn't publicly known yet I don't know
if that's what's going on here or
something else but you don't know you
just know something smells funny right
is that
yes there is a big difference also as
far as I know in the case of the des the
NSA never said anything that's what they
tend to do if you talk with them at
conferences they don't say anything in
this case they said something which was
wrong I believe that a big difference I
agree with that
the difference was the ISO registry
didn't exist back but as well as much
live release many sense for your work
I'm not a designer of software company
in Russia that uses these algorithms in
the software that is provided for
government and its proponent and so I'm
really very proud of you that you're
spending so much time on agencies
because really an algorithm that is used
must be analyzed thoroughly but I have
to mention two issues with his lights
first of it's that absence of public
information before standardization is
not fully correct even your in your
paper you size papers of 2014 and for
three book moreover it was a public
contest I agree that it was not as
public as it could be worldwide but
least was public with some prizes and a
lot of people outside of Russia
participated but in any case I totally
agree with you that any analysis and
currently should be done and about your
point about the conclusion in fact I
really want you to find your find some
time to continue your efforts because
any concerns and any questions about
structures must be answered but if you
be honest if you would find something
like Ferguson and zoom off in 2007 when
there was a statement like if the
designer see you such disagree soon then
as a sergeant I can be mounted then if
you had some statements a statement then
the question about it will be state
Russia will be stating and I saw
everywhere but if you just say that
there are some some concerns and even
the paper that you say a paper of silly
old they also say it all says that there
are quite different sins and the cosets
is the only word that is in common so
you say that there are some structures
and some another structure can be used
for exploit but they're really different
structures it's like saying that when
you use drbg use elliptic curves and it
has by door and then easy to say has a
bell - - so of course you have very good
results
and they want you to be to continue it
but they don't show anything about
attack or back door now but of course
you should continue or can't it will
will be very good if you will find some
some some attack or some method we'll be
happy to discuss it with you and maybe
you I hope that NASA will be found and
if not then it's just concern a question
why such site property who are not
disclosed or if it was known by
designers but it's there's no reason to
say about mega door or some attack it's
just some properties so I never claimed
I had an attack actually was always here
at least the paper I hope it's clear
that I do not have an attack that
exploit these properties
I do not that's that's a fact and yes
there has been some external treat
analysis of his algorithms especially
streebek there was indeed a three-block
competition but at the time the
cryptographers could not also check the
impact of the structure of the sbox they
had the designers chose they could
analyze the cipher from its
specification but that's all they had to
work with and i think it's a bad thing i
teach it i think should have had all the
information at hand from the get-go I
shouldn't have to spend three years
finding it by hand
and also so yes indeed so I didn't talk
about it in my in this talk because I
didn't have time in because it was
perhaps a bit too it would take me too
far but the fact is that this sbox
interacts in a non-trivial way with who
sets of the subfield so it interacts
with additive Co sets which is exactly
what we are used so it's not completely
different health of the pattern involves
additive Co sets which is exactly what
was used in the back door of cereal and
many the other half is indeed
multiplicative coset which is different
that's also a fact at the same time the
designers of three bug also did not
disclose the way the linear layer was
built and the way this linear layer is
built is using matrices with
coefficients in the finite field and
it's the same finite field as the one
used to design the sbox
so the linear layer also interacts in a
non-trivial way with the sub field and
its multiplicative Co sets and that's
something we don't understand right now
so I cannot exploit this for an attack
again I want to be very clear on that I
do not have an attack I can't decipher
but it's more than just finding a
specific structure and not liking it I
have good reasons not to like it
and one of these roots one of these
reasons is because again it interacts
with the subfields in a way which we
don't understand so well and we don't
know how it interacts with a linear
layer but the main reason which has
little to do with the specifics of the
property is indeed the fact that the
designers did not disclose it what I
have established what I have proved with
this good god thing is that it had to be
put there by someone such a structure
does not happen by chance I don't know
who else someone is I don't know why but
it was good there on purpose we've got
to move on to the next presentation
we're well behind so I mean is this
going to be a very short question or
something that can be taken to the rest
most of the comments
made by previous commanders so I have
her just a couple of notices one is that
I see logically in the statement then if
something can be effectively presented
in computational meaning it could be it
should be not taken by chance or by any
other things that's right I I do not see
logic in in that another one color
coincide it is that I would like to have
a great thank to the presenter to their
bringing attention to the possible
effectively computational representation
of the ends boxes but developers of the
strivers are very thankful to you for
that and for atella
bringing the attention of code golfers
though they're having more efficient
computation or representations which is
extremely important in constrained
environments thank you okay thank you
and we'll thank you for your
presentation unless you hiked all that
you're okay okay good yeah let's try to
keep it fast so we can okay this is a
quick update on hatch the curve one of
the updates appears on this slide I'm a
new author and so is Armando
Rhonda's put in a ton of work so he's
not here but thank him so in general we
can think of hash to curve the way that
we're describing at the document in kind
of three steps the first step is hashing
from an arbitrary string to an element
of a finite field the second is going
from the element the finite field to a
point on the elliptic curve and then the
third is clearing the cofactor for any
curve that has a non unity cofactor and
so the goal is to make all three of
these steps constant time so in
particular there is no hash and test or
hunt-and-peck or ever you want to call
it in this draft that is a conscious
choice
we don't think people should use it
there are fast algorithms for
essentially every curve so let's talk a
little bit about the changes hash to
base so
we've added in this new draft explicit
security requirements this means how you
choose the hash function how many bytes
you extract from the input string the
goal here is to get collision resistance
and to get uniform distribution over the
field we've made very recently a change
to build the hash to base from HK DF the
idea there is to defend us defend
ourselves against cases where the hash
function underlying that is less than
perfect one thing and this was a
suggestion from Co tech we and Sergey
gorbunov who are working on the pls
signatures is what we call pre hash for
free the idea here is hash to base is
designed in such a way that no matter
what you do you only have to pass over
the input string once so what this means
is that if an invoking protocol forgets
to or it doesn't want to define a pre
hash mode that's okay you can still get
the efficiency of only passing over the
input once and finally we've recently
had a domain separation guidelines
domain separation in general is not a
magic bullet but it can save you and it
can be useful in you know proving
properties about sort of compositions of
protocols so our hope is that people
will use it proactively and we give some
guidelines for how to do that as far as
the Maps so this is sort of the the
bread and butter of the hash to curve
this is all the algebra is so one a few
things that we've done in this draft one
we specify how to choose the sine of the
resulting point this is different than
what was going on before and the goal
here is we don't want to have to tell
implementers this is the way you must
compute square root because of course
square root can give you two possible
values implement it however you want we
can you will still be able to
interoperate with other people as long
as you fix the sign up at the end we've
explicitly handled all the exceptional
cases or at least that's the intention
perhaps or something we didn't that we
missed but if we have please bring that
to our attention we've removed the swu
algorithm in favor of a generalized
version the simplified SW so the
simplified version is faster and it
covers now all the same curves let's
push talk about IPR to the end because
there may be something now we've also
unified the way that elliegator 2 is
done for the Montgomery and Edwards
curves the goal here is
if somebody is implementing something
over say curfew fare 1/9 it'll be
possible to for you know one
implementation to work on the Edwards
curve and another implementation to work
on the Montgomery curve and that's okay
you can still arrive at the same answer
in an efficient way and finally we've
added it's a new map for pairing
friendly and some other curves based on
some work that Dan banana I will present
it chess in about a month not much to
talk about in in the clear cofactor so
I'll jump right to the Suites so the
idea of Suites is we're trying to give
people sort of a menu like if you just
want to you know pop into the into the
document you have your curve already in
mind here's how to do it so right now
we're specifying sweets for then this
curves and you can see them on the slide
there and the goal is we're gonna
provide for all of these sweets sort of
constant time optimized pseudocode and
of course constant time with the proviso
that all the underlying primitives are
constant time that's out of scope for
the document so for example we're not
going to tell you how to do constant
time multiplication because you know but
know that better than I do certainly but
the assumption is as long as you have
those the result will be constant time
and we're gonna like I said we're gonna
give that for all the sweets there are
some other planned additions so one
thing we need to do is cover more curves
we'll certainly cover all the curves
from appearing friendly drafts because
that's a place where people really tend
to be attached a curve and another thing
that we're considering is sort of a way
of helping people to sort of choose the
this week that we would have chosen if
we were thinking about the curve that
you're thinking about but we didn't
think about for some reason so that
brings us to the kind of open questions
a couple that I have are are there any
curves that people want to see covered
aren't currently specific question are
there any super singular curves that
people care about we could imagine
putting some in just for funds perhaps
like seaside related curves but as far
as we can tell there isn't much going on
that actually has a lot of use of this
so not obvious that we should be
incorporating it I PR concerns this is
going to become a big thing I'm sure so
it appears that the e cart algorithm is
covered by look I'm not a patent lawyer
so this is only I'm reporting what
jornatha has talked about on the list
thank him by the way for good work there
so ecard appears to be calm
covered by a patent simplified SW also
appears to be mentioned in a patent but
in a much narrower way again with the
proviso that I'm nothing like a lawyer
so we need some fallback solution one
possibility is to bring back SW u and
we've talked about this on the list I
have an alternative proposal which is to
use the sort of the shallow end of
boosting map which is what underlies
that's the SMW and SW u so sorry to cool
us we're not trying to kick you out the
idea is it's possible actually to get an
even more general map than SW u with
essentially the same performance and
actually a simpler interface
so whereas SW you kind of breaks the
abstraction that we're trying to build
for map to curve shallow and bundle
esteem me you know works with the same
interface so from our perspective it's
strictly better but of course we want to
hear your feedback on that so at this
point I'd love to hear any feedback
anything that we're not covering right
now any bugs in the document actually
thank you Dan Harkins who has already
pointed out some bugs in the document
it's getting better thank you okay all
right thanks for the thanks Scott and
let's move on to the pake yeah just
physical questions so are you thinking
it's one more revision a couple of
revisions before last call or it
certainly depends on how we count
revisions and hey we can do we could
probably crush it all into one just yeah
in principle it's pretty close basically
it seems like it's pretty close there's
organizational concerns and clarity
concerns that we're learning about and
we have to cover a few more curves but I
don't think there are huge changes
coming thank you so
so these dozen Flav again
now that's every secretary so we have
this ongoing process of that selection
process and I'd like to give an overview
of our current status so it all started
at ATF 103 when there was a decision to
start the process to involve review
panel to come up with recommendations
and when does it was a decision to try
to select zero more one or more packs to
recommend to the community so we have
the following timeline on stage 2 stage
1 we had our call for candidates and
first-round discussions of the list of
questions to be asked and stage 2 we
have collected we collected responses
from the designers of the protocols for
all positions of RFC
8125 with the requirements for packs and
all additional questions that we
collected at stage 1 now we have four
stages in the future and the stages are
about reviewing first of all we will
have call for viewers for the enumerated
questions because some of them are not
about security assessment and so they
are better to be done not by panel
members but and by independent people
who know a lot of particular stuff
related to these questions then the
reviewers make this rare analysis and
then review panel members provide
overall reviews for each candidate and
in the end say for the chairs discuss
reviews and try to make some
recommendations and if they're ready to
make some recommendations then at ATF
106 some acts are selected and a
production of document like
recommendations for a sophisticated key
agreement in ATF protocols are
established with reflection of the
results of the selection
some important recommendations for
publications and at the same time
documents in the usage of the specs in
the protocols can be developed so what
we have now we have very good list of
nominations we have eight nominations
for four balanced for for augmented and
this are really strong candidates I
think we are very in a good position now
here on stage one we are also collected
a number of questions to be asked they
are about shoot requirements about wit
agility about applications of PAC about
performance about security assessment
about security proof and about
recommendations for security rates usage
the last one is very important because a
lot of packs can be broken in because of
very small problems with implementation
so this kind of questions is really
important on stage to get elected their
sponsors from all the authors and many
thanks to all all source to provide in
providing their responses in time and
their words are sponsors for
requirements of RFC 8125 and the
opinions and the equations collected at
stage 1 so there's pauses for all eight
protocols what's next so now we have
starting to do the reviews and the
current stage which may be the most
important one is about call for
independent reviewers for specific
questions that we have first of all two
questions that in my opinion are the
most complicated ones are about
integration of each candidate into TLS
1.3 can shake and into equity to about
the less 1.3 we heard a lot of drugs
documents and discussions and earlier at
IETF 104 I made a presentation in
progress overview of existing documents
and we must take all this into account
and you really need people who really
know to illness and can prepare their
reviews and spend some time off for
reviewing each packs considering
regarding the usage mysterious and the
same thing quiz I quit too
I know that there are some experimental
draft about usage
RFC about usage of packs in equity but I
think that a lot of patients will be
raised and also there are questions
about usage in IOT so when we have at
least some limitations on hardware and
maybe additional limitations on around
efficiency and about privacy at least
about recommendations to prevent user
numeration in some protocols for example
our space and in opec we have explicit
recommendations about this and this is a
question that also has to be verified so
in fact the main purpose of the slides
was not only to give the overview but to
announce a call for viewers I think will
repeat this on the list and we really
need as a reviewers for such questions
because I believe that capture panel
members will provide really good
security assessment the liquid
verification of all security proofs but
it will be really good if people who
know each piece of TLS and speeches a
piece of ike we too could assess each
pack regarding their convenience to use
it for usage with these protocols so the
soul please questions and please really
need help here
hello maybe one formal remark or for the
process of a finding independent
reviewers many questions belong to
interpret bility live TLS and IPSec
based on my experience in ITU in that
case you used some kind of liaison
statements to request people from these
groups I hope that the people from TLS
and IP Shekhar here but it can be not
the case on earth such as so much people
so many of them here I propose to ask
corresponding working groups important
group chairs the assistant find it can
dependent reviewers from where people
working kill these groups efficient miss
opening have people who experts in TLS
in this room staring at some of them
yeah
and we did announce in the in the TLS
working group at least that this
competition was going on and we needed
reviewer reviewers relaying through Java
jour
Jorn I said could you post the place
where to find the replies regarding VT b
PE ke i did not find out the mailing
list could you post replies recording
i'm knowing them try VT b PE k of course
there was a replies for about VT VT key
and it was collated and it wasn't a
slice so yes for all protocols including
is this VT b PK
we have their responses and yes we've
collected them so no problem here are
they published somewhere
they were sent some of they were sent in
the least time Jose would say directly
to the chairs so I think that on stage 3
or stage 4 we we just published all the
stuff that I collected because some
answers was not in the single message
some were in the PDF so to try to
organize this in some case in some sense
and publish it for viewers in a
convenient way we are collecting all the
responses in one place but as responses
even was obtained after the deadline if
be honest some responses so we'll grate
them into eight groups and have this
ready for the reviews sorry Ivan is
typing here waiting to see if anything
comes up so nothing ok ok so and if you
have any other considerations about the
process and any other questions to be
asked please at least the chairs because
I think that all new questions can also
be considered by the review panel
reviewers like Alexis said in the
beginning in the chair slides so only
questions are still welcome I think ok
thank you and a reminder to the group
that we are soliciting more participants
for the quickly review panel we expect
this review of picks for the reviewers
to review multiple pegs rather than one
so that we have a consistent comparable
review we may gather them in respect to
augmented all for augmented well we have
four of each so it may be four per
reviewer so this is quite a large
requests and so we would hope that's we
have some dedicated people that have
have the energy and time to put into
this so we'd appreciate a mailing see
frg chairs at IRT F dark ok thank you
and by some miracle will return minutes
late we actually have two minutes left
so any other business one minute left
yes okay thank you
has anybody not signed blue sheets can
you come to the front and so we can get
even bigger room next time please