[Music]
hello hello everyone this is computing
in the network point we're going to get
going to just a few seconds if you are
not here for coin please stay anyway you
have a great program and if you're here
for coin well you're at the right place
we still need someone to take notes I
had sent them and request this morning
and nobody answered so if somebody who
is not presenting could actually be the
Good Samaritan and take notes it would
be greatly appreciated it's not not
going to name it I'm a namely a
volunteer I'm so anyway please if
somebody can take notes just raise your
hand and we're going to get going oh
you're Rachel thank you so very much
so Michael come over
[Music]
okay
hi I'm Eve Schuler and these are my
co-chairs we reach Jose and Jeffrey
welcome to the coin working group this
is our second official meeting our third
gathering of course we started with Bob
we're still in proposed research group
mode and we're grateful to see so many
of you out there and so many
contributions you're in the ITF IRT F
you know this note well slide well
things you should know our data tracker
where all of our documents are our
Charter our milestones we're in the
middle of we're in the middle of
migrating basically from a wiki based
mode of sharing information to a get
github document archive as well as code
archive and the coin mailing list is
simple to remember coin at IRT F org and
we have remote participants today we're
gonna have a remote presentation and
we've just appropriated our own slack
workspace which will also allow us to
have interim meetings more easily we
have a full agenda we have basically
many many internet drafts many of them
will be presented today at least the new
ones I think we've got eight at this
point in time and five of which will be
presented today in addition to the
administrivia we'll talk about next
meetings that are going to be happening
and I think the only change to these
presentations is that Dirk and your have
a combined merged presentation based on
their draft yeah I think it's you okay
so this is Jeffrey for those new to this
group so the general goal of this group
is to foster research in computing
network to improve performance and our
folks will be network architecture and
protocols and by addressing
real-time use-case application isn't
working in progress so we have not
modified the chart a little bit after
Prague and June interim meeting and also
based on that discussion mailing list
and thanks for the contributors and the
participants so main change now yes on
the items in scope section as you can
read in this slide but the plan is to
capture potential proposals from this
meeting and maybe after then we will
have a revised devotion submit to I have
chair to review and approve with the
consensus of this group so we also are
working on some milestones very
preliminary we know this is a whisky up
for a party so it will not tell you that
unless we are approved as a formal one
but we you know we hope to use this to
check some discussions on the future
plan so we suggested to capture the
still of art and attic articulates some
challenges then target to the use case
and also identifies the ecosystem
dependency and also the requirements
then hopefully we can have a specific
coin scope may be later next year and
specifically enough so that within which
new architecture and mechanism protocols
can be proposed
we are also linked some links the
existing individual shaft to these
milestones
just as related related rafts so
basically the input to the disk the
input up to the discussion of each apart
it's not we are not implying this will
be potential for more research groups
draft right it's too early to see that
okay yeah well we're just a proposed
research group we're kind of lucky that
we've had a bunch of people already to
do work that addresses the issues that
we want to do so we currently have as
you can see four new drafts which was
really good for this meeting and we have
three existing drafts and that we're
updated and we didn't have time to put
them on the agenda for today but they're
progressing especially the one on XR is
going to be also taken over with a new
team to make it progress the other one
we have stuff on industrial networks and
actually the problems of coin to to
drafts on that and then the App Center
from we have to do we have to Dirk's
here so we have Dirk number one on what
coin is and we have Dirk number two on
the app centers and so this is going to
continue and obviously collaborators are
welcome and if you have other ideas for
for drafts please supply them so we had
our first hackathon on Saturday and this
is the present of people who
participated and we had I think our
hackathon could have been some kind of a
train wreck
because p4 is this new language that
allows you to program switches and
there's not a lot of people who know how
to do that and we were very very lucky
that there is a local company called
Novi flow who has its business of doing
p4 and they lent us two engineers for
two days so thank you so much and they
actually got us going and so they're
around the table with the team so it
created a really really nice team we
could also poach a few people from other
tables so I ended up having quite a
large number of people what we did
obviously we there was a there had been
before hackathons and before tutorials
and other conferences so we can actually
take basic examples to get everyone on
board we had a remote participant who
actually was the guy who knew how to
program this so he had his own project
on machine learning in in ipv6 and he
made a lot of very good progress on this
we had I don't know if he's here but we
had somebody from liquid telecom which
is from from Africa who recognized that
he could actually do some translation of
p42 golang which is the language that
they use and on their networks at the
end we after one day where everybody was
actually kind of up to date and how to
do things we had two participants who
addressed a real problem that actually
we're going to face boat in industrial
networks and in this XR aar VR field
which is actually packet filtering so
compare a packet to a I called it a the
original idea was to have a perfect
packet and then compare all the other
packets to it and make sure that we can
detect when there's something
interesting obviously we didn't do that
we started by comparing addresses so
we're storing one and comparing but just
to tell you that after one day people
were really really ready to do real work
and we also made a list of ideas and I'm
going to post that on the github I'm
going to we have the pictures what we
learned is that the need to come
prepared is really good especially when
you're going to do everything in virtual
machines the the usefulness of experts
in a field that's expanding I don't know
how many hackathons are in the field
where the language is not even fully
defined right now so it was really good
to have people in you what they were
doing you can get participants the same
day so that was great people were seeing
what we were doing and they were joining
the team
you do a lot in two days which was
surprising in the way and to the
teamwork was great and we keep we have
now a shorter mailing list of all the
people who participated in the hackathon
to continue the work that we started and
we plan to have another one in Singapore
so if you're interested you can join us
so now we have a ton of presentations
and we have instructions to the
presenters and I see Dirk saying oh you
didn't tell me this so this is a
surprise so the instruction to the
presenters is if you can please try to
link your work and that's not going to
be difficult for you there to the
charter and highlight maybe where
changes would be necessary and yes so
you're in your next up and if I'm lucky
I'm going to be able to load your slides
thank you you don't have to call me on
the one that's better okay thank you
yeah so the intention of the draft that
is mentioned here and its presentation
is actually to provide input to your
planning process and discussion to be
honest I was a bit surprised to see such
a I mean detailed list of mice on the
it's good but no I mean in my experience
a research group also takes some time to
to find directions and I think oh it's
too low and but I am so this this draft
presentation is time to provide some
input on say potentially interesting
topics and also derive some research
questions that could be of interest
okay let's okay okay so I'll talk a bit
about what what does it actually mean
when we when we say in network
computing there's a computing missing
and then we discuss a few thoughts so or
technical aspects and we end with some
perspectives on what could be really
interesting to do in coin and ok so I
mean there's lots of computing in the
network already today so we heard about
smart necks on Monday web servers do
computation CDN is kind of a computing
system as well
all these cloud platforms often you hear
that edge computing and this is a really
fuzzy term and what and typically
actually means is extending well
understood and widely successful cloud
computing concepts to the edge so I
would say there's potentially not that
much research to be done there
so yeah architectures like mobile edge
computing so they sound look kind of you
know intriguing or at least unusual but
this is essentially just extending cloud
computing virtualization technologies
and management technologies to like
execution platforms at the edge to
something was like edge systems like
radio base stations for example so it's
nothing really new and and I don't think
so virtualization and automated
management for these kind of systems
particularly interesting for us then
there is this whole category of also
widely successful application layer
streaming event processing data
analytics platforms
so this is a key thing here so there
also you used all over the place and all
the popular was a powered by them so
they run in the cloud they run in
overlays in networks when network is
relatively cheap over-provisioned
and and well-managed so when you think
about doing similar things say maybe in
say less well controlled more more
distributed say internet scenarios that
there could be an interesting edge there
so these over their systems I mean that
they benefit from from all the internet
tools that we have transfer protocols
TLS and so on but they essentially treat
the network as overlays and such have
relatively limited visibility into the
network so you could actually say they
treat the network as circuits they use
different namespaces have to translate
between them so this works well in the
cloud and data centers would be
interesting to see what can the network
do to support these systems say more
than more directly and so earlier I
think in previous talks we talked about
this idea of doing that by jointly
optimizing computing and networking
resources so for example if you want to
make a computer offloading decision you
just do not allocate any available VM
but maybe you do this based on knowledge
about the topology congestion historic
performance and so on and so you have a
system that basically can do many
decisions in network itself can maybe
also leverage mechanisms they never
actually already has so like routing
protocols for example yeah let me just
glanceable it a bit quicker because I
said this so now when you try to
implement this joint optimization for
example or this integration of computing
and networking they are different
candidate technology you could look at
so so this function chaining is one so
we have a talking with one say two
but so something is basically the idea
that I arranged say pass from that
touches several network elements in my
system was the assumption that these
elements can do something useful or need
to see the the packets in the flow and
so these are functions like classifiers
filters caches and so on
normally this is these systems are
fairly statically configured so they
don't change that often you can
reconfigure them but it's not the idea
to you know switch back next hops all
the time
and typically the assumption is that
also we actually don't get in between
the TCP end to end control loop it's
more like on a packet level what you do
there okay so this is intended for
specific operator so called GI lon
scenarios not exactly a platform for
testability computing but I'm interested
to see say what our colleagues have done
in the next talk then you just thought
about the p4 work at the agathon so
there is this work on using programmable
data plane to achieve in network
computing so marco also has agency at
earlier meetings well this is the idea
that you can implement some application
logic for example in slightly more
powerful switches I would say that it's
an interesting approach many interesting
abilities but the systems that we have
seen so far I think it's fair to say
whether point solution that assumed well
you can basically intercept the packets
their work with the match action logic
and
back program the application semantics
in languages like p4 this is a fairly
limited environment and
also has kind of strong assumptions or
security I guess would be difficult to
do transfer protocols so it I would say
it's an interesting starting point but
probably wouldn't really suffice as a
general purpose platform for distributed
computing so in this group here so we
think we have like two directions that
we have been discussing so far so coming
down from these distributed computing
systems in the application layer and
trying to see how we can maybe integrate
those things with the network and then
say p4x approach for example maybe try
to move up the stack and try to see what
we can do for for applications so just
to enough give us a handle to kind of
talk about a few categories so here's
one example that kind of comes from
current work that we have been doing for
enable computing in a group of say ICN
folks so assume you have a kind of
network of nodes that can generally
offer compute services so this could run
execution platforms or any kind of
platform that could run some functions
so we assumed that we would be like
diagnostic to the specific environment
we just be able to call some functions
or two in each to create some state and
of course you want to be able to
leverage specific features so like a GPU
here or a trusted execution environment
there but in general we assume could be
a heterogeneous system and so you'd be
able to use whatever you need for your
application and so in a dissipated
application context there could be
something like sessions or like an
application in in progress that would
then perhaps allocate a subset of these
nodes and so this would be like part of
one session and you would then use them
then - yeah locate in sense yet
functions
but also a stateful so systems that
could for example also yeah have side
effects men keep stateful number time
and so on so in a system like this the
assumption is that would be like a
disability system maybe that's
programmed in a program has certain
application requirements one stand Emily
and the dynamic execution determines so
what needs to be allocated executed what
needs to be transmitted in terms of
input parameters and results so there
would be some kind of remote method
invocation protocol for invoking
functions or status functions or maybe
state for actor member functions and so
in this example here what these
functions could be very very lightweight
but also say two significant pieces of
work and as I said so one function can
trigger other function calls and so on
so in that system it's useful to have
information about so where those
functions are so if for example if I
have a stateful act or I want to
continue talking to that one it's also
useful to know so what is the resource
utilization situation so how busy is
this server for example or how well is
it performing right now maybe it's
actually formally not loaded but I just
figure out it doesn't work so well for
me and it's also good you know so where
are still an allocated resources or
notes that I could maybe integrate into
the system at runtime okay so in this
system we we we distribute this
information by some distributed protocol
you don't think about using Network
mechanisms like the routing system to at
least partially help you with that or to
use information that you get from say
transport protocol like protocols that
are you okay this is perhaps has a
longer latency right
you have some congestion information in
there protocols okay so that's just an
example to just give you someone to type
some mind shape we can can talk about
some some mechanisms so when you do that
first question we could ask okay what
are these functions anyway so how how
fine granular or heavy weight are these
so are we talking about like shifting
bits near a resistor or adding on
multiplying potentially but more visit
on the other side of the spectrum you
know like some machine learning
application find faces identify people
call it police and get people arrested
possibly so I think there's there's a
long big space in between and well
potentially I would we would say it
could could be all of that put in so
obviously not as far as this machine
instruction there but you could say have
really long time complex functions or
services as well as stateless function
that you know just you know process some
data or does it better analytics and
give you constant results on some input
data so functions in that system would
need data so where does it come from
obviously there would be something like
input parameters so an image to possess
there would be some like an operational
context so for stateful service they
would also be something we think that so
yeah background data that could be kept
in a key value store or some database
which could be modeled as a stateful
actor for example and and you could
think about how do you know specify or
use those parameters how do you identify
the contexts or systems or provisions
like this must be made could be like in
in the packet or in the message that you
convey
depends a bit on the protocol solution
if you design and but also what's the
what's a sensible data unit what this
function but this functions to be you
work on so packet processing so it's
in-service training perhaps could be
useful but may not be the the ultimate
goal in the end so because there are
solutions for that and think about doing
something for disability applications we
think it's more useful to talk about
application data units and think about
yeah some some transport a section that
allows us to convey these ad use from
one function to the other for example
and yeah obviously in an internet
context or in any context you have to
think about security properties that
means mouth indication hell access
control so these kind of things
yeah functions sometimes need to be able
to do side effects to do something
useful so this could be persistent side
effects or updates to to to database
states for example or could be more
temporary integrity effects
so there's also categories that we
suggest you to look into deeper a little
bit I'm not doing this then yes often so
in our system designed the question so
what our application semantics in terms
of how to get actually get data
so is it like like a pool abstraction or
a push abstraction so pool would require
something like a repress response for
the color perhaps push is interesting if
you want to do some say reactive
programming so event triggers systems so
we think that that is all fine that
doesn't have to determine well say how
the network protocol apply
so we'd be able to want to be able to to
met these different applications inventx
onto a student web protocol but doesn't
have to mean that the network itself for
example is obvious within push or so
then so it's easy to say that we want to
have a general-purpose
disability computing platform but I
think for say meaningful applications
you also really have to think about
performance so distributed data
analytics okay I'm almost done
for distribute data analytics you could
imagine having some some pipelines that
you know feed the data into functions
and so each function is depending on the
input data that the other function
generates so I mean this has to be well
designed to to provide any useful
performance and then things like how can
I reuse data and the system things like
caching and so on okay let me go over
this a bit right now so we have more
info on this in the draft so the coin so
I mean first of all we are the internet
research task force so I think in
general we think in general it's healthy
to think about open networking
environments so let's not make too many
assumptions on how shielded our systems
on how trustworthy either the PS are and
and so on
so in general it's a hostile environment
where you have to run function on and
generally untrusted systems and we have
to find way to establish trust for
example so that your code runs correctly
and and and so on so heterogeneous
system things security from the
beginning and so on so one idea that we
had is it may seem attractive to you
know categorize the work in different
use cases or scenarios like industrial
IOT but actually we think that it's
actually not that useful because in this
example here industrial energy they are
I guess like
with different economic classes of how
network computing could be used so there
is for example that could be done like a
virtual PLC that runs somewhere that's
just virtual machines not not that
interesting but they could be also like
this with the data processing or some
like real-time control so we think it's
more interesting to dually categorize
these these functional properties and
interaction types and these kind of
things and yeah so our suggestion for
say if you would did some like you know
experimental protocol or something
things to agree on we think would be in
the model for women method invocation
which types of functions are we talking
about what is the programming model not
so much the different bindings how do
you ascribe resources and how you
allocate resources what is maybe more
specific to implementations is the
different execution environments the
languages or web sections for those
platforms and a bunch of other things
and there's a long list of other things
that I'm talking about here thank you
very much this is exactly the type of
stuff that we would like to have
discussed on the mailing list is very
very and yeah lots of great questions
lots of very good things that we already
have a little bit thought about and yes
we should move the discussion to the
list okay thank you so very much
next up is Adrian and I have to load
your new versions
I
[Music]
in other words okay hello everyone I'm
Adam I'm a teacher student at the
recompile tech and I will present you my
work which relies on the service
chaining and I will show you how you can
rely on existing networking to agents to
a builder in network function chain so
in network in network computation enable
you will have nodes which in addition to
basic forwarding and holding a function
would have also other functions or
running on top of n which can be a
milder middleboxes
in sync running on the comedy's server
or some application functions of ready
to a later plane but in any case you
will need to be to orchestrate your
network to be sure but the set of
functions are placed on on your
networking make sure that were wide data
flow goes through a wide set of
functions to perform more complex
functions so in the service functional
training is achieved with some central
control point color orchestrate is
called an Orchestrator which has a some
limitation since it builds a single
point of failure in the networks as some
scalability issue and it sadly in our
world with legacy device however
trainings such a function is mainly
routine problems we need to show that a
frou-frou set of wage point before
reaching with the destinations and we
and we believe that we should be at the
network layer and we propose to augment
classical internet for protocol to make
it functional so instead of having some
centralized control point which make you
manage every flow in your networks and
your functions we propose to instead of
autonomous nodes which asked network
functions and also have a distributed
intelligence to traffic for a channel or
functions and to choose two instances or
they are till event so I will fulfill my
no negative cultural works you have some
gateways which are attached on which
some networks are attached by a
extension and some information and based
on that they build a network view we've
we've and we visit neutral shoe they are
built routing tables what we propose is
that we can bind specific products to
each tag to each type of functions
through to make sure that the Vinod's
know where functions are allocated
moreover if you use some any case a
dressings you you are able to match not
not only a prefix to say go functions
but also to map to introduce a GP matrix
to state function instance given that
the flow has to go through so instead if
you if you look at a Vista project you
have two pink functions for running on
trees in the front on two different
nodes and if you look at the topological
view of the IGP you have only one nodes
and each instance of this specific
function is represented by orange and
attached to this links you can you can
attach any metrics that show you you
need to through the whites in San Cisco
can be seen CPUs or memory use or time
it's it's takes to process packets and
based on that you you will be able to
build the chain of functions for
instance you if you you take these
networks with some classical hotels
running whichever for the wrong one and
some
some hotels which also functions this
this mounted rotors which we comes
anyway rotors will announce specific
traffic's for any function fails for
instance if you consider that your
yellow functions is an IDs and pink one
is a firewalls you will have extended
view which is on white and based on that
you will be able to hood first first
flow which is for white which is the red
one to make sure that he goes through
the ideas and then the firewalls and if
you you base your matrix for instance on
the CPUs perceptive use of EITS freeways
and if a second for wives it will be
able to through the second second second
instance making is some not balancing
between the different function instance
so we have built an architecture to for
our organization nodes which we call an
elevator so you have a control part
which is distributing manual on the
white and which receive a higher level
policy such as the mapping of specific
functions ribbon and gas prefix and
which will constantly monitor both from
the function is asked and based on bats
will compute the matrices annals on a GP
to to make behavior over Hooters aware
but of the functions and what is its
from user control a logical path will
take when the floating an algorithm will
take the or Monti view
shadow on the on jgp use the bathroom
stand the bathroom Station algorithm and
build functions service table which will
map the location of the other functions
and push it through over connector which
is a path which will link the IP
networks and the anvil functions and
based on the
the no caps relations we which I what we
have used which is an SH which have been
normalized at yet yet you will be able
to map the next function to through
which we've got a bill okay occasions
your packet as to earth so we make a
simple implementation of these photos of
the virtual network functions are simply
functions in in network namespace we
build our connector which before to make
it became we didn't choose up an open
the switch because it didn't have a
stateful memory so we use people to to
implement our connector to make sure
that each flow will be processed by by
the same by the same instance we make
floating and not packet based routines
and we use the an open source stack
which is a routing as a for our water
which want to west PF so we have make
some made some I large-scale experiments
with this implementation we package our
anabolic state containers and we
emulated 8787 not to topologies which is
the top rod nicely infertility we make
by working full project and on top on
top of it approaches we deployed 10
virtual and network functions and we ask
and we configure on our network to make
sure that those first function which is
were a yellow one and the second which
would be I think if there is a fiber
instant instance of each of each type of
network functions and routing proper
receiver is the shortest path and each
and the virus takes about a by uprooting
the decision and what
we show is that based on the link stated
participant update frequency we are able
to have a stable balancing on the
different vnf instances running on our
unavailable so what we indeed achieve is
that we have a free distributed a
framework to change in network functions
which is not only interoperable with
current voting system and which brings
resilience in scalability since jgpz
feel proven portable and we achieved
through a balance the load among the
validity from the edge from the network
function instance and we don't have to
add any configuration when we add a new
virtual network function instance since
when you another would have chose to to
start a new instance you just have to
announce the anycast prefix related to
this event after that since it doesn't
instance a kid to make routing system
aware of the new host for simple
networks and in future work we would
like to see if we can extend our
proposal to inter domain service project
in provisioning using pi ability and to
study the different metrics which could
be used to take routing decision for for
virtual service functions
moreover or some some classical IDP
madness and failure techniques code
could be applied to our storage
solutions and what the next step of our
works will be to a check if based on the
augments topology we build of another
Hooters would be able to take autonomous
decision to choose to start or stop and
in instances in an instance based on a
lot of the networks so if you have any
question
Just Answer okay so I was surprised to
see us be atheist here mixing preach
ability in policies in the world
possibility in general the reasonably
stable work called BGP furnace age
that's progressing in best working group
in ATF and it has BGP has built-in
constructor router get important expert
to impose policies so it would have been
much easier to implement and
inter-domain would work just as if
there's maybe something to consider
okay thanks doc Montgomery do you have
the ability to choose your rel based
upon the the overall complete service
chain as opposed to my criminal series
what we have done for now is to take a
bio decision you're on English otters
Babar golem nonetheless if you have the
Augmented view you can use in my opinion
any a path computation algorithm to take
more complex decision if needed and you
could also instead of make up by
outputting makes forceful thing using
for instance as a services to serve a
six to do that
this will be our last question
developers would you mention this vnf
prohibition maybe see in general
castration I guess in the life cycle or
no how do you control the life cycle one
associated with the routing for now on
we have weakened still new business or
functions which have started and we do
not deal with the life cycle static so
you mentioned is about balancing is for
after ignition yeah but if you start we
have a in our first paper we have made
some experiment for all balancing
scenario where you have a instance true
visceral natural function learned at
first and we do choose to start off a
third one to change the balance between
this one little function instances so it
is possible to to modify the traffic
engineering doing doing that to make the
decision to scale out introduces another
question how this was propagated through
the routing updates okay thanks
[Applause]
yeah yeah I guess yeah
[Music]
okay so hello my name is Ike I'm here to
present our draft on the industrial use
cases what you will sometimes see behind
me okay
so what you'll see here that's actually
what we are working on right now with
mechanical engineers in Adam
so the industrial Internet of Things as
you can see there are quite a lot of
different robots working a lot of
sensors measuring something and
everything is now more and more
connected and what the mechanical
engineers tell us is that they want to
essentially move all the data that they
collect there in to etch or remote
clouds and they will also want to
control the different robots also from
flaut and yeah essentially as a third
aspect all the data that they moved to
the cloud they want to use that and
actually throw machine learning and data
mining on it to later it's used to find
out how they can improve the production
environment and then feed that
information back into the system to make
it better and based on these three
aspects that we've seen here we've then
taking a look at how we can improve that
with in network computing and you can
see here the general abstraction from
the previous figure namely that we have
sensors that we have actuators on the on
the left-hand side so one end of the of
the communication there on the right
side you see the edge clouds and the
remote clouds which will then be of the
other end of the communication and in
the middle we have the the network and
what we now propose is that we could
place certain functions within the
network - yeah complement their use
cases that they want to achieve
and they're Klaus isn't so close as
presented in Prague and there we have
proposed two of them already so network
control and traffic filters and
now also proposing data stream
processing as well as dust really safe T
aspects so as these two use cases were
already presented in Prague I only go
shortly over them so network control the
general idea is that the different
robots are now controlled from edge or
from an edge or a remote cloud and they
here the problem is that the latency
that isn't used by the network is too
high so that the control loop cannot
really be working anymore and what we
now want to do is we want to put
simplified versions of the control
algorithms already within the network so
that there can be short answers maybe
two to signify it to the actuators that
everything is working okay and so that
everything is still working on the other
hand we have traffic filters so as more
and more sensors data is there the
amount of traffic that needs to be
pushed into the cloud is getting larger
and larger but a lot of sensors cannot
really be configured well so there might
be redundancy in them and so on that all
the data might be necessary to push to
the cloud and we won't simply want to
filter out under set unnecessary data
already then within Network to reduce
the load on the network a third aspect
then which is actually quite similar to
traffic filtering and in product we
presented them as one data stream
pre-processing so the different sensor
values that are pushed into into the
cloud are oftentimes then simply
combined to form new values and then the
mechanical engineers want to only only
want to store those combined values and
if we now can achieve these this
combination already within the network
we wouldn't need to push all the data
into the into the cloud but only the
combined values so this would then again
reduce the amount of data that needs to
be pushed to the cloud and then as a
fourth aspect we think about
complementing the current safety
measures that are there in the
production
so typically you have like laser
barriers so that machines stop when
someone goes through them but now the
nowadays the production environment gets
more and more dynamic so that even
production or working stations move
around in the in the in the production
hall so that it's now not that easy to
build hardware solutions for that and we
now propose to complement that by
utilizing data that is already being
sent to the cloud for example a camera
data and we could for example identify
if to camp with one camera sees the
robot moving in this direction and the
other camera sees a robot moving and
that a human moving in the other
direction and maybe identify a collision
course that then the robot could be
signal that it should stop so in the
draft we then proposed quite a lot of
research questions for all the for
different use cases and I've tried to
condense them here into two categories
the first one is the design and
development of the network functions
that we want to do so here the question
is how we can account for the limited
computational capabilities of the
network devices so we cannot solve for
example in the control scenario you
typically have quite complex control
loops and control algorithms and so it's
the building these simplified versions
of them might introduce some science
some sort of inaccuracy and we have to
account for that as well
and then is the second aspect so now we
can build them the different network
functions it might be a good idea to
find out how we can for example provide
basic building blocks for the functions
so that they can then be easier combined
or our new network cars can be built
easier the second big point is then the
operation and the deployment of the
network functions so now we have the
functions but how do we place them where
do we place them and how do we
coordinate
them so for example if we have two
functions in the network and we replace
the first one how does that affect the
second one for example and the second
aspect we done also see that the these
Network pressures will certainly affect
the the functions that are then from
computed at the applications in the end
and here we have to yeah consider how
this will then how we can define the
interaction between the in the network
parts and the applications so what is
then next for us we plan on updating
this in our use case draft and then we
especially want to do another draft or
we plan on doing another draft on
transport protocol issues so this was
done basically what I stated last on the
slide before so the interaction between
the end host and the network function in
the middle because if we simply come for
example combine the two to sensoric
values into a third one and then only
only one only one packets packet still
survives maybe this violates kind of D
and 2n principle and we want to yeah we
wanna elaborate on what we think might
be the problems here and we wanna yeah
find out what we can do about that or
what essential requirements for such a
protocol would be but I want to I want
to yeah say that we we don't plan on
designing protocol here we simply wanna
elaborate on the challenges that we have
there and if you're also interested in
that we are very looking forward to a
collaboration this is regard and yeah so
then contact mute thank you
are there any questions I actually have
one without my chair um actually I've
got in the Hat uh I I think there's a
lot of very good opportunities in what
you mentioned but I read the draft also
I think what is missing is making a
strong differentiation of what is
already existing in automated industrial
environments which as you know a pretty
advanced and what you're bringing with
this architecture and I don't think it's
clear in the in the draft and I don't
think it's clear in the presentation
either because if I look at this with a
very cynical hat on oh so you know they
already do that in highly automated
production but I actually know from
other stuff that there are new cases and
they are places in industrial
environments where this type of work
that your suggestion has a lot of work
of room so I would suggest that in the
next version of your draft that you
clearly identify what is the difference
between what your suggestion and what is
currently happening in automation yeah
thanks that's a nice suggestion we will
definitely think about that I have you
read reviewed existing transport
protocols is anything missing why do you
need additional drop but me thinking
current variety of transfer protocols
sorry I didn't get that from the
acoustics could you repeat it please
your next step if draft um Transfer
Protocol yeah do you need something new
is there anything you think in existing
transfer protocols so what I basically
meant with that is this violation of the
internet principles so typically so we
don't think that it will work with the
existing protocols or at least not out
of the box for so that we so the end
host somehow have to know that someone
in the middle is interfering with what
they are doing and this is actually what
I meant with with this draft on the
transfer
protocol sometimes like mqp like
protocols that's usually since kind of
environments sorry I'm QP so you know
there's a broker in between it's not in
current I didn't get that either okay
thank you okay
alright alright alright so it's okay no
hear me okay
so I'm Jen Jen Jen I'm an assistant
professor University of Chicago this is
actually the first time I'm in a RTF and
it's very happy to be here to share my
research and hopefully at the end I get
to connect my research to the agenda of
coin artery so if I mean unless you live
in like another Rock you know that video
analytics is everywhere right from
public transportation to public safety
everything and but the real research
challenge in terms of networking and
systems is how do you network system to
support the video analytics as such
massive scale and let's first look at
some trend here all right so first of
all did there are two trends in video
analytics one and these neural network
models are getting more and more
accurate at the cost of more and more
computing resource okay so it's getting
more and more expensive to run these
models and second there's just a lot
more cameras so these two trends are
kind of firm as have led to this
dramatic growth of the cost in video
analytics okay now just to put that into
perspective this is not just about
compute storage it's also about
networking okay
now to put that into perspective think
about video streaming internet streaming
videos like Netflix or YouTube right
these are the kind of application that
can't account for 80% of the internet
traffic to consumers now
imagine all the network systems these
days like CDNs or cloud they are all
built around these traditional
applications now the fact is these I
mean at least surveillance cameras
videos have already exceed the traffic
of Internet video in that streaming
video and the fact that these cameras I
mean analyzing one camera feed is way
more expensive than just streaming one
ok so that means there is the current
net in the today's internet systems is
way less than was needed to analyze all
these video feeds ok
so clearly there's something needed to
increase the accuracy of these analytics
with low cost and do so in a way that
can scale to the sheer number of cameras
and video feeds ok now just to give you
a sense of what video analytics systems
not like you have a camera capturing
video and the video can be analyzed
locally or can be sent to the server for
analytics
ok so naturally you can imagine there's
that kind of edge to cloud continuous a
continuum where the high resolution
videos will be analyzed locally ok and
then only the part of the video that
needs further investigation will be sent
upstream to some more complex model
typically running on a cluster ok and
then it would do some future further
futuring and the remaining video would
be only the remaining video will be sent
back upstream to a very complex model in
the cloud ok so now so far all I have to
talk about is very similar to everything
you you have singing edge computing
right but there are actually two unique
properties of video analytics the first
property is that the video pipelines
must be very adaptive to the real-time
video content now you know just what
that means is when the video content
changed over time right the resource
demand for this video analysis pipelines
which will vary dramatically over time
as well that makes resource provisioning
very challenging ok so let's just recap
the challenge of video analytics is to
balance accuracy and cost ok so
trial work on me all work these days
have been trying to do is to and I'll
customize the video pipeline to the
video content so why why this is
possible well imagine this is one of the
like very typical video analysis
pipelines out there right and there are
not a lot of knobs control configuration
knobs that you can tune so the video in
the frames of a video gets fed into this
module in am you know that resizes the
video and then select which frames to
sample and then it will get in fed into
this neural network object detection
software okay so you can see there bunch
of knobs you can choose right so you can
change the resolution the framerate and
even which neural network object data
model to use okay so so people have been
trying to exploiting this color for
these knobs to customize the pipeline to
the video content now I was just
informed that this this video is not
gonna play so I'm gonna just ask you to
imagine what's gonna happen here so
let's say this is actually two same
video on the left hand side you see
these bounding boxes these are boxes
detected cars detected by the neural
network and if I play the video you will
see these cars gonna be staying staying
staying put I mean they are stopping
there and so if you use low framerate on
the Left versus high frame rate on the
right their accuracy will be pretty
similar okay so when the objects are
pretty static low framerate operation
would be in it will be enough it's not
much going on but if you if I were to
click the play button again right you
will see there are cars moving into the
picture and running in high speed and if
you if you have objects moving at high
speed the low framerate will give very
low accuracy because they were not it
will lose track of these objects okay so
what it means is I mean that gives us or
a key insight that is the video
analytics pipeline must be customized to
the video content the real-time video
content so basic as the video content
varies over time like for example speed
changes
the best configuration will vary over
time as well now this is not just about
framerate I just used I'm just using
framerate as one example resolution and
the underlying neural network Lassa fire
should also be changed depending on how
and how frequent the content changes now
all prior work has been doing is like
one like so-called one-time profiling
they profile the video at up front and
then stick to the configuration they
think is the best through the remaining
of the video what we're proposing in
this recent work is try to try to to
argue that instead of just using one
configuration that seems to be good we
should adapt the video pipeline ok over
time to the dynamic video content ok so
this is the new idea we we studied this
idea in in a recent paper so what is
main architectural eh okay so what it
may is you're gonna have this controller
in the middle that's basically sitting
in this continuous loop right it will
periodically update periodically prefer
a profile the video and update the
control knobs you use like what frame
rate or what model you should use okay
and you're gonna run this continuously
so I'm gonna skip a lot of details here
but the the option is you can kind of
achieve a lot of resource saving or a
lot of accuracy improvement right so
this is like one traffic video data set
and you can see on this the blue ones
are profiling just once upfront okay you
don't change the configuration and red
ones is the proposed method you're
continuously reprofiling and updating
the configuration and it may just be
able to claim this right like higher
accuracy at the same cost or you can
achieve the same cost at a very small
fraction of the other scene accuracy it
is at a very small fraction of the
computing cost okay now this is just
research but what what it tells us is
even this is good news this actually
make the resource allocation very
challenging right because now whenever
the content changes you have
to change your resource allocation and
this is actually the plot of the
resource demand of the system over time
okay and you can see the resource
consumption kind of changes by 5 to 20 X
even just in a few seconds just because
the content changes rapidly right and
this basically raises the challenge how
do you actually do resource allocation
in our computing right to cope with this
kind of a spiky workload okay so that's
one takeaway from the first part of
research now for the remaining couple
minutes that would be just briefly talk
about the second unique challenge unique
property of video analytics
oh yes exactly
ok so what that means is ok so let's
imagine again you have a network
connecting a camera and a cloud and the
camera doesn't have local resource to
process the video typically right so the
video has to be streamed out to the
server
now what what traditionally what people
do is they can look at the video and
just compress it to some quality level
and then send the video back to the
server this has two problems either you
set your encoded video into low quality
it loose accuracy you can't see anything
it or you're sending high quality it's
good to for accuracy but you may not
have enough bandwidth to send it right
now the fundamental reason for this
actually is because this product I mean
the traditional video streaming protocol
makes sense to not to use the feedback
from the user
because for traditional video the users
are actually human being right you can
ask them to give you experience feedback
but in video analytics actually you can
because the consumer the user here
actually logic they send an algorithm
right it can actually pull some feedback
from it and this is what we do I mean
this is what we're trying to do and this
animation messed up but what's basically
happening here is you can kind of just
send a very low quality threat version
of the video to the server and the
server will run some analytics to give
hint to recline what it actually needs
right real-time paint
so that's another one but that's kind of
a new way to do this video streaming for
video analytics okay and this can
actually save a lot of bandwidth but
still achieve the same high accuracy
okay so the takeaway from this talk just
to take away from this talk one is that
the pipeline the video pipeline must be
adaptive to the real-time video content
okay
and that means whenever the content
changes right the resource demand may
vary as well and that will cause some
very spiky workload and whatever in
network resource allocation on network
allocation resource allocation mechanism
we're proposing must be able to cope
with that okay and a second because
we're dealing with this video analytics
is dealing with some algorithm as the
final consumer of the system right you
can actually leverage some of this
real-time feedback from it and this
actually opens up new opportunities to
bring the goals of these data analytics
to the resource allocation control loop
okay and thank you ready for castle okay
[Applause]
any question so I guess I'd love for you
to elaborate on what you what you
imagine it would entail to bring the
analytics goals to the control loop do
you see that there is metadata specific
to these kinds of Cascades they could be
exposed and then you know what do you
can you say more given that you're the
very expert yeah good question so the
question is how you if you want an
average the server or the analytics
logic feedback right so it will be
better to have kind of standardized
version of metadata to to generalize
what I mean I mean most kind of feedback
you would be used that they'll be useful
so I think that this is very much in the
early stage of research that has been
several papers along this line one thing
that's really interesting is so-called
you make some assumptions about what the
Khan
tenth or the video I mean the dynamics
of video would look like so basically
you you let the server see something
okay and the server will tell you okay
so it's this anomaly in me is this usual
or not if it's very unusual right so it
will ask you for more information so for
example if it looks that looking at very
low quality video it sees these objects
this just appears once and disappear all
of a sudden that doesn't make a lot of
sense right so that's kind of anomaly is
one thing that's really standout in
across several papers I'm just trying to
really generalize that I mean obviously
they have very different mechanisms to
solve that but anomaly in the thing the
result is one interesting result
interesting sink you look at the other
thing is so-called confidence so
confidence as in so this neural network
usually have some scores attached to
each each detection and scores being
high means it's very confident that this
is actually a thing if it's low that
means this McClure it doesn't mean
anything but you can treat it as it's
not being very confident okay
so that score is one thing also useful
as a feedback for you to pull more you
use well information from their mean for
more lunch do you know if it changed a
lot as a bit rate or is going to be much
more variable or do you still have a
pipeline with a constant before uses the
bit rate will be changing a lot versus
pretty stable okay right yes so like I
said it's very content dependent if you
have a big objects in the middle in a
self-driving car if your car is staying
in front of you
low resolution enough do you have some
figure but definitely not at a scale of
like to Megan two orders of magnitude
it's usually whizzing one order of
magnitude okay so so like if you if you
talk about video you're changing
resolution and QP rice qualitative
quantization parameter or
that's usually a wasting a range of
certain value I mean low and high didn't
what won't have a difference of more
than 10x now that has a reason that has
an actual underlying reason that it's
because the neural network these days
assumes certain input size so even if
you give a very very high resolution
video it will resize into something
smaller as well so so I'm just saying
the magnitude of resolution changing
that I'm seeing is not really the full
scale of variance that you will be
seeing if you have better neural network
does that make another question does it
reduce the number of steps or tasks in
the cloud to edge path steps as
accessible you you were describing that
the currently there are a lot of
different steps to to to to extract
analytics do you have an idea about the
number of steps is going to decrease
yeah that's a good question I think most
of the working this space is not trying
to figure out the optimal number of
layers between the camera and the cloud
they're trying to say if you have this
number of layers how do I layout I mean
how do i spread analytics across these
layers I think that's actually a real
good question for from this print this
group specific perspective to
investigate could you put up the spiky
little graph again so I'm trying to read
the the x-axis is kind of compressed so
how many how much time is between the
bottom and and and any given peak is
that seconds tenths of seconds I guys I
can't really see this yeah well let me
let me sort of you really get to the
question I want to ask how many RT T's
do I have before I see the spike before
I know that that's why
is big so this is me at the scale or me
at the scale time scale of seconds the
grandeur of this granularity of seconds
so I think if you look if you're talking
about network with RT teals sub-second
RT t right you in theory you can catch
that right I'm trying to get stars how
can I catch that and get the resource
allocation done right right but but but
I'm just saying in Syria can catch that
right right up front but you do need
several iterations to look like really
coverage and after that I mean resource
allocation is not free right so it's not
instantaneous so you kind of need to
take that into a country maybe that's
x-ray was taking most of the time and
then given that edge resources are
constrained not just in compute but in
memory yes the question is can I buffer
enough of this peak so that oh I can
keep the data long enough till I can get
the resource allocated
yeah I think you're right way I said
memories the bottom there because
usually this newer network is what's
consuming most of the most of the memory
I think if you just want to buffer the
video before it's actually analyzed yes
yes thank you you should be able to
buffer those you're saying it the the
size of the video is small compared to
the size of the model yes yes actually
yes okay well well then hmm
the interesting question is do you need
the model everywhere and can you get the
model in right yeah that's an X if you
don't have the model I guess the memory
would be the bottleneck for buffering
the video but I think these cameras
usually have pretty large storage and
buffering super thank you okay last
question oh yes did you consider how
state your name oh yes sure on UNIX are
um do you consider how urgent is it to
understand what the camera sees
like if it's really urgent then the
neural network should be on the camera
and then if it doesn't understand then
only frames on demand frames not the
whole video cuz yeah it's too much so so
I think you're you're definitely right
they are too extreme of the system of
the little too extreme for shelves of
views right so you can have like
self-driving cars
where you do have a lot of resource Amir
it's a car right and and and everything
is very must be very super real-time
alright so in those kind of situation
you do want everything local versus if
you have a bunch of surveillance cameras
or a camera network where you have like
thousands of cameras cheaper want cheap
much cheaper than the one you are you
have on self-driving cars and then in
those kind of situations you need to
have a back-end Network system to
analyze the data and but actually you're
right in those cases we are most people
are assuming they are not urgent as
urgent I mean as real-time as
self-driving cars so they can tolerate
certain level of delay yes okay so but
but you're a maybe in the worst case of
I mean the worst version of most words
right you have a lot of cameras cheap
ones and you need super real-time
reaction that's the kind of holy grail
of this kind of systems there has to be
layering because the car itself is
always going to have some kind of
mutation versus so but what you can
consider is a neural net on the on the
camera if it's a movie camera cannot
expect what's going to happen somebody
may jump the kid the ball and then in
the edge if you need sub ten millisecond
and then in the cloud if you need
something that's that's really yes
there's a kind of hierarchy of delays
you can tolerate if you want to go
further layer up from yeah thank you I
think you're the one who controls the
the microphone okay yeah maybe you will
say can you hear me okay we hear you
great very good okay
do I see do I control
okay very good okay
so let's start so my name is Jesper Eric
stone and I'm a VP of Product Management
the co-founder of of Nova flow and and I
have logged on to this session using
Marc Leclerc registration credentials he
is a dear colleague of mine me pure
marketing strategy and also co-founder
and to do this I had to promise him not
to use any course language or get him
into any trouble whatsoever so you see
Marc but it's really just for Erikson
so on the first slide the this
presentation is really about the
evolution of STM from OpenFlow to p4 and
people run time and the slide that
you're looking at right now is just an
introductory slide you know Nova flow as
a company we were founded in 2012 as a
pure Sdn company we really at least our
first commercial open flow one two three
switch in second quarter 2013 and our
core technology is is really this
programmable match action pipeline using
Mellanox MP use and also barefoot Tofino
the key verticals that we operate in and
where our technology is used is cyber
security different types of gateways and
then also on-demand bandwidth solutions
in in Wham's and broadband access so
please change so what is a match action
pipeline well so the match action
pipeline resides in the switch silicon
inside a switch or router and it's
really the embedment embodiment of the
rules by which we want to process the
packet as it goes through the switch
and in most switches you'll find a fixed
a sink and that's really what you see on
the left and an in a fixed executes a
fixed set of mass action tables defined
in there in the silicon the size of
these tables is fixed what the fields
that you can match on is predefined and
the actions that you take in the table
in that particular table is also fixed
and then you know as an application
programmer trying to use this in an SDM
context you know I would have to try and
map my application into this fixed max
match action pipeline so it's really a
bottom what we call a bottoms up
programming paradigm you have to see
what's in the silicon and that really
drives what you can do with your
application and then on the right you
see a programmable silicon and here
there's no prior set of mass action
tables defined in the silicon and the
application programmer creates the
pipeline to specifically meet the needs
of the application you know the the
programmer from from scratch
says I need this many tables this is the
size of the various size of the tables
the types of the tables and then what
match fields and actions I want to use
in each table and it really allows the
programmer and the application to drive
the packet processing pipeline in the in
the silicon ok next slide please so who
cares you know what why is this
important and and well in in our view
you know this program will match action
pipeline enables the following thing the
first one is faster introduction of new
network functionality in protocols and
you know there's an endless list of of
this I mentioned a couple here you know
ipv6
i AMSO v6 essentially any new protocol
that's introduced unless the silicon is
programmable you have to wait for the
next generation of silicon to to be able
to introduce that functionality it also
allows you to do fast prototyping of new
capabilities because the the
functionality software-defined another
key point is that this allows in this
aggregation of network hardware and
software that the hardware looks more
like a server and then can be sourced
differently you know and and then this
software is really what defines what the
functionality is and then the third
bullet here is features are defined in
the software and not in the hardware and
what what that drives is there's really
no forced obsolescence of the networking
equipment as you can upgrade the
functionality through software and over
time you can also repurpose the network
equipment by changing the software more
like a server so that yeah and then we
go to the open flow starting with the
open flow match action pipeline so it
and this is like one two three one
before it cetera and it allows you to
define any number of tables or steps and
in any one of these tables you can match
on any combination of a predefined set
of matched fields and then operate on
the packets using any of a predefined
set of instructions and actions so it
has a lot of freedom the programmer can
say I want two tables I want to match on
this in the first table I want to match
on this in the second table I want to
highlight the metadata field as an
interesting feature in open flow and and
also in p4 it allows you to bring the
result from one table to the next and
match on it it's like it carried forward
variable and and we have a one customer
that that's using this to progressively
build the result and in a number of
tables and then in the last table match
on the overall result or what happened
in there or what the pipeline calculated
it makes like this so here you see a
real implementation of a true open flow
switch and and the purpose of this slide
is really to illustrate what a true open
flow switch looks like and and switch
that's compliant with you know open flow
1.4 and it may give you some ideas of
what you can do with with open flow and
from a network computing perspective and
and what it shows is it defines let me
see them it's hard to read here yeah so
it it allows the programmer to to you
know create a pipeline with up to 41
different match fields as defined in
open flow one before up to six
instructions and and up to 56 actions
and inactions include the ability to
change the value in any match field and
you can put any match field in actions
instructions in any in any table and the
tables may be a wild card table where
you have don't care bits in the in the
match field or an exact match table and
and then each table the width or the
number of matched fields that is defined
by the programmer and the number of rows
it's also defined by the programmer so a
good example here is the Novi flow
implementation where you have up to 1
million flow entries in at ECAM in up to
60 different tables and then in the
exact match use case you have up to 6
million rows or flow entries in up to 60
tables so the programmer can really
application program you can really put
together that the pipeline using these
primitives that then supports the
application yep move on to the next one
which is the the P for the the P for and
P for runtime match action pipeline so
so notice what we've been working with P
for for about two years we released our
first commercial product in May 2018
this was a switch nos that allowed you
to use the barefoot Tofino switch as an
open flow one death v switch
we essentially wrapped open flow around
p4 and allowed the user to create and
run an open flow pipeline on it to FINA
white box so basically we the user saw
an open flow switch but internally in
the nas we map that into p4 code that
get compiled and push into the silicon
so that was like the first step
mmm so when you look at the P for P for
runtime match action pipeline the P for
part is the programming language that is
used to define how a switch Silicon
process to packets you can define the
parser which is you know what kind of
match fields you're going to get you can
program the actions know what am I going
to do and then I can program and define
a match action pipeline tables in a
match action pipeline
and then the p4 runtime is really the
interface from an external p4 controller
or internal people controller to to
access and and program this match action
pipeline you know add flow entries or
initially what what you do first is you
load the compiled p4 program then you
can add delete flow entries in the match
action tables you can collect statistics
so the p f-- p4 runtime is really the
comparison to open flow from from a
networking perspective well while i'm
talking your slides are copyright i saw
that when you started that means I will
have to take them out of our repository
is that ok with you because we don't
have it we cannot have copyrighted
material ok so what I can do
my Jose I could I could submit another
one without the copyright let me check
my bad yeah ok very good
ok next slide please so this slide is
really to illustrate the extent by which
this the parser and and the the master
action pipeline and the actions are
defined in software so you basically
define an Ethernet header an ipv4 header
the tables you know what you match on
what what the actions are and so it's a
the software definition is driven all
the way down to 2 to bare bones and then
on so you have a header types parses
tables actions metadata and then you
have this thing called external objects
so it allows you to create functions in
your pipeline that will do
operations like check some registers
counters meters and also you know I any
and the other thing you can think of so
to move on next slide so comparing open
flow and P for P for runtime both of
them give you a programmable math
section pipeline
however P for P for runtime gives you
additional freedoms as you can program
the parser and also define your own
actions in open flow you know you can do
some of that through experimenter
extensions where the developer could
define new match feel some actions so
next slide so here's a slide showing at
the components of a Knauss and what
we've been talking about is the open
flow and the p for runtime and and in
that part but on top would add in in a
typical notes you also have you know
configuration management operations
management security management and other
extensibility is so and so that was
really my presentation thank you so I
have a question I have P for people
multiple times and I'm curious if you
have potentially a more satisfying
answer to this question which is I have
two programmers each of which have
written a p4 program and they don't know
about each other what's the composition
model for composing to p4 programs into
one and what's the model for how those
two programs can be loaded into the same
switch and what's the model for if I
want to change the program of the switch
without resetting the switch yeah it
also are very good questions and I I'm
afraid I don't have the answers to that
right now but I can follow up without
the answer the answer is with the p4
people have no clue how to do this is
more I don't have the answer so I can
get back to you with with the answers on
that yeah
send that to the list that would be
great and by the way for those who got
here very late Jasper and France lent us
two engineers that probably could have
the answer to your question and so that
was really great
are there any other questions at the
hackathon yes and the code you saw was
similar to the stuff we did at the
hackathon any other questions thank you
so much Jasper yeah thanks yes thanks um
good very good
there's a thingy somewhere quite good
think I'm going to be timely and so this
draft is submitted a couple of weeks ago
as a result of ongoing work as well as
proposed research a lot of the questions
we are asking we have ideas of answers
but real ones really and that's why we
thought it might be a good idea to
actually put this to the purse research
group because we feel of that might be a
good space for it
the book is launching center around
micro services that's what we're working
in but we have a slant in the draft
around what we call it abscent fig
micro-services and the reason for that
is is really to start from you know the
app economy in the smartphone world and
look at smartphones I have about 200 on
my smartphone and and you know it has
striven you know the development of
mobile experience as we launch you know
it we use applications around our smart
on our smart devices the design is
fairly static they're softer models
they're packaged into an application you
download them from of a store and you're
done with there are extended
client-server interactions you usually
see within these apps but that's about
it and what we want to move to mentally
at least as a thought experiment and we
have first demos on this is to mental
model where we look at an app as a
collection of micro services but you can
decompose and start bouncing around in
the network that's you know why we call
apps
so you decompose a nap into a set of
micro services you execute them on one
or more distributed resources that can
be at the edge of the network and the
cloud wherever they are and you
interpret each of these computers as a
pico micro data center and that's how we
turn a term they know the name App
Center so we look we don't look at the
data center we said well you just run
micro apps on it right that's what comes
from the use case we've demonstrated and
it's described in in the draft is mobile
function are floating so it said this
runs on standard Android we do Android
because we just don't program iOS for
reasons of resources really we wrap
helper classes micro service helper
classes around modules and this is done
purely at design time so you have to do
this at the moment at least we're also
working on the runtime version does this
automatically and the the the example
that's described in the draft is you
know very simple you receive an image
you processed the image to do some very
snapshot II kind of thingy and you
display it's we micro services makes a
lot of sense right and and now we
interpret a given experience like
watching that more video as a chain of
micro services that you know perceive
process this by and you're done words
and when you run the actual application
now which is still an application is
being installed as an application from
the actual Play Store
and all these micro services run on your
device it's just as it's as you used to
because it's an app right but what you
can do we've done we wrote a small and
software model that kills the modules on
the it essentially kills the processes
and what you see because they're micro
services they bounce off the actual
device and and run in the network as in
network computing and in the trophy we
describe a policy for using the actual
ask you figure I should have probably
used a better one and we realize that
over an SD Sdn infrastructure the app if
it runs
it's a DPR on the top store stands for
the modules you know despite process and
receive you run them like that they run
on on you know that's just the APIs you
see everything runs on your mobile and
we have a very simple control UI no
intelligence in there the intelligence
is yourself that that knocks them off
and you kill for instance the processing
the p1 of the the micro service and the
chain is missing and it jumps onto a
processing server in the network
the processing is more capable so you
can run different processing routines
etc you kill the D and it runs onto it
it jumps onto a smart TV which only
implements the D function not the other
ones because it doesn't do processing so
you get distributed experiences really
cute we ran this as a demo as a concept
demo in February this year I said work
to standard Android what we described in
the draft is what are some of the
technologies we you can do this all as a
vertically integrated demo works
perfectly the whole point about
standards is to do this obviously in a
way that it works not just for our demo
but it works for everybody right so we
outline certain areas in the draft that
we feel work needs to be done some has
to do with application packaging not
entirely sure that's an ITF area but
nonetheless describe that which is
usually done at design time and what we
do we defined wrapper classes we expose
those we are in the process of injecting
them into the open source community so
they can be used you can also do
profiling to do this actually at runtime
that's the real fun part so you have an
application that hasn't been designed at
the micro Service and it's being pulled
apart into micro servers at runtime and
then it starts bouncing about in the
network that's actually quite cool we
hope to demonstrate that in a couple of
months time another various service
deployment how does the P server makes
it there I remember the one before so
there was the processing server in the
network we actually have done this by
combining application installation with
service orchestration when you install
the app we are not using the actual
Android application installer we do use
but we have a an extended version which
not only installs the application but it
points out of the asset package of the
application package a service
orchestration template and pushes it
into the netbook and says dude I need a
processing server can you please install
one for me right and the packages over
there again there's a lot of
standardization you you would need to do
to make that work outside a vertically
integrated demo and and the integration
with the app installation model it's
really quite cute because application
users just see an application
installation they don't really see a
service deployment so that's one of the
reason why we like that service routing
I too
talk about stuff bouncing about now
obviously that requires that you have in
place a service routing infrastructure
is usually done as a combination of DNS
and IP routing our bouncing about is
relatively flexible so we use ongoing
work in the SFC working group which is
now going smooth the ISE route on so
called named service function chaining
as well as service routing over to
environments but allows you to actually
do this really flexibly so we have a
couple of demos where you will see if
you do this in a standard DNS plus IP
system it won't be required work because
the city is not there and we describe
this issue in the traffic as well the
Dynamis 'ti of in network computing in
particular when you bounce functions
around based and use interactions I walk
into the room I suddenly want to go for
my actual discipline and the mobile I
want to jump onto the display in the
room that's very very flexible and it
requires solution for service routing
that are probably different from the
ones we know service pinning we describe
that based on the use case if you have
two resources that actually implement
the same micro service how do I make
sure I'm actually using the one that I
really want to use and think about the
display it might matter an awful lot on
which display you actually display stuff
even though it's the same d micro
service I really want to have that one
though and have the other one and for
various reasons the pinned relations can
change very frequently your requirements
your constrains change you know I might
walk in a different room I do want to go
use actually the other display so the
pinning has to change frequently as well
all right and how do I do this in a
standardized manner that will allow me
to do this and the last area that we
describe the state's organization we do
work with a mixture of stateless as well
as stateful microservices state you
can't enforce only one of them and
therefore state synchronization is very
very crucial
typical use cases that are very very
stateful are in particular gaming use
cases where you indeed need on good
state civilization so these are the
areas and I said we have a couple they
are reference in the draft you can see
to ongoing work that we also are
currently doing the ITF and other
working groups and not generally we try
to keep those sections as these are cool
areas to work on I think we need some
work
this in order to move into standardized
environments and it would be good to
have a place for this alright so the
conclusion really is really trying to
stick to my ten minutes is that the
trapped positions in evolution and we
tried to stick this to the app model
because everybody knows that I should be
played this story to particular people
who don't really quite understand but an
Internet really is with a sense of IP
packets we played this to teenagers and
they love this story alright by for them
the internet or application
installations so the whole idea that I
install my private Internet by having an
application is something that really
goes done really well and and we also
like the idea of moving from the mobile
terminal experience as we know today
everybody has a smartphone to something
add in handy disintegrates into
distributive experiences and that's the
the reason why we made that leap but
generally I feel obviously that the
points also blight the general micro
service use cases its itself I said we
interpret available compute resources as
these peak or micro data centers they
can be dedicated computer resources in
the demo we gave this year we played the
scenario in a entertainment scenario
hotel where the compute resource was
provided by the hotel for hotel guests
so in that case you might really have a
computer act downstairs right but Pico
data centers could be home devices it
could be another user smartphone and be
also actually in the use case jumped on
somebody else's smartphone the
smartphone was plugged in so therefore
it was a suitable data center if it
wasn't blocked in
it wasn't chosen because you don't want
to jump on somebody who runs on battery
we believe that the post corner G would
be a really really good platform to
actually discuss some of these issues
bring them together evaluate them but
also obviously link to ongoing efforts a
lot of these efforts are ongoing in
other working groups and therefore
bringing them together and probably also
you know get more people involved in the
discussion is a really really good thing
some of the comments that I put on the
list already
related to that so there were a couple
of things that I had sent to the list
the next steps
and personally I really hope that they
propose research group is indeed
approved we plan on doing is to update
the draft with more information on the
ongoing
so be quite clear or what's going on as
that they are references in but we
haven't really described in detail but
also provide an overview of other
realizations because in the currently we
are referring to a lot of things that we
are involved in there's other things and
also we plan on demonstrating
realizations maybe at an upcoming
meeting so people can see these funny
micro-services bouncing about thank you
[Applause]
one question so for the solutioning
implementation what are the information
units those functions actually operate
on a good terminating some application
so we saw the reference at behalf of the
draft is to name service function
training so we actually extend it I'll
be proposed to extend service function
change which we saw in the presentation
before too on entire name basis so you
issue a URL based requests rather than
IP voice requests and the the service
function as was presented in the service
function training one before it's always
associated with some form of control we
don't use a manner control obviously our
service function changing is defined in
the application see the application in
the application design you specify that
micro chain of you know our PD it's a
Ryan bear we're also looking at the
frameworks that automates that and
therefore essentially constructs for you
an actual name service chain which is
then translated internet such as nsh
which and is pumped into the name
service function actually receiving or
sending so what is it is it a flow of
packets or how does it work the so the
the draft at the moment outlines the the
packet is the actual HTTP request so
it's known on key packet because is that
the name yeah so so and HTTP at the
moment is the example for a named
extension thank you
okay okay hello everyone this is polio
from China mobile and I was talking
about the new draft requirements of
computing in the network so as we all
know computing in network becomes a
nutrient to meeting the needs of
emerging business what needs to be
computed and why there are several
problems need to be considered such as
the traditional network protocols only
optimize traffic which can't guarantee
the latency of packet loss rate and the
centralization of computing resource is
not efficient and for the different
business there are they may need
different kind of computing and they are
little interaction among users of
applications and the networks which
means that they don't know each other's
requirement and the capabilities so some
work has began to consider these issues
but more comment words to be considered
and the number one requirement is
deterministic network abilities which
include the latency and packet loss rate
so for the latency it's the concept from
in time to anthem which means the
latency is not necessarily the lower the
better it's just like to size agreement
and Sacre Edition and for the packet
loss rate it includes the time bearing
routing which found the link time very
regular based on AI and the predicting
the network performance and there are
also other technology such as segmented
transmissions to enhance to achieve
segmented retransmissions and the number
two requirement is computing a well
scheduling in this model commuting in
sync as a link state and the convenient
source information is exposed so cutting
to the business required requests
dynamic computing power matching is
carried out based on network status and
the performance of computing resource to
achieve optimal user experience and
network utilization and the number three
requirement is a function based
addressing and for the traditionally
based addressing it might bring some
problems and which come to current easy
they such as the latency so in the new
function based at addressing the
application components destructed to on
the server side are distributed under
cloud platform and the business logic in
the server is transferred to the client
side and the kite only needs to care
about a computing function itself so as
to realize that they function as their
service and the last requirement is
network Brown who ability and so in
network programming and the resource of
network and the computing information
can be transferred by network to users
so L to the requirements of the
information transmitted by user to
network so the network can configure
parameters according to the user users
needs and the users transfer
requirements based on network
abilities which could efficiently
support the future application so in the
next steps more requirements might need
to be analyzed considering the computing
capability and some of like discussion
about the related technologies may need
also need and thanks any other comments
so actually this is just a little bit of
historical stuff on it the original spec
for is is had a per node cost of
traversing that node which was called
the hippity cost so your packers to go
hop hippity hop hippity hop hippity hop
and back then we took it out as a
gratuitous complexity because there
there wasn't much difference between the
costs of forwarding a packet on one node
versus another node it may be time to
bring that back okay thank you very much
so we have just a few more minutes so we
intend to have a virtual interim
probably in early October we'll do an
email poll and we would like to address
probably the last version of the Charter
and hopefully a set of milestones I get
the message from Dirk
the first Dirk Dirk k about having
milestone while you're still it proposed
that proposed RG but we kind of like the
idea of focusing the work we're
obviously are going to meet at ITF 106
which will be our third meeting and
hopefully we'll be accepted before that
and thank you so very much for everybody
who came and for all your support
actually I think we're calling
themselves the gems so that the Jeffrey
Eve and I are really happy of how this
is going and we really thank you for all
your great work thank you