[Music]
you can start thank you welcome this is
Dina self working group we have two
hours this session I'm Benna Tim is
sitting over there Suzanne is over here
scribe is who subscribe actually Brian
here Berman will be helping them out
concetto pretend to be here for the
whole meeting and our minute taker is
thank you Paul thank you
okay welcome demon ah excellent
thank you very much a note well take
notice of this note well is also applied
so this working group of course blue
sheets please fill them in with a full
room we want to have a large room and
for the next time also to accommodate
everyone thank you agenda we have a full
agenda so please bear with me if we are
a little bit strict on time management
depending on a discussion of course we
have some current working group business
to a name we have something like the
chairs introduction we will give brief
context about a name and a new draft by
Eric negan I sorry I've mispronounced
your name about HTTP SVC well gives a
little bit context how they overlap but
also different new working business it's
not all new but it's not it's not dinner
stop working business yet is work on the
r DD r DB d by Steven and maybe Carson
okay some will give a presentation new
work by Paul hora Giovanni will give an
update etcetera if time permits what
I'll give a presentation on Venus
comfort good let's get started
so we want to start with a name
discussion here a name has seen a number
of iterations after Tony did some
redrafting of the document it simplified
a name draft and it makes a distinction
be the authoritative parts and the
recursive part so much of the complexity
are in the recursive part and the more
simple use case are in the alternative
part a name
at least it started out to solve a
problem like an alias or a cname in the
apex but it also has other solutions
that's a solution it spawns a solution
space with the recent SPS SVC proposal
it's address is partly the same problem
provisioning web services or names for
web services on different maybe multiple
CD ends so that seems to be an overlap
so the chair still believe they
addressed different problem spaces with
an overlap but are still both worthwhile
to explore so let's keep that in mind
when we discuss the different drafts
more specifically a name and if you have
more interest in that's use case a name
is very interesting if you talk about
API so if you go for fertilization you
have all kind of services on different
places that move around you want so it's
not specific it has started a name work
started out for the web services and the
CDN said provisioning but it has a
larger solution space also for api's and
not necessarily web services web
browsers Tim should I mention something
else on this topic to give some context
so so for
keep in mind as the authoritative parts
comp less complex in the recursive part
for HCPs it's straightforward cotton
quality solution but it probably needs
some additional processing for the
records but we expect I am NOT and web
browser developer this additional
processing is probably done by the web
browsers anyway or might be end up
somewhere extra work in Lipsey I don't
know but that's all something to discuss
during the drafts I think I give
sufficient contacts on both the draft
we reserved quite some time twenty plus
twenty minutes so it's about 40 ish
minutes including discussions of course
I think we go to the remote presentation
by my dice Evan will be in the room is
in the room and this will act as a
backup for discussions and explanations
I don't think it's necessary but okay
thank you
hello now you can hear me yeah we do
hear you I do see you and I think yeah
on the large screen URLs of this book
I'm I will go to the slide sorry yeah
thanks I think this might ask this one
yes you see the slides yes yes please go
out and say next next slide let me think
so
they know already mentioned a little bit
on the motivation
so this slide should be a little bit of
repetition this is the motivation we
started out we want to do seeing them at
the apex of the suit work for the CBN's
but it's not the only use case although
admittedly it's probably the largest use
case the nests provide us with silly end
customers now have their own propriety
solutions and so it's hard for them to
to switch providers or support multiple
model next slide a little bit of history
basically forget everything before the -
no - version that version I think is the
fundamental basis of aiming everything
before had some issues it required to
resolve a spot which made it hard to
deploy had issues with some transfers
and so the rewrite actually makes it
much simpler in the sense that it makes
aiming processing optional in every
place but possible in any place what
that means is that afforded if can do
the ending processing but then the
result can also do they mean processing
and that might be redundant if both to
them but it still works
from there I sort of cook the editing
obligations on me and I made it first
and editorial version which is attached
to a tree and then a one that resolves
some issues that was still existing in a
digital version next slide so the deso 2
version for those who haven't been
following the evening work is the much
cleaner version it makes a result of
support optional and even the perfect
look of optional that means that if
nobody's doing a name it's not so useful
it would be similar to just publishing
every circuit in the zone but the
expectation is that the DNS provider
will implement or would look up at lives
as their alternative to the propriety
solutions there is no longer an
exception for zone transfers there's
lots of flexibility to get to your use
case yeah let's go to the next slide so
- up free is mostly style structure some
moving text form from the main body to
the appendix because it's more a
background information and I want to do
this version before going into the
issues to make a clear cut so that
explains where we have a - or 3 next
fight
- afford use with a lot of issues that
were mentioned on the list put him to
the github and then and then we solved
these three I think are the main ones
first one is alien precedents there was
a discussion whether the addresses that
are next to the aining whether they
should override aiming or could be used
as a defaults when the lookup fails for
example we resolved it to being as a
default
that means in the - co2 version that was
already okay so little tax changes were
needed for the - affirm the second one
listed TTL considerations when doing a
target lookup now when you have resolved
the target and you're going to place the
sibling other circuits if the TTL will
be the minimum of all the encountered
TTL so if you do look up in Percy name
on or a name you will minimize the TTL
and then eventually will be target and
so you're going to necessary matters
it's the TTL will be the lowest you'll
encounter this is because when you're
doing this at the afford it if you're
actually playing as a resolver and so
you can do some caching but then you
have a cache at your authoritative and
then the client will ask for records and
they will cast themselves as well so
there's some TTL stretching here and and
taking the minimum TTL will mitigate
against it's a little bit we also put
some text in there for those stretching
considerations explain what exactly
happens and the third point is whether
the sibling advocates records should be
in the additional section so let me
rephrase again whether when you do a
address query so cute IP say or four day
whether the a9 should be in the answer
section or in the additional section am
is part of the answer so it makes sense
to put them in the am section but Tony
pointed out that the DNA is caused a lot
of issues still on the demos of list it
looked like there was slight concerns a
slightly leaning towards putting the
enemy in the answer section so the -
refer has specification or
that and put them in in the answer
section next slide this is a list of all
the issues with results on the github so
you can see there's a lot of work being
done next slide there are some open
issues one of them is the loop detection
issue and the loop detection issue is
the point where you doing a query in
addis barry and you're following the
target
so an address query which has an a name
on that evening may trigger another
additional query to look up that target
that can hit another server that has a
name name and that will point back to
eventually the same server creating a
loop and it's very hard to detect a blue
young posted is to list with some
options to resolve it
one option is to put the logic that a
queue type a name means that the
afforded a service should not almost not
chase the target so that accent avoids
or allows for a target look up without
one have to worry about a loop and the
other one is having an easiness option
and that says don't chase targets i know
a name myself my personal consideration
that the last one is that eventually
will hope that browsers will query for a
name or similar record and how will they
signal that support and also in the
current version of the draft we say a
for deaf can do any processing which
also can do any processing so if we
resolve a signal support for a name and
authority
could still chase targets because it
wants to give the most optimized
response so that's one issue next slide
another open issue is what to do if you
do any processing and the target lookup
fails so basically how to treat an error
response my feeling is that that you
could use the currently known sibling
other circuits as the best effort or
another option is to transfer fail
because on your lookup something
unexpected happens so would you give
back a slightly less optimized response
or would you prefer to signal that that
I look up films next slide so there's
actually a couple of more issues there's
no slide for that but better provided a
review on aiming which has some slight
some small issues that I think also need
to be covered together with that I think
we should cover those issues hopefully
shortly after this meeting my plan is to
publish a dash of five and hopefully
that will be the first thing that can go
to working book last call and I think
that's it thank you any comments from
the room
questions remarks Ben Schwartz Google
I'm one of the co-authors on the draft
that will be presented next which has
been I mentioned also bears on some of
these issues and so I don't want to give
too much of a preview or mix the topics
but I'll just say that I I've come to
the conclusion that that I think we do
want both of these proposals that I I
personally think that we should probably
standardize both but I do think that
there's an opportunity to to simplify a
name by essentially taking some of the
use cases that generate complexity and
and sort of pushing them over to the
HTTP service draft and so for that
reason I'd like to see if we can not go
to last call until we've had a chance to
absorb both of these options and see
what the best way is to divide
functionality between them yeah thank
you
Evan hunt is see I was the original name
draft author and I wanted to make a
similar but also kind of different point
I also don't think we should go to last
call but it has always been my opinion
from the beginning that the reason I was
doing the a name draft was that I did
not expect browser uptake of any other
solution I'm getting the impression now
that there is some momentum for browsers
to take up HTTP SVC and I believe that
if they do so I would personally
recommend that we not proceed forward
with a name I'd suggest that we shall
but until such time as we have a really
clear use case that justifies the weight
on the camel that said however since I
don't know yet whether the browser's are
in fact going to pick up HTTPS we see I
think we need to carry on as if they
won't until we find out that they will
but I think that I think that working
group last call might be premature at
this point tim was sinski I know I made
some comments kind of cautious about it
HTTP VC but I've really come around on
it
I like a lot of the ideas especially not
putting you know stuff in there but I
ever saw a name as trying to solve the
web problem I always saw it trying to
solve the name at Apex problem and so
and I think part of my problem this is
what I didn't want to sit up there today
because I spend way more of my day now
talking about containers and sight cars
and service meshes and all these things
and I'm think about like I see we're
aiming I get host my name right I
remember it mentioned that to Eric and
that's like how do we you know you know
a night Eric's you know Eric had some
great answers for that right but and I
look at all these zones so I'm an
operator right and I I work for a crazy
company that does weird things and so
but I spend a lot of time looking at
zone data
I see no zones anymore with a and quad-a
in them anymore and they do crazy things
where they're just service cuts you know
they're just doing zone cuts all over
the place and then doing oh we're gonna
do AWS security based on doing zone cuts
and then everybody's just doing alias
records you know at various apex points
and stuff like that and nobody has an A
or quad-a anywhere and it's just like
okay this is a totally different reality
than I think anybody's ever thought of
right and so it's like I think I'm in a
weird world and I understand that but
I'm trying to feel I think they both
have value like you say and I'm but it's
like I think a team needs to be simpler
as far as the best race it say it and I
can see a name being like your worst
case performance thing for web stuff and
then hey that makes you want to like
move to the HTTP service which faster
kind of thing
so yeah that's my opinion but yeah and
thank you Miss iestrellas work and so I
think it's really good I think we're
yeah I think we need to never never rev
on that if people want it and I don't
know if the working group wants to do
one or two so we'll leave it to the
chairs
Ron Dixon Go Daddy I agree with most of
the previous folks that HDPE SBS
definitely is SBC is is the way to go
for the web use case I'm wondering for
the API use cases whether it's feasible
to go back to you to the the larger more
generic SRV if that's feasible at all
but it's something to consider as well
but definitely my vote would be for
putting on putting a bit of a break on a
name until we know about the the other
proposal okay thank you better shakes is
I think I think that the last call is
well premature the sections 1 1 to 4 are
ok-ish and could solve the
interoperability problem between health
providers and that's okay but the
processing Condor is oversized sections
5 & 6 needs more work so we either
postpone the last call and refine
resolver processing or splitted to two
drafts and you know dude solve the
interoperability for cloud providers and
then go and look at the optimizations
because the resolver processing is just
optimization not requirement yeah I
think we'll discuss both options with
office yeah thank you just to clarify
I'm not suggesting to do the current
version as a working to block all the
issues that better mention on the list
and look it's action issue and the
remaining issues need to be resolved
first in a dash of 5
Heights tell Tim you managed to confuse
me a little you started off by saying
you never saw a name is solving the web
problem but I was just solving the C
name at the apex problem which I
understand all those words but to me the
compelling use case that C named at the
apex was the problem for was the web and
I wasn't aware that there were other
compelling use cases
and it and and records at the apex make
a big difference there for the remote
participants the different use case our
service anyways yeah so then great that
there's an another use case I'm done
with that but I think that it probably
should be mentioned in the draft you
know what what these other use cases are
doing since again yeah it's it's not
even it's not even like the browser
stuff it's all that back-end servers
that talk to all the back-end services
that talk to all the various things that
are basically and they're just setting
up zones understanding something at the
apex it's like why not I have an apex
right why do I need to actually add
anything else to it you know it's like
they're an engineer they're working in
some application space in the world
that's kind of wonderful to them right
and so and so you're saying the world is
kind of wonderful thinners so I and so
it that is sort of a different use case
than you know but if you're in this
weird container world which everybody is
seems to be running into at full speed
right there's they're just these elastic
services fancy cloud things that people
get and you never get an answer you know
you never get in a wrecker until the
very end basically right so takeaway is
put that in the draft yeah so Eric
Nygren Akamai and I think on some of
those that that particularly use case of
cloud services and I think one thing
that before jumping straight into a name
is a solution there may be to step back
and work with some of those folks to
figure out what the requirements are
because I think when you look at the
requirements in that space especially
with things like service meshes and
similar becoming more common that often
times those things are wanting to go
from a name to a to a more complicated
set of stuff like they're looking to go
to a IP port pair so it may actually be
that maybe even SRV or it should be a
server something else was actually more
applicable than it didn't solve that
problem okay so concluding here can I
come down from that I I'm not convinced
yet that we should put all the use cases
in here I feel like people seeing in and
thinking hey this might fit my use case
and now additional requirements will
come there I think a name
initially the motivation was to have
something else that propriety idea
cinematic VFX solutions and there's
those all are basically going to a
different name at your apex that is what
aiming provides sure if the working
group now thinks we should come up with
the solution that fits both CDN and
service end points and they text and
then we should say take a step back but
that was never the initial case of
anything so putting all those many use
cases in the draft I'm not convinced
that it's a good idea it's a lot of
extra work that's just delaying actual
implementation of a name thank you to
make some progress but I'm just
proposing this without any consultation
and maybe so in August Tim always tells
that all the Europeans are on holidays
who nothing happens but maybe in
September October ish early October we
can plan a virtual meeting on this topic
do you get the use case order the
overlap and the differences and more
clear straighten out so we have
something more the next step for the
next RDF meeting in Singapore okay thank
you
we will send some follow-up emails to
the mailing list to coordinators okay
thank you my dice yeah okay so okay
thank you
next yeah Eric yeah no degree of eating
okay that's better no degree of eating
them out my could have helped in that
case um so eight can talk about HTTP VC
which is a little bit of a mouthful the
the goal here was looking at a bunch of
these different use cases that were
coming up in a number of working groups
and TLS DNS off HD PBS quick and trying
to see if there was a holistic solution
for them because one of the problems
we're running into is is that we're
running into this chicken and the egg of
various things wanted to have a some
information in the DNS to use to prime
before making a connection to an HTTP
connection but there was a concern on
the browser side on this like oh if we
have to go do an extra DNS lookup for
that particular use case what is gonna
be the performance impact what's going
to be the impact on bad home bad home
recursive resolver is it that don't know
about extra record types is and also as
you start accumulating these different
record lookups are you going to be in a
situation before where where it's not
just one lookup you have to make that
it's ten different lookups and then you
have correlation issues between them so
HTTP SVC tries to look at some of these
holistically the things which some of
the use cases we've been trying to
address have been the encrypted S&I keys
discussion that's been going on in the
TLS working group which we've had a
number of design meetings around there's
the the ability to negotiate a transport
protocol in particular for HTTP 3 where
with HTTP 2 you can use a LPN to
negotiate upwards with with HTTP 3
currently the only way to get to
actually use quick is to first go
through TCP by H 2 or H 1
and then get a header back that cause
you negotiate up so the next row
round-trip there that having that
information having information in DNS
could help skip there is a use case of
indicating that that in origin defaults
to HTTPS so for example in the browser
use case if someone types a bear name
like example.com into a web browser does
the web browser default into HTTP or
HTTPS today it has to go to http M
securely and get a redirect back and
this prevents an opportunity to to have
a say much more safe and secure default
as more things ibiki to PS by default
and then the a long-standing issue on
the dns ops side is is hey we created
this SRV record why won't the browser's
implement it and which led to a number
of VA named discussions of okay we need
to create a name because browsers won't
implement as haven't implemented s SRV
and that chicken and egg there and being
able to address that but then also it's
clear that we've been accumulating these
use cases it was probably going to be
the n plus one in a year or two or three
from now in fact I've been kind of
terrified at the number of people who
have come come up with other use cases
not all of which are applicable and
since the since that or the first
version of the draft was published um so
being about to be extensible without
having to go and add new record types
that browsers would have to look up so
the goal here we have a single new brow
a single new record that browsers could
resolve in parallel with the a and
quad-a lookups that would be extensible
enough that we could use for the next
solve kind of the current cases but but
but also be extensible enough to cover
the next few the but also to do this in
a way that's a that is usable for
operators usable for site site owners
and has some ability to do some of the
performance optimizations so that it
doesn't have a huge lots of different RT
T's in the case word has been set up
sanely there's gonna be obviously gonna
be some corner cases where things are
gonna have more performance overhead but
I think another goal here is to have
something that's compelling enough to
finally convince clients and browsers
that it's going to go implement it
any one of these use cases like SRV may
not have been enough to get browsers to
implement it but if we can solve a few
of these together plus the next few and
move to more secure defaults that may be
enough to and has gotten some interest
from browsers of this may actually be
enough to start moving the needle and to
do something here so structure wise when
looking at this record there's a number
of properties of this that end up being
similar to the concept of SRV and i
think the idea here is that that within
a given within a given resource record
or RR there's a number of these things
you need to glue together and return
back to clients as a a single unit and
some of those may be references off to
other things to go use so in the SRV
case it was a you had as the name
something which was basically the name
and the port in the scheme and the
target of or the data of the RR was a
combination of things it was that
service Jim it was a a domain name it
was a port and priority information on
HTTP SRV basically starts off with that
basic kind of port and I end and
hostname that SRV has but then makes it
extensible so tied to those two and tied
to that are that are within that are are
you can start adding on additional
information such as as the what is the
application protocol such as h3 that's
supported if there are any es ni keys
that are needed to negotiate and the
handshake what are those and part of the
reason why it's critical to have those
kind of bound together at the RR is
because like in the es and I discussions
within the TLS working group you may
have these different different services
being operated by different operators
you may have with transitions where
we're seen amis has switched from or
things are switching from one hosting
provider to another or you have
operational upgrades or you may have
multi CDN use cases and you try to mix
and match things like es ni keys and
which application protocol is supported
with which actual services imports to
connect to
work so well so there are two forms of
the HTTP SVC record one of those if you
look at the structure of the record the
and the defaults in the candidate for
the default HTTP port and scheme doesn't
use any label prefixes and that
operationally makes a bunch of things
easier but in the the Ana's alias form
the very first element is a is a service
record type 0 that means that it's alias
form there's a priority that that isn't
used in this record and this forms of 0
and then you have the service domain
name so in this this form it's purely an
alias target this is one which is
handled by clients there's no special
hand it's similar to SRV where there's
no special handling that's needed by
authorities no special handling needed
in DNS SEC no special handling needed
and recursive and then there's the
alternative service form which is
basically which you can think of as a SR
an extensible SRV so it starts off with
the that service record type 1 saying
that it's the alternative service form
followed by a priority followed by the
that on that service domain name target
similar to SSR v but then a bunch of
extensible information and this we're
proposing to use the things in the alt
service format which is a format that's
defined in RFC in the HTTP working group
and then at least one Club at least one
browser supports and is also part of how
clients negotiate up to to quick in the
in the HTTP 3 protocol and so in this
case it so in this case the first one of
these records would say say that you can
either use quick to UDP over UDP 2 sv 3
3 sv c 3 example that met 8003 with this
particular set of us in Ikeys or you
could do HTTP to 2 over tcp to a
different SVC 2 with a different port
with these other yes and I keys and I
think one thing I'll highlight here is
it that well web browsers is a common
use for HTTP HTTP isn't just about web
browsers like as a from a CDN
perspective we're actually seeing that a
huge fraction of traffic that we have is
not for is no longer just from browsers
it's also from API clients think on
service to service calls and a bunch of
this information around kind of port
associations and bindings and protocols
are just as applicable to some of those
in the cloud use cases as they are to
the web browser use case on a how does
this compare how do HTTP service and a
name compare to each other I think
they're complementary they solve
different cases there's not necessarily
saying that one may need to replace the
other I think there may be cases where
if we look and say say that we can have
the two of these together and that they
both felt things that maybe we can
reduce a bunch of complexity out of a
name it may be that looking at what is a
coverage set of problem spaces we're
trying to solve might be that there's a
bunch of use cases out of a name that
could just be pulled out and reduce the
amount of camelid that's happening there
so the I think the big one of the big
differences and been helped clarify that
clarify this in the slides was that that
HTTP SVC doesn't require any changes to
DNS servers it's basically something
that's just a record type that has no
special handling whereas a name on the
other hand doesn't require any special
changes to clients the clients in it
with you have a named clients basically
just magic all the existing clients
magically work with HTTP SVC all the
existing name servers just magically
work so that's probably the biggest
distinction between those and any but on
the con side there that means that it
should PS SVC is only respected by the
compliant clients so to add support into
clients which would ideally would be
something that I'm expecting would
happen at the client library perspective
and if we've been looking at the
ecosystem of client libraries that are
out there there's a lot of cases on the
HTTP I miss
much complexity involved in making an
HTTP connection already that a lot of
operating that a lot of mature operating
systems are starting to provide higher
level abstractions so applications
aren't going and doing get hosts my name
they're going and provide calling some
some OS or library API that is going and
dealing with all the certification DNS
stuff all that stuff for them and this
so that's presumably where this would
get shimmed in there a downside here is
this is HTTP specific but again HTTP is
not a is not just about web browsers and
I think a consideration for this if this
is successful might be that maybe there
is a pattern here that some of the
things we could learn by age from HTTP
SVC might be applicable to other
protocols and having a either more
generic or other record type that kind
of leverages off some of the things
structure of this might make sense to
have is more generic and I think that
maybe also a question for the working
group of how much makes sense to over
genera size HTTP SVC versus keep it
focused on the HTTP use case so next
steps we're going to be talking about
this also in the HTTP HDPE Biss on
Thursday initially I thought that was
the best home for adoption I think in
talking with people here I think there's
a question on whether it makes sense to
have whether to adopt this in DNS
operates deep abyss I don't have a
strong feeling either way I think that's
up to the working groups and the chairs
on where they think would be the most
constructive place and where there's the
most interest in doing work on this and
but I think no matter what it's going to
be critical to get to get input from
both of those communities and I think
actually I've been very pleased on the
amount of great feedback we've gotten
from DNS so far in particular as we on
the some of the stuff we had in the wire
format didn't make sense and we've
cleared that up based and I got some
feedbacks from some browser
implementations in fact there is a
already a bind nine private type in
draft implementation that Mark Andrews
did and the hackathon as presented
yesterday someone did an implementation
and unbound I was kind of surprised
before
presented that there are already two
implementations but feedback comment
suggestions are most welcome here thank
you
yeah I think I'm the administrative
issue we had already actually did the
chairs had already discussed this
briefly and I think what we're gonna do
this get together with the HTTP chairs
and we'll figure out where it belongs
but we're gonna need review and
buckler's hmm Warren Kumari would you
mind going back to the thing where you
have the old service DNS HCP one yeah so
a quick question and sorry if you've
already answered this but it looks like
there are a number of things that you
can stick it right there's like h2 h3 ma
assist yes and I keys how big do these
end up cuz I could see this getting
really large which is funded us I think
that's the that's definitely concern and
definitely I think I think that becomes
a matter of how much gets shoved in here
and we'll want to be still want to be
some guidance on what is appropriate to
put in here and what's not appropriate
to put in here like for exact
then highlighted is that that not
everything makes sense to especially if
especially when DNS especially when DNS
SEC validation isn't being done by
clients there's some things that you
might seem attractive to put in here but
would have unfortunate security
properties um so I think a lot of the I
think the things that you would want to
put in here would need to have some
constraints on and some consideration on
what would make sense there there is
already a the alt service already has a
Ayana registry for the alt service
parameters which is part of why we're
using this to kind of leverage off of
off of that and this draft just adds
proposes adding on the es and I keys but
that could potentially be split off as a
separate draft it might make sense to do
that and I think one question that's
come up on the browser side that fits
into that is to what degree would
browsers do this over doe 53 to do 53
genus over 53 versus just doing this
over doe where some of the size issues
become somewhat less somewhat less of a
problem
I all over the Muslim CloudFlare I like
this a lot and I think this is a much
better and cleaner solutions than a name
but you have managed to walk into the
biggest pitfall the DNS has ever had
with dealing with records you have
subtyping and that has always to be
taken as a backing of thought and makes
things very difficult so I would propose
that you get rid of this first numeric
field in there and just have a case 0
with an empty shrink just type 2 or type
1 as it is in there that would be my
suggestion
under this record I'm not sure I file
I'm not sure I finally follow but I'm
happy to provision interfaces etc they
will write it based on the spec when it
gets published so when you implement the
next asked form or service record type
it's not going to get supported ever by
most of the provisions because they are
it's a one-time-only write process for
that mmm we have this problem with DNS
keys we have this with all kinds of all
the records so just have one format and
that is acceptable in the string cut yet
mm-hmm would be my suggestion
yeah as for implementation yeah this is
gonna be easy to handle but there is a
question about the sni K keys in the
multi cloud instance given a number of
operators roll these keys over very
rapidly it's gonna require online
generation of these records
that'll be and I think some of that may
be interesting that's probable a good
discussion to have on the kind of a TLS
side to see how that relates yeah
relates there so we have sufficient time
but I want to close the line Evan hunter
first of all HTTP SVC is way too much of
a mouthful I'm gonna call it hat tip
service from now on I invite you all to
join me
you mentioned implementation status on
the DNS side do you have any information
about implementation status on the
browser side um not yet any movement at
all yet okay I mention it because
changes and implementation status on the
browser
we'll inform the decisions that we make
with respect to whether a name is
worthwhile
I think and I'd like to figure out how
we can find out what what the what the
early indicators will be if this is it's
actually getting up take the other
question I wanted to ask all of our
already mentioned some typing and I
don't care subtyping as much have you
did you give any thought to genera
sizing this so that it wouldn't be
specific to http and that may be an
additional some type field that would
indicate that this is for a different
but similar use case that's not HTTP I
it's worth considering I think my big
worry about that would be that the our
our set gets really big is that if we
start he's basically start putting all
the potential services if you basically
put the like HTTP as a key in there and
you don't do this as it and you don't do
a prefix label then your are our set has
to contain all the different possible
services that you might support it may
be word I think it's worth considering
or may be worth having genera sizing and
there's a bunch of different things I've
thought about on the generic sizing
front in fact a a few years back I had a
more generic draft that was very very
similar to this but but I don't I think
what's the one option might be to to
have the format be generic but then to
hat but then for at least for a few of
the most common are are types or few of
the most common application types would
just be to use a different RR type form
for each of those but still bounding
that fairly small okay thanks sorry I
did close the mic line so thank you
Loren's clearly I think I also find sort
of the IC HTTP service SVC and just keep
hearing the word browser browser browser
browser why there are lots of
complications in our browser I mean you
use yourself mention API endpoints and
container container communication I
would like to echo the call to sort of
can we can we at least like try to
design this to be generic and not like
because I keep using the word browser
we're gonna end up doing some
engineering that only actually really
works for browsers so if you have
something like a split like DNS was over
with and application model like you know
most of Android is like that you've got
a DNS resolver and you've got a bunch of
apps to go what's happened this and that
and you could you could say that what
saps a browser cuz it just uses HTTP but
I think we might you know it huh
TLS or it yet TLS service seems like a
good idea because it is a lot of this is
in fact TLS but you know SMTP also uses
TLS it would be really good if we didn't
barks ourselves in and I think also that
would actually argue for not doing this
maybe an HTTP bus is an HTP working
group but actually trying to do this
maybe even here you know so well
actually this group can't do protocols
or can it I don't know but then then
then I think you know it would sort of I
think it would I think it would help a
lot if we if we looked at because I I
guess I see maybe you know maybe this
can become what s are we never could
right so and I think for size your
concern was size but I can't think in
practice we're actually gonna end up
doing this over TCP and then encrypted
transport anyway cuz you probably don't
want that stuff in the clear where
anyone can mess with oh yeah like I'm
actually gonna move to a different port
right cuz like oh here here's your new s
and I keys because I'm in the middle and
I happen to be yours all right you don't
want that anyway so I think the the sort
of size constraints are really not you
know material anymore but that's just my
personal opinion either discussion on
the microphone or all right Steve Brown
so and yeah good comments are all for
made that people are rolling yes my keys
every hour minutes now there's only one
real deployment but nonetheless and so
yeah I mean I guess my take is if
browsers implement this than I like it
also it's not clear to me I mean there's
an ESN I or R type in the is my spec is
your intense that clients would look up
maybe both or what
I had added a slide on that but only put
it in the deck for to the chillest
working group the but I then I think one
thing on the structure of this a part of
why I'm part of why there is the Elias
Forum is to get is to be able to to
either see name or use the alias form
for whoever is kind of operating
example.com to be able to have the
option of delegating and pointing this
over to whoever is operating the service
so that the whoever is operating those
servers could be returning this record
and the yes and I keys themselves so
that in collaboration they could be
could be doing that quick that quick
rolling without having to do without
having to go and find some way of
getting the s and I keys back into the
back into the the first part domain but
generally I mean if browsers did
implemented I mean I guess you can
handle having the es like public key in
many different formats and different
places in the DNS seems that I could
downside but I don't know what to do
about that Ben Schwartz so ok on on the
ESN I question my view is that that we
should pick one and I would like to pick
this one and not to the other one so
that hopefully that answers that
question on the online signing thing
Eric just answered this but in case it
wasn't clear if you roll the es and iqs
once an hour you have to sign them once
an hour in this in this format there's
no there's no need for repeated signing
and on the topic of being generic could
you go back to the two slides I guess
maybe the only one slide this one so you
can see on the lower example that
there's something there underscore 8 4 4
3 underscore HTTP so as defined this
this draft does admit essentially
arbitrary new protocols to be defined to
use this and the the data type that's in
the service field domain value is
essentially a completely unstructured
dick
of keys and values in a registry
controlled by Ayane and the existing
definition of the alt service field
value says that it is extensible to non
HTTP protocols subject to I Ana control
basically so you can if you're if you
write a draft that defines what all
service means for for any other protocol
for SSH or FTP then this this draft
automatically covers you the only thing
is that you do then need to need to do
the name prefixing as in the second
example here so in that sense this isn't
as HTTP specific as maybe the name
implies but certainly HTTPS is the clear
focus of the dress and I'm totally open
to to kind of the bike shed of names
that are less of a mouthful Eric or from
Google and I lead the chrome DNS team
everyone keeps asking what browsers
another clients here thinking about this
I thought it'd come give my thing at
least so we're we like the sound of this
and we are tracking it closely the one
important caveat is the current thinking
is we would only be doing this query
when we have doe mostly because a lot of
stuff in it has been mentioned is not
very helpful unless it's a secure
context as well as also it we're a
little bit worried about sending out a
third query for each requests when we
don't have a good signal that the
upstream or Chris resolver is a nice
modern one that won't crash if we start
sending extra queries to it so this does
mean that well yeah there's been talked
about sighs that maybe that's not as
much of an issue if we are only doing
this over toe it also means that if we
need to some of this information like
the zone apex issue when Chrome is not
talking Doe there's still room for other
solutions for this like a a thank you
thank you Eric
well I will so I will join the ACPs it's
it's this whip with a group session and
discuss with the chairs pretty and where
we can adopt thank you thank you
next is Steven Williams okay next step
is Steven Ferrell alright so yeah I
think we presented this draft last time
we got some feedback we implemented the
feedback in the drafts you'd like more
feedback kind of done really now yeah so
this is the summary it allows you to
kind of express a relationship between
two two names you can one of the pieces
of feedback we got last time was that
people thought yeah I mean that's
interesting but I'd like to be able to
express or this is their relationship so
it's kind of negative one and so we
added that in as part of that you're
going to possibly have a long list of
people that you don't want to be
associated with so we change the thing
to say you can either have a name or a
URL and if there's a URL then there can
be a list of names so those are the kind
of two main changes
there's the optional signature mechanism
is still there these are the kind of use
cases that I think we covered last time
so unless somebody wants to jump up I
won't stand at that really
and this is the changes which I mostly
said we had originally you know at the
first version of this we had a DCAM like
syntax which is kind of a little bit
what was like the the values for the
previous presentation at this time it's
kind of binary we scripted up the sample
generation stuff so it kind of looks
like it could work if people wanted it
to work and basically we're just still
looking for more feedback we're not
asking for it to be adopted just yes if
we get more feedback and if that's of
the nature that
this is something that might get
deployed then we're happy to kind of you
know do the changes to the thing and
bring it to the point where hopefully we
could ask for adoption and I think here
would be the right place to ask for
adoption if any per and previously it's
been on the D Bound list because one of
the apps ATS thought that was a good
place to start discussion we can move it
to the DNS op list if you prefer it I
don't mind us and that's all I had Jeff
hi Jeff Hodges um yeah this has been a
can we've been kicking down the road for
a long time it's on the D bound list
because we did have a working group a
while back that was specifically working
on this problem but nobody had the time
to keep pushing it forward we just kept
kicking can it does need to get solved
Andrew Sullivan and I believe firmly
that this really needs to be in the DNS
this sort of information on this this
draft is pretty congruent with or we
were coming from there is a problem
statement draft out there if you search
for d bound in file names you can find
it on there's also the start of policy
authority draft which this is pretty
congruent with the this draft does not
yet cover all the intricity x' at this
point in time um it kind of glosses over
various things happy to provide feedback
down the road on it I think this is good
work it really needs to find a home and
it needs to get solved great thanks yeah
I mean just sign your comment about
intricacies my hope but I don't know
it's realistic enough is enough
get mired in all the intricacies in this
draft and just do the mechanism bit but
that's what I meant
yes is there some mechanism things that
aren't mentioned yet in in terms of the
default at this point in time the
default is assumed of everything relying
on the DNS for the most part
that policy applies to subdomains
and that's not explicitly mentioned yes
and you need we you need to be able to
say at some node in the tree that no I
do not belong to the policy domain above
me awesome so yeah man and also the
current draft has it's optional for one
endpoint to our one node in the tree to
say I belong to this other one you can
unilaterally say that we disagree but
really we really think that you need to
say it both both nodes whether or not
they belong to each other
sure I heard that coming from a few
people and disagree with all of them and
I'm happy to keep disagreeing but if it
ever got adopted as a working good thing
then we would write the word and we need
to work our perspective is we need to we
need to do this and we need to work
through it and make it happen
yep thank you I'm closing the line of
the beret stefan-boltzmann I really
don't understand why we don't if we want
authenticity why we don't simply use DNS
SEC today's a draft creates a very
complicated authentication mechanism
copy and paste from DNS SEC which adds a
lot of Camela of style complexity so why
not just cutting everything out on
saying if you need to identify this
relationship use DNS SEC which is a
proper way to identify things
sure you could personally and again if
that's all working we wanted to do fine
boss I think there I'm still willing to
make the argument that there might be
value in cases where one part of the
relationship
those have DNS SEC and the other does
not and that's what the signature
mechanism does it is bit a bit
complicated but it's also a vast subset
of DNS SEC so DNS SEC is obviously more
complicated than what's in here but it
adds to a character it's not a small
subset it's most also complexity of the
in a sec how long is a camel
[Music]
[Laughter]
I'm not going to answer that last
question John Bradley yubico I'm gonna
largely agree with Jeff we have web
authentic and binding a bunch of
different projects I'm working on we if
we keep inventing point solutions to
address this these and the same issues
are coming up over and over again
eventually we're not going to you know
things will start falling over because
we won't be able to keep up with
manually maintaining lists and patches
and it's it is impacting web authentic
and the us relate their European domain
this is unreasonable as far as they're
concerned this is something we have to
progress progress
yeah I'm not emotionally attached to
this particular spec but we need to move
this ahead this may be a reasonable way
of doing it I'd be willing to work on it
to make sure that some of these we have
a broad selection of use cases that are
covered by whatever the final document
is great thanks Paul office in the past
I used to be fairly against this I'm not
flipping to the other side I'm more in
favor of it of doing this I do see some
problems that are not solved and I'm not
sure if you can solve them for instance
the one I see very frequently now at my
day job is people doing surveys
internally and then using a Google forum
and a shortener and and so then it's a
relationship between me and all of
Google and it sort of doesn't really
help me if everybody burns to these
super generic solution farms domains so
I'm not sure what this solution for that
as a name that can be thought of somehow
in this too to have a more specific URL
I guess because like I wanna I wanna
maybe specify some forms with like a
Google Form URL
of a just a domain name uni so that's
one part and I also agree with if you
use DNS SEC as the trust model has some
advantages one all people that keep
confusing Transport Security with with
authenticity of data I get another slap
on the wrist of doing it properly and
and the other part is if the power bind
draft moves forward then that is
actually your signal of saying I am
independent of my parent and so you
would solve that problem there Victor hi
this is Marie honorary co-chair I talked
about this the last time when you
brought it up and the Demark working
group is also doing we're interested in
something like this all right we
currently solved the problem with the
public suffix list for better or worse
and we've now we're just working group
last called a document that is sort of a
patch to that model that attempts to
bring in slightly more use cases that
are covered by that but not quite and
I'm worried that we're gonna continue on
this path of kind of like one more one
more one more
warts rather than a more general
solution so I'd love to collaborate with
maybe can this do something that
replaces that entire suite of use cases
and and solves that problem for us once
and for all I mean a lot of people with
allergies to use in the public suffix
lists the way we're doing it and so on
so I'm excited about this I want to see
it move ahead and if you need a home for
it that isn't here we'll take it or
something like that but yes this is this
is good stuff and if it simplifies our
lives then we'll be happy to move
towards that we even said in the Demark
document as soon as something better
than the PSL comes out jump to that so
if this is that then we want it okay
great
thank you Thanks so did I guess the only
question for now is do you want to move
the discussion to the DNS up list or
okay and please send feedback to the
mailing list and I think the chairs
about call for a dozen I think from the
room there's a lot of interest and
people want to work on the document but
yeah
thank you if it's a side mark for the
power bytes it's correct the draft from
what I understand there was some
interest in the draft but not on the
mailing list not expressed in the Menem
itself as people have an interest in the
draft these also expressed their
interest on the mailing list because
it's now being discussed on the
coordinate on the hallway please correct
me follow if not Breck so if people have
interesting power bite please express
their interest etc on the mailings it's
important for us okay thank you
next yeah oh oh sorry woody sorry I
thought you're such a familiar face
sorry yeah hi so I'm here to talk about
the DNS resolver information draft I
just noticed that the link there is for
one of the instantiations of the data
types not be resolved our information
draft so we'll fix it later
yeah
so the main thing is we are looking for
working group adoption and the reason
this draft exists is that primarily the
primary use cases it's originated with
was for doe but there was some feedback
that this should be generalized so it
could be used for other pieces of
information and so that resolvers can
publish more information about
themselves and the doe information will
move to a separate draft so this draft
proposes using I Jason to represent the
information it's presented in a
extensible form using name value pairs
and the client is can query for specific
names or a well-defined name called
inventory which gives you a list of all
available information on that resolver
so there are two endpoints specified for
creating this one over DNS which uses
the in a draw ARPA IP address of the
resolver itself and the reason for doing
that is it may allow for using DNS SEC
for validating the answers and the other
one is using HTTP originally we
considered using a special used domain
name but that was dropped in favor of T
in a draw ARPA DNS name so here's the
thing this one we are mentioning that
you can implement this over DNS or HTTPS
and the client could also decide to
query this information over DNS or over
HTTP which leads to an interesting
interoperability question which is if
the server and the client implement only
one of them and they are not the same
then they can't figure the information
out so that's something we are looking
for feedback here okay that's it a
questions feedback
then Schwartz so I I think I support
adoption I would like to solve this use
case I appreciate the work here I have
some personal differences of artistic
differences with with the engineering
choices here I really liked the special
use domain name formulation that you
have originally had much better than the
than the reverse IP address formulation
because I think a very large fraction of
users are behind DNS forwarders with the
result that the the true recursive
resolver in play has an IP address that
is not known to the client so for
example if ISPs wanted to use this
service to to offer improve transports
to their customers I think for
residential ISPs that would largely not
work because most customer equipment
most most stub resolver --zz are behind
DNS forwarder in their in their Wi-Fi
router if the Wi-Fi router actually just
passes the true IP it forwards the IP
address of the of the ISP resolver then
it will work but I'd like to cover that
use case I also think that the dot
well-known solution is is not necessary
thing it might simplify things agree
just pick the DNS thank you yeah it's
pretty brief so you can kind of reply to
that power just we just entrace had a
discussion about pcp 190 and using
well-known and we got pretty much shut
down it and you cannot get an exception
to that so not using without well-known
will be a hard problem you will first
have to convince the arc area to a piece
of you 190 needs updating right so I
think if the working group adopts this
we're gonna have all of these questions
we don't need to do them now and and yes
we need to if we'd go with dot well
known we're gonna have to like get
pre-approvals and stuff so yeah well
gentle request if you like you can
express it would be working group or it
will be adopted
it's recorded enough to get some sense
from the rumor from the cupboard
I don't like keep the strategic remarks
for later when we will have content to
put here but first from a technical
point of view getting information about
the network you connect to seems to me
very close from what are doing the
captive portal working group on also the
entire provisional provisioning demands
thing that is done I believe in the
internet area so is it isn't it simply a
very special case of provisioning
demands and should we instead rely on
the provisioning demands draft which is
I think near to completion so the answer
that one of the initial use cases could
be done in DHC as you were saying
although there's when that was asked
earlier in the dough working group there
was very little interest in that people
said no we don't care but in addition
this allows you to get other information
about a resolver it's not just for
getting finding out about dough so a
resolver might want to tell you other
things about itself such as I prefer
that you connect to me to me over TCP
things like that
so that is really a you know this can be
used by resolvers saying to stub
resolver recursive resolver saying stub
resolvers please do this with me i am
able to do this so it really isn't a
provisioning thing as much because
remember not all not all resolvers are
provisioned through DHCP people choose
other ones in other ways it seems to me
very see a very similar problem so maybe
it will be a good idea to add in the
draft why bother learning domains is not
a solution
ok that sounds good and I hadn't even
thought of looking at cap for I will
Jimmy I just think this is an
interesting piece of what attempts to
solve or your problem and I think the
one who should adopt as a document
West heard Icarus I so I shortly before
the IHF I was actually gonna write
something very similar so I guess I
support this in concept I was gonna do
it in a completely different way so the
way I was gonna do it was actually to
create a single name that would give you
a list of other records you could go
look up such like we already have some
that a resolver based like you know what
do you know ski do you support and
things like that
the so one note on that that who needs
taped over is new name value pair if
this goes through with the current set
up new name value pairs can be defined
just by expert review and specification
required mean just an internet draft so
it's very lightweight for adding in some
of those yes with the caveat that I was
about to get to so thank you perfect
architectural II we're doing strange
things with the text encoding values in
DNS we now have records that are
encoding in a number of different
encoding you know mechanisms like SPF
you know as semi colon separated kind of
stuff this is now doing a JSON and every
time we we fracture that you know we are
limiting or or the number of things that
can read it or mandating that you know
everything that needs to be able to read
everything go off and include the
appropriate parser and I don't know
positively that we want to do that with
respect to it would be easy to add stuff
you're also building on gigantic record
sizes and things like that which is why
I was sort of you know thinking about an
index based approach you know doing it
instead so you know again I think I
support the concept in general I'm not
sure I support the implementation I
think that the DNS up working group
audit solve this problem case and we
should get to what's the right mechanism
so so support not necessarily the
drafted I support the moving forward of
it and we're totally open to like for
example if people don't like hi Jason
and they want to go back to you know
like you were saying semicolons in
between such sure that's fine well and
Jason makes perfect sense for the HTTP
pool because he already know that that
that mechanism probably has it
but as you say this would add another
parser for some people maybe that's too
much maybe we don't want to do it that
way we can do in some other format
that's fine on the top of Ben Schwartz
on the topic of provisioning
provisioning makes sense when you're
speaking about local information about
the network I view this personally as
non-local at least my use cases as I
mentioned before are essentially
non-local and in fact architectural II
what I would really like although I
don't know if it's possible is a DNS
trace route that tells me but can we cut
the might line before you so as we
consider adoption I think we should also
think about what design spaces open what
are we actually considering yeah
and this might add into that trace Ruby
a thing if certain resolvers want to say
that and want to say where they're doing
upstream no limitation on that
regardless of the format that we come up
with so great so you folks will figure
out about working with adoption calls
yes yeah yeah no indeed so I think
concluding there's interest but there's
I think we do need some additional
discussion in the mailing list and then
maybe on the mailing list or maybe idea
okay okay okay thank you yeah thanks
thanks
so next speak rubbish giovanna yes
um yeah good morning everybody
so today we're I'm here presenting this
draft version for well it's strange
[Music]
alright so just this is just a draft
history it was first presented after 104
and Claude just a commander Peter the
slides here and today diversion for we
incorporated a lot of changes based on
the feedback we had on Oh for all this
changes our openness issues we're open
si shoes on github II want to cover that
and today we'll be covering most the
most important ones only and before I
even dive here to start to cover them I
would like to thank again everybody on
the 104 for the feedback I think it was
a little defensive that's probably my
the way I'm used to academic conferences
but when he went home and watching the
video was like these guys are right so
thanks for the feedback was really nice
um so changes for a no for and we had a
discussion on the title the word
recommendation that's very strong for
the ATF so we replace every instance of
recommendations to considerations women
point that point on and he was concerned
that we could reduce the setups Richard
JT because if they everyone would follow
that recommendation and in also real
considerations the word you use in many
of other several others DNS or Isis and
a note to self here it's like a ATF
recommendations different from a paper
recommendation in a paper recommendation
it's more or less like a IETF
consideration other issue draft talks
mostly about anycast but not exclusively
enjoyably pointed at except for the CTR
considerations are other ones are
related to any case and he is right but
the thing is like this is a tax we put
there our fix is based pretty much
saying yeah that could be the case can
you work for other applications but we
have only done for DNS this academic
study so we cannot actually claim that
it would work for the others but could
Wells might as well were
TTL consideration controversy like Peter
call
he pointed how complex the issue was
before DNS off like 15 years ago people
try to figure that out there was a very
complex problem and he also said like
tht I was mostly first on Montana's not
ops but there you know there's some
operators that also zone maintainer
still this typically there's child and
parent detail as well so it's important
for issue and to fix that we actually
rewrote the entire section and because
we had a new study the cover and
specifically the considerations of TTL
we just I presented last Sunday here on
ia PG and has just been accepted on the
next forthcoming IMC conference this is
a here in this URL you have actually the
submitted version a revised version will
follow up after that so pretty much we
wrote the whole thing and now we kind of
up we don't you don't say like hey you
should use a detail of one day or one
hour we just like measure care a lot of
scenarios and situations and you show
where the consequences and the
implications of the choices because
before people wouldn't you know people
just copy and paste details and let it
run in that way but now we can actually
make any form choice and how to choose
that and regards performance with
regards caching and we've got a bunch of
stuff so I recommend it you have a look
in that paper select issue 15 first
selection could be a more diverse we had
trade different papers on to the
references of this draft which you are
not co-author by us we also had this
piece of tax here to just say hey this
document actually covers it's based on
research papers and recommend folks to
read the related work section of those
papers because they they have a specific
they address that specifically so that's
what we have done
I think George Marcus when he pointed at
like Atlas it's typically biased towards
Europe for one of our considerations
that was like a c3 and he's right but I
did include and we have include that on
version oh three of the trap that
actually the consideration about any
case and this paper the folks the altar
is what they did
did not do it only analysis for the all
the awry pathos probes altogether they
actually break that down into countries
and regions so the consequences of that
is it's this text that we put there it's
a given that well Atlas has a little bit
more bias towards here but the analysis
per country per region does not change
the conclusion that locations of any
caste instances dominates latency and
just to remind us also peer review and I
think that's the most important issues
we have changed there's many more but
they're on github and I just cover the
basic ones here thanks I'm not I cannot
say that I know much positive and all
that I'm sure I would be so there are
two things that was the the wordy
document to be adopted daemon also
pointed out and that has been solved the
other thing is of course to the working
group
listen it's interesting to see that
research can be well finds its way to
operational practices or considerations
there's a group of people here in their
working group they think it's very
interesting and very good to have and
but that's more the biggest discussion
about the wordy so and for the draft
future it's also of course up to the
group what I think it's a useful
document yeah and please please speak up
here in the room or on the mailing list
also operators you also discussed things
with any card operators yeah so some of
these considerations have been there boy
by us like dining our by the earth by
odors as well we have talked about that
yeah yeah yep alright so in the room how
many folks have read it I have the
impression a bunch of people around this
document okay just as a quick home to
get where we are as far as the future
this document because because there have
been a couple of versions here if you
think it makes sense for the working
group to consider this as it adds a
working group draft these home now if
you oppose it as a working group draft
please home now okay so I guess the only
thing we can say from that is um we were
asking room for more review and you to
continue to take the feedback up
chirping thank oh yeah Matt Poinsett
I've a sort of a comment on the adoption
question
since this is a review essentially a
review of academic papers I don't really
see what the working group is going to
do to improve it it's it's an analysis
of research that's out there and I and
so I don't really see what what the
contribution of the working group would
be to improving it um it really feels
like an independent submission to me
thank you
Thanks
okay next speaker put you myself
good morning I'm column J PRS you talk
about avoid augmentation in DNA's
posterity discover is vulnerable
details are presented in my presentation
at rock sathi and this IEP meeting and
energy is said to be the biggest user by
IP fragmentation because Eden's arrow
under dynastic with widely deployed
research papers described effective
cache poisoning attacks using IP
fragmentation on the passivity discovery
fragmentation cost the poisonous 2013 IP
hunter shot attack on DNS 2030 domain
validation prosperous for MDM reagent
PKI 2000 2018 auditor toe we cannot
trust to fragment the UDP packets and
passivity discovery then we can avoid
raj UDP responses it is hot ETS arrow
has requested EDP paid all the sites
field it can choose smaller bodies more
than passivity you and I she should see
891 section six point two point one says
that note that facility with the wizard
fragmentation could be smaller than this
and truncation works well when responses
exceed specify the median suicides some
of the written truncated responses and
currently try by TCP and TCP is
considered resilient against IP
fragmentation attacks are she 77 1666
states that or general-purpose DNS
implementations masks support both UDP
and TCP then I'd like to propose new
recommendations new services or about
the shooter set to ETS arrow requested
EVP pelo sides to 2120 defined in DNS
take Archie 40:35 as minimum pay Rosa
sides and also observers Andrews
observers should set each net zero
spawned responded maximum payroll side
to 320 same body and more also it is
harbors may send DNS responses it's IP
don't hug IP version 6 don't allow
options and Hulu service is all about
may drop fragmented EVP responses there
I will hood on Dennis before I P
reassembly it is a countermeasure
against the unit's just poisoning
attacks using IP fragmentation and last
night for a week she advised me that the
constant 320 is not good calculate from
passivity or incremental value it is
wrong idea and we need a special
consideration in small mutant network
when DNS servers are located across the
increased empty body less than 280
choose the EDS requesters and responders
maximum payload sizes fit to the
smallest ring como tu barrio
otherwise the response may be dropped
and the small empty body - IP version 4
version 6 head aside and UDP he decides
it's possible in a genericized or maybe
another recommendation nina sabado
should be located on networks higher mu
tu barrio
to the major part to the major part of
the Internet is Raja
or equal to 1280 and deployment the
proposed method supports incremental
deployment when observer increments the
proposal the horses who services rubra
becomes to avoid IP fragmentation in DNS
and when an authoritative server
implements the proposal the authorative
Sabha becomes to avoid IP fragmentation
in DNS other proposal case basic OTC
with shared key requires both requesters
and respondents support not implemented
under I hope I have concern about to
drop in fragments not written in draft
drop fragment derocker elementary
responses and DNS responses I peed on
trot version 6 don't shrug options may
cause Deena's communication error
timeout and to recover - situation guru
services Israel who services world needs
to retry by TCP transport it increases
compare complexity of service robots new
robots and how do you consider do you
support this recommendation or do you
like fragmentation that's all
though largely month on that note i
think i ieave your writing what you say
the the technical content in there is
quite okay so my comment is just along
the lines of again as the last last
draft how to how to put this to the
end-users and the people who deploy this
recommendations is a strong word
considerations might be a better word
please have a look at at how that is
presented and and I would like the
working group to make a choice here how
to present that if it's adopted to the
working group be careful about how you
present this to the people who read it
that's my only comment hi
Puneet from Google Public DNS so we are
in favor of fixing the fragment UDP
fragmentation issue so in principle we
support this I think figuring out the
MTU and some of the deployment
considerations that can be figured out
on the working group mailing list
arithmetic on Akamai have you been in
coordination with the TMT SV working
groups working on APL PMT UD Trafford
ideograms it's addressing is trying to
dress in similar things it may make
sense to collaborate with them to figure
out are there some ways to make this
complimentary because there may also be
some ways to not have to set it on set
for the low MTU and all in all cases but
only in certain cases thank you
currently no but I need but there's
projects is ethnic among the pragmatic
Westside so yeah I do support the
document and as software developers we
intend to drop the maximum n2e dns
buffer size so effectively implementing
what you are recommending so yes go
ahead please Brian Dixon GoDaddy but
previously it a little bit of follow-on
research to the original fragmentation
poison draft it's much much worse than
that draft or that dark paper was if
anybody is really interested I can go
into more deep
he'll at some later point I'm definitely
in favor that definitely want to
recommend that the developers of
resolvers changed the default on their a
dns buffer size to get it down to a
reasonable level thanks Mike Andrews I
see you mentioned T seek I've also got a
draft chose submitted using a woman
teasing key which effectively allows the
DNS level to detect any fragmentation
reassembly a successful at the IP level
fragmentation reassembly attack and
reject such a response looking at the
Alexa top 1 million and looks like three
quarters of servers there could deploy a
woman-owned key today with just a
configuration update that's they all
that's about level of T that's level
where they that's the level of TC
deployment in that set of servers so I
think there are ways around this without
getting rid of fragmentation I realized
people don't people don't sometimes
don't feel like they need to solve the
pregnant ation problem but you end up
with other issues going to TCP to
just want the wing group to look a both
together please thank you mark from the
mic line I do here in support I was also
asked want to ask the working group to
look at the draft of supply and Britain
but mark and I think please give some
reply some comments feedback on the
mailing list and we will discuss it with
the chair and the author about a call
for adoption later on the mailing list
yep thank you there we go next present
that presenter John Woodward on the bill
I am morning John Woodworth here to talk
about the bulk of our again we've made a
few changes I've gotten a lot of good
feedback from the last the last time I
presented so those of you who are not
familiar with it it is basically a
compact or condensed representation that
can expand similar to a dollar generate
at a meta level and it can also be
transferred between primaries and
secondaries in a condensed form so a
single record could expand into millions
of Records
it offers standardizations around some
of the implementations that are already
being done certain vendors have similar
features and technology this would just
offer a standard way to exchange those
records between the multiple vendors
and I've also in the field I've seen
record or zone files that have expanded
well above 50 even above 150 megabytes
which don't really transfer well if they
do a lot of timeouts a lot of errors
sometimes they'll have to be manually
transfer etc or broken into smaller zone
files the new draft what I've done is
I've broken it into two drafts we had
NPN which helps with the some of the
offline signing capabilities in a
pattern generated record way we also
have a couple I P v6 examples with the
new the new formatting yes and I've
broken up the NPN into a second draft
thank you and we are still trying to get
this adopted by the working group so any
questions comments
Jeff Houston peteus on it how do you
sign it you either would use the NPN
which would modify the signature and the
validation mechanism there's another
record or you would do online signing
other comments please go after Warren so
Warren Kumari Google I mean I've got a
bunch of v6 base it sure would be nice
to go to provide reverse DNS for it
there's no other way I can see to do
that like realistically
so right thank you
all our yes I read this draft I like it
I don't like the name of the record tag
balk I think it should be renamed or
something like that and the draft could
also use some more examples off at the
input and the outputs to the expressions
you have there a little bit convoluted
that some of us are afraid of regular
expressions thank you
yeah I'm open I think all the authors
are open to renaming it as well and all
the life signing is not the problem jobs
thank you thank you yeah we would like
to see a little bit more discussion also
on the mailing list before we go see I
think thank you very much so permitting
time we had presentation by whittles
so and we have time well thank you all
there we go okay so this should be a
short one
hi I'm Vito from I see the idea is DNS
resource record for transferring covert
information from primary to secondary
and don't ask me about the covert we've
had this discussion about how to name it
so the idea is to transfer something
that should not be queried for in
bandwidth the zone the idea is for it to
be generic so that we can
spend it with another our types without
changing the behavior of the server and
the examples include note RR which we
have a draft for this Evan is here as an
author DHCP time out from Tim for
example an SEC five keys when if an SEC
five is adopted and even zone signing
keys for inline sign Inc on the
secondary although that's that's just an
example so don't be scared because
that's the most of the discussion on the
list was about examples and that's just
an example it's a generic for anything
the big I think the biggest issue was
that was on the list
and in other discussions was about
encryption and the security of transfer
because we are putting something that
should be hidden and then we we don't
encrypt it we don't mandate encryption
so for example forensic five the
encryption is not either because if you
have the zone then the an SEC five key
is not needed for it is not necessary
for you it has no value but for zone
signing key it's required so the
question becomes should we mandate a
form of security or a specific form of
security like etc over TLS which will be
discussed I believe tomorrow on on
deprive drive deep I fast so that's
those are the questions for the draft
and the details
well we there is a range in our type
numbers that's currently reserved we
want to cut a piece of it for for this
kind of Records the question also
becomes should there be a private wrench
for this kind of Records cut from also
from the reserved archives there is a
mechanism that this allows transfer to
secondaries if they don't understand the
covert semantics so if there is a second
secondary that does not understand
covert records it won't send the idns
option
that I understand covert records and it
won't receive the transfer at all so
that it won't serve it also the server
must not serve covered records without
an explicit ACL allowing it that's for
example for a note because a note is a
record that someone an operator might
want to ask for but it requires an ACL
the other thing that's in not in current
version of the draft because I thought
about it on Sunday is that we should not
we should for generic types generic
binary types we should change name so
that the zone would not load if it has
covert records on a server that does not
understand covert and there is an usage
we published those two drafts in
simultaneously there is a note or our
definition which is basically a comment
in zone that can be transferred with the
zone because 1034 has own comments but
axfr came a bit later and those comments
are not transferred with the zone and
sometimes it might be useful for
operators so for example mark that this
IP was given to this person and these
you know it's just a comment but it it
stays on on the secondary so yeah that's
it and comments feedback it's useful but
if HX is ethnic it smells like database
and I SES on top of it and I have a bad
feeling that eventually someone will
come and ask hey I want to have only
this group of users allowed to query for
this type and that group of users
allowed to create that other type and
stuff like that and then you will have
to invent mechanism how to transfer the
ACLs and so on and so on so I think it's
kind of worms and it don't belong to DNS
please don't
I Steve I guess I'd also
wonder how to think through the cases if
you're transferring is LSK over TLS that
depends on PA i'll it depends on DNS
things might go wrong there somewhere
right like I said that's that's just an
example and now I well I didn't want it
to put examples in the draft I put and
now you know that's what's happening
Jerry mandersohn
from a principle point of view just
because you can doesn't mean you should
so all of this is orchestration
mechanisms and orchestration information
I wouldn't want to see that in DNS or
enquiry Google but no hats so the
special range thing and taking like a
bunch and setting aside that feels kinda
icky to me all right I'm not speaking
about the rest of it just a you know
gonna take it well the idea was you know
if you want to put if you want to have
something that's covert and with each
draft you would have to specify that
this should not be queried for so the
idea is to have a range in which you can
put specific resource records like note
like DHCP timeout like anything else
that you know servers with would
understand that they should not allow
queries for me to take you could have a
type for covert and then stuff under
that but that's subtyping yeah that's
not allowed the comment that this sort
of thing doesn't belong on the DNS and I
just wanted to say that this sort of
thing already is in the DNS quite often
it's just not in the DNS in a way that
is resistant to open normal queries from
just everybody and I have heard a number
of people who are operators request a
way of putting something in the DNS that
will automatically be replicated to
secondaries that isn't easily queryable
and there is already data that is used
in DNS that is not easily queryable you
can't look up in SEC 3 record you
receive it if you look up something that
doesn't exist but you can't specifically
query for it policy zones are often
often have queries disallowed that's
just metadata for the operation of the
server but it can still be transferred
over a channel from a primary to a
secondary what this is is a mechanism of
having in-band data in the DNS that
resists ordinary queries and I think it
could be useful in a number of use cases
and some of those use cases have already
been done in a less convenient and less
secure way but there's projects easily I
think that evan has a point basically
this is inventing tens zone transfer
protocol which is intentionally
incompatible video all one using the
ideon assumption to prevent the old
slaves from getting the data right so I
think it's opportunity to invent much
better than through protocol which
allows like more flexibility and don't
necessarily stops all the non DNS data
in its own file right I mean this is the
perfect opportunity to do that I think
and do news on transfer protocols
because the old one is quite horrible so
Wes heard of here is a we have
traditionally so to two points I guess
one DNS is not designed to be a a entity
to entity type mechanism so we have
transfer abilities and things like that
who we expect caching we expect things
to be transferred beyond that we have
signatures that exist over portions of
it we have a draft that you know it's
signing the whole thing so you end up in
these cases where if you have partial
zones where some entities have part of
the zone and some entities have all of
the zone you'll end up will in this case
all entities that have the zone have the
zone if the covert records are not
allowed to be transferred then that's
not going to be the case then they won't
have the zone so right they won't have
the whole zone which means they can't
validate records that have no they they
won't have the zone if if there is a
covert
cortisone cannot be transferred to a
secondary that does not support covert
right so here you're prohibiting
transfers yes okay so second point is
that in a security context we almost
always insist on private information to
be transferred out of band not in the
original protocol so it's unclear to me
what the why it is needed to be in band
in DNS protocol as opposed to a
supplemental bit of information like how
we currently transfer security related
information okay Jim reads I'm sorry to
say I think this is a very bad idea
well first of all it smells what
security by obscurity and then we create
some kind of special secret sauce from
special resource record tapes have got a
special significant meaning and that
will then determine the behavior of the
server and how it then response to
queries I think that's a very bad idea
and a start of a very very slippery
slope if we're going to set aside a verb
types and see these are special
significance and the kumbhak build by
certain clients or sell and serve those
under certain circumstances I think
that's a very very bad thing to do I
think it will keep very many difficult
and proper able operability and
operational problems if the stuff
escapes into the wild now yes the maybe
I need for some candies can afford cost
not as much as covert information but as
I find information like that that make
my better description over here but if
that information is sensitive don't put
in the DNS the DNS is public partly
month at node west beat me to it
I agree that I think this this type of
information doesn't belong in the zone I
I can see a need to transfer such
information between two two servers but
I think to do it in zone is probably not
the best approach
I'm listening to the comments here I
think that having some kind of parallel
transferring structure may be in invent
a new transfer type instead of normal
sometimes grow incremental song traffic
that that transfers parallel information
or we already have the the NSC control
protocol which is another method of
transferring data but I don't see it
really it doesn't feel right to have it
inside so Brian Hamer memory are relying
a question from jabber could this be
done with catalogs ohms instead well
catalogs owns convey information about a
zone as a whole and in this case we can
for example for notes record we can have
a record in the zone guess what
we can have a record in the zone so for
example mac-10 dot is C dot org and the
note stating that mac-10 I see that org
is Evans computer which catalog zones
are a concept well it's it would be
possible to for example transfer zone
signing keys with catalog zones because
those are those are values that are
attached to a zone but in this case we
want to have something that's in the
same key our key as the zone so if we
can have a record in the zone and a note
for this and a note for this specific
record so yeah in this case for example
for note R or DHCP timeout R
it's not possible to do it with catalog
zones Paul Hoffman um just since I'm
busily typing the minutes I think that
Peter said something that many people
agreed with afterwards but didn't say
they agreed with which is this is an
opportunity to create a new zone
transfer program if people don't like
doing it this way which is seem like a
bunch of people didn't but they agree
that there is a use case and might even
have extra use cases which it seemed
like a bunch of people did a different
zone transfer program it could be
parallel that only does not so we don't
we aren't wedded to axfr and IX FR
forever if we can come up with a better
way to do it and i think i've seen
better ways to do this written on
eight boards for the last ten or fifteen
years so maybe this is the opportunity
to do that at which point in that new
transfer it's not just zone transfer
zone information transfer or you know
zone configuration transfer as well
could include this okay thank you thank
you thank you for all your contributions
and comments on the microphone any
closing remarks well please fill in the
blue sheet thank you all and see you
back in Singapore thank you thanks for
the the note-taker all and described
right so please fill in the blue sheets
yeah I could be five minutes