we don't
[Music]
please take your seats
Lorenzo Canasta close the door please
Thanks
all right good afternoon everyone
hello and welcome to DNS service
discovery this is Barbara stark and I'm
David's Knaus II and we are about to
start talking about TN SSD before we
begin we do not have a minute taker yet
could someone volunteer thank you
we set up the meet echo of the SIV
etherpad with the agenda and if anyone
else wants to jump in and help in on
that please please feel free I'll be
supporting there on etherpad so you're
not alone and the blue sheets are going
around please make sure you sign them so
it is Thursday afternoon hopefully
you've seen the note well bye now
this meeting is covered by the IETF note
well if you have not read it yet please
do so it covers things such as patents
and what your responsibilities are in
the ITF and also very importantly the
code of conduct with which this meeting
is going to run so usual reminders
anytime you talk at the mic please state
your name clearly for the minute taker
and please review the documents that
happen this working group that way your
documents will also get reviewed and
signed boo cheats so here are some links
for people following online did I get it
wrong every time I saw your email this
is so more useful links for people still
following online yeah quick usual shout
out we have a github organization for
the working group and anyone working on
a draft
in the working group or that wants to be
in the working group is welcome to set
it up there just talk to us and we can
make it happen our goals for today we're
gonna have an update on our currently
active documents both in terms of
standardization and actual running code
and then we're going to talk about discs
about service registration and discovery
relay and we're gonna have fill up the
rest of the lot of time with the future
of this working group and the privacy
efforts and what we want to go so that's
the agenda is currently stated would
anyone like to bash the agenda all right
Stuart please stand on the pink X
otherwise the Acme anvil will miss you
this is an update on our push
notifications document we discussed this
at the last IETF meeting we're on
version 19 we had working group last
call to review that that went smoothly
David requested publication when I
actually review last call we got some
feedback we made some updates and that's
what I'm gonna give a quick overview of
right there push escape
yeah there's not a media program is
cheap okay so this is the timeline I
don't need to read it out you can all
read here's the summary of what's new we
realized that the whole document focuses
on the mechanisms of push notification
which is fine what it neglected to
mention is the reality that any client
using this if push notification is not
supported is going to fall back to using
the regular DNS query to get the same
answer that's kind of obvious but it
didn't say that so we added some text
that says when you do that you shouldn't
pull more frequently than once every 15
minutes and that's just to give some
guidance so that we don't end up with
ridiculous burden on servers there was
also a mismatch in the documents late in
the process the DNS stateful operation
RFC added some explicit text about when
TLS early data is permitted and when
it's not because there can be risks with
replay so you only want to use it for
idempotent operations and there is a
requirement in DSO that you state which
DSA operations were allowed in the early
data and we had not updated the push
Draft to include that required language
so we did a bit of thinking and we
figured doing the SUBSCRIBE is not
something that will cause harm if it's
duplicated and the performance benefits
of saving the roundtrip may well be
worthwhile so we put in the required
text saying we've considered the
security implications and this is fine
with TLS early data so those two are
easy the big topic was I think I hope a
storm in a teacup but it turned into a
long email thread and what happened here
was we heard
copied text from the DSO document this
is based on where in many places it says
if there's a fatal error you should
immediately abort the connection with a
TCP reset or equivalent for other
protocols and in DSO as in this document
we are we may be a victim of trying to
be too thorough in stating all of the
rare corner cases that should never
happen but if they do happen what you
should do about them Martin Thompson has
written a draft recently that Title II
something Postell was wrong or something
to that effect it's been renamed to
something less controversial he was most
he was mostly write about many things
but I happen to agree with martin
thompson on this one that being liberal
with what you accept particularly for
the first implementation of a thing
anything you're liberal about other
buggy implementations will probably
accidentally do and if you accept it
then all those bugs become entrenched
and then you have an ecosystem of lots
of buggy code I think for the first
implementation of anything you actually
have a responsibility to be strict and
reject invalid input because in effect
your implementation is the conformance
test the ITF doesn't have conformance
tests and certifications that have to be
passed to get to use the ITF logo and
your product so we have very little
enforcement's of our protocol in effect
the deployed implementations are the
conformance test because somebody coming
along to make an implementation is going
to test it with yours and if it works
they'll ship it and if it fails they'll
debug it so early in the game I think
it's really important to enforce all the
things you want to because anything you
don't enforce you don't get to enforce
later
so with that spirit in mind
in many cases the document says if you
do something completely bogus then the
other end is going to reset the
connection so if a client connects to a
server and then sends it a response that
makes no sense
tear down the connection
don't even bother with an error code
because that is something that the
programmer is going to debug by looking
at a packet trace this is not a runtime
error that occurs in the field it's just
a gross programming error and you fix
the bug so there are many cases like
that that I think a lot of specs
wouldn't even mention we were trying to
be really thorough and we put this text
in Robert sparks pointed out entirely
correctly that DSO is general and could
in principle run over any transports for
push notifications we have specified for
now only TLS over TCP running it over
something else would be a future
document to update this so Robert said
since it's only for TLS over TCP you can
remove the equivalent for other
protocols because there aren't any oh
good point
okay we'll delete that text that's easy
in the ensuing discussion
David helpfully said well if you're
using TLS you should send us close
notified instead of reset which for a
graceful close is true but here we're
talking about really fatal error
conditions that should never appear
except in the development process and
hence a long discussion went on the
mailing list and a lot of off mailing
list discussion too I just want to
confirm there yes I didn't have the full
context in that comment so as a result
of this which was quite valuable I went
back and did a pretty thorough review of
all the places in the document where it
talks about a reset and worked out what
what the context is there was some
discussion that instead of tearing down
the connection the server could use the
DSO retry delay operation to tell the
client you are grossly buggy go and
don't talk to me for half an hour there
was some debate about whether we can
expect a grossly buggy client the kind
of client that connects you and
immediately sends you a response may not
pro
the rest of the protocol as well so that
is a question that we can't answer it's
speculation about implementations that
don't exist yet that are very buggy
there was also lots of discussion about
while the client can enforce the delay
and that turns out not to be as easy as
it sounds because you can't tell to
subsists two successive connections
could be from the same clients or they
could be from different clients behind
the same NAT gateway so all with ipv6
they could be different privacy
addresses on the same device or
different devices the whole point of
privacy addresses is to obscure the
identity of the client so if the server
can tell it's the same client twice in a
sense privacy dresses aren't working so
it's hard for the server to enforce that
I also when I looked through I found
that out of the 12 cases seven of them
are the client tearing down the
connection because the server did
something bogus so clearly in the case
of the client tearing down the
connection it doesn't need to tell the
server don't call me back because
servers are not going to connect the
clients so so the end result of this is
for the seven bogus server messages
where the client just gives up on the
connection and either tries a different
server or Waits those are now back to
saying send a reset five of them are
bogus things the client does three of
those are the client sending responses
to the server which is so bizarre that
if you look in most specs if you look in
RFC 1035 there is no language about what
to do if a client connects you and then
sends your response it's just so silly
they don't mention it we do mention it
and we say if a client does that you
just give up on the client all right
sending a fin then puts the server in
close wait state while it's waiting for
the fin to be acknowledged and if
a client looping doing bad things that
can end up to being quite a resource
burden on the server which is exactly
why web servers do not send a fin
because they don't want to have their
burden of maintaining that state so so
the client sending a response is bogus
the client sending a push message is
equally bogus because that's a
notification which should go the other
way and the last one here is the only
one that I think is somewhat debatable
and that is if the client sends two
identical subscribed requests and I want
to explain the reasoning why we had the
wording like that because as I said we
don't have conformance testing in the
IETF my fear is that some developer
might get lazy they're busy they've got
a deadline and they make an
implementation that does not sit check
for duplicates and you could easily
imagine oh we'll fix that later that's
not important right that'll be a version
2 feature if we don't want that to
happen we have to have some safeguard in
place that will cause that developer to
say hang on now I can't leave this for
version 2 because my clients going to
break so that is the reason for this is
to be unforgiving about our requirements
that clients should suppress duplicates
we do not want to climb that ends up
sending a hundred identical requests to
a server because of a bug and if that
happens the server should protect itself
so that is the summary of the changes I
would welcome any feedback I would also
welcome complete silence because that
would indicate there's no disagreement
and of course we won't make any final
decisions here in the room you can also
comment on the mailing list ok
well I'm really happy that that's
uncontroversial which it should be at
this stage in the process we will go
ahead with publication of that I also
saw on David's agenda it said hackathon
implementation report I don't have a
slide for that but I can verbally tell
you Ted and Barbara and I had a
productive couple of days sitting
together working at the hackathon the
code we're working on is on the
hackathon github repository if you go to
github org slash
IETF - hackathon you'll find the MDS
responder repository there Ted and I
have been working on code we have
running code that you can run on Mac or
Linux we've also been building it for
open wrt we have these neat little GL
eye nets home gateways buy at the size
of a pack of playing cards that run open
wrt we have pre-built packages for that
so you can try it out we did demos at
the hackathon and we also went to the
hack demo happy hour on Monday and had a
table set up there showing it to people
you can try this yourself at home I'm a
firm believer in living on software
that's how you find when it doesn't work
I have now switched it using one of
these GLI net routers as my default home
gateway my Mac and my iPhone are set to
connect to that by default whenever I
come home so I'm normally on that
network without thinking about it and
that GLI net home gateway is running the
discovery proxy it is not forwarding
multicast it is in a normal
configuration it's running DHCP it's
running Knapp there's isolation between
the land port and the wine port but with
the discovery proxy all the stuff I do
on my Mac and my phone printing scanning
anything else that's using bonjour
discovery it just works
and anything that doesn't work I find it
and then we work on fixing the bugs so
in Ted I think we said that Friday
morning we're going to start plugging
things together and if anybody wants to
build a load and bring a router and plug
it together we're going to be meeting in
the code lounge at 10:00 is that what we
said
thereabouts ish and try and plug things
together so you're all welcome to help
plug my question Stuart so if I
understood what you just described that
you have plugged this device wired LAN
part into your existing home network
creating two layers of router yes okay
and on the wireless or maybe the wired
port you now can see the devices which
are on your on your original network
what is nominally labeled the WAN port
yes on the gel I net is plugged into my
existing home network great just just
wanted to clarify that you didn't I
would say well what's the utility if
you've just replaced your home router
with one of these they're it's all on
the land side so what does it mean I got
you now
thanks for the clarifying question yes
that the utility is twofold
worn for me and Ted working on this code
the utility is testing it on a daily
basis in terms of why anybody else would
do this looking forward to the broader
picture of why we're doing this work at
all one benefit I get of that compared
to how my network was is my client
devices might my laptop and my phone are
doing all their discovery with unicast
so on the Wi-Fi link where multicast is
slow and inefficient and unreliable
because it's not acknowledged and very
wasteful of shared spectrum because it
sent so slowly I'm now not flooding lots
of multicast traffic onto that Wi-Fi I'm
keeping the Wi-Fi clean doing unicast to
the Gateway and then on the Gigabit
Ethernet that can handle tons of
multicast no trouble I'm still using
legacy multicast discovery for the
devices on that Ethernet but the client
devices on Wi-Fi are not being bombarded
with lots of multicast traffic they
don't care about all right thank
hi I'm Ted lemon I've been working with
Stewart on all this fun stuff so one
thing about the plugfest on Friday is
that if you want to come with your open
wrt device you probably want to do a
build before before then because it
takes longer than two hours to do a
build
so there's code you'll there's a URL at
the end of this slide slide deck that
that points you to the repository and
you would want to download our Fork of
open wrt and build that rather than
attempting to do something more
adventurous at the plugfest and if you
have any issues with that that's my
email address and I'm happy to answer
questions so I actually have well just
on the introductory slide here briefly I
have three things to talk about various
different bits of work that we've been
working on over the course of the last
couple of years
discovery proxy discovery relay and
Service registration protocol so I'll
talk about discovery proxy first so so
the discovery proxy I assume most folks
here know what a discovery proxy is but
just to recap my discovery proxy is a
device that receives queries using DNS
on port 53 and asks questions to answer
those queries by using multicast DNS and
so this is an important goal for a
variety of use cases the case that
dragged me into it was home net and so
we've implemented a nice fully featured
en SSD discovery proxy it actually uses
mdns responder to do both dns lookups
and M DNS lookups
and then so when you send it a question
on port 53 it goes out and does whatever
it needs to do to come up with the
answer using mdns responder which is
Apple's open source DNS all-singing
all-dancing stub resolver and so we've
implemented listening on port 53 for DNS
queries listening on port 853 for DNS
push connections so it's a it's a full
working implementation of DNS push over
TLS and it also does something that I
wanted for for home net and it doesn't
accidentally like I didn't actually plan
it out this way I just plan on writing a
discovery proxy and then figuring out a
way to wedge a DNS server in alongside
it but it turns out that since F DNS
responder acts as a stub resolver for
DNS and mdns that I could just use that
for both authoritative service and
recursive service and so this basically
is a swap and replacement for for DNS
mask except that it now does proxy as
well so it's pretty sweet and you can
try it out anytime you want runs on Mac
OS it probably run on BSD but I haven't
tried it it definitely runs on Linux and
as far as things that can do queries
against it
pretty much anything out there that does
DNS service discovery can use it however
we also have implementation on various
Apple new Apple devices that will do DNS
push so you get not only do you get just
regular old service discovery but you
also notice when new things show up
immediately rather than having to wait
15 minutes for for a retry and so and
the code for that is in the open source
mdns responder distribution that's on
the the github however the support for
dns push needs a little bit more TLS
glue to work on
sort of the posix side of things that
stuff's all working on Mac OS X but it
uses the network framework on Mac OS
rather than using sockets and so that
there's a little bit of additional work
left to do there so before I go on to
the next thing does anybody have any
comments or questions about this sounds
like No okay so the next thing is
discovery really this is actually kind
of old news but I just wanted to mention
it for completeness we did a discovery
relay implementation kind of last year
and the purpose of the discovery relay
is basically to do something very much
like what DHCP relay does to provide a
really stupid thing that you don't have
to update all the time when you add
features that consider in your router or
whatever and a full service M DNS
resolver can contact it and do em DNS
through it too a link that it's not
connected to so some folks have
suggested that you could do this with a
with a layer 2 tunneling program or
protocol or something like that and
that's very true and if you have that
available to you you really don't need
this but it does seem like a useful
feature for a fair number of use cases
it'll it takes advantage of IP routing
and to end and it doesn't require any
special filtering to avoid having it
open up a bridge to services that you
don't want to bridge so so it seems like
a valuable thing it's we haven't really
talked about in the working group for a
while in any detail there does seem to
be some interest from some router
vendors I don't know how serious it is
it would be nice if we get to
publication but it really depends on
whether the working group is actually
interested in reviewing the document if
not probably try sending it through the
ISE so I'm not really inclined to ask
the group here to tell me whether they
love this thing or not because
you know you may or may not have read
it's probably makes the most sense to
just talk about this on the mailing list
but I'm bringing it up here so that so
that when you see the message on the
mailing list you'll know what the
context is so the implementation as I
said it's we did it about a year ago
it's on the hackathon github repo but
it's on an outdated branch I'm in the
process of making of modernizing it to
use the new code that I've written and
my hope is that that code will be
available for you to try out if you want
to before Singapore comments or
questions my name is Joe Cheshire I know
you said you're not asking for comments
on this but I feel I want to share my
opinion with everybody and as co-author
on this clearly I'm biased but I think
the work we've done with discovery proxy
is very viable to put in open wrt for
home gateways for the enterprise market
convincing enterprise router makers to
put this in is a much harder sell and
also probably not a good idea
because once it's in it won't be updated
until that router goes in the dumpster
ten years in the future so and for those
who don't know this was this was Ted's
idea and I co-authored document with him
but it was Ted's idea and it's kind of
inspired by the bootp relay which has
been enormously successful for
enterprise deployments of DHCP I think
this small simple focused piece of code
we have a much better chance of
evangelizing this to the enterprise
makers who who we want to reach way back
when this group was chartered that was
one of the goals was to improve
discovery and enterprise networks so I
definitely think we should push ahead
this work is basically done we just need
to adopt the draft have some people
review it last fall or as you say go the
independent route I would prefer to do
it in the working group
Tom made the comments can't you do this
with VLANs and I think we should add
some text about that in the documents if
you already have a setup where you have
VLANs configured and trunk ports and
maybe some enterprises and if you run
their DHCP by having VLAN trunk ports
instead of poopy trail agents I think a
paragraph or two discussing the pros and
cons of when you might choose one versus
the other that's a useful addition and
then I think we're ready to publish
because we have fairly good shared
documents and we have fairly well tested
code yep
so to comment on process here
this is adopted as a working group
document we had a working group last
call ready and it failed due to lack of
interest so the issue here is that
pretty much no one apart from the
authors expressed interest in this work
with I think Tom had some comments but
it was very sparse and what we're asking
us at chairs is for people to comment
like oh especially like this is aimed at
the enterprise market is there anyone
making these devices that thinks this is
useful but you don't have to commit to I
know I want to deploy this but just
saying that this is useful would go a
long way yeah that that's where we are I
personally and not as chair believe that
this is a good document but if we want
to forward it as a working group item
we'll need more people to speak in favor
of this so you can either do this now at
the microphone or on the list whichever
you prefer
Tim Rotenberg just a quick comment which
came to my mind when Stewart
taught at the mic so if this document is
intended for enterprise vendors then
those routers or whatever it's supposed
to run probably have the ability to do
violence or something like this so
actually I think we should yeah it would
be interesting to hear if there are good
use cases which are not covered by this
because so I don't have a particular
opinion about if that's a good or a bad
idea because I don't know this problem
space well enough but I think it's
something to consider if we are not
aiming for
like customer premise equipment but for
enterprise grade hardware
something like this that the question is
can it be solved there in other ways
already Michael Richardson um I'm sorry
that the working of last call was so
silent and there's issues probably the
the people that we need the enterprise
reviewers that we need are just not in
this working group but writing email to
some people that I think may care um
I don't actually think the VLAN thing is
terribly useful for organizations that
are running many campuses in many places
there in Canada today you may know that
there are significant issues getting
VLANs out to places and multicast
traffic is significantly unwanted it's
probably yes they probably have VLANs
yes they've probably filtered multicast
out that's exactly what they don't want
on their satellite links to Northwest
Territories right okay so this would be
quite attractive for a number of things
where I think service discovery is
simply not happening period and so it
may be a decade another decade before
you know enterprises that adopted enough
such that everyone says oh we actually
can do service discovery in these
distributed enterprises well that's what
we were charter to facilitate so yeah so
let let let's try to to socialize the
document a little bit more you know
outside of the I'm gonna say the home
net is she you know provenance of some
of this working group and back to that
space and perhaps we can get some more
some which working groups would you
suggest well that's an interesting
question
right so EMU might be very a good place
to reach some people because it's the
same problem of you know with 1x going
over EAP to do authentic authenticated
join of the network
okay now that you've joined you know
what would you like and that that whole
model is the same model right that you
you you you kick back we don't we don't
punt EAP messages back to the controller
with a VLAN right we do it over radius
same same same architectural things so
that that may space and maybe just we
don't as a group have those right and
enterprise people but we do have some
people that just you know we always know
this problem the ITF we don't really
have enough enterprise representation
and enterprise operators or Christina
unicorns right so so Ted are you willing
to send some additional emails out to
additional working groups to tell them
about this work or well I think so what
I would suggest is a way forward is get
to the point where I think that
everything that I need to do the
document is done which may be a very
short step I haven't actually reviewed
it in a while just you know due
diligence and then once that's done then
yeah try to get I know that there are
some folks from various places that
would probably say yes to this but we
need to actually get them get them roped
in and so yeah oh but we should we
should probably start a last call and
and then I should do the roping and
because otherwise they're gonna come and
comment and they won't be commenting on
the last call and then later on when we
do the last call because this did get
actually quite a bit of comment at one
time but so this I mean and speaking
press chair and procedurally it didn't
feel like there was a whole lot of
comments I'll go back and look at the
list but if you get people to comment
and say that they're interested in this
work it doesn't have to be in last call
we can consider those as last call or as
statements of interest interest doesn't
need to happen during last call okay
yeah young Commissar did did send us a
review about six or eight months ago I
will take another look so maybe once you
have done your next round of changes
reach out to all those folks and reach
out to us and yet we can start another
last call that's fine but if you get
people even outside of last call to send
those state
like i've interest to the list those
will be very valuable okay I think it'll
be fine to start another wgl see all
right so will will will update the
document and then send a request sounds
good thank you Thanks
yeah and I'm just gonna echo the
requests for the people here it would be
helpful to review it I just had to look
it's only 29 pages so probably no more
than an hour of reading and if people
have contacts at enterprise equipment
vendors who are not involved with this
working group which is understandable
that a lot of them they wouldn't think
they have an interest here if you can
send us those contacts we can reach out
to them individually thank you
composer Terry the reason I brought up
VLANs was because I know from experience
that people our operators have taken a
long time to troubleshoot to learn how
to troubleshoot bootp relays and this is
another thing they have to learn how to
troubleshoot and so it's not the same as
troubleshooting the gup-e relay it's a
different thing it's a different problem
but VLANs is something they do already
know how to troubleshoot and there's two
other ways I can also think of solving
this and that's by GMP proxies I'm sorry
like I do a proxy over a tunnel of a
regular tunnel and AMT automatic
multicast tunneling and but these are a
link-local multicast AMT if there's a
there's RFC on it which is a way to join
a multicast group over a unicast link to
and then when multicast islands together
and and that will work for for
link-local multicast
yes so but anyway that doesn't solve the
problem that Michael brought up about
sending multicast more it'd be more
multi guess than you want you would have
to filter if there is multicast you one
didn't want
yeah I mean it's all just packets when
it's going over the transit link anyway
but but the problem is you know you you
want to make sure that you're not
sending anything more than you need to
and also I mean honestly setting up a
TCP connection to some device over there
seems like it's a lighter weight problem
than configuring a special tunnel and
setting all of the filtering correctly
and getting you know so so you know it
may be that the right answer to this is
that we just have a document that says
how you set up the tunnel and get
filtering right but then you have a
point solution that only works on
certain kinds of devices so like the
device has to support IGMP tunneling so
there's multiple ways to solve this
problem and you pop your document should
probably compare them sure I think
that's good okay so by the way I just
wanted to point out in case there's
confusion remember that discovery relay
and discovery proxy are two different
things discovery proxy is the smart
thing that actually like does multicast
resolution on the local wire and
discovery really is the dumb thing that
just relays the packets and let's there
lets the aggregation and resolution
stuff happen on a smart server and
you're in your machine room or wherever
so all right so moving right along so
the other document that I've been
working on is the Service registration
protocol document and Tom very kindly
did a review of the SRP document a
couple months ago at this point and I
was right in the middle of hacking on
something and there were deadlines and
life got away from me and so I didn't
actually look at it for a while after
that but I've done some updates and
there are some questions that I think it
would be worth discussing so some of the
updates are really stupid things like
the document was referring to services
DARPA and it seemed like the when we
were doing the implementation I actually
I had forgotten that it was services
DARPA and so I typed service tower and
it just seemed to make more sense and so
the document actually now says service
DARPA instead of services not art but
because it's one less letter and I don't
see any real reason why it needs to be
service as DARPA but you know if anybody
objects to that please let me know
and then the document now adds support
for TLS so if you want to do SRP updates
over TLS you can and there's a
registration for DNS SRP TLS TCP dot you
know DNS name
so for SRV records so so that's already
been added to the document there are
further updates needed to the document
so I'm gonna just go over tongs comments
a bit Tom so the document was written by
me as I was doing the implementation so
of course I had a lot of state in my
head and it all made sense to me
Tom read the document he's like well
this doesn't make any sense at all and
he had a really good point which is that
I use the term update well Stuart and I
I think Stuart and I both both worked on
choosing the terminology for this
section and neither one of us really
noticed that the update language was a
little bit confusing so so I'm thinking
that we need to change the name of the
things that we're calling updates right
now we have two things that are called
updates the actual SRP update message
which is the collection of all the
things that are to be updated and also
the individual DNS update are ours and
so what I'm proposing is that we either
make sure that we always say SRP update
when we mean the whole message and we
always say our update what we mean the
RR update or we just call it an our ad
instead of an RR update I don't really
have a strong feeling about that
sometimes the problem with calling it an
ad is that it's not always an ad
sometimes there's already an RR there
and so it's really an update but I think
that's relatively harmless so it's a
word that comes to mind is register
because this is a registration protocol
yet there's nothing in there that is a
register so we could call the the whole
message an SRP registration instead of
an SRP update
I like that all right
hopefully that will show up in the
minutes otherwise I'll probably forget
but thank you that was a hint okay Tom
also found the discussion of the whole
validation section a bit confusing I
don't really have any questions about
what to do there I just didn't have time
to do it before them before the cutoff
so I will do that when I next wrap the
draft which will be soon Tom asks some
some really good security questions this
is the first one the question was you
know why are we not sending this why are
we sending this in the clear why are we
just making a TCP connection and I
hadn't even thought about it so thank
you for pointing that out and as I said
I add a TLS support to the document my
next question is should we require TLS
support should we not even offer the
option of doing it over plain TCP
anybody have an opinion about that yes
you have an opinion about it okay I
think if it goes off the land it should
be required all right but if you're
gonna do you know something on the land
like with EDP I don't think we have a
way to do that test and and you know if
we care about keeping the information I
mean the thing is this is a this is a
record that we're publishing which will
then be able to be looked up so it's not
like it's really a big huge secret so
there is an argument to be made for it's
really not that important but timber
laying for Keith Moore yes required TCP
always even on land no no think TCP or
TLS okay yeah okay all right all right
well I'd say you know from the
perspective of voting we've got a clear
vote with this would be opportunistic
security so so it doesn't need to be
signed certificate we're already
requiring it for DNS push and the
current implementation that I have for
DNS push
the current implementation that I have
or DNS push does not check the sort it
just takes advantage of the of the you
know if you have an on path attack or
the on path attacker will be able to
intercept your connection and violate
your privacy but but at least it makes
it more expensive to do that yeah we'd
have to describe how to do that I think
that that it might make sense to
describe how to do it with certificates
but if we did that I kind of like to do
it using Dane and and I'm not really
ready to write that text so that's why
that's why I'm punting but if somebody
wants to offer text you know we can talk
so Tom brought up another security issue
which I think was a really good one that
I hadn't thought about which is that we
currently are just asking for a global
anycast address so if you send a message
so oh sorry a little backstory there's
two different ways that SRP works one of
them is that we require TCP for for
fully featured SRP clients so the client
is required to connect with TCP and then
we get a three-way handshake and that
means we know that we're actually
talking to who we think we're talking to
and they're roughly where they where
they claim to be
however for IOT devices requiring the
full discovery process is kind of
painful and so I came up with a way to
on IOT networks only support this global
anycast address update and the idea
there is basically the client just
doesn't the client doesn't do any
service discovery at all it just sends
out an update and it says hi I'm
offering this service here's the
information good luck and by the way it
uses a domain of service it sent its DNS
update server to the service DARPA
domain that's that's where that comes in
so and that's like really lightweight
and I'll tell you a little bit more
about just how lightweight it is because
it's kind of awesome but the point of
that is that is that I just allocated a
global address and so now this this IOT
device is sending this update message
and if there isn't some
things sitting on path intercepting the
message to the anycast address it's
gonna go out to the internet right this
is okay it's just gonna get routed
somewhere onto the backbone and then
eventually get dropped but possibly not
before some malefactor sniffs it and
figures out that you have light switches
in your house or something and you know
we'd like to avoid that we don't want
some malefactor to be able to sniff your
your traffic and know that there are
light switches in your house and you
just told us it's gonna be TLS over a
TCP in the previous slide okay so so -
two different scenarios here one is the
all-singing all-dancing SRP update
scenario the other is the the constrain
device update scenario so I'm talking
now about the second the constrained
device update scenario and the
constrained device update scenario we're
not doing TCP or we're not doing TLS at
least in principle maybe that's the
wrong thing to do I think that you
should we you know we you and I had some
AIIMS yesterday or something about this
document and the core resource discovery
process yeah and I don't think this is a
useful feature based on what I now know
our discussion back and forth I think
that when you're saying you don't think
this is a useful feature you mean I
don't think that this is something that
it couldn't be a device a IOT device
which is sufficiently constrained that
it can't do TCP and TLS should be doing
on its own so so we have categories
weenus 72 28 you know aside because it
doesn't actually give us you know
classes to describe the devices that are
above it but essentially if you can if
you have enough energy to run Wi-Fi then
you have enough right need you to run
TCP less the use case for this is not
that you have enough energy to run Wi-Fi
right so what I'm trying to say is if
you are that class of device then I
think you can just fall into category
eight which was which is used
TCP and TLS and the normal discovery
that we do sure okay if you are not at
that level
uh-huh then there is probably there has
to be some kind of a gateway just to get
your data from right you know the
internet that we all love to the network
that you're doing yes so that device can
do resource discovery from you in a
energy efficient way and can do service
discovery proxy to the rebels so so
there isn't a way to do that okay so I'm
saying is that Gateway can be the thing
that is translating between what what I
would what this the the purpose of this
is to do Service registration protocol
from the edge device understand that it
is not to do service is not to do some
kind of mapping between core Rd and
Service registration protocol maybe I
don't understand the space of things
because I that well enough and I but but
my feeling is that that I think that the
problem that you've created with the
anycast and I we had the whole anycast
discussion I think it wandered into
six-man and all this kind of stuff yeah
and I'm and I'm actually quite upset
that we don't have a good to answer to
the problem that you just have said mmm
I think the answer is we need a ula
central address right look server that
it gets dropped correctly okay see
that's why that's right I understand
that so I think that's the right answer
you know to the problem but before we do
that I'm not actually sure this is a
problem we should solve is what I'm
trying to say or that so working group
should solve without more thinking and
and back and forth Stuart do you want to
step up to the mic yeah this is
something where I can give some more
backgrounds as many of you know Apple
has some home automation work or with
the home kit products and right now they
use Wi-Fi which is good for AC connected
products and not so good for battery
powered products I and that this right
now is a pet project of mine
I have been interested in looking at
ways that we could make home care more
battery friendly and that's why I've
been attending the thread group meetings
for those who don't know thread is
something that came out of Google Nest
it's a mesh network layered on top of
6lowpan which runs over I Triple E 880
or 15.4 which are core to make a bit
wireless technology similar speed and
range and battery consumptions of
Bluetooth but has a benefit of being
more IP friendly which is why I'm
predisposed to like that and then I've
been going through this little thought
process of if we wanted to run home care
on thread what would we need we don't
necessarily need a gateway to the
Greater Internet I could imagine a just
a self-contained thread mesh that
doesn't even connect to my home Wi-Fi
but it allows like switches to control
life via IP packets on that mesh in
order for that to be done with the
homecare protocols the light switches
have to discover the lights that they're
turning on and off and homekit doesn't
use core Rd homekit uses DNS service
discovery so this leads us to the
question if we were to build homekit
devices that are battery-powered of
running on 8215 for how would we provide
the facilities that they need and that
leads us to this work which is how would
you do dns service discovery without
resorting to just flooding multicast
everywhere and running the batteries
down right so that's a motivation for
for doing this work and essentially what
we're offering here is just here's a
lightweight way to do this thing on on a
NATO 2.15 dot for network or something
like that and you know it's it's not a
huge change to the whole protocol in
fact it's it's essentially the exact
same thing except that you're not going
out and looking up the SRV record you're
just sending it to some well-known
address so you know one option is
certainly to say no you can't do that
that would be kind of a weird thing to
say but certainly the working group
could say that another thing to say is
sure go ahead and do that but you need
to use a site scope to any anycast
address in which case we have to go out
and solve that problem which is kind of
heavy weight or we can just make it
something where it's not specified how
the what what address is used but just
generally speaking if you want to use
this this light weight mode then
whatever IOT or constraint network
you're using it on is going to need to
have a well-defined address to which
these packets are sent so you know I
don't know what to say about the whole
core ID versus DNS is do you think
that's really not it's I'm just not even
interested in core Rd so maybe I would
be at some point in the future but I'm
not right now so so I'm just interested
in solving this particular problem and
the question is whether there's you know
whether it's something we should in fact
solve personally I think it is I think
it's useful I mean whether you think
core idea is a good idea or not I think
it is useful to be able to announce the
presence of a device and register it as
a service in DNS st michael richards
again I'm not as terribly clued in to do
what thread is doing and they're very
it's very hard to know if out going to
the meetings and paying the large
amounts money if you like to bring me
I'm very happy to go to no no but I am
working with thread on enrollment things
and they do a lot of things differently
just for the hell of doing it
differently so if if I were to learn
that they actually have a service
discovery protocol you know already I
would I'm almost certain of that as the
fact so if you were to make homekit work
under threat you would either have to
convince them to run this or do
something else okay so I think it's not
entirely a particularly important
consideration the point is that whatever
I don't think it matters whether they're
running SRP or they're running something
else or core
Ardi the point I'm trying to say is that
if there's going to be if it's going to
matter to devices outside of that
network then there's a gateway that is
leading that process okay so I think
that we could have that that that
happened I think that's a I think that
would be a better I think that would be
better
having said that I'm not opposed to you
going forward okay okay I think that if
you don't want to go through the
rigmarole of trying to find as I sight
scope address mode and anycast that's
going to leak
sorry that's going to secure be secure
when it leaks right then I think you
should defer the work until we do that
okay yeah this part of it yeah having
said that I think we should do get the
site netskope any past thing worked out
but it's as you say it's going to be at
least an hour and a half conversation in
three different six-man meetings before
we can have this happen all right
yeah so so but maybe that's worthwhile
yeah so basically the the status quo now
is that we're currently using a global
address and to Tom pointed out that
that's a bad idea and I agree with him
and so I think that the the expedient
fallback and the one that probably makes
the most sense is to just consider the
use case that we actually have in mind
and think about what would work there
and the answer is a mesh local ula a
well known address within the mesh local
ula Stewart yeah Michael you have some
interesting questions so I'll briefly
answer them because we had similar
questions when I started getting
involved with this you might assume that
the threat group has a discovery
protocol defined they actually don't at
all the way thread discovery in quotes
works today with the nest thermostats
and smoke detectors is that everything
phones home to the cloud and the quote
discovery is that which devices are
owned by the same nest account in the
cloud there is no local peer to peer
discovery it's all mediated through the
Clair
so that was a disappointment because we
were hoping to find something a little
bit more fully baked with apples
different priorities the home kit is
built without a cloud service it assumes
you've got some brains in the house and
nothing has to leave the house so so
things need to discover them other peers
on the network so that is how we went
down this path which is thread has no
discovery mechanism currently defined
they need to define one to grow beyond
their current limited use cases and
naturally this is what we are advocating
so that's how work now the feedback
about the details here is incredibly
valuable I agree that any address that
might escape the house by accident
definitely is not what we want a risk
for privacy reasons so maybe for the
thread case the answer is that the
thread local network data conveys a
configured address to the clients and
they use that so for the thread case I
think we can solve this for broader use
cases this might still be an interesting
discussion to figure out how to automate
it for all link types just analysis I
think that we have the the Rd and the
the DNS st discoveries um have there's
there dissimilarities but when it comes
to the anycast address and having an R
per domain for all those site local
things I think we should sit down
together and kind of compare notes on
what we can unify and where we where we
have separate ecosystems yeah definitely
yeah so it's a separate conversation but
yeah that's definitely worth doing
alright so moving right along I think
that the conclusion that I'm drawing
from this is that I should just say that
we should use a mesh local address and
that this document that's out of scope
for this document but but generally
speaking this is what we suggest so tom
also pointed out something in Stuart I
haven't actually had a chance to talk to
you about this so I apologize for
springing it on you on a slide but here
it is anyway Tom pointed out that sleep
proxy is not entirely compatible with
what we're doing for SRP because as our
doesn't necessarily assume that the
thing we're updating is on the local
wire and he was confused by that and I
think it may mean the basically so so
SRP is a router unicast protocol the DNS
server does not have to be on the local
wire sleep proxy requires a presence on
link asleep proxy is essentially doing
the same thing as SRP and that's why SRP
and sleep proxy are in the same document
but it's not doing entirely the same
thing because we have to support the
wake-on-lan feature so we need to figure
out whether the right thing to do is
have a sleep proxy document or to make
things sufficiently clear that it
doesn't trigger Tom and which by I mean
with all due respect I'm not saying that
you shouldn't have been triggered you
should have but but we need to make sure
that it's clear enough that when you
read you're like oh okay
not what so does anybody have opinions
on which write which path we should take
on this Michael Richardson again I would
say if if if it enhances this document
it makes it more applicable it makes it
easier for developers then you should
probably keep it in the document the
iesg seems to want us to have fewer
documents so if the motivation for sleep
proxy if the sleep proxy has an
existence or motivation which could be
deployed without this document I don't
think that's true but if that was the
case then I would say okay maybe it
makes sense a separate document there if
for some reason the document was
monstrously too big and you have had the
comment about two big documents aren't
possible to review in advance then I
would say it's something to remove but I
don't think that's the case yeah I don't
think so I think it's it's maybe it
doesn't really gel with the rest of the
concept but you know it it's a-you know
I think it fits into the yeah
the thing that we really want to add so
sleep proxy already exists like if you
have any Apple products they already
have sleep proxy built into them but
what we wanted to add to that was
first-come first-serve naming and so
really if you could think of this as
just three separate use cases for the
general SRP registration update one of
them is registering to an SRP server
that's that's serving possibly a multi
subnet land one of them is register
registering your IOT device that's on a
constrained network and the third is
registering with a sleep proxy and a
sleep proxy is not an SRP server in the
same sense so so essentially I think
maybe that's a way to explain this that
is less confusing does that make sense
to you Tom okay so so in other words SRP
updates are the same for all use cases
however SRP updates to their there are
three different things you might send an
SRE an SRP registration to changing the
terminology you might send an SOP
registration to a DNS server an
authoritative DNS server to have it add
that to its database you might send it
to your your what are we calling these
things your board or router your
constraint network border router or you
might send it to your sleep proxy three
different recipients of the same type of
message that has the same essential
features and the way that they're
handled are slightly different but they
basically all have more in common than
than there that is different about Tim
did you wanna I I agree with what has
been said before so I think it would be
better to have this stuff in one
document but like clearly separated in
in their differences because yeah too
many documents don't make make make it
better
after all right yeah we did go down that
path for a while on the ITF and it was
exciting so if if the note-taker could
could explicitly note that we're gonna
have these three different
use cases for the for the awesome oh
thank you
much appreciated alright so now now that
we're done with the boring stuff so I've
done an implementation of the SRP client
that actually I have running on a thread
board as it happens and it's pretty
sweet it's the hole the hole all the
code is less than 10k including key
generation and sig zero signing it's
really simple it just adds one service
and the message that it sends to the
server is about 320 bytes so it's it's
it's it's very compact and efficient for
what it does I think and does seem to
work I think I wrote something like this
last year second year in Montreal as
well yeah you didn't I might dig it out
and people can see it but it was also
pretty pretty simple one service and
then but it used the protocol now did
yours do the 6/0 part I'm not sure I
have to look back into it and maybe that
it didn't yeah when I looked at the code
that you had it didn't have six zero but
I don't know if I was looking at the at
the final version all right yeah if you
need any help with sig zero stuff let me
know ok so so that's the client side
I've also implemented an SRP proxy yet
another proxy right so I wanted to be
able to have to receive actual SRP
registrations on port 53 and have them
update an authoritative DNS server but I
looked at doing that two by nine and it
was actually a fairly big job I think
it's doable and and I'm talking to Mark
Andrews about that but I wanted
something that was that was not
basically I wanted something generic
that could be put in front of any
authoritative server that xx accepts dns
updates and so I wrote some code that
does that and so what the code does
is it receives the the SRP registration
and then it figures out what dns updates
it has to do now the idea with an SRP
registration is that the whole thing
fits into one message because it's all
of the all of the records are pointing
at each other and there are no
prerequisites DNS update allows you to
use prerequisites to prevent data from
being added to the zone that you don't
want to add to the zone and you know and
it allows you to do a sort of it allows
you to do an atomic update of the
database where you know if these pre
records pre Rexes are true then do the
update and don't change the database in
between checking the prerequisites and
doing the update
SRP doesn't there's no way to do a
single message
SRP update with prerequisites because
there are too many different things and
and DNS update prerequisites don't allow
you to do things like if-then-else
so so what I've done instead for the so
the proxy is receiving a single message
and then first it just tries to do the
update straight and sets the
prerequisites if nothing's there do the
update and if that succeeds great we
just did it if that fails or actually
the first it does no change so it did
the the the assumption is that the
record is already there we're gonna send
an update and the prerequisites are that
the record is there and contains the
same information as before and that can
that can happen in one message if
there's nothing there then that can
happen in one message but that would be
a second message and then the third
thing that happens is neither one of
those attempts worked and that means
there's something there but it's not the
same as what's in the SRP registration
so now we have to actually go through
and iterate and so it's it's this
complicated state machine that just goes
through and does all the iterations adds
or or updates various records and if it
comes to a kata to a situation where it
realizes that there's something in the
zone that conflicts with the SRP
registration then it has to back
everything out and send a failure
response and on the other hand if it
gets all the way to the end and doesn't
have any problem then that was success
and it sends a success result
I've tested I think I've exhausted li
tested all the various different ways
that it can succeed or fail and they all
seem to work so it's pretty sweet it's
actually kind of fun to watch because
you see like one SRP update come in and
then like a bunch of events occur in the
log that was fun
future work home net integration we need
to we were talking about this on the
helmet mailing list actually h NCP
identifies links it would be nice if the
dns SD discovery proxy that was three
implementations ago if the discovery
proxy could take advantage of the
information that h NCP is sharing
packages for open wrt we already have
them but there's still some some work to
be done so that you can just install
them and it just works without you
having to fiddle around with it which
currently there's a readme file that has
a fair number of instructions in it so
that's one bit of future work that we
want to do another bit of future work is
a fully featured SRP client similar to
what Tim did except possibly we don't
know whether he did sig zero or not so
that would be really cool and it sounds
like it's gonna have to support TLS also
and I don't think that's a big come out
of work but needs to happen it would be
nice to have SRP support in some DNS
auth server and I'm thinking by nine
mark Andrews as I said has has talked to
me about some work that he's been doing
to make by nine support a wider variety
of different kinds of update strategies
and it would be kind of cool to add this
in as another update strategy mark has
indicated a willingness to to
collaborate with me to some extent on
SLO presumably I have to do most of the
work so I'm hoping that this will happen
before Singapore but I make no promises
SRP relay if we wind up having a
link-local anycast address for the
simple the IOT style SRP update you'll
be awfully nice to have a relay that
sits on the border router that's pretty
stupid and just relays it to the actual
SRP server rather than having to have an
SRP server on the border router
so that's that's my list of future work
I'm not promising that any of these
things will be done at any particular
time but they are definitely on the
agenda and if anybody's interested in
hacking on any of this stuff please let
me know and also if you're interested in
just like playing around with the stuff
that I've already got please let me know
there will be some information on the
next slide about that SRP the future of
SRP so s RP got one review during last
call thank you Tom
and the chairs were really mean and
decided that wasn't enough and so
complaint complaint so it turned out
that we talked about this in the home
net meeting on Tuesday and everybody
there seem to think this was useful and
so it seems like we really could have
gotten enough comments to make this work
look like it was like it had support but
we didn't because we didn't actually ask
HomeNet to comment on it so we're gonna
do that hopefully in another last call
so and so hopefully that'll mean that we
don't drop this and it gets published as
an RFC so my proposal is I'm gonna
update the document add in the stuff
that we've talked about we'll do another
review and try to include home that and
maybe DNS op although that could be
dangerous and hopefully that will result
in us being able to publish this so
that's all I got some good compost Terry
so there's one comment I made that you
didn't address that I think it should be
addressed in the document and check
that's it how do you delete a
registration before the least lifetime
expires and you may not want to do that
yes yeah sorry thank you I spaced out on
that and that's a really good point so
in other words we want in addition to an
SRP registration we want an SRP
registration yeah maybe I well so so DNS
SD / m DNS currently does do that right
if you have a device that that is
sending out an advertiser or has sent
out an advertisement to somebody that
it's on the network
when it when you shut it down if it's
able to send out a goodbye packet it
does and I think this is the equivalent
of that goodbye packet and I agree that
that's worth doing you know it's just an
omission so thank you for pointing that
out and then the other thing is if
there's anything that you learned
extending update I would be interesting
I think to incorporate these into a new
version of update that other
applications can benefit from and then
maybe one day this can migrate to update
through the new version of yeah I mean
if we were if we had it all to do over
again I mean I actually when I first
started working on this I was thinking
do we really want to do this in a DNS
packet I wound up doing it at a DNS
packet because it's just expedient it's
less work there's already stuff out
there that accepts dns updates and so I
was able to test it very easily and it's
all very straightforward if we really
wanted to do dns updates right we would
probably just have you know a doe thing
that does dns updates and has like a
more post
mhmmm like a post yeah well yeah I mean
sure but but but mainly that has like a
more rich prerequisites language so that
we can do a single update you know an
atomic update to the database that adds
everything at once and checks all the
prerequisites at once and so we don't
have the situation where I have to go in
add things back out you know the worst
case scenario is I add things that I
back out but something else stumbled
over something that I added in the
process and it backed out and now
everybody's unhappy we really want it to
be atomic but there isn't a way to do
that unless it's what's happening on the
server the first-come first-serve stuff
comes to mind is something that regular
update could benefit from as well yeah
yeah for sure
yeah and actually I think Marc would be
down with with adding that to by 9:00 so
anyway any other questions should we
move on to fate of the working group
thanks Ted
all right so our last agenda item which
can cover all the time we have left
which is until 3:30 so 40 minutes is
about the future of the working group so
the Tom okay so Tom brought this up on
the list so though thanks Tom that we
don't have that much feedback on some of
our latest documents and we were
wondering so kind of where do we go from
here we were considering for a while
reach our during this working group and
one of the main topics that we were
considering for the new charter was the
privacy work that said so that that is
still a possible viable path forward but
similarly there's not a it doesn't feel
like there's a huge amount of energy
going into the privacy work and so one
option which I'm not saying over and
recommending any of these but one that
has been suggested is to move that work
somewhere else and close this working
group so I wanted to hear feedback from
anyone in the working group of what are
your thoughts on this question what
should we be doing I'm looking for
feedback from all of our authors but
also from everyone else and then
community
Stuart Church again I want to echo what
David is saying from a personal
standpoint I think privacy is really
important and I think in the last year
there's been a lot more awareness of how
important privacy is and I think that's
only going to continue I thought about
these questions of how to do discovery
in a privacy preserving way a lot and I
don't know the answers so I think it's
important but I don't know how to do it
if there are other people in the working
group with good ideas and there's energy
for doing this I would love to support
that I I think it would be sad if we
wrap up the working group or just as the
whole world suddenly wakes up to the
importance of privacy that would be
unfortunate timing so I hope we can find
a way to move forward
unfortunately I've spent a lot of time
thinking about this and I have not
worked out any wonderful answer that
just solves all the problems and is also
efficient and reliable at the same time
Thank You Stuart Ted lemon so I actually
I attended a side meeting yesterday the
met up side meeting this is a group
that's been meeting sort of associated
with the IETF but hasn't really pushed
to actually form a working group here
and they are interested in this topic it
might be good to try to get some of the
people that are that are that show up
for those meetings circled in on this
whole DNS discovery privacy thing can I
ask you to elaborate on what that group
is about so they're met up what do they
call it distributed something privacy
it's very no yeah no distributor so
basically it's ad hoc privacy so
basically the same problem that we're
talking about there are other smells
related yeah really does sound related
they
working the the work that was presented
there this time was all about coming up
with and basically doing doing ad hoc
keying so so some work that that Daniel
con Gilmore has been has been doing with
a bunch of other people on coming up
with ways to do
encrypted email that doesn't suck that
has a good user experience which means
it's less secure but but it's still it's
better than nothing right so so that's
interesting and kind of not what we're
talking about there was another group
that was doing something similar with
instant messaging I think that the work
that we're doing isn't exactly the same
as the work that they're doing but it's
synergetic with it like they could take
advantage of what we're trying to do and
they would probably be interested in
what we're trying to do and they
probably know something about the
problem space and might be interested in
working on the problems that we're
working on too so that's why I say that
they would be good people to talk to I
think that even though they haven't
actually gone down the path that we've
gone down I think if we said hey what do
you think about this they'd all be like
whoo that sounds good thanks Christian
Arita mom well I've been the one trying
for some years to get privacy walk to
actually start into this walking group
and I've come to the conclusion that is
not gonna happen because I mean we have
been going for oil things now I think
that we did some a number of things that
should be somehow published and I think
I will need to find a way in particular
to publish the policy requirement
documents that we had because they is
the nicest air that could inspire other
solutions but as far as the studying of
solution I think that they would have to
come organically from the puzzle group
start doing any kind of discovery thanks
Christian
[Music]
and that makes sense to me if we were to
try to move the privacy requirements
document publication could we could I
have a show of hands on who would be
willing to read that document and
comment on it
thanks okay so I think we can try that
you're one of the authors right
Christian on that one yeah yeah given
the general level of energy on the
project I mean that's expired but
America could easily learn a new notion
to say rehydrate the draft ya know like
if you want to revive it and then email
the list for comments I think moving it
forward and publishing all of the
because that's true a lot of thought and
work has gone in this working group on
developing these requirements I think
public regardless of whether we come up
with a solution or not I think
publishing the requirements is a
reasonable thing so Thanks
so I'm Michael McCool or Intel and also
co-chair whether things working group in
33c and my interest in this is we are
trying to distribute information about
devices but want to do it in a
privacy-preserving way in fact it's one
of our requirements to get
recommendations together some that we
see but we fundamentally need a
discovery service to control
distribution of metadata and especially
in the home context most smart city
context and so this is kind of a funny
no requirement for what we want to
accomplish and we feel free consists of
adoption so the real question is where
does it work belong right so is it is it
should it be an extension of DNS there's
also work over in core on the core
resource directory right and so in my
opinion there's make two problems one is
the service by some metadata and there's
the question of how you find that
service right and in some cases I see
these things these functionalities
merged together and I really think there
should be a two separate phase with
authentication in between because really
what you do is get authenticated
information to data and so I noticed
earlier someone is saying if it's
published that everyone knows about it's
not secret anymore but actually even
like a address as a name
temperature sensor got got that local is
a leak of information about you know
what's available so I think it's
extremely important but I think you know
we need to think very hard about where
it belongs
maybe it shouldn't be in this group
because maybe it shouldn't be dns-based
we should be a new thing maybe you know
should only be the springboard for the
initial introduction to to a controlled
surface so I think I think maybe we need
to think of this as a higher level and
think really hard about where did belong
a group should be chartered to do a
privacy-preserving discovery service
that's definitely a possibility
thank you come on back so I think this
working group does valuable work and
we're not finished with this so closing
it down right now would just doesn't
make sense and my my view I think
there's we have a problem with the lack
of participation at least on the
discussion of the mailing list I mean
today I think we got got a good
discussion here on the things we bought
brought up on the agenda but that's yeah
that's I guess the problem and the
question is how can we get more people
maybe also from different angles and
doing different stuff to to notice and
also comment on the work which is done
here yeah and I guess after all so of
course not speaking for for him but I
think Tom didn't actually want it the
working group to shut down but just to
give wake-up call on that that's that
would be my guess because otherwise I
don't know if he would be sitting here
so I think yeah it's it's once again a
good call to just see if we can get
people interested in what we're doing
here
maybe they don't even know that there
would be something which would be
interesting for them which they could
give use the question I cannot answer is
how to get these people here and maybe
some more experience the ITF community
people have a better idea but I don't
know
you're agreeing here with my idiot on so
in the lack of interaction about the
privacy is kind of concerning ap to see
that five people IP to to review it so
there will be a good sign
now typically in this kind of document
you will not find the privacy people in
this room but in other rooms the
document can stay here but making some
publicity on this document in other
working group like Brian will do on
deprive in a couple of minutes is good
so it's up to you J as well to make some
publicity outside so the we we have
tried that in the past IITs starting I
think actually Montreal a year ago and
didn't get that much support from like
other people in this community or so in
the ITF community at large to come to
this working group perhaps one of the
reasons is that they care about privacy
but maybe not in this specific context
that then I'm speculating at that point
this was a minute Roy Fraser
agreed we ran Singh Michael Richardson
so I'll point out that sag is happening
right now sorry on a psychic working
group the security area where you can
group is right now where conflict with
it
okay so you know more empty chairs than
full all the people you wanted most of
them are unless they came here because
they you know I probably would have gone
there but I thought this was interesting
I was unaware I did read Christians
documents I have a vision of actually
thinking about it in my old office which
I haven't been to in two years so I mean
it was at least that long ago I was
unaware I just assumed they'd gone to
last call and gone it I was unaware that
they were stalled okay
so I would support the comment that yeah
the working group is having difficulties
and but I don't think it's time to give
up at this point
and let's get SRP published there's only
so many cycles for everybody in the
whole and the whole thing and I don't
think so we're certainly not done and I
would encourage Christian too to take up
the pen again as well and so um I think
one thing that we were probably supposed
to do probably me was to take Tom's
Charter discussions that are in the
github and start forwarding them around
to the group to look into potential
reach our during language to explicitly
support the secure the privacy efforts
here so I need to do that so tell them
an a couple things one just to reflect
back again what Pete no sorry what Mike
said Michael anyway sorry I have several
times missed the TLS working group
because it was off to the DNS SD so
again the likelihood of us actually
getting the the really deeply committed
privacy people in this room if we're
opposite any sec area meeting is zero
and so we have to have a heart if if
we're serious about doing this work and
if this is the working group to be doing
it and we have to have a hard
requirement that we have conflicts with
TLS sag deprive you know pretty much any
any working group that's doing anything
with what's related to privacy and I
absolutely agree and that's what we put
into the data tracker but at the end of
the way of the day I don't think there's
any single slot at ITF that doesn't
conflict with some security media yeah
yeah so maybe that's a good thing in a
sense so yeah so anyway the other thing
to point out is that this doesn't have
to happen at IETF meetings so one of the
things we can do and I think I might
take this as an action item is to
actually present something about this
unless one of the authors wants to at
the next how to RS c so the
like there's just a little more
visibility and people actually join the
mailing list and start discussing this
with us as far as the energy to work on
the document again what Michael was
saying is totally applicable to my
experience as well I reviewed all the
documents I sent substantial comments on
them and and then the work just just way
I stopped seeing new versions of the
document so it's not because I'm not
interested in the document and you know
I'm not saying this to blame anybody
because I've done the exact same thing
right like I've been busy working on
implementations of all of this stuff and
I haven't actually updated my documents
as frequently as might have been desired
so we I think that we have a lot of I
think we have a lot of expertise in this
room that's related to the problem space
that we're talking about it would be
ashamed to disband that expertise
expertise however I think that the clock
rate of this working group is not three
times a year and part of the reason why
it appears that there isn't energy to
work is that we're just not working that
fast it's not that we're not working
it's not that we're not making progress
it's just that we're not making progress
on a pulse rate of every four months so
I think that that that mere fact is not
a reason to disband the working group
thanks that makes sense and one of the
things we discussed actually is that we
don't necessarily have that much to talk
about every four months
so one potential option would be that
for neck one of the next ATF's either we
don't meet in person or we meet jointly
with another working group which on
Tuesday morning the HomeNet people who
did meet actually suggested that it
would be really useful if we could maybe
just do a joint session with the NSS D
and maybe have you know have a two-hour
session like we have here and have 30
minutes for HomeNet or so yeah that
sounds reasonable
stur yeah I like those suggestions I
like what I've been hearing
I think Eric right we all of us not just
the chairs need to
figure out how to publicize this I agree
with what Ted said that giving a hot RFC
torque is a great opportunity on Sunday
night to introduce people and you said
you already listed two security areas as
a conflict which is good
let's if we decide to continue for next
time let's try to stress that more with
the IHG because what I say about the
work of this working group evolving is
we have solved some of the initial
challenges of less reliance on multicast
and more reliable discovery and now
really the remaining goal we have is
this privacy work so we've almost
shifted from being a DNS working group
into a security area working group and
people outside this group have no way of
knowing that if we don't tell them sure
thanks Tom could I ask you to share your
thoughts since you sparked this
discussion on the mailing list yeah so I
think my email was in response to the
last caught working group last call of
those two documents which were you know
the main focus of the work of this
working group and having been the only
one who reviewed one of them and no one
reviewed the other I was pretty
discouraged so and it doesn't if you
think they're good then it doesn't take
a lot of work to say I think it's good
right that's all we needed but we got
nothing and so that made me think well
you know who are we doing this for and
then made me think about well initially
we had a group of people who came to us
and said they had a problem to be solved
and we solved it and we those people are
gone are they deploying this do they
have any attention to play it are they
asking their vendors to implement it so
they can deploy it and those are the
questions that I think we need to answer
and I think they're still unanswered
thank
and I guess so this from limited
experience I suspect that those are
markets that don't maybe evolve as crazy
quickly as other working groups so to
Ted's really a comment maybe giving them
time is what's needed here yeah just one
thing to say about the the adoption rate
is that if nobody is using if if there
isn't a device that can consume some of
the stuff that we've designed here then
there's no point in deploying that
functionality on your network once there
is a device that can consume that then
then suddenly it becomes more worthwhile
so the interest let's see if there's
additional uptake now that we actually
have DNS Bush in iOS and Mac OS next
generation and actually because that's a
very good point that's maybe not obvious
to everyone could someone from that
makes handheld devices comment on what's
currently supported and what's been
added recently yeah Ted actually
mentioned this on this slide but I agree
it's worth highlighting it Ted has been
working initially as a contractor and
now we've moved in hiring him full time
ted has been working at Apple
implementing this work in Mac OS and iOS
and I'm not leaking any secrets there
because this is in the public betas so
if you install iOS 13 or Mac OS
catallena then you have a fully
functioning push notification client and
it will connect to the discovery proxy
that we have running on open wrt and
it's very pleasing for me to be able to
turn services on and off and and see
them update life on my iPhone and see
that it's all working as it should one
thing I forgot to mention is when we
were off designing this protocol
like the discovery proxy that Stuart
Mosley designed the router and switch
vendors were coming up with alternate
solutions by taking listening for
broadcast arming multicast on one
network and sending them to another and
they've kind of went ahead and solved
the problem many switches and in the in
the routers and stuff in a non optimal
way but you know that those solutions
are deployed today in on campuses and so
we have to have some sort of compelling
reason for them to stop doing that and
start doing this Michael Richardson a
question
will and I think this is an
implementation issue question will I
discover devices at my home when it
connected to it over VPN okay wonderful
that is actually a really you know kind
of killer app yeah actually when I was
demoing this an apple before are all the
releasing occurred
I used that feature and it was really
awesome I did it I did a print print out
over the internet from California my
printer was at home and I had an IOT
camera pointing at it I printed to it
and the little page came out and
everybody was all excited
that's very cool I just wanted to
mention to Tom's point that yes there
are a lot of implementations of various
hacks that purport to make multicast dns
work on multiple links and our
experience with them is that frequently
they don't work at all
sometimes they tease you by working a
little bit and then failing I have never
seen one that actually works so yeah I
just want to expand a little bit on the
funny story that Ted told he did this a
demo for the guy in charge of our
department and he wouldn't think it
would make any difference because you
could have a diagram on a slide with
with boxes and arrows and things and
saying the packets go here and this
happens but there's something about the
showmanship so Ted Ted had the live
video on the screen of the key little
camera pointed at his printer at home
when he tapped their print on his phone
and we could see the piece of paper come
out and the whole room erupted in
applause it was amazing so maybe what we
need more here is Apple marketing okay
so it feels to me like there is some
pretty good consensus in the room that
there is still energy to do work and get
documents published maybe not as a crazy
fast rate but that's okay
so my sense is to keep this working
group open keep the mailing list open
and then maybe we'll have a shorter
meeting in Singapore will seem by the
time we get there how many or yeah joint
with home net that's it'll depend on
what we get on the agenda so to our
authors please don't wait to the day
before the meeting to send us your
agenda items that would be particularly
helpful in scheduling us this time for
how much time I want to have all right
then we'll wrap up anyone else have
anything they want to mention I really
don't want to prolong this is Ted again
but what I actually think is gonna wind
up on the agenda for Singapore is a
product as a presentation about how
we're using the stuff in home net so it
will actually not really be a home that
thing or a DNS is do you think that a
both think how fitting has anyone not
signed the blue sheets and so to wrap up
I think we got a sub in for we got a
good information about the two upcoming
documents the ones that are almost
published so we're gonna discuss those
more on the list and hopefully with that
renewed energy we're going to get them
published which is great and then
Christians going to revive the privacy
of
Arvin's document so hopefully we'll
actually see you on the list and not
just in Singapore and hope to see you
soon there
thanks for coming and thank you to our
note takers Michael and Christian number
two or one to put you in