[Music]
hmm hey yeah we just a good time Joe
sent just let me one this morning final
slides replace your zero is that the one
you know
hey how are you good
sorry I don't have a slide from Juan
Carlos so I'm rushing to get them yeah
it's not ready yet
okay sorry
good morning everybody welcome to HRP
seem more about five minutes late but
that's it's the first session of the day
thank you for coming and it is it is
just me today I'm Mallory notall I'm
with article 19 but my co-chair ivory
Doria is on meet echo and I think we're
all ready I'm just checking yeah I think
I remote presenters are all here we have
our slides loaded and the blue sheets
are going round so yep you'll see we
have a nice busy agenda up first we're
going to have a talk by Juan Carlos de
Martin for the first 30 minutes I'll let
him introduce himself and in his talk
and then we'll discuss two drafts that
are adopted by the research already one
is on draft Association so I believe
Johan Stefan Carter are going to be
representing on that and then draft
political will be presented and
discussed by Nielsen over remotely and
and then we have also a draft that has
been discussed in this group a few times
now on the intersection of protocols and
feminism it's not yet adopted by the
research group but we do have some
updates on that and then lastly on the
scheduled portion of the agenda we're
going to discuss the guidelines draft
which is also a research group draft
them that sort of builds on our RFC 80
to 80 and allows people to sort of
engage in valuate review IETF work from
the perspective of human rights and so
that item and that draft are coupled
with small presentations by people
who've been doing reviews in IETF to
understand how that's working out where
that draft is and any other things
related to doing those reviews and then
we
alb so if anybody has something to add
an a OB it'd be good to know sooner
rather than later so we can make sure we
have enough time for it so if you have
something that you've been dying to put
on the agenda could you let me know let
me know now it can a we are doing some
agenda review anyone okay
well we'll see at the end if you have
something that pops up okay so the note
well it is only Tuesday so maybe you
haven't seen it and the text is really
tiny so you might actually have to bring
that up on your machine if you need to
read the note well just a review of this
research group for people who have not
been here before we were chartered in
the IRT F as a research group to look at
how protocols can strengthen or be a
detriment to human rights and human
rights being very specifically defined
as a standard in fact for the by the UN
D R & D HR and the ICCPR yeah so the the
tasks that we've identified under that
Charter are to look at the relationship
between protocols and human rights but
specifically we have in our charter to
focus on freedom of expression and
freedom of assembly and as well we are
looking at the guidelines to protect the
Internet's Human Rights enabling
environment for future protocol
development so it's we were inspired by
RFC 69 73 and that is sort of what we
have now with RFC 82 80 which I will get
to as part of the history and yeah
generally speaking to to talk about
human rights in this setting and to
increase awareness and and raise the
capacity to discuss these complicated
social issues in the context of in
engineering and technical space so we
the the research group is seeking to of
course put together internet drafts
the focus on research we're also
interested in going beyond as well to
look at the potential to write policy
and academic papers that relates this
work to to take it outside of this space
the in the past have been some even
multimedia expressions of this there's a
film called the Internet of Rights I
believe you can look you can view that
at the research group's website and as
well there's been some in the past data
analysis which I think will continue to
have to do to really look at what are
the dynamics in the ITF and how we can
learn something from that and of course
we're reviewing protocols as well so
yeah these are the my milestones if you
will so we have the proposal the
chartering the film and RFC 80 to 80
those are the main highlights we're
going to have more of those
that's time goes on and right now we
have three active drafts which we're
going to talk about today first we're
talking about Association and politics
the first and third one on this slide
and then at the end we're talking about
the guidelines draft we've had other
internet drafts in the past but those
are expired as far as I know so that is
where we're at that is the history of HR
PC we are now moving into the
presentation by Juan Carlos de Martin so
I will give some time for that to get
set up and load the slides
in you gamer yes we can him hello
everyone hello chair Minecon Callister
Martine and I'm speaking from Turin not
wesson Italy first of all thank you for
inviting me to this group which I've
been following through the many lists
but it was the first time that I
actually interact with all of you I was
supposed to be there in person
unfortunately for family reason I
couldn't travel to Montreal sorry about
that thank you for this opportunity to
present remotely just a few words about
me I'm a professor of computer
engineering at the Polytechnic of curing
and for the past 15 years I've been
working studying several topics
regarding internet and society with law
professors economists fight also first
etc usually in the count within the
context of the Nexus Center for Internet
and Society which I found it also in the
context of the Berkman client center for
Internet and Society at Harvard
University what I would like to share
with you today is our work about
something we called ethically and
socially aware data labels next slide
please
okay thank you this what I'm presenting
is a is a summary but you will find a
bit more in detail in a publication my
quarters are elaborate and Tonya vitro
ambulatory and the publication is
available both on the springer website
and also as open access on the next
Center website and you can find their
URL over there next slide please
can you see me
yeah there's just a bit of a delay
usually okay IDEs yes and also can you
see the I should also send my own video
but probably is not showing let's try
again
not that this necessary to see my face
but maybe it would be okay I'll proceed
with the slides
okay let me disable the video according
to the instructions I'm receiving
through the chat okay
now the starting point is that we all
know the crucial role of data for the
design and development certainly on
machine learning algorithms but more
generally of recommendation systems and
many digital systems just to next slide
please just to show a quotation among
many this is taken from the very
well-known book by Katie O'Neil weapons
of mass destruction example based on one
of the main chapters of the book based
on the admissions by American
universities obviously if we had trained
do training on the basis of past data
from the 1960s or 70s we would have of
course a recommendation system or our
enrollment system and that would show
the same biases or the data sets
collected regarding those decades next
slide please
now to avoid discrimination and other
unintended negative effects we will
focusing on unintended negative effects
of course care is needed at all stages
of the design and development process of
a machine learning system of a
recommendation system etc I will show
you in a second which stages were
focusing on next slide please
we're focusing at the beginning so
upstream the data is produced is
collected afterwards we have a data set
and this data set is available for use
maybe by organizations and people that
have nothing to do with the organization
that collected the data so we have these
data sets they're coming from somewhere
maybe we don't have any personal
connection or
additional connection with the
collectors so that we just have the data
and this data is used as the primary
input to develop for instance
recommendation system and therefore this
is where we're focusing next slide so
the key idea which is by the way not
original other people are working also
in the same direction we're just
contributing his effort is to support
computer scientist using data sets by
means of easy-to-understand labels so or
more broadly in our case easy to
understand the approach to better
understand the implications of the data
sets they're going to use next slide
please
more specifically now there is a fairly
large body of research showing uncertain
data characteristics may lead sometimes
in wastes are not completely
self-evident or to discriminatory
decisions on therefore it is important
to identify those data characteristics
and to show the potential risk of those
data characteristics if not understood
in their full implications next slide
please
so what we are focusing between step one
and step two so the data sets as I
mentioned had been elected as traveled
who knows where
now's is in the hands of a computer
scientist who wants to use the data set
right at that moment you would like to
provide a framework to properly use
those data sets next slide next slide
please
so we want to label data sets so the
ultimate ultimate end is as a sort of
labels that are easy to understand the
quick to to comprehend showing that
certain data characteristics for
instance and even distribution in gender
balance colon arity of a
tributes etc we will I will show you
examples in the following slides that
represent a risk of discrimination is
used in decision-making now I want to
stress the word risk in the sense that
we are not sure we are just showing that
there are potential problems with the
data set but maybe there is no problem
at all because maybe the specific
application and the specific data set
actually is perfectly fine the way it is
but we want to raise the flag saying
okay are you aware of that
and if the computer scientist says yes
I'm aware of that and that's perfectly
fine for my application then they can go
on next slide so the the focus and the
objective is to be useful to software
engineers in order to make them more
aware of the potential risk and so if
they as we all hope want to do so to be
able to use the data set in a more
ethical and socially aware manner in
addition this approach these labels
could be used by third parties to do
some sort of independent verification we
can also imagine situation where the
data set has been produced it has been
used and then there is a potential third
party which would be could be a public
authority or could be a certificate of
some sort wants to look in the process
and this approach can help with a
certificate or to more quickly do its
job next slide please
now as I mentioned this is with not
claim of originality there are at least
two other initiatives we're aware of
that working in the same direction while
one is the data side nutrition label
project which is a joint project between
the media lab at MIT and the Berkman
Klein Center at Harvard and another
project that is similar is data sheets
for data sets by gable and other authors
next slide please
now what in our approach in our proposed
approach we are
three branches three main building
blocks and I will show what they are in
a second next slide please
first of all we are going to look about
disproportionate paths so data says that
have features that are disproportionate
next slide please
secondly we are going to look at the
features of the data set that they are
correlated or in the extreme case
collinear so essentially a linear
combination of other features in data
set so we have to warn users look it's a
different feature in the data set but
actually it can be very easily predicted
by other features present already
present in the data set next slide and
third point which has been introduced by
one of the co-authors who is a software
engineer is about data quality and now
it's a specific topic which are not
completely familiar which is data
quality this quarter which is Antonio
Boudreau who is anti-retro explained us
that there is within the international
standards organization there are two
standards regarding assess the
qualitative a quantitative assessment of
data and therefore he introduced this
third branch third third building block
to assess datasets which is data quality
in this specific sense of the Izone
standards and which are articulated into
five quality dimensions which are
accuracy completeness consistency
credibility and currentness next slide
please
now having brought together these three
building blocks we wanted to test them
to do an experimenter to do an exercise
with a specific data set well known in
the studies of this this kind of problem
so next slide please
it's the data sink called critic credit
core default there is information in
this data set on default payments
of credit cards in Taiwan from April to
September 2005 and in these data sets
you find demographic factors like the
age of the person create data
information history of payment and build
statements of credit card clients so
there is a various number of all
features and some of them are critical
in the sense that I mentioned before
next slide please
for instance the data set do not cannot
contain the protected attributes race
ethnicity but contains which we know of
course it's a very sensitive feature but
contains other personal information that
can be used in a discriminatory way if
apply to assess creditworthiness for
instance gender our level of education
so let's dig a little deeper and see
what we found looking at this data set
next slide please
now let's look at the first one this
proportion at nasse please next slide
for instance very simple factor age we
see that this and the histogram of age
of very easy to to plot this feature we
see that there is a high prevalence of
young people between the age of 25 and
40 now the objective of showing the user
that data set this information is just
it's not to tell them there's something
wrong with this we don't know if there's
something wrong we're just saying this
is the age profile make sure implicitly
we are saying make sure that whatever
you want to do with this data set you're
okay with this age profile is it
representative of the people in Taiwan
is it representative of credit card
owners in Taiwan is it okay for your
application so we're just making clear
that this is the profile and you may be
okay or maybe not next slide please
now again looking at features that we
know can have potential implications for
discrimination for instance
we're saying 60% of the people in this
database are women almost half of them
attended college and we have more or
less than half and half split between
single people and married people again
we know that all these features level of
education gender and marital status can
have implications can be potentially
discriminatory if not used properly and
so we are showing the use of data set
this is the way it is in this data set
don't use it blindly because if you use
it bland we think it is a representative
of the general population maybe you're
going to produce unintended consequences
in your system next slide please
Croatian culinary team next slide now
looking at the features within data set
we found very significant correlations
between the condition of payment default
so somebody didn't pay the credit card
bills and their level of education so
their gender and their marital status
again these three dis correlations are
not surprising because for instance if
you look at the level of education you
see that the higher the level of
education the lower is the likelihood of
a payment default which is intuitive
considering all other whatever
everything we know about what is
correlated with a high level of
education but we're making
straightforward easy to understand for
the data set user saying if you're
looking beware if you're for instance
using the marital status or the level of
education and you're using it using it
without being aware that it's a highly
correlated in one way or another with
the payment default beware because you
might get something that you actually is
not what you wanted next slide please
finally that the quality I will only
mention that applying the two ISO
standards I mentioned before at
you can only apply 2 or the five
attributes accuracy and completeness
which are actually quite good for this
specific data size
next slide please I conclude so this
approach which is easily understood it
is a proposal of how to address data
sets and then produce actually
graphically appealing labels like the
two other projects that I mentioned are
working on could help datasets user to
be more aware of the potential biases
and problems of the data set before
using them so the moment they acquired
this data set they are helped they are
supported in understanding the
implication at least some of them
because of course some implications are
difficult to to assess exactly but
assemble them therefore reducing the
risk of downstreams unintended problems
also for human rights thank you thanks
very much are there going to be
questions people want to queue is
labeling data in this way not
potentially likely to make it even
easier to discriminate and if you say
are we found like 15 colon ii-era T's
between LGBTQ people and but no credit
card defaults you could then apply that
to learn from other data and reveal
perhaps privacy information about people
through labeling this data in this way
that's that's why I used so many times
the objective unintended because we are
assuming that the data users is in good
faith and so we are helping a good faith
data user if it's not in good faith so
if the intention is actually to
discriminate sure this approach could be
helpful but if it's in bad faith they
could do what we're doing anyway and so
we would they would reach the same
result with a little more effort the
sorry Jonathan Ireland I didn't say my
name
making it easier for people to do bad
things tends to make people do more bad
things oh oh well actually a warning
sign saying that be careful this could
lead to bad consequences I don't see it
as really conducive to doing bad things
I cannot I mean otherwise the other turn
ative is just obscurity so trying to
reach security by making things
difficult to understand for example
making sure the published data sets with
enough noise to break the sky linearity
I'm sure I don't understand if there is
a collinearity adding the noise and
adding the noise could mask the car
linearity by making by breaking
correlation effectively oh well if the
noise is white it's so easy to filter
out and find out the colinearity anyway
just out of the top of my head different
question my name is Joe hall from CDT in
the US DARPA DARPA right Defense
Advanced Research they have a version of
Android they've been working on for a
long time now for five years that's
called privacy enhanced Android and it
does some of this tagging especially in
the developer level like developers
using this as far as I understand it I
don't understand it very well
developers using this kind of a
framework can sort of talk about
intentions and pre label certain kinds
of sensor data and stuff like that
wondering if you've thought about sort
of bringing this down to that kind of
level maybe modifying this privacy
enhance Android to also not just be
about privacy but the things you're
talking about sort of a richer form of
intentional labeling of flows in objects
and stuff now thank you this is a very
good suggestion we would look into that
thank you
anyone in the queue remotely doesn't
look like it thank you
okay um so yeah Joe and Stefan we're
going to talk about draft Association I
think so let's Jack you have 15 minutes
correct all right let's do this
so Stefan are here is the violin I are
here to talk about draft Association we
haven't modified the document at all
which some of you might be like wait
that was your whole job but we wanted to
put forward some very specific deep
changes that might deserve some
discussion and then we'll take it from
the list and then actually modify the
document within about a month maybe a
little longer do you want to do your
yeah so yeah i'm stefan cultura I'm not
your converse t soon to be moving at
investor Maya so I'm trying to continue
to this draft but I'm also a
communication scholar as part of my
research trying to understand what's
going on in ITF and like people discuss
about values in attic so if you have
question about my research please come
to me after so Petrelli he's studying us
you're now made aware of that deal with
it
cheers thanks next slide just to give
you a quick little background draft
Association is one of the specific
rights that flows from 80 to 80 and
specific to Association assembly we took
the helm of this after kneels and
Gizella handed it off to us it feels
like it's maybe 75
done and apologies if I'm talking too
quickly we don't have a lot of time and
what we want to do is actually run
through some of the bigger thoughts we
had right now so just a recap of the
giraffe for those who didn't read it so
the research question it's centered
about a research question the research
question is others they architecture of
the Internet enable and/or animate the
right to freedom of assembly and
Association the mythology that is stated
in the giraffe is to test the casual
relationship a formulation we which we
will come back to it and so basically
our protocol calls the capacity to
associate or assembly true okay section
there's basically seven protocol cases
that are address in the giraffe so you
have the table of content here and you
have like cases of a like conversing
cases peer-to-peer networks and system
and grouping together here so mailing
lists multi-party video conferencing
Internet Relay Chat peer-to-peer system
version control DNS anatomist system and
our each of these case can have
potential - yeah
- to facilitate or constrain association
and assembly so the first big question
we have is this draft talks about
causality I'm a physicist I was ok yeah
yeah we had a question because the
mythology is based like the goal is to
establish a causality so there was this
some discussions like in the mailing
list by different people who brought
this and like it's a strong objective
causality to establish like our protocol
calls Association and something within
the giraffe of the draft for like 80 to
80 actually was no mention of causality
and also like the idea that technology
is causing stuff has been a bit more
neurons true studies for instance in STS
and communication dry famine ISM for
instance they talk about how the main
pack which is a bit less ambitious and
we don't see causality as a major
element yet so we would like to drop
like the idea of causality and maybe
replace it by something a bit more
neurons but at the same time in a way to
show that the protocols can have an
impact but although there are other
dimensions and a ways also to circumvent
these things but there's a relation but
made me baby not causal so that's a
question maybe you can answer about this
after or in the always in there yeah and
then the second one do it do it thank
you second one is the church the cases
that are chosen right there's ones that
are about communication
the conversing one there's one's about
object or file transfer sharing stuff
that's peer-to-peer versioning then
there's stuff about identity DNS
autonomous systems but it strikes us
that there's other things and maybe
these were left out and we just couldn't
find a record of that for example app
stores can propose pretty significant
restrictions on the ability to associate
by removing apps that millions of people
use maybe that's not an IETF thing or
that's not something that we need to
care about because that's not about
protocols otherwise you know think about
things like SMS right that's I don't
know if that's an HF vertical I don't
think so
I think that might be ITU something else
what I don't even know but these things
you know like the vert the difference
between SMS and more modern kinds of
messaging systems they do have impacts
on assembly I'm not sure if we want to
talk about that in this draft or what
we'll have a more fulsome discussion on
the list but and for example we talked
about all these proprietary non Interop
Oh messaging systems bye neighbor we
don't talk about signal which is maybe
one of the biggest proprietary non
interoperable systems I mean it's it's
it's I guess I can't say proprietary
because it's it's free software but
still you can interoperate with it good
luck
and then we're wondering if there are if
there are sort of longitudinal cases we
can describe that might help folks
for example turkey is a really
interesting case where the government
used DNS blocking and then you may have
seen pictures of and you may have seen
me present pictures of this of people
spray-painting 8.88 well no one no one
now or whatever but then what happened
was when the government realized that
their orders to ISPs were not being as
effective it went to a higher level of
an effect on their associational right
so they started doing internal
adversarial BGP route announcements for
certain kinds of things like Twitter
right and in those cases you know that
kind of an interplay that kind of a
longitudinal disruption on freedoms of
Association and assembly specifically in
those cases that might be a good thing
to include in this there other things
like Molly Sauter has a great book about
distributed denial services as a
legitimate form of protest that you know
in the digital world we haven't created
the sidewalks that people use in the
physical world to be able to protest so
that we have to do these things like
DDoS if we want to be activists and
disrupt things there's just no other
alternative and then I forgot the
gentleman's name but this morning we
talked about the relationship Leandre
we're talking about the relationships
between small independent nonprofit
providers of things like email and the
large huge email systems like Gmail and
Facebook and stuff like that and how it
can be extremely hard to get them to
accept your email and then when they
don't it's very hard to figure out
exactly why they didn't accept your
email and that obviously is going to
pose some restrictions on Association
yeah I wanted to add so just from my
understand maybe Leon who could take the
mic after this but the idea the last one
might be more about like spamming
protocols so let's say you use like a
rise up email you send it to Gmail and
Gmail consider it's a spam so this might
cut off the capacity to assembly between
activists so that's that might be a use
case the section we put that the lasas
is like should we because the the the
the the the draft is Center much are
around technologies but we were
wondering if we should start with like
case like good examples on our social
examples or it was made and then go on
with the specific case of existing
technologies so we open up this as a
question the last next line yeah another
question Association on propriety
platforms and we felt that the graph is
implicitly critical of large propriety
we and are not entered and so we I this
word I have this word platforms
especially search such as major social
media platform so it's not very explicit
about this but there are son sentence
especially at the end they say basic
here open an open platform open protocol
will favor more Association than a
propriety platform on the other hand we
cannot deny that social media like
Facebook and Twitter day they are
helpful platform for Association so we
know like
we know many activists we put Twitter
revolution between coats yeah but it has
been criticized but it's been used by
many social movements as a way to
associate so I think we need to take
this into account on the other Anna
actually what problem might be that
Facebook as a or social medias like like
a lot of power bi like this I see 18
people okay without it's not like it's
not regulated as as it is like in in in
the public space okay so yeah so at the
end it's part its talk about the forest
Association so social media is talking
about forcing the association of people
but we were wondering if we could talk
about freedom of association let's say
can we discuss it them yourself from
social media so it might be another way
to frame the discussion thanks like okay
so the last question is more about the
HR PC work it's something I thought this
morning so maybe we could think about
with our audience who we have the idea
that we want to convince her to to talk
with engineers but these documents are
they also attract social activists and
social science academics who get
interested by ITF and may later
influence it so in all the writing this
we might think as like you are we
talking are we talking only our to the
folks in ITF are we talking to other
people also true these documentation so
it's not specific to this but it might
be a general question for HR PC this is
our last night sorry
so there's a number of minor change
changes we wanted to mention during our
presentation after each case there's
sort of this - - list of a - any
considerations it's kind of mysterious
where that comes from
I mean you can point to 80 to 80 but
we're gonna do some things that
basically clean that up to add sentences
and content
you know make it less of a list and more
of a narrative or something that isn't
as mysterious to the readers we also you
know right now the document isn't very
clear on how these cases were chosen it
uses some some words like these are you
know typicality and a paradigmatic
nature of the cases but we're gonna find
ways to talk about the cases we talked
about so where it makes a little more
coherent sense across all the cases and
it's going to include maybe including
new ones maybe dropping some of the ones
we have now again will propose this on
the list and have either pull requests
or text changes that you guys can look
at finally there's a section in section
7 that talks about legal limitations
that you know only lawful limitations on
rights are allowed and yeah that's true
of governments that have signed human
rights treaties and feel free to to take
issue with this but it doesn't apply to
businesses and so it's sort of a half of
lawyer what I want to do with this
section is take it and and one make it
not as normative you know this really
needs to be a descriptive document I
think right listen totally missed what
we're doing here but then sort of talk
about change it lists talking about
granted in treaties and we'll ground it
in treaties for governments but then
talk about business social
responsibility is the thing that's a
hook for why businesses care about human
rights in many cases and that's it sorry
to be so long thank you thank you guys
please let's queue up you guys have post
a lot of really important questions I
think and it would be great - yes for
sure discuss this on the list but if
there are thoughts I have a whole list I
don't want to just sit here and talk
move three of us so if great meals this
year
go ahead meals
you hear me hello hi this is great
thanks Joe and Stefan so much for doing
this terrific work on this which was
much needed and I'm highly indepted and
again happy to help where I can add some
clarifications app stores and platforms
we tried to keep outside of the draft
because it got outside of the remit of
the IETF I re i RTF and we try to catch
that with the sentence architecture in
the in the research question by trying
to limit the scope of it a bit going
beyond that might make the work a bit
unwieldy another point is that in your
discussions we talked about the book by
Molly Sauter we also had a Molly Sauter
respond to the list and so we discussed
there if whether ddos could be a
positive freedom of expression and that
discussion then ended which can of
course be in the found in the archives
but it was an extensive discussion that
an attack is an attack is an attack is
an attack and and then we are we achieve
achieved actually a research group
consensus on that so I'm not sure
whether you would really to go down the
rabbit hole at least before having a
look at that at the description again so
thanks a lot for this I do agree that
Kinsella tea might might be a bit strong
even though I do not think that the the
current document is technological
deterministic because the protocol is
not so understood as as as technological
but as an assemblage but I'm very
curious to be what the new editors will
come up with with the nature of the
relationships thanks so much for word
thanks
yeah I would just pick it back up on a
couple of those comments so I as well
remember the DDoS discussion because I
disagreed with Molly's book I mean it's
an interesting book I think she poses a
lot of interesting things but I think to
say that DDoS is a print is protected
because it's Association I think
is a stretch and also within this
context I think it's important to
remember what the mission of IETF is and
what I RTF is and to understand that
it's important to have a very solid base
for using the internet and DDoS is like
exposing vulnerabilities and like
explaining them and I think that's not
the role here like if people want to
still do that with like you know that's
fine but we're not gonna sanction it
necessarily the other one that is real
quick yeah yeah sure I think we weren't
gonna like sanction it's more like using
that as a way to discuss you know how
limiting the digital environment is
before jumping into the cases so not
endorsing it by using it as sort of
something a discussion point that might
help people understand where we're
coming
yeah I mean not even yeah I mean yeah I
think it would be actually useful to
just go back to the list to do 2016 yeah
it's um it's in there for sure um the
other one that Neil's mentioned is about
the like keeping the app store and those
out I mean one thing that occurred to me
was it could be similar to like browser
extensions which is a little bit closer
to IDF but still not quite that's one
thing you could maybe consider um yeah
and then just the last thing I'll say
and then I'll take a pause for Holy
Ana's comment it's just that I would
really support inclusion of signal
especially because we have MLS and so it
can be a useful case study in the
spectrum of the case studies you have
because many of them like if we talking
about email like okay there's maybe some
changes to email but it's mostly done in
dust it's a historical view but you can
also then look at things that are in
situ and that could be one also that
could be interesting for that reason
Juliana which was i yes about the vxr8
format no the next just for questions
about the question about using Aris RFC
format to both audience I think it is
really important to use RFC format until
how to write this format because we have
more experience like talking about
technology without completely understand
how does it work to the public now to
grow their audience so it is necessary
to the same question I do to myself
writing the feminist dropped and this is
about like I'm not sure if I understood
our nails but the every question is like
we are talking about end users ever I
think while we're talking about human
rights we are ever talking about end
users and here sometimes people don't
think they are talking to end users so
we need to find the way to translate
that in terms of protocols so I think
that's very important and that's what we
have to explore and find the way thank
you my last comment I think for now is
just the you mentioned business and
human rights yeah I think it's a really
important point I also wonder I mean if
I'm are calling right that is also
considered in the in 80 to 80 so maybe
it's worth also just trying to see
what's been discussed before because
like in deeds right like Human Rights is
an obligation of states not companies
but of course we think about your best
practice for companies and like
encouraging them you know whatever so I
I wonder if we can do our best to either
not just maybe mirror what's already
there but even improve that language a
bit because of your experience and your
thoughts on that
that'd be great yep Leandra you can see
or see this is a comment when when we
talk about the the right of assembly or
or or association we mentioned this
money in the case of him a well I mean
it's an example where is of
a few applications well you have local
herbal accents global interoperability
of the racial across small and large
email operators but but sometimes it's
not enough and you need some kind of
centralized governance some kind of ways
to address the problems that appear not
in a particular way for each provider
but across providers and and well or
even in imagine like the case of instant
messages and applications where it used
to be inter some hunter interoperable
but the the attitude of providers became
like well let's isolate users so
nowadays when you want to associate
without people you need to agree on
which application you're going to use to
do that
so I mean it's I like very much the work
that because the technical problems of
of federated systems or globally
addressable systems translates into this
freedom of association or or assembly
awesome force people that participate in
governance can we thank you yeah thanks
so much yeah looking for journalists
discussion about this and just last
question on and maybe you said that's in
the beginning I've just forgotten but do
you have like a kind of ETA when you'll
see that maybe a little ambitious but I
think about a month is when we hope to
come up with the next - oh three and
probably a set of things to the to the
mailing list they're going to be like
here are some things that are clearly
not necessarily done yet that we want to
you know notify for you and then point
to things that we've done that you might
want to interrogate yourselves well
it'll be oh three but it's not going to
be done a month roughly sounds good
thank you guys thanks love
[Music]
all right so I think nails you're
presenting remotely on this one
if you're talking we can't hear you
are you yes we can hear you it's quite
loud but it's good hi okay I'll try to
put it down I was dropped of course it
just at the moment I started presenting
but I'll keep it short I got three
slides so first slide please
so this is the draft political we've
been talking about it for a bit but I
think what just happened really
Illustrated very well what this draft
aims to do namely documenting some of
the discussions that we've been having
and that also keep on coming back so
it's also like creating a bit of a
platform on the things we learned
together so we can continue discussing
them and learn from our past and
progress at the same time next slide
please second slide so what trying to do
in draft political is document a long
list
standing discussion in HR PC capture
some of the observations and conclusions
we've made a document positions in the
community document the positions that
have been discussed in a scientific
literature on this topic and provide a
platform to further the discussion
without continuously having to repeat it
so it's also like documenting what we've
been doing but we're not trying to do is
trying to discuss everything possible or
this provide new guidelines or
considerations because that what we're
doing in other documents so what I've
been doing in the last two versions
since last meeting that I've presented
integrate the very generous review by
Michael Rogers which was very extensive
and came up with a lot of changes as
well the great review but Julia Gareth
thanks so much for doing that Julia and
and then a conclusion of previous
meeting as many of you will remember was
try to do less and try to make it more
concrete and try to stay away from
anything especially
and try to make it as concrete and
observable as possible and that's what I
try to do so I've done that by
simplifying the research question
removing recommendations a removing
secondary or indirect arguments for
instance about the IITs financial
position about interoperability and
about layer competition those were
interesting arguments that in that were
related to the to the research question
but not necessary to answer them so I
remove them that also allowed me to
create a new shorter clearer abstract
remove definitions of protocols or
standards because those were not needed
added methodology text to make it more
tight and cleaned up many typos so
that's where we are with 0-3 I think
what we have now seems is much tighter
than what we had and I'm very curious to
hear from people where they think the
document is at the moment
thanks.thanks meals
yeah I'd also love to hear from folks
about where they think this draft is at
just could you talk a little bit about
the recent discussion we've had on the
list Neil's because I think that came
after this version and just wondering if
you can go through if there are any of
those any of those points in the
discussion that you think you might
actually take on board for another
version or if you've been satisfied with
the discussion you're not going to make
changes I can see that going both ways
but just wondering your opinion on that
well I think that the discussion on the
list came in response to a discussion it
came in response to a new version of
this draft but we're not about this
draft so whereas it was a interesting
discussion only one remark was by was
about a draft which was from Andrew
Sullivan and he said that he said there
might be some internal consistency
issues with one view that was portrayed
but that
but we didn't try to judge the positions
because these were positions that were
observed on the list and during
interviews and and at meetings so so I
try to answer that and I didn't hear
back from Andrew on that so so I think
with that the discussion was captured as
as far as possible but I'm very happy to
be told I'm wrong okay no that was
really helpful to note I also got a
sense that the conversation was a bit
all over the place and was not
necessarily about the most current
version so it sounds like you don't
anticipate any further changes based on
them based on that list discussion and
then oh and I went through all that and
I try to I I was very eager to make
changes but I did I didn't find anything
so so so I'm very curious to hear from
the room others of what we can do to
take this document for yeah I agree I'd
like to hear that too
okay looks like I was going to the mic
Johanna sweetie
I want to give it one that last read but
I really like what you've done I don't
have particularly good thoughts about
what to do next other than working group
last call others may feel differently I
would like to give it one quick review I
could do that this week thank you Joe
thanks Joe hello Gosha with Grover CS so
just following up on Andrews comment on
the mailing list do you think it's in
the scope of the graph to analyze the
positions presented by the ietf i RTF
community or do you think that's how the
scope because in a way the draft
currently does do that
by by lumping together at least in four
five categories the thoughts and
coupling them with literature on the
topic but I think when when people
answer the question are net-like
protocols political they're evening
they're either answering the question or
the process is political are the results
political but I mean this might be a
difference in semantics here
that's it that's a really great question
Gershon but I think there are there are
two parts I think the what we try to do
in the point in point for technology and
politics a review of literature and
community positions we try to document
as pure as possible the positions that
have been observed in the community as
they were so so we did not try to lump
them together but try to isolate groups
within that help on position and couple
that with existing literature to to
situate it into into a broader context I
have been thinking about then trying to
brick
further in conversation with each other
but that did not necessarily something
very constructive because it this is
simply what we observed and then what we
then try to add in analysis in point
five to see how does that break down
into into practice when we look at
standards so I'm not sure how I could
further analyze the positions under in a
more constructive way and I'm a bit
careful about the discussion but I would
like to hear very much more about like
the process versus the outcome or the
output because a protocol of course is a
process in itself right and it's never a
thing that's done because it's how it's
used and and it's a complex assemblage
in itself so I think it will be hard to
to pin it down in general but I'm very
happy to be the guestlist okay thank you
relating from the jabber aviary Doria
says it might be a good idea to get
people to agree to a thorough
read-through I agree I'm go ahead here
at the queue and then I have a comment
as well
hi Joseph man with these algorithms
foundation so I have a question but I'm
not sure if I'm it's gonna be a
completely naive question because I was
doing two sessions right now but when I
look at the draft I don't see explicit
reference to 20 21 19 and the uses of
like the capitalized must and shell and
things like that and this would actually
be a pretty interesting RFC to make use
of those terms in that in that formal
way thanks for your question ed meals
while you're getting to the mic to
answer that okay
that is not language that we can use in
research group documents because we
cannot make any normative statements or
do you mean that we should reflect on
the use of normative statements really
I'm just talking about the difference
like 2119 provides formal definitions of
words so it doesn't it so long as it's a
longer thought in terms of the context
but it's really the formal meaning of
the word so can and shall and should and
so forth when it really means that it
just provides the formal definition of
it versus an informal colloquial meaning
I'm not sure whether I get it but of
course full requests or or suggestions
on the list always very welcome and then
we can consider how and where to include
them so just going back to the
suggestion from RE which is a good one
that everyone has a variant I think I'd
be good if we can bound that in time so
since we also have Association that's
going to be discussed and the next month
as a commitment if people can please go
back to the list and then I
month up reading it early and just even
the slightest you know sentence or
encouragement would be helpful if you
have done so as a final read and then
for those who are maybe engaging it with
it for the for the first time or even
yeah even people who've been watching
this progress for a while if you can try
to answer the question does this draft
achieve what we would like for it to
achieve which is to help establish the
boundaries of the ongoing and pervasive
discussion about what or not protocols
are political so does this draft do
achieved that for you and your use cases
and the discussions that you've had in
this space is it going to be useful for
you to reference this and if you can
think about that when you're reading it
and then send your thoughts on that to
the lists that would be very helpful in
moving this forward I think they're all
yes thank you so much Niels thank you
very much okay Juliana you're up next
the draft on feminism and protocols we
presented it in the last meeting
so next and it was a very preliminary
version where we were trying to cover
two different problems one was on the
user level and it was like taking at the
feminist principles of the internet to
collect some cases and to relate it to
protocols and the other was try to
identify some manifestations of gender
of gender discrimination in the IETF
archive so just to say that that part
was gone so in this second note the
first version version one we are like
like focusing on based on the eighty to
eighty which uses the Human Rights to
understand how protocols can enable or
restrict some specific human rights that
this relation so they use some specific
concepts and we're trying to use that
format to make it with feminist
principles of the internet we already
presented what the feminist principles
are but you can find it in feminist
internet.org so the difference is that
in human rights
this is pretended that everyone has
guaranteed their rights equally but the
feminist principles changes that
question understanding that not
everybody has the same capacity to have
their rights guaranteed so our framework
is
intersectionality which is a concept
used from the black feminism from the
United States but now used in different
parts of the global south mainly so this
framework understands try to understand
how multiple forms of discrimination
overlap is not focused on the problem of
equality but difference and
discrimination is not analyzed in terms
of effective access of right but the
conditions and the capacities to access
that rights so we have three very
important concepts the first is the
social locations which are the multiple
layered identities people lived which
are derived from social relations
histories structures of power where
people can experience both oppression
and privilege an example is me in my
country I am ultra privileged but here I
am like not exactly oppressed but for
example in my country I speak English
very well but here I feel so bad because
I don't speak English and it is very
difficult for me to express what I am
thinking yes I have studied as many
people in my country can not do I have a
superior grade of studying yes at a
postgraduate but here but I studied
cultural studies so here this is very
difficult to express myself because you
are mostly technicians so that
configures the way I can express myself
here and I can't really have a relation
with you in terms of power I feel I feel
like very small here so this is one
point the other are the different
operations I one person can feel which
are determined by gender
race sexuality age studies geographical
locations abilities health conditions
and among others and this is all that
other important concept which is matrix
of domination is the way in which powers
that produce and reproduce intersecting
operations are organized so in the draft
we have this question I think this is
not completed but can we understand the
internet in the sense we work in
Internet here as a matrix of them in a
mass a matrix of domination and try to
understand how operations are organ and
powers are organized there so this is
where we are next
and based on disk on that question we
are trying to make this table principle
by principle and based on the principle
description first this is they said harm
and the question is how the oppression
is being expressed in this principle in
each principle and how can it be related
to protocol
so we're based in 80 to 80 and they
talked about some specific terms like
interoperability centralization content
agnosticism censorship resistance and
we're trying first to understand those
concepts related how with how the
oppressions are being expressed in the
principles and so that's where we are
with and the next step is to collect
kind of use cases based on this first
approach and yes that's where we are
it's a very difficult issue and ok
that's and this is difficult because
it's different from the human rights
because it is it has like different
points now one is access but we have
movements too and for example in
movement inside movements we have
governance and this part of governance
has is related to how do we participate
in these spaces that's why I think we
were trying to understand something
which is I think out of scope and this
version of the draft it's more related
with for example RFC 77040 but this is a
working progress we're trying to address
it better and next steps we're
developing a methodology which tries to
be more collaborative and participative
we presented this draft in the last IFF
in valencia and the problem was that we
were with women working on
infrastructure but almost everybody
didn't know about ITF and what is it
about
so it was like Mallory and I presenting
and everybody saying like Oh interesting
nothing to say so the next place where
we were we are going to share it is in
the citizen lab Summer Institute and
there we are going to make more practice
workshop more practical workshop trying
to mix the feminist principles with some
protocols texts and to see what can we
do with this based on the concepts
represented or are present in 80 to 80
and so we hope to find some cases into a
script it's better here and yes that's
something to say Thank You Juliana yeah
I'll just add to that in addition to
sort of in-person presentations and
discussions with feminists you know
movements and organizations we've also
got some mailing lists
where we could where we've kind of been
thinking about you know how to present
this to get some online discussion as
well
we've had people opportunistically reach
out to us that are meeting face to face
it's tech and social justice events that
have come across this and reached out to
us with their thoughts so yeah I think
it's actually part of it's very it's
very feminist thing to both be writing
something down and doing research but
also organizing and building
participation and buy-in from the
feminist movement like we're trying to
do both at the same time and so here
what matters is what is presented in
text but there's like a whole lot of
other organizing and discussing and
referencing and you know daydreaming
actually that happens that's not visible
as much here that it's just it's
important for something like this to
have an impact thank you
any other comments people have questions
words of encouragement hello from Europe
side of this channel well we've just
[Music]
we'll see how that goes I would
encourage you don't worry about feeling
small I feel very small in this
surrounded by technical people and I'm
moderately technical but we all have our
environments where we experience we are
privileged or power and others where we
don't I'm still searching for one where
I can feel moderately powerful in it but
anyway so encourage you not not to worry
about that but in the form of use cases
I'd also encourage you maybe look at
asylum and Refugee cases there it's that
their their place to look yes are you
talking about refugees cases yes yes yes
yes it is the question about
intersectionality is trying to
[Music]
I could see those cases - but we're
based on the feminist principles of the
internet which has like sexual and
gender lens to understand these problems
but of course we have to our question is
about discrimination and marginalized
groups so this is not the same to be
like man refugees like political for
political persecution or to be I don't
know a person who's escaping from war
and has no economic resources and gets
to another country and it's not the same
to be women the woman or something
and so yes that's the question in back
well yes I would I'd sorry I would take
it further than just the simple or the
the first stage of crossing the border
as a refugee crossing an international
border rather than a domestic border but
the once you'll cross their new you
register is asylum seeker then within
the asylum seeker side of HM may take
many years until you were granted asylum
or something but within that that area I
think there are many use cases you could
pick up where there's a there's a gender
bias towards who is who has spoken to
who is ink in control and and the power
within within no I mean I think you're
right to bring it into like there's an
intersectional purview so it doesn't
even necessarily need to be all about
gender but it could be within the
intersectional approach to looking at
power dynamics my the only thing I'm
struggling with to understand your case
is how this might be impacted by the
internet or specifically protocols but
yeah if you wanted to get back in the
queue we can continue the discussion I
think it would be interesting to
understand your point Niels you're up
and then Jonathan yeah first of all
thanks so much for the authors for
for bringing this work forward and I
think it's very good because it's really
opening up a new discussion in in the
field where one would not expect so
that's always very exciting and I think
it really helps us push the boundaries
and think further and also think further
further about power and that's also what
my question is about so how are you
going to operationalize how power is is
understood and then especially what I'm
interested in and that's maybe also a
part that we removed from a draft
political so it might be interesting to
edit here or to consider it and that's
economy because oftentimes in capitalist
society power is is produced through
capital social or economic or otherwise
so there's at the same time going on the
development of the draft on internet
consolidation and the internet
architecture which is an IAB documents
and I was I was I was I'm very curious
how to intersectionally take that into
account and what could be counter
examples if one would take feminist
principles into account how that could
lead to other architectures and other
principles but maybe I'm adding too much
but I'm really curious what I would look
like thank you yes me too yes I think
there is a problem when we are talking
about intersectionality and to
understand more in terms of equity than
equality because when easy answer can be
like okay let's design some different
protocols to better attend the
vulnerable groups yes and this is a
capitalist solution which is mainly or
used a lot
but I think we have to be like very
careful about how to talk about it and I
I've learned and here I participating in
the list is that we have to try to
address some very little and specific
problems and I think with the feminist
principles this is difficult but we have
to let many problems out of the scope so
I don't know how to solve that but
that's that is what we try now but for
example they drop the participation
nails I think it's good to do that in
other space is it yeah thanks so much
for that Juliana but you really made me
excited about and about a new paragraph
about equity equality labor and
knowledge but but but it might be placed
for another draft but I think it will be
really exciting to touch upon those
whether in this draft or another one so
I'll definitely put it on my on my think
about it list a bit more but yeah
fascinating thanks so much for the work
yeah I did I didn't go those things fit
into this if you read the feminist
principles of the Internet there's a
whole section on economy and there's
several sub points and this is one of
the things that excites me about doing
this draft is that you know human rights
are not they don't confront power and
economy the same way so that's what this
framework will allow us to do which is
quite exciting Johnson one one thing I'm
curious as to whether it really fits in
here is privacy in as much as it is very
difficult to discriminate against
somebody if you do not know their
categorization so if you don't know that
somebody is an ethnic minority a woman
now G
bTW then you can't discriminate because
on a sort of very literally sense you
can't discriminate you can't distinguish
between and so is there a space here for
saying actually privacy is probably the
the most literal way to reduce
discrimination on the Internet yes I
think the feminist principles are more
focused on the question about feminine
or feminist women and queer people
autonomy more than how can be protected
so this is a very different question
because as you know we have a very big
gender gap digital gender gap from their
use to the production and so the problem
is not ok you discriminate and to
recognize or better recognize the
differences and it can be named like
positive discrimination but the issue
here is other and this is more like how
can we make our own choices about what
we want to do how can we of course is
the same question I think it was in
political like can the internet make
this necessarily better or the society
just will be better or the internet it
will be better only if the society gets
better and this is I think it's not
necessary to discuss it here but the
problem here is more than more about
autonomy than specifically privacy and
privacy is one of the chapters of the
feminist principles so I don't have an
answer but of course we think we're
trying to look at the other side just to
add to that I mean just another way of
saying exactly what you've said Julianne
is that traditionally in
like like in the theory of
intersectional feminism it's it's fine
to be able to pass if you're you know a
LGBTQ person or hide or to avoid
discrimination but part of the point is
to not do that because that's part of
the layers of oppression so I don't know
that it's exactly the same because I
think on the internet we are looking at
protecting everyone's privacy but when
you're expressing feminism as like a
desire for the world that you want
hiding and not being yourself is not one
of those things so you turn it into a
positive expression of you know autonomy
which is maybe another way of looking at
at privacy but is a positive expression
of that rather than like if I just
weren't who I am then I wouldn't face
these issues right thank you hello my
name is Sophie so thank you so much for
this the contribution your work I think
this is tremendous and it's been we've
been looking for that for many years so
thank you so much for bringing this to
the table yeah I think it's a crucial
work so um I guess I have two questions
my first question would be how has this
draft been received in within this
community so that would be the first
question the second question would be so
I'm wondering if you are investigating
the question of you know feminist
standards and protocol not just the
impact of you know standards and
protocol let's proof from this
perspective
because I think there's a there's also a
difference there and I guess there are
already quite a number feminists
technologies or promise tech
infrastructures there are being built
and that are in operations whether there
are feminist servers or more complex
feminists tech infrastructures that
exists and so we can probably learn from
them as well I'm sure you're in touch
with them because you've been at the IFF
but I think they might have a sense of
what could be feminist protocols and
standards
there's also a zine that is upcoming in
September on how to install from this
service or our feminist servers and what
are the protocols and standards so I'm
happy to share that theme which is in
process with you
thanks yes thank you yes of course I
think that our dreama is feminist
protocols and standards but this may be
but here we are asking for the impacts
from a feminist perspective yeah so
that's question and of course we're
trying to work together with women
working on technology using standards
dealing with standards and protocols so
my experience in iff was that we need to
find a way as similar to a question in
the draft on Association I think that's
a big question to us because we have to
find a way to bring this information
about protocols to them because they say
this this is so boring this is not my
space this is not my interest I just
want to have my own server to serve our
movement yes for example in feminists is
infrastructure so we think this is
important to bring a their knowledge and
to embed it in or dropped so yes we're
trying to work with them but we're
finding the codes too were like breach
so we're here we're trying to write in
this format the ID format but we need to
bring it there so this is what we're
doing now and happy to hear about what
happens in September yeah hello and on
Marcus from foundation thanks for your
work first of all and then two things I
think the first
which could help a lot of people here
who probably don't see how this could
fit into the ITF or ITF is to collect
cases concrete cases how women or other
marginalized groups are oppressed I can
imagine originally with privacy as I
mentioned or or or with censorship
in social media or something like that I
think since it possible and the second
thing is I think you should connect to
Sarah Jamie Lewis from open privacy
she wrote even a book on queer privacy
and she's based in Vancouver Canada so
perhaps for one of the next ITA ITF
sessions which will be there I think
she's an expert in cryptography and and
and as also this correct his right mind
set let's say to I think to think about
in these areas here so this could be
very beneficial and she helped us in
Switzerland to get rid of Internet
voting that's an author story but I
could also help with connecting
otherwise I think that could be
beneficial to this thank you I think
Vancouver could be a really cool moment
and I would love so this kind of bridges
both yes also so for your comment is
just makes me realize that we've so far
been consulting like pretty widely and
like holding workshops and people come
but I think we could probably do a lot
more to reach out to the sister servers
what film servers lists like other
things and ask people if they could give
us their time and we can you know just
have a conversation about maybe even
develop questions but I would just love
to have a conversation about this with
them both ways right like here's what
we're trying to do what are your
reactions to some of that and trying to
collect a bit of it that would be really
fun too we can do it Amit Cooper I have
I'm Stephan katsu two comments yeah
first yeah like I would like to come
back like this idea of different
audience because I wrote like this
question in my present
this morning besan actually your
experience because last week I met
somebody who said are we talking about
this draft feminist RFC and I was a bit
surprised about this and I feel like we
have the impression well I had the
impression that the work we do here was
more to interact within ITF but actually
it's a good tool also to send symbolize
other people about the work of ITF so I
think it's really great that you're like
bringing this RFC to groups that they
don't know anything about RFC and
discuss this so they can think about
like what's the impact of this the other
thing it's just an idea where I have
different ideas but just to go to move
from a feminist perspective on protocol
to feminist protocols
there's the RFC that the andrew is
chairing i've shared on the alternative
network deployments where they analyze
different like different kind of
community networks and alternative
network it could be a good model
actually to use to map like the
different kind of feminist feminists
incitive or feminists and for structures
in relation yeah feminist initiative in
relation to technologies so it might be
a good step to to go to standards yeah
well I think it's really good to bring
this it's like yeah yeah I mean some of
the like what you're alluding to Sophie
as well as it there are implementers out
there implementers of IETF protocols
because they're running infrastructure
they're just very small right and
they're very like they have their own
worlds and they're important in that
world but by comparison to the folks
that come here they're very small but I
think it is a that so the process of
engaging a dialogue with them could help
us cite their work if they've done
writing it could help you know bring
them into this space so they can
contribute like just bringing that
closer right
trying to raise up the visibility that
that is actually that it that exists
feminist infrastructure feminist
internet infrastructure is a thing thank
you thank you so much Juliana I would
just too in that section and move on to
the next one which is you gray Shabbat
just to say that one of the things that
we are looking forward this is a bit
more engagement so so far the reaction
it's not has been vine in the sense that
but there's just not been much of one so
if people could really engage and help
guide it because it's very an institute
draft like it's not anywhere and your
complete but that's a good thing we're
taking our time we're trying to do it
right and we'd really appreciate
feedback at any stage so feel free to
engage with them okay that's the end
so go shabbat you're going to talk about
the guidelines draft and then i don't
know if there's anyone on it remotely
that's going to be presenting on reviews
they've done but it might just be you as
well for that portion yeah okay
hello again go sir would go yes and so
needs and I are Co editing the
guidelines for Human Rights protocol and
architecture consideration means is
they're so nice please feel free to jump
in yes
so this document updates RFC eighty to
eighty which has an entire section on
human rights considerations like
guidelines for human rights
considerations and what we're doing with
the current draft is updating those
guidelines after experience from two
views and it is practice based in that
sense and we want it to be more useful
for people reviewing drafts from this
perspective so yes so the draft was
updated in May after the last meeting
Dress your holes reviews thank you very
much lots of changes in language very
useful I think mostly to do with how we
are talking about the Internet itself
firstly we changed that to one of a
design language like these are the goals
we want to achieve rather than the
internet behaves in this way yes and one
clarification to a guideline which was
that when when we talking about
authentication we shouldn't use it in a
context to like prevent heterogeneity
support things like vendor lock-in or
digital rights management as its
euphemistically called and just average
review thank you very much and we sort
of clarified the status of the document
as well that the guidelines are also
being tested for validity and relevance
and lots of editorial changes and one
mistake I screwed up the metadata so the
second editor shows up as University of
Amsterdam and North Niels I'll fix that
in the next version and yeah we are
added the update tag so I mean based on
the discussion in the last meeting that
now this constitutes an update to RFC
80 to 80 yes so in O 2 we had also
changed the title to reflect that since
the experience gained from reviews was
that we're not just using them for
network protocols but for so for example
it was used in the review of the
architecture for software updates for
IOT devices which is not a traditional
network protocol in that sense but a
document in the IETF nonetheless and
similarly it was used in the
registration extensions group and then
the IP wave group so we want two
guidelines to be as broad as the
practice is but we still need to go
through the draft and sort of
broaden the scope of the guidelines that
are still restricted to network
protocols if you have any suggestions so
that like please feel free to suggest it
here or on the list and we notice that
there are still some guidelines which
don't have an explanation with it as in
like it poses a question but offers no
help for why that question is relevant
so we're still filling those gaps are
and yes happy to do anything the
research group would like please feel
free to step on the mic if you have any
suggestions yes and how you can help so
when you are participating in IETF
groups and you're reviewing a document
perhaps a useful thing to do would be e
so you recognize that there like this
particular technical choice might have
an impact on Human Rights then you just
email HR PC with that specific thing and
I mean I mean that's a way to avoid even
reading this draft by the way the second
thing is that if you're reviewing a
draft and you want to identify problems
that may not have occurred to you
naturally then you might want to look at
the questions in this draft and you may
recognize some important aspects that
you have might have missed yourself and
[Music]
malorie wrote an email to HR RT with the
list which is closing down yes
essentially if you gain such experience
in working groups please email the HRP c
RG so that we know how these guidelines
are being used and whether you find them
useful we're still evaluating the
utility of this work means hi oh I was
reading a book and I have a question to
you all what do you think it's useful
it's the book called value sensitive
design shaping technology with morale
and agitation by budget Friedman and
Henry and there I found different ways
in which people have thought and looked
at and assessed the impact of technology
on values and their intertwine Minh and
I thought this could be interesting for
draft guidelines but the whole idea of
draft guidelines by keeping them
guidelines and not making them such a
monster as RFC 80 to 80 is so my
question is should that go in here
should it go somewhere else or should I
just keep on reading books and not put
it in a document well could you tell us
a bit more about the different ways
they've liked doing to give us the
really high level stuff if you have a
very very different you know no say they
looked at medical devices and access to
information at engineering project it's
very said in a lot of different ways to
engineers Arctic architects and policy
makers analyzed technology and how it
worked an hour did not work well and
it's a bit higher scope than what we've
been working on and they've also been
they got good literature they got good
historical context so it might be
interesting to situate our work a bit
deeper maybe that's not the best way to
do it in guidelines I don't know
so it was just the thoughts and I just
wanted to throw it up and hear what
people thought before I started writing
another big document mmm-hmm just
getting to the make sure what do you
think yeah I think it would be like
usually to at least like have those
initial thoughts yeah a few of us in the
room are familiar with that work I don't
see why that would hurt at all it's
really good stuff that's it sorry being
so like blah blah vague but I just
wanted to make sure you had someone else
responding to you if it's not too much
trouble plugging it in or early
sketching out how you might plug it in
might help us see it better but I don't
think it'll be a problem it sounds great
cool I tried to make it to Paris uh
Marie and chuck it in and see where we
are next next meeting
thank you need anybody feel free to come
to the mic I just wanted to make a
couple of clarifying statements about
human rights for you team lists so that
will be closed down we I'm announcing it
officially now but also some email to
the list and then Colin it's going to
close it and then yes I had written to
HR PC about that and suggested that
people inform HR PC if they do a review
against the guidelines document or 80 to
80 I just like to be clear about that
too like just based on feedback that
I've received more recently it would not
miss it
bring the HR PC list into the process of
the review discussion so like if you're
sending a review to a working group list
don't see CH RPC but once that
discussion has run its course and you've
learned something through the process of
you know throwing out your ideas how
they've been incorporated or not into
than the next version of the draft
document etc etc do a post-mortem do a
debrief about that with HR PC because
that will be what's helpful to learn
from that process not to be involved in
the process does that make sense okay
cool and I will reiterate that on the
list as well so everybody has clarity
around that yes yeah and one more thing
about the draft there was a recent
discussion about the right to legal
remedy on the list if I am of the
personal opinion that so in fact this
was brought up in review one time which
was the registration a extensions
protocol working group and but that was
in a context where the right to legal
remedy was enforced
I mean in a context where it was used
against the state so you should have the
right to legal remedy against the state
and I still think it's an exceptional
case because most protocols don't
directly deal with
government of state bodies but if you
have strong or weak opinions about this
please feel free to step about in what
form if more text needs to be included
about the right to leave remedy
enjoy you step into the mic on oh that
was a lot of suspense okay thank you
okay thank you thank you so much did you
get abused yes you want to go into that
yes so after the last meeting there has
like no review experience been brought
to the list so not much of a huge update
on that but I I know from talking to
people that to our incoming don't want
to spoil those though so does anyone is
anyone using the guidelines has anyone
written the human rights considerations
section lately who wants to discuss
their experience there okay there is a
link which so some authors of RFC's and
drafts have started including a human
rights considerations action sometimes
it's not actually rooted in human rights
but nonetheless if you are writing one
please let us know if the guidelines are
useful yes a great might be very useful
to know yeah doesn't sound like
anybody's gonna talk about there of you
so that's okay and you're gonna message
us soon about that yours yeah okay in
the post-mortem end are you planning on
I mean you said you alluded earlier to
like you're gonna make a change to the
editorial mistake in the next version do
you have an ETA for that or you're gonna
wait until you get substantive comments
to do another version what's your plan
yes so in the next 45 days there should
be an update with more explanation to
certain guidelines and fixing more
editorial stuff okay and you and Neil's
I mean Neil's this question is also to
you you're gonna be working on the sort
of next steps that you outline or you
need to do you need to call in some
favors to help on certain sections or
you got it
so one thing is because I repeated this
call for the second time which is that
if you are writing a human rights
consideration section but from the ones
I've noticed I think we'll just get in
touch with them personally I think
that's the better route okay yeah so
those three four items
on our to-do list okay that sounds good
thank you
so yeah we are ending early so amazing
timekeeping everyone but there's also
opportunity for other things if you
would like to raise them and you have
any other business
no Melinda if you'd like to say
something Carlin I don't know whatever
the board's yours I don't think that
their I plan to say something about the
reviews I think there's no other
housekeeping Audrey you're also on the
line so if you want to step up to the
mic in Medeco please do alright well
thank you everyone thanks for coming
thanks to the presenters and to the
authors editors reviewers thank you all
we'll see you next time in Singapore and
on the list please sign in to the blue
sheets if you haven't done that yet I
appreciate that and there's there should
be another one somewhere if you could
bring that up to the front nevermind
it's right there thanks everyone
[Applause]
[Music]