good morning welcome to the IEP G
meeting at IETF 105 in Montreal
hopefully you're all in Montreal okay
there's no note well this Jeff will get
angry if I do that a note well thing
yeah he would we have four presenters
five presenters sorry and potentially a
six so we're gonna skip along pretty
quickly between the two the
presentations if you have any questions
I guess the presenters can take those as
they see first up is Joel we have about
20 minutes per person okay if you don't
need that much that's good please to the
presenters from my member can't hear you
and you want to stand on the pink X so
that the medical people see us yes these
these graphics are better than mine
since I basically don't draw stuff yeah
so this is actually sort of still recent
news some of us have been more exposed
to this and then others but basically
anyone with a Linux Linux box has done a
little bit of work in the last month due
to this particular complex of
vulnerabilities so I mean the basic gist
of what's going on here is that there
are various ways to panic your your your
kernel using really small packets and if
you're a malicious client you can
actually get the server to participate
in this by setting your TCP MSS rather
low one of the proposed mitigations
assuming that you cannot simply reboot
all of your machines in a big hurry
is to limit the minimum size MSS that
you can actually set on my connection so
in the in in in the CVE
one of the proposed mitigations is
actually the iptables lines that you see
here for ipv4 and ipv6 and you know
hopefully nobody is actually advertising
a TCP MSS of 500 on ipv6 I'm not sure
why we would consider that legal but as
it turns out people actually do so
before I actually went and slammed that
mitigation and several thousand Linux
machines that serve millions of
connections per day per box
I went and actually looked at two
questions what is what is a legitimate
TCP MSS we can go back to some fairly
foundational documents with respect to
ipv4 to look for advice there obviously
at one point in time the maximum default
maximum Datagram size was 576 really it
still is for v4 and um you can of course
obviously send a packet that's smaller
than that down to the size of your
minimal amount of data that's associated
with your tcp ack so about 60 bytes but
one of the things that you get at an
advice on the size of ip datagrams
not on the tcp MSS is that host actually
must be able to receive a Datagram of
576 bytes if somebody sends you an MSS
of like 48 or 64 or 200 despite that you
should be able to send them a TCP packet
that's bigger than that otherwise they
were violating RFC 791 as far as I can
tell
so that portion of mutual negotiation
that's supposed to occur isn't
reinforced by strong rules about how
things are applied in TCP RFC 2460 sets
the IP MTU for ipv6 to 1280 minimum
right so that means that the MSS you
should be able to send a packet with
that someone can receive from that would
follow on to be 1240 or so so before I
actually went and whacked 500 on there I
actually went to see on our network
what MSS is do we actually see on
packets so I looked in our flow data and
that was kind of entertaining but I
didn't really believe it so I just
captured a hundred million sins from
five different locations in the network
and then captured all the values that
were there yeah so they do actually all
fit on one slide I guess you will see
that the the largest one that's there is
six five four nine six and the smallest
one is zero I think both of those are
rather optimistic on the part of part of
the sender right there are some that are
there some that are pretty common I
think the the the most common very small
one was unsurprisingly 536 so 576 minus
40 bytes there were 3,000 odd packets
there since with that MSS said I don't
have a hundred million system many of
these are pretty rare they're both I
don't really you can actually see in
this one
if you do some quick math what
percentage of my tea the TCP sins that
we see in those pops is actually v6 but
this is actually the the percentages for
the common MSS sizes as sampled from a
hundred million sins so you know
fortunately for our expectations
fourteen sixty and fourteen forty are
pretty highly represented in this
distribution 8960 interestingly is it's
actually hard for me to separate out the
portions of my network infrastructure
that use that because we speak nine km
to use back and forth to each other from
the portion of the internet that
optimistically suggests that it can
support a 9k MTU I would say that for
anything bigger than 1,500 they're
basically counting on path MTU discovery
to work and that's interestingly
optimistic but for the most part we
clamp those on their behalf so that it
doesn't have to so um these are
obviously just the the emesis is that
they sent us not what we sent back okay
so if we look down here at the bottom
because I wanted to know if I was going
to block small as MSS is because
malicious clients might be using them
what sizes would I see commonly down at
the bottom so out of a hundred million
samples the only one that gave me pause
was this guy at 512 and the one at 256
the suit so this seemed like interesting
choices interestingly I didn't see those
in all of our pops um so they many of
these oddball ones that appear only
regionally so there are particular
providers or clusters of devices that
seem to be associated
with these kinds of behaviors they're
not generalized ie
the 256 one was most commonly seen in
Northern Virginia and when I actually
specifically filtered that the rate
increased so I can Intuit from that that
those clients were not very happy when
they got that filtered so in fact when I
built a mitigation for this um and
socked it away for good for for future
use and we put the threshold below that
256 number because even though we are
down here in the 10 to the minus 6 or 10
to the minus 8 in terms of frequency of
things that we see there's an awful lot
of those so I guess I'm looking at this
um one of the things I have we have to
ask ourselves is what problems were
exposed here there's a generalized
problem with croix understood and
infrequently exercised code paths so we
see a number of kinds of vulnerabilities
like that IP options handling ipv6
packet to big handling in some of these
are some of these are apparent in more
than one operating system and in
separate implementations so some of
these things are a product of
interpretation of IETF standards much
like say routing header 0 type
vulnerabilities were um so there are
implementers out there that are looking
at the advice that we provide and
producing configurations that are
feasible but not necessarily compliant
or maybe they're completely illegal but
MSS is lower than 536 or 1240 seem to
fit into that category so when you see
those and they're the product of say
additional encapsulations
where someone to set their MTU lower
deliberately because they're not doing
PPP
for example those are all well
understood so if you see an MTU of an
advertised MSS of 1388 it's pretty
obvious what's going on there right um
but these 512 and 256 seems like numbers
that someone picked out of a hat like
you didn't arrive at those because of
the structure of your of your link MTU
for example um so one of the things
that's exposed here is that malicious
clients are they are able to control the
behavior of servers right we new
advertise a lower MSS than the server
would prefer to use the server is going
to use that unless it has a knob to
prevent that and now Linux actually has
one of those now as a product of this
particular vulnerability but that's a
behavior we try and avoid in in lots of
things is to avoid cases where the
client can specify things that you
really don't want to do and you end up
doing them anyway
so there's also a need to mitigate
certain kinds of behavior either
temporarily or indifferent indefinitely
without gratuitously breaking users that
have made bad assumptions that's why I
didn't use the 500 value in my own
mitigation so is there some advice we
should be offering here
RFC 66 91 for example went back to went
back to what we specified for Mt use and
how to calculate offsets and provided
better advice basically because of a
lack of a lack of clarity and I think
there's some argument to be made that
there's more clarity that we could
provide to implementers that would
either prevent the sort of behavior or
give me as a as a user license to ignore
these things as bad behavior
so the Linux kernel now actually imposes
a minimum that minimum is pretty small
it's 48 you can set that higher if you'd
like and so if somebody proposes a lower
MSS than that you won't use it and so in
our cases like and we plan to set that
to 200 that's not actually deployed yet
but there you go
so a reading about our reading that the
document suggested we'd be well within
the IP and TCP protocol specifications
to enforce sending packets at minimums
that are aligned with them the link the
minimum link empty use or some value
near them as opposed to at 0 or 60 or 48
if these devices actually have link em
to use it will not accommodate a 576 or
1280 by packet they will break obviously
even before the network could fragment
those on your behalf in v6 it won't so
too bad yeah thank you
yes sir
good morning I'm Cassandra from JP RS I
will talk about attack to passivity
discovery it is a portable walks haughty
presentation this may attack the
passivity discovery is presented by IP
fragmentation attack on DNS after ripe
6006 table meeting October 2013 and
domain invitation prosperous for enmity
I am religion to PKI she comes exact
2018 they these papers show that some
implementations accept a champey
government ation needed on the DF set
with small empty body
this is on 576 under the code especially
the body at the tessera toot body and
the posse MP posterity body may be can
be decreased to 552 on Linux three-point
shotting
or rate or order and the paper show that
says that pass my body may be degrees to
296 then I would like to evaluate to sir
attack this space shows information
methodology attack fast generate crafted
ICMP packet details in next ride on
second dose send the packet to the
target and the attack Isis solder party
at MTV buried target Saba under another
machine and number three verify that
easily verify the result on the target
to machine using commands only Knox
IP do to get IP address command and on
previously his control or net tiny to
TCP host Akash disto only TST NATO's
- our Schultz passing with you
this page shows how to generate to
consideration people on who pockets
Krusty - in people's pockets contains a
shame people hate ICMP header weeds and
unreachable augmentation needed on the
deck set with small empty bar you undo
in IP version of header and in a UDP
header and specialized sauce this sauce
is mauritius massaging pasanda and
target which target victim Saba and the
new motif and try to control remote to
target to demote or summative are you ok
and this page shows how to generate a
cross needed a simpie baiance pockets i
think i crafted eyes in people's pocket
contains i simpiy bar on 6 header i
simpiy buttons the item IP version 6
header and across the ICMP balance sheet
set that contains pocket - beak with
small empty body for example 280 undo in
ipvanish header and in i UDP header with
large data sides and the field 0 to the
end o packet under these small code
shows how to generate the pocket
this place holds verification with a
lizard only knocks two points 6 points
attitude I Peru to get come on the shows
that a multi facility you change to
2,180 IP version 6 under par 70 you
change two degrees to 552 on IP version
4 and this page shows the recent
vegetation result of previously under
NATO BST previously on previously which
after attack Smt you just changed
changes to change the under 70 degrees
to 20 172 and only to Bastille after the
attack the same you t to change to 1280
this table shows aberration result of
the attack domain volition prosperous
whole empty I'm reading to pk paper
shows that some some implementations
accept crafted I simply button for
augmented need under the offset or UDP
and ICMP you degrees to 552 or 296 and
on linux 2.6 case linux 2.6 accept
accept
crafted I keep Acosta dashing people
John Holliman Tunisia and the except for
UDP and passivity degrees to 552 and
4.80 previously net Obst ignore crusty
Tai Chi Chi B button for fragmentation
needed under the except for UDP and the
previously net we see case
they don't have called for crafty
Tadashi
they don't have called for a simpie
revolution needed under the except for
UDP higher bar Linux and FreeBSD NetBSD
all except crafty crafty dozen people in
people's pocket to beak or UDP and they
and passivity you decreased to 380
this page shows summary of the attack
although Linux system doc left custom
people in media and DF set for UDP and
pasyati changed to 500 to 550 to the BSD
systems and renewal in existing ignore
action people are admitted needed under
the offset or UDP and DST under Linux
systems except a shame people who
fragmentation idea set SMP battleships
Paquito too big for TCP and a changeup a
74 much to TCP session tcp case they
check existing TCP session table and not
not vulnerable and many busy under Linux
systems except crafted in version 6
pocket Oh too big for UDP and facility
the crystal clear of 180 and is easy to
set remotely then I'd like to propose
that don't change facility discovery a
simple buttons expected to be Co TCP and
IP version 4 permanently did not reset
are necessary ho TCP because TCP stack
uses a shame PP to be Rowan's needed
under the accept to adjust packet size
to others MSS and UDP is safe to use
with packet size up to 1280 on IP
version 6 i simpiy partnerships pocket
too big for UDP balloon
and I'm proposing recommendations to
avoid the orientation in DNS so in this
page is DNS might be my draft proposals
through services rubadoux to set it en 0
requested the UDP pedal size to 320 and
also TT service under Rousseff is
observable should set it en 0 responded
maximum payload size 2 to 3 120 and more
authoritive service may send a DNS
response into its IP don't have IP
version 6 don't rock options and euros
observers may drop augmented the UDP
responsive tribe drama penis before IP
reassembly it is a countermeasure
against DNS cache for the new attacks
using IP fragmentation and conclusion
and all questions ipvanish pocket topic
is important for TCP and however many
ways except crafted ICP bottom-6 pocket
too big for UDP and posterity body is
easy to decrease to 380 limit or e I
will consider about facility discovery
and fragmentation omit
1280 or disabled that's all
questions
yeah Jolie eglee um so this is
definitely something I was thinking
about in the context of could I get
things to go lower than that right I
don't see a real high value as a
malicious agent in reducing someone's
MTU from say 1500 to 1280 right that's
not I mean that's kind of me being an
ass I suppose but like that that's not
nearly as costly as if you can say
reduce it to 200 right so I mean this is
it this is essentially a product of us
using an out-of-band signaling mechanism
because the ICMP message is not embedded
within the flow that that it's
purporting to control that said like I I
think the question here comes down to
implementation advice like if we still
want to path MTU discovery to work then
out-of-band messages are of course
necessary if you want to do it in band
well yeah there's other mechanisms for
doing that that are less susceptible to
this kind of behavior um
but unlike the case potentially in v4
particularly with really old like
architectures where you really could
reduce the the MSS by a lot I think this
is less dangerous I mean if you're using
a huge MTU like say 65 K reducing it to
1280 it's obviously quite detrimental to
your performance and behavior but you
know those are um not general Internet
cases thank you uh-uh-uh-uh-uh people
today 280 MTU is enough I see Eric fine
yeah 1280
I gave you six decision to do 1280 seems
like a better and better idea with every
passing presentation today so this has
been interesting I think the original
presentation as well about the
fragmentation DNS tech that you
mentioned in ryf was also very detailed
and fascinating I think it's possible to
do more sort of authentication if you
will of the ICMP packet for TCP because
you have some state tables for UDP you
might not because it's not the socket is
not necessarily connected it does seem
like if a socket is connected the Linux
kernel should bother it at least check
the connected UDP sockets to verify that
does it do that do you know yes is if
Sandown knows all sent you the old UDP
packet then possible yeah I think if
it's if it's an unconnected socket it
might not ever you might not maintain
any state about that but if it's
connected it would have it so it's
definitely at least try to scan that
table I think that would make sense um
yeah this I thought was also a problem
with Idina zeros MTU advertisement
there's no in-band fragmentation which
was like what eight zero eight fives
predecessor recommended for how to write
UDP applications but I I'm assuming the
TC bit maybe solves all problem there
I'm not a DNS person well actually I'm
not really worried about TCP UDP
fragmentation or texting Dennis because
we do actually know how to deal with
them we've got we can do that we can
deal with them at the UDP at the D in
this little if we have to you just use t
seeking that generates the
cryptographically secure signature over
the UDP message and there's no way a
reassemble packet passes that now as I
suggested I suggest the win this was
originally brought up that we use of
online TC TC key to completely mitigate
this problem there isn't it
and looking at the way servers respond
to unmanned t cigs I don't believe
there's a real problem other than
deploying that brings the that removes
that complete thing I had Nick I'm not
worried about DNS and fragmented UDP we
can solve that completely
this time they'll just tell us Chris I
don't think anyone here is so I'm Tim
April
I'm from Akamai I'm also working on this
project with a few people that are not
from Akamai so we're proposing a new
system that will help see changes that
go into the DNS so the overall goal of
this project is to try and make it so
that anyone who wants to see changes to
the DNS in near real-time or as close to
real-time as we possibly can get it can
get that data without having to go and
pull the data yourself from the
authorities so the problem was back in
late last year early this year they're a
bunch of attacks on the DNS where
attackers would get in make changes very
quickly and then change them back
resulting in some queries some changes
going unnoticed by monitoring systems
all around the world and the nature of
these short-term changes made it so that
like mobile devices and things that were
online but not actively doing and not
actively having users attract with them
may have sent either credentials or all
sorts of other stuff to those to the
target machines where the data was
changed so the the problem was so the
registration model that is used for the
NS many of you probably already know
where the registrar talks the registrar
to the registry and then to the name
servers the problem here was the
attackers that tried to get this data
either modified records at the Registrar
without the registrants knowledge or in
a couple cases modified had registrar
credentials and modify them directly at
the registry without the Registrar
knowing resulting in takeovers that were
essentially transparent to any of the
people that cared about the names and
then many people that have high-value
names will set up all this monitoring
stuff where you'll pull the registrar to
make sure your names seem accurate you
may pull the registry
you may also pull the nameservers
directly and see what's coming back but
it really matters on what that polling
window is whether you're gonna see these
changes or not the solution we're
proposing here is to create a open
system kind of like wrist live is for
BGP updates where the domain the data
owners push data into the system and
then it replicates the data back out to
any of the end users that are interested
so that could be the domain owner the
domain users anyone that relies on those
objects or people just monitoring for
security reasons so they in phase one of
what we're trying to do we're gonna try
and get as much data from the registries
as we can to push into this project so
this is essentially a pub sub system
that will send the data the main goal is
back to the registrant so the people
that own the domain should get updates
about when anything changes in their
name going forward we're also talking
about trying to get data from either G
TLD name servers and then possibly the
registrar so that we can cross check if
the registrar sent us this update and
the registry sent us this update it that
we know that they both know about this
what about the registrant did they send
any data to us if not that we might
notify them or we may change how these
notifications happen it also lets the
Registrar subscribe to this that's one
area I forgot to put on this graph where
the registrar could receive this data so
that when the registry makes the change
they can notice that they actually got
the update and then what or if they
didn't request the change and they see
the update they know something went
horribly wrong so we modeled this off of
this somewhat of the certificate
transparency model the one major change
that we had that we built into it was
that we were gonna try and build some
monitoring and alerting on top of it
just as a way of but you'll still be
able to get to the full log but we
wanted to make it so that you could also
you
get real-time updates for whatever
you're interested in so you're not
having to go and crawl the entire log
all the time just to see the changes
that you really want to see so as I was
saying the the data we want in is data
from registries mostly the public zones
that are out there where they've kind of
like CCDs the centralized domain
repositories service from ICANN but more
up-to-date and faster we have no
interest in contact information we these
slides are from the ICANN meeting and I
knew that was going to be a hot-button
topic if we were wanting Whois
information because I don't want to deal
with gdpr and then we're hoping to
output both our raw feed so anyone who
wants to go and look at the data can see
it and then the filtered updates for
whatever you're interested in that could
go over email SMS a web hook I don't
really care how you get it if you want
if you're interested in this and want a
different data format let me know and
we'll see what we can do so the places
were the things we're working on now
we're trying to create and append an
entity for it rather than putting it
through some corporation or some
for-profit company so that it's a real
open project rather than tied to some
company and then we're actually starting
to build the POC with a few different
data providers that we're hoping to get
up before the end of the year and
actually sending data to the end users
were mostly presenting around a whole
bunch of different places to see if
people are interested this if you're a
registry and we want to provide data I'm
happy to talk or we can you can reach us
at the contact information at the end of
the slide if you're a registrant and
want to subscribe to this sort of thing
let us know and what your use case is so
we can make sure that we try and cover
that if you're representing some sort of
company and want to try and either help
with resources or funding or something
like that
we're happy to talk mostly we're
deferring a bunch of that until we get
the organizational bits enough
you want me to jump in now generator hi
shared much I'm just curious
this seems like it might be something
that would fit in the DNS or wheelhouse
I'm curious if there's a reason why not
to park it there versus creating a new
DNS monitoring organization we had some
conversations about that I'm trying to
remember back to why it ended up that
way I'll have to I was just curious if
it there is it if there is a explicit or
implicit thought process you could say
I'll talk to you later offline yeah it's
like it's it's something that we will
consider that we had considered and I'll
see okay we actually ruled it out or not
and then the other things that we're
looking for is if you have experience
with nonprofit stuff that's something
we're actively trying to work on sorry
good question though what's the license
hopefully code developed we're trying to
make it either MIT or GPL thank you to
respond to job's reaction that wasn't my
I don't care how it is I just wanted out
there hi Johanna say again just a nice
project I really like this idea this is
this a problem we have um of course the
problem here is not the technical
artistic interest or the registration
share and two people to share data with
you you could also try maybe to build
another system like in parallel to the
one in which people can submit their own
domains if you will and then you start
tracking them from the parent and the
child allegation to see if they match
you know there's a change you can just
notify the same way so tracking that
sort of change where we're getting data
from below the second level is also
something very much on our radar and
that was we had proposed going that
method first but we actually have more
registry interest than we thought we
were going to where there are a handful
of registries that are willing to hand
us their full zone file in essentially
the same format they send it to their
till their name servers so we we're
going
try and push forward on that one so
because that requires less and user
interaction right now
I mean like because I work for one TLD
ccTLD and I'm pretty sure we couldn't
share yes it's like we're hoping to get
the steel these we have online first and
then go to the next level down and then
try and target the other cc's after that
that's a nice project thanks a lot for
Dan is dr. Montgomery's there in any
notion of limiting the scope of what you
can subscribe to monitor some sense your
resources are can i subscribe to bonnet
or any and all resources i we we were
planning to try and make it so you can
subscribe to whatever you'd like to wear
the primary reason for that is if you
look at trying to remember someone from
Verisign may be able to correct my the
domain name but I think it's trans -
trust Barris on labs comm where you can
see all of the name servers that your
delegations rely on so like if you're if
you're into a org you'll see that you
have the door name servers you have the
all the affiliates name sets and then
you have the dotnet from Verisign net
and common Verisign also rely on that so
you'd probably want to know any update
if you're really interested in no name
changes you want to know all of the
updates to any of those names and being
able to subscribe to all of that and
then like I'm a if I'm a customer of
like if my mail is hosted on Google I
probably want to know if any of their
names change so that I know if my mail
is impacted things like that
ready bouche um the DMS is pretty big so
I think the subscribers you're gonna
want to deal with scoping in many ways
um but could you sometime somewhere
posts a URL for those of us who do run
cctlds with an ICD it's page on how to
push yeah
there's your URL I didn't realize I only
have one side left so I'll send it out
to the cie PG list a little bit with the
it's right now it's a very basic website
it just has the quick description of
what we're doing and then we have a form
that you can go and say I'm a registry
and I'd like to send data we don't have
anything like we don't have any of the
infrastructure deployed yet once we do I
will come knocking will do a question
for you actually is what's the easiest
way for you to send me data I will note
that and set up instructions Thank You
Lucille in responding to your question
about setting up nonprofits that's
actually a relatively long and
heavyweight process have you looked at
the Linux Foundation sponsored projects
we have not I you might want to do that
they they take a lot of the pain out of
it and those things like let's encrypt
so you might be a good fit for them okay
keep that in mind thank you any other
questions I'm here all week if you want
to get trained later
we're down to just the last official
presenter oh yeah where are your slides
I know you did I sure did it wait a
minute so yeah what we needed you
instead of Randy where we can do Randy
than you Oh Randy Europe I'll figure
this out while we do that
miss Lehman gallery speaking so hi I'm
Randy from a J researching from our
kissing um how many people here remember
in mid-april DNS attack miss called sea
turtle please this is scary
this room's half DNS people come on okay
so what happened was DNS registration
systems are hierarchy and hierarchy is
as strong as its weakest link bad actors
were discovered by I think it was Cisco
talus group to be breaking links at the
ccTLD and other TLD levels and forging
and so on and so forth
no this is not a talk about the DNS but
it's a talk about the weakness of
hierarchy and we have another hierarchy
which I did spend some time in luckily
yob who invented it is now promoting it
much better than I could and I'm
relieved but that's the rpki and it is
has the same weaknesses as the DNS in
terms of a hierarchy it has the same
security model for the small deployment
of DNS which is object security as
opposed to transport security okay so if
you can break things up chain you've got
it and it has one the way it is
currently deployed it has one wonderful
additional brilliant weakness which is
all five of the registry
at the root of the registry hierarchies
are authoritative for the route that is
as if d dot de was also authoritative
for dot all five are IRS claimed
authority over 0/0 this is brilliant
okay in the security universe
the question isn't when this will be
attacked if this will be attacked it is
when this will be attacked okay we're
starting more and more thank you very
much for the people who are deploying
and for people like you who are putting
a lot of effort between in the getting
deployment out there we need to get the
security of the system and the
operational reliability cleaned up
before the disasters happen not after
the first disaster happens and it will
happen so some of the things we can do
are pretty obvious and getting the
registries not to be authoritative for
0/0 it's just one small step rudiger are
you ready to leak to the mine why didn't
we talk about this two years ago because
then it wasn't this way because I aren't
usually used to you being snarky
Ruettiger and I did talk about it two
years ago as his point and we didn't
succeed I'm trying to explain we tried
to talk about it from an authority angle
then and it was a bad mom it's a
security problem
it's not just an authority problem
that's it
nobody except for Ruettiger
okay okay Giovanni I found your slides I
found them but I have that shoe Brandi's
time's up
Yeah right so I'm standing here between
you and lunch but if it's already
actually for death so good morning
everybody
so this presentation is actually a work
that we did together with some
colleagues at ISI and also at the UPF
this topic that spits usually splits the
crowd the details on DNS so what
happened like we had a study last year
on IMC on details and denial of service
attacks and we saw we show how the
longer TTL protect users when there's
denial of service attacks and on the
authoritative servers and I present that
to the ops folks at this idea that I now
and they were like all right so it's
nice to know that so which details
should I use I was like oops that's a
different question I haven't looked into
that so that's what he's trying to do
here this is that has just been except
last Thursday right for publication in
IMC this year in Amsterdam um which is
perfect timing for this meeting we have
put online the submission version at
this URL if you're interested we're
gonna of course created a revised
version with the comments that we're
gonna get last week and that will follow
will be online as well now kesshun is
the cornerstone of DNS performance we
know like a 15 millisecond query
response time is real good but 1
milliseconds far better coming from a
cache hit and as I said we did a study
last year we'll look how caching protect
users from alternative service attacks
on DDoS attacks on out servers and the
thing with TTL and DNS and caching says
the DNS detail set at the zones they can
actually control cache and duration at
resolver sized site so it actually
affects latency and resilience
indirectly actually very directly and
there hasn't been a lot of evaluation on
the topic I'm just mentioned here two
studies there's some more on
paper we mentioned and no research
actually provides recommendations or in
the context of that ETF I should you use
the word considerations it's less
controversial here on which vendors are
good for TTLs because it's very it's a
very challenge it's a big challenge is
very challenge this topic to determine
what good vendors are because there are
trade-offs intrinsic trade-offs in the
choices of TTLs
short TTL allows for operation Ops teams
to change quickly services along details
with those latencies and service load so
given that and but other sort of details
is no surprise there's no consensus so
let's try to fill this gap into this
study and we break this down into three
different research questions the first
one we ask we need to know if resolvers
in practice in in the wire they're
actually parent or child centric I'm
gonna explain this in more details but
you can get some information either from
parent or child depend on how your zone
is configured and they may have
different TTL values so we wanted to be
sure who is actually in charge of the
TTL s and the second question we wanted
to know it's like how the different
parts of the fully qualified domain name
changed effective TTL life time for
example let's say you have your DNS
provider has a use a certain DNS
provider to gives you the NS records
details for a domain for an hour what
happens if you are on a record is like
two hours and how those things interact
with each other and the third question
that we address in this paper we wanted
to know right we do some background work
some in one in two to see how the
resolvers choose these details and
firmware but then we wanted to know how
actually they are used in a while how
folks are deploying that we know that
our roots are very conservative and they
have to be for resilience so they have
longer details but see the ends on the
other hand they usually have shorter
details because they want to change
things very quickly in our grow here she
provides recommendations or
considerations and choosing those values
so let's start here the first questions
resolver centricity like if you let me
see let me get let's get
one TLD that's al from Chile if would if
you would ask for the NS record of that
CL phone one other root servers I just
speak a word here but it doesn't matter
kiss all the same if you ask for the NS
record you're gonna get a response that
say is that with a detail of this value
here which is like two days and they
don't within that response that value
would come in this alternative section
authorities section part of the response
now you can also ask for the same
question and type instead of the roots
you can ask for directly to the
authoritative surveillance itself aid
that Nicosia one of them and then you're
gonna get the same answer but with a
different detail here or one hour and
that's the child value so you see
there's a difference in here for two
days in one hour and this one they the
response actually of this one comes
actually as this an authoritative answer
and comes within the answer field of
their response so it's quite a confusing
on DNS like a DNS response may have up
to three parts answer authority and
additional so that's why this one here
comes in the answer and it has even a
flag it just says that is actually the
real authoritative so we have like two
different choices there's an RFC to say
that they should resolve should trust
this one but do you know how resolvers
are in the wild there's a lot of
resolvers different versions of code you
cannot be really one person sure if you
can obey to that so to investigate that
we chose that your UI which is from
Uruguay why because well at the roots as
every single TLD they had a detail in
today's but the time of this analysis
they had an NS record TTL with a child
of 300 seconds in a record for 120
seconds so this vendors are very nice
video sorry for my experiments are very
nice but there but not for operations
they changed I let me get to that later
they change those values but for if
you're losing ripe Atlas that which I
use all the time it takes guys phone
right and those again to for this
platform which is amazing if you use it
all the time and if you usually would
measure every 10 minutes so if you run
queries tools those
records every 10 minutes every time as
you do it you know you get ahead get
against code cache because it gonna be
expired by then now so we did a bunch of
measurements I'm gonna cover two of them
here the rest is in the paper we query
for NS queries for NS records for that
year by the a record with one of those
rating themselves for Uruguay and it
just asked the probes which were like
roughly 15,000 of them 16,000 to ask
their local resolver to get those
records we don't know and we don't know
where the gonna kid could be coming from
and that's exactly what we want to know
so how we want to know how do you know
if the answers are actually the results
are getting the answers from the parents
are from the child we just analyze the
distribution of the details that come
back so remember that at the parent the
root sets the TTL their trade data for
any TLD to two days but you see here the
CDF we see here to let's say 60% or
there's a huge spike here that most
queries but for the a record they come
back with a TTL of two hundred twenty
seconds meaning that most resolvers are
actually trusting the child value not
one set by the roots and the same
applies to the NS record so what we see
here it's that most reserves I child
sank with centric preferring the details
of the authoritative answers and as
should be there's an RFC for that 2181
I'm not sure filters one of the outers
here in the list I think is brandy is
one of those maybe in section five for
that one they specified this order that
they should have just records so with
the to order experiments I'm not gonna
cover because it's kind of a repetition
but we need to double check that and we
use we say I said well let's use another
domain name that's using Google calm
because those are TLD so maybe things
will be different but no those results
are the same and we analyzed passive
data and then I know as well
so most resolvers I child-centric and I
think that's a good thing because that
gives the power to the whoever actually
all the domains enough the parent now
second question how different parts of
the fully qualified domain name
change detail lifetime how look how long
he gets in caching uh so let me explain
this is a little more tricky but let's
let me try to break this down so we we
have this case domain cache test of math
we use for testing and I create a
subsonic outs of that cache test net and
I configure this domain in two different
scenarios the first one we use as the NS
record for sublet cache test that net I
used this name server and the second
scenario out of bailiwick we use
dishonor 1 in Bailey week out of beta
wicket for enough meaner in beta week
means that your name servers is under
the same zone in this case of the cache
test of Nats so it's part of this and
out of beta wickets means in this is a
difference on and we set we set
intentionally to set a detail of the NS
record to be shorter than the a one hour
versus two hours and we wanted to know
what happens with the answers in the
cashy
once the NS record expires does the a is
gonna expire as well so we wanted to
know how this different components of
DNS interact to give answers to the
users so let's so that's pretty much how
it looks like our setup and the dot Nats
on that's what we have there the circuit
details and the cache test that this is
I also placed a time net this one's here
one hour and an hour and in our zone
that we actually take care of we set the
NS to one hour the a record to two hours
and the trick is we start the
measurements every 10 minutes with ripe
again 15,000 vantage points and at time
equals to 9 we read direct we just
remember our authoritative nameserver
and in this way and we configured a new
server to give you a different answer
why I'm doing this fame because I wanted
to know later where the answer came from
if it's the new or the old because
that's the thing I wanted to evaluate if
they went to the if they're respecting
the TTL or not and I actually asked my
reservoir should ask quad-a queries they
don't matter but like oh they're not
that not asking directly those records I
me asking records at under that tree and
I use those vantage points to write
office so these are the two figures the
first one here is for
in Bailiwick experiment this one is for
auto bailiwick we see let me start here
every bar here it shows a time being of
10 minutes and what we do in both
figures at that 10 the time equals to 0
from 0 to 10 we allow other probes to
ask for this quad a query and other
answers comes from the original server
that's the ones configuring this honor I
think is fine both cases here at time
equals to 9 when you see this arrow here
in both cases we're in number the
authoritative nameserver
and we see what happens so for this time
period here this color here in both
figures we see the same behavior what is
that
people that knew they're having cash the
values of these previous records they
still keep on going that because both of
them are still valid both a and ns so
nothing really new here people that
didn't know about that they go to the
new server because that's the one that's
currently available now that's when it
gets interesting here here only the TTL
of the NS record expires because they
had to detail when one hour so once an
expires a resolver has to refetch again
that information and we see here for the
in bailiwick experiment most queries are
coming actually from a new server but a
very different scenario here from the
out of beta week and most clear answers
come actually from the old servers so
what is actually going on in both cases
the a records still in theory is a still
valid in cache so what is actually going
on and after that some of them have to
both expire in the second error here
some of them will keep going to the
original this is a stick resolvers these
are could also be sticky but I have to
drill down this once because this is
very surprising for me by the way but
it's just I don't think all of them are
sticky but the difference is like and
that's important thing here
once your NS record expires and a
resolver is gonna get that this is just
an example from in bailiwick
configuration if your reserve your
reserve is gonna give this answer to you
but they also can include the glues here
if your though in this way even though
you had an NS record you which it has a
duration of two hours just by ask
in the aim bailiwick configuration gonna
get also the glues so the resume is
gonna get that information is gonna be
data cache or try to figure out where
this answer is located at the date later
but if it is out of bailiwick
you don't get that you just get
attractive answer answer so what matters
in here is that's like most recovers
would trust cached a records on servant
from different zones for auto bailiwick
scenario so the independence of the
records actually depends on how your
system is configure your zone it is out
of a tweeker of in bailiwick and if he's
in bed wake is if one answer or never
the NS expires is in a force you're a
also to expires okay so now let's move
to the third research question how
people use details in the wild so we
just like got a bunch of hit lists the
public of popular lists I know they're
biased but we're not interested we're
interested like in a big picture where
they have and we also use entire
Grinnell's on ccTLD and other field is
available in the root zone and you're
gonna retrieve in retrieve like TT else
for NS a quad a and Max and DNS KITT
KITT sorry and we focus only on child
TTL values why because we found out the
most resolvers i child-centric and and
that's the latch there was some
discussions of our operators so we see
here on this first line on response to
see the number of domains that responded
and the first thing we fought we they
can catch the first lesson from this
table you can see is that most of the
domains except for the root zone they
are only using out of bailiwick name
servers they alternative name servers so
we should like you have like example.com
your name server would be example and as
that example that net so most of them 95
nine percent in a both not on the routes
not other routes their routes a lot of
them have mixed set up or in bailiwick
one way
it's like rough some of them are only in
avail week and I have here two figures
of the CDF the distributions of
TTL records for different zones so the
way to read this is for example the root
and s records here from the child you
see like roughly less than 10% that
within 24 hours but if you look at the
other zones
it's like 40% have a TTL that just is
like a smaller than one day for the
other zones here for the NS record and
so that means that the roots is more
conservative more people are having
longer 2t LZ r which is what we found
but if you look at that rake a records
you see the figures little shifted to
the left I'm just gonna move back and
forth for you to see that it's because
the TTL typically of the a records are
shorter for the same domain than the NS
records themselves so that's what
they're trying to see here how people
actually deploy those values and
umbrella it's a list and I think it is
the only one in our list that not
doesn't only have like second-level
domain information they have like fully
qualified and have a lot of system CDN
names that they have like many parts and
those look like CDN domains they tend to
be very short-lived some of them use
like only for one time signaling and
that's why I see the umbrella list here
having way short details and the rest
like 60% a you have less than 10 minutes
which is like a lot now we found we so
then we look at this and now I mean if I
have to choose I like a look first look
in the TLDs
we need found we found a 34 of them had
a TTL for the NS record which was under
half an hour and one or 22 one or two
hours on the child delegation and we
contacted ATC T of this on this matter
and six responded so three of them did
not consider this question before you
said it was intentional that you were
changing infrastructure they want to
keep it low TTL values because if the
world problems would it would ease it to
reshuffle reroute stuff and one said it
was the way they got it from the client
because they are just an operator for
this Tod and they keep that way and the
cool figure after them certification we
found that 3 T of these actually
increases the TTL of their
any records because they were not aware
of that and that that's was like I
didn't expect that to happen but there
were folks having attorneys I mean I'm
gonna get it one case here of your why
yeah I'm sorry
it's something oh yeah honey it's not
passing nope Chris can help me on here
measure with I think the next no here's
fine or should be fine now can move
forward next one next one yeah
next one 22 it's not working maybe you
could open outside the browser
oh all right
oh yeah that one yes 22 probably has a
CDF in so if we have a problem can also
read from I have it here
let me just pull it for a more email so
there's
how about that yeah perfect yeah all
right no that does the trick so as I
said we know three cctlds they actually
change dirty tales of their records and
one of them was Uruguay we contacted
them and we actually asked permission to
disclose that publicly they were like
they had changed the value before in the
past and because they were doing some
infrastructure changes but then they
after that didn't change it again and
they went far for the NS that went for
300 seconds to one day so from I was
lucky that I had measured them before
they change it and one day I may I just
double check if they had changed they
had change it to one day so I measure
again I asked fifteen thousand ripe
Atlas probes to send queers and let's
see the performance that they get and
this is the CDF you see here and what we
can see instead like the median response
time for a client of right before was 28
milliseconds for all the 15,000 vantage
points for a TTL of 3600 seconds but
after that he went down to eight
milliseconds and then 75% I went down
from 180 to 80 21 milliseconds you're
shaving love like 160 milliseconds just
by changing the DT L I think that's a
great change as men of course it
requires the records to be in cash but
that shows the power of TTL here you can
actually improve a lot of response times
next let's see if it works so yeah I
yeah if you know should we probably find
a certain more figures anyways what if
it works oh it doesn't yeah well got
that that's fine yeah
so the question so just going back to
research questions a resolvers parents
are centric so just answered in Mostar
child-centric
how the different parts interact
bailiwick in pets a lot how caching
works depends on earlier domain how its
configured how are details using the
wild the Vedas are all over the place
longer and answers but then Aden Cuates
and most of the domains we see it's like
they're out of a lake max
to see if it works always obviously the
FBI wastes heavy to load that means it's
a problem let me sit me in here so high
24 it's not loading you can go to 25 is
also fine so I think the other one
probably not gonna load because there
are two figures but anyway we did an
experiment to evaluate what is like
performance impact of using longer
shorter TTLs
it's gonna be available later on the
webpage of the IPG but it's like 24
you're gonna be able to see that longer
details reduce to improve the
performance and we found out that if you
have two scenarios if you have a domain
name configured of a TTL of 60 seconds
one minute and then if you have a domain
name configured with a detail of 60
sorry one day another one with 60
seconds using any cast any case is not
gonna help you as much as caching
because caching even even though even
though caching helps a lot
it helped Cowie helps much more than any
cast if the domains cache just I'm
trying to say here and we found out that
if you use if yours longer details we
will run if you use longer detail to
observe like a reduced query loads you
nurse your server on a reduction 77% and
let's hope it works this time by 24 or
25 that we do it
yeah yeah so that yeah that one so you
see here that one that's exactly what I
said before on this figure here on the
left you see the red color we show the
detail of the domain of for the bright
probes for towards one authoritative
nameserver in unique a single location
and you see here the curve and if you
use a detail change that record and run
in the same unicast for a server that
actually has a TTL for just any TTL to
one day you see the performance improves
a lot so here you know you would see
like 60% of the people there under 15
milliseconds if they use a detail of one
day but if the user to TL of one minutes
is there roughly around 60 milliseconds
in any case rerun this on any cast we
put the same zone we put on route 53
with a TTL of one minute and my question
was like alright let's see how much
anycast benefits the users and compares
to a longer TTL maybe I have a big
anycast Network I don't care about the
tails anymore but for the point of view
of performance you see here that any
cast does improve that much for people
of we which are very close it grows
longer here for people that are both 50
dead where you actually start to see the
difference but caching helps that helps
more if the domain is cached of course
then any cast and that's a lesson here
for operators next if it works
yeah Jerry those figures in PDF and they
tend to have a lot of data point
sometimes it become heavy let's see
oh yeah he's not working
yay
yes so reasons for longer in shorter
detail so longer TT our labels longer
caching which means faster responses
lower DNS traffic to authoritative
server more robustness towards to
denying service attacks shark action on
the other hand supports operational
changes it's like faster for you to
change stuff can help in case you use
like DNS phase response to those systems
mitigation it can cope better DNS base
load balancing so the takeaway here is
like fergan ization should like wait and
this trade-offs here to find a good
balance next so recommendations are
considerations that we knew there's no
single optimal TTL for our users but for
general users longer details hours or
like even a day if you will a great like
even like 440 LG's as well the exception
is if you're if you're running dns-based
DDoS protection servers so that we would
like to have like a short it also allows
you to quickly configure your service
but feels like only BGP Bay's you don't
care about that a and quota a records an
NS relationship for out of bailiwick the
records are caching the family so we
don't really care about the details like
but if in there and made a wiki we
recommend to set it CEO of the a and
quad a should be shorter or equal to the
NS and location of those records as well
at least you should have one preferably
one at least out of beta week name
server in case the zone becomes
unreachable next conclusions so details
in DNS or a complex topic we all know
that we carry out a bunch of careful
design experiments to to factor how to
figure out how those factors interact we
show that in the wild there's a little
consensus on how to TL values are used
and what I really liked about this paper
like the discussion of the Ops teams for
some sissies here this actually led to
improve a user's experience and in short
longer to TL so if you can't do that
just do it and
this is also a very good time because we
have a draft now on IETF justice
messenger and we're proposing
recommendations of sorry considerations
for Dennis ups and I'm gonna represent
that on Tuesday and consideration number
five multi TLS it's all based on this
paper now thanks any questions hi Jerry
I was just curious if you were able to
infer behavior from different software
stacks of how the caching hierarchy
interacted based upon whether or not you
got that which answer you received so
the way they did is measurements like I
use dry pathless and it can have we kind
of agnostic because I don't know which
resolvers they are and what they do I
haven't looked at the problem but I know
someone who is looking into that his
nominee Elias works with Roland
Sheffield Roland's here from University
of Twente in Holland it's actually look
into every single resolver version and
what you see what they're actually doing
because that's a different contribution
of course I was looking into the big
picture but we need to know if the
vendors are complying to the RFC yeah
yeah I was more I'm curious because I
know many years ago people use the
additional section for you know
different attack you know you know
different attack vectors and stuff to go
and poison
you know caches and stuff and so the
fact that you can tell which answer
because there's different answers in
different places you know which answer
you received yeah and whether or not you
were able to infer from from that what
the resolver stack or stacks or you are
doing from that is it so yeah it seems
like it'd be interesting in addition
that's a good point I don't look at that
yeah sure looking today I'm not sure if
my I don't think my data allows me to
explain that but I could carry all their
experiments generalize that Thanks
that's it else Thanks morning all I'm
Jeff Houston I'm with a peening as Randy
observed IEP G meetings are exclusively
for DNS and BGP and nothing else and so
Joel and and the MTU work merely
aberrations but you know you hadn't had
a BGP dos this morning so you're early
you're not allowed out into the room
until midday so you've got to have your
dose of BGP this is actually a summary
of an awful lot of data it's gonna say
2018 was last year this is oh you'll
actually see why it doesn't really
matter you know BGP is wonderful because
of all these pieces of work bgp is the
one protocol that brings the entire
internet back to you your details might
vary with my details depending on where
you sit in the routing mesh but the
whole issue about routing protocols is
you get to see a complete topology of
the entire internet not perfect but not
bad and so in some ways it gives you
some amazing insights as to what the
internet did and if you take all of
route views over all of its data which
starts around 93 in terms of hour by
hour and this is hour by hour huge
amount of data you actually see the
major events that happened in the
internet you know the great internet
boom and bust god i'll need a microscope
just around here somewhere you know it
happened big boom and bust what actually
really happened was the rise of consumer
DSL and that fueled through the early
2000s and this whole thing about
consumer based internet drove inexorable
growth
this is v4 but the remarkable thing is
about all of this that was when we
started running out that's the date at
which I Anna ran out then a pina can
write then lactic and then we seem to be
running on empty and running at an
increased rate in terms of the routing
size even though we're not pushing more
addresses into the routing system
there's something going on there and
let's have a look at it this is 24
months in detail of every pair of route
views and every pair of rights rests
bizarrely route views sees more prefixes
and oddly enough actually more addresses
than rest they have much the same growth
model but in Europe there's certainly
almost 2/8 less of fine-grained detail
in routing of address band than in route
views a number of possible reasons about
about this including perhaps the notion
of ghosts prefixes that are sitting in
the route table that withdrawn at source
but just continue to hum around in the
routing system because the withdrawal is
not Universal so yeah an oddly
divergents average growth rate much the
same and we can break it down in detail
and don't forget there are no more new
addresses
that's 2011 over there on the left and
that's when we ran out of really pushing
large amounts of address space out into
the internet yet we're growing and at
fifty two thousand prefixes per year in
the v4 space almost clockwork and what
is even Auto in some ways is that the a
s growth 34,000 prefixes per year is
clockwork so at some point I don't know
how you guys organize this as operators
you know only ten per day and once there
attend no more no more you've got to
line up tomorrow even on weekends it's
phenomenally uniform in terms of the
growth rate of AAS numbers
BGP for traffic engineering is still BGP
for traffic engineering absolutely
nothing has changed over that same
extraordinary long period the amount of
more specifics which used to be half of
the routing table is now 54 percent of
the routing table ie around half so no
matter what we say in the message about
aggregate aggregate aggregate aggregate
whoever's not listening is still not
listening in whoever it is listening was
always listening and so the basic
message has never really changed the
only thing that's really changed over
those last few years is the average size
for routing advertisement because there
are no new addresses right
address span that's being advertised the
last few years is being constant so how
do you get all those address new routing
advertisements in you advertise smaller
and smaller prefixes the average routing
size now spans 4,000 slash 32 s it used
to span around 7,000 so the average
routing element is getting more and more
finer as we progressed that's the
address span and you can see from around
2016 or so that was the amount of
address space that's being routed in the
Internet we actually haven't unleashed
the rest of the unadvertised addresses
into the network that's now relatively
constant sitting there to around 170 /a
it's being advertised and that is know
more is coming out whoever's sitting on
an advertised addresses is sitting on
them whoever was going to sell has
possibly sold I don't know but we're not
seeing more in the routing space and the
other thing that's pretty constant is
the average AAS path length and that's
going to be relatively important but
that's remain constant for ever where I
sit it's a little under 6 a SS from
where you see the actual value might be
different but it's consistency might
well be much the same unless you change
your own routing so this is another one
this is the amount of adjacencies now
the people on this list might vary
depending on where you sit where I sit I
see Huracan electric with the greatest
number of adjacencies is $6.99 but
that's me you look at yours you might
find a different one but what you will
find is around 9 to 10 a s's have an
extraordinary large number of
adjacencies number of neighbors more
than a thousand about 2,000 or so have
around you know 10 or more adjacencies
and everyone else is out on the edge one
or two adjacencies so that it almost
looks like a power-law distribution it's
not exactly obvious who sits in the top
slot as a global constant because I
don't think it is it depends on where
you are but that shape is the same no
matter where you are so the Internet is
very heavily not even a star network
it's a dense black hole kind of network
we're a very small number of foe
do the bulk of the transit routing and
everyone else just attaches at the end
and everyone wants to get as close as
possible to those magic 10 right there
is no long AS path vectors flying around
as sort of an industry norm it's not so
this is why the actual date doesn't
matter
nothing's change you know the growth
plots it's just business as usual the
number of entries is reached you know a
magic three-quarters of a million and
it's keeping on growing at much the same
rate 52,000 entries a year 34,000 is is
a year and quite frankly the way we're
doing this shorter and shorter prefixes
but exactly the same topology so what
about address exhaustion well you know
Erin ran out just really ran out
everything's going to go in about May
next year like Nick late this year ap
Nick and right both have these last
slash eight policies you know dribbling
it out AP Nick late 2020 maybe if they
change their policies and I think they
have to a slash 23 or something it might
last a bit longer but effectively all
that's left is sort of dribbling little
bits and pieces so what's driving growth
right now in v4 is it all transfers of
these last slash eights the factor or is
it leasing an address recovery what if
you take a snapshot of the routing
system at the start of the year and a
snapshot at the end of the year and
eliminated everything that's in both
tables so the new staff you look out and
say when was that allocated so what
appeared through the year and when did
the registries claim they gab give it
out in 2010 80 percent of all the
addresses we saw in the routing table at
the end of the year were allocated
within 12 months before when they first
appeared so in other words you got an
address you routed it and that was the
major source of entries into the routing
system this is every year since then and
what you notice is it's a very sort of
similar curve but it keeps on dropping
so last year only 20% of all the new
addresses I saw in the routing system
were actually allocated or assigned by
an RA are in the last 12 months
which kind of figures what isn't quite
so obvious is that almost half are
really really old really old more than
20 years so this is almost predates the
RIR system this is getting into legacy
space and what's happened in the
intervening period is more and more of
the legatus from that legacy space
relatively is bleeding back into the
internet and the amount of sort of
transfer and trading she hasn't changed
a lot this is the major factor of what's
driving new addresses into the internet
and I can look at that in a bit more
detail
but looking at the total amount of
addresses that are marked as being out
there the amount that's advertised and
the amount that the RI hours are saying
is out there but I can't seem in the
routing system so that's that
unadvertised address space blown up and
again this gets interesting addresses we
had 50 slash eights that weren't in the
routing system we now have 48 so this
whole idea that transfers and trading
would unleash a huge amount of address
space that was otherwise dormant isn't
supported by the facts and in fact the
last 12 months were even more amazing
that the amount of unadvertised
addresses actually rose not fell and
there are a number of large transfer
deals where their end result was the
addresses that were previously
advertised to now not advertised which
again is sort of anomalous behavior so
the drawdown from the R&R pool just
under a slash eight the change in the
unadvertised and advertise place though
much much higher that's the text yeah
you've had a question Julie I can't
speak to the details of any particular
transfer but I would observe that one of
the things that people tend to require
when they when they do transfer them is
that the previous prefix announcements
go away
so that actually means that some
existing advertisement advertisements
have gone away that I know of
specifically prior to the address base
being transferred this is kind of bears
out with what we see too and the
predominant factor we see in the
movement of addresses is towards various
forms of CD ends and cloud providers and
they do go away we're probably going to
see them again at some point but in this
case the go away was more than three
months so in relatively long quarantine
period between previous use and NEX use
so we assigned some addresses from the
our our system relatively small but 2.1
/ eights actually were dropped into the
quarantine pool we'll probably see them
again a little while later and most of
that was actually heading towards the
cloud providers there so far as I can
see the biggest buyers not ISPs cloud
providers ISPs don't seem to be doing
much v6 well exponential growth for all
u v6 folk you can smile it's still
exponential it hasn't gone linear yet
this is probably for them really good
news Jared actually I had a question on
the last slide yeah these jared montz
he's from yeah yeah the speaker
identified me
thanks for Andy though so I'm still
Jared even just in case Randy forgot
yeah I'm I worked for somebody if he if
he's interested that I'm curious if
you've extrapolated out of the legacy
space when you think that will exhaust
or do you have a slide on that I don't
have a slide on it but right now it's
impossible to create a model that says
that exhausts if you look at that trend
where there was a slight downward curve
healed back up again signal-to-noise
kind of says we're going to sit between
45 and 50 for an awfully long time and
the stats aren't draining it now I don't
understand the market signals out there
you know I I was sitting there going at
20 bucks it's a steal wait till it hits
a thousand and I'm still waiting right
and maybe all these folks away
until it hits a thousand I don't know I
don't know if it's a price based thing a
logistic thing they don't even know they
own it but you know there's no clear
model of when that runs out I'm still
Randy but occasionally I try to have
manners um two things one is I'm aware
of ISPs purchasing address space from
customers legacy space from customers
and putting it in their back pocket for
next year's customers in non small
amounts I'm not talking slash eights but
I'm talking 16 the second thing is I
just had a little trouble with your
unrouted and legacy space doesn't exist
it's that some of your terminology there
seemed a little extreme but did the
motion what's interesting is I think
what we're seeing is a motion from stuff
coming from the our IRS to stuff coming
from existing holders and if I were in
our IR I'd be very happy that I chose a
rental model instead of a sale model
I'll go back to this graph which is I
think what you're referring to and this
relatively large pool of addresses that
appeared in the routing system that
weren't there at the start of the year
whose original allocation age was a long
time ago and then in some cases
predating the our IRS and the
observation is just that number is
increasing you know the percent each
year gets bigger where we're mining
ancient coal right this is not recent
energy it's a long time ago we're good
at this yo name is your person adopts I
was wondering if when you present us a
similar update in two thousand twenty
twenty about the 2019 day
if you can also incorporate our PK
enveloped announcements in a similar
fashion as unadvertised graphs that's a
good point
times have gone into looking at bogans
you know and routing issues it makes
what I thought was a quick pack even
longer but it is useful to understand
the extent to which we understand
exactly what's in the routing system is
being valid versus wow how did that get
there yes now specifically interested we
through community effort managed to
reduce the number of envelops through
social media pressure by the polling but
there's this long till 2000 prefixes
that don't seem to move in any direction
are those not in use are those up for
SIL like who knows good question Yankee
- no it's not - the presenter part of
the chair maybe first of all I cannot
find the slides on the subs that's my
fault okay about the second one I was
surprised to see that the IPG moved back
to 2018 and it's hard for me to do even
a partial analysis in under an hour it
takes me a lot longer to pull through
this data this is an extraordinary large
amount of data yeah and then I'll move
on right okay quick question back to the
age graph when you see the spike of
really old address spaces from your
analysis is this the original owners who
are now putting this into play or poison
of the sell-off of part oh no I assume
and you might say I'm out on a plank
that's just broken behind me
I assume that the dates recorded in the
RIR registry are real and that's the
date they left the shop and when Aaron
changed the date on a transfer I write
it back again because I want to know the
date it first left the shop not the date
when they fussed around with it and
changed something
so I'm going for the allocation date
when a previously unheard
becomes in play but but in but in
particular if someone sold off part of a
transferred part of a legacy allocation
you would hope that that transfer would
be recorded so that would look Heron
recalled that with today's date but I
assign the date of the original
allocation of the /a whatever it was so
I record that as old space because it is
old space yes if s RI has the earlier
earlier one that's the one I use that's
why a lot of this stuff is very old you
know I'm curious as to the makeup of
this unadvertised space there's a lot of
rumors that the u.s. DoD is setting on a
whole bunch of space and it's a little
um I said there's a lot of rumors around
about people have squatted on it so I'm
just curious what what is yours what are
your thoughts and opinions on all of
that um the data is open you can look to
Jeff how's Jeff have you done any
analysis for these very old allocations
to see what the relationship of his path
is versus those old allocations when
they have been announced no I have not
so I haven't looked at a as path or you
know changes in the advertisements I
haven't looked for where the a s and the
addresses have been sold versus the
addresses only no I haven't looked at
that it's interesting place to look but
yeah yeah so the the two things they
think might be interesting out of that
the first one is that if the s paths
have no relationship no that potentially
implies that you know the allocations
just walking away and that this is an
allowed thing of course the second thing
I find interesting out of that based on
but some of our security friends tend to
say is that those spaces have been sort
of prime pools where hijacks are
happening and this is where cross
correlation with the rpki stuff
interesting that's a different talk I do
look at that it's a different talk I'll
take it at that we'll press on for all
uv6 vote you're waiting for this this is
where I'd got to the exponential growth
is still growing there interestingly v6
risks and route views have a very
consistent view now the this is a recent
routing table it's only a you know a
decade or so old in in reality there are
fewer ghosts and one of the issue is to
what extent is the v4 table full of
prefixes that are actually unadvertised
but withdrawals haven't fully permeated
through the entire system and no one's
going to permeate a second gratuitous
withdrawal and the fact that this is
more concise and tighter the written
route view see exactly the same picture
is interesting but more than that I
don't know ghost-hunting is extremely
difficult
the routing indicators what was at fifty
two thousand a year in v4 15,000 a year
in v6 3400 asns in V 4 mm in v6 so that
growth curve is slightly higher than
linear
so v6 is certainly accelerating and
growth faster than B for more specifics
one third of the routing table
predominantly 48
if you are filtering on 32 or 35 s you
wouldn't see an awful lot of v6 so more
specifics at the 48 level and also quite
a lot of 64 s where I sit yeah your
routers are going to melt one day take
up a lot of the routing table and the
average routing size is now sitting at
around a 32 so if you're filtering in a
32 again you're going to miss a lot out
of here so average size is getting
smaller much the same as before I've had
to resort to a log scale because v6 is
crazy advertised address span it's
linear in a log scale
remember maths if it's linear in a log
scale that means in a normal scale it
would be exponential but I couldn't get
it on a graph so that means it's growing
and it's growing at an exponential rate
take my word for it the interconnection
in v6 is weird and I suspect
this is a relatively long baseline it's
the slow decline of the v6 tunnel
overlay Network and the increasing use
of native connections actually means
that this is behaving the way we would
like it to behave you're actually seeing
something closer to the underlying
topology the fact that it's still noisy
says here still more work to do
and part of the reason I think why
Huracan is that there is Huracan did the
whole bunch of v6 tunnel so again your
view will differ depending on where you
are the v4 shaped v6 shaping
connectivity exactly the same small
number of players right in the middle in
this case only two AAS numbers from
where I sit have enormous numbers of
adjacencies you will probably see a
different number from where you sit and
you might even see different players
there it's all relative
so overall it's growing what to expect
well some projections this is V for
daily growth rates 140 routes a day
52,000 a year you should prepare within
two years for up to you know a million
entries or so despite address exhaustion
despite everything there's no reason to
suggest that's going into a logistic
curve so if you're planning on fib size
and if you really want to stuff all your
routes into a fib if that's what you
want to do you're going to just have to
grow at this kind of size there's the
only other way of doing it is don't put
all your routes in the FIB yeah small
comments on the predictions as operators
we agreed that's either people need to
deploy RPK original edition or we will
be aggregate them 2/24 to protect
ourselves so there may be some swinging
later on let's hope that doesn't inspire
this could get really fascinating
because these are starting to get big
numbers even for big iron out there
the v6 daily growth rates it's not
linear it's exponential so those
predictions get to be scary because
they're 128 bits long
so at Alinea you kind of go yawn but v6
is not growing in a linear rate it's
growing exponentially we can expect and
within five years quarter of a million
128 bit entries in the FIB so it starts
to get significant so in absolute terms
v6 table is rocketing along
it'll be about the same footprint in
feed memory in about five years time the
same footprint now as long as you're
prepared to do this the internet will
keep on running BGP I'm like there's
nothing intrinsically wrong with BGP
scaling profitable properties it's going
just fine but if you don't want that
size you've got to think long and hard
about how you want around the other part
of this is the performance of BGP which
is the level of updates this is where
odd things happen in BGP that none of us
can understand this is the number of
prefixes in v4 this is the number of
updates in v4 this is the number of
withdrawals in v4 the number of
withdrawals per day is constant riddle
me that one with more people more
Brownian motion more noise more random
actors more there's more that more
withdrawals no no withdrawals are a
different thing I don't understand
roughly what is that number 10,000 a
year
10,000 per day constantly no matter
where I look I see a very similar number
but the one thing about this is that it
does have a relationship to convergence
performance Randy Randy um those two
that many of the announcements create
implicit withdrawals so the explicit
withdrawals are not necessary many of
the announcements Korea implicit
withdrawals yes
but why it's ten thousand why does it
grow even the updates grow slowly
whereas withdrawals the number of
explicit withdrawals kind of because
those updates have the implicit
withdraws okay okay maybe it only ever
takes an average of two updates for a
prefix to converge to its new state
whether its withdrawal or a new path on
average two updates on average it's been
the same since 2000
or even earlier it converges at the same
speed and because of MRI intervals that
number actually translates to just
around 50 seconds so on average around
50 seconds whatever state it was going
to now stays in that state for at least
a minute I think was the way I'd timed
that so it remains stable after that
point more than two MRI intervals and
that's been the same for ever this is
viewed no this is viewed from 1:30 1:07
to I had a different graph that did all
of route views all of the time but it
does take a lot of compute it's the same
property it's exactly the same property
because it's actually based on average
AAS path length because what you're
looking at is there's a disturbance in
the force it has to propagate a longer
convergence time actually means a longer
path to propagate through because you
always like connecting into the core
updates happen really quickly so into
the core back out again you're done so
this is why it's relatively constant as
far as I can see Jeff has so I think
your observations are correct at the
little cautious about tying it in memory
I type the timers most people don't
necessarily really have those for real
but queuing artifacts will look like
that well if MRI has been as long slow
decline whatever has replaced it has a
very similar observed behavior or
property I think what you're going to
see especially with your prior slide
with amount of HP update noise just
simply the link that something is going
to be in a queue tends to cause that to
happen so when you have a fair amount of
stuff churning around you get a lot of
convergence no niceties as a side-effect
of that where you actually get the
pathological stuff is when you have
short queues okay is where it's really
good that is an amazing thing like grown
by an order of 10 but convergence is
much the same so if you're worried about
v4 update performance in BGP don't
bother
and whether it's M right or whether it's
Q
just suggests the underlying observation
is the system is actually quite stable
from where I sit v6 is entirely not that
and I'm always been wondering to what
extent it's me and to what extent others
see this when I look further afield I
still see large amounts of operational
instability in routing updates bizarre
the number withdrawals are still low but
it's more variable the number of updates
is unbounded it just seems at some times
some routers is going to catatonic
update announcement systems a little
earlier and never stop convergence
performance as a result is all over the
shop there's no true average that
maintains from day to day to the amount
of updates that converge and nor is
there any real consistency in time now
whether this is the impact of tunnels
close in to the call or some other
impact there is something really
different in BGP carrying v6 and BGP
carrying v4 and the suspicion is it's
something to do with topology and the
suspicion is Jeff's nods if shaking his
head to say no or something to do with
overlays and tunnels and tunnel behavior
and if there's another explanation
someone should enlighten me because I'm
not enlightened Jeff has made a joke a
partial joke and made the Doug just too
much cargo in the system and I wish I
was joking absolutely much Kroger in the
system there's there's unfortunately
some interesting artifacts some of the
older trees routing software that was
out about and it causes that a huge
amount of noise in the system when I was
doing work some number of years ago for
you know the four byte a s transition
and stuff we found that there is
significant meta stable routing updates
going around and it was showing up
because it was incorrect no for by
transition code and a bit of chasing
down since they ended up being a
customer I had a little bit of
visibility and at the time was much old
cargo boxes so there's just literally I
think a lot of this noise is from the
fact that a lot of v6 is being done know
via software routing and a lot of it's
being done across tunnels that you're
saying and a lot of the things that are
plugging those things together at the
moment
hopefully decreasing is a bunch of older
routing stacks that need work well the
good news is but it's taking a long time
to get there yes and well I think that
partially that what you're seeing here
is also your observation about these
being over tunnels as we get them more
and more native v6 connectivity and the
tunnels go away
people are shipping their routes across
actual routers which tend to actually be
a little more stable versus over the
things that are problematic okay thank
you
Randy motion
um many years ago some Australian nut
said that v6 performance absolutely
sucks due to tunnels and crazy peering
agreements and so on and so forth but
that as more money started real resting
on v6 this will get fixed for to get
fixed those people playing in the game
would benefit from even more analysis so
we know what to fix I think you know
finally people are coming to the
conclusion that tunnels are is evil as
gnats but I think the other Jeff's is
saying that weak software it's a problem
it's worth investigating this is not
acceptable as a production network we
shouldn't be worth in this and we should
understand why this is still the case
today yeah yeah Joel yeagley um yeah I
mean that certainly is historically the
case like I can remember circa 1998 the
reason our BGP implementation was
shittier was literally because it was a
different platform because the soup zero
cat 65 hundredths that we had running
the core did forward v6 at that point
and so like literally the
Cisco 7000 that was sitting in the
corner was doing the v6 overlay Network
so it's literally shittier I have
observed in the in the process of
building adjacencies in exchange points
over a long period of time that people
apply the principles of benign neglect
to their deployment of v6 peering if you
take down a v4 peer they noticed pretty
quickly
weirdly because the traffic that they
were saving a lot of money on stopped
flowing if you take down the v6 one most
of them don't notice for some time dual
stack happy.i Bibles yeah it was missing
your v6 peering with Google tends to get
a lot of notice because like the
youtubes flow over it and so this that
that property of benign neglect has been
like slowly getting pushed out of that
but it's still readily apparent in a
number of regions that I operated where
um that that the management of those
resources and the the frequency with
which they're up is demonstrably lower
than the v4 ones even even in the case
where they're running on the same
hardware well I'm happy to look deeper
and others who are interested in this
should look deeper as well certainly the
data is available yeah jhope again the
blue graph on the right side it seems to
stabilize the left side yeah is that
around February 2018 yes
that's when a number of security updates
were dispatched for quaggan based you
might well have observation of
correlation and reason I done causality
I don't know again I am curious if you
could correlate those frequencies of
updates and instability with actual
traffic and actual users behind it
had this conversation and I assume that
you were going to offer me some
resources to help me do the analysis and
we're still in that conversation because
I suspect it's still like the more users
you have behind the previous and most
abilities because the Eric I both said
people do not like this stop of their
own own complaints it's worth more
investigation Jim no matter how we cut
it we need to understand this better
that's true um do you need to run a
successive protocol to BGP I don't
understand why you would need to in
terms of is BGP failing no it's not is
it scaling well it seems to be there's
no great sort of cracks appearing and no
great huge holes in performance or even
size as long as you've got the money you
can create the hardware it will keep on
working as a protocol there might be
other reasons to go to a different
protocol but you know BGP itself is
still scaling fib size line speeds
equipment cost sets up to you guys
nothing's going to get cheaper I make
the stuff is still going to grow and as
v6 grows it's going to place more
pressure on that what you put in your
cache what you are floats up to you but
the routing space itself is going to
keep on growing as far as I can see in
both protocols so you know if you're
running this stuff understand what
you're putting in your high-speed fib
cards and manage that very carefully you
can't ignore it it's going to get more
and more critical and another thing is
gets ignored is v4 v6 partitioning in
your fehb that allocation which was
normally static in a lot of router con
things Oh 10% v6 90% v4 will not work
even today you need to look at that
balance carefully and quite frankly you
don't need to carry every router all the
time you can't just default this stuff
outwards end of rant Randi again um
one place I'd quibble is the cost of the
hardware falls radically and and it's
held up artificially by market forces
etc etc but it really my entire you know
I've been in this field for 50 something
years
those damn hardware people are just
killer they drive the cost down and down
scaling up and up and up bet on them
don't bet on the software Meredith oh
you can bet on the software bugs good
and good margin net so I'm not that
worried about router scaling I'm worried
about the market forces driving what I
pay to purchase it but maybe some people
now they're coming to questions
that's me thanks a lot thank you we're
essentially out of time see you in three
months
what and we're done