we have a very full agenda so my name is
Aaron Falk this is the hot RFC
talk series I'm happy that you all have
come this is I think the fourth or maybe
fifth time that we've run this the idea
of this session is to have a series of
introductory talks to give folks who are
doing something new in the IETF a way to
get the word out and so it's especially
good for things that cross areas or are
new to the ITF maybe coming in from the
IRT F or boss that sort of thing to just
give a very short synopsis with some
coordinates on how to get involved or
learn more if you're interested we have
about 22 talks tonight so we've got a
very full agenda still should come in
under the two-hour slots so if you've
made dinner plans I think you'll still
be able to to make them but the way that
we're going to do that is through very
strict time limits so we're using the
larger time management method and so at
the end of four minutes if the speaker
hasn't concluded you should hear this
sound
at which point I'd like everybody in the
room to start clapping and thank our
speaker very good guys have got the
right idea
now all that comes down to my ability to
push the button correctly let's see on
the material site you should find all
the slides that you're going to see
tonight as well as abstracts that
summarize the talks and include the
coordinates for finding out more
information so there's not gonna be any
time for a Q&A the it's really intended
to be something that's very concise give
you the flavor or something new move on
to the next thing I hope you find it
interesting and so Brian if you would
come up our first speaker and I'll get
your slides up
[Music]
okay wait Oh yo we only have you pressed
your button yet
okay so the on the left you see some
users on the right you see some services
on the objective of what we're talking
about here is to discuss a new way of
possibly connecting the users to
services I click - nothing happened
thank you what anyway why end-to-end IP
service is no longer a safe assumption
in the Internet they will usually be
middleboxes users want specific services
they don't want IP addresses or URLs and
I Spees want to provide some services
and they want to redirect the user to
other services that was the wrong one so
what use the service type requested on
IP address to forward packets at the
network edge we're not talking about the
core of the network abstract a service
as something called a service action
type which is a small integer indicating
the service is a very generic idea near
the user the packets are routed by the
service action type and not by the
address and of course before you to ask
the obvious question IP reach ability is
one of the available services which is
how it turns out to work backwards so
here are something examples of service
action types reach ability on ipv6 reach
ability on ipv4 discovery service
computation service a storage service
and there's a list of others in the
draft packets are in a format derived
from ipv6 this is a low-level protocol
but there's a service action type
instead of a destination address because
users don't care about destination
addresses and there are other goodies
that look like a lair violation because
actually this thing is intentionally a
lair violation there's some toy code is
probably not worth looking at more
important there is a site meeting
discussion on Wednesday morning 8:30 not
in the church but in the room called
we're also discussing other draft that
I'm going to talk about in the second
four minutes and I'm done hello it's me
again with the same with the same
co-authors this is a bit more
down-to-earth why are we talking about
this in edge deployments of IOT in
particular the physical MTU and the
bitrate Oh
in some cases extremely low that's well
known so packet size matters a lot he
edge routers the edge routers may be
constrained themselves that has other
implications besides the problem of
bandwidth and bitrate header
decompression and header compression
header decompression use resources 128
bit addresses use memory so for a
certain class advertised there is a
strong case for both reducing packet
size and reducing the header
decompression and compression overhead
what why are you doing by using shorter
addresses routing on the shorter
addresses not transmitting unnecessary
bytes and avoiding any fancy compression
decompression algorithms at the level of
processing the IP header how you define
an address length in within a domain all
addresses within the domain are assumed
to have a prefix in front of that of 128
minus n bits and there's lots of bit
bytes and headers that you can get rid
of if you think about it and we use a
flexible header encoding octet to tell
the lowest layer of software how the
header has been encoded so you might end
up with a complete ipv6 header that
consists of a low length NextEra hop
limit and a truncated destination
address because it turns out in the
right conditions all the other bits and
pieces in the header intact
any use and those are the bits that you
expect the this constrained router to
look at where six low working group on
tomorrow and same side meeting
discussion in not Adam on Wednesday the
end before we go to our next speaker I
just want to let folks know that this
session is being streamed live and
there's going to be a video available on
YouTube so if you want to point somebody
to this there'll be YouTube coordinates
and usual file
okay hello everyone today I'm
introducing a new technology called
instant congestion assessment Network so
what's a main target problem first the
traffic in real networks especially
metro network is always heavily
unbalanced although we have ecmp or you
can build such kind of technologies
surely they don't really work very well
and second the traffic is always
changing so fast and traditional traffic
engineering technology cannot adapt the
traffic in real-time so with the ICANN
technology we can provide guaranteed
networ load balance in real-time
millisecond level and as well as SLE
assurance and high availability these
actually share the same core technology
but with different purposes and for the
use case one the network loop balance we
have already implement a prototype based
on commercial hardware router and
according to our test in laboratory the
whole network throughput could be
increased up to 30 percentage which is a
ridiculous resort and the basic
principle of the IEEE content knowledge
that we used the I think controller to
calculate multiple paths between each
pair of ingress and egress router and
after that the rotors will by themselves
adjust the flows between the multiple
paths based on the continuous
measurement of the
Pass congestion seach situation this is
done in a very fast manner in
millisecond level so welcome to join the
discussion with more details in tears
and RTG GG and you can also check the
backup slides of this presentation and
please feel free to contact with me with
any questions thanks
[Applause]
hi so Adam and Bob and I are working
with various international standard
setting bodies and government agencies
on a really critical problem go next
slide yeah so it's just this a small
unmanned air vehicle can very rapidly
get close to a crowd or a piece of
critical infrastructure without being
observed on route and some public safety
person armed with only something that
he's likely to be carrying needs to be
able to quickly identify that thing is
it a friend is it a fall can we look up
its flight plan maybe can we establish
communications with its operator and
know for sure that it's the operator of
that aircraft that we're talking with
this problem of mapping a physical
location to a trustworthy identity
seemed to me related to the identifier
locator split in the internet and where
we're trying to go between a logical
location and an identity and so we're
looking at the use of hip to do this and
I'm gonna let a hip expert take the rest
of the time speaking with Stu and Adam
we've worked out value of hits as the
remote ID for UAE's it provides a
trustworthy identity to pair with
physical logical location data as you
know hits our value ipv6 addresses can
be used directly over the broadcast of
broadcast media if that's what you're
transmitting like Bluetooth Bluetooth
the five is one of the buys for this
with prove ownership using the high for
the signature full mobility and
multihoming so in case you're using
multiple files on this particular UA
we're supported you can use the hip face
IPSec for secure communication if that's
what you desire need and we can come up
to a secure registration of the full
identity bootstrap on a first come first
owned for the ID that's what's available
there but it's not exactly what's needed
for this case there's some work needs to
be done the original design of hip
talked about hierarchical hips I've done
a draft on this since then and because
of ownership and other registry issues
hierarchal hits would definitely be a
value for this we need to have an
expanded registration process of what's
in the current documents in terms of a
federated registrated registration
authorities to tie in the various
metadata the actual physical location
and ownership and other information
about the device some of the new crypto
support which is out there taking
advantage of seaboard where we're
appropriate and since they keep on in
the work talking oh look at hip as a
whole Olaf method that's we've seen so
far there would be other work to be
determined as we go through this process
but we feel that this is a very good fit
of technology and a requirement
situation and we have a sign meeting
scheduled for tomorrow afternoon during
the PM 3 timeslot and it's in room C 2
for our side meeting and there's a
mailing list that's right thing ends
main list TM - our ID at IETF Court
which is just set up today
[Applause]
for the folks in the back there are a
few seats in the front and a few seats
over against the wall over there if you
are trying to get in and
hello Sharon from NexStar
Sharon from the X I want to talk to you
about a cool problem and RFC draft that
solves it it has to do with the sharing
of physical information of a on the road
between cars and it makes use of a grid
of the earth actually gonna go rid of
the earth called h3 and an overlay
network which can make those tiles of
the earth addressable called Lisp so
just as a background on the problem we
distribute hundreds or thousands of
cameras each week to drivers for them to
drive around they are paired with their
phones they do it because of insurance
in motivations and the insurers want
them to do that but as a result we
actually have tens of thousands of eyes
crawling the physical space and the
public domain in every major US city and
because of the pairing to the phone it's
not just cameras they actually
understand what they see with the eye
and they are connected using a network
so when we want all these mobility
client agents roaming the streets to
communicate what they see the connected
car industry had two options for us one
is the offline network tell us about
like a stop sign that fell or started by
a tree or construction zone which is in
permeate our of permit but it doesn't
tell you if that construction cone is
generating problems right now or if that
traffic sign is okay but the traffic
light is out right now so there is a
real-time Network option mostly for
safety and but that's a peer-to-peer
network so for example to safety
situations not for something that I'm
about to hit right now but something
which let's say I am
driving 100 kilometres an hour to a
pileup or to a slowdown I'm turning a
corner in a junction in a city to a
double parked vehicle an hour unloading
vehicle a tough situation for me to
negotiate out of and the cross traffic
sees it clearly there is no clear way
for me to get that information if the
car that the last car just drove away
three seconds ago and one get the
information or may get multiple and
conflicting informations from cars I
don't know and I don't want to know so
the solution is to pack up all these
annotations as you drive in and assign
it to a tile that tile has a ID based on
the location in the earth but also its
transit to an eID
which is a lisp address which is now
make it something I can send packets to
this addressing scheme allows me to
share information between let's say
mobility car going here mobility car
going there these cars is this guy cars
future and vice versa they can publish
and subscribe to it in tests we were
able to communicate a red light bridge
in other four milliseconds a bit of a
lab conditions between a camera on the
junctions and all the cars approaching
and affected by it so if you're
interested it's discussed in the list
working group tomorrow and happy to have
more participants
[Applause]
hi I'm Ronnie Evan and on this car I'll
present the open congestion control
architecture with network operation for
our DMA fabric the motivation for this
work is for data center that the high
link speeds that are making network
transfer complete faster in fewer out
--'tis short data burst require low
latency while longer data transfer
requires high throughput so these are
two requirement there the RTA is the
common protocol in data center network
however the congestion control is not
optimized for different usage and lack
of interoperability allowing for
flexibility in running an optimized
congestion method in the network
interface card in having fast congestion
notification to the sender can improve
the our DMA they have a trench transfer
it's common in the deficit and network
the TCP traffic is mixed with the our
DMA traffic and the causes conflicts
between priorities between them and what
we're saying is there a better method
that could solve the problems mentioned
above while addressing interoperability
so that our DMA traffic can be treated
more efficiently so we have two
documents on the open control
architectures the requirement document
and the architectural document the
requirement discussed the problems of
the currently mode direct memory access
fabric congestion and link technology
and the requirement for better
performance and the architecture
proposed an open control architecture of
host networks for the high-performance
our DMA fabric to provide better
congestion and the link for HPC and
distributed storage application the
architecture itself is seen in this
slide there are there's the center the
reaction point and then the receiver is
the notification point but the switch
can serve bosses the congestion point
that also
the congestion point but also can
provide identification
so there's can be a net only control
channel and of course they Nick - Nick
control channel that will provide the
information to allow the sender to
respond better and faster so the design
configuration is provide better
information about the congestion stay
stay to the sender faster and more
accurate from the network and notify the
sender the reaction point from their
network support it can support proactive
response from the notification point and
support our DMA transport different our
deviate transport so this what we are
talking about is something that would be
transport agnostic and support multiplex
the traffic of our DMA and TCP we did
some already some experimental tests and
we are having a side meeting on tomorrow
in Auto damn room and of course if you
want to discuss it with me this is my
coordinates thank you
[Applause]
hi I'm Paul Congdon and if we had
coordinated better I probably would have
gone just before Ronnie because this is
very similar topic but I'm kind of
approaching it from a little bit of a
more higher level not a specific
solution Ronnie has some some drafts
that that describe that solution someone
talked about strat strategies to
dramatically improve congestion control
and high performance data centers so
first of all data center congestion is
different than the internet congestion I
think we all know that's a few handful
of transactions can cause a lot coming
in from the web can cause a lot of
activity inside a data center so data
centers have much different environment
there's different bandwidth delay the
switches are implemented different and
small buffers high speed links you know
then different Internet routers there's
a lot more homogeneity in the network
design it's not so random the traffic is
very concentrated servers and storage
are all in close proximity and there's a
lot of different the traffic profiles
are kind of well-known highly
coordinated correlated and typically
they're managed with a lot fewer people
under a single management domain so all
this means that these data center
congesting the environment in which it
runs is much different than the internet
and we know we do internet standards
here but but we also do have focused on
data center standards DC TCP as an
example so the data center needs low
latency low overhead high efficiency and
high throughput so one thing the data
center kind of has in common with the
Internet is there's this trend to do
more over UDP something like we've seen
a lot of activity with quic for example
so what if we you know could do
something that that was more sort of
quick like but not quick you know as
heavy perhaps for specific for the data
center and maybe we did something that
was Datagram congestion control like but
again focused on the congestion problems
of the Internet of the data center it
would need to be Hardware off loadable
but maybe with less emphasis on security
and crypto and all the threading kind of
stuff that
have it would need to be really common
congestion control as described in the
previous talk and ideally would need to
have the network visibility marking and
signaling abilities from the network
itself so the ITF has this expertise so
let's leverage and not leave it to the
UDP application riders let's see if we
can do something we know datacenter
congestion is different the authors of
these papers have done a lot of work on
congestion trees so there's kind of two
types you know in network and in
congestion and it's constantly moving
moving around in cast or in network
we've got solutions today such as ecmp
ecn even even in a lossless environment
ecn with priority flow control all of
these have various pros and cons but
they're not completely addressing the
needs that we see so some ideas of
augmenting ecn with with a data center
focus for a UDP layer you know providing
more feedback from the switches in the
packet headers perhaps you know marking
delay inside packets so that we can get
really fine grain view of what's going
on being able to figure out is this
congestion we're experiencing right now
is it in network or is it in cast you
know because maybe we would take
different approaches being able to speed
up notifications to the source so they
can quench you know in a way that
addresses it and then implementing fast
mechanisms in the switch to respond
immediately so so what like to do is
discuss the technical approach and
feasibility of these ideas in a side
meeting so we have a side meeting
tomorrow Notre Dame it's the same one
that was announced and we're also
providing remote participation for that
and then we're going to be requesting a
ETF mailing list as well so I think I
made it we also have a whole bunch of
references in this deck if you want to
read them
thank you for the folks in the back
there's room on the floor in the front
if you guys want to sit down so just
saying
Thanks hi I will represent a walk
showing that we can leverage an existing
network intelligence to build service
from Zhang Sheng in most of existing
deployment service functions even trains
are controlled by a central control
point which computable ideal placement
of virtual functions such as IDs for
your world and the flow path that goes
for them raising some program since it
creates failure and the network's
scalability issues it's oddly
interoperable with existing networks and
it under exploit existing protocols or
negative a network for instance service
function training program is mainly a
routing program because you have to
route traffic for a set of white one
between two before which in the
destination so what your purpose is to
augment classical entire entire gate for
protocol and make them a function aware
you know in order to build service
function path I will quickly remind how
integral from functions you have a
gateway which are connecting networks
sharing information and building a
network view and based on what it it
will compute
routing tables what who proposes to bind
some prefix to a specific function such
as first file an IDs allowing to use of
routing protocol to function through
total flow through functions and to use
any casings to to use the IGP matrix to
select the functions and other
consequence you have a logical network
view which is which one where you have a
for instance pink nodes which represent
a for instance a firewall and in the two
instance on the shooters will be
we'll be fun based of some matrix where
I sit for two to be instance if you're
interested in a walk where we are doing
you can come to a contentious session on
Thursday and we can discuss about that
and you can also find the sum of all we
have presented in existing conferences
different Thank You Jeffrey from
highways so the purpose of this talk is
to find the people she had the same
interests as with me too about the
theory behind the networking so to kind
of clarify the terminology theory as a
system of ideas to explain based on
general principles so ITF is quite a
unique we have many contribution from
universities and we even have a research
arm i at EF but in my personal views
there's still an gap in our networking
area as a whole so our innovation and
the design highly rely on experience I
don't find a well-defined body of
knowledge or a set of approaches that
can help us to make design choice and
understand the trade-off behind those
decisions so I'm not the only one have
this feeling so these are very
interesting paper from Jennifer works
for the Princeton Princeton University
here she coated some doubts from people
inside and outside networking community
so is networking a set of protocol
acronyms or a heap of head formats or we
are just a big a bunch of boxes of
course Jennifer defeated as though all
these questions elegantly but at the end
of the paper she also suggested that we
can make the question we ask more
precise and
the way we answer them more Legolas and
the week maybe we can not so much value
new problems over deep answers to
existing questions we need to encourage
a more thorough and complete and the
deeper research
so why IDF so in one way this theory can
help IDF to explain and predict the
outcomes from new design and facing your
problems and also it can help us for
clinical help new generation to inherit
and make their own contributions so on
the other way when IDF who can can help
so we have both rich and very successful
experience and expertise in theory we
have so many academic participants so
why now now we are facing some new
requirements such as deterministic and
bounded delay services so we may require
more theoretical analysis than before so
this is the other example in Ige's the
proposed to apply a network calculus a
kind of queueing theory to the time
sensitive networking problem so there
are several useful reference of course
this in one way is in warranty as the
mathematical foundations and to us and
on the other yes the theory of the zan
hope the semen proposed a framework long
time ago I don't think I have time to
adjust the details but if you are
interested contact us me and my friend
can Leon from China Mobile thank you
[Applause]
okay this is about software management
if you don't use these standards which
is really the entire software industry
outside networking so you you you know
every every company starts the same way
you write a little service you start
including more services to do your
function and then you learn about micro
services it becomes this and of course
you get this and of course you need a
management plan to to make sense of this
all so for each one of those little
boxes this is what you have to do today
you have to scrape log files to find out
if the Services is acting incorrectly
you have to write some tool to generate
config files deliver it bounce the
service okay sorry thanks if it has a
REST API you have to integrate with that
you find performance metrics any which
way you can and if it has a security
model you got to somehow integrate with
that so every single service you have to
do this with and if it looks like a lot
of work it is a lot of work but a lot of
companies are cheating because they're
finding recipes on the Internet to help
them get a jump start or they're only
mapping the pieces that they they think
they need before they go into deployment
and this is a problem because they find
out after deployment they forgot
something so clearly this is a lot of
work and the standards for yang Andres
conf solve this entirely with the
industry as a whole and to give you an
idea the scope of this problem puppet
labs they estimate there are now more
people in the management plane than
there are in the data plane so more
people writing software about software
than the software itself solving
problems so this is a very large problem
and so in 2015 I became aware of these
standards and wrote a implementation of
the the yang and the rest comp specs in
go I started there so I wrote a little
my first project was this bartender and
it has a Raspberry Pi and some relays
and some pumps and it's got a little
interface to make oh that so but I
didn't flip it at all in rest comp so
there's a yang model for the bartender
and you can assign a pump to a
particular liquid and
even when you make your recipe you're
going through ress Kampf
and it was really no special tools on
the JavaScript to get this to work
rest comp really is designed really well
to make it palatable to the industry as
a whole which is what his design was so
any I really like how rest comp has
different modules so if you know amazon
published a yang for alexa skill i could
add that in and all of a sudden you're
saying Alexa said make me a mai tai so
since then I've used this in lots of
different industries IOT schools malware
detection the standards work really
really well but of course that's only so
good so when we've arrived is when I can
tell say pager duty which is a system
for alerting you to say hey post grads
when there's a slow query paged me about
it and I didn't have to involve DevOps I
didn't have to program anything and this
is all possible with the standards but
none of these tools know about these
standards or implementing those so I'm
really here to talk about this this
problem in industry as a whole see if
this problem resonates with anybody
I realized ITF is concerned about
networking but there's definitely a
bigger hole and I estimate this is there
are actually 10 million developers this
this could actually help them out so and
I'm one of those because without these
standards I find using these standards
in outside networking it really doesn't
doesn't really solve the bigger problems
so like I said if this is resonates with
you reach out to me there's no working
groups on this but maybe next ITF there
could that's it
if the ITF is about anything it's about
making bringing my ties into schools hi
everyone I'm here to talk about like
aetherium improvement proposals and
there's no time for introductions we
just in jumping so as you may know or
may not a theorem is the second largest
cryptocurrency just based on the market
cap there is a possibly the number of
developers and tools that are based on
that alright the first and hold
blockchain DLTS theorem is a home for
ENS which is a theorem naming service
which they're trying to do that eat ETL
D and also do DNS SEC in the blockchain
also for EFS or D central file system
applications there are a lot of more
apps there so I'm mostly argument
looking processes here so etherium is
one of the healthiest essential dev
cycles ethan amongst the blockchain and
cryptocurrency projects or is it far
from the perfect perfect some of the
historical and challenges like the
central decentralization requires a
non-hierarchical development cycle and
it's really hard so they have this e IP
which is in a theorem improvement
proposals which was inspired by Bitcoin
improver proposals and that was inspired
by pet Python enhancement proposals
which that also in was enjoyed by IETF
request for comment and there are some
aspects of it dropped on this path we
don't know where exactly but a security
consideration section on the IP it's not
there I'm really trying to put add it
back and it's gonna be added in the next
month probably so there is some other
process this is like the process today
I'm gonna go quickly on on these and the
slides are there for more details so
after discussing in the forum's and
getting the community supports the EIP
author would add the CIP there so
security concession is missing there
we're trying to add it there and then
goes to a selected track so the track
the core track is actually the consensus
protocol and the protocol it's a really
critical one it has resulted in forks in
the network and a lot of controversy
there are some others that look ERC if
you have heard of tokens security tokens
you are c20 they're all in this track
and there are some other things so the
process itself has like four you could
say five steps
so when it gets a community support it
gets the work in progress draft and
basically they write these usually major
major and if it's a career Pete needs
implementation the basic talk about it
talks about the proof-of-concept after
that it has in the EIP number and goes
to a draft mode here the European
and further make sure the draft to have
in a way that actually makes sense and
it has some more support and after that
it goes to the last call this process
every iteration takes more than around
two weeks and it's actually the ends up
with a call like a conference call so
here mainly they talk about if there are
there any security implementations and
that needed to be checked here mainly on
test tests and it's more on a non
official one and after that if it's a
quarry IP gets accepted and all the
clients at least three of the clients
there are like four or five ATM clients
need to implement that to get that
actually in a final state if it's not
cool then it sometimes is standard it
just goes to the public to find out
state so this is overall what I just
talked about and this is the first
attempt as far as we know to visualize
this and have something to show that
this is the process usually and still
even with this process it happens on
github proposals people request
everything happens there there's this
forum if they're your magicians that
people discuss there and magicians there
for the optimization and also this is
the call this is like a chord F called
actually the decisions happen there so
why am I talking about this so I've been
involved in also our IT process we need
that our ITF people to find the gaps and
missing pieces in this and in this
process and if I modules I'm open to any
discussions and comments and this is how
you can reach me and I would be happy to
talk about anything about watching
[Applause]
hello everyone my name is chingu I'm
from Poway I'm here to discuss what's
the next step of young unite have
actually a little bit of background for
me I used to chair area same area same
in Holmes area who deliver young be the
model for era VPN and actually witnessed
the young take off and followership but
we still feel there's some problem so
that's why I bring this topic here and
so young data model get a lot of
traction actually operator began to plan
to deploy a young beta model and but the
the reason for that actually young
actually not only happy to automate as a
networker but also allow operator to
build the more agile service young
actually can model the service from the
top and also allow you to model the
collaboration of raising of the device
allow you to configure the product on
the device get a net was set hopper so
usually the young beta model you will
classify them into service layer model
and device level model but also in the
between we have resource level model
they allow you to schedule results to
meet the service requirements from the
top and also allow you to do to program
the networker actually make adapt to
network change and so right now in idea
more than 260 young a model actually has
been developed in idea and more than 50
obviously and including 80 young teen
model and we also see actually more than
100 young
working with each other that be
proceeded in night here so which have so
many young Bella model and but the the
problem actually is you know we can
reference the intact bender in the
operated test report we can see actually
that como has widely adopted it but for
young the model still an early in
adoption stages so what's the reason
behind so we see actually because the
many operate actually you know not
engaging ideal for this young data model
development actually for some operator
who already deployed these can
technology may not aware I developed
this young Tatum model even for the
operator who actually know what I do to
him but they don't know how how this
young would put together to deliver
service to fulfill the service actually
so there's a critical gap actually they
were leader that I'd have young pay the
model actually like a sufficient input
from operators so to address this
actually one of the approach a way
proposed actually we can define young
they the model framework actually to
have operator to how to integrate the
young data model in the same namespace
and so we have a chapter actually posted
in OBS technologies that will be
discussed in OBS a publishing on one
Wednesday and try we actually we work
together with operator try try to fill
this gap to help operator to provide
such guideline how to you know figure
out how even a layer model can put
together and in addition we we think you
know standard walk is not enough for
some of these you may rely more
coordination between
[Applause]
[Music]
okay I'm full hon Baker and this is the
mathematical mesh oh so internet
security is broken it's broken because
users are finding security it's just too
much effort and you can't solve that by
asking them to try harder it's broken
because applications are not solving the
real problem I mean like look at all the
data breaches their data at rest
breaches we mostly focus on transport
and we've not actually changed our
approach very much since the PGP are
days and the Pam days we're still using
the same tool box and we're still using
the same limited number of operations so
the measure dress is three core problems
device management so you can glue all
your devices together so they're worn
gestalt contact management so you can
connect all the people that you connect
to together and have access to all their
public keys on all your devices and a
secure control plane messaging which is
end-to-end secure and traffic analysis
resistant Oh wrong so it's based on the
principle of I'm using more advanced
cryptography than in Bruce Schneier book
one key cryptography is great des you
know you can do a lot with des but two
key is better because you can separate
out the roles of encryption and
decryption if one is good and two is
better why don't we try three four five
separate the roles out more and we can
do more cryptography and more
cryptography means more security yes
there's a bunch of small powerful
concepts here I can't go through these
at all but basically there's five basic
technologies here and it's a grab bag
and they're all designed to work
together but you can also use them a la
carte in your projects going to be
talking about this effects dispatched
tomorrow at 1:30 and this is the wrong
set of slides it seems a she sent in I'm
about to start releasing this so if
you've got a strong opinions on it
please talk to me before I release it
because the minute I have users I'm
going to start protecting legacy and
code if you want to change anything talk
before I release the code there's a
whole bunch of drafts and the drafts are
based on running code that comes from
the reference library so all in MIT
license all c-sharp all that good sir
and the objective here is to provide
people with kind of like a psychic learn
for cryptography if you look at the
advanced in AI that's happened over the
past ten years that happened after the
AI people made it really easy for people
to add AI into application with things
like pandas and scikit-learn so the
reference codes an attempt to do that's
the same thing for cryptography and
you've got all the same goodness of
blockchain pkcs7 PGP x.509 and so on but
in a much smaller library because if you
make all the systems use the same
unified approach you can get rid of a
lot of code I've got rid of 2/3 of the
code of the past two years so meetup so
we're going to be talking about sex
dispatch tomorrow at 1:30 please be
there or talk to me afterwards thank you
I'll upload oh and there's also going to
be podcasts explaining each part of this
on the web I'm either Luba chef and I
really want to talk to you about law
packet loss detection in encrypted
protocols I'm looking at quick alright
I'm a transport guy I love to think of
my networks as just dumb pipes but
really for them to be dumb pipes there
could be somebody inside that pipe who
is looking for leaks and can find and
page them quickly if it's senior TCP
flow in that pipe it's pretty good
she can look at sequence numbers at
numbers figure out if there is leak see
it if it's upstream downstream if she is
looking at a quick flow not as good
there is no really no bids to look at to
see if the respect loss so it's I think
it's a problem and there is a propose a
solution that uses two bits one bit is a
cube it stands for square signal it's
very simple and that's in essence 64
when you send in packet 64 of them comes
zero cubed 64 one 64 0 so forth the
other packet the other surahs a little
bit is an else for loss event a bit and
it is set when there's a special
unreported loss counter which is greater
than zero and unreported loss counter is
maintained by the sender when there is a
packet that the sender sent and depend
sender deems it lost it increments the
counter when the packet with l1 is sent
the counter is decremented so if you can
see the picture there are two packets in
red the
lost about one or tt-to one or two later
Center determined they've been lost and
it sent two packets with l1 okay how can
we use that how is it useful so
end-to-end loss is pretty simple it's
just a fraction of packets with l equals
one bits that observer observed upstream
loss is basically how many bits with a
particular Q value are missing from a
block once you have downstream and
upstream loss you can figure out when
you once you come end-to-end and
upstream loss you can figure out the
downstream loss pretty cool so it's cool
in theory but we decided to test it in
practice Akamai's implemented a scheme
based on this in our deployed servers
and we've been serving quick traffic to
some orange end users in a number of
countries for for some time and there is
data for it actually real world data not
simulator or anything else and plenty
and if you are interested I hope you are
but if you're interested if you're an
operator or have thoughts about it
please see us we'll be a here Monday
tomorrow 8:30 to 9:30 for a side meeting
and we'll talk about it in TS vwg on
Thursday that's going to be focused on
protocol details as well as privacy and
ossification risk and then on Friday
onmyoji will actually present lots and
lots of data and talk about it and of
course you can talk to us
Thanks
brought me
I'm broad and I want to talk about zero
is not must be there are reserved does
not must be zero we all know about these
common words that are used throughout
our RFC's there's a word I'd like to add
to that list and that's the word
reserved because it is interpreted
differently at times it's pretty
frequently used it's poorly documented
there's different ideas of exactly what
it means and how it's used depending on
in what context it's used this is is
become a problem when it's when when
reserved is treated this must be zero by
a receiver and some future things come
along and go that's not reserved anymore
I want to use that for something else
and somebody goes nope that must be zero
we're gonna throw that packet away it's
no good
we're repeatedly running into this
problem in protocol implementations in
software and almost anything that uses
the word reserved so I'm basically
trying to bring the idea that we might
want to clearly define this clearly
define the different contexts that it
can be used in and what it means in
those contexts if they're this is this
is gonna be a one minute talk if there's
any future discussion if people want to
try and talk about let's codify this
let's make an RFC out of it I'm
available I'll be here all week there's
my email address I've got a couple
minutes if anybody wants to throw
anything out about it right now we can
do it do I hear you what can I hear a
second on that motion should we should I
start a draft okay that's what I wanted
to hear thank you
[Applause]
hit one enter so slightly just hit one
hit enter has to quickly jump to a slide
number hello everyone my name is Stuart
Cheshire as some of you may know I'm the
creator of zero configuration networking
and in a surf discovery and what Apple
calls Bonjour I'm sure everybody knows
it's used widely in Apple products what
a lot of people don't realize is it's
now in most Linux distributions
it's used by chromecast it's on Android
and it's starting Windows 10 it's even
in Microsoft Windows anywhere in your
software that you have somewhere for a
user to type in an IP address or a host
name you can use DNS service discovery
to give them a list of options to choose
from instead if you have iPhones here
you can tap on AirPrint and you pick the
printer you want there's nowhere to type
an IP address if the thing you want
doesn't show up you fix that by fixing
the network not by typing in IP
addresses on the client devices
traditionally this is used peer-to-peer
multicast what's great about that is it
requires no infrastructure you just hook
up two laptops with an Ethernet cable no
switch they can discover each other two
phones using peer-to-peer Wi-Fi no
access points they can discover each
other services that's great for small
networks but it's inefficient on large
networks because it impacts every device
on the network even the ones you're not
talking to right now
it's slow on Wi-Fi because multicast is
sent to low rate and multicast SAR
batched with the beacon so there's high
latency it's wasteful of shared wireless
spectrum and it's unreliable because
it's not acknowledged so you have to
retransmit which makes it even more
wasteful of that precious wireless
spectrum with these slow transmissions
so we want to discover things that are
multiple hops away without flooding the
multicast and if you do this with your
iPhone today you send a multicast but
the printers not nearby we solve that by
adding a discovery proxy your device now
makes a TCP can
action by sending IP packets multiple
hops through that network
the discovery proxy can then do the
multicast on your behalf and send the
answer back you discover the printer you
can now make an end-to-end TCP
connection and use that we'd love you to
get involved you can join the DNS SD
mailing list you can check out the code
from the IETF hackathon we have an open
wrt package for this little open wrt
router in about five minutes you can add
a discovery proxy to this and have one
running on your own home network we'll
be showing this at the hack demo happy
hour tomorrow just across over there so
you can come and see it working for
yourself and of course come to our dns
SD working group meeting on thursday
thank you
[Applause]
shooting from Maui today I'm going to
introduce you one of our new work is a
application-aware ipv6 networking so
first about the motivation as internet
he involves we could say we have already
experienced Oh IP the first generation
but there are still some challenges
for example the isolated the network
Islands or the limited program program
program ability and most importantly and
the network is still on its own and
application and the network isolated at
the coupled and now we have ice our v6
we could say we are entering a new
generation all IP the second generation
and ice our v6 has its own mission and
first it is a based on ipv6 so it has
the affinity to IP so it could be much
easier to integrate the network domains
and also it has the programmability so
it has the programmer programmable
fields so you could convey more
information from the applications to the
network so in that case you could
integrate the application and the
network make them to work together so
here are the ipv6 extension hiders we
have the hop by hop and destination
options hiders and also the routing
header i sorry choose one of these so we
have the arguments views and also that
here we you we could use to convey some
information from the applications and
that are the foundations for the
application aware ipv6 all eyes are
basics networking we call it AP and 6 so
basically we are actually make use of
the ipv6 extension headers to convey
some informations from the
applications into the network so the
network could make the flying granular
traffic operations to do the for example
the resort natural resources meant to
guarantee the SLA so it could be applied
to for example the fixed mobile
broadband like the to be to see
scenarios and also the mobile broadband
and for the solution side we could have
the host side solution that is the
application directly put the information
into the ipv6 hiders all it could be the
network site solutions that is the
network edge could attack the
application and provide the information
about the application and can wing it
into the network and we are we are going
to have a side meeting on Thursday
Thursday morning and we have the agenda
you could refer refer the related drafts
we listed in the side meeting wiki okay
thank you
[Applause]
we're on the backup USB stick I don't
know why sorry okay
yep
great my name is Joseph Potvin I'm
executive director for excel rhythms
foundation some colleagues and I have
initiated a project called
an Internet of rules I'll say right away
if you think it's a terrible name that
we should not be calling what we're
doing that please let us know I'll
restrict this to the why and the what of
what we're doing I could explain how
there's running code behind this we're
doing alpha testing right now but I've
had a very interesting conversations
over the last two days as part of the
hackathon and there's lots of different
ideas about and good ideas about how to
do this next so very happy to see what
Rodney was talking about a few sessions
here ago we're actually working on the
generalization of how words like must
must not required shell and so forth
actually get deployed so if you can
imagine any IOT implementation and let's
say there's some Court decision in some
province or state and that's gonna
affect privacy rules in terms of how
data moves around from and to all sorts
of IOT devices exactly how is that new
rule going to get deployed you could
even say oh it's going to get deployed
through the equipment providers how is
even that rule expressed and say English
or or spanish going to get deployed to
the 45,000 suppliers of these IOT
devices
this affects issues in money finance
commerce tax international trade machine
control systems internet-based
networking whatever it is the gap in
this space is so huge it's hard to see
so it's hard to communicate this
sometimes because most people are
looking for little gaps this is an
enormous gap next so the problem is
enormous ly wasteful error-prone
redundancy each of you who is not from
Canada when you pay your hotel bill
right now you're actually supposed to be
zero rated on the value-added tax but
you're going to pay it and if you were
to try to claim it back on the way out
good luck to you little rules like that
come in and they were just simply not
deployable today that's tax but any of
these other domains you have
same kind of problem it requires a
domain-specific language which we've
prototyped right now and not prototype
we've actually implemented an alpha and
an optimized algorithm search we're not
dealing with if-then statements we're
dealing with given X facts con has a
context when there's an input fact for
circumstance then Zed ought to be the
case so these are just three facts next
the actual software we have deployed
begins by interacting with an API
there's a small component piece and
auxiliary piece called lichen you can
use it or not use it it's a it's a
reference implementation create your own
if you like roll your own that provides
the context FAQ in the input in fact out
to the server in the server is a
distributed set of servers with the
collection of algorithms which implement
the rules and these algorithms are
simple declarative tabular or tupple
oriented programs we deliver those back
as output facts we do not inject them we
stop at the point of delivering back the
fact there that there is a rule and
here's what it is and next please so
Excel go the domain-specific language
it's think of programming in terms of
control tables decision tables and so
forth with a few reserved words very
very minimalist it's deliberately not
turing-complete and it uses all any
standard schema when it comes to
identifying what industry it is what
what jurisdiction it is what product
type it is next please
inter Libre sorry about it I'm okay
that's the search engine and then next
slide I'm presenting in this room on
Tuesday 8:30
[Applause]
hi so I'm gonna talk a little bit about
multiple provisioning domains a term
that you've probably heard and maybe
know what it means but I think a lot of
people don't so hence the talk so the
point of this is back in the 1990s you
had a host it was probably sitting on
your desk it's connected to a network it
got DNS and IP addresses somehow from
the network and everything just worked
that was great good times times have
changed and so recently and you know
certainly in the 20 teens and even
before that it was not uncommon to have
a host connected to more than one
network typical scenarios VPN is a
classic typical scenario but a less well
less well understood scenario or is when
you have a host is connected to say a
phone for example that's connected to
your cell service provider and to a
wireless network which may have a
captive portal on it you don't want your
network service to suddenly stop because
you're connected to the captive portal
network so things get a little more
complicated when you have to deal with
use cases like this that's a typo but
anyway so anyway so so the host so if a
host looks up a service using using
using the DNS server that it got from
from network a it is and then tries to
use the answer it got on network B if
that service is actually only reachable
on network a it's gonna fail so we need
to be able to associate networks we need
to be able to associate things like DNS
servers and IP prefixes together and of
course in the 2020s things are even more
exciting this is starting now but but
you know you can see there there are
routers that you can buy that have both
a connector for your ISP and also a
cellular backup and you'd like that to
be able to work and you'd also like your
devices on the home network to be able
to distinguish between the two providers
so how do you do that
the answer is with provisioning domains
so a provisioning domain is a connect
collection of configuration information
that's known to have come from the same
source so in the previous example where
we had network a and network B
networking and network B were both
different provisioning domains and
similarly in the 2020s example where
we've got provider a and provider B
those are both also different
provisioning domains so how do we
communicate with this to the hosts in
the 2010s usually we would just notice
that we had two network interfaces and
so we would be able to set up an ad-hoc
provisioning domain we would just assume
that information that we got on an
interface a and interface information
that we got an interface B are not
interchangeable and and we would just do
that automatically without being told
that doesn't work so well if you have a
border router and you're behind the
border router and the border router is
connected to two different homes so in
that case we need something called an
explicit provisioning domain and so work
has been going on in the ITF recently to
make explicit provisioning domains
happen so the original work was done in
the myth working group we produced a
document called the multiple multiple
provisioning domain architecture which
explained the problem that I just
explained to you in quite a bit more
detail and more accuracy but didn't
actually solve it and then just recently
a number of folks in the interior
working group been working on a document
called draft end area providing domains
discovering provisioning domain names
and data so this is using an RA option
to explicitly state that this prefix and
all the information about this prefix is
in its own provisioning domain which has
this name and so that work is almost
done I'm mostly telling you about this
because I think it's really useful and
you want to know please come to intern
[Applause]
Spencer Spencer
so Spitzer Dawkins and talking a little
bit about performance implication of
path characteristics this is a Rube
Goldberg machine which actually turns
out to be a pretty good implementation
of what I think a lot of network paths
look like these days so how we got here
we did a follow on to the tcp over
satellite working group in 1997 to 2000
talking about very long RTT interaction
with slow lost recovery we I brought a
proposal for TCP over cellular to the
IETF and the ad suggested a structured
approach instead of doing TCP over foo
links Aaron and I co-chaired the pilk
working group 1999 to 2004 and we had
specific recommendations that we issued
it's BCPs most of them for specific link
characteristics and that was adopted
actually by web forum version 2 was life
was good for a while things have
probably changed since 2004
a lot of stuff is on here there's
actually probably more things that have
changed that then I didn't put on the
slide
things like CD ends and stuff like that
but you know a lot has been going on
that'd be just to pick one of them we
weren't thinking about multipath at all
we were thrilled we could get one path
to work so what I'd like to do at IETF
105 we had a side meeting and went out
at ITF one 104 in the code lounge and
that was helpful so I was going to
another one of those meetings but I've
also been told
active in the panarchy research group
and they've been thinking about path
aware networking I'd like to talk to
them about what is engineering and what
is research so what's ready for the ITF
tournament record nations for
and was not ready for the ietf to make
recommendations for independent that's
the wind energy is meeting the thing you
know so like I say the thing that I'm
saying here that I need to make pretty
clear is that I'm talking about I'm
talking about producing BCPs for
protocol designers because we still get
a lot of product we still get a lot of
proposals from people who are trying to
solve specific problems with
well-meaning ideas that the transport
community has identified problems with a
long time ago but we never write those
things down my favorite one was you know
if you read my PhD dissertation from ten
years ago you would clearly see that and
that was the best that was the best
recommendation we had I think the ITF
has done better in the past I think we
could do better hope to see you on
Wednesday morning and Thursday afternoon
[Applause]
so for those of you not keeping track
we're down to the last three talks if
you're thinking about dinner maybe a
little bit hungry we should be out of
here in about 15 minutes so you can
start making your plans but our next
speaker is use out to talk about loops
I only have a single page yeah so we
should finish with much lesser than 50
minutes I only have a single page here
and I'm gonna give a simple okay
announcement on the loops path because
this is one of the very first sessions
of ITF so I want you guys who were
possibly just here and with your jetlag
aware that this time the session starts
from 10 okay so tomorrow morning 10
o'clock we are going to have the pub
loops which stands for the local
optimization and path segments okay the
okay give a very simple description the
path of a long-haul Network can be
naturally or purposely partitioned into
multiple segments via possibly like
tunnel stitching so loops aims to
provide loss recovery locally over some
specific segments so that's the basic
idea of loops so here are two pointers
of the drafts so please read them and
please join us tomorrow morning 10:00
okay thanks
[Applause]
so I'm team April I'm here to talk
quickly about the DNS transparency
project many of you are probably
familiar about how DNS works it's pulled
a system where there's no way to
currently get a push based notification
to arbitrary end-users without having to
arrange something with the DNS provider
this means that any short-term changes
in the DNS that aren't being actively
monitored well will get missed and there
have been recent attacks if you look at
if you were to go in Google for sea
turtle or DNS panel as you can see hold
right up on some of these attacks that
took advantage of this some of the
weaknesses in that in the current model
this project is proposing to create a
system where there's a push or
generating a push based model where we
get data from registries and then
propagated out through a pub sub sort of
system to the end users that are
interested that could be a registrant it
could be a user or all sorts of things
like that and this would get hopefully
real-time updates from as many TL DS and
then possibly later on second and third
level domains as possible and then it'll
aggregate that and ship it out to
whoever wants to get it in hopefully
real-time or near real-time formats
there are a whole bunch of people
involved you can talk to any of us I
think there's only two of us here this
week but the two of us that are here
will be here all week we've also been
working with some people from a couple
different governments around the world
to try and figure out what exactly the
consumers need and then if the things
we're looking for right now if you're a
registry or registry operator would be
interested to talk about possibly what
we could do to get data if you're a
registrar or authority operators we'd be
interested to talk later on about how we
can get some of your data if you just
want to see we have a very simple web
page up there and we also have a form
where you can fill it if you want to get
more information as we get more data
than ships out we're in the process of
trying to stand up or merge with a be
taken under some other existing
nonprofit an independent agency or
independent organization so we can have
a independent status and build something
that's hope
fully available to the community at
large and we're hoping to make it free
to end-users so there's the link if you
have any questions find me this week I
don't want to stay in between you and
dinner all right thank you so the last
session there less talk is mine so I
know some of you know about this have
been participating in it but not
everybody maybe so this is kind of a
hobby little side project I've been
doing at ITF meetings which is to try to
do a little social event that's modeled
on the sitcom outrageous opinion session
and it was the ideas to do some
satirical talks I was calling it bad
idea Pecha Kucha for a while trying to
generalize it to not strictly be Pecha
Kucha format we've got several folks
signed up now and I saw a few come into
my inbox during the session so I think
the list is growing it's Thursday night
at 9:30 in Duluth which I think is the
room right next door to hear if you're
interested in giving a talk you can do a
Pecha Kucha which is a very structured
20 slides each slide is up for 20
seconds should be mostly text free yeah
or you can just do a short lightning
talk it has to be less than seven
minutes and the way to get time on the
agenda is to send me an email with a
talk title and then I need slides by six
o'clock on Thursday
so everybody's invited there will be
some beer and I hope to see you all
there and thank you for coming here if
you have feedback about this or the
Pecha Kucha talks please send me an
email I'm always happy to get feedback
so thank anybody go have dinner and
enjoy the week
you