[Music]
yeah
okay let's go ahead and get started
welcome we have only 30 minutes some
things have happened in the past couple
days so we're juggling the agenda
quickly we'll see if we have time to get
to everything so we put it in priority
order
so just reminder on the intellectual
property you you must say if there's any
IPR associated with your drafts and your
contributions and in terms of anything
you say if the might as well this is the
no well you've been seeing it all day
yesterday so well but if you haven't
read it please pay attention to it blue
sheets are going around
we need a new ticker
someone please volunteer it's going to
easy today
Thank You robber can we have a joker
star this is just take to go to the mic
if anyone who is remote and wants to
share something with the room okay I'll
do it let you run the meeting all right
we have two documents of progress you'll
see in a few minutes that the number has
gone up since we made these slides but
we're going to talk about them in this
order the first one is with the is G and
the second one has just been in last
call this is the agenda we're going to
deal with the amount of time necessary
in this order so I hope we get to
everything but we'll see okay and that's
it tradition lesser than the agenda
bashes all right Billy you're up
[Music]
okay good morning everybody my name is
Naveen amar I'm the main Otto the the
first author of the the district after
Alex left the draft in vision 43 so I
will give an update about what have been
done in this draft since version 44
until 15 currently we are in 50 but we
are expecting to to to post a new
version 51 after receiving some comments
from a romanian ID so from 44 - 45 so we
have in 44 we have updated the author's
list and in 45 we have updated the
abstracts so that we can give more focus
on the the main scope so we have
redefined the scope so that's to animate
any ambiguity on what we want to do and
we want to achieve in this draft as
suggested by the main reviewer at that
time pascal figure so we have added in
ran of one another of i simply a to do
so we are dealing with ranch and that
any other optimization are out of scope
in in this draft from 44 to 46 we have a
new abstract which is more concise so
that we don't have much details in the
abstract and we keep them to the main
body of the text and we have introduced
that these drafts doesn't make
challenge in existing stack so with
minimal challenge to existing stack and
also we focus once once out of time that
the more complex scenarios related to
vehicular communication will be covered
in future work also in from 45 to 46 we
have specifying the scope also in the
introduction so we have now in 46 this
new text the document describes the
leading of ipv6 networking on top of the
I Triple E standard mock layer or I
Triple E 8 or 2.3 ma clear with a frame
translation underneath and we have added
these centers that the results in stacks
operates over 80 2.11 ocv and provides
at least peer to peer connectivity so
the term peer to peer was not in
previous versions of the draft using
ipv6 in d and link local addresses in
the extension and IP way of optimization
for vehicular communication are not in
scope because we have been dealing with
Pascal about what kind of Indy what are
the the limits of Indy when it comes to
vehicle communication etc so we made
this sentence so to clarify things
better in also we have in security
consideration we have added some some
ideas here so for example we added that
previous work at say V working group
present some threats while sent
presented in these children these two
RFC's is the solution against breast eft
but it's complex had not deployed these
comment was sent also by from from
Pascal but we had some other comments
from the 80s when it goes to the iesg
that why talking about
mentioning sand if it's complex had not
deployed and we replied that this is the
only solution that we have at that time
so this is what why we mention it in
this draft from 46 to 47 we have changed
the title so now we have this new title
of the the draft basic support for ipv6
over X cetera and yesterday I asked the
RFC editor if they can help even if it's
not the time it's not an FCS but if we
can gain some time to if we can receive
some feedback so they told me that the
title is a little bit long so maybe we
can we can think about it in next
version we have also included in the
introduction that the resulting stuck in
here it's from ipv6 over Ethernet so
these lenses also some debates in the
mailing list and with the ideas what we
mean by in heretic cetera we explained
that we do the same as in Ethernet as as
ipv6 defined in RFC 24 64 so there is no
charge and that's it yes for for this
version and then yes and this was one of
the hot topics hot debates which is
about the the length of the address or
the the interface identifier so we
specify clearly that independently of
the the method used to provide the even
identifier the left is 64 bits so if we
need any other if there is any comments
that should be discussed in other
working group not in IP wave from 47 to
48 Mohammed Boogedy thanks to Mohammed
he suggested he proofreads the whole
document and he suggests me in private
he sent me corrections proofreading and
such
some ameliorations to clarify some text
so many correction were made in this
version 48 in from 48 to 14 9 we had
some issues about the references which
are normative and which are informative
I think that can be I can happen in many
stage and hopefully we have solved this
problem and we fix it some remaining
typos in every time we have a lot of
typos
from 49 to 50 so it was the the ballot
so we got 10 okay so it's it's an okay
for the moment but we still have some
three discuss we reflected the comments
received from the IDS we removed to the
following not in so in the new version
which is 50 compliance with standard and
the regulation set in different
countries
when using the 5.9 gigai frequency band
is required we remove this part because
we don't need to deal with this detail
in in IETF no specific reason why this
needs to be said here so this is why we
remove this part I think this is what
the so this one was one of the main
comment of the of one of the discuss
so hopefully this discuss will turn on
okay the map pin to the exit so we have
this must that became a shirt because
one of the ad is say that must it's
strong here and is in this this idea
deals with I Triple E so why we need to
force something like that so we agreed
that this must be should I need to
remind the participant here that this
part of the draft was sent us as a
review from I Triple E 802 dogeleven
working group based on their review
a long review we we made this this
sentence here so we just changed the
must into shoot we also corrected the
normative use of may and should in the
text the normal way of writing this
these words also we reformulated the
text in subnet structure as pointed out
by Roman one of the 80s as follows so so
he suggested to to to rewrite but with
the help of Pascal we rewrite this this
part so we introduce the some specific
passivity is related to neighbor
discovery to reflect what we want to say
here and why nd with current ocv can so
I can lead to other works that can be
done in the future
we also reformist the Security section
because one of the ATS suggested that an
attacker may not heed to legal limit for
radio power and can use a very sensitive
directional antenna so it was okay so I
added this sentence if attackers wish to
attack a given exchange they don't
necessarily need to be in close physical
proximity so this detail was not present
in previous version what remains to do
is to answer one last comment in the
discuss that we have now of Roman which
deals with pseudonym handling so I think
we have now with the help of Erik we
have now I think a good text that Roman
will I I hope will will agree on so
that's it for for these versions
so in equation our comments are welcome
thank you
say what are you going to say to
addresses so we are we have just sent
few lines to Roman and we can die and we
are still waiting for his feedback just
to fix the the this short paragraph
about what is the the the the difference
between what is the impact of
confidentiality because we used the term
confidentiality in the text it was on
big use for him and we changed it into
the identity of the destination and
making the trust because identity is not
as confidentiality its to term different
so we have proposed to to change these
two terms that's it that's the main
change that we have in this section
suresh krisshnan so Russ like in charge
it tastes like the upper layer protocol
should take care of it like that's the
gist of this Texas like propose to roman
okay thank you thank you okay so
basically when you get the okay from
from any you will be submitting version
51 yes and then we will ask the the
three scums because there are three
discussions to check if they are fine
and 2/3 of that okay thank you
[Music]
hello everybody this is poor John from
SK kill you so basically this IP waive
promise statement document liberated by
Charlie pockys and three and basically
three kundo barely certified with on
this television and Charlie Kaiser he
looks like didn't finished and Libya yet
but I believe most of his comments are
addressed so after last the prom meeting
revised it two times it so right now the
version is 11 so so I will explain to
Orly be jealous
so the first revision from 9 to 10 so
from a chali so the question is the
mortar linker so Burnette models so this
is the problem statement so I remove a
multi-link a sudden a discussion just we
specify characteristic of a virtual or
linker model is it symmetric and so
mobile attack and that took property so
we just addressed and also he mentioned
the DNS motivation the pqy Deanna's
important so I explained it especially
in beaker has a lot of issue unit so
they can be lester their own domain name
or so remotely automotive services enter
can remote a monitor regulator so in the
case dns laceration also these are
resolution is important so that's why I
added a some text so in appendix I added
that detail changes so you can refer to
that so timing issues Andy so the you
can see the national highway traffic
agencies as a product service as
appetizers thank you so they mentioned
the 0.25 the second very important
timing to avoid accident
so in the case the neighbor discovery
message if used for the safety a message
0.25 exchanges required so depending on
tentative vehicle we can adjust the
interval of neighbor discovery message
so I added a tap text next the security
consideration case expanding the
considered neighbor discovery part and
the mobility management part so I added
a some text
the secondly this you can see
documentation predicts Charlie maybe
some confused why what is it is so this
is you can see the documentation
predicts right for the example
so definitely any allowed rubber IP
version 6 address it can be loud trouble
in Bennett and V killer Edie vehicle
Annette on including infrastructure
loader RS use also the third one in the
piggy run case the separate vehicle on a
dog netted panel can be merged to using
infrastructure node over newly a joining
of vehicles so you can see two separate
a banach can link with the
infrastructure loader all the other
arriving not I mentioned and that part
and suggestion are how a good a nose
depress the prom a better nose or so we
I added a text so certificate can be
used to authenticate the beaker so I
mentioned the high lever so our a
document again is for problem Stateville
letter then giving the solution so and
Burton ten case I reflected the chalice
the editorial comment so many editorial
comments are addressed some several
questions case in the appendix that I
address the what change are ton and
three hakuna volley case the article she
a fifty eighty five zero five reference
this is for the six all of em the
address alliterations optimization so in
this text that we can lead up them just
may be the solution development the page
we can consider so we tell it either
next step is after confirmation of a
charlie and then Carlos will leave you
and then we can call last call and then
we can submit is G okay that's it
I scan I miss the reason why you remove
tags denied her for five is that because
you're not talking solution hmm I did
not understand why you removed that text
okay three his comment the years that
and the optimization is the possible a
good solution but our problem statement
the case we don't imagine it may be how
we can discuss that's because you don't
enter solution space that's because
you're in promised ice that's very good
yeah yes yes yeah okay so yeah basically
we will wait until suddenly confirms
that this is happy with the review yeah
just closing on the last comment exactly
I think it's not touching on the
solution that's one thing second thing
is this was the last minute you know the
comments you know but that you are
addressing were mostly based on the
reviews from Charlie and others right
there as to some discussion randomly we
cannot insert some new sections without
any discussion in the mailing list right
so there's a reason why so it was scary
yeah I don't buy the last argument if
you say if you say okay that's not a
subjective document I completely buy it
if you tell me it's because we don't
discuss enough well let's discuss right
now that you can't just remove text
that's odd because it's like if you say
okay we have to ship now so whatever is
discussion is pending we don't take it I
don't buy that I mean you want a good
document and if you want a good document
then you want to make sure you have
settled on the issues right so if there
was a good reason to mention it then and
you remove it just because you decided
at the last minute that's not fair
either right
so so the group must are the consensus
either way we want to talk about it we
don't want to talk about it it's the
right document wrong document but you
can't just make a decision like that in
a work group document just at the moment
you do last call to snip some document
effect without the group saying yes you
can
right so the text that showed up in that
version
there was no priority discussion it's
just a randomly showed up that
intersection point of our point number
two again this spec is about
requirements right so we are not
touching I think those for those reasons
I said you know they should be okay so I
mean we we can have discussion if
somebody thinks that it has to be the
earth text but I read that it's not
about solution the document okay so then
I was instead we're saying we'll wait
for Charlie to confirm and then once at
least happy with the review I will I
will
okay so we moved to the hackathon
propose just one minute it enough
because yeah and so basically this has
only the second time hackathon we so I
think that first card the solution of
our solution is the proto-tool heated
previous the work also the hackathon
project case we approved the OCB and
also one possible solution on the big
hill neighbor discovery the multi hub at
dat so we proved concept and so the
basically we using this multi hub at the
ad to lead years at the ad arm delay or
so we can allow picker can start the TCP
connection Egyptian and possible using
the multi hub adding network and the
impact on network so we extended the
connectivity so we probably using the
simulation and okay so the appendices
are explained and this website can show
the video clip and github that's it
thank you
yeah so if you have a question fully you
can discuss so Paschal you have yeah
short time
yes if you want one are you talking that
are you saying that you're flooding the
dead of are multiple Hopf so you're
actually doing a big flood for that well
that's the one thing we just did not
want it absolutely to avoid in the type
of networks that right yo has been
working on right because because of the
bandwidth that the flooding cost you
know the flooding well each broadcast is
that at the slowest speed possible and
if you have to flood it that means
you're basically consuming all the
bandwidth for everybody time you want to
form or just check in your dress and
well many environments is just not
acceptable they can't see that it would
be acceptable the CD I don't just don't
see why it would be acceptable because
not you get it of course the only thing
you will see is that on your network
there is nobody else or anything else
not not quite a good idea so the way six
load has that of our multiple hearts is
unicast so you need to have for a given
subnet a registry and you just unicast
check that registry that's how you avoid
the flood because the flood with just
one call it looks great then you have
one thousand cars you know nothing works
okay so inter pastor the adding load
mark are he suggested we need to
consider a multi up the ad with the
unicast so that's why we implemented
some possible solution but once we the
penises promise statement document can
discuss it not just example do you plan
to do some real OCB yes definitely yes
my group already have the Kota Wireless
our Cu and ODU so we will test paper
protocol okay thank you yeah so yeah
yes thank you for pointing out to the
hackathon so we made the two hackathons
in the past one in Dakar and second one
in Kampala last month during the Africa
internet summit so we got two good
results because we are using not
simulation but real cards and to test if
there is possibility to to connect and
to send pings and we use in Wireshark to
capture and to see the the frame and all
fields and all details that's what we
want also to do next time okay thanks
thank you I guess we don't have time for
for the presentation if they I mean for
those are interested on that
Piscotty within six month I mean six
long six robot a like a standard version
right so you can take the video
recordings if you sure yeah okay okay we
we are done Thanks where are the blue
seats okay thank you