[Music]
okay alone people stem the clock
so it's so it's about time for us to get
started if we can work our way down to
one boss in the room at the time at a
time it will probably be helpful to the
area directors I am
Spencer Dawkins and this is Oh waitron
we are your Pepe both chairs for the
gluts pop if you're in the loops pop
you're in the right place and if you're
needing to be somewhere else we'll miss
you
this is a Bob at the ITF so it is
covered by the note well which many of
us have seen and references PCBs which
all of us should have at least looked at
once this is our agenda for the day and
wanted to give a brief pause to do
agenda bashing if anybody has thoughts
so good excellent
so we will go with this agenda please
remember that this stuff is not working
group forming which is means that we're
thinking I wanted to do a little scope
scoping for our discussions we're not
replacing the internet quick or TCP we
are talking about optimizations where
things work but don't always work well
we're talking about optimizations
between network elements not involving
hosts and your network might not need
loops but somebody else's network might
I think the first law of optimization is
first do no harm and so that's one of
the things I'd like for people to be
watching for in our path we're talking
about a transport independent
optimization we are not changing the
indian transport protocol payload and
our goal for this off is that we agree
on what happens
so there's a lot of things we could talk
about for two hours but I would like to
direct your attention to helping us find
out what needs to happen next our face
to face time is precious this is not a
work group forming both because for my
other reasons the proponents were
meeting for the last day and a half and
they learn well they were learning a lot
from each other what I think this means
is that people are different people are
working in the same space but since
there's no IETF activity yet they're not
doing things the same way and there
wouldn't be you know anything they
produced would not be produced providing
the same services so it sounds to me
like kind of a opportunity for us to
avoid our experience with gnats where we
said this is a bad idea but people did
it anyway and they didn't do it here for
the longest time people come to mini
buffs debuffs for many reasons note that
it's possible to watch a train wreck
while looking down at the Train we're
not going to ask if you came to see a
train wreck but we are going to ask ya
who consider yourself and this is show
of hands kind of thing primarily a
transport person more than anything else
okay so about the third of the room you
think cool so consider yourself
primarily an Internet application person
or Internet encapsulation person that's
almost as many people as transport so we
have the right co-chair
application layer it's a smaller number
but thank you for being here primarily
operations we have we have we have we
have to we have to we have to excellent
cool this is double the number of the
average profit
primarily a measurement person yes
that's okay yeah so at least like at
least like four or five people in here
without expertise primarily a security
person we're seeing one hand two heads
and I'm pretty sure that they're all at
the quick thing at a in our W that was a
joke who's read the problems
opportunities draft Wow this is where do
you say a third of the room cool and who
is working on a product that does local
transport optimizations I'm countin
eight hands ish yeah you know like more
like ten yeah okay so maybe maybe this
is not a proposal from one percent of
group sorry Aaron fogg mkhaya are you
product or a system I mean some people
are not building trucks I don't
understand the intention of the question
so know that I don't understand yeah yes
yes yes thank you for thank you for
clarifying questions hi Cory hi Spencer
I'm taking notes do you want to say what
you find out or do you just want to tell
me afterwards I can send it to you
afterwards but to summarize its
one-third transport one-third Internet
one tenth on the application to people
on operations five people on measurement
to one and a half and security perhaps a
third of the room has read the problems
opportunities draft and we have sort of
1012 people who are actually working on
products in this area or systems in this
area fabulous thank you so I'd like to
just put the questions to guide us
between now and ITF world
six up we're going to loop back to this
slide at the end of at the end of our
discussion time but this is these are
questions that I'm going to be asking or
hums and my client
if you're humming no to help help us
understand why not
and so I say you'll see the slide again
but I wanted you to have it in your mind
since we started the discussion so I
think we're ready for Carsten good
morning
Monday morning is not my time I defended
my PhD on a Monday morning so quick
question who in this rule was not in one
of the previous loop side meetings we
had at the last word yes okay so it
makes sense to say what is the room for
pouring thank you so basically how can
you do the incorrectly slide searching
it's not doing first name yes yes thank
you okay so basically this is about
packet loss if your network doesn't have
packet loss you're probably in the wrong
room more interestingly if you if Peck
loss is not a problem for you you're
probably also in the wrong room because
all we are going to do for the rest of
the morning is looking at optimizing
things so we have less packet loss and
I've also mentioned that one form of
pick loss for instances tail loss
Michael has provided
this nice demonstration of tail loss and
so there's always a little bit of
latency consideration behind that but
what we are primarily try to do here is
reduce packet loss and the the approach
is to do the simplest thing that could
possibly work which is we have a network
path between two hosts that are
oblivious to what's going on here
and we have two nodes in the network
that cooperate both are on paths they
cooperate in reducing the loss and it's
about compensating
for losses that happen in the path
between the two nodes so I think it's
hard to do something that's even simpler
than that so that is what we're trying
to do here and of course there are
things like retransmissions and FEC and
and things we can't could do or could
not do and that's possibly something
that a working group could let to find
out what exactly you want to do but
right now let's try to understand the
problem so the point is to recover
packets locally so locally has two
meanings
it means close together low latency but
it also means with no impact on the rest
of the network and that of course
requires a little bit of thinking how
you really can make sure that there is
no impact on the rest of the network but
the main thing is doing it locally
allows us to do it with low latency
that's one of the objectives the second
thing is we want to do it in the network
so host participation is not required
that doesn't mean that there shouldn't
be activities with host participation
that's fine but it's not what what's on
the agenda today so we want to do this
in the network and something because we
we don't want the whole
to participate we don't want to touch
the hosts packets
so traditionally peps have been very
intrusive and and have looked into
packets and actually changed packets and
this is not the objective the objective
is that the packet that comes out of
loops is the same one that came in it's
just more likely to actually really
emerge then it would be without loops
and this of course means it works with
any kind of IP packets so encryption is
not a problem for for what we are trying
to do so don't look and don't touch so
with these three framing things copying
things it's pretty clear that any
solution would have retransmission
forward error correction or both and
right now we are looking at the solution
that actually can do both and of course
for retransmission you need some
information going from the egress to the
ingress which we call reverse
information like X next whatever and you
also typically include some forward
information although Michael will talk
about the case where you actually don't
need that so if the terms reverse
information and forward information I
come up these are things that need to be
done and these are the things that
actually we want to send it as here so
we can interoperate the same thing is
true for forward error correction since
that may not be as familiar to people it
means adding redundancy to the packets
so if you lose one out of a group of
packets you can recover independent of
which of the packets your us this has
some latency advantages and it gets
really good when you do a dynamic
selection and adaptation algorithm for
the parameters of the fact things like
block size if you have a block size and
fake rate
how much redundancy do you actually add
it helps to dynamically adapt there and
to be able to adapt you need measurement
and we will see a few other places where
measurement is useful and finally it
turns out there are some some hybrid
approaches where you react to a neck by
adding FEC so this is not not out of
scope what we don't really want to spend
a lot of time on is things like protocol
setup negotiation and so on we're
assuming this that this happens in an
environment where we have some
controller thing that does these things
for us and we are hand waving there this
is not meant to be part of the effort
but of course we need to understand what
information needs to be in that setup so
maybe in the end there will be a yang
model or something like that ok the
other part as I said we don't want to
influence what's outside there and and
the most important thing is we don't
want to blow it up and this means we
have to be careful about concealing
packet losses because if you completely
conceal all packet losses then of course
the end hosts will ramp up and and you
get into all kinds of problems because
you will increase congestion so a
necessary component here is congestion
feedback to the end hosts and yeah the
preferred way of course is easy and we
have a way to do congestion feedback but
for those flows that cannot use Sen we
also need a fallback for Beck so we
don't get an deployment problem
the permanent disincentive everybody is
waiting for easy end actually some
informal measurements make me very
optimistic about ecn about the
percentage of traffic that already is
easy and caliber but that's maybe not
for this of to discuss
and the other observation is we assume
the transfer protocols on the hosts will
improve over time and we want to play
the puck a little bit to what where they
will be yet not where they are now so we
are assuming more easy and we are
assuming more time-dependent loss
detection stuff like in rec instead of
packet number dependent loss detection
and so on so there are a number of
improvements that may may shape the
optimal solution of things for loops but
since we are not picking anything today
that's just something to keep in mind
yeah
so in summary we want to do the local
recovery thing we want to do some
measurement both to set recovery
parameters like when do I stop
retransmit ring and also if we have to
signal a congestion by actually dropping
packets we want to do this as little as
possible and maybe measurement can help
us understand whether a loss was was a
congestion or a non congestion loss and
we have to do the actual congestion
feedback what's not in scope but what
maybe at some point some people want to
do is adding multipath to the picture
well traditionally I would propose
adding multicast mobility and security
that's always the three things that make
things interesting but multipath is
joint that list and also we are not we
into diagnosing that path segment we
have ways of diagnosing paths also IOM
and so on this is not really what what
we are trying to do here we are seeing
the path segments as one thing we want
to do some measurements on it but we
don't necessarily want to understand
which of the nodes is which of the links
is causing the losses
MTU handling is not something we will be
the first to solve I mean it has been
tried before and we know that there are
a number of solutions that are not
always very satisfying but we will just
live in that thank you and finally since
this needs tunneling we probably want to
use some tunnel encapsulation this is
not about defining one and not not about
choosing one but really we want to be
able to use any tunnel encapsulation
that that's out there and there are some
sketches to make sure that's possible
but these are proof of existence
sketches and much things to choose from
there are a couple documents out there
for the problem opportunities draft as
Spencer asked about there is a strong
and proposal we will spend a couple of
minutes on later they even is a charter
proposal for a new working group but we
are not working group forming buff so we
are not going to discuss that and there
is a groups mailing list you may want to
join on what you may want to consult you
okay ten minutes can I ask a question
yes lucky chose democracy I'm the
co-chair of the network coding Research
Group where we have a tunnel where we do
per per segment coding where we have
dealt with the issue of hiding and
hiding losses and not breaking the
internet where we do have error recovery
and I'm wondering why we need another
group to do that
so the one possible one possibility
would be standardizing it in the IETF
okay yeah we've been a research group
but yeah because a lot of the problems
that were stated here are things that we
have been addressing for what five years
or something like this yeah this is why
we have mops
this is good thank you a lot of people
in this room have been working on this
for five or ten or fifteen years
spending the last ever since I graduated
from college and looking at my old age
you can imagine how long that was so so
what I would say that yeah there's
already a lot of work done in a research
group that could actually profit this
absolutely absolutely and then have some
slides about it later but everybody in
this room can can go home comfortably
thinking this new work is a spinoff of
the work that did it before so this will
be a NW c RG spin-off if it becomes a
working group if that helps I booked
Brisco independent I I just will an
answer to this question when you move
from a per link retransmission to an
overlay retransmission you stop being
able to tell whether it's a transmission
loss or a congestion loss when you're on
the purling you know whether it's a
transmission loss or not but once you go
away from that you don't so the the
statements you made about wanting to
avoid hiding congestion loss don't
square with the scope of the of the both
as far as I can see because your your
honor you're definitely on a multi-link
scope so tying the recovery scheme to
the link helps you but I don't agree
with the other half that if you would
not try it with the link you cannot say
anything I don't agree with it well how
do you know the difference between
congestion loss and transmission loss if
you're not on the lane well maybe the
delay window maybe the delay went up
okay so you're then starting to do but
that's something lot of things we
have to look at and there is a number of
things you can do relatively safely and
there are a number of things that may be
a little bit aggressive and then we are
right there in congestion control and
where we have a number of algorithms and
mechanisms to choose from and there will
be BCPs and and everything I think this
needs to be examined I just want to
point out um we might want to do that
might come back to say real quickly here
one of the things one of the questions
that it's on our list of questions is
how much you know how much of this is
what's research and what's engineering
so we you know we are kind of headed
towards that question in the first
couple that have come up and I wanted to
thank you all for helping us to
understand that that one of the
questions so tender than it is most you
all david black as a transparent group
chair or one of the chairs want to quick
get up to do two quick plugs from labor
at first for all bob Brisco who just sat
down has written a couple of drafts that
are that are mostly done in the working
group headed for IETF last call soon of
important interests of this group is
that they explain a bit about how to
handle EC and a tunnel a tunnel ich
egress and particular bob has written
some text on fragmentation that might
also in might also apply to FEC if you
don't look at it look at at the details
to closes on cars looking that at those
drafts one of them has Easton and cap my
name
the other has RFC 6040 updates shim in
the name we apologize for the not
exactly intuitive draft names and then
having mentioned tunnels there's a
long-suffering draft in antic area on
tunnels please read that and don't
reinvent it thank thank you David just
and just those are both TST WT working
group drafts right the interior one
isn't no yeah there's there's there's
2tsp WG drafts one sec and cap the name
one has
RFC 6040 updates shim in the name oh and
there's an indie area draft on tunnels
and of the 3d interior draft is probably
the most important because it reflects a
bunch of things learned learned along to
over a long time the hard way about
tunnels Thank You Ted lemon so to me
so I'm a little frustrated by what
Carsten just said because to me the most
interesting problem that that needs to
be solved in this space is the is the
problem of the edge device the leaf
device talking to the border router
between and I a constrained network and
a bigger network and so if that problem
is out of scope then I actually have no
interest in this work that's not to say
that I don't don't think it's a good
idea it just I personally don't have
interest in it so and I'm not saying
that you should change your mind I'm
just making I'm just raising that point
to point it out to you thank you
sniffing Vega one thing one thing that
came to my mind is I think this this
problem that was described here is at
least for many more tricky links solved
in proprietary ways by basically
everyone and I think it's also quite
common that the that said when you have
a satellite link that your satellite
uplink and your satellite downlink and
the boxes attached to it where something
like this has to happen are from the
same vendor and they do them and a
specific thing why is that not
sufficient anymore are we are we
standardizing just for the sake of
standardization good thank you next
presentation thank you so I'm going to
present a use case so hopefully some of
the questions can be answered when we
have a very specific use case so here
here is the usage scenario we are trying
to introduce thinking about
intercontinental when past for example
from Paris to Beijing either over NPSL
over Internet but here we're trying to
focusing on over the public Internet
so we find out as the default path does
not always keep the latency we required
or the best latency so what we are
trying to do is look at the small square
here we create the workload from
multiple clouds in different geographer
sites to build a better web pass via the
overlay nodes those square boxes
actually the overlay notes record crowd
the Internet network science or
something so we have put this virtual
nodes or cloud routers globally then we
have experiments based on 37 cloud
routers then we find out wisdom we have
71 percent chance of finding a better
path in terms of latency so what's next
we find out even we have a selected path
gives a better latency the loss still
exists then there are some pretty
well-known negative impacts of packet
loss in Longhorn Network the Longhorn
Network here we refers to the long
pipeline at least like tens of hundreds
of milliseconds so there are at a loss
problem for short flow which possibly
caused by the timeout
possibly a few seconds at the sender or
it may take an additional Artie T for T
spirit transmission in so the long flow
completion time is is expected in this
case and for large flows the throughput
is the large flow I mean the cares most
so there are chances that the TCP sender
actually reduce its sending rate even
when the loss is not caused by a
persistent congestion so in summary the
packet loss negative impact most because
of the internal transmission it takes
time especially in long-haul network so
too
have some further study on the packet
loss pattern we we have this picture
sorry syllabus little bit more but for
those is in Chinese but you can guess
there there are locations I mean they
are Shanghai by Eugene I think there are
Silicon Valley and like San Paulo or
somewhere so each pair of them there's
the small square here actually captures
the loss rate so it can be easily
identified that the loss over past
segments has very different
characteristics some Dom them the loss
is is persistently high and some some of
them the loss almost can be ignored in
some random the laws vary over time for
example higher getting higher over the
peak peak hours yeah something like that
then another finding is the loss over a
single specific segments may affect the
end-to-end loss significantly that is to
say the loss detected by the end-to-end
pass actually can possibly be
contributed by a short single segments
so in our usage scenario there are at
least two opportunities to new
opportunities we have now with where we
find out that can solve the packet loss
problem the first one is in this cloud
internet we have overlay nodes they
partition the whole heads into shorter
segments naturally and we can enable the
per segment operation for example
quicker recovery from loss comparing to
entry and also we can do the adaptive
recovery so the adaptive here means for
each of the segments we can decide
whether we should enable the local
recovery or not always should use the
retransmission or we can enable the FEC
with different level of redundancy
another opportunity we find out is the
overlay nose nowadays have computing and
memory resources so are capable of
provides providing the complex features
like
detection recovery measurement is a
marking others things so here this pay
trying to show a little bit how the
segment based merriment can help us help
determine the cause of a packet loss
look at the picture here the left-hand
side actually I think is from where
Frankfurt or Shanghai on the right side
from Frankfurt to Shanghai and the left
side is from Shanghai to u.s. West so
the blue is the loss rate the red is the
RTT so we can see there is a strong
correlation in these two cases so that
somehow in ties if it has such pattern
the high correlation pattern then there
is a loss then we check that at that
time the delay is high then we it's
highly possible that losses caused by a
congestion otherwise it's possible that
caused by a non-contrast reason so why
we care about this remember the slides
that are shown by Caston somehow we want
the feedback the congestion information
to the sender so that's how the segment
based information helped us I believe in
the solution sketch presentation may
have made touch more on this
so to summarize I have introduced that
is a particular scenario in the overlay
nodes allow us to improve the loss the
packet loss over some specific channel
based path segments in we are requiring
mechanism to be defined to achieve the
local recovery and at the same time
minimizing the undesired side effects we
I kind of think the loops buys too
should buy to existing overlay tonneau
insulation we do not want to invent a
new ink encapsulation
that's or for this quarry
Gouri first and cartwright question so
we we have these effects going on at
multiple layers so I write I put my
operator hat on I'm doing stuff that
late to mail maybe layer three then I'm
doing routine control to try eliminate
these things I've got transport
protocols running over the top I see
real dangers that we have too many
layers trying to cross optimize the same
things over slightly different time
scales is this something that you're
considering okay for this one I am it's
highly depends on their deployment
because for this one we are thinking
there are some underling nodes and it's
not under control of the operator who
provides all the small square boxes so
this is an overlay note managed by
somebody else so that's why we have
layering so naturally they're not doing
traffic at you are they not looking at
the BGP tables and considering how to
optimize this this um you I'm trying to
say actually there are some underlying
optimization that that's the I mean
operators are trying news right guys I I
think it's possible but that part is not
the I mean they're the provider with
this layer will be worried about and
from some of the experiments will show
actually the latency I mean they the
unrecorded underlay actually the
underlay latency given by them is not
satisfied so that's why they're the
middle layer operator I want to do
something by themselves Aaron Falk
Akamai thank you for your presentation
was very clear I thought it was very
helpful could you go to the slide that
shows the delay and loss rate and I
think this is a the point that Corey was
making which is at every layer that you
are implementing loss recovery
you are converting loss into delay
because each layer is doing some sort of
loss detection and then recovery to
ensure successful transmission so that's
happening at the link layer that could
be happening between routers you're
doing it between your cloud routers so
what that's going to do is that's going
to mask some of the signal so if you are
using an indication of delay to say
correlated with loss to say that this is
congestion related loss you may be may
be incorrect in that because what's
happening is that a layer underneath you
is converting that loss that it's
detected into delay so what we are
trying to do is at least we need to do
no harm so this is just an example to
show in case there is a strong
correlation what's possibly we can do
but if I mean if people really have
worries about this we can just do the
local recovery and then let the sender -
as they usually do I mean if one they
want to decrease the sending rate so
just as a conventional TCP sender but at
least we are to doing no harm
this can you go back to the slide with
the graph and that shows that topology
the topology graphic so this kind of
makes it look like the majority of the
transmit path is the long-haul which in
regards to the latency seems like that
would be where the most delay is so if
local recovery is over the largest part
of the path I'm not sure that that's
going to be very different than and
recovery so that's in your comment on
that yeah that's fair I think that's a
fair comment so from our experiments we
normally we have at least three segments
I mean so so as the previous
presentation in custom showed if there
is a longest segment that is our TT is
almost
equivalent to the end-to-end now I don't
think we should enable loops so you
break it into smaller segments the
advantages of localization but then the
obvious problem becomes what if I have
lost it each segment and they'll have
additive delay which is making the
problem even worse oh it's just some of
the things I'm sure you're thinking
about these things yeah so so that's why
I mean during the solution
considerations I think we want to make
the recovery mechanism more adaptive so
some sources for certain segments maybe
we don't want to enable it at all for
some of them maybe retransmission okay
now for some of them if you see with
different redundancy might be applicable
so that's yeah but we don't have very
very specific solution right now but
because this is known working group
forming both so that's what I'm thinking
Spencer Spencer Dawkins speaking as
individual contributor so one of the
things I wanted to be sure and say was
again I'm glad that Aaron stood up and
started talking
Aaron and I co-chaired the pilk working
group which produced the advice for
subjects sub network protocol designers
a long time ago and one of the things
that's in there or is about being aware
of reach you know retransmissions we did
that so long ago that people are still
running IPO for x.25 you know in the end
people were still saying that they want
to say your hops that were completely
reliable completely reliable so those
kinds of things so we've had the ITF has
done work that required a you know that
that tried to help people be aware of
that problem and I think what we're
saying now is that that problem is at
more than one layer down you know it's
more than one layer for the two layers
that could be arguing and so I think
being aware of that is going to be
really important and this is kind of
what I was thinking about when I was
talking about performance implications
of path characteristics at the at the
IRC talk thank you
and Rebecca you pointed in the same
thread it's in the same thread it's
returning to the previous point about
doing no harm with the correlation named
Lillian sorry innately
Andrew McGregor if you hide or smear out
in time the correlation between
congestive loss and the delay you're
doing harm end of story
because it reduces the ability of the
congestion control to see what's going
on if on the other hand you have some
level of non congestive loss then
papering over that is purely a good
thing the question is can you tell the
difference and that's the that's the key
problem in all of this yeah and the
reason works layer too by the way and
you know there's probably more than four
instances of an algorithm that does
exactly this for per person in this room
running is that you know that it's not
congested was right Wi-Fi you dropped up
you know you have an error rate that's
rather high for an indifferent internet
going you dropped a packet because of
that we'll find just paper over it right
whereas you know if you don't know on a
long-haul path whether it was congested
or not you should probably leave it in
the string so let me answer that quickly
the point of the congestion feedback is
to not lose the information now let me
answer the other question which is
essentially we have survived the last 30
years why are we doing this now there
are a number of things coming together
and the cloudy stuff that you talked
about is maybe one aspect of it but I
think the important observation is this
is not supposed to reply we've replaced
the existing Internet this is a
particular performance optimization that
you can employ at specific places in the
network that have the characteristics to
make this useful and having
a sizable part of non congestive loss
probably is a precondition to to make
this really worthwhile so there is an
assumption there is a controller
somewhere that is looking at the network
and has already has some measurement
data and that helps you decide where to
put a loop segment and and we are not to
put one and the third observation is the
the blue segments work best when they
are shot so this is not supposed to be
an edge-to-edge thing this is supposed
to be in the network deeply in the
network and the final observation when
you think about this problem try to
strike from your minds that a
retransmission scheme has to do
resequencing so most people who want to
do that something in this space don't
want to do resequencing many link layer
solutions today have to do resequencing
because the link layers are you find to
be sequence preserving and also the the
tunnel based solutions often do
resequencing and this is pretty much
about exploring the space where where
you can have performance improvements
without resequencing okay Thank You Joan
and Yuen long you're next so that's one
more presentation on use cases for this
problem and then we're going to talk a
little bit about solution sketches just
in a matter of time keeping we're
running a little late but I think this
discussion is very useful and important
to understand the problems but at some
point we're going to you know draw a
hard line and ensure that we get off
questions answered as well so you're
enforcing and forcing MTU size on time
slots good job the problem is that the
questions have come up make me think I
need more in five minutes
so anyway so I'm going to show you a
couple pictures about satellite use case
so basically you know today it's TCP we
put a pep in there over satellite to
optimize one of the things that
optimizes is recovery from loss over the
satellite link a particular thing that
makes it a little different than what
was talked about earlier is you're still
going to be latency there even with a
loose based solution but the key thing
we're looking at though is with the move
towards things like quick we can't do
split TCP anymore
so we need some kind of underlay as was
pointed out you know we actually have
proprietary solutions now so one of the
questions a couple why are we looking
potentially a sterilised one well one is
maybe we can leverage open source
solutions especially with respect to
solutions that include more advanced FEC
the other thing is for my future thing
which is out of scope I think Ted
brought it up even though right now
we're not looking and going to the end
host you need this this part in the
middle to get there because I would like
to optimize recovery over that Wi-Fi
link at my remote site also so you know
in the longer term I want to build on
this solution to get to the point where
I can actually recover because that's
another thing that pept does for me is
it gives me the local recovery at each
of the three spaces so that's kind of
where we're looking at it you know terms
of why we're interested in this from the
satellite what have you so I kept it
under the 5 because I talk fast there
any questions
fantastic you'll recover two minutes oh
no
I'm going to create the problem here
actually again with the chair we're
actually having two drops that actually
want to put fvc inside quick to deal
with losses without having another layer
so how do you go well how are you going
to deal with essentially two layers of
FEC one below which is what you want to
do in loops and the one that we already
have inside quick why do we need to
loose well I I'm actually very
interested in that solution also because
I actually because it can learn
something about the network and be very
specific to the transport protocol this
is more generic but also you know
hopefully I would say I would set this
up to be intelligent enough that I
wouldn't use this one if I didn't need
it if if it was there or maybe I use
this one you know quick still going to
have a learning curve to figure out that
I'm going satellite-linked so I think
they could play together but they are
actually there's two different
approaches and I'm actually interested
in both solutions towards us the FEC
inside quick is very interesting to me
you know I think what I hear is that
there seems to be a gathering of a ton
of different pieces of information that
come from a ton of different groups and
research groups and I don't know one
task that you guys want to to take is
actually to see what exists and what has
been done and what can actually be used
here next slide set ok well thank you
but what I'm saying is that yes there is
going to be FEC inside quick and I hope
that who do not work against one another
yeah I guess one of the problems I have
way you just said that you said there's
going to be its research is it really
good I have to say the reason that our
draft is not in the quickly in the quick
working group is because they are
focusing on delivering the first version
of the product yeah and we didn't want
to come in too quick and with this FEC
proposal and
things up well and actually I will tell
you that the way the draft is being
structured right now it is not
structured that their research draft it
is structured as a working group draft
but we're holding on to it so that lures
can start sleeping at night and not
figuring out that we have these people
coming yet another add-on to quit that
will the last two hours of sleep I added
so yes it's inside the research group
right now but it is not to be a research
paper the strategy is the minute that
these guys issue version one or whatever
the stable version they have we are
coming in the in the working group thank
you okay
yeah and I hope that's the way it works
out I was trying to hedge my bets yeah
cuz I I just wanted to say again we want
to play the part to where the entrant
protocol will be so of course yes we are
considering if you see that is being
done end to end so that's useful stuff
going on and what loops can do is
provide FEC in places in specific places
in the network where it's needed and not
having the overhead in other places so
this is 100% complimentary and yes the
fun part will be getting the to dynamic
adaptation algorithms work together
correctly that will be enjoyable and I'm
looking forward to it
well I don't have the research for that
yet
but again there's a difference between a
protocol and a mechanism and we can
standardize things at different times so
when we understand good mechanisms to do
this optimally we should send analyzed
those and we should define a protocol
within which we can do these mechanisms
investigations actually I should
probably mention that we're kind of
getting towards the discussions that we
would have
at a chartering time for a working group
which it's now is not be honest out the
conversation we're having here but then
it is stuff that we have to think about
and probably stuff that has to appear in
the Charter but it's just not necessary
for us to know what to do next after
noon today
Lars Eiger chairing the quick working
group so we don't have fact on the
agenda at the moment on the agenda on
the Charter at the moment and while
there is significant interest in having
some sort of effect in quickly at the
moment it's it's if they're all
individual proposals right and and
there's no working group consensus on
what to do with this I will know that
that fact was actually part of Google
quick at some point it was removed at
least one particular way of doing effect
and quick because it didn't deliver on
the promise a new proposal for doing
second quick might be different thread
and better and and - to cause it to
perfect at the moment or if it is no
such plan on the charlie
thank you can have this visual image of
the new flick that the hordes are hiding
against the castle gate and as soon as
v1 drops we're gonna be I don't wanna
sleep now but I I so I think that
you know I came here to try to get a
better understanding of what the problem
is that that the blue who have used
cases feel they need to solve I think
that will inform some IETF activity
maybe it happens in a new working group
maybe happens an existing working group
and also to learn about some existing
proposed solutions to try to understand
what the solution space is you know
what's changed and what are people doing
so I think that the network coding is an
important piece of that quick is a piece
of that the the overlay stuff is a piece
of that so I don't see you know this is
an informational bar so we're just we're
not making decisions about what's gonna
happen we're trying to understand the
problem space and so I don't think we
need to have the argument about where
the work is going to happen we get to do
that in a we're going to performing Bach
Jinlong you're you're next
morning everyone this is John from China
Telecom and like I like to present a
petition scenario that loops could be
applicable as its mentioned in the draft
I will talk about a zombie six and base
that Enterprise one connection his kiss
for loops after say I will take a brief
introduction about the background China
is the largest public Internet backbone
network in China a melon provides Robin
Internet and a cloud access was for
public users and enterprise users their
entire network devices are ipv6 enabled
and we plan to support SRV Six Sigma
routing of ipv6 to provide the path
selection to me services array however
when we deploy some services of the
internet for example enterprise usually
require network connection between the
branch offices or between branch offices
and cloud data center over Geographic
distances the problem we encounter is
that the traffic over the Internet a
subject to lose during the best effort
networks so there is a urgent need to do
network optimization to provide high
quality internet for specific service
that needed the reliability of data
transform the following in the use case
as the picture shows there are two
branches of the enterprise which access
the internet through visa Vee for one
connection and recipe connects to a
cloud-based pub which further directs
the traffic to the PC for cloud access
you know we see PSO and they favor two
node in the network so it can be
enable with some whining I did services
to be provided from providers work so we
can see there are three typical services
deployed the yellow one the yellow line
represent one connection and the green I
represent the cloud axis and the red
line represent the DZ interconnection so
obviously we can say one we see p2
another vase EPE recipe to a cloud-based
pub pub to pub can be over a long
distance
which could be divided into multiple
Szabo paths based on a sorry six
segments but some of which must have
packages generally so this is the will
be of opportunity for loops which can be
enabled for the segments of the scible
paths to solve packet loss and provide
the better for path selection with with
this deployment we can provide her
County internet connection in terms of
loss rate so do you think it is so
applicable use case for loops that we
also should focus on and I think it can
be applied to the enterprise one
connections an area apart from that s
our v6 provider provide the path
selection naturally so it could be a
specific encapsulation protocol for
loops so it could be considered in the
following work so if you are also
interesting this topic
welcome more common and discussion thank
you okay thank you very much so the next
presentation is by Michael giving us
some ideas or solutions can look like
the Spencer has definitely started
trying mercy do my best to be yeah
double time here alright quick overview
of how loops could work I got the
impression from the discussion already
that some people tend to have a specific
image in the mind of how a loop system
is gonna work like it's definitely going
to affect or it's definitely gonna do
resequencing and I think none of these
things are none of these things are
decided yet so this is just an overview
of the possibilities that that we have
you know some things that we thought
about a strawman of the information that
would have to go between an ingress and
egress so that this whole thing could
operate that's you know the context for
the for the following details you know
we have data going into an ingress we
have data that's possibly encapsulated
not necessarily there are two
possibilities here and I'm going to
explain what's an egress the egress is
gonna act on AK or both and the ingress
is gonna reach transmit or it's gonna
use fetch or both not probably not but
we transmit or use FAQ and then well the
end goal is that much better data and
leaves tigress I mean more data less
death less testicle there so the
problems that we'll have to try to
address loss detection and regions
mission we need to somehow do something
about loss we need to well probably work
on fact then the will also be a need to
detect congestion that happens on the
path segment they will need to be some
measurement that will need to be some
congestion detection and we'll need to
think about how congestion is signal
towards the end hosts if it was if it
was detected can be done by dropping a
packet which is against the whole
purpose of loops but you could drop you
know a better packet in the last packet
could be done using ecn which is
preferable some concrete ideas on how
these things cooperate are coming now
but it's just a straw man
the two modes here that I'm going to
present to you the first is tunnel mode
which is I guess closer to what most of
the things are that you've seen so far
step one of the steps that you that
you've seen is encapsulation you would
on the ingress side encapsulated in
something we don't specify how yet you
know there are the document has caches
of gooey and of genève and how it could
be possibly done but the point is you
would encapsulate and add some
information that is necessary such that
we can reflect for instance sequence
numbers we can use you know proper X so
you need obviously right you need to
identify packets you need the sequence
number we identified also some other
information Tunnel type an actus arable
flag I get to what that is about quickly
next slide and whatever might may be
needed by a key so regarding exact
desirable flag there are two blocks that
are currently being envisioned for the
feedback this box would be just sent in
some way right it could be interspersed
it could be repeated they could be
piggybacked on packets but the point is
that there are two information blocks
that are transmitted from the receiving
from the ink from the egress back to the
ingress one is an optional bottle both
are optional they don't always have to
be included in every a key one would
contain the PSM this sequence number and
an absolute reception time such that we
get the delay signal that could then be
used for as a congestion indicator and
the other one building would contain an
occupied map that's based on the packet
sequence number and a delta indicating
the end of the the last psn of the
bitmap so that's the feedback and then
getting the feedback the ingress would
do something right it gets max or it
gets it so it learns about missing
missing sequence numbers from from this
occupied map or about catenaccio make a
decision that's somehow related to the
congestion estimate that it's taking
possibly use this young you know if that
if that works to somehow influence the
decision calculate late severe variation
from the timestamps in feedback blocks
and well and then it would either
retransmit or sent factory pair packets
depending on how design goes the egress
on forwarding it but you know effect is
used it would defect and it will have to
inform and holds about congestion if
needed so there is an opportunity here
to make it you know to to distinguish
between between congestion corruption
loss or some some other form of loss
loss that happens that isn't congestion
if we can do that something that I find
personally interesting about this as
people were saying you know this is what
introduced delay and it would you know
if you can't you know in the worst case
you know you'll have to you have to
inform the aunt systems about a lot loss
here I see that as an opportunity to
make use of ezn signaling you have an
systems today that uses yen and
basically no equipment inside the
network that makes use of ezn so here
there will be some equipment I could you
know basically you could turn a loss
notification into an easy end
notification with this right if you have
easy and capable sandals you can tell
them so that's a summary slide of the
information exchanged in tunnel mode on
forwarding the packet sequence number
tunnel type actually terrible flag that
would inform you that occasionally you
want to have this timestamp included
anything that's needed perfect and for
backward these two blocks one that
contains the timestamp the other one
that has this occupied map now just to
show that this whole thing could be done
in a much less intrusive way as well and
a very different way we get to this
transparent mode that's in the appendix
that's a bit more radical and the point
here is to to have the least intrusive
possible thing the goal is to never
delay anything and to not even tunnel
just
I'm just just discussing retransmission
you could do the same with FAQ you could
have all kinds of variations in between
the spectrum yeah but in the simplest
case you know you would on the on the
English side just forward and keep a
copy of the packets with the hash of a
packet so I you could identify it so
it's just taking a copy but forwarding
not adding any header or anything the
hash calculation made it many to include
data beyond IP but this is not relying
on a specific protocol anything it's
just taking the bytes and the egress
would answer in this idea here bodek it
couldn't neck right because we don't
have consecutively growing sequence
numbers we just have hashes and the AK
format could be similar to the tunnel
mode now the ingress upon seeing that
there's an RTO for one of the hashes
that it has it could make it make a
decision to retransmit packets that
could also be that should be done based
on a congestion estimate as before the
cost of a hash coalition in this whole
thing is kinda low because what that
would mean is you mister retransmit
opportunity if you if you have a hash
collision you just can't store it in
your cache so you've reduced the
probability of being able to reach and
submit something at the egress we'll
just forward so that that's you know in
that particular case that's all they
would be doing there wouldn't be any
reordering I think sending things on
without resequencing I mean yes you have
modern TCPS that can handle that well
you have rack you have experienced loss
detection mechanisms but I think it's
important to keep in mind that for TCP s
that don't have that or any mechanisms
that don't have that you know the worst
thing that would happen is that you
don't have the benefit of the region's
mission right it's not going to be any
worse if you just forward you just don't
have any benefit in in the worst case
then they're all done would be you
udp-based transports all kinds of
transports that might you know not have
a big problem with the reordering anyway
so there may not always be a need to
delay packets
sequencing to summarize this on
forwarding you wouldn't add anything
extra on back or backward you would have
roughly the same thing as before this
blocks one and two they would have to
look slightly different block one will
be limited in some way because this act
is Arabic flag doesn't exist we don't
have any forward information right yeah
and then everything is about hashes so
black two can't really have this
occupied map you know we could maybe you
have a bloom filter or something like
that some interesting way of encoding X
and that's that so the point is there's
a spectrum of possibilities here we're
not trying to nail it down to one
specific mechanism just yet rather the
idea could be that we could have a
framework that would allow to implement
several mechanisms in all cases it could
be pretty beneficial when the RTT on the
segment is much shorter than the
end-to-end rgt that's already well I
think these things have been said you
know while this next use that fact and
well I believe in the benefit of
reducing Talos yeah clarifying question
I don't I don't think that I mean we're
getting close to this lot of longer
discussions anyways oh yeah all right
[Music]
in excellent work on time management
thank you okay so so there are a number
of questions that come up with and again
and again some of them already have come
up just to answer a few of them so one
one misunderstanding you got early in
the process was that this was only for
encrypted traffic well it's for any
traffic and the message is that we can
work with encrypted traffic and loops
does not peak beyond layer three
well maybe the part numbers but not
beyond that so that doesn't mean that an
implementer couldn't apply some secret
sauce they still have from the pet days
and do wonderful things by digging
forward and combine them with groups but
we're not going to standardize those so
the solution we are discussing here is
based on don't look don't touch how do
we actually know which of the packets in
an aggregate are worth worth recovering
and the answer is Lukas doesn't have a
way to find out but there is a little
bit of an assumption that the the setup
mechanism the controller based setup
mechanism that you use for installing a
loops pair somewhere in the network
might also have a way for for the
ingress know to sort between the useful
recover ones and the ones where where
you wouldn't care Korea how how would he
have an insight into which ones were
better to recover well it might be part
number eighty-eight oh no so there may
be ways in
network you know oh this is an important
customer so we are going to to support
their application and this other
customer hasn't paid their dues so we
are not supporting their application
itself called Project something for
coming this completely out let's go out
of scope for this third question how do
we transport the measurement related
information or actually any reverse
informations so any measurement related
information that is going in the forward
direction probably would be put into the
encapsulation as a form of an extension
together with the sequence number so if
you would need to send a timestamp for
some reason we would put it there we're
not currently advocating for that and
the the reverse direction could be done
the same way we do with the AK
information so again that depends a bit
on the encapsulation if you have a
bi-directional tunnel you might be able
to piggyback it if your tunnel is Julie
directional you have to send several
packets for the X anyway and you can
include measurement information there
and you do the fullscreen thing again
code screen holds mean fullscreen
carsten yes David David black real quick
real quick note on your second FAQ which
says this is an l-3 only mechanism I
assume that's that that's intended to
scope for whatever whatever comes out of
here is that correct yes
okay one could point out and I apologize
not doing this during during the second
presentation and the satellite
presentation if you look at what a
satellite pepper does it does two things
one is it does some things here to to
deal with losses as soon as you can
figure out the size that something has
not bounced off the satellite the other
thing that it does is it MUX with the
transport protocol to grow the window
historically this was needed because
endpoints just didn't have enough
buffers to fill the pipe up with
satellite and back the former it would
be within scope for loops the latter
would be out and have to do it in the
transport protocol itself somehow okay
the question that comes up loops has
some cost even transparent load has some
cost because you have to send forward
and back the ancillary information how
do you know that this cost is actually
worth it and again we assume we have
some some Network intelligence some
controller thing that understands what's
going on in the network we may want to
put something in loops that might
actually enable the protocol to
dynamically be switched on and switched
off to make this quicker if the
assumption is something is providing the
information and providing the monitoring
that allows making that call yeah and I
think the the final question has been
answered but just to repeat we need
congestion relay we don't want to lose
information in this tunnel so we need to
do a dropping for non easy and capable
transports and yeah we can do this by by
dropping we can probably more usefully
do this by simply not doing
retransmissions when we know those would
be dropped for organization feedback
anyway okay so let's talk about related
work for a moment Cori has a better idea
I'm looking forward to him telling me
after the meeting so of course as we
said many of us have worked on systems
that did something like that some people
have first sent mail about interesting
papers about this we know that link
layers are doing that for us all the
time and if we look closely at these
link layers these are often tunnels
so yes this is being done and an
important part of the actual work will
be to get a better overview of what's
going on there does a custard so I'll
note that there's a lot of related work
as you say in the ITF but but the the
most sort of common thing that was
brought up today are pets and those we
don't have any idea because the vendors
of those boxes have had no interest in
an IGF standard ever right so I you know
has that changed it so bill those
vendors participate here or your are we
are we standardizing something that then
we'll never get actually shipped well I
can so I'm also about pimping is the
interest from the vendors that
traditionally this is very close to a
pet box but we don't standardize those
here we never have not for lack of
trying simple because the vendors
weren't interested has that changed at
other vendors that traditionally have
shipped these boxes for customers do
they want common standards in this space
now you think that's very much a
business decision for them well if they
decided that it's in their interest to
so what do you think that's a
prerequisite for doing this work yes I
don't things that is relevant here is
that that's a really good question for a
working group charter time
but I don't know if we're going to be
able to figure out the answer between
now and twelve o'clock that would guide
us on what we do after twelve o'clock so
I would encourage everybody to not have
a food fight about business models and
things like that but it is an important
question for us to talk about at charter
time I mean my answer would be that time
is playing for more and more software
based networks were much larger variety
of you know vendors are coming into play
so the opportunities I think are
something that we can try to leap onto
right now I don't think that traditional
hardware vendors might be the first ones
to pick up after the experience
was correctly recited but that's not the
market anymore alone today all right
Aaron Falk I want to respond to largest
point I think that I think that what
we've heard here is expression today of
operators who see this as a problem that
they want to have solved the fact that a
set of vendors doesn't want to solve
their problem for them is irrelevant
right somebody they want somebody step
forward and solve it they're asking you
if you have to do it if the ITF doesn't
do it then they'll find some other
solution that's what is what the pet
benders did so the economists word is
this is disruptive we don't need the
agendas that might be more discussion or
question no no we speak about pets but
this discussion is also relevant for all
the software define one equivalents that
are in the market today that are not
interoperable so if we want to
standardize something we may want them
to be to work together but there are
already lots of solutions that do this
kind of things and also something that I
think is missing if the discussions now
needs to distinguish whether the scope
is enterprise networks or public access
because as soon as we have public access
we have all these they're true
mechanisms that will break whatever we
just adding another layer on all the
existing layers okay I just want to give
a very specific example following
tallest comments regarding why we want
to standardize this for example we have
current we have an EMV function we have
vcp and the v8 way so they're possibly
provided by different different parties
so that's why I want to stand out
hi Stuart card critical technologies I
just have a couple of points on scoping
there's a focus on loss mitigation and
there's an assumption that we can really
only help when the round trip time on
the path segment is significantly
shorter than the end-to-end round trip
time neither of those need be the case
if you think of path segments as
essentially being transfer functions and
different path segments having different
statistical characteristics they are
different transfer functions and so the
end-to-end transport protocol is
presented with a composition of
functions that it may not be well able
to handle and so the different transport
protocols with which we are familiar
makes certain assumptions about those
statistical distributions and congestion
versus non congestion losses and so on
it may be that by simply taking a
segment that exhibits a different
statistical distribution that then the
end-to-end transport protocols are
anticipating and causing that segment to
conform more to the expected
distribution we may enhance end-to-end
performance even if the segments that we
are mitigating has a long round-trip
time and even if the underlying problem
is something other than laws yeah I
think that's particularly true if the
other segments contribute something to
how the decomposition feels in the end
the other segments segments are
completely lossless completely clear you
are not winning a lot Tom Harper so
thinking about the use cases this
actually looks a lot more like a piece
of QoS to me so we're basically offering
a well it does in the sense we're
offering a path with more reliability or
lower latency or something like that so
if you view it as that it sounds to me
like this could be considered one type
of QoS for a path and then something
like the pan or G or some of the other
efforts to make
qos aware networking might be applicable
so the application or the transport
layer may in fact know about this
information it could then adjust its
transport layer no you want to keep it
transparent to the end host but there
actually could be advantages if you
could somehow expose this to them yeah
there should could be advances to a path
away networking we are not solving this
problem in this room well I have a slide
on that one comment I know you want to
keep this completely independent and all
layer three but the second you have any
sort of multi path where you have you
can take possibly two segments you're
gonna have to make sure that you do that
per flow at the transport layer so it's
it's inevitable you're gonna have to
look beyond layer three or use the flow
label or an ipv6 or something like that
I just do one come up again when i was
III Brian Crandall my energy co-chair
had energy say it said like three times
so I was summoned um I would say that
the problems that we're trying to solve
here in loops are actually kind of
overlapped with a lot of the problems
that we're trying to solve energy the
approaches that we're looking at energy
are entirely different in that the
energy we're looking at taking the this
information whatever measurement
information you get from the path that
goes into the deeps ingress point we're
actually taking it and taking it all the
way to the endpoint right like so we
have a completely different name we want
to modify the endpoint so that it can do
paths where sort of stuff that being
said there's a big question going on in
panner G as to what is an endpoint is a
tunnel ingress midpoint also an endpoint
maybe I don't know so one of the
outcomes of this lake so things that are
a little bit less engineering uni a
little bit more research he could
certainly come over to panner G and be
digested a little while and then come
back to the idea I think that's that's a
way to do it so I Aaron Falk again I
just we shouldn't lose the sort of
initial insight from your
you're opening science which is that the
concept here is to fix packet loss close
to where it happens
which is not what and in fact or energy
stuff is trying to do now
maybe there are other benefits but
that's part of the trade-off space right
that if you know you're you have a good
put increase if you are able to do that
so I just think we shouldn't lose track
of that thank you okay now to my
presentation have really sad yet I
wanted to quickly point to four pieces
of work inside the aisle I eat EF and
actually in one case inside the IRT F
that are interesting in this context one
of course there's lots of work on
measurements and we want to stand on the
shoulders of those people and not on
their feet there is actually some work
already on ER loops like recovery thing
going on which you have noticed yet
because it's happening at the internet
layer there is the the network coding
Research Group work and the TSV work in
particular on sliding-window IVC I'm
singling this out because it seems to be
the next thing we want to touch but
there of course other things we want to
learn yet there and there is something
called tunnel congestion feedback so
let's talk about these four things
quickly I am or Institute OAM is used to
collect information within the package
why the package traverses a path between
two points in the network so it's about
hop hop hop hop information it might
return the measurement to a third party
using postcards and yeah my observation
would be loops is really about an
ingress and egress pair and not about
lots of hops so at some point we won't
may want to mix that
in some form so rubies may be able to
make use of information that i ôm
provides but right now this seems to be
a little bit different i also uses the
generic information model approach which
is not new in the IP PM community so we
can certainly learn something from there
so we can map our protocol to multiple
formats and speaking about formats the
data formats that the IP PM people have
developed and maybe some measurement
methods are of course things that may be
applicable so that's rated rogue number
one related work number two the 6lowpan
fragment recovery word came up in 2008
in the 600 plan but in a world where I
was to chairing it I have spent the last
10 years mainly and in trying it not to
make sure it doesn't happen but at some
point the 6lowpan group was decided to
replace but the 6-2 working group and so
on and this is now no down it has passed
working with last call in the 6th over
Europe and we'll hit the iesg soon now
this is a little bit different because
it's about fragments within a packet
it's not about packets and and a number
of parameters constrain the situation a
lot so that actually may be more
attractable than it would have been in
the global Internet and yeah of course
again the congestion control issues the
the interesting one and the question
about the control loops working against
each other
so this is work that's going on and I
would expect other pieces of work will
be going on in the ITF at some point
when it's really needed so I think it
would be good to bring these things
together in groups I mean I don't mean
stopping this work but just learning
from it and going forward
the sliding window fec I think is
interesting which has has left the
network according research group and is
now in TS vwg draft and that's certainly
something that will go into a good
loop's solution and finally there is the
channel congestion feedback framework
well yeah this is one one more of those
TS WG drafts they've like mentioned a
few more ones that we may want to use
there is an IP fix mapping in there we
may want to use that as a source of
information elements that need to be
part of loops okay I'm doing this really
quickly I just want to say what is
really out of scope of loops and really
the the litmus test here is do you need
host participation to make this happen
and well Panaji is about host
participation Erin sorry I just I just
want to challenge your framing of this
question because it seems to me that you
know we're motivating this by several
operators who say they have a problem
you know I think would be they haven't
said that the host participation is
impossible from their point of view that
it is that it is a it's a requirement
that the host cannot participate I'd be
interested in knowing whether that's
actually the case or not yeah maybe I
should have been more specific because
in the slide that John showed you have
this leaps loops thing in one of the end
hosts but the interesting thing about
this loose thing is in an actual
implementation this would be in the VPN
layer it would not influence the
transport layer in the host so you're
talking about the solution not the
problem I'm trying to understand the
problem right yes I don't care whether
loops is the solution yet until I
understand what the
that is trying to get off like if I
could just do it your interrupt here it
would have been reasonable for us to say
at the beginning of Carson's
presentation that this is Carson's view
and these are the things that the we
could talk about a chart you know and
probably really a charter time so it's
not necessary for us to to figure out
what all the linkages are really but to
figure out where we need to be with you
know with observations like Erin's so
thank you yeah thank you that thank you
so it's almost like that did I hear you
it's out of scope from my current of
three years yeah but I mean why because
we want to solve the tractable problem
first before we do the interactive real
ones and how do you make the judgment
call about what's tractable or not
shorter time yes I'd say I mean there is
there there is no reason to try to
constrain you know the specification of
the solution to something that you must
not deploy however you figure out also
on the Intel's right the point is that
this thing works best if there is not a
deployability block that is caused by
hosts this is really what I'm trying to
say nobody said you must deploy it on
the host the the the the way I perceived
what you were saying is that you exclude
the you know option to even do it on the
host or the host is a node I think the
question has been noted you end the
community needs to be aware of that
question as we discuss things further so
I think this really helps clarifying the
concern yeah so the point is if we do
this right it doesn't require host
people to do something now there is one
other thing for instance the the spin
bit discussion in increase
if that creates something that could be
used that's great if the problem that
you're trying to solve with loops is on
the last or first help to the host how
do you solve it well maybe solving it
second the difference between the the in
network case and the case where the host
is involved is that with the host a
number of additional considerations come
in like how do you actually do the setup
what are the privacy considerations and
so on know as you yes you just brought
the example right if you basically
simply do it sure implementation
questions decide just you know as part
of the network layer in the host stack
then you're having exactly the same
architectural model you're just also
able to include the first last hops yes
in the solution so I don't think we
should go beyond that but that option
certainly shouldn't be excluded so I
think we are actually moving past the
end of Carson's last slide and into
technical discussion so like to thank
you Carson program leaving this section
of the are for sharing the maps and gaps
analysis that you've done so far very
helpful and I think we are - open mic
time we have a timer running for just a
little under 17 minutes for us to talk
and then we have ten minute we measure
will go off and we'll have like 10
minutes to talk about humps and things
like that so please make please make
your comments please make them succinct
Brandon Williams Akamai just one quick
thing about the previous talk for
completeness Network coding research
group is also looking specifically
satellite use cases it would be valuable
for for you to track that as well thank
you
but Briscoe again I just wanna I said I
might come back to this and I'm coming
back to it I've not heard an answer to
the question I don't get why you want to
do something on an overlay that's
relatively easy on a link and the link
if the link knows it's bad it do it
because they want to sell their
technology so why try and fix something
that someone else has got the motivation
to fix anyway and they can do it really
easily and it's really difficult to do
just slightly above that layer it just
doesn't make sense to me that's actually
interesting because in a rational world
you would be right but there's a bad
coming years if there's a ssin may not
be the person that owns the name yeah
that's the answer to the question are
you talking equipment build a person or
operator person yes both but what I was
saying is that those that develop
technology have a standard idea at they
are chiefly or whatever link technology
they they have a perfectly good
motivation to do link layer
retransmission if it's going to make
their link better so I'm no longer a
satellite person so John can stand up
and correct me but just use a satellite
link as an example but it you know any
any physical layer right when you design
the data transmission for the link you
basically make an effort I'm going to
try so hard to get the data through and
then at some point I'm going to give up
and there's sort of an economics
they're like you know how much data can
I consistently get through under what
conditions you make an assumption on how
that link is going to be used by the
person who designs and runs the link
often knows very little about the
application and within the application
owners or the various parties that are
in between the app the the end
application user and the link designer
may have very different ideas of how
that link is going to be used and if if
the link is better than they need nobody
complains
except maybe about price the only goes
worse than they need then you then some
other party has to try to improve the
data throughput right and that's what
we're talking about now right the in
going the assumption here is that the
link is not good enough right otherwise
you don't deploy this at all yet once
the link is if the link is good enough
then we don't have this conversation
[Music]
Danny the other case that you talked
about is we are that the person who
wants to make the optimization sees a
path that person doesn't have access to
all the individual links okay has the
part and it once said they want to
optimize the usage of their path but I
actually wanted to give another example
we are what you said it's not working
either net is standardized by Triple E
and wireless Wi-Fi is kind of trying to
be like either and there is one
constraint in Ethernet that IP doesn't
have which is even as the sequence
preserving IP is not sequence designer
so we can do things at layer 3 that you
came up to weight layer 2 which is weird
but it's the current situation yeah I
was just thinking - Aaron had said no I
was thinking that they big change that
you're proposing needs to be split into
two parts the other I power on the
sequence not preserving pop and and and
once the link people know they don't
have to keep the thing from sequence
preserved then they've got a different
way of fixing their links you know
currently they do it to a certain level
and then they think I can't wait any
longer to get this retransmission
because I've got to keep everything in
order
I'm buttering up a receiver but if they
can relax that constraint then we don't
well the paper I sent on me on the loops
list a couple of days ago says how you
can now know where the racks being used
or not and so or something like
something that's less order okay so Cory
first and we said was it a transport
thing if you start fiddling with
ordering and changing the transport
properties of your path and this is
certainly a transport topic Tom Herbert
so to me it seems like the biggest now
use case of something like loops would
be a long path delay say over the
Internet where one of those segments
within that is low delay but possibly
high loss and to me it sounds like that
would be a mobile network satellites
interesting but that seems like that
already has a long delay so I'm
wondering or guests asking are there
applications in mobile world where we do
have that situation like at the last hop
or Radio Network getting to that point
that could be that low low delay high
loss is there value for loops in that
scenario or is everything already
covered by some layer to retransmissions
that's not an issue
Spencer Dawkins speaking as an
individual contributor
I like Tom's question and I would offer
as a semi friendly amendment what if
there are two what if there are two
network segments like that and and that
that you know it seems to me that we
can't really guarantee that there would
there would only be one and so to the
extent that there is more than one
I think that changes the way we look at
the problem well look at it this way
what's the most common use case so we
have our mobile phone connecting to a
wireless network eventually it gets into
the intranet and goes to Google or
whatever so I'm assuming that that later
part is already pretty highly reliable
but the longer latency but I'm really
interested in it is that short path
where we could definitely have high loss
and to me if Luke's is optimizing that
and it seems like the key here is if
we're going to do these retransmissions
it has to be so fast that that really
doesn't affect the end-to-end view of
delay so if you can slip this in and
save a packet loss as opposed to
increasing delay then and there's a
value yeah I would also maybe observed
that when Aaron and I were co-chairing
milk the B common case of what people
were optimizing for was like 56 kilobits
links so you know I think we should
probably think towards the future as
well
it's Ducard kernel technologies just a
specific example of such a low latency
high loss case I Triple E 802 that 11 P
wireless access and VA theater
environments dedicated short range
communications especially when you're
handing off from one access point to
another
totally sacred I missed the beginning so
I'm not quite sure if the scope was more
about you know dealing with congestion
loss on on congestion loss right what I
would say is that traditionally you know
the non congestion loss is something
that you know subnets try to get rid of
but you know if we look through the
industry that hasn't always been very
successful so I think one of the
questions would really be you know how
awaiting the scope of you know
congestion laws local solving and non
congestion loss local solving right and
I think it would really be nice to have
something that's more generically
applicable to all type of subnets if you
have a shocking subnet where it doesn't
you know the provided mechanisms of that
layer to submit are not good enough to
deal with the loss it has the non
congestion
we've cleared the mic line which I find
amazing we have about 17 minutes until
we're through so it may be time for us
to move back to the questions to get us
right so the biggest one do we
understand a problem and I don't know
Spencer do you think we should have a
discussion on each of these or should we
try to do humps as we go we have 17
minutes but we've only has 6 already 6
16 minutes but we've only got 16 minutes
let's do humps and see if we need to do
a discussion on the no that's wrong okay
prepare so those who think that we do
understand the problem can you please
hum now thank you and those who do not
think we understand the problem please
hum now
okay - yeah 6040 perhaps but yes we so
so we made it we made the right yeah we
made the right choice by having it now
worker forum Bob hi Aaron Falk again let
me try not to kill you what I think I
heard because this was exactly my mind
in thinking that this question which is
we have identified a bunch of problems I
don't think we've identified how they
group together to become the problem
there's a bunch of there's work that's
going on there's a lot of history here
there's stuff that is kind of outside
the scope of the IETF and it's that
there's mechanisms that are happening
way down in the staff
and in the applications and I have not
come away from this discussion with a
clear idea of the thing the thing that's
unaddressed that there needs to be work
on so that's that's what I heard
I was trying some 70% policy modulation
I understand the problem so I think it
very much depends on a lot of the scope
details right so I haven't heard you
know just vague sub sensation of trying
to differentiate between different
traffic right obviously congestion
control expectations of this adhesive e
are different from TCP right would we be
willing to do that and the whole
discussion of why the heck would we want
to exclude the last thing so
understanding comes a little bit through
the refinement of the scope and I hope
that we can solve this for me 30 percent
remaining I burn caramel no hats at this
point the so I hunt yes because actually
I think we've understood this problem
for the past quarter century and we've
had the problem for the baryon
supporters entry and we've come up with
a bunch of bad solutions for it right so
the the the thing that I'd like to see a
refinement of is one a little bit of the
refinement of the scope but to a little
bit more of the fun none of us not the
scope of the problem but also scope of
the solution great like so a little bit
more discussion about which exact subset
of the we do not have complete
clairvoyance for every past segment of
transport problem do we want to solve
here and then a little bit more of the
the reducing down the solution space to
something tractable I think this this
ball was a very good sort of start to
that and I'd like to see you continue
but yeah that's why I hummed yes and
still came up with a mic line and thank
you to the presenters and everyone who
participated for that
yeah given that we half of us don't
understand the problem yes should we see
what they know so one one way for us to
rephrase the question now is that I
think I heard assertions from multiple
people out of the research community
that at least some parts of this are
engineering so as long as some parties
can answer engineering to the previous
thing because there was some comments on
the microphone that made it an important
distinction between the program and the
scope of the problem
I think 60% of the room answered the
question do we understand the problem in
40% and such I don't understand the
scope of the problem and can we so so if
I was going to do a friendly amendment
to the question that's on the screen I
think I would be suggesting something
like is there engineering are people
ready are there things that we talked
about today that were ready to do
engineering that don't need additional
research and I was thinking in before
the buff that if we had enough people
show up saying I'm working on this now
that that was at least some people have
thought that but the microphone lines
are open as they say yeah you're caught
too quickly looking at the first bullet
I was actually humming with the question
in mind whether we have a common
understanding everybody may have their
own idea of what the problem might turn
out to be useful to have a common one
and I'm I haven't Gilly that hasn't come
across to me
Colin Perkins with with no hats
[Music]
is this Engineering or is it research I
would say that big chunks of this are
engineering and parts of it are probably
still research but I think that's okay
this could be a good topic at the IRS GE
dinner I mean you know I mean to expand
a bit I think there's enough of this
which is engineering that there is a
useful IETF work we can do there are
bits I think we don't know don't
necessarily know how to solve I think we
don't necessarily need to know how to
solve them all to do an initial version
of this yeah it wouldn't be the first
time the ITF has chartered a group but
we don't have all of the answers at the
beginning so stiffening up I come back
to that question which I had originally
I read here is this engineering or is
research required blah blah blah I would
say absolutely there is research
required maybe not technically research
but I think I think base insufficient
input on whether there is actually a
demand for such a standard for
standardized solution that I do not see
personally david black i hummed no on
not nourishing a problem because basic
please come what I heard some matches
mine which is a bit concerned about the
scope is our problem here yeah that's
probably more than one I've heard
discussion wander back and forth across
levels two three and four and I think I
want to see a focus a clear focus on one
of the levels with a clay defined scope
to change my hum from no to yes thank
you
Aaron Falk again so I think what I heard
very clearly was a proposed set of
requirements for a protocol something
that operates over a subset of the path
doesn't involve the endpoints works on
IP is transport independent and doesn't
modify packets as they go what I'm not
clear on is a
how important is that how useful is it
how what what set of problems it solves
having said that you know I'm not
opposed to seeing somebody go and build
something like that and try it out I
don't know if I would recommend that it
be used on the internet or what problems
it's going to be useful for but so to me
this is even with that statement it's
not obvious to me it's it's in the the
gray area between the IRT F work in ITF
work I wouldn't actually be opposed to
it in either place I'd kind of like to
see the thinking of how this could work
move forward I would also like to see it
not interfere with some of the other
ideas for improving things like effect
and quick and the panel G stuff so I you
know I say if people won't work on this
they should be able to work on it I
wouldn't stand in the way I don't think
it's necessarily a bad thing just don't
think we should over promise what its
gonna do was hurt occurred I say I guess
with my IAB had half kill turd because I
have questions I'm not a statement or
iam so I the whole point of the IRT F
and I'm very glad that there's people
here that are working on that part of
the area if it's not me the whole point
of the RTF is to eventually transition
work into the IETF for Standardization
and I think that this this whole baath
shows that there is no an effort or
desire to to transition to something
that might actually work
I do think that the proponents and the
research side need to get together and
seems like there's sort of a split
between groups and they really need to
sit in a room and say okay what elements
are ready for transition and what it's
still in research and if solutions exist
great now is the time to to push those
forward into standards so they can
actually be deployed and and put into
interoperability the one concern I have
is whether the research community in
particular agrees that there aren't
issues that are hiding where even though
the engineering side may say we think we
have a
Ellucian the research cited say no you
know we haven't actually figured out
like the whole house congestion getting
away and how are we going to make sure
that we're not actually building adding
that the engineering solution doesn't
add to the problem that's just my
thoughts I think you know the list of
places that we need to look look at for
this work in addition to just what we're
thinking about here I think that's going
to be not a short list thank you
Andrew Berg Riga I think the answers to
the first two questions very strongly
depend on what the scope turns out to be
because there are things in here where
I'm sitting there is research required
in the potential scope of this and there
are other things which you're like yeah
sure we can do that that's fine so yeah
it really does require a very careful
discussion on scope so Carson has been
standing there for a long time you wanna
go now a lot of people who think
researchers required some of the
questions that came up today I'm really
hearing that people think there is
research required on the things that
we're trying to do sorry yeah I look a
control loop response reply you know
yeah
control it yeah I'm I'm still not very
sure about how all this interacts
between different layers so there's this
transport questions and there's ops
questions and I guess this routine
questions here and I'd like to see which
ones of laws actually have concerns and
by whom because the the use case we saw
was simple but our people signed up
against those two use cases or do they
have more and so so I see questions here
and I think these are research questions
that we don't see data now with the
answers
let me clarify this what we need to do
is standardized protocol what we also
need to do is understand how to
correctly use that protocol all the
mechanisms so TCP was standardized in
1983 or something and 76 how you look at
it and we are starting to understand the
mechanisms now and I think we can go
ahead and do a mechanism the mechanism
work do protocol work excuse me
on loops now and fully understanding
that we will have five years or so
looking at all the research questions
that finally go into DBC piece on how to
best one it's on I continue to believe
that a basic version of loops can be
built today so there are some existence
proofs and I didn't understand that the
purpose of this path was to find out
whether there's commercial interest or
we would have done more working so yes
there's lots of interesting research
waiting for us that is going to go into
busy piece at some point but the
protocol stuff should be possible to
grow the first version of that so if I
could do an ad interrupt everybody stay
at the microphones that still at the
microphones Magnus asked if I could do a
hum if people believe that
standardization in this space is
required is required or if if it's not
and if you think that it's not a few hum
does not feel you know feel free to hop
up to the mic lines we've got about men
and I have to go but we'd be interested
in hearing could I ask for hum of people
who think that standardization in this
space is required
can we clarify the question yes
standardization in this space required
required is a strange way of phrasing
this little wait a second if you don't
get to change the question the chairs
ask the question would it be beneficial
we standardization be desirable of
beneficial I think right so those who
think that standardization in this space
is beneficial or desirable can you
please hum now and those who do not
think it's desirable or needed please
hum now okay we are at 25 seconds left
to go in our time is I'm doing it so let
me bring up an important point right so
nobody talked about I think analyzing
what's already out there in the market
there are a lot of proprietary solutions
to do these things they may cover a lot
of IPR
but they may also set a good amount of
references of you know what we could
achieve and you know showing what we
want to achieve compared to to that
stuff so it's ugly work to try to do
that analysis but I think it would be
very helpful thank you and that's
actually it's actually where we hand the
mic to the ad so on this last frame
who's actually willing to do active work
of looking at what's doing and working
on the scoping and we have some hands
okay we have some 15 hands that's good
great so my conclusions here is that the
scoping etcetera in small discussion we
have the loops but loops mailing lists
to do things so please if you're not
already subscribed go there and let's
have some discussions about scope etc
and what's what's available or not and
let's be done okay thank you everyone
see you on the mailing list