we're just testing the mic but we can
start anyway so welcome to idea Friday
morning met Reggie session I'm Mia
criminal and I'm Dave Wonka
I thought marrying you that but other
people might not know yeah so this is an
IIT of session we also have basically a
note well which is kind of aligned with
the ietf note well but slightly
different terms but I guess you've seen
that what this note well is actually not
pointing at is the code of conduct and
harassment policy but it's also
important things to note so please be
aware of all these things this is the
user site which is in there for your
convenience with our mailing list and
and also the jabber room and the link to
this session may need to look it up
later
and this is our today's agenda just a
couple things I wanted to mention about
the status of the group and things that
are really healthy and mapper G as well
you know we have a lot of people we
always have a packed agenda as we do
today and we'll work our way through
here one of the things I wanted to
mention is the last couple meetings I've
went to PRG the privacy enhancement and
assessment research group that's
measurement related as well and they're
doing some interesting things so look
for opportunities I think to sync up
with what they're doing and watch what
they're doing especially when it's about
privacy with measurements the the next
thing let's go the next slide so this is
the way I was greeted when I got my
badge this week none Blanca and it may
be they are anticipating that I won't be
there at the next in Singapore so so we
have one Blanca this time in non-pom
Connect next time can you go to the next
slide so Mary and I were going to call
for an alternate or additional map our
gt-r chair we've been running for about
four years
I'm not meaning to step
from it but we could certainly use help
with another person when we're covering
meetings in different parts of the globe
so if you're planning to attend IHF 106
in Singapore and are interested to work
with the two of us on preparing the
agenda and and vetting and reviewing the
candidate work there let us know we're
especially looking for someone who is in
academia not because it's a credential
that you need just because we're both in
industry right now and you might have
some contacts that we don't have oranges
upon so it's not a requirement but but
if you have that you might like to join
and then like I said you'd be able to
curate the upcoming program which is
kind of fun and it's a little bit of
work about like Miria this time for
instance did a lot of legwork contacting
people to get to get the program filled
out so feel free to write us about that
I think is that the last thing we had
there yeah that's the last of that so
our our first presentation is going to
be is going to be a remote because Yoder
song is in New Zealand and it's very
late there so we're gonna let them go
first
and let's see your are you in the I see
it in Java are minute sorry in the
Medeco huh hello hi we can hear you fine
we're you're ready to go hi everybody my
name is Yoda so I will be presenting the
paper understanding evolution and
adoption of up level domains in DNS sick
this paper was recently published in the
2019 I Triple E imminent measurements in
the networking conference and other
co-authors of this paper are Surya
Ramachandran and dr. Anika mohanty both
also from the University of offered an
excitement so we focus from the
top-level domain and speaking about
domain in the das hierarchy and we also
provide a brief overview of the ASIC
implementation in New Zealand
specifically
generic top-level domain or ggod is one
that does not represent a country for
example calm organi and a key motivation
for this study was the new GT program
introduced by egg-cam which introduced
over a thousand theories through the
internet since 2013 next likely so
that's a timeline of the generic
top-level domains and when they were
introduced so in this presentation we
will classify generic top-level domains
into three groups owed for the ones
created in the 1980s early for those
created between 2001 and 2012 in a new
generic top-level domain for our
thousands of new generic top-level
domains introduced since noon we will
also look at country code top-level
domains OCC Tod later on next slide so
in terms of related work
let's paper exchange upon the 2015 paper
in analyzing top-level domain and
second-level domain adoption we also
later on briefly look at being s
implementations specifically in context
of the New Zealand public domain NZ next
time for data collection we used two
different sources for our data so we
collected packet traces from the campus
network of University of Auckland which
is the largest university in New Zealand
was over 40,000 users in addition we
also collected metadata for an internet
NZ the manager of NZ New Zealand
national top-level domain for three
national level data sets meaning
classified the generic top-level domains
into the three categories old early and
new based on the time of introduction
and finally we carried out pub level
domain and DNS sick analysis in it looks
like so moving on to the results next
slide for trace over
you we found the number of DNS queries
to grow between 2013 and 2018 was the
proportion of requests to early G
theories new G theories and country code
top-level domains are increasing while
there has been a lot of growth in the
new generic top-level domains compared
to 2013 they still only account for
around 0.3 percent of total requests in
the local campus network next time in
terms of the top 10 most queried
top-level domains we find some common
generic top-level domains that calm
donate door and in terms of low country
code top-level domains the NZ not a UN
dot cm for New Zealand Australia and
China or regularly appeared in at opt in
every year there were no new general
public domains at all in the top 10 in
any of the years and for early early
generic top-level domains the only one
to appear was not info in 2014 and 2018
next time so for unusual top-level
domain usage we notice the country code
top-level domain for Slovakia or SK 2
ranked 4th in both 2017 and 2018 we
found over 99% of these DNS requests to
actually be machine generated as part of
antivirus software used by the
University so different from the fully
qualified domain names of usual websites
such as say wo comm we find a fully
qualified domain names of these machine
generated requests to be much longer and
containing seemingly random combination
of alphanumeric digits so while there
was rapid growth in the number of
queries to Slovak and SK TOB we found
that this ghost was not actually driven
by human activity but rather just the
machine generated
DNS requests next
we also found in terms of unusual
clearly usages that the country called
pop like the country code top-level
domains which were not restricted to
only the citizens of that region may be
often used as generic top-level domains
instead
for example the thought IO country code
top-level domain for the British Indian
Ocean Territory was topped here most
most query in both 2017 and 2018 and
this was not due to interest in the
region itself but rather because the
top-level domain is quite popular among
startups and open source projects online
so the IO and several other similar
country code top-level domains they are
now heavily used as general public
domains instead are now classified by
Google as GCC Tod or generic country
code public or domains similarly we also
found that you the usage can be used by
domain hack or concatenating sections of
the fully qualified domain name to form
a different name so for example as is
commonly seen in youtube link shortener
YouTube PE which uses the top PE country
code top-level domain for Belgium so
what may now be a country code top-level
domain may be more accurately described
as a generic top-level domain in the
future so the top level domain
classifications we identified earlier
will need to be regularly updated to
reflect that changes next time in terms
of Tod grows from 2013 to 2018 we find a
number of queries to new generic
top-level domains to far outpace the old
generic top-level domains and there was
also some spillover effect into the
country code top-level domains where the
generic top-level generic
country code top-level domains as
classified by Google grew at a much
faster rate than on generic country code
top-level domains next slide for these
ranked frequency plots the top one is
fall 2013
and the bottom is for 2018 so between
these weekend most notably see growth in
the number of new generic top-level
domains we can also observe there there
was this zips though in old and early
junior top-level domains and let learn
new Jeff top-level domains are much less
concentrated as shown in the flatness
slope in the graphs next time in
addition to top-level domains we also
looked at second-level domains so in
this example here the dock hole for
company before that ends it New Zealand
country code top-level domain it's the
second-level domain so similar to the
new gTLD program by I came the second
level domains in New Zealand were open
to public registration in 2014 so this
means that instead of choosing from one
of 15 predefined second-level domains a
company can theoretically use any name
as the second-level domain so the
second-level domains account for over
twenty percent of all new domains but
only account for 0.6% after a total
requests in the local network next time
so right so one of the potential
problems from opening both general
top-level domain and second level domain
registration to the public is that there
could potentially be overlaps between
the tree for example QE is a term used
to describe New Zealanders and currently
there is both a doc Kiwi top-level
domain as well as a doc Kiwi the NZ
second-level domain and the New Zealand
in the top-level domain we found an
unusually high number of Kirito
NZ domains registered shortly right
after their release as shown a spike in
a graph which we think could be due to
cyprus for him from those who already
have stock kiri domains and wanted to
avoid others registering for similar
domains today all next time so for the
SI being a sick overview we found a
spike in the DNS SEC implementation in
only 16 likely from cloud Freya's
introduction of universal dns sick we
also found that since noon and secured
that equations are slowly growing again
and now while the proportion of signed
domains with expired signatures has
decreased quite significantly since the
invaded district holes still remain high
with little improvement over the last
few years
next slide so fulla takeaways next time
the takeaways for the domain names so we
find nearly introduced your top level
domains and not ends it second-level
domains to grow in popularity but still
not very heavily used yet advantage of
new general public or domains is that
the cause is this publicly concentrated
in the most popular domains cyber cyber
squatting on a large skillet
theoretically that's feasible compared
to cyber squatting on the older generic
top-level domains however a potential
problem we found is the overlap between
similar domain names and the top-level
domain at second-level domain level
which will require further coordination
in the application stage to prevent this
from happening next time so for Dina is
sick we found the implementation in New
Zealand is growing but chain of trust is
incomplete main problem being that the
incorrect Deus trickles without which it
is not possible to authenticate the
public TS key records in the chasm we
found an improvement in reduction of
expired signatures as a proportion of
the total signed domains which we see as
a growth for a basic implementation in
New Zealand next time so finally the
concluding remarks so in this paper we
presented a longitudinal analysis on the
adoption of new generic top-level
domains and the deployment of DNS sick
in new zealand new generic top-level
domains are growing in popularity but
still not very popular yet
we believe there needs to be more work
done on exploring the top level domain
topic further before the second round of
new generic top-level domain
applications in the future thank you
thanks eurozone so we've got time for
Q&A and I see George's up at the mic
over here so let's go there hello hello
George Michael from a pinna cue can hear
us yes so I think a study like this
needs to explore the concept of D G a or
generative domain names hash names which
are a mechanism for command and control
in botnets and so aspects of behavior in
the new gTLDs relate strongly to
compliance checks on how you justify
your need for a name the old gTLDs and
ccTLDs
tend to be harder places to get a name
and the newer younger TLDs often are
attractive targets for bad actors you
talked about ESET using hash names and
machine generated names for good purpose
but I think you have to address the
question of the use of hash names for
bad purpose the second thing is that
many of the new TLDs have no intention
of offering delegation services to wider
public industry dot iBM is not an open
domain it is a private closed domain and
its growth will be a function of IBM's
mission it's not a function of a market
process it's a function of their need
for labels under IBM the third and last
comment is that you typify cctlds
as if there was some normative behavior
that is prescribed by ICANN but the
quality of a ccTLD is that it reflects
an independent
economical nation-state that in effect
is a UN chartered entity that has
standing as government it's not about a
contract binding or a belief of meaning
it's about the fact that they have an
army and so they are only different in
the quality that they own tanks and not
specifically that any legalisms govern
what they do but your paper was very
interesting and thank you for presenting
it thank you
Tim Tim welcome back actually quickly
ask you to step over to the other mic
because that's where the video is
currently okay hi now I'm on video so
thanks thanks for your talk what I would
be interested in and maybe you can a
little a little bit elaborate on that is
where did you did that get the data or
which kind of data did you have for your
analysis so you talked about you had a
collaboration with the top-level domain
registry but what did they gave you and
how did which which kind of measurements
or analysis did you do doing that data
so know what's in this so they were in
the presentation that was specifically
the DNS SEC overview graph as well as
the second-level domains created over
time for Kirito ends it's like okay
you've got like these numbers from them
or yet like I suppose you didn't get any
zone files or something like this way
you did measurement okay and as the last
remark I just wanted to drop the ripe
Atlas Project if you want to do again as
like measurement stuff you can also do
like any kind of DNS records they're
also limited to direct geographical
regions or something like this that
might be interesting for future research
Thanks thank you
now this is a lush pizza from the
Swedish in the registry first I want to
say to George we are not a government
agency we never have been
you never will be the Swedish government
has not been involved in the running of
the dot se registry and for the record
we don't own tags so it CCTA these are
really very wrong over the map so but
back to the topic you said that there is
a lot of domains more domains signing
the NSA then there is domains of sending
India's records and in that I would like
to know do these newly signed domains
support the CD s CDNs key because that
is then something that registries could
actually use to foster the adoption of
the NSA further metadata we were
available I don't think this information
was available for us to see so I can't
comment on that
thank you thank you Ben Schwartz Google
you mentioned that 10% of DS records you
you saw were invalid you clarify what
you what you mean by invalid here so for
example are you saying that those
domains if I tried to resolve them
through a validating recursive would
fail with surveil I believe it's the
recall don't match with the hash of
child child the ASCII records but I'm
not entirely sure on that okay thank you
thank you Cosmo could you enough room
Jake could you could you speak up to the
mic Ilocos Sur Cosmo could you honor
whom JP arias about
top ten mostly low tier de Graaff I get
a Sameera I know I see you by using loo
talks about data under which data do you
use the most queries will based on local
campus network local the campus network
we okay I see thank you and if I could
ask one last question your song the you
mentioned in your takeaways the problem
of the overlap for instance the doc
heated at TVNZ I was just curious how
effect how effective can one be it at
identifying that those are essentially
clones or what are the methods that you
use or you can imagine we can use to
determine that are there essentially
aliases do you have to do active
measurements or can you determine it
passively from from the registrations we
actually didn't look specifically into
the domains that appear in tough human
doc here we go ends it but I think that
we can look into that further in the
future
alright um well have a good evening
thanks for staying up late and
presenting this work to us and let's a
round of applause for Tommy Tommy we're
ready for you
[Music]
thank you so Tommy's coming back to
update us I think for the third time
maybe on yes if this is hi I'm Tony
Polly and I'm gonna be sharing some
client measurements that we've taken I'm
at Apple and so this is information that
we get from looking at sampling from iOS
and Mac OS devices previously we've
shared a lot of information about how we
see ipv6 adoption I'm gonna be sharing a
little bit about that now but one of the
new cool things that's happening is that
we see a new protocol version TLS one
three coming out and ramping up and I
wanted to share some information about
how we see this happening so as some
background on what we're looking at here
TLS 1/3 was published as RFC eight four
four six last August
been in development for a while but
things were not really I'm deploying it
at marked scale yet now on our clients
we enabled TLS one three by default for
pretty much all connections in March and
so this was my OS 12.2 had Mac OS 10 dot
14.4 so at this point we were able to
start collecting data about how often we
see TLS one three actually being
negotiated with servers that our client
devices are talking to and you know
anecdotally we had heard and I think
many people are aware of TLS 1 3 being
rolled out we were aware that many
server deployments were turning it on in
some percentage and increasing it and
ramping up support but I at least I have
not seen a lot of data
I'm shared from either server side or
client side of exactly what scale we are
seeing yet I would love to see data that
anyone else is willing to share but we
thought we would kind of take a step
here and let people see how the adoption
is going so the questions that we asked
before looking at the data was first how
much server adoption are we
seeing of TLS 1/3 from the perspective
of the clients like how much is this
growing and then also one of the key
things about TLS 1/3 from a measurement
perspective is that it's supposed to
have some performance benefits in almost
all cases it can shave off one round
trip from the handshake time so we want
to see is this actually playing out in
reality how is this actually improving
the overall connection establishment
time that we see from the client so
before I get into the data just some
notes on the methodology we are
collecting this data on a per connection
basis and in this case it's a per TLS
connection we're not looking at for this
data anything that's not a connection
that has TLS enabled on it and this is
all going over TCP what we're collecting
is the TLS version how long the TLS
handshake took the alp n value that we
negotiated over TLS is this HTTP 1 or HP
2 as well as information about the
address families are we going over v4 v6
and our v4 v6 enabled on the network
that we're connecting over and so
because of all of this what we're
representing in general is the amount of
TLS 1/3 that is being used
this is not strictly the number of
servers or the percentage of servers
that have enabled 1/3 but rather like
the percentage of popular servers or how
often our clients really using this in
practice we imagine of course that there
is a long tail of things that have not
turned on new protocols but that users
don't often access and the data for this
presentation is being collected over
around a three month period this
represents April to June and it's a
random sample of for those devices and
those users who have opted in to data
collection point zero five percent of
all the connections so there's a large
scale of connections and this is getting
a lot of data but it's a small sample of
it
all right so here we see a trend over
the three months we are sampling the
green is the amount of teal s13 that we
see compared to the overall amount of
TLS and I'm only showing teal s12 and
TLS 1/3 the older versions are there but
they are extremely tiny they are less
than half a percent it's not interesting
and so we see a really steady march up
10% 17% 22% the the amount of servers
that are turning this on is definitely
growing but we had other data in here
and so we want to start correlating it
and it's very interesting if you look at
this same trend when we look only at
connections that established over ipv6
and here it's a similar trend very
similar line so we see that the numbers
are kind of being ramped up on these
servers but the the absolute numbers and
absolute values of TLS 1/3 are much
higher and as of June we are already up
to a third of all of our connections
when we were going over v6 we're using
TLS 1/3 so this is great so looking a
little bit more into this kind of
correlation because this is an
interesting thing we noticed in the data
so we wanted to dig a bit deeper we ask
the question how likely is a server to
support TLS 1/3 if it is also upgraded
to support ipv6 so this data is now only
looking at connections that are
established whenever on a dual stack
network so we have both before and v6
available we're asking for both a and
quad 8 queries and so we're essentially
checking does this server support v6 and
we see that of the arguably larger
number of v4 only servers only 12% of
them by June had adopted and enabled 1/3
but of the servers that had previously
already been rolling out ipv6
that number is of
third it's at 36% so there's a fairly
strong correlation there and kind of
looking at this the other way around
when we look at the overall amount of
server enablement of ipv6 today when
we're on dual stack networks we're
seeing about 40% of connections go over
ipv6 but when we sample only for those
that are going over to us 1/3 so if
people have been upgrading recently we
see that at almost 70 percent so if
you're looking at you know new TLS
connections these are almost all
happening over ipv6 this is an
interesting correlation here in the data
similarly we look at the correlations
with a OPN so how likely are you to
support TLS 1/3 if you have also
upgraded to support HTTP 2 and again
it's actually really really similar
number so if you remember for v6 and
before v4 had I think was 12% and v6 had
36 or 38 and here we see almost exactly
the same numbers if you are kind of a
legacy server if you're doing HP 1
there's only 13 percent of them have
upgraded their TLS but for it should be
2 connections over 40% of them are
already on TLS 1 3 and again looking at
things the other way we actually see
overall from our clients about a 50/50
split of connections use it should be 1
or hb2 on any given network but if you
only look at the connections that are
using TLS 1 3 we see 75% of connections
are using HP 2 so again interesting
correlation and really quite similar
numbers here and then the last thing we
want to look at was the performance to
validate that other question are we
seeing the performance gains that we
were expecting with TLS 1 3 and here the
answer is
pretty clearly yes so this is a PDF
showing the number of milliseconds that
we see for both GLS 1 3 and TLS 1 2
handshakes and we definitely see a much
stronger skew towards the faster
handshake times with TLS 1 3 than we do
with 1 2 so it is clearly a benefit all
right so that's the data we have to
share
so the overall observations we're making
is that TLS 1 3 support has more than
doubled over the past 3 months the
performance wins that we expected are
being clearly demonstrated and we're
getting a lot of value here
and then the other kind of correlation
insight is we're noticing trends of
these kind of two populations we're
getting bimodal populations of leading
edge servers that are doing TLS one 3hp
to ipv6 and then some straggler
populations that are doing POS 1 to HB 1
that are ipv4 only and so you know
client developers are looking at needing
to optimize for two different
populations here and they should be kind
of expecting these general groupings and
it's also I think interesting when we're
looking at new protocol adoption I know
that these three protocols represent
definitely different groups of people at
the IETF and I think it shows that we
have a lot of common interest in common
patterns that when we look at the
devices that haven't been upgrading to
v4 those are kind of common enemies of
apathy or inertia that all of these
protocols are trying to fight against
and we're kind of all in it together in
this so questions please hi George again
can I just check is this a sample set
mediated from your experiment in the
client or are you doing some traffic
measurement at exchange points or are
you bound on the server side what can I
might have missed it mm-hmm it informs
the
the next question so this is your
mechanism in Apple for measurement of
client view of server behavior right so
this is on the population of both beta
users and users who have opted in to
data collection on across the world on
just normal devices that people are
using
so generally Wi-Fi cell networks that
users are on so I'm not using skew in
the negative kind of pejorative sense
I'm just observing capital exclusively
we're in the domain of the apple handset
in mobile distinct from say Apple and
Android you would have some question
around is this a function of update
cycle and availability of things because
this is a client negotiation right the
server proffers and then you have a
downgrade so it comes to a question is
if only newer devices you recruit is
there some skew here that affects the
relativities because if you were across
a random population v6 would naturally
have a higher uptake of 1/3 because it
tends to be present in the newest
software releases on carriers and 80% of
everything is v6 in mobile and that was
really the only point and it's not to
criticize yeah this is great data but I
just wondered if that was an aspect yeah
that's a really good point and so I will
add to kind of like methodology in the
population here we are only gathering
this data from the people on operating
systems that have upgraded to enable 1:3
so these are not going to be older
devices these are of course not devices
that we don't own so it is an early
adopters on the client side let's just
one thing to interject we've got about
four minutes and five of you in the
queue so let's let's drain that out and
then please remember to ian's what
Google thanks for presenting this data
it was a similar question about
selection bias actually I was wondering
if you had attempted to do a hold back
experiment where say half users like did
not have TLS 1/3 enabled but recorded
when TLS 3 1/3 was was available and one
the other half like actually used it to
get a better idea of like because I
would remove the server
selection bias that might otherwise be
present and we found it for quit that's
kind of important but that being said I
suspect your data is still largely in
the same direction I just asked ya so
earlier on before we turn it on by
default we were doing probing
essentially detecting when TLS 1/3 was
available even if we didn't use it kind
of just as a product decision we decided
to turn on full-blast for everyone
because there's the performance when we
didn't want to hold some people back but
yes that's a very good point
young lute regarding your last
measurements with the PDFs um I was
wondering you physically showed TLS 1.3
server's seem to be better connected
more up-to-date what kind of what is the
reason for the PDF being so low is it
that they are just better connected or
is it the protocol that is better yeah
that's again a very good point there's
lots of biases that get introduced this
data and I think the other information
that we showed of like hmm
these are clearly servers that are
adopting on the leading edge means that
they're probably optimizing other things
more yeah I think you know at least
isolated measurements we definitely do
see the benefit of one RTT this
particular data is only looking at the
handshake establishment time right so
the RT T's are a major factor in this so
I do think that does dominate this but
you are correct
thank you professional jobs you I really
like to remark about there being as sort
of the leaders that are deploying new
stuff and I was wondering could you if I
can put in a request look at whether or
not these people have their domains DNS
excited and whether it was validated by
just looking at the ad bit in the DNS
response that your clients get we don't
have that but that'd be great yeah could
you do that I'd be great thanks well
noted all right Brian Trammell not as
Banerjee Koecher despite the Hat the
with another bias question which I'll
actually freeze it as a
comment because I think the answer the
first question we know there are a few
things that you could look at in their
responses that might identify server
software so that you could essentially
Coralie some of these sort of like you
know early adopters and stragglers by
what the software the earth are running
cuz one of the things that we saw like
for example with ecn is um nobody
actually cares about turning it on is
just that the defaults are better and
one thing that would be really great for
this community to know is to what extent
is the work that we're doing toward
driving the defaults forward driving
some of this deployment into what extent
are these people who are making actual
decisions based on the merits of Chios
one three Thanks yep that's a great
question there's of course concerns for
us about trying to do too much explicit
fingerprinting for privacy purposes but
I think developing ways of doing this
that our privacy preserving would be a
great idea gen-i and god I was actually
going to say something very close to
that which is have you have you
considered looking into fingerprinting
the the SSL libraries that are being
used at the service to see there's a
correlation between you know if it is
possible that maybe does one SSL library
that happens to have bad defaults of
that and you turn it on and performance
actually sucks which is why people have
it turned off I don't know
but that's one other correlation that I
was interested in but I don't know how
easy it is to fingerprint SSL server
libraries or how feasible it is for you
to do it even if it is possible right
right and of course there would be the
concern about kind of ossified on the
fingerprint that the given
implementation has you know we've been
seeing actually issues on the other side
of certainly firewalls our other
measurement devices expecting certain
patterns of our own TLS implementation
and having changing behavior based on
that so it's tricky area so just a very
quick question I did not see any
breakages mentioned in any of this yeah
the we weren't sharing breakage numbers
but it's essentially very low and pretty
much the same as one two we don't see
anything that's really specific to us
one three that's lovely thank you
[Applause]
thanks Tommy
Cory's next we have now talks to talks
related to quick as you expect us to
have usually hi I'm Corey first and yep
we'll talk about quick I'm going to talk
about a some results from a test bed we
built we use vagrant to configure some
computers virtual machines we ran tests
with quick we use quickly and thank you
for the people who helped us do that and
we put a real Hardy light path between
our two endpoints this work was jointly
done by me and Tom we're all from
Aberdeen University so this is a summary
plot this is a summary plot of a lot of
experiments and you can see maybe look
at me right left box first and you can
see red which is straight using TTP to
do a W at this time of 100 kilobytes
across the satellite link and you can
see they takes six seconds to transfer
there are some outliers and this is
working across the hall access path from
the satellite and the internet and doing
the measurement across the path they
could go to the green box in the left
one the green box shows with TCP using
TLS 1.2 to get the same thing and the
green box shows the advantage of a pet
the performance enhancing proxy which
the satellite operators put in their
network and you can see it's much better
on the left with the green than the red
so the real question is now what does
quick doing what quick has to use the
full path it it has to go over the
satellite the satellite can't benefit it
so it does quite well it does almost as
good as the pepper so which is really
good news thanks everyone for working
with quick however it's not quite as
good as per happen
and you know little bits make a big
difference when you do web performance
let's look at a bigger transfer that's
the one on the right though you see the
red plot goes a little bit wild why
because when you're using TCP and you've
got a high bandwidth delay product and
something goes wrong the pathology can
go many different ways ssthresh can get
clamped low and all sorts of things can
happen so big variants on the right
quick did well but not quite as well as
TLS 1.2 uh-huh just a minute and we had
a previous talk what about 1.3 let's put
1.3 in here quick he's using 1.3 so it
should be as good as TLS 1.3 and now we
see the gap because TLS with 1.3 is much
better than TLS with 1.2 thank 0 for
didn't doing TLS 1.3 that worked really
well and quick isn't yet as we tested it
as good as the TLS 1.3 and that's all
right let me tell you more about what we
are actually using as our link it's a
satellite access link it's a commercial
offering we're using an engineering
platform the forward link has a bit rate
nominally of 10 megabits per second and
you can easily get 8 point 5 megabits
using iperf across this reasonably good
service for an isp returnin link is 1.4
megabits
pretty good and not as much here
symmetry as many people will have at
home if they're using soft light but I
mean that's ok bandwidth delay for the
very large majority of packets was just
over 550 milliseconds however let's look
at some long-term measurements of what
actually the RTT was you'll see the blue
bar is the average RTT and it's a high
bandwidth delay product link nearly
always at around 5 50 milliseconds but
there are many outliers this is because
there's a radio link underneath it's
trying to merge the resource
occasionally you'll get resource
requests which can't be satisfied
because got a contention busy time to
the day work badly
occasionally resource requests will fail
you have to try second time to get
resource or your partner traffic changes
abruptly so these are single packet
measurements you see these large
outliers so I assert this is a wonderful
test case for testing a quick
implementation if you want to push this
implementation in a weird way
check all the time is work check all the
transmission stuff work this is a great
environment and it's real
so we're carrying on doing this we've
done a lot of measurements and one of
the things we've done is plotted and TCP
as sequence number divided by MSS
because that's a thing that's roughly
equivalent to the quick packet number
and you get plots that look like this
and okay I mean there's lots of these
there's lots more in my dataset if
you're interested in these come and talk
to me and maybe next ITF will organize a
side meeting to go through this sort of
data with multiple people I'm not going
to take the question to the end because
I'm going to another a rather different
notes where I'm going this is the
download and yeah all the time quick
does well sometimes it didn't do as well
remember TCP has this pathology as well
so what we need to do now is look
carefully at exactly what's going on the
link logging is wonderful we can get a
lot about lot of logging out we can
really drill into it and lists are not
wonderful so we have to figure out how
best interact how timers are interacting
yeah okay so we got lots of data what
did we conclude I thought I might get
some people to like so I'm going to be
quick quick quickly was wonderful it was
a great experience using it Thanks right
and no complaints about this and we have
you to the logging available but then
we're always already talking about what
we should log TLS 1.3 had a two RTT
advantage one or two RTC advantage
always always better always good the
fullness of quick or satellite was not
as good as for TCP with a pet but it's
within shooting range so I'd really love
to try and get the NIT signed out so it
is as good downgrading to TCP is not a
long-term solution for these people
these people are currently actually
pushing you to use their pep in many
cases because
it's a predictable environment that's
got a stop we've got to enable quick of
this network to do that we must make
quick work well do that we must
understand quick well and understanding
performance issues falls into three
parts so this just probably
implementations I mean we're getting
there but there are things that could be
changed maybe small changes to the spec
in areas of transport maybe there's some
simple new mechanisms that could really
help
I'd love to explore that I'll bring that
up to the ITF as we find out we just
started I'm trying to say how exciting
this is
we just started will continue doing
measurements we're going to talk about
logging and tracing because we're
currently building our own tools they're
not bad they're passing JSON they're
taking peak ups for the TCP putting them
together the Q log stuff could be really
fun
and if you're a satellite person or a
radio person and somehow we can run our
tool across that using a virtual testbed
that'll be cool to get a wider spectrum
of results my slides have quite a few
extra bits but I don't intend to go
through them unless people really want
me to thank you questions thank you
going it's actually a great great thank
you did that and it's particularly great
to of the tresses of people can do a
simulation and chunder starts the the
one the little caveat I have with your
talk is that you are mentioning quick
when in fact you are testing a specific
version of a specific implementation and
I about human we add the 19
implementation of quake a truss
interrupt if we tried all 19 of them
would get 19 different results
I think at the moment I'm not sure I
completely agree that when the 19 have
finished there will be that different on
that sort of test if we push harder on
better tests which we will go to I'm
sure we'll get very different results so
yeah yeah okay but on network tests and
things like that so so it's very likely
that we would get and the reason I said
that is that I did spend a lot of time
tuning an implementation of quake for
this kind of scenarios not exactly as
you know you mentioned which is cannot
the edge kind of tuning you do at the
end of your beauty tune for the main
cast first and then you go to the other
casts and and that tuning involves
things like checking the way you compute
timer or shaking the way you manage
spoken for windows checking the way you
do to recovery and so all that is work
and so basically that the typical
process that people get dissemination
they look at what's going on as a haha
and they tune her concern here and there
and eventually they get to the level but
I think that's the great conclusion of
your talk is that if we do do that work
there is no reason to believe that will
not get to the wizard okay I checked
from that a couple of points and one of
them being that maybe next idea people
who are doing similar things with all
the other scenarios or other quick
implementations let's get together let's
spend some time actually drilling into
that not at the protocol level really at
the results of what we're seeing to
actually find out why and how yep thank
you let's make call on the end of this
queue then I just so we can stay nearly
on time denying God Wow so many parts
first I'm actually super impressed at
how close quick is to the pep PCP and
how far away it is from the VPN TCP
which also makes me super skeptical
partly because and I do to Christine's
point you're using quickly so I will say
you're using the right implementation
I'm biased because I implemented the
loss recovery in and so I must partly
partly responsible for some of the
performance you are seeing which is also
why I'm trying to understand what the
pep is doing so if the pepper is so I
don't really understand that that itself
that is being deployed is it a full
Terminator
is it a or is it just doing
retransmissions HACCP its BC I know
that's obvious from the tracers if you
look at the traces yes obviously they
receive traces if you want to be clear
so I think I mean thank you for us for
doing these experiments is awesome in
terms of the I think what do you at
least part of what you are seeing is the
difference between Reno and cubic
because quickly correctly implements and
deploys Reno yes and this is a really
high large B DB link and so there will
be your difference there and for the for
the transfer sizes here you have I
expect that cubic is going to ramp up
much faster I we have looked at that and
I think that's partly it and I think
also limped some timer issues and minor
details that could be fixed so yeah this
is not a complete piece of work is the
starter yeah so do big things one I'm
super happy to continue working on this
and you know this is happy to take this
back and sort of fix the quickly
implementation for any bugs but second
we you might know that we have Martin
Simon and I have been working on a
simulator environment for testing these
things so it'd be good to actually
validate this stuff with the simulator
as well to see if we can replicate the
same results there excellent thank you
yes right Google I want thanks for two
things one for not using the chrome
quick implementation because so many
papers and benchmarks have been based on
it and you know there's always my
personal concern that that's overfitting
and implementation and maybe we have
some bug that turns out to be a
performance enhancer number two thank
you for picking an implementation that
as close as I know actually implements
the most current version of the recovery
and congestion control spec and so this
is sort of validating that what's in the
spec largely like works pretty well and
then the
it's just you know I think there are
some approaches that probably could
allow quick to perform better here
namely like and maybe TCP as well PBR
would be one of them there's a lot of
good events that perhaps are detrimental
to BB are not helpful and so that might
mitigate this but I'm sure there are
other things we could do as well but
thanks okay
great work gory please keep it up do you
know the weather aqm is in use in the
networks or any of this measurement they
were not in these experiments okay so
I'd be interested in seeing how that
compared and the other thing that I'd be
interested in in your future work
looking at is comparison of fairness on
the tour the terrestrial network on the
far side if how quick behaves compared
to sort of stock TCP yeah we should we
probably would put an emulator in series
with the actual satellite link to let
let's do some wireless effects and odd
things to concatenate two paths hey
Colin Perkins with no hats and first of
all thank you
great work I can a slightly like to echo
the point Christian was making ever seen
a lot of or heard a lot of people having
read particular papers which talk about
particular quick implementations wildly
over extrapolate the results and it's
something that that I don't know whether
it's this group or the quick group might
consider putting out a statement on how
to benchmark quick and how to report
results and how to how to describe what
you are benchmarking what you're
evaluating because I think it is harming
the perception of quick and what people
are doing experiments with very early
implementations of quick comparisons are
very highly up to most TCPS and writing
what looked like very general
conclusions when they're actually much
more specific yeah
that's one of the reason want to stand
up here because we pull quickly and
compile it and run the test so we want
to keep it way up to date and anything
we do is patching that because I think
that's the only way to do it if you're
benchmarking it now please don't use a G
quick benchmark as your baseline it's
different thing the things that moved on
we really need to make sure we track the
latest version in the quick way and we
really need to make sure that
publications writing about quick are
very specific about what they are
testing and what are the implications of
that yes I agree with that
thank you thanks much Cory okay next we
have eaten from Google actually talking
about the immigration to ITF quick which
is also quite exciting yes what I'm here
to talk about our migration towards ITF
quick from Google book so so where's
chrome now be 46 which is a Google quick
version that has no real meaning but
I'll explain to you approximately what
it is is now a default enabled we also
enable be 39 and 43 on the server at the
moment be 46 is in variants draft three
and below compatible and it has
transport draft nine packet types which
I think actually are maybe but still the
same packet types that we have now a
future version will be in variants for
compatible which is the new but that
changes everything by like one byte
which is a rather relatively minor
change technically but I'm sure when we
deploy that a bunch of other things will
break before t6 does if a quirk that
actually only supports Google quick
style eight byte connection IDs in one
direction and zero in the other that was
just a convenience because it allowed us
to delay if we went to call the variable
in connection IDs which took a ton of
time thank you david scamozzi i don't
know if you're here so the rest this
talk is all about b43 to be 46 so if if
you're wondering like what versions are
what transition is you talking about
that's what I'm talking about
the first thing is the change from
public reset so Google quick has an
unauthenticated public reset that sent
anytime you want to close a connection
and you don't have any state or you're
too lazy or whatever but basically it's
like a TCP reset - connection closed
during the handshake and a stateless
reset post handshake and idea so why is
this hard it turns out in our code we
have lots of spots we send a public
reset like well over ten I think it
turns out and each one had to be fixed
and tracked down and it just took a
while also why does it matter so
handshake timeouts and I all timeouts
are quite a bit longer than getting an
immediate reset in particular idle time
out of our default is 30 seconds right
now that's extremely user visible so you
know getting this wrong even like a few
percent of the time is a is a major
source of user visible like problems you
really want to close the connection as
quickly as possible any sort of
circumstances so when this and what and
do you quick if we have no state we just
send a public reset that's pretty
straightforward ITF quick header in
their state you send a Salus reset if
it's a long header no state and its
initial we try to start creating a
connection it's a long header in those
state and it's handshake we send an
initial close and hoping that they still
have pinche our initial keys which is
sort of a you know I hope but it works
in G quick at the moment and the
Persians not supported it's worth we
send VN there are definitely some quirks
here where you can get into this
situation in the final version of IETF
quick where you start receiving
handshake packets and you're like there
is nothing I can guarantee to send in
response that might close this
connection quickly and so you just have
to send initial because it's the only
thing you have a keyboard
hopefully that will not turn out to be a
practical issue so let's talk about
quick identification it turns out at
least one major company and increasingly
more large companies are trying to do
quick identification sometimes this is
to just give you network monitoring
tools like your network is this much HBS
and this much you know quick in this
much DNS and this much although other
stuff and so
it's also for selective traffic you know
and enforcement basically like I want to
disable quick or I wanted disable quick
if I can't get BS anion which we'll talk
about later so be 46 when you started
rolling about at a very large increase
in post hinchik black horn so it was
about 2 X be 43 I'll explain it a little
bit later how we determine post and
shape by :
but again this is one of those things we
draw closely because it's very user
visible and waiting 30 seconds for your
connection to timeout before reissuing
the request of our new connection is
really really painful it also turns out
historically these have been user
focused so a given user will experience
this all the time and the other 99.9% of
the population will never ever
experience this so it's not like every
once in a while a web page is slow it's
like one user is having like a bad month
or a bad year so understandably we don't
like this the confounding factor is
sometimes the network just goes away
right like this happens and so we have
this base level of noise that we assume
is the network going away but we have no
real proof it's it's a very you never
getting this to zero right like
especially with mobile devices like
Android and other things and this height
is higher on Android for understandable
reasons right however on April 13th that
suddenly fixed itself like a or
basically fix itself I mean there's a
little bit of a gap there but it went
from 2 X 2 like 1.1 X over the course of
a weekend and we didn't change anything
because we don't things out of our
weekend let's first talk about what what
too many are tears and then we can tell
you what happened on the fifth RTO
ng-click we found that that was a
reasonable signal for closing the
connection kazoo is black hold as I know
at the bottom 5 RTO is and our current
implementation is kind of comparable to
seven RTOS
in you know linux which i think is some
time's configured as a default so you
know we're not so far off we sort of
stumbled upon this by accident because
we were just having some unrelated
issues but it's enabled by default on
Chrome desktop definitely your heuristic
we could probably do better but it turns
out if you bump it up to six you're so
close to the idle time out it doesn't
really save you much and if you make it
any shorter you do occasionally just
kill a connection that you don't really
mean to so Bates we're rare but this is
sort of our proxy for like black holing
and it's it's worked out to be a pretty
good indicator and in this case it's a
better indicator than we thought it was
so when you started debugging this we're
like how can we get more data about when
this is happening in a connection and
one of our team members have the great
idea that we should add the number of
connections sorry number of packets that
have been sent or received before
closing the connection due to too many
RTS and on the client side the receive
metric was was very indicative as you
can see all the extra black holing
energy is all between two three and four
packets so basically if you got in
packet five like the rest of the
connection is set you are all good to go
and if you didn't get pack at five then
you're gonna have a bad time wait 30
seconds
unfortunately this typically happens
after you've completed the handshake
because four packets is more than enough
to complete the handshake in Google
quick so typically the difference
between two and three and four is like
this is a case of you don't do zero RTT
you get a packet and then that's a
reject and then you do burn a round-trip
and then it sends you to the cert and
that's somewhere between one and three
packets just as an explanation so that's
why sometimes two three or four but they
said basically this is like two flights
of packets and then like whatever it is
is blocking traffic okay yeah so it
turned out to be quick them in a box
identification suddenly improved when a
vendor updated their identification
software so happily most users of the
software update or middle box update
weekly we recently found out a few do
not be aware of this because you know
it's been fixed for a few months but
some particular individuals did not have
it fixed in their local instance so you
know if you're in the future if you're
debugging random quick issues and you're
like well I think this was fixed
by this vendor like months ago be aware
that there is sometimes a long tail of
updates and it was impossible to
diagnose because it worse like we talked
on tactic the vendor and they're like
law it's fixed and we contacted the user
and they're like my life is terrible and
we appreciate both perspectives and so
let's talk about how to block quick if I
was gonna ask you to block quick because
like this is sort of a favor and I'm not
saying anyone's going to change what
they do but you're really cool if you
did if you're gonna block it can you
ensure that all packets in one direction
or the other are blocked like doesn't
matter which direction like don't care
you can let all the client packets go
through and drop all those server
packets that's fine
just try to drop all of them because
anything else is really user visible and
chrome now has some heuristics to try to
avoid networks like this and avoid using
click on them but it basically goes from
consistent and utter failure to flaky
hangouts or hangs and connection like
loads followed by like it works suddenly
and you don't know why so it goes just
basically from failure to flaky it's not
fixing the problem it's like a flaky
test for our only test so the other one
I wanted to talk about from V 43 to be
46 is antivirus blocking suddenly we
noticed that the usage of quick on
window has dropped
we eventually actually traced it to a
single company at the time we found this
out v 46 wasn't blocked so we're like
hey maybe they read the CFM variants
graphed and said not to drop the idea
from variant correct but decided to drop
Google quick I mean this is like me like
thinking my most optimistic thought this
was not true this was just completely
false we turned on V 46 and two weeks
later they like stopped started walking
that and the last thing is anytime you
change the location of sni you're gonna
break a bunch of stuff there's a few
more versions left so we're gonna
probably break some other things and I'm
really sorry and it's a hard transition
but we we're trying to do this as fast
as we can okay so I'll stop and give
questions
is that your last leg yes that is my
last word thank thank you heal from
bringing this bringing this here this is
something that I been sort of sitting on
the edge of my seat
for a while to watch what happens when
the G quick format changes and as
expected it's already been ossified this
is this is like this is exactly what we
were afraid of and this is exactly what
you worried about and it seems like
maybe some of them are actually doing
updates which is promising but that's
something that you mentioned so the the
point that you are showing there with
the energy in too many audios is is in
the early key packets there so that
suggests a particular type of behavior
in middle box right where they allow a
few packets to go through and then die
and we've we've seen this before and I
wonder if this is actually it's
important enough now I mean missing this
again here and then one thing this is
important enough that this is the sort
of thing that you want to protect
against meaning that if if we keep
thinking that all packets are going to
go through or none of them are going to
go through it may not be it may not be
compatible with the way that middle
boxes build their architecture because I
imagine that some of this is basically
like you know the forwarding thread sort
of parting it passing it on to a
different thing that actually goes off
to do detection of what type of packet
this is and by the time that completes
and comes back you already forwarded a
few packets I'm not sure exactly what's
causing it to happen but we've seen this
it may be worthwhile two things it may
be worthwhile actually documenting some
of this detection for others to also be
able to use I think it's super useful
for non chromium clients to be able to
build this sort of detection the second
I wonder if this is something we can
specifically detect as behavior and use
for failover in Chrome yeah we've
thought about specifically detecting it
but it turns out the so far we've only
observed one vendor actually doing this
and so we can email them and ask them to
fix it usually and so we've done that
and because the concern is otherwise
we're aspiring the protocol on this
weird thing where we have this
workaround feature and then we're stuck
with that sort of forever and so and
everyone else has to build it too so I
mean I guess I'd be okay if Kron had to
edit because you know were early
adopters and we're pushing things but
like if every quick client on earth had
to add like a bunch of extra heuristics
for the rest of time that because sad
thank you so you don't have any insights
why this behavior of this window showed
up sir because you said it's one winter
but you don't have any insights what the
intention was there and the intention in
this case was they had a Enterprise
policy they had both monitoring consoles
and an enterprise policy and enterprise
policy allowed you to drop quick and the
way they drop unknown protocols is they
give it a few packets in each direction
and then if after two or three packets
they haven't figured out what protocol
it is then they start dropping it and so
quick classified in be 46 as an unknown
critical and then get into this weird
bin so that's the other thing I was
going to comment is this isn't good for
like any transport I seriously like like
unis people are thought like whether
it's you know SCTP over DT OS like all
these things have the property that like
if you complete the handshake and then
black hole it it's going to be like a
really bad time so for the general
interest of transport innovation on UDP
across the entire internet I would like
people to try to avoid doing this it's
not just for quick I mean this isn't
just for us this is a little bit more
yeah it's basically it seems like so
what I what I've seen people talk about
is that there are console on the console
of the middle box it basically says
packet received cannot classify cannot
classify and then it drops it so it's
possible that it's you know trying to do
some classification on a separate thread
and that it eventually times out or
gives up and then says I am done and
then it decides black hole but yeah this
is a huge issue unfortunately the people
who can change this aren't necessarily
in this room which is the frustration we
cut the line and we would like to people
to hurry up a little bit and if you're
quick you can still join the line but
please be quick all right thank you for
sharing this I'll try to be quick here
first of all a question when we see the
black holing is it
only on a per connection basis it's not
really like across the whole device to
the IP typically it is actually across
all the connections for that like
basically like every quick connection on
that hoe starts getting black hold yeah
okay because because it's a middle box
we're all quick connections are going
through yeah so it's it's sort of a
host-based not based thing yeah cuz
you'd mention the kind like the
background level because we're always
gonna have some things that happen to
drop off after four packets but it's not
really possible then to look at kind of
all the parallel connections and you can
see if oh if this other connection
dropped off and it was further along
maybe that's just a network impairment
but that would not work in this case
yeah I mean we don't really mean our
client side is not fine enough grain to
actually even prove that back but yeah I
don't know yeah unfortunate I think we
can say for sure whether or not that's
true yeah
I burn a trammel quick question I'll
take the rest of this offline probably
as the co-editor of the quick
manageability drop I'm gonna follow you
a couple of issues to take this
presentation into that draft the so you
said that the dropping all of the
packets for a connection is much better
than dropping some of the package for
the connection from user visibility
that's kind of obvious and I think we
should actually kind of write that down
and yell it from the tree cops in the
IETF and then you said that like so for
one of these you're basically you get
the first three packets and then you
drop are you seeing other things where
you basically get like intermittent
drops after you have actually like spun
up data um like so data channels like
you get like you know you get some
actual data it's like oh great great
now quick works and then you drop every
other packet or I mean like look can you
characterize a little bit more the kind
of drop patterns that you're seeing we
we do see some level of other like well
post inject dropouts yeah
anecdotally it seems to mostly be not
related we're out in nap times I was in
that poor and the fix for that is if you
like typically happens in the following
circumstance it's more like the than
that times out the server is sending a
bunch of packets to the client the
client stops sending for some period of
time and the net timeout instead of
being a you see
timeout is a fixed timeout so it's like
yeah you know at 60 seconds I'm going to
time out this UDP like a couple instead
of after 60 seconds of idle I will do
this I then then just send a ping to
reopen it I mean totally seem quite a
bit of that on non quick traffic as well
so there's like there's some there's
something that's in Java and the college
is another okay cool
it's not super common but it does happen
yeah okay so we see that you guys ask a
lot of great questions we have 50
minutes of content this fit into 45
minutes right now so we're gonna ask
Alexander who had 22 maybe 17 minutes or
something like that and similar for
Roland afterwards you cut a few minutes
off so that people can ask you questions
but otherwise uh up next is Alexander
about packet loss signaling for
encrypted protocols thank you so I will
we have as an operator we have the day
to take issue of what to do to locate
losses it may seem a bit strange but we
are not completely aware of what happens
in all nodes of our networks that's a
day to day truth so maybe for many
people networks are just dumb pipes but
it's only true if someone can look at
all the nodes and if you get some
Oh am I'm something that tells you okay
I got some drops on that interface and
you have app sorry no blind spots it
might work but in real world in the real
world it's not the case so what we do is
typically we do some liquor to me
we use some observer in the middle of
the path and try to say if some problem
occurs upstream or downstream from that
point and then reiterate we do this in a
day to day basis and have been done so
fro 30 years on TCP obviously using
sequence number and X that's trivial but
what do we do with the encrypted
transport very quick that's a much
tougher of course so quick as you may
know has something for RT t
measuring RTG with the spin bit but
nothing for us for now so we've got a
proposal to to solve the problem which
is that based on only two lost bits
which we named Q and L the Q which is
square signal and L which is the lost
Evan signal the square signal is just
one toggle every n packets so that's
like you're the one the alternate packet
packet marking also something mentioned
by kazuo yeah a year ago about earlier
in earlier loss detection discussions so
the U cube it is just flipped every N
packets so when you look at it at a
middle point you just count the
sequences and know how many packets have
been lost
upstream from the points the last seven
bit is fed by the stack itself and set
to 1 whenever some earlier packet has
been considered lost so by counting both
of them you get the upstream loss and
the end to end nose so the nth windows
is just a fraction with l equals to 1
and the upstream loss is the the
difference between the expected number
of Q and the observed number of Q's and
of course the downstream loss is the
difference roughly the difference so
we've been doing running an experiment
an orange network through real customers
with thousands of Relkin customers in
four countries with Akamai CD ends so
Akamai CD ends use a quick stack which
is based on chromium with proprietary
patches and in it we implemented the the
QL bits as you might know in the current
quick specification it's not possible to
add those bits anywhere in the packet so
we did use some ugly level free trick
you poked
those bits in the IP header in the TTL
high high order bits this a lot this is
completely ok it's a hack of course not
supposed to be generalised
but that's a way of doing a real-life
experiment today
with negotiation with version
negotiation in quick it's absolutely not
possible to do a large-scale experiment
for anybody but people holding a browser
or popular application we do not have
any of them so we were first to do that
okay the topology of the experiment is
the same for all four countries you
typically have an observer point which
is just below the Akamai CBN's serving
the access network the suspected usual
suspect in network troubleshooting of
course the internet paths and the access
network paths so whenever we start an
investigation in our networks even today
with TCP we'll always start at this
point because the key question to us
first is whether the responsibility is
ours or not the implementation details
are as follows so the quick stack patch
by can I just compute the qnn bits and
insert them in the in the TTL high bits
and then we had to put the value to a
out of the qubit so you you which was 64
as a trade off based on a few audio
experiments and we will see that it's
not so bad so this gives that also not
another constraint wisdom from the the
hiko the high collar used which is the
TTL high bits of course since we use to
high bits it means that TTL must be
below 63 but is no real constraint as
the Akamai server just set the value to
verse 63 so what we do to gather data at
the observation point is we do traffic
capture with step aggregators and we
only capture the downlink pass we don't
need the lag flow and also we truncate
the full payload is completely useless
so we only gather packet summaries with
timestamps IP ports the qnl bits and the
payload size for debugging the
segmentation works by top hole and time
out obviously because the we have no
insight on the exact signaling going on
in quick
and this allows to capture in one
compact text file per flow or would that
happens and then do various tests with
the post-processing of the signals so
both based on those files you will see
that both statistical and unit analysis
can be performed so here before going
into the analysis I'll adjust the
plotter CDF of the flow size because the
flow size is important
as you know that the cubit just counts
sequential consecutive packets with the
same value of course if you got fewer
than 64 pi packets in the flow you see
nothing so what I've done here is plot
the value of 640 which is 1010 1/2 K
odds of Q which gives a boundary and the
under image that the last chunk the
importance sadistically importance of
last rank which obviously is incomplete
so if you just clip the data set above
640 you get roughly 10% in the in the
worst case but that's enough given the
number of point captured so the review
the refusal we used to exploit the
desert are of two kinds first is
statistical you watch which calculus
kattappa lots so we just give the very
dimensional distribution of the loss
derived from the queue and from the l
bits and then the unit view if we want
to debug what happened on that point on
this connection we just plot an
individual cumulative display of the
Dallas's which is over the time in the
connection how many packets were lost
other Angwin or upstream so when we look
at the first kind of plot when it is we
analyze it this way we've got AB sum of
stream runs against end-to-end us the
diagonal of course means pure upstream
loss because when the packet is it is
plus upstream is also appears in the end
to end the vertical is pure downstream
loss it appears only on the end-to-end
measurement and not at all on the cubit
but the bottom right is
supposed to be impossible right so we
will see well then when we do unit
analysis you you select one of these
points and look at the the way that the
laws are spread over time in any one
given connection in this example you can
see that both are completely
synchronized which means that it's pure
upstream loss which is every time
there's a cat which is lost it's also
lost end-to-end in this other case you
see only end-to-end absolutely no
upstream so it's pure downstream this
case you see something which shouldn't
happen which is no end to end and
they're completely insane and
concentrated upstream loss which this
case was based on miss segmentation the
heuristics applied to the signal
counting the qubits is supposed to do
something about reordering I get
rubbering and in some case it does Polly
and also miss segmentation happens when
the timeout doesn't is not enough to
detect that some connection was reusing
the center pole in this extreme case
you've completely uncorrelated losses
which happened to be due to observer
pass saturation observers now we are
going to look at the four countries so
these are the four scatter plots quickly
you can see that there's one of them
which is an outlier the bottom left is
completely insane and we see why the
first one country one as you can see is
concerned the main energies on the
vertical axis which is pure downstream
loss there are a few points on the
diagonal which are really under they're
gonna which in some events of upstream
loss and there is also some noise in the
dragon area which after unit analysis
have been shown to be due to reordering
so again that's due to when reordering
happens the boundaries
consecutive packets with Q equals zero
and one must be somehow accounted for
one country true it's much cleaner the
noise from razoring is very low and we
also seem some energy on vertical axis
and a few spots on the diagonal winning
events of strong actionless you can also
see that they are not exactly on the
diagonal below and this has been
accounted for by the fact that in quick
you sometimes have packets going down
which are expandable these as for
example ax coming from window update so
we have corrected them to do that
country 3 3 is come insane 1 and after
after correlation with other flows on
the on the same capture pass from TCP it
was shown that it was completely
saturated capture chain so the method
also is able to detect something that
TCP could allow which is detected when
your measurement purchased doesn't work
country 3 is a cleaner tool and a few
outliers due to musical notation now you
see the CDF the summary or CDF films
from downstream loss ratio which gives
you the difference between the X and y
axis and the earlier drafts but plotting
them at the CDF gives us a quantitative
view that's better than the the scatter
plots okay so to summarize what we've
seen in the dragon area sometimes you
some noise is due to imperfection of the
denoising heuristics some is due to miss
Eckman session and some is due to
observe all's which obviously should not
happen in your life and the summer is
all these noises can be disambiguated by
unit analysis so we are not at all blind
and also the heuristics have been
quickly developed and could be improved
and reduce the noise as a wrap-up the
unilateral deployment was made possible
only because
we use we didn't use the quick vague
vehicle itself
that's all hack to that and that's the
only way to do a large-scale experiment
the signals were designed to restore
disappear like ability to debug networks
and they do worse and short of direct
quick support we are not we do not
expect to get in anytime soon and other
vehicles is needed so any suggestion are
open and the mechanism can be applied to
any other protocols quick centric the
only contribution that is expected from
the stack is the Elbit which is the the
mechanism by which the stack tells that
it has rust buckets so in the summer is
a tree it works and we really do need
something like that to keep the
beginning networks shot of that with
just the current state of quick and no
extensions we are we are completely
blind all right we can squeeze in like
one or two questions
yes but Google thanks for this data this
looks certainly interesting one question
I had is for the spin but there's a fair
amount of analysis of what happens if
one or the other one of the two end
points like tries to for lack of a
better word subvert the signal it seems
like it would be very easy for either
end point to sort of convince a middle
box like of whatever signal I wanted as
well as some pretty crazy signals have
you had any thoughts about the ability
to reject implementations that either
are buggy or just basically like you
know not complying with a with this
scheme or how to figure out when it's
negotiated pertaining the client server
in their heart leap spinning and so it's
a server-side right so for the for the
downstream path only the server sets the
bit and in the it's what we are
interesting in because it's where the
congestion
now networks okay so the most valuable
signal is unilateral my module at the
fact that right now you'd drop half of
these packets because the removing
header protection with them just to add
possess site or native for TCP is also
unencrypted and it's also subject to
gaming right somebody wants to send you
interest in TCP interesting-looking
disappear stream nothing stopping them
all right thanks so much Alexander so up
next we're gonna have Roland talk about
the RPI and you've got twenty minutes
for this and then we've got one last
presentation okay
thanks Dave so I apologize to the people
in the video in advance I'm gonna walk
off the video to start their animation
because my laptop didn't work with the
presenter thing right this is a talk
about the RPK wayback machine
my name is runs fresh Sakai I work for
an omlette labs and I hope if it's that
somebody recognizes this Logan Ziggy
says there is a 50% chance we'll end up
in 2011 hands up who knows quantum leap
there we go good right so I don't know
it labs we make rpki relying party
software which is called Bruce inator
and this has already seen quite a lot of
uptake in production for which we are
very happy but we also want to test
ourself for ourselves and to see how
robust it is and we found out that the
ripe ncc had a really really nice
dataset that had all of the rpki our
away data for all of the RI ours pretty
much since the inception of our PGI and
so this is really cool data so what we
wanted to do was use that data to test
route inator and we wanted to run all of
it through our validator software now we
got dumps into our gzip files and
towards the end I'll tell you where you
can find a mixer now open data and we
wrote a tool that we called siggy to
transfer this back in
RPK time so interlude L telling holding
Ziggy and telling Sam where he's gonna
go next right so what does Ziggy do it
is a Python script again open source URL
will be in one of the later slides and
you give it a date and what it'll do is
it'll try to figure out which of the RER
repository data needs to unpack it needs
to recreate the towels because the
towels are missing in the tarji set
files and then it uses a tool called
fake time to run the route inator for
the correct date and we did this for
data starting January 2011 until
February 2019 at least that those are
the graphs that I'm going to show you
but actually during this week I did some
more processing and I have some really
nice animations that I can show you that
go until Monday this week right for
those of you are less familiar with rpki
a quick recap of some of the jargon that
i'm going to be using throughout this
presentation the rpki is the resource
public key infrastructure this allows
you to set what are called route origin
authorizations and basically this
authorizes a certain AAS to announce
certain prefixes
this is cryptographically signed so he
can sort of validate that some a as was
allowed to originate that prefix and
what we typically deal with after
validation are called verified raw
payloads yes that is an acronym in an
acronym and this is a cryptographic a
valid statement about a prefix from an
hour away right so first of all if we
look at our PKI it started in 2011 but
it uptake sort of started slow and then
as you can see it is escalating towards
today it's really growing exponentially
what is also interesting is that the
historic data that we got actually
turned out to contain some flaws you can
see little arrow on the on the graph
that says first day right data validates
before that date something was off in
the manifest files that we got from ripe
ncc and it didn't validate and it is on
a road map to use old or
pti software to also validate that data
and see if we can make this graph cover
the whole period another interesting
thing that you can observe here is the
DES spike in the Green Line from AP neck
and these were three asses that suddenly
D aggregate all of their rows which
basically means they disable their max
max length attribute and rather than say
oh this is a pretty role that's valid
first say sixteen prefix and you can
have sub announcements of stretch 24
they remove the max length and basically
converted that into a whole bunch of
slash 24 rows and apparently this was a
mistake in some software and it got
fixed pretty quickly but the impact is
quite visible of course we also have to
look at ipv6 because that's a modern
protocol and again you can see more or
less the same trend it's it's far fewer
prefixes for which there are rows but
the trending growth is pretty similar
it's still growing exponentially is
growing up towards today and this is
good news so people are really starting
to apply this technology so what I also
looked at was the prefix size in VR PS
over time because the hypothesis behind
this was that as ipv4 exhaustion
continues you might expect to see fear
piece for smaller prefixes and actually
as you can see in this this graph that
is true so this is a CDF for five years
and in 2019 the fraction of prefixes
that are 24 is sort of let me see let me
say that so that's going down mmm I'm
trying to figure out what I wanted to
say there so the and the same is true
for mix lengths right the the when mixed
length is used you can again see that
the max length becomes smaller and
smaller and smaller over time so there
it's going down toward slash 24
for a v6 we see pretty much the same
thing again the prefix size is
decreasing over time so we see vir PS
for smaller prefixes and this is also to
form X length there are by the way at
the end of the presentation there are
many more graphs that I didn't have time
to put in because I would be way over
time if I present all of these but again
the takeaway from this is max length is
decreasing for post v4 and v6 right now
this one's a little bit interesting
right because there's been some debate
about whether or not you should use max
length or water or or if you should
prefer 2d aggregate and have lots of
rowers that cover smaller prefixes and
because the reasoning behind this is if
you have a max length but you don't and
now announce all of the sub prefixes
that are underneath that you're expose
yourself to high checking attempts and
what you can see is that max length use
over time was going down until about a
year ago and it's slowly starting to
rise again and while we can't confirm
this we think this might be because
people are now validating a lot more and
it turns out that people were announcing
sub prefixes that we're not covered by
the by the rowers and their
announcements were getting rejected
because of that and then to fix that if
you're announcing sub prefixes it's easy
to add a max length that is valid and
then your stuff will validate again so
it seems I mean this is kind of a hand
waving a bit but it seems that this is a
trend now again so average prefix size
so there's a note that says compare this
to Jeff story in in routing that was
because I use this slide at the right
meeting in Reykjavik where Jeff Hewson
presented something about the BGP table
where you also see a decreasing prefix
size in the announcements that are in
there well no surprise we see a
decreasing averaged prefix size in the
VR P's ball
again max length and the prefix size
that is in the row up right again for
ipv6 we see pretty much the same thing
right we see the average prefix size so
more rows for smaller prefixes now I'm
gonna go so this is interesting so this
is something that I did over the week we
I'm gonna walk around so I can store as
Mary you're gonna start it for me no
okay so I'm gonna walk around and start
that story on the video so what we did
here was I we have a tool that will
exist a video that one no oh okay I need
to click harder there we go
what this shows you this animation is
the coverage so this is the what we took
was route fuse data for announcements
that we see in BGP we took the veer
piece for certain dates and we use the
NRO stats to map those the prefixes that
we see in the announcements and in the
rowers to certain countries and what is
animation will show you is coverage so
these are this is the fraction of
announcements that are covered by Aurora
and this animation runs until this
Monday and hopefully it's kind of
visible on the screen what you should be
able to see in this is that it's slowly
getting darker and that means that we
see more and more and more announcements
that are actually covered by Aurora and
what you should also see is that we're
now April May June that this is
accelerating towards the end and I
apologize that the screens kind of
mangle the the nice colors but if you
want the graphs I can give it to you
sorry can we play it again of course we
can play it again
oh and yeah you're from South America
they're doing really well in South
America as you can see right now all of
the tools that we use to create this our
open source so he there's a slide at the
end where he which shows you where you
can grab them now there is one more
graph that I like to show you and this
one I like even more what this shows you
is accuracy and accuracy we define as
the fraction of covered announcements
that are valid right so and what we
graph here are those countries that have
an accuracy of 90% or over so I cut off
everything that has a lower accuracy
because this will show you again that
even there is already a high accuracy so
all of the countries that you see right
now on April 1st 2018 had an accuracy of
over 90% for the announcements that are
sort of for the prefixes that are
assigned to those specific countries but
what you will see is that the quality is
really improving a lot again what you
see here is a some kind of a disappeared
oops but the takeaway from this is that
quality is really really getting good so
if you are not filtering based on our
PPI you really should be doing that
because the quality of the data is very
very good right the accuracy is high and
can we go back to the slides I have to
stand here sorry America Mario's very
strict
right so those were those two let me
figure out if I can somehow if people
are interested send me an email I can I
can get videos for that right to
conclude we wanted to test route inator
and it turns out that RPG I took some
time to standardize properly right
because we couldn't validate some of the
older data the data raises lots of
questions but it also shows you that you
could deploy our PTI filtering in your
network today because the quality of the
data is actually very very good the next
step that we want to do is to compare
this against routing information in more
detail and we actually already did that
we submitted a paper to the ACM
measurement measurement conference that
was accepted so we'll be presenting that
in October in Amsterdam and also this is
some free advertising as the one of the
general chairs of IMC please come to
Amsterdam in October to the wonderful
internet measurement conference with
that I would like to give a big thank
you to the folks at the ripe NCC for
actually collecting and keeping this
data to a meal from ripe to help us make
this data available this data is now
available as open data so if you are a
researcher you want apply play with this
rpki data go grab it off the ripe FTP
server and and also grab our free OSS
tools ruminator the secure reading stats
which is what I used to do all of the
computation for the the maps that I
showed and I turned the repository for
city public earlier this week so you can
grab that I will actually now download
the data from the ripe archive see what
you do is you run it you give it a date
it will grab the right data it will run
routine a tour if you have a local copy
installed and it will give you the vir
piece for that date and with that I'm
open to questions can I now go back to
you Mike I Robert Kiyosaki ripe ncc one
suggestion I don't know about the exact
incremental value that you would get out
of this but if there was an option to
say disable manaphy
check then you could fill in the gap
that was before 2014 for the MC the
reason is the manifest is there to
protect the integrity of the whole set
and if it's fair that it was not
compromised you know in that time period
yes there is a footnote there but if you
assume that it wasn't then you would
feel that yeah yes
well it's certainly something we want to
do is it's just that with all the work
we've been doing on the tool set we
haven't had time to sort of add the flag
but we're certainly gonna do that and
we're probably also gonna make all of
the validated the data that we file a
date it will probably put it up
somewhere so that people G can just grab
the vir piece rather than having to do
run the validation themselves Oh Brian
Trammell former rpki skeptic thank you
very very much for putting all of this
stuff together like so the entire stack
one of the problems that we've had and
sort of trying to figure out what the
state of deployment of a lot of these
things are is that from the research
standpoint it's like oh you go and you
read a paper from 2011 and then you read
another paper from 2015 and you have two
points and are very hard to draw a line
and here you have data points from every
day and the line is very apparent one of
the the reasons I was in rpki skeptic is
sort of the the base rate fallacy
problem that you have when you're
enabling optional security um there's a
risk to turning validation on because
the data is you know there's problems
with the data you might actually start
projecting routes and you have
availability risk
um and you're creating African security
risk the number of it so if I were
trying to come up with a risk number
from your data set that would be one
over accuracy correct yes okay because
the things that are uncovered or are you
know not going to be a problem anyway
okay and those and the scale on the
geographical data you're showing was
like ninety nine ninety percent to 99
percent of aggregated prefixes or at
announcements announcements
announcements and you're kind of hoping
yeah and then the other quells
unique prefixes in announcements yeah
okay yep perfect thanks
okay thanks alright let's do this one
last question and we'll go to the last
presentation Montgomery it's more of a
comment on the last question is that
when you look at those accuracy numbers
you have to be careful to see if the
route that's invalid might well be
covered by another route that is valid
or not found we've looked at that and
the coverage is pretty high the coverage
that uses the same path as pretty high
coverage then ends up in the same origin
is pretty hot okay thank you Thanks so
[Applause]
so we had we had a little a bit of
juggling with the agenda and we decided
we decided to have you on come and talk
to us about his recycling large-scale
internet measurements for about 10
minutes and so we're gonna do is bump
the hackathon report that I would have
done but all is not lost there's a link
to the three minute hackathon talk that
I gave you can find it in the agenda so
in the in their updated slides for that
so take it away on thank you so this is
work we already presented at Pamela's
here and basically this all started out
well I've been doing intuit measurements
for the last couple of years I was here
at ITF in London and presented some
stuff about Google quick deployment so
yes this is a talk we're also quick ISM
but we also scanned follow up more we do
DNA scans TLS scans HTTP to scans and
the thing with these scans is we are
looking for something very specific but
if you for example do a tcp/ip v4 scan
on port 81 percent of all IPS will
actually give us an EXO answer what
about the remaining 99% right so the
idea basically that we had in this paper
Wars is there actually something we
aren't scanning for but we could have
scanned for all can we reuse the data
that we already have and to find that
out we basically captured all ICMP
traffic that words ingressing our
measurement networks as we do not
generate ICMP traffic for ourselves
this is either background traffic or
traffic that is actually generated by
our measurements so the idea was okay
let's study
ICMP and let's study what actually is in
there and we were surprised because
within a week we got what is it six
hundred thirty seven million icing
penises from a whole different number of
Phi piece over 53,000 autonomous system
and you can see a plot basically where
you can see that yeah well they
correspond to our measurements which
typically start at midnight if people
correctly set their and yeah
that's not going to detail into this and
we basically first thing that we looked
in Wars okay do it does it make it
different what we're actually scanning
for and yes it does so if we do like a
TCP scan on port 80 you can see yeah we
don't get a lot of destination
unreachable or port unreachable messages
which is obvious because you would use
probably reset for that but there are
still some of those it also makes a
difference whether or not we're simply
doing ipv4 scans we also do dns-based
scans where we have a lot of zone files
for example it'll be an Essbase and you
can see that we get a lot of destination
unreachable because host is prohibitive
messages if we do scans based on DNS
data and on the right you can see a
little table it summarizes basically
what kind of messages we go out and I'm
going to from some of those types and
see what we actually found when we
looked into those messages I think it
should start with redirect messages so
if you don't know what redirect messages
are they are basically used to signal a
better pass in your local network so
RFC 1820 1812 actually states these
three things and the most important one
it's in the middle it basically says
yeah well if the source address of the
packets on the same logical network is
you you may send these things however we
never are but we still got 18 million of
those messages over the public Internet
100,000 of those are network redirects
which the RSA says you must not send
Pickers they don't make sure we make any
lot of sense if you look at them well
but the majority of host redirects and
they affect roughly two thousand asses
and these are roughly four thousand
in these redirects roughly were 400,000
destinations and within all our DNS data
that we actually have we found also that
900 of them had an a record and some of
those actually redirect you to private
addresses or bruised left address spaces
okay this is not good
next we looked at source quench messages
so if you you probably remember that I
didn't actually really knew what source
quench was when I started this and it's
basically like easy ends grandparent so
the idea was when the route is congested
it's and the source bunch message to the
sender's however research found well
it's kind of unfair if you do that and
it can lead to blind attacks and you
guys said please don't send those in
1995 and you also said please ignore
those messages in 2012 and most actually
do that since 2005 yet we still found
that they're roughly 2 now a thousand I
piece located in over 350 asses that
still issue those messages mostly those
messages were issued in the destination
access but we also found some that were
issued on path I mean we look into some
vendor manuals of yeah some some router
manuals and we found that most of those
vendors also state that they removed it
in between 2000 2010 but you can still
see it takes decades to get stuff out of
the internet so whatever you're
standardizing people will use it forever
if I once activated it all right yeah we
also looked at another thing
fragmentation and if something gets
fragmented because as I said we also
scan for quick so our packets are
roughly 1000 fluid bytes and it as it
turns out or is we use a map default in
our scans and they don't set the don't
segment bit so we got some fragment time
exceeded messages from another couple of
scans where we do set those bits we see
that there's a bit of fragmentation so
yeah
another big bunch of messages that we
actually got were TTL exceeded messages
which were kind of what when I first saw
them because I was
well those internet paths actually so
long what are our TTL values and it
turns out it's the max in Z map and the
otherwise we take the Linux default so
we ask yourself other paths very long
are the many middle boxes tweaking our
titi outs or are there maybe routing
loops and we basically performed a whole
bunch of trace routes to see if there
are loops and we were able to basically
defined roughly 440,000 / 24 from
roughly 20,000 SS that were unreachable
dgo loop yeah
interestingly we thought we could find
130,000 that or the pass where we had
all a piece of all involved routers and
with simple checks we could see that
roughly 5,000 of those actually also
cross is boundaries of loops
however you can definitely make that
better
yeah then we also looked at whether or
not these loops are persistent so we
compared basically trace routes from two
weeks apart and we found that loops from
roughly 150 Isis disappeared but they
were still 404 subnets unreachable
we also found loops in our upstream ISP
in the German research network which was
nice because we can contact them and
they confirm the loops which they didn't
really like they fix the loops and for
her so we're specific they could tell us
basically it was a static route they had
once in one router then they removed it
another one but it was basically still
forwarding packets to the other router
but this rotor had no knowledge about
the drought anymore and send it to its
default route which was the first router
and yeah so it's that you loop
all right this brings me to my aunt so
as you probably know the internet is
full of defecation badly configured
systems we've got more things in our
paper
the nice thing I mean we all know that
but the nice thing is we could find that
without actually doing any new
measurements these were all done from
apart from the trace routes
we're all done using data that we
already cooked
what never looked at yeah lots of
routing loops our data set is partly
available until last month's will
visually our drives run full yeah thank
you all right we've got four minutes
left in the session yeah questions for
Yann or if we don't have those any other
comments on work for the group would be
great along the lines of ice for the
last three times we've participated in
the hackathon so we're welcome to Meaney
what can I talk about that anything
thanks young okay so um along the lines
of the invitation to talk about topics
for the group Mary and I have been
encouraging people to do measurement
work here not just report it so we've
been doing that and the hackathon and
the large-scale scope of it is what I've
been trying to do in the hackathon is
create an anima anonymity sets for world
wide web clients and there was some
really nice work at the nrw if you
haven't seen the program there check
that out about what can you learn from
an IP where they surveyed the
server-side IP addresses and what you
can learn from those and in PRG and I'm
also interested in doing this creating
anonymity sets somehow of the service
side so people can't profile encrypted
traffic and determine what you're
talking to so if that's something you're
interested in get in touch with me or
talk about it on the list or you might
be able to do it in Singapore the
hackathon feel like that's all we have
thanks so much