it's time all right guys it's time
all right this is the Netcom
group meeting if you're not already
familiar with the no.12
please go through it there's a link also
at the bottom of the flight alright so
blue sheets have been passed out make
sure that you do put your name down on
the blue sheets at the mic make sure you
do pronounce your name slowly for people
we're trying to take notes in ether pad
which we'll come to in a minute pulls
all your questions on at the microphone
itself so that remote participants can
listen to the question we the chairs at
least have their own JavaScript's but if
anyone else wants to take lead on it be
happy to have someone else be the
JavaScript okay I guess we the chairs
who then will act as describes we do
have etherpad so anyone sitting in that
room can use that link at the bottom of
the slide to contribute to the meeting
space just to let you know that we also
rely on the transcribing of the meeting
both the vocal inside of the voice
recording of the meeting to actually
take notes and up up take a minutes
there is there been at least one draft
that was published since the last make
up meeting the congratulations still the
author author's into the workgroup so as
far as the status of shattered items the
yang bush suite of drugs that are at
least four of them they have passed IESE
and in the RFC editor key already in
fact they the artsy editor has been
through most of the changes we expect it
to be an odd 48 stay pretty soon for the
final review before they are published
as RFC in the meeting today we expect
the client-server suite of drugs to be
presented so that's working progress
yang push notification capabilities is
also being presented today as we'll
discuss the status of that draft we
haven't had requests for presentation of
their yang push notification messages
draft but we still see that to be
working progress as far as the agenda is
concerned it's already published in the
agenda on the IKEA website
all of these are chartered items except
for the last item which is still an
individual draft
the item left on the childhood item is
of course the notification capabilities
which will be as I said presented today
I think maybe it's giving me zero to I
don't know I'm the non charted items we
still have a we have the multiple
streams originator dot and the new draft
which is the HTTP based transport
authenticates of solutions so that's any
questions related either tildes lights
these lights out the agenda items
bhavish Langille ericsson i would like
to ask what's the situation with some of
the other yank push related slides i do
the UDP encoding there was the binary
encoding or unity transport the binary
encoding Cole home that was
provisionally taken out from the yang
push so there was a draft called UDP
pub/sub is that the one your friendship
that was they working group adopted
draft but we unadopted it last time
because the main post focus was actually
the multi-stream originator what bad
draft needs to do is to be we read of
you know brought to the workgroups again
has a notice draft so if something like
you did he notice so someone can first
you know really submit it in that
fashion then it could be accepted by the
working group good sense
sorry could you speak that well the my
business and the website is still up to
some the stateís patriot EP pops top is
still in the working truth we did ask
for secretary to another course the
binary encoding and called whom the
binary encoding so it's still an
individual ground it's not a workgroup
item if you're referring to the table
that I presented a couple of that comes
yet so it's still there hey may not mean
in the division but it's if I knew your
draft at this point and call home parts
that we took out from yank bush
is there any development on that or so
the call home parts I think if you look
to the draft that Mahesh is presenting
the last one on the on the list here
it's actually presenting a a note of
transport for configured subscriptions
which does in fact do couple more like
that case I wouldn't say column let's
just say device initiated connection and
okay tiny mrs. Hank ever joining Ken's
presentation later and in that context I
want to highlight that there could also
be a co-ed call home because in the
context we were present here that so I
was like there could be multiple
variants off to doing this and I'm not
sure if there should be across documents
or in a single document so Hank is
saying that there's another effort for
doing a binary transport a binary node
of transport for notifications
you can start with the presentations
okay hi good morning so we're gonna be
presenting the suite of the
client-server graphs and of course
asthma has just said all but one has
been adopted working group item the last
one HP client-server we did attempt to
run it the adoption the same time we did
the TCP client-server adoption there was
some pushback from the HTTP bids chairs
which honestly we didn't have the energy
at that time to pursue and you know
because the focus actually when we moved
to the next slide the focus is on the
first three drafts that we're trying to
get them into working group last call as
quickly as possible
so you know after those have actually
achieved last call status then the focus
will shift again to try and get the the
remaining hierarchy of drafts adopted
and published so that's when you should
look to seeing the HTT client-server
drafted adopted and let me just quickly
see yes okay so this presentations focus
is threefold
there's the crypto types draft which
will you know spend actually most of our
time on I think then there's the
keystore draft and lastly restaurant
server draft but I so this presentation
actually just touches on you know if you
go back to that previous list it really
just touches on three out of you know
how many are we looking at nine drafts
and in particular it doesn't talk about
Hank the trust anchors draft which I
think you we were discussing yesterday
you wanted to ask a question about so
maybe now would be a good time to ask
your question about the trust anchors
draft and especially how relates the TLS
draft yeah okay so this is Hank again so
this is my officially it's a car hat
it's probably also yang of things hat on
all of these people who try to do binary
yang there is core Kampf coming up
formally known as call me and this is
using DTLS if it's secured of course and
it should be and that will be and
in coop and on the DTS level a coop
advises to use a different securing
basis you secure co-op and that is a
public rocky a row public key as a
minimal CMS frame as it was standardized
years ago and also we have this concept
of pairwise symmetric keys that are pre
provision and both of these are
suggested methods to secure co-op by the
coop RFC and they can be applied to to
two levels they can be applied to DTLS
and therefore what extend into TLS which
is effectively also done today I mean a
lot of people use PS case probably known
as pre-shared keys we like the term pair
where pairwise symmetric key and the rob
public key of course is a little bit
different than the SSH key material so
my proposal here and this mic is true at
these two flavors like the raw Papa key
and the pairwise symmetric key to the
trust or draft and canned I've already
talking about so we are aligned but the
room has to be fine with this because
this extends a little bit into TLS in
the DTLS it is mandated by a co-op end
and karatsu on the communication layer
but also on the on the application as on
the object security layer so it's a
communication security and it cannot be
an object security so it also goes back
into ask or the object security for
constrained environment also so there
are multiple consumers of this
information and my personal point of
view is we should add that to the graph
itself ok great thank you
and actually to add to that even with
the TLS straps i'm the TLS itself we
primarily think about certificates but
it does support other forms like PGP and
and pre-shared keys and currently trust
anchor draft does not have any support
at all for these things it's really in
that we ourselves should have caught
before and I would expect is she would
have if we are taking those drafts last
call
so what Hank is raising right now in the
context of DTLS actually we already had
an issue with the TLS trapped and and so
you know extending the trust anchors
draft to support pre share keys and and
was the other thing
Iraqis is would be the proper thing to
do and we have another comment coming to
Mike ah Tim Kerry no key I do have a
question on this approach though because
you know there's gonna be many consumers
of these particular drafts hopefully
right outside the context of you know
just client-server type of stuff so here
we have an example of Comey and co-op
wanting to augment and I use that word I
think appropriately here some of the
work that's happening in the keystore
you know from a different area so is it
is it the approach or strategy to
continually revising these drafts that
is the universal crypto or key store
types that we wanted to deal with or or
do we expect the other working groups to
use those drafts or incorporate them
into their into their work and so I'm
just trying to understand you know the
difference because otherwise we'll be
revving this thing for you know every
every every use possible and that's
right quick gleams Nick so there is a
second review of the set of drafts
sometime later today or maybe tomorrow
and be looking for proposals well from
them to tell us whether the approach
that we are taking allows for
extensibility if need be without
necessarily devising these set of drafts
continuously so please if the framework
of these drafts looks I could enough
then other working groups can extend the
more models
I'm the sing it again and addressing the
concern of Perpetual churn we don't want
that so it's basically the same scope
but I think it was like more like an
oversight on the on the DTS part so we
are not not moving outside TLS and ssh
here so the requirements are coming from
the same document so we actually have
the same skull but we are not completely
in that scope i think and and beyond
that it should be different drafts or
formulas of managing us okay so what i
understand what you're saying
Hank is is that the that the base what
we would consider to be any base draft
that would come out of net mod will
incorporate both SSH TLS and D TLS
implementations and then we kind of Miss
the DTLS and that we are agreeing as a
working group that DTLS is a core secure
transport or for the IE q but for for
for the work that we did right hmm okay
so i don't know which hat i'm using at
the moment but this working group is
primarily focused on net coffin rest
cough and they only have association TLS
as being official transport bindings not
co-op yet sorry Hank and that's why I
mentioned that even though TLS itself
actually already has the need to support
preacher keys and wrong keys it's in the
Tila strap so our support of TLS for our
own purposes is already incomplete and
so that's what I'm really you're saying
it's not a detail a saying it's a it's a
TLS thing we should soon complete Hank
Reyes did he it's actually absolutely
correct it would have been caught by is
she had we tried to take the last call
but you know it's better this way that
we can while we're the focuses on trust
anchor getting it to last color we would
extract core to take if they want to use
this for detail us we would do anything
different right we would expect cord to
take well I think after after trust
anchors has been published if any other
group wanted to extend it and add
another kind of trust anchor then it
would be a proper augmentation at Yangon
mentation and it would proceed
basically luckily coincidence that this
is not exceeding your scope okay good
okay very good
all right so before I move to the next
slide and kind of get into it again
these first three drafts that we're
focusing on trying to get the last call
crypto types which we're gonna spend
quite some time discussing today is so
probably the one that's going to take
the longest to resolve trust anchors I
thought was resolved but per the
discussion we just had is now meaning to
be extended slightly I actually don't
view this is to be terribly complicated
and will likely conclude before the
trust of the crypto types discussion
concludes and then lastly there's the
keystore which is also on today's
discussion but thankfully I think we're
at the end of the tunnel and it is going
to move forward quickly okay so back to
this slide again and I'll just move on
that I think so let's begin the first
discussion about crypto types and
algorithm identities strategy I'd like
to invite my co-authors Michael and
Frank sorry what will hang and Frank
know just just how long okay great all
right so so first I mean it set up and
then transfer okay so the high-level
decision that we're needing to make
right now is whether or not we stay the
course or simplify the current approach
with crypto types is to unify all the
algorithms produced by disconnected
security area efforts so there's lots of
working groups within the security area
and each of them are defining crypto
algorithms that are effectively the
identical kinds of things but they give
them different names they create
different IANA registries having
different numbers Regiment assigned
numbers to them which is you know
convenient because you know the each is
in their own protocol but here we're
trying to define a unified layer this
keystore layer it needs the store keys
that can be used by any protocol so we
get ourselves into this problem space
where we're trying to unify the set of
you know algorithms identities or
enumerations or whatever we're using
that can span the gamut of all these
different protocols that's the
fundamental problem that we're dealing
with right now solving this problem is
the right thing to do but it's difficult
and as Mahesh just mentioned a moment
ago last week the chairs did request an
early sector review we were rough it was
assigned and we had a call with him last
week and then just I heard over email
that the topic was raised in the isg
discussion on Sunday and now someone
Michelle from Ayane has been asked to
have a meeting with her FET and the
author sorry the chairs in order to try
to discuss what the next step is to do
so there is some progress on that front
in terms of what is the right thing to
do so but before sorry and I think maybe
Ignace if you want to say something
about that yes this was discussed
briefly at AG sandy meeting and the
outcome of that is that there is no
outcome at this time right and what is
needed is that probably this working
group needs to think of what what of the
possible what of the proposed options
either we don't have a registry but put
a half coded values into into the
documents and we spend that every time I
have a unified registry which is on an
aside or have something in between this
is something for probably not convey
here to think about that and provide a
recommendation what you would see what
would be the
say more stable in the longer term right
okay perfect and that's the set up for
the the last line here the arthur's wish
to see this approach play out again it
is the right thing to do but we're
beginning to think about fallback
strategies so this discussion number one
right here is to first try to talk about
what is the you know how we can the
current approach the right thing to do
and how what we can do to make it
complete and insult
then there's the discussion about a
possible fallback strategy and then
actually again in my conversation with
Hank yesterday during a hackathon
there's a possible third approach that
we could consider as well which I'll
discuss at that time
okay so then now I think I'll pass it to
my co-author yeah good morning everyone
my name is aqua
from Maui cooler of this IKEA abstract
quick to attack Everest
yeah I mean help in these crystals my
identifiers so in this style I will give
some background on the crypto type
crypto errors my identifiers yeah
initially we used identity too
and by issue security everything like
like the upper yeah in the upper figure
yeah for each security algorithm we give
a name and we give a description that is
and so on we classify them into a few
categories for example we have a hash
algorithm and symmetric encryption
algorithm and asymmetry swaps
also change but later actually some
expert from I to intercept the they have
some suggestion that maybe enumerate
type could be better because it is
simple to management and also when new
algorithms designed we can simply add a
single value in the irony I any and yeah
I've seen from different group can refer
to the alien in the practical definition
so after that in the recent draft we
change to the new style in the enumerate
format and future crypto I will indeed
our value field you have to identify
these areas yeah but details can be
looked into that can refer to the
destructor 10 so this on my tangible
contribution on these crypto algorithm
yeah actually I have some personal
observations or the Critical recently
used the unity of it there are many
artists that use different security
areas including worst puppy and cement
chi and also the hash like in the TSI
piece sack and I to answer so many apps
he has been published and many crypto I
will have been defined and related to
the ia the figure below shows the
algorithm from two groups vines TOS
wines SSH so different group and the
different apps he has your own style in
different defining crypto algorithm for
example human for the TOS 1.21 3 that
the definition is different so this
brings a lot of effort for the app see
editor designers had to define review
implement I manage data I wish so
usually they are going to be using a
real system so I think there are lots of
additional maintenance work has to be
done the year also so peace and ease
operation I have some question yes we
come up with a unified framework for
example initially star or any piece for
crypto algorithm identifiers so that
they can be shared among different
groups and abscess for example we can
classify the crypto algorithms into a
few categories and can assign unique
number to each of them and so other
artists in the future can refer to this
this list and do not need to specify the
house absolutely
identified by themselves it's just a
simple reference yeah this is what
what I'm thinking based on my
observation so if they are a better
message so we can put it on Minister so
you can even put them later put in the
crypto type trapped yeah so that's what
I want to share
so the I'm speaking of better methods
this is what I was saying or what my
discussion with Hank you were talking
about Cozy and how when this is the
encryption of JSON documents right and
and when that that draft became RFC the
it registered a bunch of I Ana
registries is it they actually I in a
red shades and they they cover a large
number of cryptographic algorithms I
think your proposal was that we might be
able to leverage that work yeah this is
Hank again it's it's a it's for cozy or
the variation but Jim shot is the expert
on this registry and he that all the
groups there are other participants
there in the group did an awesome job
it's keep my perimeter zits its curves
is hashing its signatures its crypto and
it's always in combination that only the
safe only done with the basics but but
the combination of key strengths and so
it's very elaborate
eye on our registry already there it's
pretty much I don't want to like to say
complete but it's very very detailed
already so this could be another wave
maintained source for everything crypto
ago I'm not saying that is complete for
your scope because it prunes some of the
very old stuff and of course of the
deprecated things but it's the best
maintained come a Anna I know actually
so maybe yeah
ah Frank sorry Howard our interests and
general question about this kind of
thing thank you that you have mentioned
that for the Cody for the world for this
technology we have a very complicated
crypto algorithm on a page right so what
is the relation with this new and the
pager and the with the existing and a
pager for the TRS for IPSec and SSH and
what is your future plan of how to align
with and you know this is a very
important the problem yes I think again
this is not resolved yet so we have
either the option to choose in the
module where to go to but this can be
very confusing and it would require a
lot of implementation and complexity so
that's usually a bad idea but but if
they're gaps and if you see maybe an
assessment of the tables is an order
your your Lea TLS based so busy that's
the way to go you cannot something wrong
there I think from the yang of things
point of view we could just document
that and put a futsal so if you have an
extension point that there is good to
argument so so the young of things realm
could do that just and live with that
and that's okay
we just wanted to highlight that this
there's another table so it's very
maintained and it goes beyond what us
does but it might not be complete
because I have not made a one-to-one
comparison of those actually so this is
just the first discussion about this and
my my personal comments is that it's not
the responsibility of the individual or
group chapter to mention or to reflect
the latest update of crude origin I hope
that uh those I know pages can you know
can be aligned with each other
they take care of this kind of thing and
we just reference to them I think that's
the best way for not only for our tracks
or maybe for future on another draft
right
I know you take care of that moto 2 or
this kind of thing so maybe thank you
and okay great
well you're right so this is definitely
a good resource for us to look at and in
terms of potentially using you know
folding some of those ideas into what
we're trying to achieve with this
approach and to Frank's very last
comment exactly I think that we
currently the crypto types draft defines
one IETF module and really we should be
thinking about breaking it up too many
Anna - modules so you know this is of
course assuming we stay the course with
this approach but you know twofold first
assigning to I Anna allows IANA to
update the modules outside the standard
RFC cycle I think this is important and
probably what Frank was just saying
although I there may be some
disagreement just extent that I Anna
will actually be updating the modules
outside the but we need to figure that
out but that would be the intent is to
allow them to be able to make those
updates so as and when any security area
group defines an extension a new
protocol a new addition to registry
automatically the yang module would be
updated and published by Anna not us
secondly breaking it up into many
modules enables each to have a better
focus you know as a so it's unclear to
me actually how important this
particular point might be but it does
seem like it would be favorable to
especially Anna if they were being asked
to maintain them yes question Wilson
Cisco what why would you spit it in many
I Anna module something missing that
step as to why it goes from one to many
ok the many though it's the second
bullet point so again as unclear to me
how important it may be but it to myself
like well like programmatically it
doesn't matter but from a maintenance
perspective especially for asking Anna
to do the maintenance it could be
helpful to them that then it's been
broken up too many modules and
either case it'd still be one draft like
so this draft the crypto type draft
would continue to be the draft that
would you know create all these month if
there were many modules it'd still be
one draft that designed all the modules
and assigns though them to the IANA
those modules are they are they
representing what the different security
working groups are producing what's the
exact quantity yes it'll be for instance
a module that be for symmetric key
algorithms another module for asymmetric
key algorithms another module for
hashing algorithms if it makes sense to
do this it you know to break up that way
okay all right so again so we would
continue using this trap okay so the
fallback strategy this is you know in
case we don't stay the course and we
wish to simplify the and I did post this
to the mailing list there was no
response um but so here we are going to
go over it the general idea is to admit
that TLS is the transport layer for most
protocols right I mean in reality like
on the network and imagine us you know
outlining ourselves to a more TLS
oriented solution a TLS protocol is
heavily defined using asn.1 structures
right if you look to RFC 5280 you'll see
nothing but a ascend one in there which
is how you then wind up with things like
pin which will not pin but during coding
and burr and coding you know in
particular or even pin
they're all effectively encodings of
asn.1 structures already crypto types
draft defines many a and ASN ones types
so there are types for in particular CMS
structures so sign data encrypted data
and just plain seamless there's actually
six or seven CMS types that are defined
there three of them I think are used
directly by these zero-touch draft and
of course having them you know in the
crypto types track so actually zero I
should say zero touch copy-pasted it's
the same tax dues but to get the zero
touched out the door didn't actually
have a normative reference to crypto
types it's just so anyway it's an same
idea it would be valuable for the crypto
types draft to have those asn.1 types to
find in it so why not add one more a
that one type to it in in particular RC
59-58
defines what they call one a symmetric
key it's a strange name I know but the
title of that draft is asymmetric key
packages and if you look there at the
ASN dot one at the bottom of the screen
you'll notice that it has private key
algorithm private key algorithm
identifier right and so already they've
somehow solved the problem of the
roulette you know all the different
identifiers z' that can be used and how
to refer to them when encoding a s and
that one dot structures so exactly
notice this private key identifier if
you dig a little bit deeper you'll see
private key identifier is an algorithm
identifier and if you dig into that
you'll see that this algorithm is
identified by an object you know an ID
and then you try to figure out what that
is and you don't quite I think that
ultimately maps to an Dianna registry I
tried to find it I couldn't find it so I
kind of bottomed out at that point but
you get the idea they've tried to solve
they they have solved right because it's
running code we just need to figure out
how it's being done so but then what is
an open SSL private key and and you know
I kind of is I think some of you know
I've written two lists I'm in the
process of it creating a restaurant
server and it does implement this it
does use IETF restaurant server which
means the entire hierarchy and down to
key store and trust store and all this
and I'm trying to write code and the
simplest thing for me to do is use open
SSL you can see the first command there
ec pram I want to generate a private key
and then from that I want to you know
generate the public key I'm basically
executing open SSL command line you know
utility command line commands so you
create these things for it for me and
then of course I create this certificate
signing request and sign a certificate
and all that goes into trust store but
what am i doing what am i putting the
key store right so currently we don't
have a well-defined solution and I'm
kind of just getting something to work
and so I hack it and I just basically
put the basics before encoded whatever
openness sellout putted and that I've
stuck into the key sort I'm a lazy
programmer this is easy everyone will
probably be wanting to do this also it's
very simple so you know that's the
question so what is this thing that
opener cell is outputting is it and one
asymmetric key I you know I tried to get
a better parsing you know that's the
that's what open SSL gave me but I can't
quite see if that's an a.1 asymmetric
key it doesn't print out the oit's so
that were regardless whatever open SSL
is using would be convenient for us to
adopt even if it's not the one
asymmetric keys so here's something or
or find a simple way to convert between
the two it's what we need to do okay so
that's the end of that discussion but
somehow I feel are there any questions
did anybody have any questions about
this I guess maybe I've kind of skimmed
over the fact we're no one raised her
hand what do you mean we're only gonna
support TLS
what about SSH SSH is important right I
mean neck has a mandatory transfer
somebody was gonna ask that question
right I can see people not in their
heads yes SSH is important
I don't okay so I don't know exactly
what we would do for you know what
course would want to support it but um
maybe the SSH client server draft well
we'll just have to figure it out I mean
I'm sure there's a way of getting to it
it may be so choice and then inside the
choice it's it's what one asymmetric key
is the one option with a choice and the
other option is Joyce is something we
make up it's very SSH oriented and
support SSH
so we'd find a way to to an you know
carry forward ssh support but primarily
the intent would be that we were
focusing on tell us that make sense okay
that's the end of discussion one no more
questions thank you alright so the
second discussion was regarded we are
grouting the keystore draft and in
particular it is long discussion I'm
sure everyone was privy to between
Martin and others on device generated
keys and the hidden keys so to be clear
with key store the goal is to enable
manufacturers to ship devices with I
divided II certificates
or any you know cryptographically secure
identifying certificate I divided II is
just a particular one but any this
implies that the associated private keys
are hidden because if you're shipping a
device with a forever certificate you
need that private key to be forever and
you know if it were ever exposed to be
not it'd be disastrous effectively so
store you know generating and storing
protecting those keys inside
cryptographic Hardware like a TPM would
effectively become mandatory for
companies who wanted to ship their
devices with out of 80 certificates so
that's one goal so having this ability
to support devices ship for
manufacturing with key stores that have
values in the operational data store
that contain private key and associated
certificate for Ida bit easier tickets
secondly is to enable devices to
generate keys again this is a best
practice generally you don't want I mean
many people do create private keys and
then upload them to a device but best
practice is you ask the device create
the private key for you and and hence
the private key itself never left left
the device it's not it's not on your
file system it's not in your memory it's
nowhere for a hacker to get to it unless
of course they go to the device itself
three is to enable clients to install
subsequently hidden keys so even though
you want the device engine right keys
sometimes it has to be the case you
generate keys outside but once you load
them onto the device you want them to be
treated as effectively hidden protected
so that they can never be discovered or
figured out from that point forward and
you know some people might claim you can
use NAC em for this you know just you
know have a habits that only the root
user the restore session user can can
access that key but even then it's not
quite what's being asked for here when
they when people ask for these forever
hidden keys for is to support standard
backup and restore interactions
so to the greatest extent possible we
want keys that are being created or
loaded or hidden or whatever to be part
of config we want it to be a case that
you can do copy config get your
configuration and then if you need an
RMA a device you can do a another copy
config or edit config and put it onto
the new device and it's there so there's
you know so we want to support standard
backup and restore interactions the
implicit statement here is that these
hidden keys can't be they need to be in
config even though they're hidden they
need to be in config and and the sort of
the punchline here is that need to be
encrypted so they're in config but
they're encrypted so that's what we're
getting to
and then v don't have keys and running
with values only and operational so this
is say some people are talking about if
you have a value a key that's in
operational but you want to use it in
configuration just create a proxy in
configuration that has the name for
instance I handled to it but the rest of
it is missing this is kind of
problematic from the gangue module
design perspective because it you know
whether or not that the key values are
mandatory true versus and mandatory
false it's there's lots of great
properties that you get if the values
are always mandatory true okay so
several strategies have been tried
you've probably noticed that you know we
published the full suite of clients who
are drafts three times since ITIF the
last IDF first we tried having action
statements that created values and
operational which had you know benefits
of generally following the rule about
how actions you know create values or
are executing the context of operational
data store but the cons were that you
needed to copy the values into running
in a way that was really complicated and
we it never was really nice user
friendly then we switched to an approach
where we were trying to encode trips
hash like values into the configuration
this had the benefit of all the values
for in running but the downside is that
then we were encoding verbs into the
values so the
values themselves encoded like a verb
requesting the device to actually
generate the key which was considered
unacceptable and then lastly we went
with this I'm calling disconnected our
PCs but I only mean to say that they
have no data store effect like the
execute the RPC it returns an output
value but it itself has no effect on any
data stored not operational and not
config nothing instead the client that
receives the output needs to round-trip
and return back to the device the
generated key to wherever it wanted that
key to be located so Pro is that it
satisfies all the use cases it seems and
especially wouldn't you include the fact
that the output can be encrypted that's
the main thing but the con is that
round-trip I just mentioned nonetheless
number three appears to have traction
and I just want to go into that just a
bit more just so it's clear so in crypto
types we have grouping so again this is
a crypto types the the previous draft we
were talking about we have two groupings
symmetric key and asymmetric key and
notice that there's a choice key type
and it has two two Leafs one is just
simply key binary that B or your
ciphertext I sorry your your clear text
key so the actual key values themselves
are at raw and visible and then there's
another type hidden key which is of type
empty and so it's just an empty value
and then now in key store draft we have
some groupings so we start with on the
left hand side key reference type
grouping which is you know we have this
choice of two different kinds of T type
key types is that are you referring are
you referencing a symmetric key or a
nice symmetric key
we have encrypted value grouping so here
we were using the previous grouping but
now we're adding to it that there's a
value that's a binary value and then we
have symmetric key grouping which is
using that grouping from crypto types
the one that was on a previous slide and
it's augmenting in a new kind of key key
types of were before there's regular key
and hidden key now there's new thing
called
encrypted key and encrypted key is
something that's using that encrypted
key value right so the key so what's
happening is that there's there's a
value so there's a binary string and
there's a leaf that's referring to the
other key that it was encrypted by and
of course we do the same thing for a
symmetric key store and then lastly
there's to our pcs one for generating a
symmetric and asymmetric key they're
identical except for you know basic
names in the input you can pass
optionally in encrypted with parameter
so you can ask the device yes generate a
key for me with you know said algorithm
properties and but when you return it to
me
encrypt the output value using this
other key that's already in the key
store and I'm referring to it and then
you get back an encrypted key from the
actual data model perspective you can
see I'll just go through one of these
but they're effectively the same
asymmetric keys and now you can see
there's the the private key and there's
these three types the private key hidden
private key and encrypted private key
right and then underneath encrypted
private key there's that leaf ref to
another value in the key store and of
course the the ciphertext value of the
encrypted key so how does this work an
example so you start you know at the top
we have TPM protected keys so this would
be a key if you look on the left hand
side a special key shipped with the
device used to encrypt the operators key
so let's jump to the bottom we have a
symmetric key which is the operators
encrypted key so this would be a special
key used to encrypt all other keys
installed by the operators crypto
officer right so every operator might
have a secret symmetric key that only
its crypto officer knows and at any time
they want to bring up a new device they
encrypt that symmetric key using the
device specifics a symmetric key the one
sword in the TPM and then lastly in the
middle there you have a generic key
which could be you know any key that
might be used by TLS or SSH for your you
know any other
that key has then been encrypted by the
operators key so this satisfies the
goals that we showed before enabling
manufacturers to ship devices with it
was their certificates so now we have
both of those they're in operational of
but also they could be in factory
default there's another draft and going
through net mod about a fact our new
factory default data stores so
absolutely
they could be in factory default as well
and the private key is being reported
with value hidden and empty type so this
satisfies that goal enable devices
generate keys so now we have this RPC to
generate the keys and the client can
decide whether not the key is encrypted
enabled clients to install subsequently
hidden keys so here the client can set
using for instance at a config in
encrypted key but so it's actually not
hidden I mean the use case the goal is
to that they're hidden it's not actually
hidden it's better than hidden it's
encrypted and it's in configuration so
still in configuration which means it
can support backup and restore
interactions which is number four so all
keys except for hidden keys the truly
hidden keys that want the ones that were
shipped for manufacturing are in fact
reported in configuration so you do get
config and you get them and of course
the RMA procedure can migrate the
operator wide key and then all the other
keys that were used in you know the 99
percent of the configuration are then
migrated to the new device and in five
we don't have keys and running with
values that are only an operational is
that awkward ATM that we have currently
all the keys are mandatory true and then
we do have an open issue related to that
though so we're reporting all key values
and factory default and running should
the algorithm or public he knows be
suppressed so this saves an open issue
because Martin I don't think is on the
on the online raised this continues to
raise this is a potential concern so
that's why I'm trying to address it I
personally I think that it's better for
those values to be there because the
pros are that the yang model is best
stating that all the fields are
mandatory true we tried the mandatory
fall approach
got really complicated and I didn't see
any value to it
furthermore there's no harm in reporting
these values the public key is public
it's okay if people see it you can
report it the cons is that the values
only have to be reported and operational
so it's unnecessary so I admit
technically speaking they don't have to
be reported so we're having something
more than necessary and then also con
Martin points out it seems like special
case handling that's true but I don't
think this is really an issue and the
reason why is because I actually think
this is something that needs to be
embraced so firstly number one it's
already the case the server has to
handle has to have you know quote
special handling for the hidden key type
so there really is no such thing as
hidden key there's actually a value a
real value and operational already the
devices have to have special handling to
understand this notion of a hidden key
so I don't actually you know in for
instance when you're doing an edit
config and there's a value of hidden key
the when the device is actually trying
to commit that config we're not actually
telling it to delete the algorithm in
public like if for if if the algorithm
public keys were missing and we're only
passing hidden key we're not actually
telling it delete the algorithm public
key can't do that
it'd be illegal so already there's
special keys handling that's going on
and so I think there's asking it to
don't actually modify so if we were to
pass the algorithm public key and
instead the special case handling is
don't actually modify in case the client
tried to change the values you know
don't actually try to change the values
that wouldn't make sense instead throw
an error I think it's it's just special
case handling of a different kind so I
don't see that as a bad thing
um and then number two I actually think
it'd be better to define an annotation
of some sort metadata that could be used
generically
to identify nodes that are effectively
read-only I think that you know such a
annotation could be used in many other
use cases outside of this use case and
in particular you think about scheme
amounts where you might have some data
that's that you know it's it's in the
host system but it's been shared to a
virtual system
effectively that data is read only in
the context of the virtual system so
when the the virtual system you know if
you do get configure in the virtual
system you get the value but you don't
there currently it's not flagged in a
way that indicates that that value is
effectively read only in the context of
the virtual system so you know something
like a an annotation that could flag
this algorithm and and public key and
you know even hidden key those three
values is basically being read-only
would be perfect for this use case
though we could embrace and extend this
idea to support that as well
opener she's continued RMA required a
special new step I spoke to this just a
moment ago but I go in just a level
deeper assuming operators follow what
would be effectively become best
practice which would be to create this
operator wide symmetric key that's
encrypted on each device using the
devices hidden key and subsequently used
to encrypt all the other keys that's the
best what we effectively be saying is
new best practice all operators should
try to follow that approach if possible
then the RMA process would change from
what you know currently is today load
the config from the old device and then
do whatever additional customizations
are necessary such as installing any
node lock licenses and it actually
probably that might be out of order you
might actually have to install a node
lock licenses before you try to load the
config on some devices so that will
change is a little bit to a new approach
which would be to manually install the
encrypted operator wide key on the new
device and then edit the config you know
from the old device so you did a get
config from the old device edit it just
a little bit to delete the upgrade or
wide key value that was there there in
the key store just delete it and then
save it and then let that be the
resulting file that you load onto the
new device um
that's number three loaded onto the new
device and then lastly do these
additional customizations such as
installing your node lock license keys I
think that's it for this discussion are
there any comments about this again this
key store draft I think we're at the end
of the tunnel
hopefully Robertson Cisco is it safe to
have a single operator wide
symmetric-key I mean is that good
security practice in the sense of if
that key gets compromised do you then
effectively compromise all the vices and
if so with these schemes to work if
rather having a single operator wide
symmetric key they were managing
separate keys for each device so when
you are a it you use what the kids
didn't find that
sure you're right it could be the case
that it's a per device symmetric key not
not operator wide you're right it could
be it just be more maintenance each
operator had to remember what was the
symmetric key I used before but yeah it
could be done so that's their choice
though that's that's their choice and
and again I mentioned crypto officer and
so again we kind of push it to them
push the problem to them one solution
would be a per device symmetric key
another solution would be to design some
code that the symmetric key itself has
being stored inside a TPM of some sort
and then they develop a client that
basically does a handshake transferring
this symmetric key to the new device in
a way that the crypto officer actually
never was in was never revealed to them
with what that symmetric key value was
so that's also possible okay so I think
I think having some security
considerations of this and speaking of
security people about whether this works
or not yeah one other question I have on
the bottom on you so you so you modify
the old device to remove the old
operator wide so okay so okay why it's
either okay it's either do that okay so
remember it's at first the first little
point is go to the new device and load a
new operator white key yeah the second
thing is if maybe this is out of order
right but the second thing I'm thinking
if you load that configuration from the
old device and it has a new definition
for an operator white key that would
overwrite the value that you just stored
so it you're kind of like avoiding that
overwrite so maybe just train to order
this load the old config and then
manually overwrite the old operator what
key oh yeah or another way expressing
this would be to say when
you write that hold configuration you
need to strip out
yeah the old device key or replace it
what even yes with a new one yeah
there's different ways of saying this
but but the the intention is actually
the same key it's the same symmetric key
is just encrypted with a different
public key cuz it's a different device
and you device a different so it's
actually the same symmetric key value
just encrypt it differently so the
config is slightly different different
for that reason excellent
any other questions about key store
draft I just want to know how these
symmetric keys used the symmetric key is
actually currently only being used for
this purpose of encrypting other keys in
fact like in this example the data model
up until the very last or most recent
version of the draft did not have this
symmetric key section there were no
symmetric keys being stored in the trust
or the reefs re in the key store the
reason being that it'd be foolish to
have the symmetric key value in the
configuration where anybody could see it
all all security properties would be
lost but now that we have the ability to
encrypt the symmetric key then it opens
up the possibility that the symmetric
key can be stored safely so that's one
and then two we can then use it to
encrypt all those other keys that are
being for instance used by Association
TLS etc so that's how it's really being
used currently but to Hanks previous
comment about extending the TLS support
and Trust door to also pre-shared keys
and rocky's I would like to have those
pre Securities and Rocky's be also
encrypted with the symmetric key so that
would be the other use that I'd be
thinking about question yes if you give
actually she's one so now for this one
one more and again again yeah again I'm
not sure which side you're looking for
the open issues okay open issues there
we go so I didn't get I think that your
your point took bottom the cons is it
might be
better to define annotation to mark this
configurations read-only the status
read-only so the factory default data
stores read-only by definition and
running is controlled by the client so I
didn't I didn't get that bit what you
mark is read-only
I'm sure words the question so the
annotation is you suggesting I have me
an annotation to mark something as
read-only
yes but factory default Plato is already
everything is read-only same is
operational right so what's your what's
the annotation annotating oh okay what's
what what's actually doing yes um okay
so remember factory default is kind of
like startup where it really is it's a
place where you copy and and you
initialize running right it's the first
running effectively so so it becomes
running and then you're doing a get
config on running and that's when it
would be helpful for there some people
to know that this is actually a
read-only value kind of like we need ooh
with defaults you're being told this is
actually a default value okay so on yeah
so you say effective you try it if you
had you try to write to one of those
values in running the device would
reject that's the intention
yes yeah I'm not sure I like that okay
yeah I mean so we can just basically
hard code it for this draft and not
create the annotation but I think
there's an opportunity to create an
annotation that could be extend be used
in other use cases as well so that's we
don't have to I'm just opening under so
possibility let's take an online so we
have a comment on jabber from hang
saison and yes
providing confidentiality to key
material should include all key material
okay well as Daniel Erickson this
annotation could be very useful for
server capabilities of times where you'd
need you can't change them because their
capability is really and what you want
to reference them for example in mast or
refresh statements
okay sure yeah but then I question
whether they're running configuration
I think capability so they still needs
to be solved but I'm not sure that's
configuration this is not coming from
the operates not all clients come from
the device well but I think what blush
the saying is like when I Torres first
said the topology drafts and the
topology was being discovered through
the data plane and populating
operational but then they wanted to have
configuration that would extend in parts
of what was just got part of the
topology that discovered they wanted to
have configuration so they wanted to
refer to them and the solution that
we've told them at the time was okay
we'll kind of copy those nodes from
operational and put them into running
and the intention is that when it got
stored that the device would know oh
this is something it's already and
running I don't need to create it again
but to balázs is point it be actually
helpful if they could be tagged as you
know and made it a little bit like with
words and I tagged as you know this is
actually a value that came from
operational or this is actually a value
this read-only exactly I don't care if
we called it running we're not running
it's a value that was discovered from
somewhere in capabilities cases probably
from the software itself and then I can
put that say must your configuration
must not it must use something that the
device is capable of currently you can't
put a must between operate or config
falls and coffee true this is the way
around robots and so I but I wondered in
that case whether you want to be getting
that configuration you to intended so
you intended you I have more freedom to
be allowed to inject like system
configuration or templates and things
there is more freedom there and that's
where you're doing the validation so I
still see that the ideal for running is
it's just what the operator provides so
they say this is the config file for
what that device should be doing and
they have complete control over that and
then you merge it with intended which is
where ISIL to see these sort of default
Keys coming in violation all works
because it's actually effectively
intended that's validated and Runnings
implicitly valid by the fact that
intended is but not operating running
hmm okay so let's flush they're on the
list again this is an open issue so it
needs to be discussed on the list and it
I hope to see you responding to those
yeah but that chain of threats and okay
my the chair is at alerting me that this
is running over but just again we had a
ample time on the schedule and the
discussion is important nonetheless I'll
try to wrap up this last part quickly
this is the last discussion number three
regarding the rest comp server structure
strategy so why is why are we talking
about this well the motivation was to
follow the pattern that was set by all
the other client-server drafts in
particular TCP ssh TLS and HTTP models
for all of them there is a grouping that
represents the configuration of just a
single connection a single TCP
connection a single SSH connection and
how you could configure that single
connection but this pattern wasn't
followed in the Netcom from rest cough
models instead in uber application level
grouping was provided you know to
support both standard and call home use
cases and for each many endpoints so you
know it was almost like an application
level model it certainly wasn't a model
that was representing a single
connection so the change was to move
from the left which is essentially one
large data model that contains listen
and call home and inside each all the
endpoints to then on the right hand side
have really two the second yellow or
orange line down have a grouping rest
cough server grouping that represents
the per connection grouping so just what
what is in C the only configuration here
is their certificate Maps right how do
you how and this is a server so how does
a server map the incoming TLS client
certificate to a rest cough username and
that that's appropriately ress cough
it's not a TLS thing it's a rest call
thing so that that would be for instance
what can be done but then
you have the restaurant server listen
stack so if you wanted to define the
configuration for listening to a a
single port for incoming restaurant
connections here is the configuration
for doing that and then there's an
another grouping for a call home stack
so if you wanted to define the
configuration for listening sorry for
initiating call home connections that
would be the configuration stack for
doing that and then at the bottom we now
have our application stack which is the
combination of it all it has both the
list and Ana call home sections and
inside each the multiplicities of the
two stacks which is spoke of and in the
end the before and after there is no
change because that the actual data
models are the same just restructured
and now we have teased out this ability
to have configuration models for you
know the call home stack the listen
stack and also for single connections um
so the question really I have I think
this might even be the last slide is do
we continue this approach currently it's
only applied to restaurant server I did
that because as I mentioned before I'm
implementing the restaurant server and I
wanted this so that's where I started
but it was I think it's goodness and I
think we should propagate it out to you
know not just fresco server but also
restaurant client and in both net client
and server any comments about this it's
the old it should be done then I would
do it perfect ok so that's it thank you
for the input no more questions so just
quickly summarize the next steps that
you have planned for the summary of
crops I know one of them is the
definition of whether we want to go to
the ana registry should look like
anything else yeah ok so I always feel
guilty answering this question every ITF
that comes up and of course the pressure
is
to say you know we'll get it into last
call in two weeks time and then it
slides the reality is as I just
mentioned cryptic types traps is we're
having sector review it needs to go to
Anna
there needs to be a discussion if we can
do the right thing or if we need to do a
fallback thing how long will that take
to play out I don't know
but it is the dependency of everything
is everything depends on it so and I
think it's the long pole in the tent
then there's a trust anchors draft which
I thought was done but Hank just
mentioned that there's a desire to
extend it to support be sure keys and
Rockies and we need it it was an
oversight we should have done it
we'll add it it's a little bit more work
but I think it'll take less time than it
will take to get the crypto types thing
resolved and then lastly keystore which
I just presented I think we're done
there's a couple points about openness
you wanted to which we need to resolve
but they look relatively minor and
definitely we should resolve sooner than
crypto types so ultimately it comes down
to how long will it take to get crypto
types on and I don't have an answer for
that I don't have any more questions
rushon
okay i'm balázs danielle from erickson
and i hope to speak about something more
simple now that we have the yank push
three anchors drafts in RFC edit or
phase now I'm really starting to stock
up with the chancre capabilities new
quarter benoit was added lately so the
problem why we started all this is still
that unchanged notifications about
datastore changes that is a feature and
yes if the note supports it it still
doesn't mean that it will be supporting
it for every single leaf and every
little bit of the datastore there might
be a lot of reasons why that's a no-no
Enoch this counter is cannot be updated
on every time it changes so we need a
way to document which parts of the data
store actually support this unchanged
capability for reporting data store
changes the draft has been updated since
the last IETF one of the comments was
that different data stores candidate
running operational might have different
capabilities for own change may be for
example unchanged notification from
intended is not that interesting so we
need differ a separate way to define for
data store also in the data model
unchanged capability unchanged related
capabilities are only needed if the
device ID or the server actually
supports the yank push on change feature
if it's not done shouldn't these should
not even be there so any feature was
added
time units were unified now it's always
70 seconds like in the Yankees drafts
and I added some quite big examples to
see what kind of instance data would be
a result except for one question I think
the authors do believe that this is
ready for working group transport but
it's stable on the left so what kind of
yang model do we have after these
changes one changes that we have a pure
data store list that defines which which
data nodes support or do not support
unchanged notifications this has
basically two default values one for
state and one for config and then these
capabilities are inherited down data and
a data tree and if you have a few
exceptions like you want to say that yes
I support no unchanged for all leaves
but accept the statistics branch then
you can have these few exceptions
documented in some lists some other
capability is related to updates were
also added update per year dampening
period marks down and Max objects per
update this is how it looks like and I
think it's quite stable except yesterday
there was one additional question raised
that the you see that the unchanged
capabilities are defined for data store
and even the inside they store
potentially per schema node or data node
on the other hand these times like
update period and dim dampening period
are defined on a global level and that
was the assumption for quite some time
now
esteemed colleague raised the question
that they need a more specific
definition for this one as well I
understand that sometimes I'd say
hardware might be able to defer to
report I don't know every second one
other non-text Hardware only every five
seconds questions how detailed how
complicated we want to make it my
feeling is that whether you support
unchanged or not yes no capability
that's very important and you don't get
any feedback if you don't if you try to
ask unchanged and it's not supported on
the other hand for these periods and
maximum number of items you do get the
kind of negotiation yank push we could
fake it for a data store where schema
node maybe the transport mechanism and
it might also change with software load
so questions how complicated do we want
to make it or is it to have it on a
global level binocular Cisco so actually
I like very much unchanged flexibility
because that's right at for example we
could have unchanged on the entire data
store we could have unchanged for a
specific feature we have that not the
minimum they did period there for
example the question is not how complex
you want to have it the question is how
reliable we want to get this contract
with the box right so if I go on a box I
want to be scored you could do okay they
are implementation where the minimum of
that period is for entire data store
great but there are some other as well
where actually the the cadence right
that you that you want to get
information is different on a line card
for example for a specific interface if
you're for if you get information from v
etc now if we take like the the the
guidelines that we want to get the
contract whenever you connect to a box
it's important to understand the minimum
of the period for each of the different
things you can get right because if you
want to assure your box
it's like difficult to say okay let me
try like 10 seconds your information
okay I could do more that's right like 8
and 5 and 3 until you get like well beep
you can't do it
it might be better to get this in the
contract and we connected a box telling
for this part of the three I could get
you every half a second but for the
other one interface counters on their
line card on this big box I could do 30
seconds so if you have to rely on this
to get any assurance and it closed the
protonation we need this flexibility and
I get I get it that it might be complex
but we might be getting the same
flexibility that we've got below or at
top as well I see it as somewhat
different because these global minimums
are saying that the best the box can do
in any part of the data model any
datastore is I don't know 170 seconds
and then you try that for interface oh
interface sends you back that it's only
2 seconds I can do and then you still
have that reliability yes it's a one
more round trip you can put it in the
date this one as well so these minimums
mean that that's the best the box can
ever tell you and give you and so maybe
some parts will give you a worse value
but maybe it's not the right question
right it's the best that box can do to
get me that information as opposed to
that one this is you did a question that
we have to answer right as opposed to
because you know if you implement this
you know update period will say well
okay five seconds why no you're the
minimum is 10 70 seconds I'll try to
incent the seconds and then the box will
tell me that okay let's do that
10 whatever unit then we'll go to some
pumps all you want to use the box and
say right I want to get like my fav
information every house whatever unit
and then you say oh actually no mr.
customer because it's like more like
five seconds it's common sense so you
know it's it's a question of consequence
being the right expectations or to rely
on the information Rashad Cisco just to
add to what Bruno was saying I mean in
terms of implementation you get
collectors and sensors different
hardware which are out
very different collection capabilities
and you already have feels per sensor
path it's not like you're adding an
extra list or whatever it's that field
could be if you add if you put the
update period per path it could be
optional by default he inherits what's
at the top it's not something you have
to add but for people who want to
support that it's there so I think
there's some significant benefit thank
you I I can live with changing the model
in that way yeah for me it's it's new
Brooke Wilson Cisco I have not read the
rights version the drop I have two
questions one is is this information
will be available offline is like
instant State this is a yang model and I
very much hope that instance data will
be provided but that's not really up to
the vendor to decide that yes I provide
you with instance data then the second
question is in terms of these paths if
you have a device that sports many
interfaces can you wild-card those paths
to say the counters under an interface
on any of these types of interfaces will
have this and performance where is
without having to list every single
interface at this point I'm using node
selector from an ACM which might be
moved to you the yank types that say
it's the format is the inside anti-fire
but you can omit the keys with meaning
then it that means that's every every
key value for that so if you want to say
that all the interfaces yes you can do
that with a single single item if you
want to go into more specific Ethernet
interfaces or fast ethernet interfaces
such groupings then no this is then you
have to have to do that one by one okay
but I don't think we want to get have a
full regular expression language
embedded here no and I agree and I think
that's probably right compromise but it
goes I think it's back to what Ben are
saying is that ultimately this is a
contract
I think contracts of what's the minimum
capabilities you're willing
support rather than necessary the
maximum so if you say I can support a
damping period of five seconds or
whatever happens with me then you should
effectively be able to honor that for
everything it's a slightly different
contract the two parts unchanged means I
really I promise to support it but these
periods either global or if we put them
per datastore that node or pair whatever
its you might still have a CPU overload
and then it will come back that okay I
already have too many subscriptions
going figured so your subscription will
get on really I don't know twice that
dampening periods because I have six
more subscriptions already in my in
place okay this these times I don't
think they can ever be taken as a
guaranteed time would you would you
reject that subscription if it came in
and you couldn't honor it I think though
what's the SUBSCRIBE notification sites
that you reject it and they say that
okay try with the double the time or
whatever time okay but not less so I
want to come back to what you said if
you can't guarantee the minimum of that
period well actually depends because
there are multiple ways that you could
do telemetry right these tricks interval
or if you wait until after the
connection the correction time but the
point is that we should do the best that
we can for a device is healthy right if
the device is not healthy because it's
CPU is overloaded etc I mean yes we
arrived in the situation where we should
give during those those dead timeout on
the fly it's not it's not at the point
the point is that I connect to a box and
say contract now I understand that you
want to do this for two different use
case like implementation time right and
the run time I care about the run time
at discovery right I can agree that I
would change the model as you like
putting all these values under the lists
probably it will need to be renamed in
that case still I think that it's not
just healthy or not healthy if you have
one subscription you will get the
promised values if you have already
hundred subscriptions on the device it's
still healthy but yes you have hundred
subscriptions and the device might know
that I can't give you the lowest value I
promised design time and I can't revert
that I just only wording I can put there
is that this is the promised value in an
ideal case but the device still has the
right to say that I can support on the
double time exchange thank you okay so
that means that unchanged capable notes
list you have to be renamed to I don't
know datastore subscription cap no
specifics or something like that and all
these are the update periods max objects
and minimum damping period will go under
that list yeah that was an example that
usually you don't need to put this or do
this specific stuff in the in the
instance data you only have a few values
and the other the question about last
call you looks like me to make some
changes first yes this model needs
update but after that I hope it can go
so how many people and just get a sense
from the room how many people have read
this version the back raise your hand a
few and there's no really follow-up
question one
Gendron
hello everyone no one is chained from
Maui and I would like to introduce the
update on the subscription to morrow
stream originators district and firstly
a brief introduction we know the the
yunkish describe the magazine about pops
up and this this draft is about the
distribution is distribu to the
extension to the young push walk and we
took it for a transporter independent
next we describe the two use cases in
our draft why is about the the router
with multiple line cars and one wanna to
actually push data from line cars to the
two other tractor and the other is about
the IOT is narrow and I would he node
can push data to the tractor and the
border outer does not assemble data as a
broker and there was discussion since
last a meeting um this about the IOT is
narrow since this case requires node
management protocols in addition to the
push mechanism for example the node join
or the leaf no discovery and so on so
this I'm open so it if it is a really
useful or helpful to include this out
use case in this draft I'm open to hear
the suggestions in the working group and
next
here is the solution over vo we do not
change actually and it described the
basic magazines including the
subscription decomposition the
publication composition and the
subscreen state change in notifications
next we propose to extend we propose the
extensions for the publication
composition because the receiver need to
know the number of component
subscriptions so we propose to add a
list of publisher ID for configured
subscription we add this to the
subscription started and subscription
modified notifications and on the
dynamic subscription we add this to the
established subscription and modify
subscription are our PCs and we stopped
here in lustre revision because we think
this should be this job this draft
should be transport independent but
there was suggestions in the Middle East
to to consider the transport
configurations for multiple line cars so
we have the following the following two
discussions next the one is about the
extension folder configure the
subscription we suggest to add a list of
channel configurations under the
receiver configuration and in this case
all the potential channels are
pre-configured and the actual
publication channel are selected based
on the subscription decomposition result
and here I also give an example we
borrow this from the narco HTTP
notification draft
and we put this we put all the we'll put
this in in you know a channel container
for this configuration for this
configuration in the channel comfy
container and next contributor just a
question so it is a list of channels and
by channel you mean line card presses
yes yeah you turn card well hydrogen and
the other the other one is the extension
for dynamic subscription this seems more
complicated complicated because because
there are several transport options for
the the line cars firstly the line cards
can run on server mode or client mode
and the connection could be dynamically
set up or pre-configured so we have two
option one is to generalize the rest
cough notif jeff'd
this is the mode firstly the rank has
rung on the server mode and the
connections are dynamically set up so we
need the RPC to return the resource
access information and the receiver can
get data from the line cards and the
second option is used to consistent with
the configure subscription just like the
previous example and this mode actually
the line cards runs on the client mode
and the connection is pre-configured so
all the channels are pre-configured just
just a push data when the subscription
requests accepted
yeah so next we consider to improve the
examples but we also have question what
kind of reuse employees expect it
because of we see we do not see a
similar example in the the subscriber
the notification draft I think you this
draft is can be compared to a standard
one but we did not find a similar
examples and we also accept other
suggestions on issues we need to
consider in in the following work and
questions questions
so Tim carried no kids we did have a
question and I think I brought it up on
the last time and I in the yes question
again about the IOT use case right and
my concern was that outside of a closed
ecosystem a network element itself you
would have to have some additional
capabilities in place to to be able to
discover if it's in the network element
the line card from the from the from the
gonna say proxy for a pet I forget what
to call it the master guy and so there's
got to be ways to be able to do all the
discovery elements in there so if you
tried to extend this to anything outside
of closed ecosystem I think there's some
considerations that that that need to
happen or for the solution to work
correctly and all the security that goes
around it right right now you're just
constrained to a to a locked box if you
look the extended past that then you got
to worry about discovery and other
elements so that would be my concern
with the IOT use case yeah so what's
your suggestion so you think we should
not include that's in the chapter or
unless you're gonna want to go into the
I think so I think so want to go into
those other use cases you're going to
have to address these different issues
and so I don't think that that was your
original intent with this draft right
you're just trying to say look I've got
a I've got a closed ecosystem that I'm
gonna put together a master publisher
that's gonna kind of coordinate that
stuff instead of having different
streams right that's effectively what
this was doing right and so I would keep
it into the context that was in if you
do choose to make it broader then you're
gonna have to address these other issues
okay sinks as a contributor my takeaway
from that would be at a minimum the
track needs to have a section that
speaks to this and at least no
identifies that that intention and and
then and then there's question of
whether or not the draft actually solves
it so
one potential solution might be for it
to define in config policy operational
state that lists out the channels that
the device is having available that
descriptions can be made on and that
would be one way to solve is another
might be to look to the equivalent of an
entity myth where you can somehow
discover the line cards that existing on
the device and then you know derive from
that that they might be suitable for
using as channels detonators in either
case I think this draft needs to talk to
it and and choose an approach that you
know but you either say that it's out of
scope and and you know it's only going
to support closed ecosystems as ten
dimensions or it's in scope and point to
a solution that people can use right you
can imagine an IOT you know if you're
looking at this an IOT would be some of
the mechanisms they use for discovery
may be out of coop you know that type of
stuff so you can it can spin quickly if
you want to move it out of that closed
ecosystem but even within the closed
ecosystem you're correct you might want
to give them some guidance say hey look
when you build a line card it comes with
what you guys were talking about becomes
a channel right you know you want to be
able to listen abilities okay thank you
poignant from a hobby for this is
rushing I just a machine we have already
implemented in our some pro taught and I
interact with the customer
so I can't as a contributor I guess I
was I think we talked about we discussed
this on lists and the with the channels
it was unclear to me that the channels
was a lists of channels or or you know
or not also there's you know we don't
have a gang model that is yet defining
this this node this container called a
channel or actually is a list without
your sirness so you'll have a note we
don't have a gang model that defines a
list called channel where where is that
gang model working no it presumably it
should be in this draft
well actually really presumably might
offend in the SUBSCRIBE notification
shaft but I think that there's a you
know it I'm not really clear how to
extend this draft to have that
definition of the list of channels in it
being maudlin could you go to the
configure substitution yeah yeah no yes
this size so right now if this is not
included in the in the yeah model in the
draft so if we can agree we can have our
consensus then I would like to add our
list of add a channel list under the
receiver yeah that means the each
receiver can have Chhabra establish
annals each receiver have several
channel configurations okay again as a
contributor right so and and also the
co-author of the HTTP note of draft that
my actual net present after your
presentation mm-hmm that HTTP note of
draft is the first note of draft that we
have that this working group has
produced for a configured description
and the approach is taking which is in
fact was sort of you know suggested or
we're almost mandated by these describe
notifications draft or ARF's are almost
farsi was to augment the receiver
No and so that's what that track does it
augmented the receiver note yeah and
then what you're suggesting is that
there'd be a channel that's underneath
the receiver yeah yeah and that it
should actually be augmenting the
channel note yes and so how is it
it knows am I supposed to be augmenting
the receiver note or am I supposed to be
lifting the channel no how can it you
know so I think we get into this issue
of like in these not've they should that
it's the intention the note of craft
it's kind of somewhat independent of the
transport so out of the contest
so how would it know if this is a device
that has slang carts or not and what is
the appropriate augmentation one I think
that's the issue that we know this this
is C and this is also an Augmented to
the the subjective draft so let me see
if you own if you opened if you wanna
only wanna enable the one channel to the
receiver is like the sub no TV after you
you just augments that draft and added
audio configurations on the receivers on
the receivers and if you wanna enable
the mark on line cars the multiple
originator scenario then you can augment
the augment the channel configuration
sounder to China here I think I
understood that and just sort of restate
it what you're saying is that the HTTP
not've draft could actually have two
augments one to receive who wanted
Channel and each of those arguments
could be for instance with a feature
statement so that you know it's only one
or the other or maybe both I don't know
or I think in and no need to do that
because that the channel configuration
is also under the receiver right so you
you just add you just augmented the
augment your configurations to the
receiver
of the sub not've shaft but the
subscribe notification strap doesn't
itself how the channels list in it like
by default and and so yeah devices that
only implement that RFC he will not be
having Melissa Janice yes not that is
the question yeah I realized this
question then so I initialize I send a
send email true to you to suggest to
suggest your transporter document we
included these channel configurations so
so that can be compatible of if you only
enable one channel or multiple channel
okay
there can be many notice transports that
are defined the HTTP notice is just one
of many possible its begin and and I
don't think we want each of those notice
transports to themselves happen to be
augmenting it and optionally implemented
channel that's it so it's not the right
place to do it I think that you're a guy
can have a data model that augments the
receiver lists adding in a channel list
some devices will implement it others
won't the note of straps we could
actually have it that they have a
dependency both to subscribe
notifications as well as to your draft
with two arguments and there's a feature
effectively that the server chooses
whether or not the note of is a
augmenting one of the sub the channel
list if it exists or not I think that's
what we could do but we can't just hard
if we move the channel list into the
HTML oh crap and it's only one of many
possible future note of that it's not
the right location for it
but Angela Erickson I'm confused by a
statement on this list all potential
channels are pre-configured so others
this configuration data perfect route
notes yes is configuration how do you
prevent the user to add or remove
channels that actually exist or are our
dummy
we have that problem in the many places
and have a Erickson specific or 3gpp
specific solution but what is your
proposal I actually do not realize your
problem so I see that all channels are
pre-configured
to pre configures and the device itself
or for device or device to configure all
the channels but what does what prevents
the operator from going on and saying
that there's also balázs channel
actually there's no such thing but it
looks like from now on as if it was
there so how can you prevent someone
messing up this pre-configured set of
channels there's two things there's the
adding of channels to don't exist and
there's the forgetting to configure
channels that do exist or removing
channels that were pre-configured right
I think maybe the channel is some other
results just use delivery for eun-jung
and every reference like an interface to
be called like a FTP we maybe we can
specify the outgoing interface we just
configure the interface but that
anything master begin the interface
model and adjust the reference state
maybe like this okay but that doesn't
really address the problem I think that
if you operate ER by even by mistake
removes a channel will it ever get back
there or how shall he know that he
should put it back there you mean just
configure King to if for he company to
remove the channel and how to get back
that sound right
maybe we should define another typo
trust of for Vader only for maybe
another channel for reference maybe so
we have a comment on jabber from Erik he
says I support Ken's proposal for multi
stream originators in its GPS not of you
can augment subscribe notifications or
some objects and multi stream
multiple line cuts are needed thank you
you're going back to the previous
comment or discussion I was just we're
having let's take a step back why do we
want to have it list the channels at all
the reason why is because some protocols
require her channel configuration for
instance and actually it's questionable
right but for instance in TCP you may
want to specify the source IP address on
a per line basis also for TLS you may
want to specify the cryptographic
credentials on per line card basis but
those are TCP and TLS specifics not all
notifications transports will
necessarily have either or any such
considerations for instance a flat UDP
let's say syslog or UDP has none of
these concerns and so a global
configuration of sits log of e to be for
instance just going to receive her you
know augmenting receiver and then the
could be a global flag that says I want
the these line cards to be able to send
syslog a read P straight out the data
plane and that's it we're done
it's just a global flag there's no need
for a per line card configuration of any
sort right so no so I think let's try to
take a step back and and you know see
you how much configuration needs to go
in there and can we tease out certain
flags that exist in the global level
versus for line card bases yeah so so in
the interest of trying to move this
draft forward one conversation that the
chairs were having was to figure out
maybe we need to put a design team that
might be helpful for the for the authors
and if such a design team would informed
if people here would be interested in
and of contributing to that design team
identify the problem may be defined the
scope of the graph help to move it
forward that would be one day a week
would suggest
how you move to that pole yeah there's a
design team it's very welcome
yeah I mean to be clear the work group
very much wants to adopt the strap we
think it's important work I shouldn't
say the watch group I can't speak for
group chairs niggas I think we welcome
if I can't say working group we adopted
you to keep up sub three four because
this was the use case that we were
hoping that it was going to solve but in
the end it turned out to be a UDP
transport which is actually not so we
did actually as a working group adopted
this idea if we want it we need to
support this so we're trying to get it
over the line quickly as possible and
we're just thinking that it might be
helpful to have a design team um so
would anybody be willing or to work with
the author on a design team basis your
hand yeah I see some hints so that's
great and you everyone in the race are
here and send a message to the author so
they can sync up with rocker think it'll
okay great thank you
ah thank you and we need to move to our
last presentation which is Mahesh should
be providing
Shh
No
[Music]
no it's not hollering so I'm going to
talk about HTTP based transport for
subscribe notifications so this is the
case where we talking about configured
subscriptions next slide please
so the motivation behind this draft has
a couple of references have been made
the SUBSCRIBE notifications draft
defined the container for receivers but
kind of left it up to the other drafts
to actually define the transport so this
draft tries to do that it's it's simple
in terms of the fact that we defining
one well-known transport protocol which
is HTTP in this case and it's using
well-known encoding support that is XML
and JSON used today a bit net content
has come next slide alright so the
design is the of course the ability to
support multiple subscriptions to the
same HCT it's gtps receiver and the idea
is that without replicating the
configuration for a receiver the model
basically augments the subscribe
notifications container receiver as you
see at the bottom on the right side and
then that augmentation refers to a list
of receivers or a receiver actually in
this case and the receiver as we say in
the module has a list of TCP TLS and
HTTP parameters that it uses from the
module at the drafts that Kent has been
presenting and is working on so that's
really the sum of the entire draft and I
know there were a couple of questions on
the mailing list
Rashaad cisco why is it called HTTPS and
not rest conf is that deliberate or is
that
yeah I think it is it's gtps meaning
it's not it doesn't have the heavy pay
off the rest of the rest conf it's
mostly its GDP s okay okay I might have
further questions or not all right no no
robots in Cisco any thought to using
binary coding here ah
good question yes I guess there was that
draft presented early and co-op is also
suggesting a binary based notification
so that's certainly something we could
consider as a contributor this graph
actually supports both JSON and XML and
the way it does so is through this
describe notifications draft already
inside that data model there's a leaf
called encoding Eastern identity with
Drive types XML JSON in theory it could
be extended to support binary and then
it you know here just be binary over
HTTP
so we distract herself we don't think
you know leads to itself you know it's
it it's already not it's indicating what
encoding is used being is it just
inherits it on the subscribes other
patients trapped okay makes sense okay
thanks all right
next slide all right if there are no
other questions actually in interest of
full disclosure I and axe and Kent since
via co-authors on the draft I want to
step back and have our ad kind of come
up to ask the remaining two questions
you can as well doing this well if you
really insist I can certainly read those
two I'm sorry right but now you you'll
be on the video and you can actually see
the hands that way
because I'm fine I can actually read
those two lines if you insist
so again serious question is the working
group sees this as the work that is
needed if the community would eventually
see this being deployed and used what
can I see can I see a show of hands
right if you so about who has who has
read this document all right now I think
this needs to be raised into the mailing
list about adoption please read the
document and please provide your
comments and feedback about that from
from those hands which I ca think it's a
little bit premature to ask this
question right now so let's take this to
the mailing list so I read the draft in
detail and it's well returned it matches
well with subscribe notifications can
all that so it's all good but one thing
I was asking the restaurant question
before is we don't actually have an
HTTPS draft for dynamic subscriptions we
have net can-can restaurant right so is
it just configured or is there something
else for dynamic subscriptions actually
it's that's the part I'm struggling with
okay so first I'll thank you Ignace for
running this question we'll take it to
the non list and then back to Rashad
question which you raised before but so
with a contributor hat on so over the
course of several a test we didn't race
and talk about this discussion and
certainly dynamic descriptions have to
be restaurant that cough because you're
coming in over a restaurant for an
economic connection to begin with with
configured descriptions is it the best
choice like if the device is going to
proactively initiate a connection
to a receiver would that should that
connection be of reskin a connection
which all that into it entails meaning
it's a full configuration operational
stage etc type connection do we want all
that or we were looking for something
smaller simpler remember this is being
implemented online cards so it has to be
simple and and you know and typically
you know people talk about pushing
notifications syslog SNMP is sort of the
baseline what we're doing so the next
simplest thing that we're thinking is
HTTP s because it is fairly simple
protocol and and it doesn't come with it
any of the extra management overhead of
oh oh but no rush comecomecome
okay thanks for dispersion Oh 3gpp has
recently started defining here yang
solution set for number four Wyndham
issues and they actually stated that
they prefer a configured way of
subscription you're subscribing to
notification so I see this is important
we are three minutes ahead of time
that's great um yes that's it thank you
very much for coming to the session of
course it's lunch now after lunch will
be met Maude I believe it's in this room
met mom session one and then a short
break followed by even that mom session
two in the room next door
see you then