yep so we're gonna work through the
administrative detail here this is a
continuation of the immediately previous
meeting which had occurred in the
adjacent roof so our agenda still holds
as planned I would observe that the note
well still applies to this meeting just
as it did to the previous half of the
meeting so keep that in mind this is
very much an IETF activity blue sheets
are going around it is not actually
Liggett or II that you signed them both
times since we're having the same
meeting but if you didn't sign them
previously by all means do so so that we
have an accounting of the fact that you
are in the network of vertices these are
different blue sheets yes
[Music]
okay administrative details we do have a
media echo session for this I was
scribing in there for who was speaking
we have the same etherpad as previously
so we can just pretty much pick up where
we left off all right so agenda wise we
are going to start in with the design
team and so this is actually about half
of our agenda for this session and first
up is Joe Clark
a versioning design team update all
right so it will actually be three of us
presenting actually be three of us
presenting today I will be your first
host oh okay next please using that so
there are agenda today will be five
minutes hopefully less for me followed
by I'm gonna guess the bulk of the time
with Rob and then Bala will round us out
and Rob will take us to next steps next
please
so the first thing we want to talk about
is the versioning requirement changes
and the reason this is only five minutes
is because this is going to be fairly
short essentially last time we agreed
that we would adopt this document it was
still unclear as to what the fate of
this document will be if it will be
taken RFC or if it will just be
something that the working group agrees
to that these are the requirements that
we're trying to solve and instead we
will then adopt solutions work through
those solutions as a working group and
take those two RFC but we did adopt it
there has been one change since just
transitioning it over to an IETF net mod
document and that is changed to text for
requirement 1.4 based on feedback we got
directly at the last meeting next please
that change was the original 1.4 said
essentially that non backwards
compatible changes must be allowed there
was some consternation over why must
they be allowed instead what they were
what we really wanted to focus on was
win non backwards compatible changes
occur those changes need to be signaled
or documented so that one can see that
between two revisions of a particular
yang module that
backwards-compatible changes have
occurred so what you can see down there
under the new heading is the new text we
arrived at this was posted to the
mailing list a little bit of while a
little while ago we haven't heard any
additional comments on this so at this
point the design team feels that the
requirements draft the ITF version at
revision 0-1 is final these are the
requirements that we have been working
towards in terms of a solution at this
point questions all right as to what the
final resting place of this document is
we of course leave that to the chairs
and the working group the design team
feels that what I said earlier this
document will not progress to an RFC
it will just be there to serve as the
guidelines for the requirements that
will inform the solution or solutions
that come forward actually on the next
document but it maybe is pertinent to
this question wait and it's really why
not combine the two and you have like a
solution overview document that repeats
a whole bunch of requirements in it if
you really believe that we need
requirements somewhere let's keep it at
one place rather than have because the
requirements even though you don't think
it needs to be documented it's not meant
twice so it'd be great just to have one
document and maybe maybe what we end up
as from a working group is a
requirements in solution overview or
requirements and framework document and
that's how we end up publishing that so
we fold in what's now an individual
document into the working group document
and let that go forward and you know
maybe all the historic stuff goes in an
appendix just for context okay so so I
do feel that the documenting the
requirements are important not
necessarily document is a ratified
document but I get your point and maybe
that's what then will become of the the
framework of the next document that will
be presented
any other questions comments ones
requirements are facing stone even if
they are in document we don't spend our
time reviewing them all the time because
they're wise you're back to square one
right well we definitely shouldn't
change this one once we're done with you
know the process of agreeing that we've
arrived at that point very good and
actually that's a hundred percent my
objection with repeating requirements in
another document now I have to go review
those make sure they're right now we
have to go discuss them is it the right
way to summarize let's not do that
please
so we're saying yeah our intent is that
these requirements now become fixed
these are the requirements for which
we're trying to solve the the
requirements in the overview draft are
only there to make it easy to read so if
it's easy to have them now just refer to
this one that sorts of it's more easier
to say the requirements are documented
here go read it just give a second
second set which isn't written quite
exactly the same way that you have to
figure out what's different what's not
different yes that's right well oddly
Rob why don't you get up here I'm gonna
get out before something changes okay so
so I need a quick update for next slide
please so I just want to we continue to
have semi regular meeting since ITF 104
there's quite a few people who've I'm
dialed in either a weekly or semi weekly
basis and we've continued to progress
various documents I like to thank
everyone down there on that list I don't
repeat them and our main output really
is that tweak the requirements document
the judges talked about an updated sort
of solution solutions overview draft
that sort of tries to pin everything
together and show
you wear the different bits of the
solution hanging together and then our
main focus has been working on this sort
of new / updated yang moderate module
revision handling draft that evolved
from the somatic version draft that we
presented in 104 my opinion is that this
draft accommodates all sort of core
feedback we received during the working
group meetings and also the versioning
discussions we had at 1:04 and so we
think it was sort of reflects that
consensus from that next slide please
so I'm now going to spend the next 20
minutes discussing the solution overview
I'm just trying to set the scene of
where these drafts ought to hang
together then there's me subsequent
talks on some of those there are
different parts so next slide please so
my intention here was that the solution
David Dreier you draft is meant to be a
sort of transient temporary document the
the idea here really is just to help the
readers who are reviewing those drafts
understand how they fit together what
bits haven't yet been written but in
what will be written a mind teacher
wasn't intended to take this to RFC I
mean it could be done but that the
attention of this was to help people
during the review process in terms of
updates there will be a separate
presentation by balázs on updated mod
revision handling I will talk about
young packages after this and Rashied
will talk about version selection so
those three ones will be covered in more
detail next slide please
so the overall solution as we see it now
is made up of five different parts the
first one is in updated yang module
revision handling so this is doesn't
talk about semantic versioning at all
but talks about yang module revisions
and how they can allow non backwards
compatible changes and Express those and
more branching and fixing other things
related to that area there's a really
just a semantic version number scheme
that it sure could be described fairly
abstractly that hasn't been written yet
but we derived from the text from the
previous one draft 30 over DT net mod
yang Simba's eros eros or take the
semantic versioning a definition from
that draft you just extract that text
and I'm putting in isolation so we'll do
that in the next phase there's a version
yank packages draft and this one was
published this update was much before
ITF 104 I need some changes to take into
account the changes in the updated yang
mode revision handling so I will present
that one this time it wasn't presented
in 104 and but there needs to be some
updates to that there's also a draft for
protocol operations for package version
selection so that's draft Wilson Ahmad
yang vs. election 0/0 again that one was
published before 104 Rashad will be
talking about that so again that is sort
of quite early draft we expect there to
be more substantial changes to that and
then the final part of this whole puzzle
we think he's tolling related to doing
schema comparisons between either a
module by module basis all you group a
set of modules together into one is yang
packages to actually version and be able
to compare two schemas and report at the
schema level what's different or maybe
on a per leaf node base of data node
basis what's changed between those two
schemas so that work is on is our least
lowest priority at the moment we're to
try and get the other work out the way
first so next slide please okay can you
talk about if there's any significance
that the naming of the document I notice
go through some transformations from
version design team only well I think
probably not at this stage the ones that
came out of the Verde T the design team
obviously have the Verde T prefix the
young version yanked packages and the
packaged version selection were not work
there was output from the design team
there in need to individual drafts that
I wrote but I that's not because the
design team doesn't align necessarily
with that direction I don't think it was
just more that that's when they produced
the proposal later on here
is for the design team to hopefully pick
up those documents and work on them as
design team documents that's the plan if
that's okay
the name doesn't it's a file name so it
doesn't really matter but whether we
have a complete solution from the design
team or a partial solution I think does
matter and we really are looking the
chairs are really hoping to get a
complete solution from the design team
yeah and if for some reason a design
team didn't feel that that was a a noble
goal we should you talk about that so
it's great to hear your plan so yeah
it's one card they're like one comment
on that
not everyone the design team believes
that the version selection is required I
would say so that's the one we're not
going to redo des Kate are our
requirements and that it's in their
requirements yeah I'm sorry that's one
so you know good so of the first of
those five drafts the updated yang
module revision handling this is the one
there's a more detailed talk on this by
launch we'll cover all of the different
parts of this in a lot more detail so
this is just a one slide summary of what
we've done and what the draft covers and
you have the core enhancements to Yang
or to allow but not necessarily
encourage nonlinear module development
eg for bug fixes so we allow we allow
some sort of branching to occur in yang
module history and to document when not
on backwards compatible changes have
occurred in the revision history so
we're not saying that we're not
encouraging that people should do this
but even when they do occur at least be
able to describe that so that when
clients when people read these documents
and or client tools are processing them
they can know where and Nan box
classical changes have occurred the next
part of that is that we we still
identified module revisions uniquely
using the revision date so nothing's
change from what we have today but we
allow a new freeform text label to be
associated with a revision
and this text label can be used
effectively to overlay like a semantic
versioning scheme for example or some
other scheme that somebody else comes up
to it's not we're not defining within
this document what the form of those
text labels can be but we do allow these
revision labels to be used when in the
file name for example in replace for a
revision date and the import by derived
revision again can also use this label
as well we define a new version of
import
so today yang has an import that will
choose any revision or has an import
that chooses a very specific revision
and one of those is two general ones to
specific so we are introducing one
that's import by revision data or
derived and that effectively you will
find you a revision that is either that
or that's within its history and so
that's the attention there is if a
module that you're importing has a new
container added into it or new and you
know that you're referencing then you
can put dependency on that revision or
later so you put in that source code
dependency we define
backwards-compatible versus non
backwards-compatible changes and these
are actually the non
backwards-compatible change so bogus
collateral changes are very close to
what is defined in our c 7950 with some
tweaks and the non box-cutter ones
fairly obvious from that we clarify and
prove yang status handling so in
particular we clarified the deprecated
means you still have to implement the
node or otherwise and use deviations to
indicate you're not implementing it and
obsolete means you don't implement the
node and then finally we've added some
updates and guidelines for how you
update yang word rules based on these
updated rules next slide please
so the second draft
and this one's not been written yet and
this is the semantic version number
scheme so I'm just saying what the plan
is do it and we tend to to do this over
the next window next four months is to
define a semantic versioning scheme that
allows a bug fixes to release software
released software assets so effectively
it's what's already documented the
algorithm in the draft DT net mod yang
symbol 0 0 and it's a version of semver
2 0 0 but with the ability to add these
bug fixes in to the released assets when
necessary the main changes to is that
doesn't actually now need to define what
constitutes a backwards compatible or
non box-cutter will change that would be
assumed to be defined outside this and
this is this is what will be used we
expect this is some people as a revision
label so effectively the revision labels
you have will use this semantic
versioning scheme so you end up with
having semantic version for your young
modules and then again it's worth
pointing out that in terms of this this
versioning scheme is not going to be
tied to yang so although it will be
defined or have some references to the
and models it could be used anywhere
where you want to do this sort of
semantic versioning of assets but you
want to have a bit more flexibility to
be putting be to put bug fixes in two
older released code or released api's
looks like so yang package
again an overview I'm I've got with more
detail on this later on so what is a
yang package is identifying a set of
yang modules and their dependency so
it's a bit like taking Watson Yang
library and putting it into a file or
this one example but it's a bit more
flexible than that so whereas Yang
library will tell you what the schema is
for a particular data store an entire
device this allows you to do subsets of
yang modules so bits of bits of stuff
together and group them and the key
thing here is that those packages can
then be versioned in the same way that
modules are being versions so rather
than having each vendor implementing
choosing exactly which module version
module they want so every single
language will they're implementing I
think the use of packages could
encourage people to have more
commonality in what they implement so if
you took the ITF young model for example
you could have a package that defines
the base models and types and things you
could have separate package for routine
you could have a separate package for
VPN services for example and those would
be versioned over time and so rather
than somebody saying well I want this
version this or this version of that you
could choose something off that the
history of those version packages yes
yes yep it copes with that has
dependencies between packages and you
may have dependencies between packages
that conflict and
so the the solution here requires that
you resolve those conflicts at the time
you combine those two packages together
into a into a combined package you have
any conflicting module dependencies you
have to resolve them explicitly say how
they're resolved so yes in terms of
packages that could be available offline
using the yang instance data document
they also the plan is to augment yang
library so that rather than necessarily
downloading the full module list off a
device if you knew and expected what
package version it's going to implement
you can just check that it's
implementing what you expect so make it
an easier check for comments conformance
wise and as I said there's a separate
present presentation on this following
later so that's what I cover now next
slide so the fourth one is protocol
operations for package version selection
so one of the key aims of yang packages
is to allow devices to potentially
implement different versions of modules
as cohesive sets and then to allow
clients to select which ones to use so
this could be done where they're
choosing between some different sets of
vendor modules or it might be they want
to choose to use the ITF yang models or
a particular version of the open config
yeah models as examples and so the
packages are identifying those sets of
modules and then using our pcs to select
which ones to use and this could be the
case that the server only allows you to
support implementing one particular
packaged version for the entire
management interface or it may be that
some devices allow you to have support
multiple different packaged versions and
to select those depending on maybe the
session that's being used so again
there's another presentation covering
this but as I say here is failure the
early draft there will be more changes
in here but really it's just the ideas
are being presented
and next slide please
and then the last one so there's no
draft written yet they slightly lower
priority I do think it's a key part of
this set and that's to define an
algorithm to compare to schema trees the
detects backwards-compatible versus non
backwards-compatible changes so it looks
through those two schemas and says that
these are where the changes are so P
yang already does some of this the
result could then be given at the schema
level or it could be given on a data
node level and it could be also taken to
account features or deviations or the
subset of the schema actually being used
by by the operator so if they are only
using no 1/3 of a particular protocol
module they're not using these options
then when you're comparing to see what's
changed between two versions of that
module you may not care if stuff has
changed in the stuff you're not using so
again be able to compare the schemas and
subset it in to the stuff you care about
I think gives you almost like the
perfect answer there is some some cases
where this is difficult to do you can't
well known it's very hard to have
tolling that would check the description
statements and find out whether there's
some change in the semantics behavior of
a data node until our machine learning
gets a bit better XPath expressions and
regular expressions in other cases where
it's very hard to see what has changed
it's very hard to tell if it's a
backwards compatible change that's been
made in those cases so I think there's
consideration there as to whether we use
some form of annotation potentially to
mark those cases where it might look
like it's about as compared to a change
but it's not or vice versa it looks like
a non box collateral change but actually
it's backwards compatible any questions
on this one okay
come on automatic sliders is so so this
is just a chart I'm not sure how
accurate this is it it's effective
trying to show you the dependencies
between the the modules between the the
drafts with the darker blue arrows
showing sort of proper dependencies and
then the lighter colored arrows sort of
showing user level dependency so where
you may choose to use semantic
versioning scheme for example but
there's not actually a dependency
between the drafts and you can see that
this module the module revision handling
sit to the top and pari has a key
dependencies then everything that might
want to use semantic versioning scheme
'obviously has dependency on that but
other schemes could be used it's just
one choice the packages draft depends on
the module versioning and the package
version selection of C depends on that
one and then the schema comparison
touring depends on packages if that's
what you're comparing or modules if
that's what you're comparing now next
slide and that's it for me so any
questions on that overview section at
all in terms of the sort of overall
picture of how the solution fits
together you have any examples examples
of the first the first one versioning
the Motorama version right and we're
using revisions so if you have an
example the new revision format looks
like yes in the in the next so the
module revision handling draft will be
covered in detail next so that covers
all that and a lot more detail of those
examples in there I will talk about the
packages version schema draft after that
Rashaad will talk about the package
version selection the two that we're not
covering any more detail today is the
semantic versioning scheme that's based
on what was there before we have
written in yet and the schema comparison
told him that we haven't really looked
at in great detail with you the design
team really want the working room today
I think what I would like to know is
where the people in this room think that
as a sort of solution space of solving
the entire problem is does this look
like the right set of things that we are
solving and does it look like it covers
all the pieces you would expect it to
cover does it look like it's morally the
right approach
so obviously they've become some
individual drafts and things but does
this look like overall the right thing
then work is needed exactly all of this
with you show there I am I'm not hundred
percent sure that maybe the scope is too
much over there trying to put it but
what they see as a problem when doing
yank are the dependencies and figuring
out what are my dependencies what they
have flawed in order to enable the
service and we are planning to be able
to create abstractions at different
layers that going to change where
they're happening and be able to take
into the content and maybe even
prepackaged those things up and saying
oh here's my whole package and and it's
it's getting deployed you can unit
tested etc it is very helpful exactly
how to do that that's a question not
because there many of the issues that
you're just beginning to the stuff in
the other comments so I think I'm
bashing them up they start at the end
but I think the plan will be to try and
continue down this track effectively and
try and get these bits the doctors as we
go along
earlier we're looking for the design
team to come up with a full and set of
it
documents that answers all the
requirements and then bring them to the
working group for further option call so
it's important to make sure that the
working group is aware of what's going
on in the design team and is generally
aligned with the answers once once they
become working group documents we're
going to follow a normal working group
process which is everyone in the working
group has it will have an opportunity to
provide equipment influence so it's not
that at adoption we're done it's that we
have a focus team that's trying to give
us a starting point don't you blurt
about the pre-comp so when you're the
semantic version sounds great I was
always wondering why it didn't start out
that way so it that's not great
when you're talking about visualizing
the difference between schemas would it
be the resolve schema
once you've resolved all the groups
because usually that's what consumers
baby eyes are mentally visualize or is
it visualizing I think I think both is
answer so I think you're comparing a
module itself then you might do it on
the module text but even even then
actually I think you have to resolve the
sub modules and allow groupings and
things to move around so I think it's
sort of the the resolved schema to some
level but I might not be fully resolving
all dependencies it might be this module
with dependency still hanging in open or
it might be the entire scheme like a
yang package you take the whole package
resolve everything internally and it's a
complete package you then then look at
the actual abstract syntax tree for the
yang effectively constructed and could
be comparing those on a node by node
basis okay I think it's time for blush
so this draft is there let's say the
main out main output at this point we
derived it from the complete solution we
try to separate parts of it and we
believe that we had discussions on the
last IDF on the on the meeting but also
outside afterwards with many people we
believe that all the all the main
comments were included one point is that
this applies to yang modules so sub
modules they are very closely connected
to module 2 the modules themselves so
they should just follow the modules
themselves next please
this updates a number of current RFC's
one is the yang one that one because the
update rules are sometimes not not
specific enough but sometimes they are
too strict those updates yang library
because the versioning provides
additional information that we want to
include there and also the authoring
guidelines for example hydrogen
information should always be present and
and life cycles of the different schema
notes should be also included so what do
we have here we have an extension that
will go into the revision statement and
include indicates that this revision of
the yang module is not known backwards
compatible and BC to a previous version
if if it's not there then it's assumed
or it must be backwards compatible we
also explicitly state that we allow
nonlinear yang module development so
branching and updating previous
previous revisions which was not
forbidden in 7950 but many people assume
that they are there we will have linear
development only we introduced to
revision labels because many people many
companies have nice versioning scheme
Sykes same wear or some other ones and
they would like that information that
gives a short compatibility information
short history information in some form
to be included provision or derived was
also mentioned earlier so that states
that you can import something that is
newer than whatever mode module date you
chose but it can't be just a date
because of the nonlinear development
anymore we had to update what backward
compatible and the unknown backward
compatible changes mean because we want
to accept some NBC changes and
especially the status related changes
were not clear in 79 15 we have some
additions for status handling and yang
library are updates as we mentioned next
slide please
so maybe the most important part is here
the red thing we have and BC changes
that indicates inside the revision
information that this revision made are
incompatible and on backwards-compatible
change to compare to the previous
revision and it's always in this full
list of revision statements the previous
revision that means that you should not
remove revision statements maybe you can
remove the description part or shorten
the description parts but you should not
remove their revision statement itself
because at that point you lose this
information also you should add a
revision statement all the time I think
it's not mandatory in 790 50 every time
if when at the Green Point where we just
added functionality we don't have this
revision extension this will allow
normal in their development so here the
February first revolution date was also
developed because whatever customer
didn't want to upgrade to the new
version and then we have two branches
and there's actually no limit of
branching so you can branch the branch
and then again and again do an infinite
tree although that's not a very good
practice but if business needs force you
you can do that because if you look at
it every yank file in itself is linear
but the yang module might have multiple
files that go on different branches in
on this tree we don't this boss this is
a possibility that can be misused we
don't recommend arbitrary branching
especially not for as the earth and each
yang module the text by itself will
represent one route from the leaf of
this tree up to maybe the root or at
least to some level next please
so we have revision labels because the
NBC only tells you that yes we have and
change but to actually understand that
you have to parse the module already and
look up all the revision statements
which is quite a bit of work so as an
alternative you can have revision label
that contains similar information this
draft does not say what is in the
revision label these are examples and we
can will have multiple drafts or at
least one drafts about at the same where
can be in the revision label the format
is rather free only concern is that it
should not be not be mistaken or as a
date
and it can be used later for other in
the import statements as well yeah next
one please okay here is an example of
what the revision labels for assembler
would be if you see that the main number
changes every time when we have this
read NBC changes extension there so from
when we just add something then we only
go from 3 to 0 to 3 1 next please
okay import by revision or derived
that's a very important part of this
work so we said the simple import
without any revision date is too liberal
if you have the revision date there is
too strict what the usual case is that I
want something that includes the
functionality I'm depending on already
and anything later on I very much hope
that it will not remove what the
functionality I depend on it's not a
strict promise that everything
afterwards is good for me but usually it
is enough very revision or derived can
be based both on the revision label and
it can also be based on revision date or
derived would it stop at a module
revision and has NBC changes no no
should it no because most of the time
the NBC changes don't impact the import
there is a risk there and that we had in
earlier versions very complex sets where
we said that from this version to that
version and it gets more and more
complex and usually you want to leave it
open-ended because you don't know what
changes the new revisions will bring and
many many times that even if the changes
are NBC they won't impact your import
won't impact your importers so this is
not as if you really want to be strict
and really be sure then you must check
every every date but we don't want to be
there actually in the previous versions
of the same draft we had more strict and
more complicated solutions and this was
the most user-friendly and feel helpful
the revision will derive dependency it's
almost like a source time dependency
when you actually come to use these
modules you knew something like downline
really on package that will constrain
exactly which version you're going to
use anyway and in the case that
something comes along and breaks your
source dependency they made some
nautical change at that point you've
expected probably to releasing a new
version you revision off your jewel to
do the import then fixes to a later
provisional derived or changes up to
them to fix the important pence again so
we think that this is the right balance
being not too strict because otherwise
if you limit it it's more likely than
actually but I said you're not gonna be
impacted you start update your module
anyway so we think it's better to be
better to ask forgiveness them to be too
strict performed okay I think my only
analogy here would be like suffered you
know when you're building and you have
dependencies on libraries and you'll say
I depend on library you know three dot
one dot two so if three dot X I'll
support but if it ever goes to for TEDx
I don't want to support that so
sometimes there's the ability to put
brackets or limits into how much future
you want to support automatically but I
accept you know it's been discussed by
the design team just want to make sure
that was something that you guys have to
cover and also previous might as well I
think it was yes so this the the two
future statements that you're creating
here is this what I understand to be
possible extensions to yang quarreling
gang language yes okay
max next okay so in order to define what
is when we put in those statements we
have to define what is backward
compatible and NBC 7950 gives us a very
good basis for that but not the full
statement because deprecating and
obsoleting nodes can actually be NBC or
BC depending on how it's implemented
what we assume is that if you deprecated
the node it's still there so that's a
backwards compatible change but if you
obsolete a node then it will be removed
so that we define as a non backward
compatible change also reordering data
definition statements in most of the
cases that should not hurt anyone so
that we allow that and anything else is
known backward compatible but stating
that opps obsoleting is NBC that's a
definite change from 7950 next okay we
have the so that we have the status
statement in yang we want to change what
deprecated and adopts elite means we
still is this is not a mandatory
statement so it's not a must or a shell
but we say that deprecated should be
still there working fully functional
while obsolete should be removed if if
you don't remove obsolete that can or
that can also result in surprising and
errors so even for obsolete I think we
is important to define this but for
backwards compatibility we put into the
Yang library to the extra leaves that
states that do you follow what we
recommend here or not if you don't put
these extra Leafs then you are backward
compatible meaning you can do anything
you like and your clients will be
surprised maybe
also when you deprecated or obsolete
something often you have a reason for
that often you have a time line when you
will actually remove it maybe you have a
replacement so a status description
statement was added for that so I like
the idea of having an ability to specify
whether or not the server actually
complies or not that being the case why
aren't these musts i mean and backwards
compatibility i three months the server
has data more data than it should but
for the first bullet point where it says
it should be implemented its must I mean
how else can we have interoperability if
it's not sure the clients aren't sure
that it's actually there because you can
check in the yang library that is it ro
the deprecated nodes we implemented and
functional if you sorry okay so the
third by you saying gang library you're
talking about the third bullet point yes
that indicates if you follow the first
two or not but are you saying that with
third bullet point that is possible for
the server to say that the first bullet
point is actually those two will
contract you must not judge yes if you
yes if we next then I agree that we
would try and get these to be fine
since you're doing extensions you can
change the rules for implementations
that implement that extension so you can
say if you implement this extension you
must do these things okay and it's
probably worth reducing the number of
options so in the case where you have an
extension think about making things more
bus than shirts Martin be account held
previous meetings a very strong opinion
that we need to indicate in the yang
library whether whether these first two
rules are followed or not we should not
make them must probably could get about
masks now that's what we want isn't it
yes I agree with two you know but we had
some pushback that's why we have this in
young library to indicate whether these
are followed or not
please so what we have in the yang
library is two nodes deprecated nodes
implemented obsolete node up steps and
these are the first two bullet points we
have discussed lately and if they are
not there and then there anything can
happen with these that's one of the
problems that in yang one that one that
they the definition is too open
the other problem was that currently
yang library doesn't specify which
version which revision of a yang module
is imported if multiple revisions are
present and that might mean in some
cases that mandatory data nodes are
present when we thought it's not or
mandated three nodes are absent when we
thought they would be there so it's kind
of a bug let's say or a missing point
piece in 7950 so it's not the rules data
model of some of angle eyebrow is not
modified but the rules what they mean
are modified to make it very specific
which more module is imported in this
case excellent
or in a question whether the second
point here exists really bug fixes is is
something that a raft failed to cover or
not my precious is a change of behavior
offensive it couldn't be covered in an
errata but he was opening that if we
could get in after that would be better
he's clarifying I hate Lee that's
ambiguous today we're still trying to
digest what exactly what seconds no it's
both 1 & 2 of the second so I need to
see the errata before making a call as
to the level of change that's being done
yeah okay to judge whether it's right or
something is suitable for errata or
abyss or update okay yeah I think the
specific proposed text we have to look
at not the problem but the solution
ultimately if you believe it's a
clarification you should probably just
submit it and then we can debate it
except that it will be in a row then it
will be at a unverified errata and we
can add it to the list or discuss it so
you're right on track but you're on
track for like another 10 minutes okay
yes data it was required
requirements to do say what it what
happens with versioning instance data
itself is not version because what
backwards compatibility means there
that's not defined on the other hand it
back versioning is very useful for
instance data understanding if the
schema defining modules can be somewhat
different next please
and then we have some guidelines telling
others how to do changes that not to do
NBC changes and try to make the changes
for the clients that's painful use
deprecation use this more flexible
import use status information and such
things and sometimes duplicate data to
be able to use both new and old versions
or potentially sell right version
selection next please
if clients is kind of a requirement of
recommendation for clients that yes
changes are coming and they should
tolerate a number of changes and also
they should monitor what kuat happens
with modules so they should check if the
module is backwards compatible and my
first answer is I don't know don't care
this only says that we have a revision
label where you can put in some numbers
now there will be a separate draft about
Sandler based the revision labels
yes ember has difficulty with unlimited
branching there whatever you put into
the revision label will have its
limitations or maybe you have a
versioning number
version numbering scheme that's all
powerful them no limitations but that's
not part of this draft again
we here in this draft we just defined
that there is a place where you can put
that in the further drafts will propose
the same where based a visioning system
and there they will have meaning but not
in this draft we here just we have a
placeholder so Robin just have one
comment to that so you so somebody might
a vendor might choose to choose their
module labels as foo and bar and what
said like choose whatever they want
so he's whoever's doing that scheme is
define the semantics of the scheme so
very quickly to cover the next steps
there's just one slide here actually we
sort of discussed it earlier so at the
beginning we were going to seek adoption
for this first draft I think the
feedback from the chairs was that
actually they want to adopt this as a
set so I think of fatally we're going to
continue on the same track any comments
we received on the module version draft
will update but the other ones will
effectively work on the other ones the
static version scheme yank packages in
version selection drafts and also the
tooling one but I'm not sure we'll get
those all done before the next IDF
there's still a lot of work there and
then on seryung packages please that's
it
so I already covered a little bit of
this this is just a little bit more
details and so next slide please on this
and yank packages and so
yes effectively the idea here as
beforethe said 'is to diversion sets of
young modules together with their
dependencies and in terms of how the
yank packages draft is written at the
moment it's using the yang cember
solution as a way of identifying or the
the version number scheme for these
modules that's the one thing I think we
need to update or at least discuss
relative to how we've changed the
modular versioning and made the semantic
versioning number a label and option
thing rather than things tied in the
packages could be hierarchical so a
package can import other packages and
that gonna curse down the packages
themselves can be I their complete or
incomplete so you don't necessarily have
to tie off all your dependencies
depending on what you're doing and that
might help if you were you had
dependencies and like type modules and
things that like you may not want to
depend those the package themselves can
be available from yang library or they
can be available on a lot of line and
yeah instance data and in the yang in
stated discussion there was talk about
how you identify the schema using yang
library I think yang packages might be
another example which were a good way of
defining that schema a better way
because it's it's more what you're
actually trying to do rather than yang
robe it's returning slightly different
information and as I mentioned the draft
is slightly out of date because it
hasn't been updated with the changes
that we've done to the module level
versioning you say it works but I think
it does say yes it's just okay so why do
young packages of what we're trying to
solve several problems here we want to
actually get consistent version sets of
modules just versioning modules
individually when you have hundreds of
them or tens and different organizations
becomes too hard it's too complex and
it's too likely that different vendors
will implement different versions of the
same modules and get too many
incompatibility so for one vendor that
might implement B GB version 2 and Ice
PFE one and on different OS or different
vendor while does BGP v1 and OSPF v2
yang models and then when it comes to an
operator and that
to use these well neither those sets are
ideal because they can't get a
consistent set across both of them if
you've got young packages and your and
your versioning for like the ITF routing
protocols and every time the module gets
a new routing module gets updated you
add that into the yank package then and
a new version that yang packed you've
now got a more linear update in terms of
how these packages are evolving but
you're not fixed to that you can still
deviate those the packages that you
still use your override and say actually
I'm going to support this baseline
package with these changed in these
differences to it another one another
use case for them is to avoid
downloading this this full set of
modules off the device and having to
check your exactly what you want because
that's a hard thing to do it'd be much
nicer to say actually I support this
package or these packages these API is
the things I support with these
modifications and rather have to do an
individual check on every single module
either I've got a higher level
conversation about the API that you're
supporting and as to say and again you
can do this with yang library making the
schemer available offline so you can
check it in advance and you can design
your tooling to expect to talk to a
device and expect which which API which
package version it's using and correlate
those is easier than how to deal with
full sets of of packages when the full
sets of modules when they differ
next please so this is just an example
I've I've got a simple ITF network
device version 1.1.2
there's some metadata description and
other information where you can wake and
a URL of where to download that package
from and that lists a set of modules
that implements here and it lists a set
of modules our import only and again
this could be fully resolved it might
not be resolved and the definition
includes metadata like URLs where to
find it it lists features that mandatory
so which features that if you implement
this package you are obliged to
implement and support it has a list of
the imported packages not there's none
shown here
but list the pictures you importing list
the modules that are implemented by that
package and the import only module it's
a very similar to yang library from that
point of view except it recursos and has
a list of imported packages and then
finally and again it's not shown here is
import conflict conflict resolution so
if you combine two packages and they
each those packages import different
versions of modules and you have
conflicts so when you do that when your
package pulls in two separate packages
with conflicts you surface and you
specify exactly which version of which
module you resolve to next slide please
one more slide so this is another
example package example ITF basic
routing package and this one is
importing from Network instant network
device is one that 1.2 and then so it
lists the extra modules that are
implemented as part of that extra
imports on top of that and as I said
before any version conflicts or change
must be explicitly resolved that's
that's one thing that's critical here
the forgiven package definition the list
of modules that it's using is is exactly
tightly defined that's the specific
versions and the package version
indicates the nature of changes in the
modules or package imports so the
version number that we're using here is
again using like a somatic versioning
scheme so if you update your package to
include a module that's changing a
number non box compatible way which in
semver would mean going from no 2.00 to
3.0 to 0 then your package would also
have a major version change in its
version number as well if you had minor
version changes in your packages or you
own or you're importing more modules in
your package definition then you have a
minor version change so it's using the
same send their ideas and rules and
things for doing versioning applied a
package level rather than a module level
yeah two slides back you said that if
you say that you support the package
you're obliged to implement all the
package versions as they are I just
wanna clarify
is that include features and or and or
deviations so you you what you'd be
allowed to do is you've allowed to run
the saying you you implement this
package you would implement your own
package on top of that or they're in
they includes this one and then has it
extra modules with deviations listed in
terms of features you would list the
features you support but you're obliged
to support the features that are listed
here the mandatory features or otherwise
deviate those nodes so you can steal
these deviations and changes but you
have to expect them explicit and then
the key issues the key question in terms
of updating this draft so the current
package draft of actually draft uses
yang Simba's the versioning scheme
because that was based on the work that
we did for ITF 104 where it looked like
that was the version seen we were going
to use but the latest module level
version now has been decoupled so in
terms of the module revision handling
and it's and its concept of backwards
compatible versus non backward but non
box collateral changes and you separated
from the really the versioning scheme
that you're using so yang semver is one
of the examples of the version scheme
you could use so I think probably it's
better for yang packages also to have
that same be coupling so for it not to
have be hard-coded to a particular
semantic versioning scheme but just to
say actually it can use any scheme
that's partially ordered sets of
identifiers to have that more
flexibility in to what's in terms of
what it's done or in terms of what it
uses and allow yang cember as one
example of what could be used in that
case then the question is is to be is
how flex lie you in that how do you do
that do you have an identifier or an
enumeration to identify the different
schemes I'm not sure we want to have a
huge proliferation of them because every
single different scheme will have impact
on clients that need to be able to
compare these things so but same time
toyotas yang Semba might be a mistake
does anyone have any thoughts or pins on
us
Charles that call for table more like
the version of the package as it said it
would be ordered
so is it implied as the version of the
package increases the version of I think
entirely decoupled so I think you'd be
allowed to there's no correspondence
between the package version number and
the version numbers inside other than
other than the semantic change the
package so if you've made a change to
the what's included in that package this
numbers compatible because you've
changed your numbers compared to a
module or you've down read the module
that would be like a non box
non backwards would change to that
package definition so it would go from 1
0 0 to 2 0 0 if you were doing a down
Rev I think does that answer your
question yes any other
on this issue at all opinions are you
coming up because we're speaking next
complete resolution you mentioned I
think in one slide between two different
packages in a different slide you type
one package how do you explicitly yes
so you see effectively say on the config
resolution say I want to have this
particular version and I think I try to
remember having read the draft recently
I think in terms of import only again
you might need to identify which
specific import you are overriding and
the and the overriding version but it be
only other day you're explicitly saying
this is the version I'm gonna use in the
circumstance I think you are now up so
can you elaborate either on your view of
the design team view of why you want to
allow multiple ways so in terms of the
modular version the reason for doing
that is because that's what some people
wanted they thought that they don't like
the yang symbol scheme because they find
it too restrictive some people other
people think it's not well why don't we
just use the standard Semba and I think
it's not flexible enough so there's
difference opinions as to what version
of scheme is required and if you are a
vendor and you end up having arbitrary
branching of your modules for whatever
reason then the semver scheme we
defining can't accommodate that
deliberately so it's limited
deliberately some partial branch but not
too much so I think that's the reason we
had that separation in the module level
stuff and then in terms of packages the
question is whether if you've got
modules that have that flexibility and
you package them together you probably
need a versioning scheme for the package
has the same number flexibility we
progress from the design team to the
working group because to the eventual
something we submit to the is G we'll
really want to think hard about whether
we want that flexibility because anytime
you have flexibility but that really
leads is to interoperability problems
and of course the reason we have
standards is you know for
interoperability so if there's good
reason to allow that different off those
different options sure but if there's
not you know we should think really hard
about the cost of that flexibility
greatly if you want a question about the
different water networks continue
question on that conflict so I need
werden conflict must be how can we
resolve that so if for example this was
importing two modules to the two
different packages and one of them he
was using IETF types version 1 0 0 and
up was using ITF types 1 0 1 then this
package as well as doing the import
would say I'm going to use ITF 1 0 1 as
my version for this package then but
each pack each tire package each time
you're combining modules with two
different packages two or more packages
you're explicitly resolving that you're
specifying exactly which module you're
using anything interface Bank on do
another module they are not a package
need to user interface 2.0 they are not
compatible and I hope to use two
packages together how do I do that
without I think is something you can't
do
I mean in the day if you're trying to
combine different
$6 another set foxy application your
doctor C library Lipstein southern euros
we all pay we have both live in there so
you define two packages in that case
interface modules - that one though they
were a madman but if you've got that
sort of splitting your yang ecosystem
where you got the modules that that
different and there and there's no way
you can combine them you got some
dependencies on the older than you
well you're combining them into one
package so if you got dependency says
half of my package depending on ITF
interfaces one and half as depending on
ITF interfaces - and there's significant
changes between the two then you've
either got to split that and just do
them for one and a separate set of
packages for the ones that depending on
version - you can't you can't magically
put those things together this won't fix
and the same system together then yang
does not allow that yang says you can
only implement a single version of a
module you can import multiple versions
but in terms of implementation you can
only forgiving scheme oh you can only
implement one version of a yang module
actually it's possible if you have two
different Netcom for restaurant servers
each server can has to have a specific
implementation show up in the device but
in that case you're in two separate
packages working packages sometimes may
not be practical too much education
about that but it but the same issue
exists with using yang libraries is no
different in that scenario so you're
trying to you can't do it yang packages
you means you can't do it young library
either there's no fun little difference
there it's just how they're being pieced
together
can you use the mic please only one
person can represent can be yes so I'll
be presenting the version selection
graph on behalf of Robin myself so this
slide talks about why are we doing this
well this comes from the requirements
3.1 and 3.2 from the requirements draft
you spoke about and the what this is
basically saying is because yang modules
are change in non backwards compatible
ways we need to help clients migrate so
servers can support multiple versions
and help clients select which version
they actually want to run with next
please
so the summary so it allows servers to
do non backwards compatible changes
without forcing clients to make
immediately migrate it does make use of
the yang packages draft Rob was
presenting earlier and it provides
mechanism for servers to advertise what
versions of the package is the support
and it allows clients to choose among
the ones advertised which one they want
to run with on the pitch Lee recession
next please so before people start
throwing bricks servers are not required
to concurrently support clients using
different schema versions those things
are optional servers are not required to
support every published version and they
are not required to support all parts of
all version schema the important thing
is when we say support non backwards
comes come
all changes if you remove functionality
in the later yahng yahng yahng version
obviously you cannot support the newer
one and the older one but in some cases
if you've we organized your yang module
you've moved your nodes around in a non
backwards compatible way the server
should be able to support all the older
version and the newer version
next please okay so the overview which
you'll see in the yang tree NEX is you
know a version schema
it's a yang schema which Rob was talking
about with an Associated yang revision
that could be the semantic version
number in the draft which will be done
soon and yes as I said this could be
yang package the schema set is a set of
related yang schema one per datastore
the server support configuration for the
default schema and they also support
configuration for what we call the
secondary and maybe more net confess
count instances to use different schema
this is done by a port number for both
net count and restaurant and for
restaurant we also support the the
different route path which we source to
see like which schema to use this is it
for this slide next please
and this is basically the schema tree
for what I was just describing you can
see you know you can you can configure
your the schema sets and all that or
read/write but in terms of the
information per datastore that's all
what the system the server decides to
support I don't believe we got any
comments on the we probably need to do
in Ex Rev
based on the latest discussions from 104
work and all that and hopefully we'll
get this cut will get comments on this
draft and the yang packages draft and as
Rob was explaining earlier in the next
steps for the design team we actually
want the this draft which is currently
private draft to be part of the design
team orc questions
don't feel obligated to rename it if you
want to rename it that's fine the
government okay not to okay and as a
contributor seeing the protocol names
there
alerts me just a little bit macabre
scoffs you know what about other like
co-op do we have to call out those
protocols by name here well if we just
support port we don't have to I believe
my recollection is they're separated
because Raskin has the route path okay
support but I mean the route path
support has not been discussed maybe
we'll take take that out so since
they're optional you can still have both
of them and then wholly set that when
they promote a football yep
easy too soon okay that's can do you
have a suggestion here of how many think
we should attack to know the keystore
draft some things you've got more
separation so is that what you're
suggesting might be a good approach to
use it I was leading up to it I was
looking at the port and I was wondering
what the intention for that port was and
why wouldn't we be using the the
appropriate client server drafts from my
comp oh yeah what's referencing notes
directly okay
I need that works yeah well I mean so
this isn't even adopted work yet but
nice and the that working neck off will
be done before this and so hopefully
it'll be it'll just make sense where I'm
set then I actually related to that I
think eventually this draft who then
would probably end up in good michael
wings up with a yang model for
[Music]
is a microphone hello today I want to
introduce a data file unit module for in
the measurement okay sis chapter 2
funding model fold is a base the network
policy management and it can provide
some billete to fold an imagine function
to control that information a monitor
state changes on the network element and
if the sister if the trigger condition
be meted and you can perform some simple
and instant action and this document has
we discussed toys in the working group
and the since many people are interested
in two interesting related works
so we update sir document and in this
version made a new leaf
a group ID it can be used to group a set
of events that can be the group a set of
key witnesses can be excute together to
perform some specific tasks for example
to provides a service assurance and the
way also optimized must even leave it
moving from action lists to trigger
condition lists and allow the one even's
trigger to reference nazareth even stuff
nation and the way a change stratford
condition in choose a variation
condition to further clarification
difference between poland trigger and
the variation trigger and we also
simplifies action container in this size
will provide our example how to use this
module to perform some
and here with the fund even a and it's
being used to monitor if the trigger a
to be we be set up so it can trigger
even the B and the even P use a call
even if the even exist and there's a
polling condition net sending the
triggers corresponding action to active
standby a fair work okay and we use a
group ID to groups is to event to
perform the proverb provides a sort of
surance a test okay okay it says
document have discussed at least it
system is already discussed three times
and is same some many people are
interested in this works so I think
maybe we can think about document yes is
there somebody comment at the mic
processing units just is provide for
routing policy and here we use this doc
use this module to perform such high
service assurance if you here is example
if for example food loss package across
the street then it can perform the
relate action for example logins
you lost packet cross their food and
then perform some action to Octavian
birth of fare over taxes yeah yeah yeah
we want to define the more generic model
and they can perform provide ability to
do service assurance to our munchers
yeah I understand your question but here
our document
ma do not want to coverage routing
policies the walks and here is just to
provide okay if some condition met and
we can do some management walks like
starting okay policy documents one of
the co-authors I like I just like to
state that this is more a data plane
document whereas the routing is strictly
a control plane policies for a control
plane for you know the
the selection and complete and
redistribution and Newport export
complete protocols so there isn't other
than in the word policy yes so yes so I
understand this record I think I
understand this correctly there is no
correlation between either work neurotic
working group in the policy there using
the event condition action as well as
well as some constant question and in
this work here is that accurate
now this work here I would have mixed on
standings incorrect is this work just
data plank or is admit the general was
is it meant for control playing or other
usages a single the intention for these
the motive actually means that provider
of closed loop was of its managing that
close to a life cycles of its maximum
punishment and so they can Kalu imagine
model and probit model so is that using
this kind of policy in order so they can
trigger the automation so is a
management automation is it so is it
destined for applications of control
planning data plan or up
I think not sure we should right next to
the control plan but I think that may be
happy to the state of a name and
imaginary cheapening thank you um who's
read Benoit clays so goodnight let's
just explain to him some bio information
so we created the working group called
super in the past by use of policy
scratcher structured reaction shamrock
was there became an interest raft he has
submitted their of the main reference
which is then in that super working
group the goal must be something generic
so they had policy that the routing
policies we're going to be using that
and security policies to be reusing that
yep so now it's in the next right it's
based on the policy document which is
convert raft but reg do something
generic while the world has been moving
out so this is like discrepancy well
yeah and everyone still needs one of
these two for each of their applications
um so who's read this it's actually been
here twice I believe so far the zero
zero and the zero one have been
presented here so who has read it either
in its present Oh to form or in one of
the previous forms okay so some people
have read it of those people who have
read it actually let's just generalize
that let's say yeah who here is
interested in the topic and thinks we
should do work on it okay
no hands went down there so
that's a reason that's a reasonable
number like that is at least as much
attention as many of our drafts get who
thinks we should be doing this somewhere
else or not at all okay nobody so it
sounds like you're probably here for
better or worse yeah so we're at a
starting point I don't think we will
yeah yeah no no we want to pull for
working group adoption after this I
think you'll be interesting to see how
many think this is a starting point we
ask that the last meeting and there was
a pretty small number you know
interesting to see if that changed or
there are people who are not on the list
of authors presently who are interested
in this work with an eye towards
participating in any hands for that okay
well one partial hand from somebody I
greatly respect so I guess that's
probably of some value yeah I think
we'll probably pull for adoption on the
list after the meeting so what it sounds
like
okay thank you
next
hi anime based notification and jin-woo
is presenting yeah my colleague er is
not here I represent his topic my name
is him actually the topic is powder
empty base notification for antenna
based another configuration update
actually this job has been around for a
while actually moved from net cough
actually has already presented twice in
tent mode actually my colleague actually
revised this chapter base his experience
on the network network a conversation
very question so we sinker we most
negatives job to turn an empty ative
actually for actually but you know they
can work together with the problem is a
negative right now can compare the
difference between the datastore by the
limitation is the latter type ability to
verify whereas an elevation from Indian
or other sauce take effect so we we sink
so that the the solution we propose is
that affine notification actually to
reporter this cannon a verification
event to check these miscalculation
issues but the week not you know check
out all these miss conversion issue
because for for summer cases may rely on
you need to export data from different
device so so we gave some cases like you
wanna maintain the considered a
consistency in network configuration may
cover a two different device you want to
maintain the consistency as it is
something we cannot just use this event
and here we gave one use cases and we
think we can use a native to compare the
antenna with the operational data store
and we have two different cases so for
some object that may be present in
but another present in operational for
example you may have an interface but
another physical exist so it can exist
in antennae but not existing in
operational another cases they may
present in operational but not a present
in intent so typical case actually is
interface MTU and so here the maximum
weight way proposed actually we need to
you know make sure the server can detect
the hardware changing so this may rely
on the system interaction with the
hardware so based on this assumption
actually we can detect whether there are
some miss compression issues and
probably actually here okay we'll get
some phrase we can compare the
difference between in 10 and operational
and we can make sure all this actually
caused by some mystery sauce and here is
the motor structure we make some change
actually we introduce a application tag
actually to provide additional to
provide a new parameter to identify each
update and also we clarified that
difference with native and we think this
can work together with a nominative and
this is the position of the CMD
notification on education and we already
present this in an outside eye TM
meeting and we show how hot the position
of this message so this job has been
around for a while and we think actually
the seems concern synergize with any
media first so we want to hear what are
you thing about this again
yeah so I think the challenge with
discussing this since I don't see anyone
running to the mic at the moment is that
at 104 and 103 there were pretty
few people who had read this I guess
that is their queen our show of hands of
anybody who's read this in either its
present form or the I guess
o 1 and O 2 versions that are have been
present previously prevented presented
okay well there's a few does do any of
those people have the willingness to
express an opinion as to whether or not
this more work is worth progressing Rob
I'm gonna put you on the spot so I'm not
sure it turns off of how I imagine your
sisters working
I would imagine more that the devices
were just monitor operational and
monitor the system that way around so
rather than getting errors back from the
ply failures whether used monitor
operational and detect the changes
between what you as an operator wanted
the device to do and what it's actually
doing so that's one observation the
other one is I think that it's possibly
really hard for some systems to
implement this to be able to report back
when some of these operations have
failed because to be committed to the
running datastore the configurations
there the actual apply phase with system
might go through many different demons
and my how other intermediate failures
and things like that so I think
generally my experience is really hard
to track these errors back we've always
struggled with this sort of thing so I'm
not sure
that helps I'm not sure yeah one
clarification amusing actually medical
computation and verification is very
popular that's a lot of you know
research on this and you know this seems
actually morning--i to this systems data
that are put into the operational data
store actually we can leverage this
network variation Maxim to to do data is
possible so that's why I bring up this
kind of idea again it's a certain thing
for the verification side and check into
the verification the configuration is
valid what your state's all about
completely agree with and that makes
sense but in terms of the next set of
applying it which is sort of a sickness
or semi asynchronous and systems are
aware of that's the big thing that's
harder than trackback so I think that if
you have a simple device you may be able
to do that and may have value for that
but I think there's many devices that
this would be to trigger to do and
instead you would you expect the
operator to be monitoring the
operational safety device and the
applied configuration to whether this is
happened or not and another observation
here is that some things this
configuration takes a long time to be
applied so so what do you do in that
scenario
Jim Carrey Nokia so when I read the
draft there was a couple things that
were it was running through our mind
I've just couldn't I just couldn't form
an opinion on because what I've seen
here is is what we've done in the past
is grated up the examples that you use
this is well if I have something tonight
of the sign oh so did you did and now
I'm going to put it and there's a
difference between that and call me
differences between data source now it's
gonna put the easy assignment problem
right and in the past we said okay those
are just status I'm on the side or not I
put my own tl-one things right so that's
usually solved in a status type of thing
all right so so I was struggling in what
we wanted to produce notifications for
right typically to produce notifications
when there's some sort of mystery but I
on a Sunday to be this but someone plug
in that right and then I need to get any
of that from this particular draft those
things where I think it's also saw that
those particular notifications are
generalized notifications there's
notifications in the context of the
problem that you're trying to resolve on
I'm going to do a quick meet I'm going
to do that type of stuff and so I that's
what I was like going on I don't know if
this will do you realistically if this
will be you and you really use because I
think it's the problem the maintenance
of the use in the and the person or the
enemy that's interpreting that is not
the server the thing being actuated for
the thing that's doing acts like the
client and that's that's what I was
going through my head as I go through
this I go I don't know
there's other ways of doing it thank you
I think what we're hearing here like is
some people who have given this a little
thought but they're not they're not
necessarily interested in being
consumers of it and that would actually
I
think be the sort of thing that would
drive interest or its implementation and
refinement and would also get us better
feedback so I think um I I think
borrowing some kind of expression of
interest of that variety on the list
this is probably not something that we
need to revisit if if you know if we can
find that or muster the energy in the
community for people who are interested
in it then I think it's pretty easy to
come back here and go well we've
reviewed this enough that we can call
for adoption but I don't think we have I
don't think we have the level of energy
or enthusiasm with respect to being
consumers of this that would cause us to
to really ask that question at this
point okay um thank you for your
diligent efforts however yeah thank you
to refine this into something and to
seek feedback thank you it's in the
other room
that's not it's noisy so watch their
semen on to this one we focus on a
transition
I'm gay protocol translation you see it
yeah I see that
okay this is a tumor again and I want to
talk about an MD protocol transition
issue discussion there's a many
discussion here we already have lot of
discussion on these kind of issues
actually recap a little bit because
right now actually
Nana colress coming and he has ought to
be published and actually right now
mostly idea for young anymore should be
the NMDA compliant and also there's more
young a motor that developers should be
done be combined but we still see
actually there's some temporary and no
MDA actually exist to bridge the capper
of the time period and kill them they
can be available so we see there's
transition stages so our you know
confusion is how how so how long is this
transition period will will take
actually when this can get started when
and so so so we have some misconception
with sinker the current are empty young
town lying actually only provide a
guideline for the young trans transition
but the tenant provide the transition
kind line for the protocols actually so
especially another case actually so
protocol actually if we forego support
empty but you you still can use some
Nnamdi modules so so this is something
we think maybe there's some gap actually
maybe this is a misconception we already
discussed this
on the man is also offline discussion
with several people and so here we give
several option you know we have a client
actually they can be the MBK liner
convenient lambda cannot client for the
device who support a net AMD could be
the AMD server on and no long an MDA
server but in a between we single may be
the other cases you know for the server
they only implement MDA Maxim but it
doesn't implement the button tenant
support MDA combined young data model so
actually talked with some some people we
think the lacing the semi an empty is a
very confusion maybe we were Chester you
know we can remove these semi MDA so so
based on these are some she actually we
we sink you know the colonel problem is
when the non empty a client they talk to
the server who support the Amity and an
MBA actually using the traditional get
operation you cannot get as a
system-generated complication so we try
to address these issues
we propose a three different solutions
so the first one actually you know we
can add as a state a copy node in in the
inner MTA young big mantra I think this
is another good approach it because we
already moved to order an MD we add back
actually seems you know actually not a
reasonable actually but this is the one
solution we can using the get operation
challenging get operation to care as a
system generator
the second option is we can you know
define the state module state model well
using the same structure as an MDA
module and this is something already be
discussed in mm dae-jung timeline and
but the problem is this state of module
actually for some cases that you may
when we actually move toward an MD for
some MD model doesn't define of these
stay the module so that will cause you
know we when we implement this we need
to implement some non-standard state a
module so whether we should you know ask
all the NMB multi-with you provide us
data module so this is a something we
single could be the solution but the
with this data mode you stay the model
we can actually address the problem we
can care system generate the
confirmation from these data modules
the third option actually we can
actually you know enhance the get
operation to allow uses the traditional
ket operation you get a system generated
a pattern this actually the impactor is
you know only modular post so we think
that's possible to actually get but that
we simply is very you know the influence
we haven't evaluated we Singham
maybe it's very hard to see this so we
so we we propose these three different
solution so so the first question we
want to ask is actually church as you
know as we assumed actually we may have
for for the server name a support semi
an MDA so we you know so the question is
a supporter you know when when we
migrated to the MDA just athos away
supporter and MDA
protocol like an alcohol rescue empty
air support and then we can support a M
de young beta model are we when we
implement all the other choices that we
implement the young Vinney model and MDA
protocol
at the same time so so so we for the
option
we we proposed actually we may have
three option me we may actually be
single we can skip these transition
stage if we can go directly to the nmda
solution actually this already be done
by ITF is a completed standard solution
but the we the problem we are facing is
we sink we assume many at nanoka line
that doesn't support an mp4 right now at
this stage here how to migrate it and so
we propose the another to option one is
option one actually option will actually
you may take a one of solution we prefer
actually the the solution to actually
you may define a state a module but this
is not a standard state a module in some
cases so another one which has to you
know Chester you know agrees there's a
transition stage it but there we may be
we may have different no standard
solution we we can pick oh what do we
and take so that's a option we single we
can address these kind of issues any
comments on this so I mean I I think
pragmatically probably something to so I
think one Colin here is the potential
for a given server or vendor they could
have a bespoke in a conflict switch to
choose whether it's going in and nmda
mode I think for a lot of deployments
that's probably sufficient and fine and
that the operators would would either
upgrade all their clients and won't go
or not so to do this in terms of the
option to we do there is a specification
in the young off guidelines of how to
generate that state module that's quite
prescriptive and fairly easy steps so
one option here could be to say the ITF
young modules that we run through that
process and we dump those date trees and
the names well-defined into github for
example and then they're just there so
I think that that may be a pragmatic way
for it and then the other session I had
was I think on vesties in terms of the
new young library and get operations
used to have a case of where existing
gets returns there are the extra spec
trees exact estate modules but the new
ones also work as before so I think
there are ways through this whether we
needed another standard or document to
define the I don't know yeah the puzzle
we're facing is the way which taker the
operation to actually we need to you
know have a completed standard solution
you for every an MD model you should
define and stay the module so for some
Oh an empty a model they may didn't
define the state model such as a motive
attack or some maybe some other cases or
so that will delay implementation so how
do you how do you address these so I
think it's just you need to publish a
scientific you publishing I took routine
- state I think that's okay with the
same version number and you follow that
also how to generate it and then you've
got that state route so even if they are
not included with the appendix that
module how to construct that equivalent
state module is defined so it logically
this doesn't just because this is a file
somewhere I think two different vendors
could apparently generate that same
module
yeah Tim do you want to go okay so Kent
as a contributor so you say agree that
there's an NDA a transition period I
mean that is in fact what we have right
now we are in a in MD a transition
period so I don't think there's anything
to agree on the you also early on your
other slide I think is solution number
two you mention the possibility that the
bad state module is missing but I think
that's a hypothetical like do you
actually have an example of dismissing
ya Modi tag actually is a typical
example
that one that particular draft was
discussed on this just recently it's
okay for that draft not have a - state
equivalent because it contains no config
false notes and also the has no
meaningful operational impact have
tracked the operational value of the
conviction notes so it's actually
allowed to not have a state variant for
that draft yeah but I see the nd respond
actually he sees is wrong but I don't
know but it may be this is another cool
example actually we have some other you
dumb prods Chester you know operated for
some of mmm be compliant model doesn't
define state emotive so so these state a
mode we should be follows a young and a
young kind line and but this is not a
standard state Amodeo so it's just that
defined in the appendix issue we are
free to may be different people given a
developer implement in different ways
that will cause the you know you know a
lot of interoperability issues models
that are progressing right now through
the ITF that don't have - state that are
an FDA compliant yeah I haven't check of
these so if that exists we should go
back to the working group that's
progressing that tell them they they
should add - okay unless there's a
reason not to and if the ist is
processing if the is GE is processing
such in in other areas they the ISP
should should say you need to get formed
with the PCP and it is true that like in
tags one of the ways you conform is
we've looked at it and don't think it's
opiate for this particular module so
that's a that's an okay - way to conform
with the BCP okay but if it's going on
and really this is a comment i Torrini
to bring back to the is-3 is please make
sure that the PCE is being followed
yeah that's a cool situation definitely
knew these he says that the I think it's
the introduction or the abstract to say
that module conforms to NMDA or not it
just says to imitate well it should also
have in it the thing like we have
especially looked at and have concluded
that it's not necessary to conform to
NMDA so it's explicit supposedly said
yeah there's some saying maybe there's
something guideline should be modified
to just yeah yeah yeah okay but
regardless I think what Rob said earlier
is that if there isn't missing that
state on a published draft we can always
retroactively to go back and publish the
- state for okay okay okay let me
utilize others SPO those were our two
great models on my own right so they
said oh okay yeah we need your stuff
it's all problem who use it well the
problem is is that we moved to NDA right
there are organizations that said I'm
not going to produce a module that has
produced eight modules friends of d8 -
so their organization - yes yes sir
that's the standard operating procedure
there are organizations that says that
will do them right so there's a problem
in the industry that were not consistent
on our point of the Rothstein transition
to them yet and I would say that as the
the authors and the owners that probably
has incumbent upon this group us to
provide guidance where it's necessary
above and beyond
now we've done that need some of the
some of the guidance I will say the guys
in some of the groups that are marketed
and looked at that since 1918 and has
has made some decisions of it right s -
I can't go into too much because of both
member organization tree had have made
decisions on some sort of some of the
decisions that have been made here says
everything has to be a state model but
they're getting caught up on some of the
permutations that human even was missed
in earlier drafts which says I got that
non on a client's client you know for
permutations trying to find the
circuitry
audience aw server is not defined like
in what and they're getting cut up
around like some of the operations that
we're introduced it so I like my my
concern is is that if we don't talk
about this I don't know if we've got I
don't know if we've got all all the
pieces in place that we get from
industry the necessary guidance that
they need to get through this we're just
I think crates tink modules and has to
end and look at the existing DCP some
say some of the resolutions in this one
room was simply okay so we are out of
time
just quickly so three things one I'm and
we'll have to take all this the lists
but one I'm wondering if we should
consider a flag day something on the
order of currently the guideline to say
you know as soon as possible but maybe
we should as important group say how
many years one year two year three years
like is there a deadline should there be
a deadline if so could we do that
secondly Andy had written something -
Jabar but we don't have time to go model
text and lastly I knew one of the ask if
there's some interest in
Leia's on to address your issue Tim
again we're out of time so we'll take
all that to list thank you and there is
like a yang next meeting tomorrow
morning yeah for that amazing actually
there's a young next step meeting on
Tuesday morning remember you can check
out the wiki page for the side meeting
and we will organize this meeting to
discuss the summer issue may be related
to the I am the transition but not know
that is who I actually just so it is a
side meeting that and if you're
interested in it you should go but it is
not one of our things okay thank you if
you haven't signed the blue sheet please
come up and do so this is your last
opportunity