[Music]
so we're gonna give it a couple more
minutes because people are still having
lunch and we're missing some of our
presenters still
[Music]
okay so welcome to MPI 3 in the last the
last slot of this this ITF I'm Matthew
botulin shows
Chacho Sam Sam or drea and we were
issued doing the doing the minutes today
our secretary thank you here is a note
well I'm sure you've seen this many many
times this week that's we have to show
it once again basically it says that
anything you say here is a contribution
to the ITF okay blue sheets are going
around there's one on each side of the
room please sign the blue sheets and if
you're the last person at the back of
the room with the blue sheet if you
could bring it to the front and you're
done that'd be much appreciated so the
agenda we have four drafts on the agenda
in addition to the working group this
working group status update any comments
on the agenda so a milestone so as usual
these are completely out of date and we
need to update them I've just these are
the ones from from the dates tracker
I've just quickly updated the milestone
regarding that the data plane solution
which is genève which has been submitted
for to the is three website to Martin
now but we need to we need to come up
with some some sensible timelines for
the rest of the milestones so watch this
space any comments on the and the
milestones apart from they're out of
date ok document status so we have quite
a few RFC's but no new ones since the
last IETF our most recent one was our
CID 394 the split NVA document control
plan requirements
so an update on the data plane
encapsulation
so that's surgeon Eve draftin Eve which
was the data encapsulation identified by
a doe deplaning capsulation design team
is now with Martin
so we've requested publication for that
we have another draft which describes
the output of the data plane
encapsulation design team which I think
at the time we thought was useful to
publish something yeah yeah semi would
Ross yeah yeah I think I think I don't
think we are gonna update it more so so
it should be ready for the last court
okay
thank you okay I just get a show of
hands of who recently was read the data
plan encapsulation draft okay it's
reasonable proportion of the number of
people in the room
okay so we'll probably take that to list
and do a poll because we you know it's a
pretty mature document it was just the
output of the design team so we just
thought it was a good a good idea to at
the time to publish that really as a
documentation of our experience in
picking and encapsulation from multiple
competing encapsulations Martin do you
are something Martin has a routing ad
I'm finally for the working group
believes that it's needed be aware that
typically on some of these types of
documents ideas she tends to ask whether
that's really needed to publish as an
IFC yeah this is this is more more for
the benefit of the broader eyes you have
to document the process by which we
picked picks an encapsulation format
when we had quite a lot of controversy
around which encapsulation should move
forward and this is something that
happens repeatedly in different working
groups so it's really okay is that clear
early in the document that that's the
time yeah all mission were fine yeah
okay should be
okay we in working group last call so he
had the eevn applicability to dodging
Eve which is currently with the document
shepherd so that went through working
group last call there wasn't any
objection to that
I think Samuel you're handling that you
only give an update on where are you I
think B Shepherd rate updates or do so I
will be doing that tough for the 80th
meeting we also had a virtual machine
mobility draft that some of you may
remember that went through working group
last call last year it also had some
reviews and quite a lot of discussion on
the list from TSV area review team the
ops Directorate and there was also a
routine Directorate review and I think
that the some of the issues that were
raised by the TSV are not direct reviews
weren't fully addressed by the editor at
the time and the auditor has since gone
absent so we have a we have a volunteer
to pick up the pen on the draft much as
Linda why has that gone others it looks
like we have a technical problem
there we go yeah I'm quite sure what
happen there so hopefully we'll be able
to move forward with that document and
get those get those get those reviews
addressed I don't think there was any
other real problems with the that they
were raised during the during the last
call I think it was mostly some some
comments that were raised during these
these area reviews that needed to be
addressed properly so thanks Linda it
was unfortunately not here for picking
her up there's actually a bad connection
this table Tom Mizrahi just a short
question regarding the the excellent GPE
document we have a plan to publish that
in the future so yeah so so so now that
genève has been published
well not been published yet but now
Geneva's with with the ASG so I think
just to refresh the working groups
memory the original decision was that
the other encapsulation drafts could go
forward as informational or experimental
following following a publication of
Geneva so that's really yeah I mean it's
kind of up to the up to the authors to
at least refresh the drafts and so so
can I get a show of hands maybe who has
read any of those other encapsulation
drafts and such as VX and GPA recently
okay if you I think it would be I mean
we did promise we would do that and a
working group agreed to do that so I
think we should probably maybe after the
design team encapsulation draft has been
published it's gone to the is you it'll
be good good time to then thanks then so
then publish those because then then
then a little bit of context to the is G
about why we're going forward and
publishing or so publishing these some
other end cap drafts okay
Gregory ET I appreciated to tell
so you mentioned that because GUI went
to different area for its own fat
so the excellent GP you consider it to
be informational or experimental yes yes
okay yeah because this working group
decided to pick one standard track okay
how much of influence you see that the
working group will have over the
informational experimental track
document well they're still working
group documents here they're not
individual submissions to the to the RFC
editor there that's not the track it's
not like when we originally did the X
line and I went to individual in which
case we didn't really we didn't know
that this must be owned because it's in
my interpretation of experimental and
and information it's just reflective
whatever being implemented so it's not
that I think that's true for
experimental but for informational it's
definitely can be more than that yeah
because I said in either case they're
still working group documents okay
because I do have strong concerns about
what they've done in their recent
versions okay given that they are
working group documents I think working
group has a say in how the document is
going to be sure yeah because yeah I
appreciate your clarification because
again in the standards it's quite clear
in my mind that their editors in the
working group is working with the
document but with informational
experimental it's yeah I don't know if
for the experimental case Martin do you
have any comment on that because I think
that's probably more why the ambiguity
is isn't that so so I guess the question
is if px 1 GP for example is published
as experimental or goes forward as an
experimental document how much say does
the working group have over the
technical details of the draft because
of course it's documenting an
implementation
again and that's my interpretation of
experimental that it reflective of in
some cases we have at ITF where their
implementation or defect the standard
being put on an informational track but
experimental is more of really
reflective of some experience of
particular implementation so basically
that you know we cannot really say oh
you should have implemented differently
because the response I would imagine
will be no but did it this way you might
disagree but well at this point it's
informational so maybe we can leave it
that way and avoid the potential issues
well my understanding is that if we
don't have any buddy from the this group
of working with the vehicle NGP document
I think that needs to be discussed with
them what they would like to do I think
we kind of need to have a consensus of
its working group as well as to which
way forward I want to go with with this
if it's just simply uh I mean you know
you can argue probably they could be
experimental because we have one
standard stripe document so why are we
arguing over there or debating the
technical details of another
encapsulation why don't we just document
what's what's been implemented for the
other encapsulations it seems perhaps a
little contradictory to have one
informational I mean this is my personal
view it seems slightly contradictory to
have an informational document
describing encapsulation and the
standard strap document describing an
encapsulation the perhaps and the
perhaps an experimental description
might be more appropriate I think in my
view the main problem with the
experimental is that you need to revisit
it
two or three or whatever years
afterwards and if it's informational you
don't necessarily need to revisit it
okay okay so the security requirements
draft that's on the agenda
it's next up on the agenda I just want
to have a notes about there's a draft
that was originally discussed in the BFD
working group for BFD over genève and it
doesn't really propose any changes to
BFD I think it's not more about how you
encapsulate in Geneva and there was some
discussion with the between the BFD and
the NVA for three chairs about where
this document should be progressed and
the feeling amongst the chairs was it
should go forward in nvo three yes and
we followed on your suggestion and we
resubmitted it yeah with the individual
draft in the or three okay yeah so we
were we are not presenting at this time
so okay I think well we died says from
some review review of that draft and we
would like to go forward or we think we
should go for it with a working group
adoption poll if there sufficient
interest in the working group okay so
has can I get a show of hands does
anyone actually has anyone read this
document let's draft you know and we
definitely did a little bit more people
were reading it may be great if you can
send something to the list asking for
review but yes actually
as a golfer we won't ask you first let's
discuss there encapsulation draft so
then we'll take this feedback from there
in via encapsulation discussion use it
in our view of this document and then
we'll do a discussion of the deity
document okay okay sorry that's the
working group stay
don't know thank you
hi so I'm gonna present a little bit the
security around Geneva so it's it's not
especially focused on the requirements
draft but it's a how we envision I mean
Jenny of security the problem we have
with the currently defined unit and how
we would like that to be moved forward
so yeah genève without transit devices
is really a hand and to end protocol so
we can use the end-to-end security so if
you're willing to use IPSec or DTLS
works perfectly fine when you when you
have transit device things change
completely depending on what you want to
disclose to the transit device and what
you don't want to disclose but it is a
fact that using end to end security
protocol you will always result in a I'm
hiding everything to the transit device
or I'm disclosing everything to the full
world and so there is a balance we need
to find that so that's what I can
illustrate with this payload so if you
have envy both nve are interpreting all
the options so you have the packet that
is transmitted from one and V to the
other one if you secure that with DLA
DTLA the same with is a layer below but
if the in that case TLS will provide an
integrity and confidentiality protection
for that jean-yves packet from one env
to the other one so in this case we
assume that
nver processing all options and all the
header and the payload and and so on and
the purpose of TLS is and DTLS is really
to to prevent that someone in the middle
can intercept read or do whatever it's
doing with that gene if packets so the
contradiction is that when you're
introducing a transit device you you're
sort of defying the purpose of the
security so as I mentioned earlier you
have two choice either you disclosed
everything so no protection at all or
you provide I mean you you bypass the
transit device so suppose we are in a
situation where envy is a providing
option a B and C and the other hand nbe
is provided is only processing option a
but the transit device is supposed to
process option B and C so if without any
protection while the packet is sent
through transit device the transit
device as a full access to everything in
Geneva packet is processing option B and
C and you move that to nve that is
processing option a if you use DTLS well
the thing is that the transit device can
process the expected options BCD so only
option a will be processed I mean in
that example the transit device is
completely bypassed so you you either
had this way disclosing everything so
transit device here might be the
legitimate one you may have another one
that is not legitimate but they have the
same access to the same data if you use
DTLS while all the transit device has
been removed
so the current genius specification
specifies that transit device can only
read and I think everyone agree with
that it's okay it's fine but if you
disclose everything and you don't
provide any mechanisms I mean we don't
have genius police so if the device you
you have no way to enforce this only
read so it's only that you trust that
the transit device are behaving in a in
a in a good manner so we need I mean the
purpose of the security here is really
to if we have opted agreed it doesn't
mean he can't cause arm we really have
to provide some mechanisms that and
force that the transit device may access
to some information we can't do anything
else then reading that information and
then we must also be able to limit the
information the transit devices having
access to I mean that you want to
transit device to read an option you may
not want him to read the full packet or
being able to monitor whatever traffic
is being provided from one and ve to the
other one and so that's why you also
need some sort of encryption so with
friends device if you would like that so
transit device so two things I mentioned
and forcing the radio only the data and
restricting the data are being accessed
by the transit device so on this graph
what I'm trying to show is that if you
want to disclose some options to the
transit device then you can't use DTLS
so one way to do and I'm happy to to
have other ways but
can I move in oh there is a pointer yeah
okay
so one way to do is that okay we need to
disclose the option and maybe the
Jeanette fixed header so that I mean
where you have the the network
identifier because that's might be used
for routing purpose so okay so this
should be disclosed because those are
going to be used by a transit device but
those we don't need to disclose them
because they are not useful for the
transit device and actually we don't
want this transit device to have access
to this data so one way to do is to do
make to provide a security option that
says everything after is going to be
encrypted and that's gonna be negotiated
with this one so this layer is encrypted
the transit device can't read this but
he can't read what is supposed to read
and then because I mean I'm telling the
transit device AAA you're not you're
only allowed to read I mean if you've
rights you will change the data you have
to be able to to check that is only
gonna read that data so you need a kind
of security authentication so I put a
security option that's ID okay these are
the data I'm disclosing to that transit
device and that's going to be
authenticated so in case you change that
this one will be able to check a sum
option has been changed it's not the
packet that this nve has been emitted am
issuing so basically the the
communication is sealed between this and
ve and with such mechanisms you can
disclose some information to
transit device I mean do we have any
question on why we do that and why DTLS
or regular end-to-end security protocol
doesn't work here I'm having to take any
question so why do you swallow semi
Boutros from VMware the game but are you
saying we encrypt one option so no okay
so we'll include absorptions I mean so
here I'm saying it's it's like a marker
it's a proposed solution so so that can
be just I don't think that will work
right because you know the option lens
has to be known to the header right so
you cannot encrypt some and leave
summary I think what we discussed is
that will only do a sonication right so
this option basically will say from here
it's gonna be encrypted
and you can have you mean the whole
packet would be an option will be option
but as well that won't work because we
have a maximum length of okay okay so we
but the idea is to provide some needs to
say from the second great thing one
option may not be no no sorry can use
mine so what you're saying is that okay
options together and I mean the the the
length is specific so we can tank rip
the other thing I if we want to have
something going clears and we cannot
encrypt the options right
we cannot encrypt any option video right
I mean they are in this case in this
case what I'm suggesting is that this
option is going to be encrypted correct
which is not possible well not we can
discuss it off location it's not
possible I think we discussed is having
is being able to Asante key and we can
you know I think we are saying we are
to read the option it would be good in
my opinion right to change some of the
option not add option but change it
which means that you can authenticate
some of the option not all options you
can pick what you want our son to get to
allow the midpoint to change some of the
options they want say what you would
like is that certain education whose
option they are sending very clear and
and if you want to allow some of the
option to change the authentication or
the hair should not include the option
oh yeah yeah yeah but I mean so what
you're saying is that the transit device
may change an option correct may updated
right okay so that's that's a different
requirement okay I think I think we
probably miss this one so may want to
consider this one like an application
but in terms of encrypting one option on
the I don't think is possible so it's
feasible it might not be a good idea
okay so that we can discuss but okay um
I mean it may not it may makes no sense
to encrypt but not one option that's and
I mean the that's the kind of things
we'd like to know on how to design I
mean the security requirements to know
exactly what we would like to achieve
because we can end up in something very
complex which is what were you I think I
mean the requirement we have now are
pretty complex because we're kind of
opening all the different possibilities
so we might say it's funny
I think in my opinion in Krypton is a
fellow was the hosting okay it's payload
or whole thing options we Asante get the
whole thing what portion that's it so
watching what you are saying is that
either we anchor it from here to here
the whole thing
okay let's repeat it yeah that's yeah
I'd be saying we encrypt everything or
or is that beautiful only the payload
okay that's my opinion you know it's a
private
okay so which means all options will be
either correct or not correct and option
can be authenticated yeah all of them or
portion and violante oh yeah so okay so
I mean that's okay that's a that's a
good point
I mean I'm I'm fine yeah we can discuss
that
it's a languor thanks to Nikki yes I are
you hear me yeah yeah yeah me hear you
yes okay good so first of all I would
like to state their architectural II
what we envisioned is NV is an entry and
protocol I think I've explained this
multiple times during the you know in
the mailing list as well as part of the
review
it's an end-to-end protocol and so the
transit devices are nothing but
forwarding elements that are already
available in the underlay network you
know it could be routers or switches and
so on so if we you know they if there is
an end-to-end encryption is employed
which means that these forwarding
elements will not be able to see their
you know options header anything that's
perfectly fine and we have already
described saying that if such is the
case these elements which are called as
transit devices will have to forward it
like any other IP packet that's it right
so that's that's that's very clear and
these you know forwarding devices or
transit devices interpreting these
options is not an absolute requirement
for the functioning of the NTN protocol
so we did not you know an omission
saying that okay let's just show part of
this option to this particular transit
device and you know exchange keys
between the transit device in the
endpoint that was not the intent at all
and that's very clear if you read the
draft I mean there are many different
protocols like example if you take it in
RFC 8:08 6 which is GRE over UDP same
thing you know equivalent you know GRE
key is an equivalent to an option here
there is no you know requirement that
you go and just selectively encrypt or
decrypt or send it in the clear you know
just this GRE key so that
intermediate forwarding no need to look
at it no that's not the intent right
same here
I mean Geneva is no different than any
other European capsulation protocol so
this whole argument or you know talking
about saying that okay let's go and you
know show this partially partially
encrypt some parts of the options that's
not supported in the architecture and
that's not what we really wanted to go
out go in this direction
actually I think that in addition to
looking at the payload we need to look
at how this security framework will be
impacting active om okay because if we
want to do
[Music]
traceroute their tunnel that we're using
so to determine where in underlay we are
traversing the network so we need to
transcending and how to work if we're
doing encryption or we saying that om
would not be encrypted again would I
security will not acquire to add before
here okay again adjuster we're not
discussing it don't have to discuss
challenges something to think about it
and look at how to work may work ok so
just one thing when you say oh am the
OEM isn't genève option no and that one
should be oh no it's a it's a bit in the
header is it okay the bitumen header now
refers to as a control packet will be
discussing om encapsulation later today
in a session what I'm just saying is
that active who I am
is specially constructed packet that
injected but what's important and
critical is that
active or a.m. follows the same path and
receives the same treatment as date of
law packet so basically they hate
sharing so would encrypting the data
packets and for example possibly
speculating not encrypting test packets
will still enable us to do page sharing
or not so okay so that's something to
think about it again no no no no but I'm
I just want to understand so this means
the way I see that so it is that om is
implemented through maybe an option and
some fields in the fixed header no om
implemented through the payload Oh
within the payload okay and so what you
would like is that some payload would be
non-encrypted well again I I envisioned
that there is a need to traverse the
underlay tunnel and for that the payload
means to be visible the transit note
okay that's a I mean I mean we have to
check that how to make it but an it's
interesting again one possible scenario
is that we'll say okay there at the 4
a.m. for that purpose would not should
not be encrypted but the question then
is that would that still preserve or let
us preserve hate sharing with the data
flow some all dream Google just want to
act what thing if you're sending the
packet will your packet then the or just
the data plane itself is encrypted right
from end to end it doesn't mean anything
because you cannot peek into the payload
you respectively whether you're a
transit device or are so if that's how
it should because it should behave just
like any other day
I mean I mean otherwise you are pretty
much breaking the the security whatever
you have set up for the so I have a
couple of for high-level questions the
first one is I know this was kind of
discussed but I just want to bring to
the notice of working group so we had
this as genève security requirements
Yeah right
why not mu or three because this is
nothing to do with specifically Jenny
this should be for the virtual networks
because we are driving the virtual
networks yeah so I would say there's an
vo3
got the option point as part of the data
plane and cap that is part of that then
kept protocol okay but so one reason is
that there is an envy of three
requirement document and but his draft
has not been continued so we started a
genève because one of the main
difference between the the security
requirements provide for n vo 3 did not
consider the transit device sure but
that goes to my question of like what is
transit device in the architectures but
that should be addressed from the
architecture perspective but not the
security should define on neither should
and cap define what trans appeals should
be part of the architect oh yeah yeah
definitely because I mean we are a
little bit like because we don't turn it
what those transit device do and I think
currently the situation we are is that
we said ok so this device have not been
defined at properly so well they can
have a single option they can read they
can have a single option dedicated for
that diversity can encrypt and so and
probably we are providing too many use
cases that are
not intended to be used so and Mister
but that goes to the solution aspect
here are the requirement aspect okay so
the solution or so from the requirement
perspective right yeah if the there is a
definition for what transit device ease
then the requirement should address and
they okay
right yeah yeah that's pretty much it if
you're considering this as end-to-end
protocol and you're going to define the
protocol for end-to-end then the
security should address the end to end
part of that and for the transit then we
need to I think Kamata can talk about
that what the transit how we are
planning to do that but we shouldn't be
defining what transit means as part of
the secure okay yeah so I think the
thing was when transit devices were
originally envisaged perhaps so some
people were saying they were more than
just just a Rooter
I mean they could be a firewall for
example or there could be some other box
that does some deep packet inspection or
something on the on the on the mvo 3
frame so and the prop but the problem is
that was never discussed or never
described as part of the MV o3
architecture any of that functionality
and so the only definition that we
really have of a transit devices in the
genève encapsulation draft which is a
little over you know it's problem may
not be a complete definition I think
from from what I understood from what
Ilan was saying if the transit device
will be only a router or of are all
exactly said Matthew right then it
shouldn't be inspecting any options
answer transit device here simply a
router should not be looking at option
it's on his Andy who looked right so so
and we can look and now when we are
talking about option between and bees
should we encourage them should be only
authentic ISM and that's about it so if
an NDE will if device will inspect the
options that is an MD yeah and I think
we can go that definition to that should
be fine that
there is no treasure device that inspect
option of course transit device exists
but only as router or as far towards the
floor as IP packet and cannot look
beyond IP back shouldn't shouldn't even
you know no the problem is that
statement should not look beyond we know
today that you just do because I saw
they do assume yeah if they do hashing
on five tuples or even seven couples are
looking at UDP or the transport layer
force they not look beyond layer four
right so so so the router even the Faro
right if you are talking about layer for
are old they look only at UDP ports or
TCP port so they look at therefore so
yes sure you can look at therefore if it
exists if then we decide to expose the
UDP header and the genève header and not
secure not encrypted then the router can
look at it and maybe this should be the
definition if everybody is okay with
that is that transit device really has
no role in the in enviously architecture
altogether and engineer as well as I
only exist because there are routers
that can switch back yeah well in fact
in practice this exists right the
devices you know is easy NP router for
example right they they look inside the
packet right they skip over possibly the
options and look inside the payload and
then might still employ easy MP policies
right so one second one second you you
want the router here you look inside the
payload after the option and and and and
do something with it
it could that's what I am saying that we
don't we can't preclude that if the
packet isn't the clear no no one can
stop an intermediate device right in the
underlined network to peer into our look
into that information and then do what
it wants to do all we are saying is you
know we fit is looking into it then
there are certain you know restrictions
we are trying to run I know make the
people aware that if they are looking
into it
they're not supposed to do certain
things that's all we find in the job
okay I see so so so watch what you are
saying in other times it says the
transit device can do whatever he needs
to do to forwards a packet but really
not alter any a tiny eight on the back
that's exactly what we have to define in
the draft and if you're worried about
you know a transit device tampering with
the data then there's a possibility for
you to introduce the interior and
authentication mechanisms so that you
know no data integrity mechanism and
this thing's this what we are saying is
that the options what we are saying is
that the whole package includes a
transit device won't be able to look at
any payload here because it's encrypted
if you already or if it of the packet
goes in clear you are right the currency
device can do whatever it can do with it
but without changing anything of the
packet if security is in play with the
sonication for example right so so I
think yeah those absorption were
discussing I think we discussed an extra
option in which you are saying the
option header between and v-not a
transit and because I think with what
you are saying here who is handling
options really handling meaning
processing understanding what the option
is about and so on is going to be in
these not transit device that's correct
that's what we have a clearly explaining
the draft and what the security
requirement draft is trying to go on
interpret it's in one it's one way and
trying to give some solutions like what
you know Daniel is right now explaining
and that's not what is supported in the
Geneva collection that's basically what
I am trying to say okay so so from
security aspect we just need not to have
any transient devices here we'll just
call them and be so there is no machine
will be there it will be there whether
we like it or not these are under layer
devices you know these are device will
not be there but what we are saying is
not playing a role in security right
meaning is not Osan ticketing is not
encrypting is not decree or it's not
doing any of that so where the device
exists
as from a security perspective as a
pass-through device but I think just to
what you said earlier was we do have
similar technologies like VPN and all
that stuff right and this is no
different to that so we shouldn't be
redefining like the partial lookup for
the transit device out there is no
specification or precedence to set like
parcel option and those kind of that's
what I'm trying to say Lachlan we
shouldn't be coming up with some new
requirement when other protocols which
are already in existence do not define
those this is not different I agree I
agree so I think the partial stuff that
I mentioned yes I I agree it's not if
they are Andes nows and yes they can
change the options on - I really hate
that scent again so so so yeah so the
whole option of the whole packet can be
encrypted was the whole packet can be
authenticated option and balaam except
that the final thing should we convert
this to a new or three requirements a
new or three security requirements
instead of general yeah so then we
shouldn't worry about transit I in terms
of security procedure but as Janine is
defining as the transit is the
pass-through device for packet whatever
it to is the packet it's its own
discretion but you but if security is in
place should not change any options of
that so in the Geneva we won't have any
transit device that am I correct in the
specification well so we will not have a
transit device from the security
Presidio perspective but the transit
would exist to still forward as a packet
but the problem we have is that if the
transit device is able to look at the
options he can look at the option but
he's not allowed to alter or touch it so
so you know going back to the the the
parallel with VPN architect
as we do at least recognized in I
believe in going back to that the
provided provisional VPN architecture
the fact that Peru what they call P
Reuters exists and they do describe them
so we're not defining we've got to
recognize that they're there so just
saying they don't exist but you can say
they do not touch you can say what they
do not do - they're well they're not
expected to do to the genève header okay
I think that's probably the western read
it brother won't they weren't I don't
terminate as soon as you terminate it
that's an envier you want to change
anything in it you're an MBA but you can
read it you know transit doors can read
it and you know some forward my son 14
decision but with no it's I want to
write you know but with no touching of
it right or altering it ya know we can
scope what it what it what it does to
genève or doesn't do to genève I said
from I hopefully who is saying here is
that Geneva penalties describing this
so if description is fines and they
already have a description but there's
nothing specific to Geneva bout this is
not special to Geneva it's just written
in a Geneva off because it wasn't been
done anywhere else ah yeah because you
need was technology because there will
be devices between and Vees that will
forth package because a lot of this
discussion arose after the MV o3
architecture was done so so maybe I for
exampie or three angrily architecture
probably assumed that there will be
transit device but we have no rule no
role for tech minuting tunnels in common
I don't recall the discussion even
coming up until we started talking about
transcending tracery of OEM
I see yeah but I think yeah there's REM
implications of these things as well so
but but in terms of OEM as well you know
was three South and so on where it can
be treated like an IP packet right you
know an IP UDP packet a router if the TV
Alex
he would sends ICMP error back well for
the for the others for the under light
but I mean if you do something yeah but
there's ways that isn't sending as well
right yeah we I mean it's not refreshing
to it's not refresh recently but I think
the objective of that was to trace a
particular be and I I see where it went
through throwing the underlay yeah you
know I assume here was what you are
defining if security supplies and the
transit cannot really change any option
attack yeah but I thought that doesn't
affect exactly actually terminates and
replies somehow so even if you wanna do
or at least not be annoyed and should be
okay but a device that as a different
behavior if it's secured on non secure
is bringing a contradiction into the
architecture because it means if you
want to secure that deployment you have
to balance that the ingress point and
the egress point are the only nodes who
are what allowed to touch that you need
and do anything is a packet right yeah
and and you know so if you are touching
your and enbe you are knitting a family
or an IV if you want to do trace route
between those two and V by transit
routers right it's fine to write because
they are not going to be touching
anything on the package that would
simply be sending errors back or
something right so some indication back
to the English point that yes I am on
the way yeah but the thing is that if
you have a deployment that is going
through a transit device and you rely on
the fact that he's inspecting the packet
I won't be able to secure that that's
fine but but that's the architecture
that's the deployment scenario yeah
they're like we do have like VCC we
deployments we have different
deployments right if you don't secure
end-to-end then you are defining your
network design yeah to make sure that
others can actually inspect the packet
but if you really want to do that you
secure the whole payload including
whatever exactly you so
phillipians and these would be like one
hobble a so in other words there is no
requirement to say that there is a way
for the transit device to look into that
as long as the pail or the the network
or the encapsulation allows it there is
no requirement that it should or
shouldn't do certain things selectively
things if the end-to-end is encrypted
period yeah I cannot look into that okay
if it is not restricted or not encrypted
then yeah in transit device can look
into that
yeah but yeah but if if you have a
deployment where that is relying on
those transit device and then you have
been asked to say well can you secure
does an ve to and ve communications yes
you can secure it because you are either
encrypting betweens MV so the transit is
a pass through doesn't doesn't look
doesn't know what's inside the packet or
you can authenticate her and in that
case yes he can look because the data is
Cle but he cannot do much as well right
you know he's only looking at what you
sent in clear yeah but that's a huge
impact I mean the deployment cannot be I
mean that the deployment of security is
going to be deeply impacted by those
transit device because depending on what
you are much of security I think a
sensor is at your discretion you want to
show stuff in clear or not if you don't
want to stuff in clearer than is a facet
is simply for routing an IP packet yeah
but once you choose you can't go back
it's really hard so I think we should
take this to this because we've got
three more doors
ok ok thanks Tanya thank you thank you
sorry
so hello everyone so here we arrive at
the sixth version of this draft and you
may notice that we have new members our
design team especially we have one who
is come who is the author of another
young draft which is dedicated for
genève and vixen TPE so the design
methodology of this two draft is aligned
and in the future the two draft will be
well coordinated so the first day I
would like to recall the motivation of
this draft so in ITF for the in terms of
network virtualization overlay the data
plane and the control plane have been
covered and that there are several
ability the works on it and clearly the
Yamato is still a gap so to be covered
and why we start with a base a very
young because there are several
encapsulations and vivian technologies
and if we run to run directly into
individual calculations will run out run
into with a positive works and a non
consistent approach so it is better to
start with a common and reusable young
in the first place and it can be used at
the start point for individual
encapsulation two people can actually
element the space young any type one
necessary to define the young model for
individual encapsulation and in this
base area model we will use we have used
the reference eyes such as vo3
RCS for example the framework
architecture and we have used the rigid
RCS and works in progress in ATF so
there is a relatively significant change
in the current version and in the
previous previous version the NVE is
defined as a container and inside this
container we defined as the via
instances and but now we define mve as
an interface actually Ignace has a
comment during the last ITF and we think
it is a good idea so we adopt it and now
the e is defined as an interface via
augmenting the ITF interface young and
and in the pace I will three young
module we have indicated which and the e
interface that the via instance a snotty
to so basically the relationship between
the VI and the NVE is still the same but
here we use different logic and here you
have the the sauce with high P which is
the address of the Anika's it way if it
is enabled here and if it it is enabled
we should have a bypass with high P to
you know to identify uniquely the AE
inside of this and it has to get way and
this style gives you a impression about
house and very busy is mapped to the
architecture and inside the the base a
very young module we we define the via
instances and here we the the via ID is
configured and used as a K of the VI
instance and here as you can see we have
the source and ve indicating that which
and we'll a very interface is mount 82
and we have also a PDP control plane in
Ebola to indicate if the AES
are configured dynamically there's a bit
difficult controlling or it is
configurable study statistically and if
it is the later case
the the static appear and they define
here so we also have the the multicast
group per defined per VM basis and for
different very I we can have different
multicast service note and another
change a that the mapping between the l2
VPN or I Australian to the to to to the
via instance it is now defined by
augmenting the ITF l2 Vivian or our sway
VPN module and pre in the previous
version the mapping relationship between
the VI and I - oh I also really n it is
defined in the V container
so next step
we open to your comments and if you
think that we are moving in the right
direction
or the idea to define the base your
module is the right direction please
consider our deficits draft eyes working
group document so any comment you can I
get a show of hands for please raise
your hand if you've read this document
that's quite a good number of people
okay thank you
so good afternoon my name is Sammy
Boutros from VMware I'm presenting the
Mac move draft so yeah we presented this
draft I think last year so so the idea
here is that the use case we are talking
about here is a dual homed device right
between nuts a couple of and the year
and we are doing data clean Mac learning
so so so we're talking here about data
plane Mac learning with a do at home
device so now you know that do at home
device if there would be a failure so so
here's the door at home device as well
is the axis here is not villain
it's it is a genève tunnel between what
we call they have to service and then
these so so you have a genève tunnel
between the nve's of course and between
the layer 2 device and then V so now
those and V is of course they can be
talking control planes they can be
talking evpn talking whatever control
plane to distribute max or mac IP
bindings and now if the primary path for
the dual home device goes down then
there is no way for the dual home device
to know that he is going now to be
getting traffic from the backup and V so
for for it to know that we are proposing
the extension so again in simple term a
device that device could be hypervisor
for example the old ho doing home to two
and these two leaves to two tours and he
is setting up be excellent tunnel to
those envies sorry setting up genève
tunnels to those envies and now the env
is there is a failover
between a primary to the backup and B
and the backup and V has to give an
indication to the device sighing okay
hey switch over HAP so this is it right
you know so are saying we can have a new
genève option TLB and this option TLV we
can send on the genie packet right to
send the failover notification when the
backup or the standby and B becomes
active and the document describe a very
simple protocol following what we did as
well for MPLS TP for MPLS CP we had a
Mac withdrawal draft and the document
here follows the same thing follow
exactly the same protocol it's a very
simple data pass protocol to increase to
I to increase of course reliability and
make sure that that message will arrive
for example to the device sign that the
back up sending saying I am now active
and ve and all the Mac that you learned
from as a primary and ye are now visible
Barney so I think ensures that said any
comments ok never done Nokia can you go
back to the diagram please
so the target scenario is basically you
are building this hierarchical jean-yves
so it's not hierarchical it's not hard
like you mentioned from the wave 2
device as a genève tunneled genève
tunnels access access Ginny
okay in the other side you have the
other side you know can be anything can
be mesh of course sorry could be mesh of
tunnels could be MPLS could be anything
so could be EVP and based yeah yeah yeah
of course this what I mentioned as well
it may not be very clear here but the
other side could be MPLS based
think I think what what's being said
here if he imagines the whole network is
this a plane learning right data pin
McCloud nning than the other side can
use exact same similar mechanism but if
you use a data plane so the messages
that you are defining haha basically
what they say is okay there was a move
correct and from an old and feet up to a
new Vita correct that's it but you do
not define a list of MAC address no no
no no only all what you learned from the
old
a reachable Navami it's not yes MPLS TP
mac was rural stuff was defining a list
of Mac knows that's not doing that you
know it so what well here and what that
means is that basically you only have 1
layer 2 device right because so MGE 2 is
the one sending this mac move message ah
correct right correct what you're
telling the the remote nve's 800 i have
to have this a slight a you see the
super confusing forever
ah no no no okay okay I think yeah this
was all slight going back to the device
so they are telling their layer 2 device
that all moved but evpn you switch yeah
the about money signaling arrows going
the wrong way isn't it on that towards
to let it should be ok so yeah I'm
trying to you have to tell
well first of all you you advertise MAC
addresses from a given Ethernet segment
so you tell others flush MAC addresses
from this Ethernet segment not from a
feet up to a different video right you
will move it up if you are doing my
cloning on Zack's it's very confusing
for me sorry I can't discuss stuff line
if it's not clear I'm gonna clarify move
the slide as well so Allah I will update
the draft you okay thank you no prom
just ensure so I agree on the comment
it's confusing high rated number of
times okay okay and some of the name is
confusing as well because it's not
really that much mock has moved is that
the interface became unavailable so
you're pretty much signaling you've got
some relationship between and we won and
we did from from the service perspective
so if you've got the relationship so you
just need to tell the layer to service
in this case that yes which is down so
it's not really much move its everything
move right you just move from one
interface to another you flush no so you
understand but the service you represent
here is going to rewrite the destination
for hallmark addressed have learned from
envied want in v2 right so it's not just
to be confusing now when you explain it
here clear
but I will have is enough to make it to
match the explanation singing actually I
think we did more or less the stimulus
thing
true before so there are some sorry
sorry cRIO
there is another protocol episode
concluded was called there are some
ideas we could borrow there are some
tricky points here for example for the
meu 1 & 2 you see the step primary
standby are they supposed to use some
like any caste IP address for both of
them no they are using different IP
addresses there are two yeah yeah yeah
yeah of course of course if you want to
use any caste that's another approach I
I'm talking here about any caste non any
caste approach for the for the Mac move
signal if you think kind of thing is
like 20 days yeah ARP so it looks like
to me it's possible you just you know
making this assumption to are on the
same layer to segment and we can use to
the device
you know graduates are or or when when
the any caste switched from an v1 and v2
Xan we do not need to do anything at the
device so you just now you said it's not
um the black arrows they are not
multicast Iraq is a multi post single
correct not equal unicast okay so so for
the MA two to one there is no special
tunnel because that is that is the
special time no different from all the
others okay I I guess I think I think
you know the slide was talking about an
old genève data clean Mac learning stuff
right but what will change just to make
sure it's it's clear and very easy to
understand is that we won't care about
the core of the networks
cloud sing the core of the net who won't
care about it only the access is what
we'll focus on right and it's similar to
the war if you are familiar to the war
we switch from primary to backup and we
send in pseudo arias and what we call a
pseudo our status so this very similar
pseudo our status but you are sending a
tin band engineer this kind somehow
should be required that okay the
McKenney and my guess me I will update
the mechanism and he send comments yeah
you know I'll update so mechanism wait
for the refresh and the mechanism would
be very clear done so if I ask an
obvious question but so the the Mac move
signal goes within the in even caps
relational data plane correct okay so
you need data plane traffic to trigger
they update yes no no it's a special
message you send a genève packet with
the option was no data no payload you
don't need traffic to send it so if you
need a contraband signal sure if you
want to call it this way okay
thank you any more comments okay thanks
folks okay thanks to me Greg
okay so the question is then we had a
very good discussion in Prague is how we
encapsulate active om and genève so what
is active or am active om uses specially
constructed packets the monitor
troubleshoot localized effects and must
be not leaked out of Janine's domain and
multiple active or a.m. are required to
support oops for management performance
monitoring fault management active Orion
protocols must be clearly identifiable
in Geneva so we have four options for
your consideration and discussion IP UDP
encapsulation direct identifiers MPLS
generic associated channel header and
Geneva so okay let's start with IP well
understood
we have genève header obviously there is
transport encapsulation above Geneva and
after Geneva the next protocol points
the protocol type points to ipv4 or ipv6
since we are using either types this
already the these are readily available
and after the genève header we have
inner IP or v6 header and the
destination IP address
it's either so it's one of the martian
addresses and the multiplexing is based
on destination UDP port usually active
om uses UDP and already assigned UDP
port numbers and maintained in AML
registry
okay so that's pretty simple it's well
understood it's well known method for
example and OS LSP tunnels but the
problem
is that it adds up on IP UDP overhead
and as was mentioned in a discussion in
Prague it potentially creates a
possibility of generating false negative
if something wrong with the IP UDP
encapsulation because the distances are
there om packet from the genève header
direct encapsulation so the protocol
type is active or a.m. type for each of
protocols and then following their
genève header you have your control
message no overhead but then because the
probe likely will be multiplicity of
protocols for example echo request reply
BFD performance measurement protocol
there could be some coordination for
protection switchover or anything else
that each of protocols who require its
own type assignment MPLS generic
associated channel so it will use MPOs
protocol type and then after there
genève header will follow
gell generic associated level label and
it will be marked as bottom of the stack
so it will be only one label and that
will be followed by generic
associational header which is very
similar with the well-known and pseudo
wire associated channel header and we
can in we use the channel types that
already maintained in Ayana registered
to the wire associated SCH
- types and followed by the body of
their active protocol message so
positive we reuse to the wirele CCV
method or with gal and we don't need to
define new protocols because pretty much
everything is already defined for to the
wire Mississippi so just a question by
using a gal here rather than the other
because the obit is not defined obit is
not clear where the OEM is is it om in
extensions or om in a payload here is a
clear protocol type and then we go in
the protocol and the protocol just then
we go it's in PL s we look past the
header
it tells MPLS we go we look this is Gail
we know that Gail means it's a ACH or
gas and then we'll go there so we don't
need a bit here everything is straight
forward without oil now having a
question is should I be better defined I
mean it seems to me that you've got
three potential yes I was pointing
abstraction
yes I was pointing that all the way for
discussion of Geneva encapsulation and I
was of opinion that we don't need of it
or at least we don't need a beat for
identifying or am case at least I am
active or am we don't need of it if
somebody wants to use all be to identify
the presence of OM information and
extensions of course but for active Oh
am I don't see the reason we have
protocol type that's efficient
this precaution from Cisco was how it's
different the existing that I knew
you're three om draft it was a year
draft also for business
I don't recall the India draft om it was
channel was used with the eighty nine
zero to be threatened if you can show me
the link or make certain because again
similar information is engineers BFD
draft yes because Tuco offers discussed
it and put it there but then we decided
to extract it and first discuss this but
I don't know frankly draft I'm not
familiar with the draft it here yeah
just if you can find the draft and send
it to the list
thank you okay and and the worst is
Geneva associated channel then we need
to define om protocol type so it's
either net but if we can you reuse
existing either type for om it's already
there and then we don't need a gal we
can reuse format similar to to the wire
VCC V reuse the channel types and active
om so there is minimum overhead of just
a ch4 octet and actually we don't need
to create new registry we already have
all types in so which code 20 which if
the type reusing yeah there's a generic
hermano
yeah the same that 1731 is using but
it's not 1731 lesser so no no right but
we're using the same either type
yes okay sure yeah okay so that's what
we're proposing and we appreciate the
discussion your consideration and what
we would like to ask Cheers is to put a
time limit on the discussion so
basically to put the terms of when we
want to arrive to conclusion so
specifically it's a question which of
the encapsulation yes we need to select
one encapsulation
we don't need multiple because that will
be painful for everyone so on this one
on just for my understanding so if the
protocol time is OEM that's the the
aforementioned 89 or to either type that
means the the active OEM packet would be
C of M or what goes into this active OEM
thingy there no it doesn't have to be
CFM why it has to be CFM I seen it it
can go for example our d FD control
packet give D control packet because it
will be channel type the channel type
defines what is active or am not
protocol type defines what active or am
the channel type defines what active or
MD multiplexing is based on channel type
what do you foresee go in there either
type om right an example what give me an
example of what from your perspective
they're told it's BFD control packets
for example channel tap have you looked
at the water VC severe
okay so so I think my concern is
overloading the yeah overloading to meet
the meaning of the protocol type o a.m.
if that really means effectively CFM
yeah but we are we using it well but
it's not CFM here it's ACH
yes it's either a decision okay then no
do we need a different do we need an
ephah typefi see yes yeah i star am yeah
okay if it's confusing that we can get
the neither either type but i think that
one option for the genève we can reuse
it because if we if we can use for
example IP over Ethernet as indication
of IP payload then why we cannot use
ethernet om as indication of geneva am i
understand that we are not allocating
new IP over genève either type or are
waiting my understanding where we're
using IP over Ethernet right so is it
confusing no tom is right so are you
suggesting to use channel type 89 0 - no
no the channel type is it's what's in a
a Jana to the wire ACH registry so it's
a BFD it's all there so and that's it
the multiplexing what I'm suggesting is
to use a protocol type as Ethernet oh um
well so so I think my concern is Harry's
of the extensibility and future if we do
want to run raw CFM over over this then
what you use for the protocol type but
why would we run CFM over genève the CFM
can be run over service and then it will
be encapsulate in actually that will be
transported as pure data because if it's
end-to-end ethernet om that for genève
it's a data or in theory but as those
use cases worse
if M gets run out of all sorts of things
so I just the question of whether or not
it's appropriate to use the protocol
type fields just ICF em there rather
than Geneva REM or something but again
again to run CFM it will require so much
additional configuration so I really
don't see the case and why would we do
it for layer three because we understand
that you need to configure maintenance
the main name Nathan's the main
Association so the complexity of running
layer to OEM when we can run their 3om
on this tunnel segment right but but the
issue here is ov is it's confusing to
overload a well-recognized code point
for the protocol type okay well if
that's if you take you know a wire shop
snapshot of the packet you might expect
that if it says CFM in the protocol type
you're carrying directly CFM III need to
double check what whether it's really
interpretation of either type but it's
it's not really a sticking point so if
that's the problem we can allocate asked
to allocate another either type of the
technology so it's not that exactly that
thing is that actually if CFM goes over
tano it goes as data it doesn't go as
CFM okay so then in this encapsulation
it will be Ethernet if Geneva Geneva
will see CFM as Ethernet not as can you
be so kind and send the name of the
draft and it links to the draft because
otherwise I cannot answer you
my question as the protocol type that's
one of the proposals yes but if group
thinks that it's confusing we can look
for allocation of new either type so how
do you want the working group to respond
you have multiple proposals right so how
exactly you would like working group to
actually around you
well I think that we need to start
eliminating so we need to start
eliminating some options and saying okay
this is not acceptable at all and so
probably will end up what I would like
is first in the first phase of
discussion and that was two options okay
so let's first eliminate two options out
of four and once we get to two options
then we'll have more extended discussion
okay what I will do is I will send a
note and I would expect people to vote
because I think that eliminating two
options doesn't require a real argument
the technical discussion okay Martin of
a different opinion or has a proposal
simply to say nothing we don't vote
okay okay no warning then any other
format because what I would like to do
is I would like to have to make this
decision
way before meeting in Singapore so I did
as a stop we need some discussion on
this on the list
so we can get some consensus on the pros
and cons of the different different
approaches okay then let's have a just
discussion whether you start with that
started discussion and then we'll try to
measure the level of support
but I would probably do it in two rounds
so the first round is with objective to
get to two options and then in the
second round
just get one option yeah let's see how
it goes because we don't have a very
good record of coming to consensus on
online cancellations for anything in mvo
three lists so so we may have to zoom-in
step up to have to go for design and
actually then I would ask Cheers
to decide what the nuclear option will
be because then you you you say if you
don't come to consensus the nuclear
option is this they I think the choice
would have to decide would have to say
what the consensus is in in the working
group or pick or get a design team to
come up with a recommendation that we
can then get consensus on in working
group okay well if there's notice if
there's not in sufficient discussion on
the list I suspect no again a design
team okay and I do have a comment
question on around at the same time what
is the goal of this what we are trying
to achieve here and especially from the
actual usability perspective Greg you
mentioned about CFM and the complexity
of that CFM is a technology stack which
is rather well understood in the field
and basically the community uses that
for their two-minute ability purposes
that's rather well-known for trying to
invent something similar but not the
same that probably would not resonate
too well with the community that's just
additional complexity can we run CFM
over this channel and what while we are
happily talking about the fields values
bits and other things what is the
general problem that is being addressed
here what's a deliverable out of that to
provide for different encapsulations and
channels to carry Oh am not necessarily
knowing what are the problems what that
OEM solving do we have the requirements
what is needed for running these types
of networks Mui
have you on the overall manageability of
the stacks basically than the old tunnel
running and the Oh on some form of
underlay how that manager what are the
manageability problems that and I don't
expect an answer from you here this is
basically an open question but do we
have this understanding well we don't
have it formulated in a document yes
that's the case I would say that at ITF
we do have well-developed and longtime
deployed and tested om stack it's not
that might be coherent like again CFM
might not be the best example I would
then use 1731 because 1731 combines
fault management and performance
monitoring but we do have a suit of OM
active om tools that are functionally
match to 1731 so I would not say that we
inventing new OEM protocol know I know
their relationship but I'm saying they
functionally CFM is much shorter than
1731 know so no other way I think he mr.
you you have a good point here because
if I think back to the the OEM protocols
that we defined for those channel types
or that were identified by those channel
types you listed there a number of them
were originally developed in the context
of an MPLS transport network not so data
center VPN so so there is a question
here of which of those are actually
applicable in this sort of an
operational environment again if we look
from the field perspective MPLS OEM is
another technology stack which is rather
well understood by the community if we
can take and reuse that that would be
definitely be a benefit instead of
trying to reinvent something new which
basically does the same function but in
a different way right but
that's basically if if you look at this
again mpls om stack an IP om stack are
practically identical okay because it
was not developed for MPLS it was
adapted from IP into MPLS or at least
created look alike for example LSP ping
BFD works the same way as it works in IP
network it works over in paris OSP
channels tunnels ok so again what we're
discussing here is what the best in
simplest way to make available or a.m.
to set work over genève tunnel there
there the goal of this discussion is not
to develop new OEM protocol ah but how
to make existing om tools to work over
genève so i'm very happy by the first
part of the answer
please don't invent yet another William
thing because there are plenty I think
this is definitely for I don't want to
occupy the time this is definitely for
broader discussion over the broader
community I kind of get the feeling that
the group does not necessarily see the
clear view of how this can be used what
are the actual requirements maybe that
would be a good starting point to see
what is available and how those things
are being used basically what are the
problems in these types of the
deployments and how to address those I
agree that actually the requirements for
om functions it's a good document to
produce but I don't see that this
discussion of how we encapsulate active
om and discussion of what we need to do
in active or am I think then they can go
concurrently in parallel they're not
[Music]
they're not getting each other because
this is not what we do this is how we do
it
what we do is different okay so discuss
decide and then we were planning to do
look at what extensions we need for echo
request reply because continuing on what
Agnes said I do believe that yes this
environment may require certain
extensions to apply functionality
especially to probe their particular
things okay but so as I understand just
check my understanding verify with you
that I will send the email starting the
discussion you'll be judging the
consensus yeah I think in addition to
this I think Ignis I write a very good
points about the requirements yeah just
just thinking back to some of the I mean
normally which tools you need to use in
a given environment probably shouldn't
dictate the encapsulation but maybe here
it may be here it might influence say
the choice between UDP and and an ACH
okay there's a whole bunch of tools so
actually i i i i have to bring that back
history some time ago we had overlay om
design team and overlay om design team
came up with their requirements and then
we were told and I was told that oh no
we don't need this document so we have a
doc
and at least that we can start working
with because it lists requirements I can
bring it up I can bring it into and vo
group specifically and then the working
group can start looking and say okay yes
that's relevant not that's not relevant
and that's missing so would that be a
plan to play game plan this is going
back and forth right yep we have had
this effort within the routing area yes
to form the design team well design team
worked it produced number of documents
and among these documents was pretty
generic pretty generic I admit list of
requirements we can start it from
scratch or we can start it from the
existing document I don't have the
context of that but at least my
understanding of the outcome was that
there was no consensus on what is to be
done okay then then how will I rest my
case
is the list okay all right thanks Greg
and I think that's it thank you
[Music]
you