is to be a JavaScript where is Brian
okay in and fell and Tony will be taking
notes thank you guys and blue sheets are
going around already a our agenda for
today editorial will kick us off with a
job profile a with for 25 minutes M then
Aaron will talk about a Roth for
browser-based apps for 25 minutes
Danielle will have to is a sessions to
talk about the indie pop and and they
push the quests and the Annabelle I
don't see here yet she'll have a ten
minutes and I will wrap it up with ten
minutes of what a mr. Jones yeah
so let's get going Victoria all right
Victoria yours sorry see if it works
oh yeah is this is this a PDF or is it
okay so it probably I'll draw it from
here yeah you'll do it yourself yeah
yeah okay let me know when when the
drawing all right
Bonjour everybody and welcome thank you
for taking the time to come here and
hear about the progress we made with
generated profile for both to access
tokens how many of you guys read this
back hey that's not bad at all
thank you can we go faster so for the
benefit of the ones I did not read this
back and for the ones of you who read it
while having drinks or other stimulants
I'll give you a very quick recap of
what's in there and above all why we are
doing this because that will inform the
various things that you need to decide
and then I'll very quickly go through
some of the main changes thanks to
everyone who gave a feedback and induced
those changes and then I'll place on the
table free open issues and at least for
one called
for consensus all right so it's the very
cup thank you great so why are we doing
this once again in a you know current
user most for a physician service for
trying to use dread abilities for access
tokens arise I have made formal
presentations in which have presented
some research showing that they more or
less every vendor uses conveys with some
information they just use different
syntax and so there is no in
very easily opportunity for
interoperability and also given that
everyone did these in organic fashion
very often they went through our to say
utilitarian routes which led them to do
things with we might define anti
patterns and similar so very clearly a
guidance voice is not just a problem of
interoperability and finally something
that I failed to highlight during other
updates one thing with you observe very
often in the market is the fact that
more and more products are asking
clients to send ID tokens well instead
they should ask for access tokens reason
being that in order to actually make a
job they need to have a stable format
that they refer to they need to have the
information but we typically get in the
ID token so the outcome is that if you
want to use Google methods you've got to
send them your ID token there are a
number of flaws in Amazon but require
you to do the same so the hope is that
if we create a profile but actually
place in the access token where things
but those products need then we will
curb that practice thank you
so in nutshell what we did we define a
layout where we lay down the values
claims that represent most of the
concepts and type of information but
we've seen vendors are already placing
in their existing in production access
tokens we laid down some rules about for
example determining what should go in
the audience how you would mark certain
parameters and resource into the actual
content of a claim of a token then we
went down with details about how you
validate this talking like classic
enumeration of rules and then we took
finally this opportunity to advise
implementers for pitfalls piracy shows
the security you might encounter when
you place with kind of information in
the access token and if you want to dig
deeper into this we have a couple of
links in other events in which I covered
and just to make these a bit more
concretely Caesar what is smallest
durability access token would look like
and I'm sure there is nothing surprising
in there is like basically what you
would find in a skeleton ID token plus
one indication about who is the client
ID plus with scopes and then if you look
at this back there are other things that
can be done any questions so far
did anyone have our coffee did you check
all of your emails or are you still
checking your emails Zack wore Facebook
for walk or whatever you are using
alright let's look at the open issues so
very quickly what we did our way doesn't
say on it Donny as a question got had a
face it's just too mean Edlund so
question is are you go back can you go
back one slide one more so you said
something you were talking about
guidance on token validation if your
guidance meant to be normative and do
you expect to have some conformance do
you expect conformance to come out of
that
so like certain libraries would meet
certain validation libraries would meet
certain conformance criterias you mean
official tests to certify that's
something that could be used for library
conformance well I guess that's and
that's it possible outcome that to me if
he sees it didn't look quite all the way
normative when I was looking at it I
think it's fairly now maybe I'm missing
vien once or the semantics of normative
verses but to me very spirit of visa is
to help library implementers to know
exactly what to do when they receive is
talking and how to decide whether they
should accept it or not they exactly in
the same fashion as we have done for the
ID tokens back here you have exact steps
that you are supposed to
in order to say whether this is valid or
not did I answer the question all right
Marquis is not having an adverse
reaction so are you satisfied a mere
answer you know more of a normative
document to come out not necessarily
just a guidance so you add you want an
extra level something like open ID we'd
be looking for to do some conformance
testing and stuff yeah well I think they
got a lot of a guidance in here is
definitely amenable to be turned into
conformance testing so I think it's a
possibility for sure great all right so
summarizing the changes since the
earlier episodes at first all the claims
in there were mostly mapping having that
source map to open ID and instead we
changed visa to actually go all the way
to they draw a specification which makes
more sense then in the place where we
mentioned that that we would have tokens
which represent identity I was only
mentioning open ID and instead now I
extended it to mention also
introspection and basically explicitly
opened up to any identity potential
source of identity claims so pretty much
and then also mentioned there clearly
vector opposition servers are free to
place whatever attribute they want in
there as long as we don't have
collisions and similar then I added more
details in the privacy sections in
particular as a result of early feedback
and also misunderstandings thank for
example people are started saying things
to effect over now that I know where
formative access token then I can look
inside the real access token from a
client which clearly not a good idea
so I added language explicitly to
prevent that then although I'm told that
it's super early I
anyway already with all the restoration
templates for jana and then for the off
time i had an open issue so i'll hold on
that and then i had in initial note
which i was saying a number of existing
access tokens in production carry
information about whoever the user
authenticated directly with a physician
server or through an identity provider
and a field reference up but turns out
that if there was no interest from
anyone to actually make anything
normative in there so i just took it out
and then i had a note in there about
finding out whoever victorian is
actually a user token or an application
token and I have an opening from that
but for the time being I just took out
the note okay so here is a released all
the things that the gardener the most
interest and the most discussion but
didn't end up with a clear conclusion on
the list so I'm how big and we can use
this time to come to a conclusion so let
and it basically is a the thing about
distinguishing between subject type and
then some discussion about the affinity
of time behavior and then whoever to
recommend infected together encryption
or anything but to use symmetric keys
for signing or securing the access
tokens so let's look at the first one
thank you so here the idea is existing
access tokens in the market for various
vendors have mechanisms that are used
for the API to determine whoever this
token was issued for a resource owner or
for a or for an application as in does
the subject represent a user or an app
and it very is a variant which is a was
of a token obtained through a
confidential client or for a public line
what is a like let's simply find it just
look at users versus applications and a
very different ways in which people
achieve this like for it
identity server doesn't include a sub
claim when the token is issued through
client credential grant there was a
discussion released and the consensus
was mostly toward we must include if
it's like if we have a sub sub that has
to represent an entity but was
authenticated and in the case of a up
Israel so you've got to have sub in all
cases so we ended up saying about the
yeah we do need a 12-man so we cannot
use these mechanism backwards guys were
using for the third winning
whoever dave token is an up or not then
Carla from octa proposed maybe we can
have a claim a grantee type which
includes the grant that was used for
obtaining wins and the apology for jock
already has this claim but they're in
Veliz they were a number of voices
saying we shouldn't burn the burden the
resource server with knowledge about
this because it's an implementation
detail on the client and of a different
server so we basically excluded that
approach then there was a longer
discussion about whether we should
impose a but in the case of an up token
you just have the sub equal to the
client ID but Vento also doesn't work
well because a lot of current
implementations use different internal
mechanisms for generating client IDs and
the subjects in their own formats
subject can also be different depending
on the relying party
so the and also you don't want to allow
people to choose their own client ID
because especially for entity ends up
being a mess up for security reasons
that we heard during the meeting earlier
in a week and then finally there was
another proposal but we didn't really
vote on which was let's just have a
claim a new claim that states the
natural or the subject is in the service
and represents resource owner or a sub
represents a application so here
basically I'm asking you guys do you
have any idea for solving this for me
they are like I would love it whether
the last one let's say having a new
claim that expresses wins but I'm also
up
the outcome of this is complicated with
as bad implications and so let's not do
this at all and let's leave every vendor
to worry about this aspect in their own
and let's not have it in the intro
profile just richer so two things one if
you are letting your clients pick their
own client ID you're already opening
yourself to be yeah we said we don't
want to do it yeah yeah so that's where
most of the problem of this usually
comes in because if the AAS is
controlling the namespace of the clients
you can make sure that you know the
client ID looks like a client ID
whatever that's supposed to look like or
if you're letting your users pick you
know gooood x' as their username
something else is probably wrong the
other thing is that okay so I guess it's
three things because the other thing is
that in a deployment that I did we
played around with having the grant type
claim there and it really it wasn't very
helpful as it turned out so we we ended
up dropping that and just
differentiating based on the it's like
the subject and there's a client ID
claim that comes back from introspection
so if the subject and client ID are the
same then that signals that this is a
direct client token Justin do you want
elaborate on why you concluded that it
wasn't helpful basically we we figured
out that it was kind of a weird bit of
signaling of like how this token showed
up instead of like what this token was
and what it meant so it's it's basically
it's saying how somebody got this token
and not necessarily what this token
should be good for and who this token
represents and so it was I don't know it
was just kind of a weird mental jump I
mean it's it is a handy shortcut because
you're probably doing that the other
thing and this isn't something that we
ran into in production but the other
thing that we thought it was that
clients can use you know client
assertions
to get a token on their own
that's not client credentials grant type
and so it's not necessarily the right
signal it's kind of it's standing in for
something else which is that the subject
is the client ID and so that's that's
the logic that we went which I think is
the third yeah
the third option there finally Annabelle
has a draft for subject identifier is
that why you're here okay but we should
do that I think and fantastic Annabelle
thinks that's a bad idea
and it's her draft so she's probably the
expert but perhaps something like that
that that allows a little bit more
structured definition could be adopted
into this because that will what allow
us to have more than just a single claim
can you expand on what these draft
so this draft is in the second dense
group and it's for security event tokens
that basically says there is a an object
structure for different types of user
subjects so you can have more than just
a single subject string in the job but
it's all sort of collected into one sub
object so you can have an issue or an
subject field within that you can have
an email identifier a phone identifier
each of them with a type field as well
so is visa something that goes into a
value of a sub claim no no there it's
it's its own claim separate yeah and
there are rules about how it has to
relate to the subject claim and it's not
intended for use in this space but from
a distance there seems you know squint
right and they look close alright thank
you now I'll tell you why that's a bad
idea
Annabella Backman Amazon so I that idea
flashed through my head and the idea of
using subject identifier for this the
reason I think it's a bad idea is that
what that draft talks about is subject
identifiers and types of subject
identifiers so does not talk about types
subject so it's saying I am pointing to
some principle that is the subject and
I'm pointing to it using for example an
email address or a phone number or
theoretically a key pair or any number
of things that we might define down the
road it's entirely possible that we will
have subject identifier types that are
ambiguous as to if they could be handles
to a user they could be handles to an
app they could be handles to an
organizational entity any number of
things so I I would not it might be
interesting to look at that draft as you
mate maybe there's a parallel approach
to follow here
but I would not say throw subject
identifiers at this specifically alright
um now what I actually got up to up here
to say is two things I agree with not
using grant type in particular because
it is tightly coupling this concept to
specific protocol implementation details
and doesn't really make sense to tie
those together what what makes sense as
a mapping between those two which grant
types apply to which you know subject
types that mapping may change over time
it's going to get more complex as new
grant types are introduced as new
subject types are introduced it's
unstable and it would be really
burdensome to try and ask the resource
servers to all figure that out and
understand that if if you're having your
resource servers understand that then at
that point there's probably enough
coupling between your authorization
server and your resource server that you
don't need a standard way to do this
anyway I had a third point which
hopefully says how we do it yes no no
actually of course not that would be
easy I was wondering if you could
quickly summarize what the use cases are
that people are solving or trying to
solve by differentiating between
user and appetizer or what are the
surprises where they need some specific
mechanism to do that so I tried to tease
these out from any people aback we're
already doing these and these Kaiser was
mixed with a case in which the API wants
to know whether the client was a
confidential or not mostly because of
that gives more guarantees about better
client ID actually being a client and
the other case is for when they want one
particular client ID to be say the one
but actually they've the one here is the
only one that can call and there are
certain our physician servers that can
use the same client ID in a different
capacity you can have a client ID but
when you are using it from an iOS app is
just doing the public client flow with
code when you are using it on a server
side instead you can do the proper kind
of credentials okay that sounds like
it's less about user versus app and more
about how what are these circumstances
under which this client and byte by
client here I mean remote piece of code
that is calling me what are the
circumstances under which it's been
authenticated and what the circumstances
under which whatever user may be
interacting with it was authenticated by
me and I think that's very different
from user and applicator versus app as
two different subject types what I think
of is kind of three legged OAuth versus
two-legged OAuth like is there a user
involved in this relationship at all or
is this just a client calling on behalf
of itself so I really think you're
probably asking the wrong question here
so yeah and if you're just gonna go in
time check you have a few minutes over
so see wanna try to I think you have one
more point so you write yeah do I have
points but okay it's a good point thank
you thank you Justin richer what Annabel
just said and I have a concrete example
for that if people want to talk about it
with medical records so great just it
exists okay so on in the interest of
time for this point we'll go back to
release and I left week Lisa to be
rather than subject type determining
whoever the client was a confidential
gossip actually a vindication get ladder
to be okay I think Annabelle made a very
good point we need to rethink the
question here and maybe reach out to the
guys again I think that that was very
good insight great thank you
okay these are is another tough one the
idea is that when you use these access
tokens in for example a first party
scenario in which the access token is
way only artifact that you are sending
to API there are a number of the things
that you normally get in the ID token
such as the time at which you
authenticated and the type of
authentication that you use and similar
become important because you might have
policies that you want to enact on top
of these depending on what you receive
and so basically we need to take these
information and place it in the access
token as well and a lot of providers are
already doing this organically in the
wild of course we challenge what we have
in here is that the momentum of
education is not corresponding to what
to be a lifetime lifetime of a token so
basically here we are placing claims
whose value is determined elsewhere like
for example the moment in which you
sanidine
and you got your first batch of tokens
or if in the middle of a current session
you have to do a step-up authentication
and then we authenticate from time
changes and the method of authentication
changes when next time you use the
corresponding Refresh token we need to
reflect it into into a claim to the
token and here like they need from the
practical and business perspective it's
very clear let's say people already do
this so but at the same time when we
discussed these some people on the list
expressed unease so I just want to give
the opportunity to other people
that unease to bring their concerns and
if you have alternative solutions that
of course still deliver on the
requirement then this is your
opportunity apparent Campbell thing I
one of the doubters and I continue my
doubt but I accept that it's gonna be in
here because yeah requirements and
people are going in anyway but I get I
do get really nervous about what like
what you just said a step authentication
in a session after token was issued
should somehow be reflected in the auth
time of the next token on refresh that's
that sort of thing is is like drawing a
lot of links between things that aren't
really linked and I'd like to see it at
least clarified to this is this is the
auth time or the AMR whatever that was
used at the time of authentication that
the grant was approved or I don't know
the right language it's hard but
creating some sort of ephemeral and
imaginary link between an ongoing
session and however one might describe
that and issued access to friends off of
some other artifact the Refresh token I
think is it's super confusing and
potentially dangerous I agree it's
confusing for the dangerous I think we
should yeah
expand it I think about it we lever to
solve this problem somehow anyway
because I get to make another example
say that you have this access token tied
it to a session we were certain token
the Refresh token and the Refresh token
is a supporting rotation and save it
someone abuses the rotation and uses the
wrong token and have a right time and
now you have to gets a revoke all the
Refresh tokens and allegedly also the
access tokens that were issued as part
of that so you rarely ever that link is
just vector in this case you are you are
using that link to reflect potential
changes in the off time
but in the other case instead of you use
it for doing verification but the thing
is this link between session refresh
tokens and access tokens already exists
in various other aspects part of that is
when you say allegedly it doesn't exist
it's potentially some link that's done
at implementation time and and even if
it does exist it's super weird to have a
step-up authentication that happens in a
completely different context and have
access tokens reflecting that were
issued off of a different authentication
context reflecting that sort of in some
magical real time sorry guys yeah yeah I
need to cut the line here and you can
drop oh okay sorry if we are skipping
goes to the last point there so you
can't you can talk about this the last
point but I don't want it okay great so
fun Annabelle you're good to to come
soon
I just want to give an alternative view
of where that would be useful and that's
if you are doing an oauth2 authorization
request in a context where an earlier
say password-based authentication
happened but because of the nature of
the oauth2
authorization request you need to do
step up at that time then you're going
to have a case where your password based
authentication might have happened
yesterday but your step of your
two-factor whatever you're doing happens
now so having having those as two
different pieces of information could be
valuable having said that I think given
the ambiguity of the term step up and to
factor and all of that and the wide
variety of implementations I think it's
gonna be very hard to really formalize a
nomenclature for all the different
things we're gonna want to talk about
here so this may be a place where just
having the an opportunity for the
different vendors to plug in whatever
they need might be more useful
great tech for time reason not but I
think what I'll call this out
specifically Melissa there is a very
language image spec which is along those
lines so let's look at great just
perfect so Anna here I'll just present
basically we Ave at the very beginning
of a recommendation to use a symmetric
crypto for signing tokens because it's
just easier for people to have a fixed
sequence of stats for retrieving stuff
for metadata and similar I don't
suggested that we should actually
require it and I'm not against it but at
the same time I know that privacy
conscious people were pushing to also
include in their recommendation to use
authenticated encryption
the thing is reka indicating the
corruption today the only specs we have
all use symmetric kids and if that makes
me very uneasy because now I'm leaving
as exercise to the reader something
which is super important which is
acquiring their stuff you use for
tracking tokens and at the same time
like I saw basically here I wanted to
hear from you guys what that parent will
be run on yeah yeah I agree we're
another fan okay sorry thank great thank
you Thank You Aaron my chance jwe does
authenticated encryption but first by
using public key key derivation so the
symmetric key is a transient artifact
it's all doesn't done using public key
cryptography
okay this is gonna be a whirlwind I'm
Aaron Preki great look at that so if
you're who here has read this draft ever
curiosity this is a fun game to play
great okay a few of you so the summary
of this of this draft is that it is
recommendations for people who are
building browser-based apps or
JavaScript based apps or single page
apps whatever you want to call them that
are doing auth to in a browser which
typically means that that the browser
ends up holding the access token but
we'll get into some of that so that's
the sort of overall scope the read this
is sort of supposed to be the parallel
to the native apps best practices that
that we already have this is a summary
of what the document currently says some
of these points are currently up for
debate
so the recommendation for browser based
apps use auth code flow plus pixie do
not must not return access tokens in the
front channel which rules out the
implicit flow completely must use the
oauth2 state parameter for CSRF
protection it absolutely requires exact
redirect URI matching that's actually
changed from last last time we met and
there is a recommendation that access
authorization servers should not return
refresh tokens and that one is one of
the points we're going to talk about but
that is what we had currently discussed
before we started having discussions on
the list so some changes since the last
meaning exact redirect URI is new it
used to say same domain redirect URI
matching which yeah I did a whole
restructuring of the document to split
this into describing essentially three
architectural patterns for this kind of
app deployment and one is architecture
patterns is when your everything's on
the same domain the resource server the
client and the authorization server and
there was a bunch of clarifications and
typo fixes that a bunch of you help me
find so thanks for that
this is one of the architecture patterns
single page app with a back-end and in
this case this is this is one of the
things that I think we need to discuss a
little bit more about what we actually
want to recommend here the
recommendation here is basically that if
you if your single page app has a
back-end then you should actually do o
auth in the backend component and not do
OAuth in the in the JavaScript code at
all the question then becomes do we say
anything about whether or not the access
token should actually live in the
JavaScript app or if that should be
something that is not the access token
like an encrypted session cookie or some
other thing that's a point up for debate
this is one of the architectures one of
the other architectures is a single page
app without a back-end which i think is
probably actually a less common pattern
but it is still possible to do this and
plenty of people do have situations
where this is necessary and that is
where your JavaScript app is served from
a web host that doesn't have any dynamic
back-end itself and it talks then
directly to the resource server in
efficient servers and in this case the
browser app does in fact carry ahold the
access token it has to actually have
access to it and you can't do any cookie
level protections of it
so same doing applications this is one
of the ones that's gotten a lot of
discussion on the list which I think we
need to come to an agreement on what
exactly is the scope of this document
recommending here so same two main
applications what I mean by this is that
when everything is on the same domain or
sub domains so if everything is off of
example comm like resource server
example API two example com auth dot
example comm and app example com they
can all share cookies on example com so
you had end up actually not needing off
at all for one and if you do still want
to use OAuth there are ways to protect
it better than actually having the
access token end up in accessible from
JavaScript so right now the document
says maybe you should just avoid using
OAuth and do some
on your own maybe that's not the best
recommendation we should be making for
an OAuth spec but it does but but
actually using OAuth as written in this
situation is actually worse because
there are more holes that can open up
when you have this protection mechanism
that is already otherwise there so
that's a first point the redirect the
redirect step where everything's being
passed around over redirects is where a
lot of the flaws come from an OAuth or a
lot of the holes come from and you don't
actually need to do that if everything's
on the same domain but having a
separation between a s and RS and all
that is useful because it lets you
centralize your account management and
MFA and all that so there's a couple
different approaches we could do we go
here I guess we could say that the scope
of this document assumes that you're
going to be using OAuth already and we
ignore the case that you might not use
OAuth and only talk about how to do
OAuth in this case in which case what
exactly do we say about this case is
there anything unique about this case or
we try to say that there is a particular
recommendation for same domain
applications that maybe doesn't use
OAuth maybe uses OAuth in as a new way
so I'm curious about thoughts on this
bucket this is one of the three the
three architecture patterns which we
discussed in the last meeting and on the
lists and now we're kind of seeing that
some some questions around it I'm gonna
look forward really quick yeah okay
let's talk about this one and then I
have a bunch of other open questions
Justin richer yes this absolutely this
discussion absolutely needs to be in
scope because people coming in outside
of the auth working group are going to
be saying I have a browser-based app
I've heard of ooofff what do I do and if
I get to an official document that says
hey if your app looks like this don't
use OAuth I might actually do the right
thing and not use OAuth so I think it
would be a dangerous disservice to the
Internet if we remove this part of the
document that said we do have to be very
clear about
the boundaries around this which I think
we can continue to clean up the language
there was some discussion on the list in
the last couple of weeks about framing
this in terms of if your back end still
does oh off that's fine but that's
outside the scope of this document the
other part of this is that I know a lot
of developers will look at their SP a
with a back end and will see a back end
less SP a with an API that they're
calling even if it's on the same domain
and all of that other stuff conceptually
in a lot of cases the SP a developer and
the API developer are separated from
each other so they're seeing them as
decoupled services and therefore looking
at Oh F as the solution for doing that
so because this really addresses a
deployment pattern and not necessarily
an application type we have to be
careful with how we describe that so
that we are routing people to make the
right decisions I think that's
absolutely possible and absolutely
necessary that we keep this in this
document the audio of zero
I agree four hundred percent that we
needed to be giving guidance to people
they and if the guidance is for this
particular deployment don't use off use
these other mechanisms that what we
should say the thing right there I will
be careful about is helping people to
understand the implications of a choice
exactly this is something that I'm
trying to do on our cellular product but
the thing is if people do that and they
write our API with some meter world
which expects a cook as opposed to a
talker and then maybe take miss API and
expose it to other clients and now is
API is expecting the cookie than the
other clients will not be able to use or
even in the future they make
architectural changes and these
deployment no longer works people needed
to understand that they need to
backtrack from his approach and then use
the other one and then
if it's likely that their future looks
that way then perhaps they should use
off in this particular case because
otherwise we'll do their work twice so
long story short I think we should tell
people this is a simple and way of doing
this or might not be the right tool but
we also need to have them understand
what are the implications of an
architectural choice is moving forward
yep thanks on the mic sorry I wanted to
clarify it doesn't necessarily mean
backtracking from from there are
critical choices it might mean
augmenting them it is totally possible
that a API can accept a cookie or an
access token of protective there's like
but it might be hard repeat that though
sorry Pizza Pizza us
he said depending on the developer stock
which is fair but I actually came up
here to be jabbar scribe on behalf of
dr. Torsten ladder staff yes comm he
says I think same domain applications do
not belong into this BCP if you want to
describe that pattern write up another
ID we need to either describe it with
all the consequences including the
threat analysis and security recommend
recommend a shion's so okay so I'm
hearing a couple different things here
and possibly probably committing this
analyst but possibly one of the ways to
reconcile this is not calling it same
domain applications and instead trying
to find a pattern that describes this
architecture other than the fact they're
on the same domain because it's
that's not a distinction that Olof
normally makes so maybe that's not the
appropriate distinction to be making in
the spec but we need to find I think to
Justin's point we need to find a what
are people going to be looking for in
this document when they have the
situation we're trying to describe
what's what's their keywords they're
gonna be looking for and that way we can
still cover this content but maybe not
with the same caveats or same
distinctions which I think would also
address Hurston's point I think yeah we
probably have to discuss this a little
bit further but it sounded like very
different advice from different set of
yeah so we have to find out what that or
we have to find out what maturity at
least thinks which direction we should
go because I thought that was actually
quite good
in the sense that you are recommending
not to use ours but you're not saying
what what else they should be using so
in some sense we're not doing a straight
analysis for the other solution that may
not be an idea of topic at all I don't
know yeah that's also also a good point
if if we're gonna say don't do this we
should probably have somewhere else to
send people to tell them what to do okay
so it sounds like we're not gonna be
able to get through this one in any more
progress here so let's move on to the
next because I do have a bunch of other
do you have something else it's fine if
it's not in scope but I think there's a
real opportunity for sort of complicity
by omission if there's nothing no
mention of it in the document people
will come to it and assume that means
it's the right thing to do so I don't
know if it needs to be an architectural
pattern or even just description in out
of scope it doesn't mean this something
some mention of the possibility that
this is not the only way to do it I
think it is necessary in the document I
don't know how but in green with Justin
there okay thank you any other points on
this topic from people who I haven't
heard from yet no okay
so there's a handful of other open
questions what's the time check ten
minutes left
okay these are I think small issues but
these are all ones that we were not that
year there was some points on the list
that I went back and forth on we didn't
come to an agreement on yet so let's
just are the top state right now this
effect says use it for CSRF protection
even though it also says use pixie
security best practice says you can use
pixie force tape for CSRF protection so
those things don't quite match there are
some issues with the fact that the the
client doesn't know that a/s supports
pixie but in this spec the S has to
support pixie so the client should be
able to know do we actually want to
still say that state has to use for csr
protection or should I take that out
because theoretically is covered by
security BCP and using pixie any strong
opinions
if not we'll just skip it and deal with
it later I think so so we have very
carefully designed the language that we
have in the security BCPs or probably a
reference to that would be fine that
which means so you state you must also
use pixie if you're actually used pixie
you might want to drop state under some
circumstances oh that doesn't sound good
at all because right now it actually
says you must use state for CSRF
protection and I'll be rolling that back
into like and I don't think this is
special - okay really I think unless we
identify something that's really special
to the SPS yeah if there's nothing you
need to SP a situation then it is
probably better to not mention it yeah
from Jabra Phillips's leave it out or
rough BCP covers it okay um I'm gonna
come back to refresh tokens in a minute
pass for grant right now there is it
basically says you should use auth code
and pixie but if you really need to you
can use the password grant
can we just say you can't use the
password grant because I don't think
that's a good idea for anybody I'm
seeing a bunch of nods of yes let's kill
it
I'm a chopped Bradley yubico I'm in
favor of removing the password crap
because it's just great that also means
I can simplify I can make it a must use
auth code and pixie which clarifies
everything in the scope as well there's
a plus one from Torsten great okay
that's pretty that's pretty raising my
plus 1000 okay great
section nine point eight in the document
it this is I might just talk to Torsten
about this there there is a list of
security issues specifically with the
implicit flow a lot of these refer out
to the security BCP for the details and
there's just a summary of them there are
a couple in there that are I didn't see
in the security BCP that are unique to
the implicit flow and I put them in here
because people you're writing JavaScript
apps are coming out this with the
history of having used the implicit flow
and I wanted to specifically call out
like here's all the reasons not to do
that which is why you should be doing
this instead I think it was Torsen who
suggested just saying hey go read the
security BCP for this but I think it's
important to keep a reference to these
in this document because of the baggage
of because of the history just enricher
plus one we need to keep in mind what
people are going to be looking for and
what people are going to be using this
document for and that's more important
than our idealistic structure of
documents and information
okay my goal here is not to repeat not
to duplicate all the analysis and and
the the content insecurity BCP I would
but I do want to have a summary of when
there isn't overlap I want to summarize
it and then link out to it I think
that's I think that's safe and you still
refer to that yeah yeah refer normally
refer to the security BCP when it when
it mentions one of the points I'm trying
to make but I think people are gonna be
looking for it here instead okay for the
oh yeah this I kind of mentioned this
for the single page app with a back end
do we need an indication that the access
token may be sent to the browser and I
guess that would be an indication to the
resource server or authorization server
that this access token actually may end
up in a browser which is not a
confidential client which has a totally
different threat model than the
confidential client this is an
interesting one and there's no mention
of this right now in the document and I
don't actually know of anything else
that's sort of doing this the benefit to
this is that the a s would be able to
make better decisions about token
lifetimes and when every prompts rough
indication things like that as it is
right now if you write an OAuth app and
you just go and you get a client ID and
client secret and then just don't use
the secret the a s is gonna think that
it's a confidential client the S may
know that the grant happened without the
secret but there isn't really an
indication that whether that access
token is you know held tight or ends up
in a browser okay so I don't know what
the solution would be here we we need to
talk about what mechanism to actually
use for this but it wouldn't need to be
some sort of communication about the
access token or about the grant that
says the client is probably gonna give
this to a browser which is a much less
trusted environment does this sound like
something people would like to have a
mechanism for and then we figure out
what the mechanism is later some nods
some nods anybody really opposed to this
is anybody like think this is totally
pointless
not securing alright I just question do
you really need to send access to a
computer browser well this kind of use
case that is a good question in it makes
some deployments easier because you can
avoid having a separate session with the
server um we could also say don't do
that and like force you to require to
send it to make a session but then that
does is like limit your architecture a
little bit it requires you to do
something else I wouldn't be opposed to
making that a requirement for this
architecture though because it does
clean it up
Anabelle back in an Amazon um else I
think there are use cases or access
tokens and other kinds of credentials
being sent down to the browser and use
directly from there tonight can I enter
that it does it does it is the
particular case of there is a back-end
that's gonna be proxying API calls so
this is this is this particular case for
the case where the total yes in the case
where the the access token is actually
being acquired by a back-end but is yeah
there's there's communities for
acquiring it on the back end and then
supplying it to the front-end for use
from there they're what actually add up
to here to say is that I'm not strongly
opposed to a signal that this token is
going to be sent to the browser but I
think we have to be realistic about the
fact that we're handing access tokens to
a client and oftentimes we don't know
what the hell they're doing with them so
I be cautious about creating a false
sense of confidence in the client
behavior by including something like
this it's ultimately kind of opt-in on
the part of the client anyway and if you
are being really sophisticated you can
probably detect things like this without
an overt signal okay
jabber on jabber on behalf of Torsten he
says I don't believe this is a good idea
without Sundra constraining which I
think makes it really hard but um in a
Brian here on my own behalf I I think I
kind of agree with that about it I feel
like trying to build explicit signals
here is a super slippery slope that gets
hard like we're gonna have a I mean this
is one specific instance but it's like
you you want some kind of signal here
for a client to tell you just how
promiscuous they're gonna be with the
access token it's like I it feels really
yeah okay okay not good to me it's like
you know I don't know when I set my
password with a provider they don't ask
me are you gonna share this with
somebody else and make different
decisions about rotation policy based on
my bad decisions or my my signalling
intent about my bad decisions it's
that's a fair point right nothing that
it's gonna happen it's like everything's
on a protector it might be a good idea
but yeah victory of zero I think we have
a argument about there we can't protect
everyone in every situation doesn't mean
that we shouldn't when we already have
some knowledge of a topology in this
particular topology we know what's going
to happen because we are telling the
implementer how we want them to behave
and at that point they're given what we
said earlier about the scenario in which
the resource owner the source server
wants to know whether we are being
called by a confidential client or not
in this case it seems that having
something that helps we're positioned
server at least to avoid whatever would
be used for signaling this was a secure
client is should be a must
let's say that I wouldn't feel
comfortable with recommending people to
do this without also telling them here
is a way of somewhat defusing their
potential power or this socket and then
it's true where people can take your
talk as simplicity and a public folder
Google Drive and you cannot prevent that
in this particular case I think what
that we very least even if we don't make
a mechanism even if we don't invent a
parameter we should put in the notes if
there is any way for you to tell that
the authorization server a particular
physicians have an implementation that's
your intent then you should make it
manifest okay and Annabel Backman Amazon
I think we should think about what the
alternatives are here for the from a
topological standpoint if I'm a client
and I'm passing an access token down to
the browser so the browser can make
calls directly the alternative topology
there is presumably be the browser
client making a call up to my end point
and I'm resolving some kind of session
token' or something in the cookie to
look up an access token and a database
in my side in which case I'm already
dependent on something in the browser
like it made it may or may not be
exposed to JavaScript
once again my access token going to the
browser or what does that mean does that
mean I'm giving it to JavaScript does
that mean I'm putting in a cookie that
you'd have to distinguish that but my
point is that we already have to think
about the downstream effects of the
clients decision of how to how to
authenticate their own and how to secure
their own
kinnor actions with the with the browser
client that impacts us whether the
access token is stored in the client or
in the browser or in this on the server
side you can kind of cut line after
Brian it's actually about four Torsten
again be a jobber why using a back-end
if in the end you send the eighty to the
browser so that is a fair question some
people do it is the answer
reasons is the answer and ITP
okay I think I'm out of time but there's
this whole whole topic which we
unfortunately now will have a lot of
discussion time for visit but the topic
is refresh tokens
in single-page apps there was a lot of
good accession discussion on the list
reasons that it's a good idea and also
reasons it's a bad idea and I'm not
seeing a lot of ways to reconcile this
guidance right now the the document says
you should not include ascend refresh
tokens to browsers that feels like not
enough of a guidance for the situation
there are a lot of reasons the good idea
reasons is the idea so some ways to
resolve this situation we could say
there should be no bearer refresh token
so it requires some sort of proof of
possession which is sort of undefined in
this situation right now we could
require that refresh tokens have a
limited lifetime and that would either
either time based or based on
authentication session we could leave
that part up to people but requiring
that they have a limited lifetime would
I think helps some of the concerns
people have with issuing refresh tokens
to the browser requiring that they
rotate is probably good idea it's also
mention about security BCP I feel like
that's worth again calling out here and
saying go look at the security BCP for
the details if they are rotated should
the new one get the new lifetime again
or keep the same total lifetime of of
the initial refresh token because if
they extend out the the lifetime then
it's essentially an infinitely long
Refresh token which was one of the
concerns about browser apps or do we
just take out any mention of refresh
tokens from this document because there
isn't an agreement and you are just
gonna go and figure out figure out on
your own anyway so that's the list of
potential decisions that came up with
based on the discussions I don't know
what the right answer is I feel like not
mentioning it as bad I'm kind of leaning
towards definitely requiring rotation
and not like having to extend a lifetime
and making sure that's clear because
that helps eliminate some of the attacks
people were describing I don't want to
not require bearer tokens big bear
refresh tokens because there isn't
really
solution for that right now so it
doesn't feel practical I go ahead okay
but right last comment yeah go ahead cut
the mic spa's need a way to get fresh
access tokens or access tokens for
another RS with using resource
indicators without refreshed hook and
what's a reliable way to get those
iframes rely on third-party cookie
access which is in the crosshairs of
pretty much every browser vendor
nowadays constantly redirecting blows
you act so no so does pop up since it
requires in user interaction either we
put forth restrictions on the ass and
client to be able to get refresh tokens
eg using pop Center constrained rotating
on every use something else or get
searching for a completely new mechanism
oh Jesus
we need sorry apologies no need to proxy
Brian Aaron is on the same I'm glad you
got city okay well that was the fun
that's a fun discussion I guess we'll do
with that one is I will actually put the
other little proposal on make a new
thread on the list we can talk about
that again there and keep it going so
thank you very much hello Dan is that
from Liscomb I'd like to present two
things today the first thing is the
earth to zero demonstration of proof of
precession at the application layer or D
pop shot
what do we want to solve for the
solution as you might know the or
security PCP and we've just also seen
the SP a BCP makes yeah good points of
using similar constraint tokens but
currently we do not have suitable
mechanisms for sender constraints
constraint oaken's for SP ace and
probably also some other requirements in
areas we have MPLS which is good
you cannot really use that in browser
and we also token binding with the lack
of browser support and the future is
pretty unclear of that therefore in
Stuttgart at the last world security
workshop we started drafting a solution
on the application layer and I think
Brian came up also with a name for that
that's on the bottom right corner
he sought an es fan yeah that's our
Deepak came to be what we want to do the
main goal of deep pop is to prevent
token replay at a different endpoint
more precisely if an adversary is able
to get hold of an access token or
refresh token because the adversary
setup a counterfeit authorization server
or a resource server then the adversary
should not be able to replay that token
at a different endpoint authorization or
resource server so that's the main goal
of Depot as I already said we started
discussing discussions in March I
created the first draft in product
during the last ITF meeting and now we
are at version zero two and this is what
the current proposal looks like we have
the client on the left and we're in the
client sense the token request to das
then the client attaches a deeper proof
what that looks like we see in a moment
and then the client gets back if the AI
supports D pop a an access token that is
deeper bound this is signaled by the
token type D pop and also refresh tokens
for public lines at least that our two
bound to that deeper key n on when the
client wants to use an access token for
example then it also has attached a
deeper proof to that one and it's not
worth a that we use the same proof
structure the date token structures or
two
say in the token request and in the exit
when the access token or Refresh token
say used it's this okay this is what ad
prop proof looks like in a header you
can see that we have a type of epub plus
JWT and we have a public key and in the
body of the JWT we have things such as a
token ID we have the HTTP method of the
HTTP request to which the token is
attached we have the HTTP URI and we
have a timestamp and all of this is of
course signed with the private key that
belongs to the public key in the header
in the token request the depop token is
added to a new HTTP header called depop
and when as I already said so this is
additional to all the stuff that we
already have in the token request which
is completely unchanged if the a has
supports
depop then the AAS will send back the
access token with token type deeper
otherwise if it doesn't support deeper
then everything will go as normal and
the client will see that the AAS does
not support deeper now the resource
access in the resource access there is
an authorization header as before but
the token type is not Vera that is depop
therefore the header is depop and then
the access token and there's a deep
opera as before with the deeper proof
belonging to the resource axis in the
introspection response or if you have
agile UT access token there's a CNF
claim signaling that the access token is
bound to some key and in the CNF claim
there so Jake 80s to five six claim
which is the basics before URL encoding
of the JW key
2:56 thumbprint of the public key to
which the token is bound that is the
resource other can check that a deeper
proof was presented for that access
token regarding the security of PC of
the pop
we have server features that prevent
token replay we have the jei the token
ID and IIT the time stamp which together
can be used to to maintain a list of
tokens that have been seen and that
would in theory be still valid we also
have HTTP URI and HTTP method which bind
this token to the access or through
there to the request status make to
prevent a swapping of Depot tokens Depot
proofs with other JW teas that are
traded somewhere we also have a tad
claim which has the unique value that
must be checked
we don't allow the signature algorithm
um and regarding message integrity which
is not guaranteed by the prop as you can
see there is no signature about the
message buddy
of course you have the transport layer
of course use enter and TLS if possible
but really if you want to prevent that a
token resource endpoint that is
manipulated or that is malicious
uses the token at the same URI at the
honest endpoint then you can or with
changing the request body then you can
also bring your own data and sign it in
the Deepak token so it's extendable if
you really want to do that but it's
definitely out of the scope of this
specification M TLS is a more rather
robust mechanism if possible use M TLS
but as I already said in some situations
is it's just not possible okay
Honus yeah speaking as as myself here we
have it
team working group items that pretty
much do the same stuff they don't have
this shiny named of um and I was
wondering on whether you had sort of
like considered that work because one
part of the work is is actually split
into documents one part is the key
transport which we talked about last
time where it was made his comment about
do we need to add a proof there and
which was followed up with this formal
analysis and then we have the second
piece of work which Justin was asked or
is be heading the assigning which of
course has the very same does mean a
more or less the same stuff in a you
know in we have different incarnation
incarnations because there were issues
challenges I think that's yet to say
request signing had always had some
challenges in this group so I'm curious
on why what motivated you to come up
with a completely new mechanism instead
of just reusing what you already hadn't
had to sort of get that finalized so I
think others here my chimed in on that
because they're more familiar with the
other drafts I can say that depop is a
very simple very concise mechanism that
is we also have already some working
implementations of that because it
doesn't actually it actually does less
like from a functionality point of view
and what we previously did with the ACE
working group we tried to as you
remember we tried to balance this work
with ace and RTC web because they needed
the approved possession mechanism and
they also encoded the fields in co-op
and we had the corresponding but in HTTP
because we said that we would do the
HTTP stuff here the core there is
working group does the court stuff there
so there was kind of a understanding and
so now we I'm feeling we're doing the
same thing twice even like you had in
earlier slides you have this you call it
a deep op pro possession
I forgot what the name was in the other
case because it was also finding the key
to the token so yep well maybe correct
okay so not so camera alright so oh you
know kind of wondering the the
graduation ship of this draft to the key
distribution draft which is and and then
also there's a draft that I wrote a
while ago which is called j-pop of which
a part of the spec was actually taken
out to become an TLS but this one is
looks like trying to do more that's the
same thing except that this can only be
used for code for Wow in that case
because we arrived Jpop is wrong on key
description we can actually be useful it
was the first oh yeah Brian try to put
some color on on the origins and some
new history here to it but these not
address but talk to honest questions a
default came out of I think a desire and
a real need from developers using this
stuff for a simplified concise mechanism
to do public key proof of possession for
an access token both at the
authorization server and the resource
server and while it bears a lot of
similarity to some other things that are
in progress it it it does I think it
does more with less its it delivers that
public key proof and for both the the
delivery and binding the access tokens
with the authorization server as well as
using them at the resource server so
it's it has a lot of conceptual
similarities but I think it's it's
significantly simpler has a more
straightforward model and is
much more concise me I asked you on
explaining me where it is simpler for
the two interfaces for the interface
from the client or authorization
Southwest more simplicity in their
tedious in its both in the well in in my
view it's simpler in the key
distribution because there's there's not
the overhead of the potential of
symmetric keys the key distribution
itself works the same way for both
presentation that are us and they ask
it's it's the authors it's the client
saying here's my key
here's proof of it this is what I want
to use and it's I imagine it's super
simple for more information
implementation is quite a symmetric keys
because because we worked with these
other groups that asked for symmetric
keys and they have isometric Easterday
that's why it's in there because because
we had to align with these other groups
so I think you're giving that sort of a
natural tension here that that you're
working with those other groups and
they've taken on a lot of time just me
it's like but despite the there's work
here that's bits aimed at deployment and
use in the wild and I know there's other
groups that's building on top of all off
but this is specifically geared at
deployment and usage and the possession
distribution stuff has taken on a role
of being an underpinning for additional
work within aids I guess I guess other
working on how to wear on RTC web so I
there's some tension there but this was
maybe an end-around from that work
because it has a more explicit and
straightforward goal including not
symmetric keys because there's no
mechanism for proof of symmetric keys
and trying to account for that
significantly complicates things as
you're probably we're trying to have
written it in in the document
I mean I frankly I've wondered at times
whether the the pop t-distribution
document shouldn't actually we had that
discussion and this group decided that
it wants it has to be here because it's
the HTTP but so on that topic of
symmetric I will say I was going to
actually ask the question of why the
specs specifically limits this to ace
use of asymmetric signature algorithms
we found that there are use cases where
asymmetric signatures are still just too
slow the idea was to make this as simple
as possible okay so I guess a question
none for the working group is is there a
significant enough win in terms of
simplification to warrant having a
mechanism for proof of possession that
is specific to asymmetric signatures or
does the proliferation of pop methods
outweigh the that that simplicity gain
the other comment I have on this is the
draft mentions being able to bring your
own data piece but it doesn't really get
into exactly how that would fit into it
the the the job it doesn't provide any
likes like III would expect to see at
least some claims defined for the
typical things somebody is going to want
to sign like a request body or headers
or
yeah yeah so maybe we can draw from out
get to some of why that is important in
my talk yeah okay good so the origin of
this came to security I'm gonna cut the
line sorry I'm gonna cut the line no
John Bradley yubico so the origin of
this came from the security workshop
where we're specifically focusing on
what could we do for single page
applications to do proof of possession
should token binding not come to
fruition so we set out we said okay we
could use web crypto and create an onyx
portable key in the browser and these
would be the mechanisms they that we
could do it so that's why is there no
symmetric keys because there is no way
of protecting a symmetric key in the
browser and being able to do proof of
possession so this describes how we can
address that particular use case if the
working this lays out a way to do it if
the working group wants us to refactor
yes we did take the ideas of Justin's
draft which is not currently active and
but I believe it's expired
so so okay so it's expired for reasons
so it is entirely possible to profile
should we reconstitute that document we
could profile that document this is what
we specified is a subset of that
document and arguably the way that we're
publishing the key to the authorization
server at the at the endpoint is a
subset of key distribution but we're not
distributing a key we're using a very
small set of that so could we do this as
profiles of those documents should those
documents actually be active sure but
this is essentially our core use case
document if you want us to refactor it
to
use other specs okay but those other
specs have to actually exist didn't be
making progress but this is a concrete
use case of people something that people
actually want to do to bind tokens as we
talked about in Aaron's presentation
there is no way
currently for you to actually do group
uh possession of the Refresh token in
the browser should somebody use this
mechanism they can't actually protect
the Refresh token in the browser
so this is a real use case there is I
think we need to actually address the
use case if we want to address it in the
very narrow sense and yes we took out
all of the other stuff that addresses a
bunch of other use cases so that we
could actually focus on what's the
minimum that we need to do this we want
to refactor this to point to the other
specs I'm perfectly okay with doing that
we're not saying that the other specs
don't have value but we needed to focus
in on what is this use case how can we
we solve it exactly how we format the
spec I'm completely okay II plus one
Mike Jones Microsoft I'm actually
representing right now our engineering
teams who did a detailed analysis of
whether and how they would use the spec
and there were three sets of comments
they had one was they want to use
different pop keys for access tokens and
refresh tokens it's my belief doing a
cursory analysis that they could just
use different keys in the request and
have that work and the keys are not just
maintained as state between different
requests off the top of your head am i
right yep I think some could be okay
think about that but I think I was right
when I told them that second they were a
little bit surprised by the tokens
issued being bearer tokens and then
there's secondly being a perv
that's distinct from the token which
it's up to the recipient to check the
proof using information in the bearer
token that it actually is attested to
you now I understand the reasons for
that that all of that you could by
adding this proof header continue
sending the access tokens using 6750
using authorization bearer token and
resources that don't understand that
there's also prevents nothing that's not
how it's currently in the traffic so
currently we're using the yeah so we're
using the okay educate the D pop this is
the this is how we do resource access
currently and as you can see it's not a
better talker because it's not so it
says D pop and then you provide the
header okay they would actually be happy
with that because they don't want to
just add information to that existing
there because some resources would break
even though they're not supposed to yeah
thank you I will report that back to
them there and the third thing which I
failed an issue on several months ago is
despite some of the sentiments in the
working group for years we're going to
continue using the implicit flow and
that's not up for negotiation so they
want a description of how to use deep up
with the implicit flow if they're going
to use it at all
so that could either happen in this
draft or I could create a separate draft
but if we're going to use d pop but
Microsoft there must be an implicit
binding so I think this is something we
should talk about after way if they're
working group decides to adopt this item
to to discuss
what the working group thinks about this
that's fine but I'd also like to talk to
you and some of the authors about what
technically you think that binding
should look like and I want to get it
written down and it's a working of
decision whether to adopt that piece of
it or not but I have a mandate from my
employer to create it either in this
draft or as a separate draft if we're
ever going to use any of this yeah and I
just wanted to put that on the record
okay Brian off mic said he would be
happy to see it in a separate draft and
would work on it with me Thank You
Justin Richard to that last point I
would be unhappy to see it in the same
draft so plus one to Brian's point so
all right since my name was tossed
around a bunch I figure I should get in
the mic line having tried to spec out
HTTP signing and implemented a number of
different signature methods I think one
of which we're gonna hear about later
it's really hard it's really really
surprisingly hard
I'm with Annabel that there should be a
few additional fields but I mean that's
it you have a structure we can add that
we can specify that that's great
signing headers and signing body very
important in other types of requests
yeah yeah totally I really like this
approach I agree with pennis in
principle that having a server provided
key to enable symmetrical keys and stuff
like that helps a lot of different use
cases embedded use cases especially
because of key generation costs but
other use cases potentially as well and
even having the server generate a an
asymmetrical key pair makes sense I know
but it makes them deep hug does not have
that functionality I know how does can I
finish my sentence none of the documents
has
the capability to service I generate
asymmetric keeping I thought that pop
distribution allowed that okay well
that's a gap in pop distribution in that
style
so anyway ultimately if this is
cryptographically agile enough I think
those are details that will fall out the
mode of the client presenting and
proving possession of that's an
important part proving possession of the
key that it is saying I'm going to use
is a really really important pattern and
that actually solves the security use
cases for the majority of ways that we
want this thing to get used because if
the server provides a key the client
hasn't proved yet that it can actually
use that key to do anything so I like
this pattern so much that I also
invented it because this is how
currently key proofing in possession
works inside of X Y Z so it's the same
kinds of structures and yes before
Hannes asked I was aware of my other
draft for HTTP signing so and I
purposefully didn't use it for this
because that is a really complicated
thing and there really has not been
enough energy in the working group to
move that forward possibly because we
have cabbage signatures we have a bunch
of other things that have been making
progress that people could use instead
ultimately I don't care where that draft
lives if we were to take all of the
proofing stuff in here and paste it into
the HTTP signatures draft and call that
the new version fine you know like
whatever if and I think that we might be
able to do that if we extend a couple of
fields with some normalization rules you
know that's all doable so yeah at the
end of the day message signing and four
key possession is something that we need
something that we have needed for many
years but we haven't solved yet because
it is really really really hard and we
getting stuck on little bits and details
instead of just trying to do something
howdy roomie didn't you is the
responsibility taking new technical
position on what we just kind of talked
about here that's for the working group
to talk about what I would strongly urge
before we talk about we're group
adoption we make sure that we better
understand the equities of perhaps other
working groups put them on the table I
actually don't know all those equities
are we sure check and make sure we
surface them as we reason about what to
do here and ditto I heard that again
this is kind of my first real meeting
with this working group you know as we
talked about past decisions the fact
that we don't remember what we decided
and that's kind of coming with your same
vacuity and that let's just kind of
surface that as we figure out what you
know with the scope of it and boxes of
some of these drafts and so what let's
again surface what the equities might be
in the other words - okay thank you
yeah that's good - Mary so I wouldn't
I'm gonna be able to adopt this document
at this time so over here take it
offline okay just go ahead okay yes okay
my next presentation is about this it's
not right no it's not yeah that works
okay my next presentation is about push
request objects and the aim here is to
find out whether there's interested in
this working group to go forward with
developing something in the IGF what
approach to request objects you might
know that there's the JA draft that
moves request object management to the a
s so this is an extension that would
move the request object management to
the a s as I already said this was
developed in the open IDF RP area based
on experience gathered in open banking /
BST -
context what is the rationale here as
you might know in JA we have a mechanism
that ensures the integrity authenticity
confidentiality of the authorization
request by essentially signing all that
stuff or whatever and the problem is if
you put the signed draught for example
in a you know authorization request by
value you would put it in a request
parameter you end up with very lengthy
URLs there might be a lot of scopes in
them for example and the job itself is
very long if your effort so there's a
method to to transport it by reference
called the request your eye where you
put the shot somewhere on some URI and
then in the authorization request you
have the parameter called
request your eye that refers to that
your eye so the a s goes to that your
eye and takes the job from there problem
with that is the client if it puts it on
its own server needs to handle inbound
requests from the a s which is a new
thing the client needs to store a
potential large number of objects and
also handle cleanup for them
there's might be delays in the
authorization if you have problems with
latency or if the request URI is not
available and the a s also has to make
outbound HTTP requests that is you enter
the whole domain of service site request
forgery problems which are a lot met
there are some input from you so just
clarification the jaw graft actually
doesn't quiet clients to store no it
does not the jaw draft says put it
somewhere can be on the client can be on
the a s can be somewhere else and at
least open how to
how to do that yeah that's right so this
this this is kind of left open in the
draft so the post request object is
essentially a description on how to do
that the idea is to move the staff to
the air so the responsibility for
managing these request objects by
creating a new request object endpoint
so the client calls this endpoint
delivers the request objects say with a
post request the client is then provided
a unique your I to that request the
contents there and this is then used as
the request your ID parameter
essentially the jar draft already
foresees exactly that I think there's a
sentence somehow outlining this idea but
this makes it more concrete
there could be two modes the reakless
object could be stored as a job if you
need the features like signing
encryption whatever or it could be a raw
request object just in JSON format to
keep it more simple this would look like
this this is the post request to create
the resource up they request object so
you would send a post request and in a
post request you will have a jason with
all the parameters that you otherwise
would find in the authorization request
you could also have this as a dot then
you just post the draw it somewhere in
the response you get a request your I
containing enough entropy sir that it's
unguessable by somebody else and then
when you send your authorization request
all you need to send is one single
parameter request URI containing
whatever you receive before you request
URI that is the mechanism as I already
said it has some advantages there's no
reakless object management on the client
itself deployments can choose from these
two options to have a JSON or jot
we can have client authentication at the
endpoint where the request object is
posted so you can refuse unauthorized
clients very early in the process and
also you can have patterns where the
authorization process itself relies on
the identity of the client because you
know her essentially proving the
identity of the client and also because
we now have the option to transport very
large authorization request requests
this is also a good foundation to convey
something like rich authorization
requests aka structured scopes where you
put a lot of information in them sorry
are not limited for example by the size
of the URI while still having a defined
implementation pattern so the question
is what are your opinions shall we bring
this to the ITF or rather not correct
hierarchy um I I think all these are
very good points this makes a lot of
sense I just wanted to point out that
this is almost exactly what I
implemented when Justin first are
talking about XYZ last year the initial
thoughts behind that I I did almost
exactly this just as a plain object not
with a non wrapped in the job and it was
super easy to add to an existing OAuth
server that I had and I made a lot of
sense so I just wanna throw out there
thank you john bradley yubico one of the
jar authors so jar has been in flight
for a while perhaps too long as it
closes in on completion again shortly we
prop you know things have developed over
time and this pattern has become clearer
and clearer as being preferable we left
it open jar open to this pattern but
didn't include a whole bunch of new text
you know have we had the timing been
different this might have gone into jar
but we don't necessarily want to reopen
and extend those people are
some people are counting on jar
finishing so that for some of the
payment stuff we don't necessarily want
to delay that so doing this as a
separate draft make sense will probably
debate whether or not the raw format or
an unsigned joj is preferable so there
are a few details that in it that I that
probably merit discussion but yeah as an
elaboration of jar this is probably
should happen so that we have a
consistent way of not doing it and as I
say we would have done it in jarhead
timing potentially been different yep
Annabel Backman Amazon so I want to
point out that this is very similar to
what the device authorization draft
defines in terms of we're pushing a
request up to the and endpoint on the a
s we're getting a URL back and then
we're opening that up or were in this
case you're adding that to an author an
authorization request but ultimately
you're getting a URL and you're you're
opening it up the only real difference
is the if the other direction how the
response then gets back to the client so
so it seems a little bit weird to me for
us to standardize two different methods
to do very potentially three different
methods to do this same address the same
challenge of how do I securely make this
request to the AAS at I know device
authorization is very far along in the
process and I don't necessarily want to
say we should derail that but maybe we
should be we should look at the fact
that we're treating both sides of this
transaction they get to the a s and get
back as if they're intrinsically linked
as if the mechanisms by which that
happens are intrinsically linked and
maybe we should be coupled those and
look at standardizing those separately
gonna cut the mic after that thank you
for that introduction a development
Jessamyn richer so you know obviously
this once again this pattern shares a
lot with X Y Z because I stole all the
best ideas from everybody and puts in
one thing I mean a lot of the motivation
was noticing that there was a lot of
overlap between things like the device
flow and request object registration but
I actually went to try to do the
exercise of collapsing those two within
ooofff - you really can't do it it it
there there are bits and assumptions
made on both sides that it's if we were
to try to like twist this into device
flow or make device flow like that it
would break the models for both of them
right so unfortunately I think that if
we do want to bring this in as an OAuth
2 extension it does need to be its own
thing and that is a shame but to me that
is also motivation for next generation
protocol that doesn't have those same
assumptions that can actually split you
know how you get the user there and how
you get the user back which is exactly
the structure that XYZ has I mean this
this is the world that this that that
project came out of right and that's
said I've implemented this I do think it
makes a lot of sense it does solve some
key use cases it's being very very
similar things are being used today in
the financial space some of the
proprietary some of them sort of pseudo
proprietary cabal's and so having a
standardized way to do this I think is a
really good idea there is an open issue
about the about the request format which
I have some strong opinions on and maybe
some sad acquiescence about where it's
probably going to go after talking with
Brian but you know if we bring this into
the IETF that will all obviously need to
be aligned I think we should bring it in
I think it fits under the group's
umbrella and you know just to reiterate
I think this is more motivation for
working on a new protocol that also does
this stuff but in a cleaner and better
kind of way without all of the legacy
baggage that this of necessity has to
deal with so just a couple of
clarification game this has rated the
scope of this document they're sending
the request URI to the authorization so
what actually is covered by char so it's
out of scope this document there then
it's called the the scope this document
I think should be just pushing the
request object to the the authorization
server and just getting back a response
which includes there because your
repeater so small concise look yeah yeah
yeah you know I just wanted to make sure
that people understand yeah okay good so
on so how many people read the draft
show for hands please okay we want to so
it's their interest group to go into
that yeah it's not about process
specific structures so for all the
whispering for kind of everyone else I
mean the specific thing is we're talking
about a clarify Burundian we're speaking
about is this the idea we want to bring
in we're not talking about a specific
document might as the documents that say
the okay except history yeah okay so I'm
gonna then call for a hum here and see
get the feeling of the room okay
good sorry I really dude I just want to
clarify the hub is that we think we want
to bring the idea into discussion
exactly correct yes right as an
organization thing I was confused
whether the document is an ID or not no
it's not
in some sense we can't really Humbert as
someone is going to write up an
individual document to bring it to the
group I think what what we've seen on
the microphone is a couple of papers
saying or that sounds like a good idea
so Romi genius we can get again to
clarify the hum we're about to do is
that someone that participates in the
IETF community has an idea and would
like feedback from the community in a
very concrete way that he should he and
his team should work a lot harder and
bring something to the ITF which then
we'll decide further again if there's a
draft except that you actually check
charter scope and the rest of it exactly
yeah so that long freeze is the aam okay
if you are I guess you've heard the
request here so so I'm gonna ask you to
harm to support this or not so if you
support this bringing this work to the
IDF please hum now if you're against
bringing this work to the IDF please hum
now perfect thank you thank you I've
heard almost everyone how many or
everyone humming in the direction of to
bring this to the IGF which is a
non-binding yeah every way but that is
your feedback thank you thank you
aníbal
so this is gonna be interesting so just
looked in like half my slides are
missing so that's cool so I'll kind of
wing part of this that's okay so um what
I want to talk to you all about is how
we do HTTP requests signing in AWS using
a format that we call signature version
four guess why so in brief quickly up
why and what is this all about there's
three specific things we're looking for
the three specific things that we get
out of request signing in AWS first is
authentication of the the client that's
making the request second we do it for
message integrity which means we're
actually signing a significant amount of
significant number of the different
parts of the request as you'll see and
then we have some element of replay
prevention that we get out of this as
well
virtually all requests to AWS api's are
signed using signature version 4 there's
a few exceptions like anonymous request
to s3 but for the most part if you're
using AWS your you're signing things
using this algorithm as far as what goes
into these signatures like I said we're
doing it for message integrity which
means we're hitting a lot of different
parts of the request method endpoint
path time stamp query string parameters
body and some of the headers and I'll
show you how some of that works in a
moment and then we're we're using H Mac
sha-256 with a key that is derived from
a shared secret to do that which is why
I was asking about symmetric versus
asymmetric earlier so there's three two
we will walk you through what this
signature version four algorithm looks
like there's three basic steps we have
to canonicalize a request we then use
that to construct a string that we're
going to sign and then we sign that
string and stick that in the HTTP
request I'm going to go through this
part a little bit
quickly because if you really really
want to see it you can go check it out
on the public documentation but just to
give you an idea of what we're talking
about I'm gonna go through this so so to
start with let's talk about how we
canonicalize this thing the top there
I've got kind of an example HTTP
requests to a example service at the
bottom is the format of kind of what
goes into this canonicalized version of
the request like I said we have the
request method we have a
canonicalization the docs call it a
canonical URI what it really is is a
canonical version of the past component
of the URL that you're heading and then
we have a canonicalized query string and
canonicalized headers and lists of the
headers that you are actually signing
and then we also include a hash of the
request payload in that so we just kind
of walk through this make it clear we
start with the method then we
canonicalize the path by we provide some
pretty specific instructions on how you
can analyze that we do reference some
RFC's for that
likewise for query string we reference
some rfcs we also have specifics like
you're gonna sort them by by parameter
name then by value etc headers it's a
very similar sort of thing and then I'll
tell you that's a hash of a payload and
you'll believe me so that that's that's
canonicalization of the of the request
next step is we take that and put it
into you a string to actually sign and I
think I actually skipped a step
my example there but that's okay oh no I
didn't okay so the the actual string
design has a few different components
first we say we specify the exact
algorithm we're using in this case it's
this tag AWS for H max sha-256 all sig
v4 uses that but it could change we put
in a timestamp for when we're making the
request we put in this thing we call a
credential scope which relates to how we
derive the key that we're going to use
to sign this when we derived that key we
bind it to the day the region your
communicator but yes region you're
communicating with and the AWS service
you're communicating with and then
there's finally that the hash of the
canonical request we just created so you
create that and you sign it with a
derived key as I said the derived key we
generated using date region and service
it's basically a series of chained H max
starting with a secret key that both you
and AWS know mm-hmm you like I said do a
bunch of trying to change H max you
generate this key and then you sign your
string to sign and you have a signature
and then you stuff that generally into a
header in your HTTP request and you're
good to go and that's the end of what my
actual slides contain whoops now let's
talk about why we do some of this stuff
and some of the lessons we learned I
want to start with this so minutes three
minutes cool all right let's go quickly
then to start with some obvious stuff
crypto agility it's good it's important
that's one of the reasons we're on v4
and not v1 because we had to add that so
that H max shot 256 bit bear and that's
important another thing we ran into over
the years protocol agility we started
out with a protocol that was very query
string oriented and so we were just kind
of signing query string parameters over
time that changed we needed to put stuff
in the body we need to put stuff in
headers etc etc we need
to extend the format to enable us to
sign more of the HTTP requests in as a
whole because different protocols are
running on top of HTTP are gonna put
that different value on different parts
of the request canonicalization that was
a big thing we talked I mentioned that
word a whole lot of times there we are
if you look at our documentation it is
very specific about how we canonicalize
these things because you have to be even
something like URL encoding you can't
just say go follow this RFC because
guess what the RFC changes or the
recommend the list of of reserved
characters change and then you have to
deal with the fact that older libraries
aren't doing it that way a newer
libraries are you can't just say URL
encode and assume that the API is gonna
do it right because if you look at
languages take JavaScript for example
there's like three different encoding
related methods you could call and they
all encode things slightly differently
so we have to be very specific about
that sort of thing
it gets alright yeah going back to the
assigning different parts of the request
there's a reason that we specify what
headers were signing and there's a
reason we specify explicit ordering for
query string parameters it's because
again you have to here it's not so much
an issue of how are things getting
canonicalized but an issue of middlemen
between the person who is actually true
the code that's actually trying to make
the request and your server that's going
to receive it the obvious middlemen are
things like proxies and load balancers
and whatnot even if you throw those out
you still got middlemen because you've
got browsers you've got SDKs you've got
language libraries that are gonna get in
your way in case you don't believe me
just think about every API that lets you
specify query string parameters as a map
maps are unordered how are those going
into the URL you don't know so you have
to have a specify how you're ordering
those and how you're signing those
more fun with headers going back to
protocol agility I talked about protocol
agility for what's running on top of
HTTP but what about protocol agility for
HTTP itself when we went from 1.1 to 2.0
the host header changed from host 2 :
Authority and so we had a bunch of
services that were expecting the host
header to be signed and required you to
sign the host header but now there's no
more host header so what are you what's
the client signing because they don't
necessarily know if this request is
going over HTTP 11.1 or HTTP 2.0 it
might change over as it's sent over the
wire so they have to deal with that as
well we thankfully because of the
flexibility in our protocol that you
specify what headers you're signing we
were actually able to deal with that
just with some code changes and
documentation changes we didn't actually
have to Rev the format so that was kind
of a positive there the the last thing
I'll say real quick if I've got one cool
performance I mentioned a little bit
earlier with asymmetric crypto there's
two to two different places where we
kind of ran into some interesting
performance challenges one is symmetric
versus asymmetric asymmetric would be
awesome does great security properties
but there are honestly scenarios where
it is just still too slow and likely
always will be because as things improve
to make asymmetric crypto faster they're
also going to be improving to make other
parts of the system faster and so you're
still going to be looking at increases
in latency at potentially double the
cost of the API call so that's something
we have to think about lastly is I
mentioned Rick body was saying the body
of the request the fact that we sign a
hash of it not the full thing that's
again why we run version 4 not version 1
or 2 or 3 that was something we realized
hey this is not a great idea so another
reason for flexibility in what parts of
the request you're signing and how
you're signing those
and that was my world warden to earth
through AWS Sigma 4 if you google AWS
signature version 4 you will find our
public documentation on it if you want
to dive into that and see a little bit
more there's also source code for all of
our client SDKs pretty much on github
you could look at how we actually do it
there I are you planning to bring this
work as a specification to the idea
facilitation or um that's an interesting
thing to explore
yeah I think our presumption is that
there wouldn't be interest but yeah ok
ok thank you
so I'm just going through this quickly
so we've talked about a nested jaw to
him last last time what was missing is a
use cases so the issue was there in JSON
today it defines the concept of a nested
jawed but it has a limitation of that
the enclosing dot doesn't have its own a
claims and so the goal is to extend that
that that concept and allow the
enclosing jar to have its own claims if
there are two use cases that I'm aware
of
one is that native app that a interact
with two different authorization servers
what one is that that the native as
aware of that first authorization server
but not that the second one in and
because we don't have time and I'm not
going to go through that the flow itself
in the second use case is a use case
actually and now it's too late actually
to affect this this document because
it's a it's a think already with there
is G and that a allows that in or needs
look at that same concept of a nested
jot one inside the the other and with
with two different a claims in and we've
talked about em I'll talk about the
example so we've talked about
defining a content type and a new claim
to kind of define how would you nest
those a together range rights
so I want to say too much because we're
gonna have time right now
go ahead I just quickly wanted to say
that that passport document is just
submitted from the work group asking for
publication rights okay okay maybe it's
doable so we'll see
so who read the document any show of
hands one two three okay
for em I don't know if it's that's not
not enough people I would say have read
it to make the make a call for adoption
um yeah I think we will okay yeah so
it's to read it okay okay good I don't
have failure perfectly okay okay perfect
okay and I will add the second use case
that the still use case it's not in the
document but thank you all and yeah see
you next time I guess thank you can I
have a last word
so administrative leave coming in again
no value judgment all the work what's
really with really always excites me
we're not coming off as the tight link
of people have code I'm doing this thing
like I need this addition and kind of
the fast inner you know interplay is
phenomenal but from the governance
artifacts we have there is a lotta lot
of insight into what's actually
happening and what's on deck and what's
the next step miles the latest miles
games are July 27 TM it's tough to tell
from the Charter what working group
documents yeah beyond so in the coming
months we're gonna polish that on bill
and let's just put that out there now
that's just to make sure again my
primary driver here is that we know
where we're going and one of my key
things is there are folks that don't
participate here and they don't
understand that this being Adam gate
doesn't mean we're not doing
work so our ability to talk about future
milestones is signals to the community
that we have a lot of work to do to kind
of keep watching the space that's a good
point
thanks Roman we have planned to do this
already since 2017 at myself I rebuild
but I would post questions and then we
can we should
you