good morning everyone
this is the best competition element
working group session so yeah that's why
we still use well not well we're cells
they're already so even if you come are
supposed to be aware of the IPR policy
within the ETF you supposed to be aware
of that even when you subscribe and
restart to the unit of meeting so please
take some time to be aware of the wounds
on make sure you abide by them when you
contribute to the hf so usual stuff the
blue sheet should be running across the
room make sure you have signed them down
before during the meeting it helps us to
track the number of attendees and make
sure whether problem for next meeting
and can accommodate every attendees need
it Howie taking the minutes thank you
Harish we also have you nothing golf
connected to trouble parental please
make sure that you come to the mic on
the pink cross make sure when you have
question to you the mic because we have
streaming we are recording so everything
should be hold by the mics and make sure
you everyone can understand what you say
remember to stay tuned and when you come
at the mic also this is your football
sore hari taking the minutes and people
remote especially
we have people attending remotely by the
way one of them will be presenting later
so this is not just Siri there are
people connected from remote so how I
said before how he has been appointed as
the PCE working group secretary so
thanks again Harry for agreeing to take
that position Harry M is to among us
they succeeded in helping flush the
backlog of the PC document on other
stuff PC working group so thank you for
the help agree on it's likely that it's
your last meeting as a PCE co-chair so
thanks a lot thank you for everything
work I danced everything and the terms
from beyond the castle thank you
[Applause]
hopefully we keep seeing you here
[Music]
the meaning is as usual the many
documents that will be presented here
that haven't been discussed on the list
yet this is a pity you don't have to
wait for a presentation to trigger
discussion on the list many things can
happen between the meetings so the list
is open 24/7 please keep on trying
triggering discussion there that's a way
to make it all progress even between the
meetings so it's very useful to force
yourself to trigger discussion over
there because that's one of the tools on
the PC working we'll probably under use
that tool the week
it's been a while that we've been set up
that week in place seconds so correctly
up-to-date and it allows us to track
various cues for document adoption in
the walk you noob walking with Blasco
[Music]
sharing responsibilities and so on so
this is useful tool you may be
interesting also to bring in your a test
there if it makes sense it's open to
anyone with an account so if you feel
something isn't accurate you may also
add from there the link is included as
right so have a look at it it's useful
info that goes beyond what the data
tracker is already providing so feel
free to look at and maybe comment
implementation policy so we've been
already talking about that on the list
as you should be aware of
it is required that the working group
define an implementation policy for the
world they are defining and specifying
so in the PC working group we've decided
that we should abide by this rule by
including an implementation status
section in each document so unless
specific reason to be discussed means
the the chair is identified we expect
that all PC document include that kind
of section and it is especially true for
document occur close to the walk-in
Blasco be aware that we won't start
working with last goal without
addressing this issue it's been already
pointed out on the list review them in
this situation so this will be a
breaking point starting from now which
is already a breaking point
so please update your document we
through this section it doesn't have to
include a lot of things if there are few
things to do but the section must be
there I'm not empty of course so the
agenda has been shown for a while also
no major change note which is scheduled
anyone wants to bash anything in the
agenda okay we we've been as Jillian
said we've been working quite hard to
push the backlog out of the working
group and the result of that is we've
now got a lot of documents that are
beyond the working group since Park two
of them came out as RSC's the ability
to actn and the state for
point-to-multipoint both of which have
been a little while in the in the
production so I thought but it's good to
have them out then we've got three more
that are in the RFC editor queue so
they're shortly to become RFC's the
first of those the segment routine
document is part of cluster 340 a
cluster is a a group of mutually
dependent documents that need to be
progressed through the RFC editor as a
block I believe that all of those
documents are now with the RFC editor
and and 340 is going to come out soon so
that RFC will come the second one w son
RW a is dependent on the gmpls document
that's just a little lower down on the
slide so that's all okay and hierarchy
extensions are in with the authors to
make some comments back to the DRC
editor John and Laura lo Anderson since
MPLS also had at least one document in
that cluster 340 I have talked to the
RSC editor and they say that this
publication of all those drafts are six
to eight weeks out oh well okay thank
you I guess that means the the cluster
is fooled out that they haven't edited
yet yeah okay
two documents are with the ASG they're
both actually really sort of back with
the authors after iesg review and
pending updates I think if there's no
well updates they need to make but if
any of the author's is confused please
talk to the chairs and the Shepherd to
move that forward and then we've got
we've we've scared
our ad which is quite fun because part
of this moving the backlog means we've
suddenly pushed rather a lot of
documents through there are now six in
various states with with the ad with the
ASG I don't think I need to go through
them all but they're in various states
from needing updates after history
discussion all the way through to
pending a review from the area
Directorate so quite a range we've got
two early Copeland allocations that
looking quite safe they expire later
this year but they're both progressing
through the publication so we don't
expect any challenges there and we have
no errata in hand so now
since they were working with documents
on the agenda none of the authors asked
for agenda slot but I thought we should
put that and let's discuss our working
with buttons that because those are the
most important charted work that we have
already agreed to progress on so let's
go through their status predict WA T we
have some documents which the authors in
the past have claimed that there are
nearing working group last call and as
Julian mentioned the main gating point
where they are stuck is the
implementation policy that as a working
group you all have agreed to and please
talk to us regarding how to progress
this since maybe this is the first time
you are adding this so is there any
questions we are here to help you out
and some of the documents have already
added so you can also refer those
documents on the amount of detail note
that that this is your this doesn't mean
that you must have an implementation it
just means that you must talk about it
in the document and even if you have
implementations that are coming or you
don't plan to you can put that
information as well in the dis section
so start talking about it and then we
can start progressing these documents
the last document in the set is the
gmpls document that got merged during
the last last meeting a refresh was
promised which is still pending which
was supposed to deal with more editorial
changes so once that is done I think
this document is also nearing working
your plus call and I think surfer wants
to say something
yeah just any agree with the money if
you need anything both this am available
for helping with their document okay so
now one document which got updated so
let's look at the status of that
document which is our PCP and one
technical change was with respect to key
where LSP ID key also got added into the
LSP dB this is useful and make before
break cases where the you may have for a
temporary multiple LS B's so using the
LSP ID as a key
is helpful so based on that comment this
change was done and rest of the all the
comments are related to the RFC style
guide and how to properly use the
references or droughts and etc which
were discussed on the list and all those
things have been done as a status the
early young doctor review of this
document is also done but we do not have
any implementations of this young model
yet so if you are aware of this or are
you planning to implement please reach
out to the authors or on the list or the
chairs so that's about the yang model
some other documents which are not yet
fully cooked but but we need to discuss
one is the PCC see the PCC C document we
did Maidan of the update was made and it
was posted and they have added the
implementation status discussing about
what's what's implemented with respect
to PCC see the second document is the
native IP this was presented last time
there is no update and I think mostly
dependent on the movement that we see in
the t's working group of the related
documents we have the LSP scheduling
refresh was made but more technical
changes again I think implementation of
this document is something that the
authors would like so if you have plans
for implementing this please teach out
to the working group to documents which
were recently adopted or the flex grid
and the SRV six supporting piece up and
the one document that we wanted to
explicitly discuss was the enhanced
errors this was an agenda in IT f-104
and it was presented after that we
decided that there should be a guideline
of all the future documents how they can
use the enhanced errors and notification
so the guideline is as you can see in
the slide it requests that any new
document if they are defining new error
type or notification they should think
about whether this
error needs to be propagated in multiple
domains and what kind of error
criticality condition they should refer
so this is the die line that at least on
the mailing list who kind was agreed on
so if you have any thoughts on this
guideline still reach out to us and we
plan to either put this guideline on
wiki or in the draft itself or both and
the request would be that let's since
this is our working of document and if
we have consensus on this let's start
making sure that all the documents which
define new errors also refer to the
enhanced error techniques available any
comments on this good okay so the last
slide from the status we know that you
care about your documents and you may be
asking chairs that when the adoption
thing would happen we have a little bit
of a queue happening here it's a pretty
long Hugh wastes will slowly get to it
our first focus was to get the working
group LCQ happen and as you can see
that's empty for us now but now we have
a little bit like a no backlog at the
adoption whole thing so your chairs are
aware of it and we will get on this and
in fact the adoption pole for the first
document is ongoing now I ask from you
would be that we would need to hear from
you that it's we're not just doing this
poll for for the sake of it we want to
help whether the working group is
interested in it you can always say that
you are not it's doesn't have to be just
support it's your choice of saying that
no this should not be adopted and the
working group effort will waste it while
working on this document so but please
speak out the silence doesn't give us
the clear indicator on dodging the
interest in the working group for
various items
rakesh from Cisco the PC path segment
has both SR MPLS as well as SR v6 path
segment right now right the the MPLS is
a working group document but the survey
6 is not so I think maybe we need to
sort that out for
before we have adoption call for the PC
part segment should discuss with among
the authors and come back to us yes we
already did okay so wiki's open when you
make some decisions and you want to
remove the document from the adoption
pool cue and go back and work on it or
whatever decision that you make come
back to us and let's keep the wiki up to
date so that all in the working group
are aware of what's happening when
daughters okay thank you
let's start with the first presentation
the first presentation is Mike so if I'm
not mistaking Mike it's a presentation
to the PC working group welcome on among
us so my name is Mike Koehler chef and
presenting on
I'm from Cisco presenting on behalf of
the authors so the purpose of this draft
is to clarify stateful piece a behavior
that would leave less room for
misinterpreting certain things and we
compiled it as a result of basically ent
C Interop exercise so the main kind of
thing that we're doing is we're trying
to clarify the meaning of what the state
mean instead for piece up and how do you
exactly manipulate the state how you
maintain it and so we introduced these
two databases the LSP database and the
Association database so these are both
stored on both the PCC and the PC and
they have identical structure on the PCC
on the PC and one thing we
do is we update the RFC a23 one by
saying that PC request is not mandatory
for the PCC to send so this simple files
basically OSP bring out so first we
introduce this LSP database so we kind
of have these five basic rules about
what it is and so on the PCC the LSP
database is modified kind of pretty much
continuously by the PCC whenever it
whenever it decides to signal a new path
so and then on the PC the LSP DB is only
modified by PC report messages so there
is no other way that the PC can modify
its house be done please and we also
clarify that there is a two-tier
structure to this database in that there
is something called a tunnel and the
Stono is a container for our species and
so the tunnel is the thing that's
identified by the POS PID and the
symbolic name and there was is
identified by the RSP identifier and I
just want to note that basically these
this wording of tunnel and LSD is up for
discussion so SP stands for label
switched paths but this applies to non
labeled protocols and so perhaps saying
path database is a better choice instead
of LSP database so and we also introduce
this association database so this one
has is more it can be updated kind of
both by messages and configuration on
both the PCC and the PC and so each we
we kind of say that each a so is a
container for LS B's it's not a
container of tunnels so because if we
try to make it a container of tunnels
then it's not possible to do a make
before break
from one association to another because
you can't say that you my re-up tell us
P is in a different Association the
current house and last is the the change
we're proposing to RFC eight to three
one which states that PC request is not
mandatory because basically the PC you
cannot really enforce this so we found
that even if you don't send this request
the PC the PC will still you will still
react to your PC report just as well so
it basically saves one message during
state for bringing up or two messages
doing stateful bring up so I think
that's a good thing
and this is the end of my presentation
so every one of these time for questions
[Music]
okay sorry in a hallway sorry future Lea
okay so one thing that simple comment if
you want to have a different name for
LSP I would suggest connection I always
like this better than LSP for the
reasons you just described okay and
basically it is also better than path
because but you would confuse passes
computed paths which are not provisioned
so allow the connection database would
be a better term okay so this is more
firm I guess a question for the group
was like understand Nokia I think this
is more of a question for the group
we're diving board point to the fact
that PC request is not supposed to
modify state there are maybe
implementations out there today which
are doing reservation with given of
course if it's a PC request you might
not expect a report coming back so there
could be time of mechanisms and other
implementations to still hold
reservations primarily in the use case
of bandwidth so I'm wondering as a group
is that statement
that PC request is is shall not you know
modify the LSPD
LSP DB is that something that should be
a may or is that too restrictive
or do we generally think that that's a
silly idea it's no question for the
group thanks
hi this is Adrienne as a as an
individual it's three things and be
really careful about specifying the
format of databases in implementations
that makes no difference to
interoperability and what we do as
protocols for the wire so I only and say
what state what information needs to be
stored about how it's stored is up to
your competitors to screw up you want to
encourage them to screw it up second
point which was kind of just made I
think it's too strong to say a PC is not
supposed to create any state a piece he
probably doesn't need to but there's
this kind of concept of sticking state
where you you make a request and you
don't know whether the networks going to
use that information but you kind of
want to get ahead of the IGP just in
case they do so think about that and the
third one was 82 31 updates I've got
this little draft clarifying the use of
bits if we're gonna make 82 31 updates
we should think about whether we bundle
them together or not yeah I just want to
quickly just say about the peace request
not modifying the LSP TV so I think
there may be a use case where you kind
of use the PC for OAM so say you want to
ping like an inter domain path right and
you just want to basically say you know
give me some path right but you don't
want to touch the network you don't want
to
modify any state in the network based on
that like you just it's it's like you
know you just want to probe the network
right you don't want to modify it so I
think that's why I mean that we said
that but we're kind of open to whatever
the workgroup says they're Hilah burger
I agree with Adrienne's point about the
databases you don't want to specify them
as formal requirements but as a
conceptual talking point as a way of
characterizing the information that's
being stored I think that's really
useful it's good to have some common
terminology so I actually like that and
just don't make it that you actually
have to build it that way the have you
thought about protection paths and now
you're gonna represent them protection
yeah I mean there's just the association
objective well you can there's there's
different ways to model if you're
thinking about it from a database
representation and you could choose just
to leave them uncorrelated and then you
have to walk the whole database to find
the Association you know which ones are
associated or you might do some formal
linkages okay I would say if you could
write down on the mailing list in more
detail than I think we can it's really
just think about how you want to
represent that so it's it's usable
information okay cool one thing though
about the the database I think we should
specify the key of the database right
because like if different vendors use
like if one vendor uses the LSP ID as
the key and another vendor uses the
tunnel ideas the key like you end up
with a broken you know they're not gonna
interrupt and then nobody wins in that
situation so I'd say that's an
appropriate thing to think about if you
are defining data models like yang
models if you're talking about just sort
of informative concepts it's fine to say
that you think of it that way I don't
think you can specify it if you want to
specify it I think you have to end up
with some foremost
Asian language which we end up with
doing yang I mean okay as you know
Adrienne pointed out we defined behavior
on the wire we don't be a defined
behavior inside the node all right
thanks
eatle woozy from away I have a question
for radiation you say that in the
Association is not between tunnels but
in teas we are modeling in Titan and
modern association between Tennyson and
be confusing is the limit so yeah just
trying to understand why we have
different viewpoints on different
working groups right so this is
basically you can have association
between tunnels if every I was peeing in
in tano is associated to every RSP and
tunnel B then the two tunnels are
associated but making it purl SP it
gives some more use cases such as if
you're doing bi-directional for example
then the two LS B's there may be you
know a real plus B which is associated
to the real optimist be on the other end
it's not associated to the current of us
B on the other end so services agent
again I think we have a disconnect on
terminology that when you're down in the
transport world a there's a double
disconnect on terminology and not not
the layer 4 transport the lion transport
when you're down in the late in the
underlying transport world a tunnel is a
pipe in rsvp-te world a tunnel is this
conceptual collection of potential
connections we call LSPs right so it
tells term tunnel is your turn LSP
my definition of tunnel is very simple
it's just the thing identified by the
POS PID so your point is that the LS PB
did the association between tan s is
model as association between all y LS PB
on the Tumnus that's the way you address
that yeah you can you can solve like in
some cases it doesn't make sense to have
association between individual LS B's in
that case you just associate the tunnels
by associating you know there are space
yeah yeah I'm not saying it indeed you
can associate an S in that then you can
do that by using all yellow speed or or
not I'm confused so basically just a
clarification when we model T tunnel we
basically saying that Alice piece that
go on to the same tunnel like walking
and protection Alice B's they do not
meet any association they already I
children of this tunnel and associated
native lives for that when we say
associated tunnels it means that there
are tunnels basically all their
connections or only working connections
it doesn't matter but for example there
is an association one supports one
direction in data plane and another in
opposite direction and so forth this is
like a higher level of Association so
basically putting everything into
connection Association or I lost
association it's actually confuses a lot
of things
okay so again
LSPs that belong to the same tunnel they
associated by definition their
association object the tunnel ideas
association object yeah and we're not
trying to associate two osp's within the
same tunnel typically that there's no
use case for that associate a las peace
between themselves because they belong
to different tunnels okay they just
unprotect the tunnels if they have a
single LSP I'm not sure you said them do
your previous thing that we're somehow I
mean it's not necessary to to associate
LSP is among it within the same tunnel
and I'm saying I agree with you there
and but but you do need to associate
tunnels basically as parents or
sometimes sometimes sometimes yeah and
there are different reasons why you do
that
you do not associate them on the less P
level that's what I'm saying your
associated okay you can bring that up a
new in the meaningless and we can think
of a solution thanks tarick from
Jennifer I might all right so about the
Association itself I just want to
clarify you can have multiple types of
Association right there's diversity
there's carotid Ness you're so cold out
goodness is one example where you want
the LSPs of the same tunnel or possibly
forward and reverse to be associated
right right I don't think we should
dictate that you cannot do it per tunnel
or you cannot I mean LSP granularity is
fine by me
which is the fine granularity but one
can choose to do it on per tunnel and in
fact you know if you have diversity you
want to always be you know this tunnel
is diverse from this tunnel no matter if
you do make before break or not so my
comment is not to go technical but I
think dictating it raises the concern
but if not fair enough I don't see what
you're saying so okay thanks
maybe we can go just out there Thanks
yes I think the Association is for LSP
but is the recipes can be across the
different tunnels so that's how is
modeling T's as well so I think what
you're saying terminology wise it kind
of makes sense
okay thanks rubbish yeah I think there
is maybe maybe this this rule it's the
also as a continuum for ESPYs maybe
that's left up to the individual also
definition then I think a more generic
way yeah thanks Mike Mike as you
progress this work on I think a
suggestion that I would give you for
this like you know right now it's a mix
of clarifying things mix off making
changes into RFC eight two three one so
we need to scope it a little bit better
and maybe the things that needs to
update eight to three one work with
Adrian and we we scope it as a standard
strat thing and the things which are
clarifying there we and again when you
are clarifying I think currently you
clarify from the database point of view
and you think of what is the database at
see see what is the database at PCE but
in ITF and in we should worry about
what's on the wire so if there is any
confusion between what people are
encoding in LSP identify TLD or people
are making mistakes with symbolic paths
name and some correction needed there
that is more important than how does an
implementation stores the information
the same thing with a SOG DB whether I
create a DB or I it's a state in my LSP
DB itself why does it matter
let that be up to the implementations to
figure out I agree with you that you
know we should I understand okay
ideally that we should be concerned
about protocol on the wire stuff however
in this case what Mike is trying to do
here is clarify interpretation of those
values on the wire so during in araba
ran into that where the meaning of a
certain number of the meaning of a
certain name or the expectation of a
certain name or number to exist or not
exist and how it was used
there was differences of opinion there
and I agree so instead of showing it as
a data base at rest we should show
what's the message that the require the
report message or update message should
include so my kind of comment to that is
it it doesn't matter what the message is
so I mean okay maybe we are interrupting
message is more important so for example
what I'm saying here in the first point
is that the PCC DB is mod of PCC LSP DB
is modified by any trigger it could be
PCI update there could be a local
computation it could be configuration so
regardless of what triggered it like I
don't need to specify it you know the
same thing 3 the same rule 3 times I'm
just saying that basically it's the the
tribulus common and you know your state
changes in one way so we can discuss
that on the mailing list I think so I
this useful work I mean we've had
various implementations interpret things
different ways so I think is really
useful if you're going to add some
recommendations for what the Association
DB needs to look like and proposed
terminology for tunnels and things like
that I would encourage you to look at
the T tunnel modeling's work that's been
done there's a fair bit of work that's
gone into how the associations are
specified for connections belonging to
various Colonels across various
technology so take a look at that before
you make any recommendations in this
topic
okay sure thanks thank you much
so you have a unified some interesting
issue to you to work on here so please
so what makes presenters is the first
worker is state - synchronization
between states for PCs and firstly let's
briefly recap what has been done in
these drafts so basically it's a yeah
original motivation is to describe the
procedure for the sync up function
between the states of PCU communications
and the objective is to make the
deployment of pce
in a more resilient way and we can solve
the computation and loop issues for the
dependent task computation like the
diversity so basically we have also
included a scenario so is written NPC
for backup or to the load balance and we
are also looking to the applicability of
this mackensen into the inter domain PC
and the hierarchical PC is nervous so
this work has been discussed previously
in ITF 100 which is almost two years ago
so since the present her has a bad
memory and I'd like to reintroduce some
of the key concept in the draft so
firstly with har get all set up at this
obsession between the state for PCs
which is named as state sync session and
the second object would be say to
synchronize the RSP state between this
the state OPC is using this session and
this kind of say synchronization can be
applied to in both directions and only
the incremental state would be required
for the state single synchronization so
that would be also risky because if you
miss one of them or you duplicated some
of the wrong state information that
would be a kind of inconsistent data
base between the PC NPCs so we also
introduced the master and the slave
relationship between the pcs so for
multiple errors piece and one PC you can
become the master and the other can be
the slave and all the RSPCA is a kind of
dedicated to the master pcs and we also
have some minor contributed have to
describe say the use a draft database
portion to maintain the latest change
and also we need to maintain the earth
piece data from multiple sources and we
use an example to describe a a kind of
how this state of synchronization is
done so we assume in the figure this is
a time order of the three phases and we
have one PCC connecting with two
different pcs and there is a kind of
synchronization request is between the
two pcs so basically are as very
beginning time phase we have the PCC
trigger let's call it a dream message to
both PC number one and PC number two
but unfortunately the delay of the PC
message delivery is different or
Tuesday's to PC is so it is possible
that a while is
one of them is to reach earlier than the
other so this problem would be somehow
solved by using the states of
synchronization sessions and finally the
PC to will recorder the latest RSP state
Korea I received from the PCE one before
receives a responding message from PCC
and then we suppose there is another
changer that market has a yellow one on
the slides and PCC also need to trigger
the changes to both of the PCs and again
it reach the PCE number one first or so
out great
thank you yeah so meanwhile when the PCC
number one is propagating the the yellow
message for the PC 2 is still receiving
the message from the PCC so that which
is a kind of not synchronized the state
but to give him the mackensen specified
in this document we allow the PC number
2 to figure out which is the latest
RSP state with different value and then
the PC number to understand he need to
ignore the the Korean War which is the
old one so and finally there is a kind
of late message from the PCC who if you
see number two but that would not affect
any changes in the in the RSP database
so we okay we looked back to what has
been discussed in IETF 100 and all
comments has been clarified oh how the
PC is interacting with each other and we
have addressed this kind of problem by
aligned with other state for PCs and
hierarchical PC of work so this would be
an important mechanism you
for the Mokpo PCU session so we request
to the working group to adopt this draft
or and it's the protein to the adoption
queue yes sir that do it now okay that's
all for presentation any comments I
personally feel that this is important
some some of our recent publishing work
like stateful HPC and actn work also
referred to this document so this is if
I have feeling that has not been seen by
the right set of eyes yet so should we
ask how many people have read how many
people have read this document okay
that's good should we check the interest
so how many people feel that this work
is whether we should be working on this
document as a inside a working group
okay so almost the same set of people
and anybody has any objection on working
group taking on this work none good good
we will reconfirm anyway as our usual
process things on the list thank you
Thanks as always we open the technical
contribution to how this work and there
are some commands to be addressed anyway
but know again nothing to prevent a
motion to other operation this is how me
again and this time I marked my name
with a color so the next presentation is
about the extension or say for PCE to
allow optional processing of the PC PC
objects so basically we see this kind of
discussion all the layers are talking
about the processing of flags and it's
kind of
Seabury is a kind of mist when we
migrated from City less PC to late fall
and this graph to specify the usage of
PFLAG and I flag in a piece of message
so PFLAG is the semantic meaning is to
indicate whether the object is must be
processing or it can be optional and
I've Clara is a follow up flag
indicating that whether the piece of
speaker can ignore this message so what
has been done in the States for PCE RFC
82 thirty one is they have specified the
state for PCE saying that the usage of
P&I flag must be set to zero in the
transmission and should be ignored on
the received so the problem is the
behavior on the pni flag in this object
this object is somehow stated but see in
the other object the specified so the
specification is missing and we finally
find that some of the object would be
useful if they can have the pni flag set
or not set so that's the draft that
that's about the draft so we clarify how
the pni flaps are used and to identify
the optional objects and this is
applicable to all the organs a PCE
report update and initiate message off
semi interstates for style
so we also update what would be done if
there are some unknown objects based on
this kind of flats so so far we have
categorized all the PCE into two
different
one can proceed as a peon I flag and the
other cannot do this so it would be
necessary to introduce a new flapper to
indicate the capability and we use the
state for PC capability are we and
introduce relaxed format so if this
speed is set then the PC you can process
the P&I flag according to this craft and
if this is now set then it will always
ignore the pni flag so this it is worth
noting that so the kind of relaxed flag
need to be set by both peers I simply
talked with juniper again so about the
relaxed flag and the P and I when you
say ignore is there a way to say best
effort ignore like say you're doing
exclusion of multiple addresses or links
or nodes you want to go best effort kind
of exclusion or inclusion the integral
for the ignore means all the
informations object will not be taken
care there is a case where your
computing a backup path know your your
exclusion constraint is input yeah but
that you want to do best effort kind of
you know let me clarify I think our C 5
4 4 0 when we set the P flag in a
request message we basically meant that
PC is free to ignore it but it is
allowed to process it as well so if so
ideally what we usually do in this case
if the path is found meeting that
constraint we will give that path but if
we are not able to meet the constraint
then we will ignore the object yeah my
point so this is best effort in my mind
I don't want to ignore it I want to
still consider the object but and on a
best-effort so so so let's say diversity
is you know computing to LSP two paths
that I diverse I cannot find fully
diverse paths they could be neat
at one place I'm okay with that is it
possible it's possible in the diversity
Association drop document so within that
Association we try to handle this not at
the whole object level oh okay the
reason we're discussing this is in the
modeling effort we did model this yeah
my question is what happens is that we
see while doing the path computation
okay though there could be two
situations it is possible to wanna say
inclusion and come up with the path
which is longer in delay that if you
would orbit this inclusion
allo and and get it a better delay okay
so how do you handle the compromise
between two optimizations one is
following not mandatory inclusions and
another provided like a birthday way I
think you are asking how to balance
optimization between two different
parameters yeah yeah how do you know so
basically what this PC is supposed to do
if process that was a choice
ignoring the inclusion it will come up
with a better delay but owner inclusion
it it will be closer to the path that
was specified but providing was delay I
think this is a general problem for past
computation and my understanding is the
PCC can indicate effective objective
function right so since multiple
parameters instead of one so that is a
little bit away from this document so
what the modeling that we did in T right
so basically the way we addressed this
problem which is a big problem right
away the resid as honoring this
non-monetary inclusion as a base
optimization okay the same as
optimization like this delay and we
provide basically the weight to the
optimization then PC knows exactly what
to do what would be the best
optimization overall you might consider
I don't know what can do cut it down
with the flags but we can achieve this
by setting our captive functions and
balance between different constraint or
using a kind of like a best effort
actually that's an interesting point but
that was beyond the scope of this very
specific document so well maybe I should
do something in the list only when we
talk about these things before in the
past but that's far beyond presentation
so okay let's move back to slides and we
given this our flap we can indicate the
capability of the PC to preceding or
these two flags and then we keep the
definition on how to use a P flag and I
flag so for the P flag firstly the
semantic meaning is to indicate whether
the object so with this flag is
mandatory if the flap is set or it's
just the option now if the flap it's not
set so different message rule requests
the flag is indicated apart by different
entity in different messages so in PCI
update and initiate message with PC is
entity who should indicate the PFLAG
processing and PCE
report manager this this black rupee
indicate by by PCC and P equals one
means the object must be taking into
account and P equals zero means the
object that can be ignored in the
discussion from the etheric or the best
air filter is a sub case for P equals to
zero and four regarding was a flag so in
the it would be effective being PC
update and report message and when it is
set it means the there is an optional
object it proceeds is processed and if
it is not not set it means the the
object is not going to be processed and
indicated by by by different a PC or PC
in the PC update Henry report
accordingly and it would be noted that
in the PC initiated that there is a flag
its minimis and should be ignored so
with semantic meaning of the PFLAG and I
flag basically its PFLAG it's the PC
sees sorry the PC speaker need to check
the status of PFLAG and the to process
in so following a procedure flowchart so
the first step is to check if the Platt
flag is set and need to determine did
decide whether the PC speaker is free to
ignore and if the flag is set then that
is II also need to figure out whether
there are some unknown objects in the
object er we and if there is because P
flag is set and the PC must process so
if there is unknown if there is unknown
objects the precept should reject the
request always I error message and if
everything is known that would be a kind
of normal procedure processing so in
this working document we reuse the RSP
error code TR we define the instead for
PC RFC and we have not introduced NC new
so the status okay
the status is we we updated the the text
by adding the dedication scenario and
the state the problem space has been
confirmed now the mailing list and we
believe there are other documented
talking about other flats and people
agreed although useful of the document
so again we our request for the working
group to adopt this work that's all for
the presentation you come on from room
and your other commits I mean since I'm
correctly in 1831 updates if I
understand this correctly you're not
proposing any change 282 31 you're
proposing and an extension that people
could choose to implement yes okay thing
so but this one I think we don't you
have some problem socialization to which
even that on I think it is linked to a
moral issue that has been raised Monday
comin from turrican ego so glad to see
some parallel discussion not necessarily
linked to that graph itself but maybe
also to diversity graft which is also
tackling some interesting mechanism
linked to tax question so please make
sure that your use case is fine and
we'll take that to the list of progress
those may be in all the document on this
one thank you so next presenter is Cheng
Ying Chun Li from Maui my topic today is
convey okay thanks conveying okay the
bank vendor specific information in
peace app extension for a state for PCE
so basically what is than the
specification information so the vendor
information can be arbitrary or
appropriate information such as than the
specific constraint between during the
post into computation and the price
number uniquely identifies the
organization responsible for the
definition of the content and meaning of
the vendor specific information so by
definition this implies inequity in
inability to interoperate at the
functional level between the vendors
unless the research there's some
cooperation right so the history of
vendor specific a specific information
is in RFC if 7150 it defined it that
the vendor information objet and theory
which can be used for I mean stateless
PCE but in I've seen a 74 and 770 it
obsolete the previous one and you find
some milk on point for the theories in
this I've seen the vendors information
TV can be used by the precept object
that allows option theories and also the
vendor information objects support in
his PC requires request NPC reply
message but they but this RFC didn't
mention anything of than the information
in for state of all piece set so that is
what we do in this draft
we stands the extension for supports
supporting the state for PC by including
vendor information object in a piece app
report and PC update and as well as this
initiated message so and as well the TV
was already support so what we have done
in this job is we make some extension in
the state of all PC messages such as
peace report and this update and peace
initiate so let's take a look up the
format's of these three messages okay
then questions and next steps so
basically we could like to request the
comments from the working group it did
it is it useful and is it correct and by
the way is there ready for working group
adoption any comments
no one so question of the usefulness is
legitimate so begin to have some
feedback on that correct I think so
you're using some more different
mechanism make sure it's properly
supported all existing device it so
correctness is okay for me a usefulness
interesting to know about from the
working group so if not today from the
list that's not a complicated Pokemon so
ready please do we will consider it's
useful to qualify your limitations or
specification this is pretty easy to
understand so yes I see my coming this
is Mike Francisco because for example
not sometimes some vendors you know they
they kind of jump ahead of the of what
the working group is doing and sometimes
it's useful to just do something in a in
the backward compatible way to signal
something and there is also some things
that you know may be very specific to a
vendor that you know so on a signal so I
definitely think it's useful thanks
thank you
[Music]
updates 282 sort 182 81 as well yeah
indeed
triumphant I'll come here under now
easier any initiation in the previous
document that limited the unity of the
theory harder message you know you have
Mason and his tiara we had been put into
you to to PMS or message and your uncle
and they you a lot of Sri message so I
think I just want to you know any leave
shakes me in the kind of see reverse
right yeah yeah here
easy Ernie you something you now see 7
for 17 to restricted the tyranny POV you
in other let me try if I understood your
question correctly the 7 for 7 0 said
that this theory can be carried in any
object that allow optional TLV so that's
why when we define stateful objects like
SRP and LSP object we were able to carry
the TLV but we were not able to carry
the of judges yes
so this document simply says that you
can also carry the vendor information
object not just the TLB okay yeah
basically what we have done is we tried
should do something that that that is
missed in that I see yes so you stopped
just run to make the vendor information
object the P in care DD in the PCP
exactly just answer I suppose this work
I mean it's beautiful and in my previous
slide who are going to use it for what
useful stuff so I think it should be
progressing okay okay
Thanks thank you for feedback so next
presenter is Mike again hi this is Mike
coalition from Cisco so I'll be
presenting some brainstorming that we
had about how do you a signal ecmp and
UCM key information in kissa so we are
motivated by the need to encode multiple
segment lists for SRT policies some of
you may know 30 policies they have these
are candidate paths and which candidate
path has multiple segment lists which
have you CMP among them so I just quote
the segment routing policy draft here so
I highlighted that it's basically saying
that the PC may compute not just a
single segment list but a set of segment
lists as a solution to the optimization
problem so doing kind of our
brainstorming we realize that there is
actually two use cases here so one the
first use case is when you have a single
optimization objective and this was the
solution to that objective is multiple
ecmp paths and the second use case is
when you have multiple optimization
objectives and you want ecmp among those
objectives so you want a signal both
these are valid use cases and in fact
they're kind of orthogonal which means
that they can exist independently of
each other so here I'll give an example
LS p1 and LSB - you have different
optimization objectives and the PCC
wants to have a CMP among LS p1 and LSB
- so LS p1 gets single path X and speak
to get
to ecmp paths y&z and so as a result 50%
of the traffic goes on tax 25 1 y and 25
on that
so we'll see later that how we propose
to represent this in Pisa
so for use case 1 which is the single
optimization objective yielding multiple
paths we we basically propose three ways
to or sir two ways to encode this and we
would need to extend Pisa to specify the
maximum number of paths that PCC can
handle so for example if the if the
router can can install like 32 outgoing
paths with UC and PU and it would just
need to signal that number 32 and then
the PC would reply with 32 or less
unequal cost multi paths and so are two
kind of options that we proposed here
are basically different ways of putting
multiple euro objects into the same LSP
so option a would be to introduce this
yellow attribute object and basically
use it as a separator to separate
different arrows so basically it needs
to carry the weight and needs to carry
the upper status for each using P path
and can carry optional T of ease and
then option B is something that drew
suggested basically this is to reuse
something from T to MP and here we we
can use already existing objects to
separate the arrows so there's already
this this type of us to our us object
that is actually very similar to what
we're proposing so if we go with this
approach we we just need to define one
new TLD for it
to carry the weight and basically this
is what the the encoding would look like
so you see arrow 1 + 0 2 they're both
encoded under the same LSP and they're
separated by these endpoints in STL a
subject and basically the advantage of
this approach of option B is that you
can reuse the RB n F that's already
there in the RFC and you just need to
define one single TOB to use so use case
2 is a is a completely different use
case so it's basically if you have if
the PCC knows in advance how many
objectives it has so if it wants like
one path on red and one path on blue and
once ecmp among those two paths then
basically the LS the PCC will allocate
different piece of tunnel and tunnel in
the sense of my previous presentation
for each objective and it would create
some new Association type for example
code EMP Association - by buying these
tunnels together so here I give an
example of how these two use cases are
orthogonal and they exist at the same
time so I already gave this example I
mean in the previous slide so I'm just
gonna give the piece up representation
so if you have 1 LSB or so if the PCC
has constrained for example it wants 50%
traffic on red 50% on blue then we
create like sp1 and I will speak to you
and put them in a single Association but
within the LSP itself there is the
option to give to return multiple equal
cost multi paths so that you could have
you know 50
going on red as one path and 50% going
on blue eyes as two paths so that's what
this is and that's the end of my
presentation
oh and Peter can you go to the slide
where you mention piece of tunnel okay
to console yourself
so one a can you go to one a the example
yeah I think you have the Pearson yeah
yeah I think you can still retain this
existing vnf if you introduce a sub
object to carry the ingress hop action
okay so if we ever extend piece up to
signal a multipath why a dag you could
reuse the same sub TLV so and then that
way you could still use the existing BNF
today we do have precedence for a CRO
very inside a production object as a
second sub object so if you think of the
load balance specifier as an english
action you can just put it as a sub
clearly so that's one comment like can
you go further up this one way yeah yeah
so when you say different piece of
tunnel what do you mean here
so I mean exactly what I meant in my
previous presentation today okay Tohno
is the thing identified by the PSP okay
so there's a single pls PID you would
create if you want to different
associate us to different objectives you
would create two different PSP IDs okay
yeah that works thing just one
clarification
even if he do sub objects to do a ro
list
we still need to update our be enough
because our problem is our report update
message only allow us to put one Jaros
object
so Liz you have two options that one is
today the semantics of ero would say
that you process the first one and if
you see more than one year or you ignore
the rest or you could use a CRO as for
the additional ones and this and that
fits your en of a arrow / ero followed
by C arrows and all of them carry the
same I think our piece of I'll be enough
is little bit different so I discuss
this with you and we can go over this
hi it's Aaron again as an
individual I'm trying to sort out in my
head how the weighting of traffic across
this set is different from the flowspec
work that we've got in other words it's
telling the system what traffic to put
on which LSP is that is that a
reasonable question to ask don't have
the answer for you I think that's
reasonable questions so I think let me
reply actually on the mailing list yeah
sure thank you John from Hawaii and my
question is when I use the Association
group 2 Association the least or the ero
that we can beauty like ECM pou CMP
daños and I think we have a draft in
four as a policy in peace app was the
relation between this draft and that
draft yeah so basically there's two use
cases right so in the first year's case
you don't know in advance how many ecmp
paths you will get you just simply say I
can install up to thirty two paths okay
and the PC then may give you one path or
it may give you two paths or it may give
you sixteen paths or thirty two paths in
the second use case that's where you use
the optimization objective that's why I
use the Association object to bind the
different Association objectives that's
when you know the PCC knows in advance
how many objectives it has in it that's
when the association is used so you can
really use the association object in the
first news case because the PCC does not
know in advance how many hours piece it
it will cut the line of so on the same
slide I heard you say the two approaches
are orthogonal but can't coexist yeah I
was confused to me the second example
option second option is a specific case
of you know the first option is a
specific case of the second meaning one
LSP one optimization objective is a
specific case of multiple SPS and each
have a different optimization objective
do you see it differently yes okay I am
not clear if you can clarify I mean I'll
give an example there so it's that's
where what I'm trying to say is you have
to you have two LS B's here and each has
its own objective function objective
function strange objective function and
constraints but if you wanted one
objective function and one constraint
you're free it's a special case of the I
mean I don't see but you create to say
you can install 32 CMP paths would you
create 32 what I'm trying to say it's a
it's an operator decision to specify I
want multiple or one I understand but
basically the problem is becomes very
inconvenient because say if your router
can install 32 ec MPs then you would
need to say create 32 empty osp's
delegate them to the PC and then the PC
you would give you maybe one path and
there are say be empty so all the
details and one policy I might choose to
do one LSP one objective another policy
I might choose
do two of them two of journalist p1
objective you can't have two objectives
for LSP that's that someone I said I
said one policy one LSP one objective
another policy to LSPs and two
objectives on the same box and the PCE
should be able to me there's no there's
no policy your first of all right so
that's why I'm giving you an option
where there is a policy so I'm not sure
where the policy is in terms of policy
is something SRTP SEP is okay okay so
what i'm okay i think we regardless i
think we should be generalizing rather
than restricting and yes so this is the
movies to is the generalization and for
it i believe that they're both
orthogonal and the only way to
generalize it is can i apologize i
didn't read your draft and I didn't even
hear your presentation so my question is
that say if I ask for say 100 G pass
okay and can PC return an answer such
drug that I cannot do it in one short
but I can do it say in two ways one is
40 G and another in 60 G yes exactly
okay okay and then and then you can use
this as setting up for example a set of
what Ovilus piece right that can
collectively provide the there yeah well
you can say I want like a hundred gig
path and with certain constraint like
you know going on some certain set of
links and I also want like another
hundred gig path on some other set of
links and that is use case too but the
original use case that you gave is a
basically if you if you request that you
want 100 gigs but the PC cannot give you
one path that satisfies 100 gigs so it
would give you two paths back right and
say you cmp among them can it give like
a several options like for example
either this two of these three something
like that that collectively well
satisfies one hungry G or it's just one
this duel is I'm
I mean say I can do it in one short
right but I can do either like 60 and 40
or like 300 basically that's that's an
interesting I mean you could have like a
whole bunch of different you know
different solutions I mean there are
solutions that you can choose yeah
currently I mean what kind of we're
thinking is to I mean you only have one
but that's a good idea
okay so consider that because we're also
considering that okay thanks
kiss me quick gesture so to adjust
audience question the binding of factor
T know is coming in BGP update as color
and point so this is how you know which
still associated with which fat here we
are mixing a bunch of use cases and I
think we should decouple them one of
them sin get when you use PC to compute
to know our number of tools associated
with the policy rather than trying to
provide segmented to knows because we
cannot satisfy a particular number of
constraints that two completely
different things and mixing them creates
lot of confusion and say it's different
things I agree but we need to mix them
in order to be general you know you need
to become problem in order to sure but
solve one problem and then every game
thank you Mike so the next presenter is
human
so my name is human wit Kohli from Nokia
I'm new to this working group please be
kind as the French say in Mexico good so
this graph is about point-to-multipoint
policy so just to give an idea why we
are introducing this graph and I think
on the unicast side we have done a
really good job for the next generation
networks to be simplified when I say
simplify I mean we are a controller
removing some of the MPLS protocols but
multicast is kind of lagging behind
we do have protocols like B which uses
the underlay IGP but when it comes to an
MPLS transport as of now we really need
rsvp-te point-to-multipoint MLBPA etc
etc so just to be in par with unicorns
we try to introduce this draft that uses
a controller very thin layer of
communication between the controller and
the PC see we are starting with Pisa
eventually we probably going to move on
to other protocol su but basically the
controller figures out the tree using
bgp LS it has all the states in the
network it sees the route and the Leafs
it calculates the path from the root to
the Leafs via a set of policies which
I'll explain later on and it uses PCE to
download or Pisa to download all that
information to the PCC so basically what
this will give the operators going
forward is to bring the multicast in the
same level as unique as from program
programmability
on the on the router itself so to do
this there is a couple of objects or
segments that we are introducing in
spring and one of them is the point to
multi-point segment so basically the
simplest way to explain the point to
multi-point segment it's it's a
container that contains the route and a
set of Leafs and it needs to be
identified
a set of parameters which you can read
the draft and figure that out how the
root and the leaf are discovered there
is nothing new we can discover them via
NP BGP procedures was at the entry and
VPN procedures the RFC 6514 6513 all
those discoveries can become indicated
up to the PCE we are the mechanism that
you guys already have and invented
previously as you will read it in the
draft or later on in these slides so
there is nothing new here the only thing
you gotta keep in mind is you need to
understand what is a point-to-multipoint
segment so the next part is as I
mentioned point-to-multipoint segments
actually contains the rule and a set of
leaves obviously between the root and
the Leafs there's a replication points
and that's what the replication segment
comes in in a simplest way to think
about sitting a replication segment
think of it as a forwarding instruction
at each new at each no that's a simplest
way of putting it incoming seed incoming
label for a segment label for a
replication segment that identifies the
resource and then you have the outgoing
interfaces with outgoing labels that
will connect you to the next replication
segment that's it
that's all one thing you need to keep in
mind is pure replication segments they
can be disjoint via a unicast SR segment
if you will in that case you guys have
already invented the seedless we use a
Sibley's the the unique as is our policy
to connect to replication segments
together and our important thing to keep
in mind here is replication segments
they cannot be stacked
why is that the reason for that is when
you get to a replication point that you
have multiple OFS outgoing or if's
if you start stacking stacking segments
multicast segments where you really
cannot go through every single one of
those labels to figure out which is the
leaf
disconnected on beach of' in malta in in
multicast you know if you look at only
the top of the the list if you will it
will not give you the entire picture on
that replication segment for all
outgoing interfaces so this is why when
it comes to the replication segment
there is only a single label that single
label on that note will identify the
outgoing interfaces and the labels or
the seats that are being used to the
next one again this is only true for
replication segments you can connect to
replication segments via a seedless and
unique ass as our policy so just going
through the data path very quickly the
source sends a payload that payload is
the IP gets through outer a router a has
a replication policy that says your to
get to router D and E which are the
Leafs your next hop is a replication
segment c b.push c payload is on the
bottom we send it the the packet to see
C looks at the see the label C
identifies the replication policy or the
replication segment segment looks at
their outgoing instructions the outgoing
OFS outgoing interfaces figures out what
is the label that it needs to push on
each interface to D it pushes D to e it
pushes E and it forwards the packet
through the according interface to those
routers the next one is fast reroute the
PC can camp compute a fast reroute that
bypasses the link between a and C that's
via router G that fast reroute could be
TI l fa it could be RSVP T it could be
anything it's beyond the scope of these
draft but you have the fast reroute that
is sitting on the data path and you can
achieve very fast fast readouts here's
an example when there is a node that
does not support replication segment on
the on the network that's not B and F as
an example here so in this case is
because PC
that note B does not support replication
segment they actually push on a label
stack saying that C which is the next
replication segment is at the bottom of
the stack pushes B for unique hash
unique SSR C and forwards that packet
through B to C B pops a label C gets the
label label C figures out what is the
replication segment and forwarding
information on C and forwards the packet
that is what as it was in the previous
slide going forward you can have all the
good stuff that you guys have in unicast
canada tad let's speed redundancy fast
reroute etc etc we are using all the
draft all the tools that you guys have
already invented we are not trying to
come up with new mechanism I think you
guys have done a great job previously so
we're just using all those tools all
over again
here's that high-level bird's-eye view
of how the objects loop again some of
the objects that are already there
Canada pads
you know nothing new the only part that
I as I explained previously is you need
to understand the point to multi-point
policy and the replication policy the
replication policy can contain multiple
canada paths and this candidate paths
can be used as LSP redundancy they could
be end to end or aka global optimization
if you will throughout each one of these
candidate paths and for the sake of time
I'm not going to go through the details
of what are the bits and bytes in this
graph you can go with the draft one of
the things that I want to specify it is
that the RFC's that I put in there the
first you RFC's they probably don't make
sense to anybody
there should be 82 31 I believe it's all
right yes and the second one is 86 23
which is the new RFC that you just gave
out so those are some of the current
other sins that we are using we did try
to change and introduce some very minor
objects which were necessary as an
example we are using the CCI object but
currently in the CCI object you can send
down the single label
going forward we are using or CCI
objects
on multiple labels for the seed list for
the outgoing interfaces because there
could be multiple outgoing interfaces
hopefully all business stuff are
explained in the draft if they are not
clear please send the email under a
mailing list and the workflow I'm not
going to go through it too much for the
sake of time I want to leave the the
rest of the time open for any question
comments that are there one thing I want
to bring up is that from author's point
of view there is one author missing
which is by the microphone right now so
I do apologize on that you'll be added
on the next one please go I Holman this
is Tarek with juniper I'm gonna go easy
and effective SEO Marcy so Mike we did
this cuss offline and I don't want to
raise it debate here but we should be
open to the replication segments on
transit nodes to be shareable it's a it
we will discuss this further and there
might be reasons why not - I'm open to
them I'll leave it right there and that
that's a very good question and and and
I'm I know you we discussed this but for
the sake of working group I want to
bring up there are some differences
between multicast and unicast one of
those differences is if everybody here
remembers the old way of way we were
doing the unique acid for VP RN even
there was a subnet that was in a verse
that was connected to a tunnel so a
transport tunnel back in the days was
really identifying a subnet itself we
went away on the unique aside from this
mechanism we actually have now a VC
label or a rough label whatever you guys
want to call it that the transport
tunnel gets you to the end and then you
pop the transport tunnel you look at the
valve label or the the service label
gets you to the to the service and then
you do a lookup in that v RF and you
figure out where is your IP going on
multicast on fortune of behaviors
the stock in the 18th centuries so it a
transport tunnel a point-to-multipoint
LSP can identify a specific SG so you're
absolutely right in some cases we could
use replication and reuse it but for the
cases that that point to multi-point LSP
identifies a specific SG within the
worth we need to have a unique
identification of that point moil
multi-point lsv throughout the entire
path that's it yes we will work on it
try to figure out whether we can make it
reusable thank you woman thank you very
much I'm thinking about that Shoei
maintain some state of State on the
replication note right when you say is
say them not question so there is a
state there's definitely a state on the
data path and even depending on the
implementation maybe even on the on the
multicast or if they're there there will
be a state it just really moved their
protocol but the thing is if you use
beer so just yes it could be feasible
that two different or multiple yes it
will be a sub all is this code in a
certain part of the topology share the
same interrupt location state and
therefore you you know might the
replication policy but they might
diverge you know later down the tree and
so to do what you're suggesting you
probably have a carrier tree or it can
be policy context in the data plane
engineer so my point is it is feasible
but it comes at a cost
I reckon sorry I cut the line in the
movie yeah that is talking thank you
so the next presenter is remote that's
my mom
you know she can be quickly out of time
hello kami yes great I could model today
I'm going to pretend that you snitching
to PC for SR pass protection so first of
introduction we know that some of a
critical real-time at the live traffic
may be transported by SR pass for
example we may have a surpass from where
Punk to New York Stock Exchange which is
to be used to send requests for buying
or selling stocks we may also have SR
past connection between operational role
and polkas office which is used by
doctors to do remote surgery we may also
have some kind of as a pass to support
life Ethan's life broadcast so for all
these esta pass we need a fast
protections so without fast essa
protection we may have big loss for
example for real-time stock exchange or
trade if we have broken answer a pass
then we may lost lots of money for
example in the peer market the stock
away going down very fast so bank may
send a request to sell quick as quick as
possible to sell stock before the mock
market going down going down
so in so without fast protection if SF
has broken and then those requests were
not executed faster so we we almost not
so money so for what this case we will
have big loss result faster protection
for SR pass so night speech so we're
given over view about pass protection so
right now we have te else fees so for T
LSP is we have end-to-end fast
protections we have incurred production
we have a midpoint protection and then
we also have equals protections
however for SR plus we only have a few
drafts which proposed to put fast
protection for the only middle Point and
the egress ingress so there is a need
for provide fast protections for the
ingress note of SR pass so next page so
the extension for PCC for support has
equal protection is a very good feat
because right now we have PC extensions
for essa passport on oh so he's very
literate to extend the PCE to support SR
pass English protections so next page so
in order to provide SR plus interest
production we need to send some
information which is a lidded for
english production to the bike hub
equals node so the information we need
to send to the bankable ingress egress
not include bike hub as a pass primary
universe node address in some case and
also the description of the traffic
which is transported by the SA pass in
addition so essa pass may transport some
service
so those IDE of that surface which is
transported by the s epatha may also
need to send solitude the backup equals
note so for this for some of this
information the encoding we already have
for example for the SR passed primary of
us because we have extensions for the SR
sake policy in that exchanger where we
already have extensions for support as a
passing coding
so for pike harbors a passing coding
which we can reuse those encoding for SR
primary path so for the rest of them we
may have some kind of simple extensions
to PCE to support backup of support
image ingress protection so next page
so before we send all the information to
packable risk equals note so we also
have Sankar we need to have some kind of
ability exchanges banks ways to save
time can we skip the encoding and
directly move to the final questions it
wouldn't help really not be the best
time like we are running a little bit
late so people can go through the
encoding in your drafts so let's just
focus on the motivation and some
questions because the encoding is it was
so much weight you psyche it okay so we
need a comments and the suggestions of
discussions for this this one so I think
III raise some questions on the list as
well so I hope like you can answer them
a little bit more clearly and explain
why we would want the backup ingress to
do this protection and when the source
is anyway doing the
affection the why should backup ingress
detect and I got the not a direct answer
but I thought the your answer would be
that you don't want to make the backup
path active and only when the fail you
detect the failure at that time you make
the backup path active so these kind of
use case if you think it exists maybe we
can generalize them and we already do
flowspec for identifying of what flow to
go into a particular particular tunnel
so if you have a particular use case
maybe we can think of doing solving this
in a more general way rather than just
as a backup ingress that's just my
personal without my chair hat on opinion
thank you I think we need we generalize
this one so have we presented some use
the case in the draft and the pattern
will make a more sense agree yeah yeah
it's different so for orange I'm sorry I
haven't read the draft but it from first
year it's in similar to the Protection
Association is it really different or
not okay so what VI what is V very why
did you your voice is lower so yeah
sorry
so you were telling that you'd submit
out of the protection association so in
this case what is the value added that
you are bringing so you mean to which
one have protection association
protection we for let me try to answer
from what I gather the differences with
respect to detection like primary
getting failed that detection we never
talked about it an association draft and
this document somehow says that it's the
job of the backup ingress to somehow
detect the primary has failed and now
switch the traffic that's what I gather
I'm not wasn't sure but just
we can move the conversation along so if
we allow that when will we have the
second speaker ready let's go thank you
for representation thank you let's
present to give a present for my
colleague on yeah all of them are not
able to join a session and therefore
this contribute for this project in so
it's about as beautiful she see for
assigning to demand for the over real
there are some more passing has been
done they are being dying I have in
different working group so I just what I
could to give an overview of this but I
want to redesign that's try to save time
and then next okay okay
for this so I do it just give some
analysis about what we could do the
first amazing is a very direct and a
possible association and signalizing is
inter demand pass corrilesa or we can
call it association now this is a
different kind of a location of a past
segmental it could be located by the
past prior in the PCE or could be by
child oficial
she said and the english instructor we
consider two kinds of scenario the
facility in Terraria ii know i think i
yes it could be pieces in unity
throughout it could be stated for
Casilla hierarchic a PCE scenario next
for this slides away just gave us some
analysis of the case that is the inter
area case how it was this this I was
kidding in the story area together we
just try to use an association work what
was this - sorry I was a few second in
the together to a former and and I was
he passed
and next day some into a solution and
the in this case is a different from the
previous line in this case I would also
try to propose to use a stitching
liberals who try to form a end-to-end
pass with the included into a s pass
segment and the int sorry
intro yes and the inter yes it's a
consisted of a five five of a segment in
this scenario and this is a this draft
raises a some give some over real over
the absolution that we want to do by the
way
currently we did not give our extension
that may be needed
they also another companion Java Teresa
is a part of the Association Apogee at
retention which will be present in the
later and for the next step we sing we
will just to try to give some details
loose and for the Peace app and and also
we welcome any comments and discuss it
yeah a similar question was asked in the
SR when you presented this in the MPLS
working group that why the path segment
is being used for stitching so I don't
want you to answer right now but this is
something that I hope you can discuss in
spring or MPLS whichever is the right
place and then we can think about doing
this work NPC because our main concern
is whether this segment should be used
for stitching itself that needs to be
clarified before and now I also wear
there's another similar to awfully
working over the way have already talked
about also that work try to figure out
how to proceed next
his good morning everyone my name is
Ching I'm here to discuss RGB extension
for PC EP security capability support in
the PC discovered this job is Aris are
working to adapt and the basic idea is
so now we have dcpl suppose we have a
TRS supporter we have many different
security capability how to reproduce
these different ability to allow ECE to
company with his PCC so a quick update
actually this job actually is a DB
extension so that's why it discussed in
the Arisaka kukaku but it also
references our GP extension for PC a
discovery that we developed by the PCE
working cool so for for this job
actually we discussed in a Paris our
working group when during the carpet
option actually summer situations is to
consider to add the tier theory for the
key ID and a key name but to support
that actually we required to update the
obviously fake 50 88 and fifty eighty
nine and so that's actually we make this
change actually and this get adopted in
last night in November
ITA meeting in Tucson 18 so here what we
like arrays is we would really want to
get a feedback from PC would go it was
when we first bring up this draft that
didn't get a lot of Attraction so we do
to the concerns in iOS are but that we
didn't get feedback from the PC so for
the channel will make actually we
require to update of C
89 to allow the advertisement that
Tara's teacher several theory related to
the security parameter so we have some
feedback from Aris our Minister some
some people really some concern whether
we should advertise this and long RG
period information is may impact the
performance but the the benefited to
allow advertisers kinda capability is
actually you can really you know
piggyback some security community to
simplify the operational also we from
also perspective we think actually you
this kind of advertisement only you know
take place out of the initial stage
before you accept you the connection
between PC and PC you so it's not a big
deal actually to impact the performance
so but we'd like to hear the feedback
from a CPC working Co about these kind
of issues and for the second issue
actually also relate to this first the
issue that because some of people
suggest that maybe we can make it a base
for the FC 50 88 and 89 where them to
write another document to define these
kind of security support so we we we are
flexible for these issues and we want to
hear your feedback on this and in a
minute I'm actually you can come out and
right now we can you can come on it is
so wait we also can follow up how to
deal with these issues so for next step
we will look at all your comments and
and also to chair we want to make sure
whether these right a placing errors are
or in PC we can go yeah
comments thank you so so far working on
the external GPS so you make sense
show me from Eastern with the PC working
group with also for you event so it's
thank for that
back to the issue quickly because we
won't have much time to go over them but
second issue is for me under a set of
rate equation either graph remains in
the working group the way women are
progressing is up to the reserve rule
punchers and for the first question as
far as I remember the limitation about
further extension was imposed by the IGP
your eighty working groups at that time
so if now okay to move this limitation a
scene from the PC standpoint it's pero
to have this restriction removed Thanks
so we move to our last presentation for
today three four minutes thank you as I
mentioned in last apprentice and it's a
companion just that one it's about an
extension to try to solve the interior
case let's go directly into our case and
here for this case with other propose to
you the associate to try to extend the
Association projector to describe EULA
how to associate this RSP in different
area together and this is a format of
the association with us to use some flag
of the tree indicate the source of
transit and destination Tom I'm going a
little set this is I think this is the
only accessing units document so next
step we'll just want want to request
involve comments and any discuss are you
are welcome thank you
regarding with previous documents I
could write use name a chunk from Hawaii
regarding the previous presentation I
think it should be a information or
drops because there are nothing to do
with the extension right and that's it
yeah eating from Holley cucumbers I
think that Tibbets for the transmit SB
is not necessary because if an SP
segment is neither sauce l speak nor
that signature SP it should be always
the chance to meet else peace so I think
that tip it is not necessary I can tell
your comments to my colleague oh and
maybe you can discuss on you meaning is
yeah okay I think this this document
also has the same question about the
path segments and I think the stitching
the association becomes important if you
use part segment so I think that's the
key so for both the documents let's
resolve that and then we can progress
any other business okay see you in
Singapore
[Music]
okay I would show this to my colleague
I'm not for me Oh blue sheets people