good morning crowding we're starting our
second session assume hello yeah thank
you
my name is Asim chowsie and I am going
to provide the updates on queuing model
okay so I'm going to cover these topics
okay so there was adoption called in
version 7 of the model we got some
reasonable set of comments we had
replied to some of the comments beyond
sense some of the comments we clarified
some of the comments rest of the
comments we were able to incorporate and
based on that we were able to publish
wasn't n of the model next slide thank
you so basically you know some of the
comments would had been regarding the
references there were some missing
references there were some incorrect
references so for example we had a
reference for yang 1.1 into the draft we
added reference for the imported modules
also some of the yang nodes we provided
specific reference from the work which
had been done in the past in the various
RFC's for example for pali sir
one rate three color and two rate three
color we were able to provide reference
for RFC two six nine seven and two six
nine eight
similarly for choose and scheduler we
were able to provide comment through
solid reference through audacity to
eight nine
similarly we added reference for Yankee
diagrams which is RFC a340 as well as we
added reference for nmda architecture
all right so so some of the comments had
been regarding the dates that is for
either in some case in not updated and
so what we updated the dates for
copyright information we update that
it's for revision of the various modules
also we added section for I know
consideration we provided some editorial
note in the introduction section
detailing that you this particular you
know once the RFC is created and remove
this particular section or update the
RFC number according you annex I also
you know when we were going through when
we were reviewing the draft ourselves we
figured out that in the sir model we
need to provide further restriction into
in what cases we will be able to
configure difícil module and that will
be based on the divs or policy types so
accordingly we added a when statement
for it so to summarize the the draft you
know we have created a basic framework
of Q s as an classifier module we have
action module policy module and target
module and these are the base modules
based on these base modules we have
created set of derived modules which are
difícil module
and this'll include match and action
related to yourself but it takes those
matches an action and combine them
create the base framework of policy and
classifier and create a policy out of it
similarly we have created derived module
of queueing policy which actually work
on the metadata information and and then
we are able to configure the queuing
parameters similarly for excuse me
schedulers you know we have provided the
actions for scheduling also you know
that reference II have been provided
from the PS RFC's for that also this
model is very very adaptable to any
vendor requirements and any vendor
because the constructs are so different
across vendors fork us so they may be
able to you know use various match in
action and able to stitch with the base
framework of Q s and can create their
own set of model also and they can keep
adding lot of features they can keep
adding lot of a match in action when
they when there is a requirement for so
ok at the next step we expect any
further comment we we will be looking
for any further comment from the from
this community also vendor prototyping
is in progress in some cases also you
know to be realistic unless until this
is adopted and become a working group
duct document vendor will not invest
that much to actually implement the
draft so once it become a working
document then vendor will go ahead and
implement it out yeah ok let me finish
the last point also so currently you
know it is in candidate for working of
adoption
please provide your opinion on that
Thanks yes dan Bogdanovich so this
document has been being bounced around
now for seven years eight years not
really fears we study I think in 2015
yeah because before that because there
was a previous version of that document
that was in then we started into it was
restarted in 2014 because or even
beginning of 2014 because I was one of
the authors on that right you were part
of the doctor yes XO and we are still
trying to issue the first version of
that document okay document do you know
to start work so I think there's a good
reason for that though this is quite
difficult to standardize these QRS
models so it's not it's not a
coincidence but yes it could move faster
but what is your specific point well the
specific point here is that you're
trying to match on all the
functionalities instead of saying an
obstructing saying these are the basics
however how curious is working these are
the basic elements and then different
characteristics of those elements came
in and specifies afterwards but right
now we still don't have a common syntax
how to specifies you know POS in the
systems okay so so of the schools of
thought where we go we'll go with the
vendor C school of thought or vendors
Jason oh I think this has been clarified
in the past presentations that may be
proceeded and we understood that it will
be accepted by all is when we have a
kind of a superset of the model and that
not only is the operational excellence
in many cases but also it allows many
vendors to implement in a couple of ways
the same configuration in fact some of
the men I do allow the configuration
that in a multiple way to to ease the
operational excellence
so yeah means may
I'm missing the point here means what he
does pollution here you try to over
specify too many things in a single
draft without sorting just have a basic
syntax that could be implemented then
see and then adding you know the
additional curious features on top of
that nor example you know like there
buffers everybody's using buffers and
cue specify them describe them and then
different types of buffering and queuing
mechanisms depending on what vendor
supports which version can be then added
and extended keep excellent yeah it
means basically the queue schedulers and
police are the basics of the QoS so if
we don't have you know agreement on that
it's hard to say that we have a the us
model so we have to have agreement on
all those aspects the basic aspect of us
so I was really this hasn't been adopted
yet from my point of view I think fairly
obvious the ITF does want to do a qsr
model we've been working this for a long
time and it's changing I'm not sure we
need perfection here we need to get
something out and shipped and we can
extend over time so I I'd be very keen
to see this the doctor as it is there's
a lot of time spent on it and then
refine it a bit as as we go but try and
actually gets out the door because
you've got lots of other yang models out
there and we people want to use these or
or should be wanted to use them so we
want to try and push this along if you
can
okay so yeah means that the model has
been stable for some time now
it just said you know be helping the
question for more and what comment so
that we can incorporate those there was
a versus seven there was an option
called
we got some comments regarding the you
know mainly regarding the format and
some of the correction to be done in the
drops which we have done but other than
that yeah the model has been stable for
some time defense former range I have a
senior event has then had about not the
complexity but we develop details in
terms of scheduling which is in
currently in the document because
especially the scheduling is something
which is really oddly dependent and you
may not be able to do exactly the same
thing and express it at least in the
same way on one Hardware of yoga so I'm
really happy to see that you have some
vendors that are trying to prototype
this model and I will be really happy to
see the outcomes of this prototyping if
it's something that which which is
really physical in term of madhuri or
not okay so there had been some
reference in the past in the
particularly the RFC three two eight
nine and we are actually describe about
the scheduling parameters and all so we
have referred that - you know model this
one so and we have similarity across
vendors to implement those scheduling
the pieces there are some similarities
but it's not exactly the same and today
we are already facing some issues when
we are moving from one platform to be
over to really express our customer that
because sometimes it's completely
different we cannot really do exactly
the same thing so okay so has to
understand that specific so that but as
we have debated across vendors we do
have a similar set of parameter when it
comes to scheduling and queuing a
ceiling the masses of systems I in
defense of this I haven't reviewed the
latest version but I did a review what a
couple years at least year-and-a-half
ago or something of this model and it's
it's not the one of the real problems is
is chip designers have had no motivation
to have any common analogy and the in
their QoS the way it's attached and
there's and at one time I worked on
trying to unify the CLI this was years
ago for different line cards families in
the same chassis but but it was just
about it was a hard problem exacting a
minimum subset and you you really
couldn't get something that was bit
one-size-fits-all for it exactly means
it's not easy prominent assault but over
a period of time we have debated a lot
we have come up with the model which
actually works for all and we see that
all the vendors will be able to adopt
the way we have design it right now and
so I'm pretty confident that any vendor
will be able to use this model to to
configure their device even though you
know for all the you know even for a
single vendor there will be differences
for qsr based on the platforms in all
but they still you know provide that
common CLI across it and so we have
merged all them together and I think all
the vendors should be able to probably a
pretty confident for that so in terms of
this document we already like start an
adoption call back in December I think
exit Nam and a lot of this you know the
changes you've applied or responses to
that and so and other feedback so I mean
we're planning to adopt this we've
gotten a lot of feedback that this
approach possibly isn't as useful as
another approach but does anyone
actually have an objection to going
ahead and you know adopting this as a
working group document polishing it off
and publishing it as you know this isn't
a working group last call but in general
our intention would be to adopt it
finish it off publish it does that
produce any damage any objections to
that I'm supportive I'm very supportive
to adopt it as a working group document
I just considered this document too
complex that's you know that's one part
and if people try to put some of the
other daughters some of the other
related models to work with this small
or will run into challenges okay but but
do you see this as a good basis to start
with to adopt and I would cut down
significant amounts of document but this
is my personal opinion okay okay so
would anyone opposed to adopt this work
here and start refining iterating
through
sounds good so we'll continue that
option process and they're a bunch of
warnings please fix them before okay
thank you thank you hi so we've been
working some of us for on automation for
multiple years and on the management and
as we are implementing some of the
concepts we are seeing some of the
problems that we are running into it and
some of you know I read so I really when
I saw this on Twitter I really liked it
because we are putting the cart in front
of the horse there are some changes
coming in the networking that will
require some significantly different and
approach to how we are doing network
automation but we are still using some
of in my opinion concepts that are where
too much device related and not much
service related why I'm saying this we
are seeing a large increase in routing
endpoints in networks today large
networks will have six seven thousand
routing points we are talking to service
providers that are planning to increase
their networks to 120 plus thousand
endpoints AT&T publicly announced
they're adding 60,000 routing points in
their in their network and how we are
doing network management today I don't
see how we can effect it will scale that
because the traditional network
management it is very much focused on a
single device you are building up from
multiple device configurations you're
building up a service
the larger the network is the harder it
will it will be it will be harder to do
that as well it will you know take
longer to provision new services across
significantly larger network than what
we have today we are trying to move away
from a human interface to a machine
interface but some of the content that
is being provided through the human
interface we are just translating it
directly into a machine interface and we
are missing some abstractions we are
trying to do that with the models but
still models are too much I would just
point out to the QoS which in my opinion
is to be the reason I'm pointing it out
because it was the last one mentioned
just before Mike before my presentation
but it is instead of trying to abstract
actions and saying this is the abstract
way how we can do it and it can be
implemented across multiple different
architectures we are trying to cram all
the architectures into one model and
then we ending up with something pretty
complex that is not helping us moving
forward as well
we are not improving the programmability
the programmable capabilities of the
network that we are trying to do I put
in here a couple of you know essentially
these are descriptions different lecture
definitions but the key thing is that in
the automation with minimal or no human
intervention there are a few private
enterprise operators that are very good
at doing this but many people of them
their self relying on the CLI and on the
human operators the idea is that we have
to if you want really to scale those
networks and provide those new services
we have to rethink you know some of the
management how it's done even you know
some of the tools because the idea is
look you have to do it from a service
perspective
and from a service going down
essentially turn it upside down this
brings us to the API management you know
approach and we have today some tools
and protocols that are there some of
them are developed within the ITF
community some of them are being done by
the vendors some of them are being done
by the consortiums plus open source
they're all helping us rethink how we
are doing the automation in seeing how
we are you know how we can move forward
in order to address the new requirements
but some of us also have to switch the
net engineers we have to switch our
thinking and start thinking more in
doing programs what I will show this
later there are no conditional loops in
the configurational data that we are
doing it will be very nice to see oh how
can we add unit tests for certain
functionalities as a network engineer
and this is this is one part that we
have to start thinking more in trying to
adopt more software development
techniques instead of what we were doing
through different vendors provisioning
processes that were mainly saying oh
here's the business logic that want to
be executed on the device but I cannot
put any conditional statements inside
that provisioning information with the
API definition requirements we are
defining the and what we are doing here
at the ITF with the data models we are
essentially defining and we are we are
describing different levels of
functionalities that are available in
the devices as well in the networks we
are talking about what operations can we
do we are deciding how we can you know
send the data back and forth that we can
understand it that we have standardized
it because most of those things which
are well known within the software
development in the networking until
where recently was very
on its own and our best tool was tickle
and expect and we all know the paint's
that was causing us that the data models
there are you know so again there are
vendor models there are some community
models I'm just building you know going
for all of that just giving you a brief
overview but some of the models I'm
saying we have to do we have to provide
better abstractions if we we can say
there are common functionalities that
every single vendor is using but how
those functionalities are implemented
should be abstracted away we should we
should not continue pushing up those
implementation details into the higher
levels throughout the data models if we
continue doing that we will not be able
to scale the management forward and then
all the efforts that we are doing will
be I don't on the same vein but I'm
going to say so the transfer protocols
they are multiple of them everybody can
decide which one they want to use but
one of the things which I'm a little bit
concerned is that G RPC is becoming the
facto standard for telemetry if G RPC is
more or less owned by a vendor mom a by
a by a single enterprise and not what we
need all of us commonly might be good
for us what might be good for that
enterprise and seeing more and more
requirements that saying oh we want you
know GRP cg and a my support is you know
it's a nice thing to hear because if
they're providing some good mechanisms
they're a good framework on the other
hand I'm also hearing some concerns that
some that the framework is not
sufficient enough for what some other
operators network operators would like
to do so if we are looking at B in
network device configuration and
management api's is
we have device resource and network
functions that should be used for high
level data models if in the net mod
working group we're trying to define how
can we build up packages that will
provide the abstractions for different
functionalities and systems that you
want to build in order to ease the
management and provide common schemas to
the higher level ones the point there is
the young data model is in the young
language is a common it's a common
language that is adopted some people
prefer protobuf / yang but majority of
majority of the industry settling down
on yang the bad part of that thing is
it's too much tight to two out of three
available transport protocols that are
in use widely today and us working on
trying to say hey there is another
framework that is being de facto
standard but yang is a standard and
those things are incompatible is a
problem that needs to be solving that we
should you know start thinking about
that because the more we will grow apart
the harder it will be to come together
and we will run again into a management
problem forgot to mention at the
beginning there is a I heard it from
several people that the golden standard
for network management was the Wellfleet
frame relay network management suite and
many operators are remembering how
nicely it was done they saying if you
can provide us something like that we
will love to buy your product because we
needed a very small number of operators
in for us to manage a continental scale
network and we have to do that but we
have to be sometimes a little bit more
open and saying let's forget about the
implementation details and decide on the
functional details in order to move it
forward and make sure that what the
industry is doing that we are you know
aligning the common interest across that
and making sure that we are not letting
certain things out because it can you
know really hurt us
this is a example of a open config
device model and the reason why I'm you
know putting it out this is done by a
consortium and they put in
functionalities in there that they
really need it there are things that
could be you know extended there are
things in there that are you know
missing but there are also things that
are there that could be used that my
main my main issue there is it's a
device model where is the where is the
next one the service models on top of
that in the ITF we have two service
models that we have worked so far at the
L to SM and l3 SM we need many other
service models that can set you know on
top of the device walls and built up if
you look again into the open config G
RPC interfaces and I'm going here a
little bit more Ruggieri's interfaces
since last time they're presented at the
ITF there has been an evolution and some
of the concept that did that we did in
the ITF and drop they picked them up and
or they came with their own ideas that
were similar to ours ideas and expanded
that one of the interesting interfaces
that they added is the G ribeye this is
you know if some people might remember
the I to RS the original ideas of the
ITRs and JIRA by have certain things in
common
but then the very interesting part is
how the integrating with the G NMR and
getting the information of your body
from informational state they can use
for certain you know other operations
and this is a nice example how they were
building on top of the abstractions and
putting you know into a pretty common
frame pretty foundational framework that
works well if you want to build
different applications on top of that so
quickly why like G nmi it
you essentially capabilities so you're
getting you know okay
give me the the capabilities what are
there I can get and set on them and I
can subscribe and I like the way how
their subscription stream works I think
that what some of our subscription
frameworks that we have available today
have things missing I also don't think
they I think they are too heavy for the
devices and we should try to see what
can be changed and what can be adapted
from some of the other frameworks
because one thing what I really love
about the jean-mi is for the telemetry
and you can decide okay here's my you
know I want to subscribe and this is the
path to the path element for which data
information I want to get this is
interesting because you can create
telemetry you can create data collection
subscriptions for a cert for specific
service and get data for that service
that means when I write an application
that provisions the service I can
subscribe only to that service relevant
information and use that as certain
event triggers that can provide the
corrective actions that can be the input
for my conditional statements in my
service provisioning in in in my service
provisioning logic so do we have the
right tools today yes and no we have the
right ideas some of our implementations
could be better you know
I'm guilty as charged I've been working
on that for years and you know we are
learning as we are moving forward but
getting I will make a call out that US
vendors are not the best people to talk
to and rely on us on how to do
operations I've been a vendor my whole
life so you know this is the one part
that but we also know how to do certain
abstractions and we should do that
forget the implementation details focus
on the functionalities and saying this
is what we can do as a vendor the
is what we can get input from the
service you know from the action from
the network operators and use the input
from the network operators to refine the
network functions that we are providing
to them to build the network services
the service Wallace has mentioned you
know they are two of them open config I
will say the only define you know model
set the device level and growing the
network just based on the device level
will not scale we will run into many
problems if you will you know when we
see like a 10 or 20 X increase in size
of our networks the way how we are
managing you know that today and the
many network operators have their own
proprietary tools that they are creating
in order you know to manage the services
this how they are managing this how they
manage network how they are creating the
value and this is how they are at the
end making money making profits if we
can help them by providing them better
tools for them to create the higher you
know values that will you know be also
better for our industry in general so
the question is could we use any
reasonable pattern to design and
automate networking service there's
something that we should be asking us
when we are working on any of the
standards that we are working on so we
try to classify certain things you know
in the ITF but yesterday during the
first working group session the
presentation from Reza and Nokia he was
mainly talking about translation of a
business service into lower layers I
will say that again we are not the right
community to define the business
services and interfaces to the business
services but we can help them to define
an interface between the business
service and the network service and then
you know going down into how the network
service is being decomposed into
multiple Network functions based on the
characteristics that the customer is
asking for and what the network operator
currently supports
for the network service automation you
always have essentially three heads one
of them is a business user I like to say
this is our good old non PLM here they
have to define the use cases tell us you
know what use cases have to be defined
and the network operator knows about
troubleshooting operations provisioning
and then we have a network developer
when they talk to some of the VARs and s
i--'s today they're saying we have 2000
CC II's and 1800 J and C is great but
those guys cannot really they are good
as a network developers you know the
question is how many of them are as a
network operators and how many of them
will be really good at translating the
business user requirements into you know
into the lower layers so if you look at
the traditional network service
orchestration approach you still have a
network operator that is following the
alarms and then executing certain
predetermined actions when I was working
for a large vendor at an SDK
one of the biggest applications they
were using for the SDK was preset
commands that the network operator was
executing based on the alarms they were
creating custom CLI for a different
level of an operator I'm asking why do
you need that operator in there to
execute on that create a loop control
loop and let that automate that and let
that operator do something more valuable
but our tools are not there yet
because if we want to build an ensign
application the natural developer has to
listen to the business guide they have
to look at the operators guys and say
this is my business technical and
operational requirements and I will put
that together into a single network
application I will be using the the the
well-known procedures of software
development where I can unit test my
functions I can unit test my service I
can do you know different types of
testing functional testing on that
I can run that application multiple
times I will have no the predictable
results when we have been up putting in
different configurations we are still
trying to figure out what is the state
we are not always sure that the state on
the network will be what we were really
putting it and if we would go from a
top-down perspective saying this is the
predicted state we can then compare what
is the state on each device and try to
do the corrective actions and that would
be the first part is that we have to
saying we are having a set of api's from
our devices that are being you know
streamed upstream data being from a
network service instance being pushed
down and they're being you know
essentially streamed up for the
monitoring you know of the device
resources this would be the step one
when we are trying to add conditions on
the network to be tested and verified
where our service logic based is
checking on the function that we have
invoked if we build the right service
and we can then provide another API to a
high level application to be consumed by
that if we can achieve that today there
are certain operators and enterprise
they're building on that they have
experience on that and I would be happy
to you know work on such architectures
discrete descriptions just as in
informational documents with the other
people but now where we really have to
start going as the next step is deciding
hey we have a distributed device
management platform and I really want to
have a streaming event bus that is
providing the operational and
provisional interface in one I'm just
passing into the stream and that's in
the stream will push the data to all the
devices for the service so instead of
being on the device base I have a
service level in that service level
because device is configured for certain
types of events it will receive the
provisioning information but it's also
sent back the operational data for that
there is a pretty good framework out
there that is done by a vendor and there
are certain things that I would like to
see in that framework to be expanded and
extended
maybe even standardized because this
would be very helpful and that we can
have for the configuration actions as
well for the monitoring actions a single
API we can have a single common data
model for both of them which would makes
the something because one of our biggest
promise realization between the
operational model and the
configurational model and trying to
figure out what does this operational
model mean in configurational terms this
should you know be able to simplify the
actions that we are trying to do and
then as the last iteration would be that
instead of having enough separate
configuration and operational parts we
will just have a network service
instance that would be using data lying
SDK and instead of being an expert in
CLI you would say oh this in your
library that they have to learn in order
to be able to provision this new service
and writing a new application would be
network independent as well as a vendor
independent because you're talking about
the abstractions and saying look for me
to do a filter have to have a match
condition I have to have a action on top
of that and I will be learning about
different types of actions and match and
actual conditions I have available in
order to execute on that I can find out
from the network what is available what
is not available are the resources are
there are no resources and based on that
make a decision can something like that
be deployed across the service topology
or not these days why do we still have
to use rollback and then question is
what is the state across my network
after I did the rollback and that would
be the end of the application the
presentation and if you have any
questions I welcome
but my class of 510 for this so it's
great
now what I'm missing is okay what are
the top three things we should be doing
in this community to get together top
three things what are the top three
things we should be doing now to get
there in this community I will welcome
getting so I will go back to QoS and
Akko to have it better abstract it'd be
less implementation detail so provide
better abstractions for all the yang
models get in try to reach out because
my big war is telemetry and GN mi is a
really good telemetry framework what we
are doing here needs a lot of you know
work and I don't think that it can scale
to what we are to what we need and try
to re-engage the GN mi in order in
together that so but then also I would
ask that vendor to be sometimes a little
bit more open to our input as well what
we are proposing back because we also
have our own reasons why we need certain
things that my different you know from
defender so my I will say again we need
better abstractions for devices for
therefore the network functions devices
network functions and a certain extent
first for network services so I like to
presentations good and I think that I
agree that would be useful to have an
official draft documenting how to use
some of this and do the lifecycle
management through yang unless they have
that be greatly beneficial and I have an
interested in that's what suffers well
one question on this particular is what
do you see the s what do you see the API
has between the operators and the
services is that something that's
written in yang or is that a
programmatic interface in some
particular language its programmatic
interfaces whichever language you know
you prefer and you like to use okay so
who writes that SDK and who chooses that
language so
if so the the language the you have
frameworks that can once you write the
definition can give you a library in
many different languages and it's a
question now how you can get the data
model be translated into the language so
I will not go into the specific
different frameworks that are providing
you their functionality but that should
you know there are frameworks out there
that can be used and again it would be
easier I will come down to that if yang
would be a little bit more independent
to be able to write some of those
translation between Yang and some of the
other frameworks without having the
other transfer protocol restrictions
what we have we could you know work from
there
so this is another part that we could
you know we work in as a community
because yang is being adopted and it's a
useful tool that we can use but we have
to evolve
I mean they also I would like to see
more about yang next what he could do
you know there was young next and then
suddenly it disappeared it vanished
so I I don't want to be very much per se
on the language specific I say this is a
common interface that we can use in
order to provide there can be variants
of the features that are supported
within that but it's they share a common
syntax okay so does that mean really you
need to translate yang into something
like open api or swipe or something and
then that could be used to generate
whatever language findings you want yeah
listen Leon from sallee Oh from North
American we support different defense I
have two questions one question is aware
of northbound interface in this
architecture and the second question is
regarding this
streaming event bass so he's past you
are talking about pops up which is
required
communication for telemetry may be fine
but for the per inning how you guarantee
you know what your print will be
immediately you know being committed
it's working
your pops Avenida synchronize not
necessary what do you intend to present
well beeper yeah so there may be delayed
okay so I have a question now first you
ask worse than North but the interface
word the north and salbon interfaces are
and then the second question is how do
you guarantee the networks that the that
the provisioning information was it has
been provisioned across the service that
you desire yeah
so on the northbound and solve an
interface this is relative you know
where you're putting in in this case
yeah southbound I should have put it
there an API and say this is my API to
the devices and think about devices are
the physical layer that are doing the
packet forwarding then you have the
device management platform is where you
are abstracting the devices in a set of
functions and the resources that they
are using as well you are providing you
know the the messaging the message bus
that has the provisioning and the
operational data that you can subscribe
to that you can you know collect and
send the data to so you have here
multiple northbound and solve on
interfaces I am NOT hung up and very
much on that
what framework it is I just want to
define what are those you know data
models what are the schemas for those
interfaces for the what the actual
implementation will it be on that part
what today might be on tomorrow might be
you know protobufs day after tomorrow
might be you know shameless you know
blog Volta bus whatever doesn't matter
and if we can agree on the general
network management architecture that
would help us with the next step forward
and then you're asking me how can I
guarantee that my provisioning was
correctly across the network across the
service topology so I can when I'm
writing software
I can always the unit test and verify
that I have the outcome today when I
want to write unit tests the operational
model and the provisional model are
different and have to do transformation
with the data and making sure it was
this really what I meant
does this you know operational model
really translates correctly into my
provisioning model and vice versa so
this is one of the problems that we have
today when we are doing that if you can
remove some of those abstractions in
between then you can start doing unit
testing and making sure through others
you can then decide what do it does it
have to be an end function or it has to
be an end function or how will you know
combined of each of those unit tested
you're they're going across the network
what would be the final outcome this is
what the network operator can decide
based on their own internal policies so
in the synchronize the communication
busier you send the request your
autonomy that come back e-reading effect
few seconds but for us here is the bus
you send something with what you respond
may come back our later
so you either no guarantee you will miss
so it's bad that's a big difference
so for telemetry it probably is fine but
hold on so email please say there I just
want to make sure they understood so the
first of all you said you're interested
in if the data is correct is
synchronized so it's super busy like you
can write a right Reggie of software
right for simple right
synchronized communication means you
send the request you respond I'll come
back within second expected is come back
with our short time window but we will
give you utilize the search path which
is mr. is a pop subscription model this
means you can be sure it's a
synchronized you send a request you
respond we come back hours later so you
now guard he'll come back within a few
seconds so these days sometimes to get
the wire that get the state on the wire
takes 20 minutes so a few seconds I will
see that there's a quite a good of
improvement I mean I if I find this with
your question is today we have a problem
that you know different devices take
times in order to get a note on the on
the same to get the same provisioning
information my network state suitable
for any type of traffic is good for
telemetrics but now may not be good for
Prairie then can you try to answer his
question say for you if I'm chief on
your from that of all the networks so
for the scenario you described it's
pretty much like notification
it's a other kind of notification not a
telemetry so for that kind of
notification other common management
protocols are they support that nikon
has notification and there so you can
get the nod of cleaner that way two
questions for clarifications the first
one he songs sliced you have two
platforms and both of them are marked as
distributed here so from the service one
we have multiple instance and and it
looks like a distributive system but the
bottom one we call it the device
management system and it looks like it
should be centralized reminder explain
why you think this is distributed system
devices in general are will be so so and
then like if I want to create a single
centralized management platform the
question is how to scale it and if the
idea there is that you want to keep up
certain latency requirements for the
certain devices that you're abstracting
in the geographical area you could be
using today's technology can bull build
a single device management platform for
the whole us for the whole North America
but how much does it make sense because
of the latency that you will be seeing
in order to communicate those devices
collected so if you are doing some
hierarchical
management platform assortment platform
that is distributed you can you know get
to certain performances that you need in
order to do the right provisioning okay
so there can also be multiple platforms
on the same level and they do the top
with each other or how they interact I
mean not the scale on the scalability
perspective okay it's okay to have
multiple platforms also same hierarchy
so there are different schools of
thought on that and this is a you know a
so if I would that's an example how
would you want to do database sharding
and how they want to implement that
there is a question how different people
will do it then different people might
have different ways of implementing that
but they can come up to the you know
same result in this presentation you
talk about a lot about the network
service and if I understand the crackly
low service is something that called
exists in the service management
platform and something beyond it for the
user plain I also notice that in this
slide and some other previous slides the
term service is missed in the kind of
device management platform so are you
implying are you implying that the
service say the management platform is
is not aware of this network service or
so the device management platform and
the service platforms are different and
I was talking to you more about network
management than specific services I just
see it as build ups on one on top of the
other because the network operator for
them services are revenue generating and
the control plane the physical layer is
a cost center so they would be focused
mainly on services how they can
provision the services faster with more
ease it
or to satisfy the customer demands in
making sure that the underlying
operational infrastructure is being
managed most efficiently API here we
basically focus more on the resource
rather than the service right it's its
capabilities and resources they are very
tightly coupled together and so just the
last two questioners and we're closing
the line here and try to wrap it up in
about five minutes
Stephanie from Orange I have a very very
open question and I don't have any
strong opinion about it
let's focus in 10 or 20 years okay
abstraction are really something which
is required especially from provisioning
because it will speed up how we are
creating services and so on but now if
we are focusing on really network
operations don't you think that at least
on the operator side people may lose
some skills and will not understand
anymore how things are really working if
they are only manipulating abstraction I
can go back through the same way their
computer science are we losing you know
that people are only learning
higher-level languages there will be
people who will want to understand the
system throughout that would like to
understand how packet pipeline is
working but I don't see that within a
large enterprise like yours you will
have five thousand people that are
really interested in knowing how packet
pipeline you know creation is working
you might be interested you might really
want to dig that understand that there
will be people who really would like to
know that and they will dig into it they
will be able to go through those but in
order sometimes to understand how things
are working I go back to the days when I
went to school and you know I had the
you know like a piggy board and in order
to do certain functions and the
programming I had to shortcut them in
order to get there and to understand how
high-level concepts are was a pretty
of journey and sometimes saying oh this
and some of the new concepts you see the
abstractions then they may go down
understanding it and you're learning
some use up so it there is something to
be said for both yeah because I'm still
not concerned or worried better some
question about yeah 20 years if for
example I have a packet which is taking
one cue you know one specific chip of my
box which still I be able to know it
yeah well this is a good beer above
discussion cisco say i just want to
comment on this is some discussion early
on about secrets versus a secrets
probing models for doing configuration
i'm a big fan of doing this in an
asynchronous way where you push the
configuration down and you assume that
the device will take some amount of time
to apply that configuration and not only
that but if the configuration set is
large different parts that configuration
we applied over a period of time
so i think there's a there's a lot of
benefits of being able to monitor and
get telemetry data backup of what the
configuration changes are so you can
actually see what the device is doing
over that period of time rather than
getting a snapshot after twenty minutes
is that now it's all done and in that in
that window you don't really know what
it's doing so that's one benefit of
doing this in a serious way another one
is if you want to be modifying your
devices a relatively high frequency you
don't want to be blocking and waiting
for each device to reply back before you
move on to the next one on certain
things you have to do that there are
certain provisioning actions that
require you to do that yes agree but I
wonder whether those provision actions
that should be controlled by the
controller or as the sequencing and not
the devices themselves yeah thank you
Halla document dealing with us pretty
much in daily basis I would second you
have to be a synchronous networking if
distributed system you don't want to
deal with slurry there's slow writers
you have to do this we cannot go into
synchronous month with thousands of
devices you'll be looking forever so
it's personal comment so next up is
Oscar Gonzalez did years
do we need okay can you hear me now yes
you can do you okay okay I think I I
immediately I just needed to press the
blue button the blue button okay so
thank you very much guys it's a pity not
to be with you today but fortunately we
have these remote facilities to to
present so I think this or the idea
today is to present you the layer 3 VPN
network model that will have lessened
this admitted together with some other
operators and there was a request in the
middle is to present it in the routine
working group especially a wide we need
a new model and implications with the
rest of modern-day architectural
implications so please if you um move
one more slide okay so we'll I'll go
from Kratos do we need a net model for
billing service so we will see how to
use it in the different architectures
that we have seen and what is is in in
the in current approaches how are we
doing this and which are the open issues
please go to the next slide okay so
first of all why do with network for the
VPN so we have already a layer three a
service model the one that is defined in
RFC 899 there this model is very nice
and describe the service from the
customer perspective and it can be seen
the communication between the customer
and the network operator so we think
this model is good for that a
communication so this does not enter a
discussion of the parameterization of
the net
the resources that you need to
orchestrate in the in the network and
also it does not enter in to how the
service is mapped inside of Peters
Network okay so please go go ahead
Nexus light please okay can you move one
slide okay so so what would be the the
architecture so we have taken the
pictures from the RFC and map their
different models so in a deadener
architecture what we'll have is that the
customer that is the user of the service
they can be is a l3 same model to
communicate with the service
orchestration layer in the operator okay
so that will have a working gun young
model for that and as we said this model
should not carry me anything about the
network resources even internal routing
details he's just his part of the of the
movie okay so then we have the what we
call the service the network model so
this describes the service as perceived
by the network and he saying that a
business the input to automated tools so
you can do the provisioning you can do
the assurance so some model to be used
by the operators okay so this work came
as input so when we started to do our
automation in telefónica and in other
service providers and then we started
looking at the models and try to
implement the models when we discover
that the current existing models were
not enough or were not died at the end
that what we needed
okay
so this model he cares about topological
details for someone understands about a
piece and also is able to understand
about a network source for example the
allocation of artists and artists that
they do sometimes precise they also you
need to give them as input when you want
to create a service especially when you
need to go through multiple domains that
preserve some of these parameters across
different segments then you need to
include them in the network model but
those days you don't need them for the
customer the customer can't forget about
them also a model but it is aimed at
input to automation tools
it does not detail how the service is
transported and also does not detail the
node configuration that is the role of
the automated layer to again translate
this this model into device
configuration so here also we are
assuming that the routine is already
configured so you don't need to do it in
advance without entering that in the in
the model so also later this
orchestration layer will take care of
how to present a service if it's needed
to set up new Gillespie's who to
transport it ok he will take care of
that occasion next slide please
so also we can try to map the
dispatchers in the ICT and architecture
so here the this model in conjunction
with other other models will be used a
in the multi domain service controller
part or between the MDI parent and MDC a
child ok so we think there is where the
model the model will will apply ok and
but not in the device constellation part
okay so we live l3 SM between customer
homonym Yesi and internal energy NC on
between parent and child so please you
go to next next slide okay so what is
missing in the in current service model
is the reason while creating the the
network model so there are some Easton
areas where the the service model from
the customer perspective is not
sufficient for the plot of the service
so we need to identify and to identify
the provider rates where we are going to
deploy the service also we need data
submitters so I think we think that the
key are the the bidders that are the
physical connections to the piece so
that is the network element and the port
but correct like so we need the eeriest
and I think a peon and we need also the
list of the pillars that are available
for each side also we need to have cases
where we need the remote-firing
configuration for example we have use
cases in our operation where we have a
pseudo wire stitching to an l3 VPN also
a we have cases for multi domain
resource management so we have to our
VPN is splitted in several domains also
we need some configuration a specific
tool to donoso lastly the equivalent to
the to the PRF that we need to specify
from service definition and also to
cover more routing protocols between C
and NP okay so next slide please
okay so I do it so we are doing a
Protestant approach okay so we try to
preserve as much as possible the
structure of the of the service model
and just to remove what is unnecessary
for the network perspective everything
about customer details and locations etc
from the customer and we can remove them
and we extend extended to consider more
the operator perspective so we include
the concept of a VPN nobles and the
people willing them to the bidders that
are the connections to the VPN nodes
okay so I don't want to enter into the
details of the other model itself that
is for you to read and discuss here just
to present a concept the concept today
okay so maybe can you go to the next and
the next slide please
okay so what are the open issues and I
think those are the ones that are some
of them related to the previous talk or
team so first of all is how to link the
network solution model with other
modules so we are assuming that the
network operation the network automation
also called some people call it Sdn
controllers as you want it there will be
set off a modules available there and
they need to be linked to each other for
example topology a first one so we
assume that the service endpoints or the
solution or the points from where we
want to establish services they are part
of an existing topology okay so to link
them somehow a for traffic exceeding
there is already a proposal in in yes to
be able to map a success and a also the
LSP analyst at this this is need to be a
completed and road
another part is dead there's another
chance the compulsion to create any
scenarios that go beyond the single
operator services so this is only custom
thing over for example I shouldn't say
sparrows who is also some of initiatives
to deal with a hierarchy of controllers
so in many cases we live in the reality
that each domain is a domain it will
have its own control we need to create a
hierarchy so can we create this model
genetic enough so it allows this
hierarchy also we have some as in every
new design every time we have our own
model in discussions for example the set
attachments if you have separate
container or part of assignment
velocities are just people young modern
discussions also for example the use of
profiles versus creating the resources
deadly under the EPA no concept so here
we have our pros and cons of disability
but you said yes I think mine or a lot
more I can discuss and not as general so
for me general discussion that is a need
or what IDF an especially rooting row
working group can help is how to link
different young modems together so that
they are not separated modules Islands
because otherwise it is and you have to
do hugs or tricks to be able to link
them together ok so you got to just
operators as well network so thank you
much and I hope that the remote
presentation so open to questions I was
the singer Britain so just question for
clarification today we have Leah 3sm
model right as you mentioned that allows
clients to communicate service to the
network we have numerous models for the
network Orchestrator for example to
discover topologies ok including multi
domain scenario setting up tunnels we
are also working on the model that
allows steering services like layer 3
services to the tunnels O'Donnell pools
or even topologies of slices so
basically it is not really clear for me
what exactly is missing and those those
last pieces of work that you have
mentioned I have a complimentary ok so
what this year or what these complements
is the service
model that currently the service model
is just created from the perspective of
the customer so for example the customer
does not see where the quality to which
a specific port is it is connected in
the network he does not care it can go
through difference which is it it does
not know to which encapsulation it is
reaching your network so that you can
use it as input and the operator can
decide okay based on this service
description I am going to put this
customer in this P and I'm going to put
it in this particular in port and with
this particular encapsulation so that is
not part of the service model because
that is done from his perspective so
this is why it complements the the
service is the current series model so
it is a description of the series from
the network perspective okay so this is
why and the other works that you just
mentioned the stealing of the traffic
etcetera they are complimentary to to
this one okay and the other things that
are missing they are there Spain also
they for example the l3 same does not
have parameters like artists or artists
that as operators when we create a
service we give them and today the l3
same model explicitly says that they do
not enter into that resource allocation
so in the network model as operators we
need to enter into that resource
allocation business so this is why we
have to obtain today to the model so but
what is not expected to get into the
network resources right yes yes the
client yes
but this is this model is not a not
being used by the by the customer okay
the customer is fine so the customer is
perfectly fine from with using their
three same model okay so this is from
the service orchestration on a layer or
the OSS layer within an operator today
to a network controller so this is the
particular part of the chain or the tool
chain in an operator where we do think
this model is is needed and where we are
going to implement it so the network
historico takes as an input
but our client communicates over a layer
3 sm model and then it use separate
models right to discover and basically
allocate resources and set up services
ok so we are talking about different
models which are all in progress right
some of them in tears some of them in
the source right so basically from what
you well what I hear there is something
missing in terms of client to discover
how their services map to the access
points but beyond that I don't
understand we need to talk on on the
Beast ok yes please please feel free to
to comment on the on the list and and we
are happy to clarify there and and to be
clear that would be in the up Syria
working group list yeah so far we are
discussing there in in ops area working
group list ok we'll take the last two
sets of questions yeah this Prakash I
have question regarding your service
model is there any dependency on the
device model because finally the
services has to be implemented by by the
device itself so do you see a
relationship or any dependency on the
device model or they are totally
independent so so far is it it is
independent
okay for that what or the piece that you
are talking would be the some circus
decomposition into device model so far
it is independent and I think it should
be independent on how you implement it
okay so so far independent so the
assumption is that the service has been
implemented by some kind of consistent
technology across the devices a
different segment of the networks are
being enough made of the same kind of
using the same kind of technology or yes
I am assuming that the that the
controller of that portion of the
network is able to provide the service
based on doing his device configurations
and this model I don't enter how they
should do those configurations could you
please repeat a name for the either bed
your name thank you
Bob Wilson Cisco so I just had one
question on your implementation you say
that you prune and extend and I was
wondering about the prune bit
particularly the cases like hierarchical
models where you want to have
hierarchical controllers I was wondering
what you need to carry some of the
information that's in the l3 SM top
model further down the stack and hence
whether it should be more extend improve
I don't I don't know either the model so
they know what's been proved so far let
me clarify that the we have done extend
and we have not yet started the prune
okay so yes when we start the prune it
will see how much a can we remove from
the l3 SM or how much do we need to pass
from from
threesome I guess all the technical and
routine CP part will be kept and we will
just have to remove some of the more
commercial related information or the
site related information which is
relevant for the service but not for the
for the network okay so this is next
next next step
there are also some parameters like a
grouping that were associated to the
client and that you use them in the
service layer or in the service
orchestration layer to decide for
example if you if one or two accesses or
dude took or do you connect them to two
separate years and so on so once you
have decide that maybe then they are not
needed okay so the broom part will be
next and these are the kind of things
that we are thinking in in pruning from
the frontal threesome model okay I think
that makes sense i but one of the
questions with the pruning it may be
your change information with mandatory
possibly in the top level l3 SM model
and then make it optional to potentially
be carried through down to the lower
level called the other model or never
okay that might be nice yeah that can be
an option just keep it keep it optional
just just think it's if needed and down
down side can we go
last very quick comment sure yeah this
is true from Huawei I feel this work is
quite important because I are in some
implementations we were seeing people
directly converting l3 SM model to
device model and because that's the only
new models that existed and not having
this network model was creating even lot
of implementation complexity so really
welcome discussion on this
thank you Thank You Ana right okay
thanks a lot
Oscar that went very well remotely thank
you so next up is yari arco right good
morning this is work that I've done
together with Brian Ted and Steven and
it isn't necessarily a new thing and
it's not rocket science but it's we
think it change in the environment and
the internet environment that causes us
to think that this is a topic that
should get a little bit more attention
now at the IETF another other places
there's a couple of drafts and there
will be a society a few more you can you
can take a look at these if you like
it's also be some discussion that the
recent IAB workshop on deployment
expectations and versus reality workshop
happen in Finland at the beginning of
June and at the this idea we also will
have a discussion at the security area
group on Thursday I think and so there's
this RFC RFC 3550 - that is guidelines
for writing security consideration
sections on on RS it's basically all of
us follow try and figure out what what
kinds of security things we need to
consider and describe in in our our seas
and one of the sections there I think
section 3 possibly is about the infinite
threat model and basically tries to
describe you know this is the
environment that we should prepare for
and defend against or defend against the
bad things in the environment and it
says first of all that we assume that
the attacker has complete control of the
communications channel that you know our
are communicating in and and that's
obviously still valid they can be
attackers in our environment and may be
making some progress I think recently on
encrypting more traffic and using more
encryption and cryptographic mechanisms
to protect our communications and that's
great but it also says that we assume
that the end systems engaging in
protocol exchange have not themselves
being compromised so basically assuming
that well you know outsiders are bad
inside this are good and and that's the
assumption that we build protocols for
and try to describe how they manage in
that that situation and basically the
the belief is that changing my screen
here okay so the we believe that this
the protecting the communication is
still very much necessary and we
probably need to be doing it better than
we're doing today there's some
improvements that that are useful there
but we are sort of doubting this second
part of this assumption in in this this
RFC it seems to be basically counter to
current reality so and there's a couple
of reasons for that we've as I said made
some progress in encrypting Internet
traffic I think at least from some
networks that I follow we went from say
20 percent encrypted traffic to 80
percent and you know headed towards
hundred so that means that if you were
you know previously spying on stuff by
you know attaching a sniffer on the
network and looking at the packets that
is no longer possible as easily and if
you are determined attacker
you know criminal or governmental or you
know surveillance or whatnot you will
think about other options so you look
elsewhere now and we've seen some of
this actually there's been government
surveillance agencies who are today more
focused on acquiring data from say
provider than firm looking at you know
what's going on in the in the wire or
the wireless domain for that matter
there was a case of Australian proposal
for a law and say I think actually came
to be a law about what they can you know
try and force various internet entities
to provide for them and this is sort of
to the heart of that desire by some some
surveillance agencies there's also
surveillance in a commercial sense
surveillance capitalism estate call it
and there's new risks for us the users
because some applications are having you
know far more data collection than they
perhaps did in the past so information
about us or our activities are being
collected there's a very big database is
being created perhaps as part of this
first item here and there's a fairly
common design pattern for building
network things where you have you know
centralized parties that are controlling
other other entities and or you know
that that if I want to communicate with
my friend first I go to the cloud and
then the cloud communicates back to my
friend and that that design pattern is
is almost universal today there's also a
fundamental issue that the interest of a
party that you communicate with is not
aligned with your interests in all cases
so so you might be you know fully
encrypted and protected and
authenticated but you know the the
entity of the other end of the tunnel
might might not be having your best
interests in mind let's say a social
network or somesuch there's also the
question like you know when we consider
compromised notes and things that can
happen that I network that you thought
that was not connected to the internet
or wasn't like interesting from a
vulnerability or attack perspective
actually turns out to be attackable a
little bit more on that later
so I have some descriptions of this I I
won't read the poems that my colleagues
brought about this topic I'll just let
you read them yourself this person won
so the depressing worldview kind of
poetry and there's also you know more
pros like approach this describing the
situation so basically we assume that
applications either on our end or the
other end may themselves be working for
adversary or maybe on a network with
other endpoints hosted through to our
interests or the applications interests
and and that's sort of breaking what the
RFC's said earlier so the question is
what do we do so the four of us we've
been thinking about this we've been
writing some things and and and talking
about it it's we happen to be on the IAB
at least for now for us but but it's not
an IAB thing at the moment it's a
personal thing that we're we're trying
to discuss this idea of basically which
is sort of calling for interest and
discussion and get some guidance and
feedback if you think we're crazy or you
know we should do something else or you
should just this so that way please tell
us and you might also say that yeah
that's all true but you know there's
nothing that we can do which is built in
a communication spite it's not our
problem there's some truth to that but
there are also some useful things that
we could do one example is obviously
data minimization that we should think
more about that like what we actually
communicate in our protocols and systems
we should maybe avoid creating new
centralized architectures and everybody
can think of
some examples maybe some recent examples
apps from the DNS space for instance
where that's that's been the case
there's also other things like protocol
things or cryptographic things like you
know trying to keep things as modular
and separated from each other things as
possible so perfect forward secrecy is
one is one such example I've been
working on one protocol for instance
where we tried to make it you know PFS
capable today even though it was
designed as not such a protocol many
years ago and and the reason for that is
that if something leaks or some node
gets compromised then you don't want to
lose all the communications in the past
and in the future but you actually have
some compartments and another example
that's not on the slide I've been
working quite a bit with 5g and it has
many many really good improvements over
previous generations of systems and not
just in speed and latency but also in
insecurity one of those improvements is
identity privacy that the identity of
the end users is not not visible to
other sites it's pretty secure from from
that perspective it's not visible to
others sort of like looking at the radio
traffic but internally in the networks
the network's of course still have to
know you know who this is for you know
building reasons and other other reasons
but but if you look at the network
design the details of that they the real
identity of often are the real phone
number of a device is actually revealed
to a fairly large number of devices in
the network which you know if we
redesign things now maybe that would be
something that we should look at and
reduce the number of entities that hear
about this particular piece of
interesting privacy related information
just keep it on on a need-to-know basis
so that that's the kind of example that
we can do in this space and also when
you do your security considerations or
design new architectures or protocols do
think about the
abuse cases and not just the use cases
like what if you know somebody
compromised this node what would happen
or what if somebody made this a
centralized architecture and collected
the information what would it look like
and and see if he can actually defend
against it the RFC with security
considerations guidelines possibly we
might update that later or we write some
some other RFC about this this topic
we're not there yet we're just
discussing for now we're probably going
to create a mailing list and talk about
this topic yeah I wanted to sort of
briefly go into like why I'm here and
what how it might impact network
operator situations for instance I I did
want to say and hacked on my slides but
if you look at my draft there's a bunch
of guidelines and and it's one sort of
briefly mentioned few of them so starts
with considering the first principles in
in communication or protecting
communications that like if you perform
something by something of some node
instead of going directly from your
friend from you to your friend then that
means that if if you want to protect the
communications against others then maybe
you should protect them not just hop by
hop to the node in the middle and and
then back to your friend but all the way
so end-to-end protection so this means
that you have to think about things not
just in terms of you know we just use
TLS and in just stick it in and then
everything can it be five but you
actually have to think about like what
are you doing and what are you trying to
protect from want to minimize
information pass to others want to
minimize passing control functions to
others what we do with all of that in in
the operator networks want to avoid
centralized resources I mean or at least
need to be aware of the risks of
centralized free resources and controls
anyway so network operator networks it's
a so a lot of this work has been
inspired by sort of like end-user
internet views that you know how do we
leak information from individuals to to
large entities from the other side of
the world and that's not really the
problem that we have in with operators
but they also have large networks and
their problem is slightly easier because
you don't necessarily need alignment
that you have to worry about in a lot of
other cases so all your things are sort
of under one control one owner said
perhaps one network manager but even in
a closed or you know what network owned
by one party there's you know a lot of
potential for for being vulnerable so if
you think your your nodes are under your
control you haven't been reading enough
documentation about attacks on Intel
CPUs and such so so there's plenty of
opportunities for nodes to become
compromised and I think we should assume
that entities like this can be
compromised in in all kinds of networks
and design architectures with that in
mind doesn't mean that you can't have
your nice control node in the middle of
the network but it does me that you
should understand the implications of
you know what what happens if this thing
goes down or if this thing gets
compromised in some fashion and of
course that's in the most general sense
that's probably an unsolvable problem
plus Byzantine generals or Byzantine
routers but but I do believe that it
deserves some further thought so that's
what I have today and be here to discuss
or take feedback or you know have people
join join the thinking team Thanks
equation
so he re just to recognize Frank Rock
nurse I think this is useful despite the
fact nobody stood up and I think we have
to get ready for a world where we may
only want to go and trust devices that
convey trust along with what they're
sending so maybe we just mistrust
everything and then no like we have
today where we believe everything
behaves and maybe tomorrow we believe
that nothing behaves and as it's proven
that it behaves and I think there's a
steering that direction so that you're
reversing the logic of what we believe
in equipment does today and I think it's
useful to go and look at that what we
can do whether we can have information
conveyed along with the operation that
this device can be trusted and as such
and then intrusion and then compromise
could be slight misbehavior like iqu
messages a little longer than mine so
that in a financial transaction you
loose oh I win right so it's not massive
necessarily thank you and yes I agree
and yeah I mean one thing to say is that
there isn't necessarily a solution for
all of this but but it's still I think
important to be aware of this and and
understand our risks and manage those
risks anything else are we done they say
you cannot be paranoid enough so sorry
Adrian Farrell it's alright Yuri you
don't have to come back as a man
targeting Frank I I don't think you can
approach this because of that last line
by downtown Reuters are hard you can't
approach this by saying I won't trust a
node unless I can prove it works because
as a sociopathic principal there that
the node will prove that it's okay until
such time as you trust it yeah so you
can't you can't establish that anything
is trustable thank you everyone and will
soon double
you