okay we're gonna get started it you know
in a second so please come on in
find your seats plug in your laptop
alright good at good afternoon everyone
and welcome to sag my name is Roman Jo
and I'm co-chairing with Benkei duck so
why don't we get started first up this
is the note well you've seen this in
other meetings this of course applies to
the session we're having today if you
have any questions on what's there
please don't hesitate to come up to the
mic and we can have a conversation about
it the agenda we have for you today is
the usual one we're gonna open with
talking about what happened in working
groups or what will happen for those
sessions that have not occurred we'll
talk about pops one or two
administrative items this time we have
two invited talks and then whatever's
left is open mic time to discuss
anything you would like to talk about
would anyone like to bash this agenda
all right with that let's roll
thanks to all the work groups that sent
their information to sag we're gonna
quickly skip through the ones that have
reported if you want to follow along you
could obviously go to the sag mailing
lists archive or in the slide
proceedings you'll see a URL to their
status report so we're good with ace
Acme Kersey curdle did not meet dots mu
I to minus f IP second me kitten lamp
smile MLS is meeting on Friday is there
anything that needs to be said there
okay we'll move forward
o auth brats sockem is meeting later
today anything to say there
SEC Dispatch second-- no report anything
to report negative okay moving forward
suit met no report anything that needs
to be said at the mic we sent her for
five minutes before the meeting so it is
out there now the only thing that we
could add that's not in there is the
chief working group has consensus to
take a dependency on the suit working
group and the rats working group for
that matter and so that's just an inter
working with the may be of interest to
people that suit and breasts out have a
customer which is us as teeth perfect
courageously work in collaboration
across the areas there's steep TLS
anything you say about tok behind okay
trans well this is one issue left again
we've been saying it's like five IDF's
now and this time it's pcp 190 and how
it affects the the trans URI hopefully
this will get resolved in the next
couple of weeks and then we'll send RFC
and close a working group again
hopefully and so they've got some
discussion going on at the art area
mailing list that's right okay there are
quite a few other activities that happen
across the IETF their SEC related Viet
this is a partial list probably not a
complete list if anyone wants to come up
to the mic to comment on any of those hi
this is Elliott I think I would just put
ops Harry working group on the list in
terms of we're doing a lot of mud
expansion and one of the particular
pieces of work that we'll be looking for
guidance on is that there's a mud
reporter draft out there which would
which is ARF like that might generate
reports back to manufacturers there are
obviously privacy considerations
throughout all this and you know it's a
very nation draft we're still trying to
figure out
what's going on and so over time I want
people to just keep an eye on that one
for us oh yeah sorry there's no like
real monitor speaker pointing at us I'm
not sure if everybody heard the name of
the working group that that's going on
opps AWG when they Seltzer w3c we will
send an update and if you were in the
paired research trip yesterday you heard
Pete from brave speaking about some work
in privacy considerations and
specifications between w3c and IETF I
invite folks who are interested in those
issues at the web application layer to
come over and check out things that w3c
is doing in our privacy interest group
and in our web application security and
web authentication working groups
thank you ever under external related
another organization is itu-t study
group 17 which sent a liaison or a sent
multiple of them to the teeth working
group they're doing related work and
fortunately we have overlap and
participants wherever the editors if the
documents come to IETF participate thank
you tuck and so right now we believe
that we are aligned but it is an
external activity that we are tracking
from with an 84 thing group and this is
Linda Deborah from future way for the
external related to work
there's the Owen ug open network user
group there's a software-defined
security services is related to security
service for the hybrid cloud and also
for the IETF in the routing area we had
a IDR has quite a few
contributions related to how to do
controller of PGP to distribute IPSec
parameters so that was related to
security
like you want me to mention the Netcom
for sure actually okay rich sauce net
comp has got a draft out for crypto
types and actions and monitoring and so
on and anyone who's implemented any kind
of cryptography will look at it and
Blanche
so I encourage everyone to look at it
and Blanche or expert or do whatever you
need to do I want to mention the buff
that we've had this ITF Lake buff those
who weren't there sure there's been at
the start was quite pessimistic and
think that the content was the dirtiest
we have a group of people wanting to
work on this it's about creating a
lightweight authenticated key exchange
for using IOT specifically requirements
that came out of the Oscar working group
and well the people in the room were
kind of split among people wanting to do
something very narrowly tailored to the
Oscar working group and people who
wanted to do something more by burning
and of course we already have two
suggested solutions for solving this
even though the requirements are not
down yet so since that towards enough
enthusiasts in to form a working group
I'm not sure that this scope is hammered
down enough to do the so I guess that's
what the eighties now yeah yes / for the
eighties thank you you've and Steven for
chairing that working group we were
excited to see a lot of enthusiasm the
the problem around an ache is understood
and we were excited to see enthusiasm
around both Oscar and a broader kind of
solution but we have some kind of tough
choices to think I've had about how to
actually proceed so for those that
participated kind of thank you for the
input to stay tuned on how we're gonna
do next steps
okay so that one's to the end of our
planned updates and gets us to talking
about our invited talks so I invite Dirk
to come up and we're gonna talk about
kid lock related issues so thank you to
era director sent to the chairs for
giving us the chance to present our
activity here on behalf of Pettit who
could not make it to Montreal and my
name is Stefano go and we have this
activity for some quite time was varying
participation of people in the IDF
community and the yeah I try to describe
what we were heading for and try to
explain why we are interested in
identify a locator split or separation
approaches and why we think that common
privacy consideration on the different
solutions which are available could be
of interest and would like to see some
reaction comments and how to proceed how
to focus yeah okay
first we'll start Morris on explaining
what we think is meant with this
identifier locator separation and then
also on privacy which always comes up I
think if we talk about identifiers which
could yeah harm the users privacy and
also yes there was a technical linear
also on privacy and a lot of activity
and the sick area is on privacy issues
we see some use cases where this should
be especially interesting and perhaps
may come up more than in past
okay the solution space is perhaps too
early we there are some approaches but
we first want to see what are really the
problem what's the purpose statement and
where what are the requirements we have
to fulfill and after that it's time for
the next step so with a traditional
approach routing between two IP
addresses for an session between two
endpoints identified with by their IP
address this is working fine in entrant
transparency more or less but in some
cases Mittman may not be enough
efficient maybe too complex too much
encapsulation and decapsulation and
tunneling and D tunneling and things and
for instance one of the UK's mobility
high speed mobility extreme ability with
the IP addresses or they point of
attachments changing very rapidly and
the session above cannot survive perhaps
the change of the endpoints so some
applications needed so there could be
one problem and of course also moody
homing multipath transparency when you
bind several paths and transport packets
over different paths and have to
recollect it different IP addresses and
to the session cannot live with us or
need some more circumvention for to
solve this and then also this issue with
cloud and with physical entities which
are distributed but have one logical or
virtual identity entity and with their
identity and we think that this is
something where a separation of the
identity and the locator and using this
the identity as the end point with
changing locators which are bound to the
identity more or less as the different
approaches are available but this
approach generally may be an advantage
here and
could as these help to survive the
session so yes this is there are
multiple protocols and solutions and
RFC's available only to mention here
lisp with not only RFC 6830 3 this is
the control pain part but there's all
6830 for the data plan or user plane
part then we have Ireland PE which came
out of research group activities they
are for instance our C 6740 and then
there's also proposed by Tom Abbott with
ila identify located addressing which is
in draft status and they all of course
care for their security and privacy by
themselves and have solutions but they
are not yet or not deployed in a large
scale of course they are experimental or
also least was going for sendeth or
there are multiple deployments
implementations they are and small scale
deployments on ila also for for
databases but yes there's not yet an
operator who uses this approach for its
network and to have this approach
largely not as an overlay over another
overlay also it would be I think kind of
ideal a solution of course we need
something purchase also practical and
that's what we want to yeah that's the
way we want to proceed to see whether
there is something on common ground of
different approaches perhaps kind of a
more alight solution which of course
nevertheless serves the same advantages
for this for what these ID lock
approaches have been proposed so to
reduce the burn of the ipv6 or ABI
address which is normally
handling both the identity and the
location which is for instance for the
virtual machines with their different
locations for the same identity would be
helpful and then new network
architecture is required for them for
police that's it I would say a kind of
totally new architecture of course can
provide all this seamless mobility and
so and of course also thus mapping very
fine and but it's for an operator not
yet I've not seen one who assess yes we
deploy this in our network because we
see that it's viable yeah so the net
magnetic bearing systems can of course
be used ENS for some but also own
mapping systems instead of routing
cables to look up for and yeah and all
this approaches were you know what the
source destination identifier is carried
in in the header to find the right
location for the packet or a tribute to
instead of the IP address in a useful
manner okay but what you see especially
as the applications areas is now
industrial iot with a small messages and
the could be a large large head us much
more larger than the payload where such
an you not you but then if their depth
that approach could help and of course
also vehicle and networks where they're
all the us are moving the entity
endpoint at entities and they very
frequently change of course their
location and what what all is included
in 5g maybe mobile network with wireless
and fixed network access technology all
combined together
these are all areas where this ID
location would apply nicely to but also
again the privacy issue has to be solved
it has to be considered enough so that
there is no new privacy risk when using
this and I would like to go shortly on
the different approaches which I
mentioned which are available so the
list protocol is as an SOS approach uses
an extra mapping system and encapsulate
the packets Tunnel set between list
domains and can also of course interact
with non these demands but the new list
architecture course could be a burden
for deploying it into an a running
system ok there are of course you does
specified new entities which do all this
and as usual if you have the identifier
and you need the locator you have to
query the mapping system but only if
it's necessary of course if it's not
changing you need not vary again so
that's not noted no only the overhead if
you guys is required for instance if you
flow is transmission direct formation is
starting or if the locator is changing
and there are ok different RFC's and
updates to this RFC's now are under ASG
evolution evaluations sorry as proposed
standard instead of experimental and
there are of course more information on
the dispersed net for existing
deployments and also cost for the least
working group information the I N and P
approach can be more seen as a host
based approach the IP address is split
into the locator and note identify a
locator of course is something which is
significant for the
topology and issues for fathering and
routing and the identifier is the
notable naming the note which may be
physical but logically note and normally
does not change and yeah what is the
advantage it does not require any hooter
changes no new route us are required for
this and it uses ENS the existing
mapping system but of course this is
perhaps not a good idea if we have very
frequent queries for the mapping system
of course DNS is also evolving and Salim
who could not make it here has someone
else in the hackathon on Saturday an
implementation working with extensions
yeah and also there has been a tutorial
on Island P and meeting 102 and of
course then there's a website for Island
P implementations and the ILA based
approach use to transform addresses also
to split the existing IP address into
the identifier and locate apart or 64
five bit and it can have a mapping table
to look up and determine which locator
is fitting the identifier edges required
and this has been deployed and
commercially already on IP layer and
there are also limitations available you
know it's a little so it's this is all
which is working and special advantages
that the upper layer UDP and we did not
did not don't need to change when using
ila and there has been in one coffin il
a worse there's more information also on
the link even there so that's what I
want to say they all have of course
their own privacy considerations but but
what we think is required if we want to
go for a solution
which is deployed by an operator it
could be something a mix of all our a
new approach at least with preps new
requirements to privacy and that's what
we want to get to investigate yeah and
this I think that what I wanted to
conclude in this slide so why is the
privacy important of course because this
identify us in the packet header have to
be transported anyhow to pursue you use
it for routing odds also and if there is
yeah there there are chances to to break
the privacy if they are transported you
clear so just generally so and and the
that's also kind of a threat
and and there of course I would pull
versions of prior privacy leaks over the
location itself may be preached and may
be available to others who are not
allowed to you need to know it and not
only the location but also of course the
movement and I come in combining
different information this can lead to
two new risks and of course also that
was something which moody party CP
Marcello pointed out that if we have
multiple paths that is also the privacy
risk because there are multiple
informations more than one location and
may lead or result in more precise
location information for the adverse
user which needs should not do it yeah
okay we there have been as a set of
solutions proposals already for and and
they have their own solutions as well in
this person Island P and also for ila
here only in a draft status moment but
the question is why has not been
deployed so far
yeah the question is privacy of course
may be one of the reasons but the the
deployment itself that ID lock systems
are not deployed in networks today is
some other reason of your architecture
you need of new components you need so
you have to change a lot and operators
are not willing to change something if
they are not true about the positive
outcomes out we also have to point on
the advantage of it of course and one
approach may be that the mapping system
perhaps is not so complicated so looking
for a new mapping system may be one way
but we are not not yet sure about this
but therefore we see there's a lot of
potential work we see and we want to get
done and are looking for people to join
us
we call it hit lock privacy in identify
a locator little approaches we have a
mailing list and have been since you
have menu since I give 102 and if we
have clear what is our focused problem
statement which we can actually solve we
would like to go for above because
besides the problem statement would be
interesting to start with our
requirements rafts and based on the use
cases we have identified and eventually
we find working group where the work has
been done or we get a new working group
created for this to do then the actual
work on solution space and I think don't
know what's the time but we have time
for a few have time for a few questions
yeah and then the other slides are just
for pick up I available in the
Proceedings of you can look it up there
and you can join the mailing list there
of course and
and review our drafts which we have up
to now in a very draft status also
published yeah I understand I would be
happy to answer questions or get feel
dangerous
oh gosh : um is there a reason to
believe these problems are soluble sorry
is there a reason to believe these
problems are soluble sigh so you have a
requirements you have a problem
statement do you have any proposed
solutions yeah this approach by a by a
Tom how about the on and fast on the
firewall and service tickets this is a
draft he has published so what that
would be one thing we could discuss but
we still think we have to start over
more or less with a real problem
statement before we go into shortage
my husband was trying to figure out if
this is a research problem or an
engineering problem research Eliot there
I was I would just add on to what occur
just said which is I could envision this
problem occurring not just unless the
Nile NP but you could consider it in the
context of basic 802 dot dot one VLANs
you could look at it there's an analog
to this that you could address in the
context of MPLS VPNs and so I guess
there's a granularity issue and I think
it is an interesting research problem
but I don't know exactly where you'd
like to define the granularity as to how
you want to solve it and having a having
a little bit more clarity on that would
be very helpful
let's alternate mics please I'm sorry
it's alternate mics but if you'd like to
answer sure if you'd like to comment
research problem yeah we actually we
still see it also as a research problem
but also we want to have it yeah a
solution which is viable also for a
deployment so I think it's perhaps a
combination of both hi my name is Tim
Shepherd and there was one uuugh named
several identifier locators what systems
but the one that I was most fond of and
I think it's 10 plus or minus five years
ago in the IETF there was some work on
hip host identity Palin and I didn't if
you mentioned that I think can you talk
a little bit louder that it's really
hard for us to hear on stage it's like
I'm hearing a lot of myself come back
from the rabbit so 10 or 10 plus or
minus 55 years ago there was a lot of
work on hip h IP and i don't think you
mentioned it as your examples of things
that's fine there's yeah but one one of
the thing one of the things I remember
from its story was that you could have a
femoral hits in that system and the idea
was you could create them so oh and now
bob was coming to the microphone I think
he was the originator of hip anyway I
just wanted to point you at that
something you might want to also look at
should the other mic now I'm ran a
concern and Island P is my work in
collaboration with Selim baki at the
University of st. Andrews and I don't
think I'll NP particularly has any
unique problems in this area the same
techniques in RFC 49:41 that are used to
generate ipv6 privacy addresses those
same techniques can be used with il NP
as is with the current Island PRF CS and
with the current aisle and P
implementations so it's unlike slide 11
up there island piece just leverages the
solution work that's already been done
to mitigate these risks with ipv6 and we
don't need any special magic sauce
that's Island be unique so now okay I
don't want to question this that is its
own security measures and privacy
countermeasures but Ireland P is also
not deployed by operators and I think we
have to look for something which is more
easily to be deployed and preps raising
new issues thank you you can take Rob
next we're just gonna Thomas who is a
she consulting the hipster except when I
can hit by car my hip I'm a lurker on
these lists I filed along doing it
aspects of hip and hip bone are very
similar to some of the issues being done
here I'll note that I have a work
project on a privacy based exchange and
I have a customer who wants me to get
moving on it already and a few other
things so there are things that we hit
with it's long lived identities which
are definitely could be considered
privacy issue there is work soon
starting which would be addressing on
the privacy issues with with hip just as
an aside but I've been lurking long and
of tennis on the sign meeting so that
the guys know me and I know them okay
would you like to have post this comment
on our mailing list that would be nice
okay thank you Robin Wilson I'm glad to
see this work being considered because
the more we think about privacy the more
we realize the importance of protecting
data that's at the infrastructure layer
and is very hard to obfuscate so that
the fact that privacy considerations are
high on the list is in my view a plus
point I think it's also valid to ask
whether or not there's a solution to
this problem but only if we also
recognize that solution is not
necessarily a binary thing there may be
degrees of mitigation of the risks this
involves okay thank you
I think we should consider this hi this
is science you mentioned that some of
those solutions are being used in the
IOT space and industrial IOT and I was
wondering whether you could shed some
light on on this topic shake what
explain what your experiences with that
IOT or deployment of those technologies
in the industrial IOT space okay yeah we
we have okay some some text on this in
the draft but I think we should
investigate more on existing solutions
and if you can point to some would be
great so as you you're asking if they're
like our existing deployments of this in
IOT
because that's a little from the
previous from one of the slides I got
the impression that there's some
deployment of this in IOT environments
and that's why I'm asking because III
can't contribute something in this space
because I don't know not you know the
problem is really really hard because
sometimes you simply transfer the prom
to someplace else
your transport numbers the long-lived
ESP spies long-lived how do you deal
with those things yet if you address you
fix the address you're only doesn't
remove the prompt is somewhere else and
some other layer of the protocol so
there's still a lot of work to be done
here
and looked at very carefully that you
you think you solve the problem but you
won't evolve what you think is the
obvious problem and there's just this
other one lurking there as well so it's
still very much a research EEPROM in my
opinion
yeah and that also gets back into a lot
of work from the technology plenary
yesterday
this adeno lispers dotnet i have won
some experience with a deployment of
industrial iot it uses list with ipv6
cia's their crypto e ids because it has
a association with a key pair and we use
encryption at the data plane to solve
the privacy issues okay thank you all
right perfect
thank you so much ok thank you for the
comments and trips you have a look at
our mailing list and thank you so next
up on the agenda we're gonna switch over
URI or Steven or gonna talk to us about
exploring whether we need to extend the
internet threat model so the IIb had a
workshop there months ago in helsinki
about deployment realities versus design
expectations and two of the submissions
were these drafts that you and i have
written in pen utley we may emerge
stylish if depending what happens I
essentially asking the question and
there's some we re presented this at the
routing area working group earlier in
the week and we had a quick discussion
with the IBM isg about it so if you look
at 35 52 that kind of describes the
internet an internet model that we kind
of used when designing protocols and the
interesting part says two things the
first one essentially is that we assume
that an attacker has complete control
the network and that leads us to
generate all sorts of COMSEC protocols
and to want to turn on concept becomes
like mechanisms in protocols the second
thing it says is that we assume the end
systems engaging in the protocol have
not themselves being compromised and I
guess what we what we think is that
thing one is still absolutely necessary
we shouldn't consider weakening that or
doing silly things in that space but
thing to may no longer be sufficient or
maybe it doesn't matter yeah
anymore and this is perhaps something
worth looking at I guess I mean I would
say that in the you know in defense of
3552 it may well be the case that as
soon as you go beyond what it says you
run into problems that are so hard
there's very little you can do about it
so this may be a problem that's a bit
too hard or maybe there's things we can
do so again looking at thing two and
thinking about comparing it to the
current reality if we get better COMSEC
as was all the thing one then that
motivates attackers to look elsewhere so
they you know keys under doormats kind
of things or all those kind of stuff
surveillance I think has been an issue
we've talked about from from the point
of view of three-letter agencies but
also in the real world today there's
this kind of surveillance capitalism
that kind of generates new risks because
of the breath the collection of
information the fact is that this is
essentially unavoidable if you're using
the Internet today and family wrote 35
50 to the Internet was a pretty
different place I think it's also true
that even for a network that you think
isn't really vulnerable even if that's
true at a particular point in time some
short time later it's probably no longer
true so people who have thought that
maybe they're designing that
applications or protocols in the ITF who
think I have this bit of the network
that's safe over here and nobody's gonna
touch it because it's in there behind a
perimeter that doesn't seem to be true
nearly as much as you would think and
certainly that doesn't match reality we
have cases where we see competing
interests involved in so for example the
whole debate around applications doing
net DNS is a case in point about where
this you know different parties have
different interests and the fet model we
have doesn't consider that I'm not sure
what you can do about it and but even
more glaringly if you if you look back
at thing - it says the end systems we
assume are not compromised and what the
hell is a nan system these days when you
have virtualization you have
software-defined networking and a whole
bunch of other things that are really
not what we would considered as the kind
of host requirements which is I guess
that the mental model we might have had
like them so there's an argument that
thing two is no longer sufficient Ted
suggested that we could do a poetic
version of this and there's two poetic
versions one that this is one they're
really horrible this is the second one
also really horrible and the only reason
I put this up is you can guess who wrote
which if you really care first and the
picture in the back is kind of
reflective of where we think we are a
bit but prose might be better as an
ambush
and so what about this activity but I
guess all we're thinking about it'd be
good to get people looking at this
problem and trying to consider are there
things that we can do that better
reflect reality but also that are useful
for people doing work in the ietf or
elsewhere in designing protocols that's
kind of like you know one of the nice
things about 3552 is the threat model is
nice and simple in other places in the
ITF for example there's an RFC for the
OAuth threat model it's a gigantic
complex thing so that's probably not
useful as generic guidance even though
it is a threat model that does include
the idea that parties involved in the
protocol may be colluding against one
another so we may end up with some kind
of statements like this the four of us
we all have to be on the IRB at the
minute but it is not an IRB thing
necessarily we're looking for guidance
and feedback we think there could be
some useful end results so for example
we have in RFC 69 73 some privacy
guidelines that are not really part of
the kind of ITF process formally but
that are useful talking about things
like data minimization maybe we can
think about the fact that some of our
protocols are some of our security
mechanisms and protocols may be
increasing tendencies towards
centralization in ways that we'd be
better off not doing we may have some
design process issues so for example in
the ITF somebody comes along and says I
have this use case I want to do and they
invent something that has a new
identifier that's a long term stable
identifier that gets everywhere and that
causes privacy problems maybe we should
be considering or encouraging people to
think of abuse cases so how can the
thing you want to do be abused and build
that into the design process and that
might be a simple a little bit bit of
guidance we could include so we're not
proposing right now to do a 3552 base
I'd have tried that didn't work
I think what we'd like to do is get a
bunch of people who are interested in
this to work together maybe I think
Taylor's gonna try and see if we can
stead of a mailing list if unless people
say this is all crazy and you shouldn't
do it and we could just kind of work the
problem with people who are interested
in us and perhaps after we've done that
to see if there's stuff that can be said
and then see can you window that down to
something useful that could apply to
places in the IETF or people putting
this kind of work perhaps after that we
might want to come back and look at some
kind of modification to the process and
BCPs that we have so we're not proposing
that the client dive right in there yet
without doing a better preparation work
and we're looking for feedback we're
looking for people who are interested in
being involved and if if people don't
tell us this is all stupid and crazy
you'll probably set up a mailing list
and send the cord that's to say hi Mohit
Erickson so this is not completely crazy
or stupid so I think you should continue
I get get that there is a need to
maintain the balance that if we open
open up saying that endpoints can be
compromised then we need to like think
how far they can be compromised and and
so on like we are not here to like
protect against someone you know do
physically threatening your things but
there are still still some things we can
definitely look at so for couple of
examples that that came to my mind miss
binding attacks are at least I I also
spoke to Acker about this is something
where one of the nodes participating in
the communication is compromised and
then he misleads you to talk to some
third party and if you have a server
database whether you are using a
symmetric fake or asymmetric or whatever
balance imbalance bake these kind of
things do make affect of what happens
when one of the nodes get compromised
and perhaps for us as protocol engineers
when we are designing these these things
we could
a better choice and prepare ourselves
for for the case when one of the the
parties is compromised then again like
we don't want to open the floodgates and
let everything end so definitely
interested and would like to see this go
forward need to be a little bit careful
I didn't see the order which people came
to the mic so let's just alternate I
demand a close an ski with myself
actually thank you for the presentation
this is extremely relevant as you know
sorry about missing the workshop I
didn't know it was going on I missed it
myself as you know I also have a draft
which is a new threat model smart ski
for this particular meeting which you've
commented on as well so I very much look
forward to working with you and in that
draft I do go through quite a lot of
threats that are happening in the most
recent years in particular with malware
botnets and data breaches so hopefully
we can fold that all in to have a more
broader perspective so I look forward to
working with you thanks thank you Dave
Taylor thank you I didn't know about the
workshop either until this ITF but I'm
interested in this topic we actually
have two working groups in this area
that are meant for cases where a thing
too is not true those two working groups
are rats and teeth and so the point is
yes I think it is good for us to have
some document as an area whether it
comes out of this effort or something
water that says how to think about this
in your threat modeling because we have
working groups so rats is trying to say
how do you do attestation where your
device may be compromised but your
device may have multiple different sub
modules in it whether it's different
layers in a secure boot chain or whether
it's different processor context one was
one is secure one is normal or whatever
depending on your architecture and so
rats has to do with that test station
and he has to do with remediation how do
you get out of that state and so since
we're actually doing work in this area I
think it's one that's good to make
visible across the area so as people do
their threat models and even as people
do say take a dependency on
authentication
mechanisms that where the threat model
is appropriate then they can take
advantage of say attestation that would
come out of say rats
sure yeah well and suit you but yeah but
the most relevant parts here are rats
for attestation for detection that
something is out of compliance and it's
in some secure way and then t4 during
remediation is how do you get back in
back out of that state if the device
actually supports that sure and there's
other ones to you right Kathleen yeah
all right and then I guess I know this
is looking at post compromised recovery
for key silicon I wanted to air my
surprise or well okay maybe I am
completely confused the surprise that
there is this thing to kind of seems to
be working twenty years ago did we think
about the end devices being vulnerable
phenomenon that after Snowden we focused
so much on the to miss transmission
paths that offered to certain attacker
environments a cheap way of of attack
and successful attack and we lost the
other parts of the world out of view
[Music]
well kind of surprising that this level
of discussion kind of such a thing could
happen if it actually happened this is
jeffrey askin
i think it would have been very helpful
to my project if this already existed so
i plan to join your mailing list there's
one of the drafts talks primarily about
security while the other draft includes
both security and privacy i'm i don't
have a strong i don't know if it would
be better to combine them or separate
them
I suspect the W
we see has interesting things to say
about privacy so there should be some
ways on with them sure so when you refer
to the draft you meant the ones I have
here or there two that were listed on
this session Ali Rezai key Nokia thank
you very much for making this
presentation and I look forward to
working with you I think it will be very
important to get the definitions right
define a scope and also look into use
cases where it makes sense to be handled
by the IETF here thank you I look
forward to working with you if I could
process and interrupt and where are the
blue sheets you could bring them forward
so everyone can sign them back I'll have
a strong I think that would be good to
talk to people outside of the idea about
this in the w3c for instance we have had
a lot of work that assumes that the
secure thing is not the endpoint it's
the user agent and the secure thing is
executing the devil's cold so we assume
that the part that is controlling what
this we're supposed to be doing is the
enemy on the other hand they do try to
offer primitives so that it's possible
for one and one page to be reasonably
sure that it's not itself compromised so
that it can set up at rest environment
and just relationship with a server for
instance the one it's loaded wrong so
that a question of who is the endpoint
and who is it that we are assuming these
are being secure
jumps around a lot even within a single
application so I think assumption 2 is
really able but you have to shrink the
definition of the endpoint down from
everything that is beyond the network
interface to think that is a bit smaller
than that thank you all right Eric
rajala yeah um like we were 30 52 we
weren't like unaware without any viruses
or malware or like she's got compromised
I appreciate that people are fixating on
this this point at the Internet throw at
all um the the section at the endpoints
being compromised I'm prepared to
concede it may be in artfully written
but the point there actually a still
stands which is that when you want to
build a concept protocol if you assume
the other side is compromised at the end
of the day you're not in a very good
shape that doesn't mean that you're not
doesn't mean you can't be talking to an
attacker but it means that it's that
it's very hard design security protocols
that protects you in the face of the
actual counterparty you're trying to
talk to I've been compromised and worse
and it's really true that the ideas
about that have expanded over the years
in terms of P FS and PCs and stuff like
that but nevertheless that still is
largely correct um so um I certainly it
seems like interesting work and uh you
know certainly I think we could try to
UM you know Easter as we discussed a
lunch expand some of the notions the
endpoint or expand in some cases
contracting others by just I do want to
resist the idea to like somehow like we
were so dumb but we didn't understand
like machines to be compromised that's
really not the case and there's like an
entire section about DD about dose and D
us in here so it's something about the
case we didn't understand that you could
have a compromised machines in the
internet yeah this is not gonna solve
all the universe's problems we might
make some improvements but we're not
gonna stop all bad things happening or
something yeah Dave Walter Meyer so I
mean Deckard's points this isn't
something that we can solve with a
single protocol either right we need a
variety of different solutions that are
targeted at different pieces of the
problem now one of the one of the
challenges that I've experienced as
someone who's worked in some of the
management the security management
protocol space that exists in in in in
ATF is we've heard a lot of comments
that are like that that are basically
around those kinds of protocols being
sort of second-class citizens to a lot
of the you know security protocols that
exist and I think this is bringing out
how important a lot of that you know
security management work is to solving
these broader problems and instead of
actually shrinking the definition of an
endpoint I think we should actually
expand the definition of an endpoint to
ensure that we are providing all of the
management capabilities that can provide
for a a more hardened you know internet
infrastructures in the middle as well as
on the ends near to some degree this is
about getting away from the walled
garden mentality of of looking at you
know security
you know our protocols have a fairly
crunchy outside but we still rely on the
squishy inside to be secure and we need
to do more I think from an internet
perspective to ensure that that squishy
inside is also protected because it's
terribly easy to attack today hi Alma
today Simo tech so I read the the drafts
I was not aware of this our workshop
Peter so I'm young here so I have no
idea where they should go I think it
should go somewhere just after all the
story on TLS that that we've been
through we got the feedback that people
considered that security should only be
done on the inputs of the communication
so we said why don't we stop on that and
try to understand what we are talking
about sort of endpoints what is it about
the setup model and we made an internet
draft called
capabilities and limitations of endpoint
security solutions with the intention to
simply codify and put words on on that
that's called class by the way I have a
sign meaning at 4:00 p.m. in color if
people want to go there
we got a lot of feedback and and and the
thing is that we realized we got a
number of lessons first of all I thought
that this was not good value because
since we are doing endpoint Security's
in 30 years everything should have been
written on the topic so first surprise
one we had no taxonomies on endpoints
second surprise the best we could find
on the threat models was my tree attack
and we're still asking ourselves is it
the right model for us to describe what
we need so we start with two big bad
surprises and so then we started to do
another in saying what would be an ideal
security security endpoint of course it
going to be very hard and then we
started to list all the limits we
started to figure out we put some
production data to show what it is we
find with real production data about how
many attacks the endpoints cannot see
and even network and sleep just to give
us a real sense of the reality and we
continued with asking ourselves like
your good point about what is the impact
of all of that by governance but is that
the impose on the endpoint attacks or as
regulations as well as what human rights
are seeing there and finally the
economic cost of all of that because
someone will have to pay for that and
I'm remaking something which is like we
Frankenstein do you ever remodel by
which to secure the endpoint you need a
nitro computer on each side so we have
to answer a number of questions here as
well in your in your draft first if you
make a good point on social attacks and
so the question is this is not an attack
on the device this is an attack on the
brain so do you include the person in
the endpoints or not because this will
matter a lot there is an attack on the
brain on the UX even before you are so
anyway the summary is that we have done
some work it's expanding we have a
program for that we discussed this
afternoon we think it makes sense I
don't know how you want to tie it I
think I have more typhus Jerry's work
because I it's more aligned with what
I'm trying to do and maybe it's a full
so we are happy to contribute happy to
continue to work on that whatever stuff
so please keep doing so just answer I
guess it was a brother
question languages help to contribute I
guess it sounds like it's not crazy
we'll make a mailing list and trying to
listen I Stephen Elliott here first of
all nice presentation and a couple
points as a scientist statement I think
maybe worth still reviewing 3552 to see
if there's if it should be dusted off
and and some stuff being looked at from
Security's consideration standpoint I
know you're growling the room but yes
you know they're definitely time has
moved on we probably should at least
take a stare at it the second point I
wanted to make was that in response to a
Dave Taylor's I think actually his work
and what you're proposing actually mesh
really nicely together in that if you
come out with something in with some
reasonable alacrity I know that's a hard
thing to do in this context but we could
actually drive some of the work that
that that's going on in rats and teeth
in terms of saying well here's you know
here's the mess we're in and here are
some solutions that we can get to which
leads to a question which is suppose we
get to this Internet threat model and
let's posit a world maybe in which heap
and rats aren't quite there yet
what sort of formalisms would you
envision addressing a threat model that
you would propose like would there be
protocol approaches that you you could
envision that would answer some of the
threat models that that would address
and how would how would you envision it
apply to the IETF and mostly I don't
know I mean I think some some there has
been some suggestion and chats with
other people that maybe there's there
needs to be some kind of descriptions of
different threat models that might apply
in different kind of protocol contexts
in terms of what kind of formalism if
any like formal formalism would be use I
don't know but there's a programming
standpoint or from a description
standpoint
yeah I don't know if the answer your
nuts could be si
yeah like you just kind of lit it to you
with different threat models for
different applications I believe that's
basically the point where we gotta get
you because what you asked in your
presentation is it worth to get to one
consensus I believe it's not quiet
because like I said it's incredibly
difficult to design protocols when I
can't trust the other party at all and
that's basically the case when the other
party is arbitrarily modified by anyone
that's not on my control so I believe it
would be awesome to have such a thread
model but I believe it's also worth
considering to have like multiple steps
in between that are pretty codified so
that we have a decent way of talking
what kind of threat model we're building
against and where I have a common
language on deciding what we're talking
about without defining a given threat
model for every single individual
protocol and standard but still getting
far towards multiple use cases yeah I
think this would also mentioned that in
a chat that there's been some academic
work on threat models in various
contexts that we might be able to
leverage for definitions and things like
that Ben Schwartz Google I think the
title of your dress was does the
internet need a new threat model
something like that I I wonder if a
better title would be does the internet
have a new threat model in other words
it seems to me that across the IETF over
the past let's say five years there has
been a revolution in the way that we
think about security and we've seen a
wide variety of security innovations
that take a new perspective one one that
is apparent to me a certificate
transparency it's a very powerful
approach that's very different from the
way that I'm used I was used to thinking
about security five or ten years ago so
rather than thinking about this as an
exercise in developing a new threat
model I think it might be
more conservative but possibly easier to
think about it as collecting and
summarizing the new threat models that
as a community we are and in harmonizing
the the new threat models that as a
community we have developed and really
advanced a lot that's fair points much
of the routing area would agree but i'm
lawrence lund blade i co as a co-author
of the eat draft in the rats working
group i haven't read your drafts just so
i'm just going off but i've heard here
but a lot of the discussions been around
compromise and i think my i think of it
differently as what you really want to
know is who implemented this thing and
did they do a good enough job so that it
will not be compromised because you
can't really detecting compromise and
trying to do that that's kind of hard
but if you can find out who implemented
something you know dedicate the the
implementer find out and think will
nourish trusted that gives you a leg up
like okay I'm going to trust talking to
these guys but not those guys so i
basically trying to suggest a different
way of thinking a little bit way of
thinking there and really what that is
is kind of a definition of attestation I
think lots people define attestation in
a lot of different ways but I'm offering
this as kind of a sort of one way to
look at a station in the attestation
that Dave mentioned when he was making
his comments okay Marty so Mountain
Thomson I've been enjoying watching the
the three conversations or four
conversations layered on top of each
other here and I wasn't going to get up
then you do cuz I'm on the IV and we've
already had this conversation and you
don't need that that input but I think
it would be helpful for this
conversation here to sort of make clear
that there's a number of different
conversations going on here there is the
the aspect of the conversation that
ecers talked about which is that it's
very hard to design a concept protocol
when you are operating out of the on the
basis that the peers that you're talking
to are compromised by attackers in in in
the context of that concept
I think that's pretty well understood
there have been some evolutions in the
way that we understand how that how that
operates such that we might want to put
balance on the the extent to which we
believe that to be true and and there
I'm talking about things like the
Pearson and whatnot but it seems to me
that the discussion that the workshop
and the drafts is is pointing out is
something else which is that we're
talking about alignment of incentives
more than anything else
previous speaker talked about
attestations which is another thing
entirely which I hadn't really
considered that was probably more in the
first bucket than the second one but
when we're talking talking about these
things Ben was clearly talking about I
might be fine knowing that my connection
is secure in the in the sense of TLS to
give an endpoint but I don't know what
they're doing without that information
once they've got it and and maybe
they're maybe there aren't necessarily
any alignment of incentives between what
I want and what they want to do with
that information and that's one of the
major failings of the web as we have
today so thinking about what you want to
do with this work in either the first
context or the second is probably what
we need to do and being very crisp about
that would be okay I think this is
Steven that's nice that you wrote things
up but what I don't see maybe you can
shed some light as is where with the
idea of contribute to this because for
example Dave Taylor provided some
examples on current activities that
don't make this assumption that you
previously cited and on the other hand
it very much makes those assumption just
for a smaller subset of
in point like talking about the secure
world being secure rather than the rest
and the OS case is not too different and
so the IDF is in a business of providing
sort of protocols for interoperability
where would the idea of contribute to do
these type of things end point related
security mechanism so it doesn't make so
it doesn't lead to an a difference so I
guess I'm confused I mean so I think
this this work would G IDF work just
writing things up is like write a book
about it um yeah that would be cool nice
pictures and everything yeah but that's
not that's not really getting anywhere
correct I mean I think so I think part
of this would be figuring of what we
thought of whole bunch of people think
but in another part of it is trying to
turn that into something that's actually
useful for people doing protocol work in
the ideas so it has to be and that's the
part that I'm missing I don't see that
those those aspects of way ice actually
where's the info for me as a particle
designer that would make a difference I
don't I don't
missile I I mean I guess we've had some
cases taking not only thinking about use
cases but abuse cases for example I
think that is a defensible thing that
you could say this is something that you
could argue that should be part of a PCP
in the IETF somewhere and it's a good
exam but maybe more maybe it maybe just
will fail I don't know Gary I guess does
it ago yeah yeah so I just wanted to
into tech slightly and say that yeah
this is this is really hard what Stephen
said is correct that we need to move
forward and and have some advice that
would actually be useful for for ITF but
I do think that there are some things
that that you can take into account so
I've certainly personally done that in
in recent work you know adding BFS to my
you know protocols that don't have that
thinking about system architectures
where I'm spreading some information for
too many nodes when I could have you
know kept it to need-to-know basis I you
know looked at things where we were
sending information to
centralized parties in the internet
where we perhaps wouldn't need to and so
on so there are things that we can we
can take into account at the IETF work
also at least that's that's my
experience that doesn't solve everything
under the Sun but maybe a little bit
helping and if I could add cuz I can't
get one of us has to be up here so I'll
take my privative I mean it's about
residual risk it's not there that the
ITF can address cut of all of those but
the ability to kind of document those
put them out there then when folks take
IETF protocols and they compose them
with other things that we've reminded
them that they need to consider this in
the integration process Daniel can't go
more a cou so I'm happy that we're
having this discussion I'm a little bit
concerned about the idea of the ITF
trying to figure out how to reach into
the endpoints themselves and do a lot of
stuff on the endpoints because I think
we haven't been very good at doing that
it doesn't mean that we maybe shouldn't
try but I would I can imagine
folks who work on the endpoints being
territorial about that but one of the
things that I think I don't think it's
just about the network transmission
stuff versus the endpoint have a lot of
sympathy with ecker said about it's
difficult to design a communications
protocol where you assume the other
party is malicious but the thing that I
think is missing there is the sense of
time perhaps about what happens outside
and around the protocol so when I think
about that I think of things like link
ability right where the where I may want
to interact with the third with this
external party but I want to make sure
that that interaction is distinct from
other interactions that I've had with
that same party and so there there is a
there's a there's a gap there and I
think thinking about it in terms of time
maybe more than transmission versus
endpoints might be a useful frame sure
Brett Jordan I read your draft Stephen
and I read on Dominique so I didn't read
the other one so I apologize for that I
wasn't also aware of any meeting that we
were having about this so I do think
this work is important it's very
critical
I do fully support it and even if that
means at the end of the day that COMSEC
protocols have a section in there on
risk management for operational security
to help illustrate what this means and
help people you know put this into their
risk profile when they're doing risk
management in a large enterprise or a
large organization I think it's it's
really important I do support it and
thanks for doing the work you know for
you and Dominique both graphs were great
some things been Caidic so I came down
here to the floor to share some thoughts
as an individual and they've been
changing over the course of living
listening everybody else maybe I
should've just stayed up there but to
sort of maybe try it and then summarize
and synthesize from what we've been
hearing it seems like is probably gonna
be useful to recognize that there are
more subtleties and gradations and to
sort of broaden the horizons about what
we're thinking about as we design
protocols we may not need to try and
reach into the end point with what we're
doing but we could think about you maybe
there's not just a single end point you
maybe there's multiple different layers
on the end point with things that have
different layers and trusts that are
implemented more robustly that you are
potentially more susceptible to being
controlled by an attacker and we might
want to think about things in time you
know what where the broader effects of
what we're doing over time and and just
to sort of recognize that we have not
just a binary black-and-white situation
we might be talking to someone who we
trust to correctly implement their
software and to correctly in from the
protocol but as Marie was saying to
house a misaligned incentives so you
know it's not like we're talking to a
completely adversarial relationship and
so there's some things that we can do
with them but you know we're not just
gonna hand over all of our data to them
blindly and we need to be able to work
thoughtful about what we do and what we
you know he was talking about that yeah
I've been said of number of things that
I wanted to say so thank you um I also
on district Oh wiki tikis you just said
I think one thing 35 seats you just
quite a bad job of he's sort of on
privacy now it wasn't really sort of
like being at the time but um no it
doesn't do a good job at all recognizing
the ways in which our protocol is great
privacy risks and especially the way in
which sort of large-scale use of these
protocols crates um you know the
addition of us of a you know a very
small a large set of small individual
privacy risks together a create a real
problem so I think that would be
something which really would benefit
from some from something I'm not quite
sure what that would be but if there you
know I don't think we really had the
notion at a time that sort of high
dimension high dimensional likes you
know sparse data sets were just such a
big problems that turned out to be
and so having something and as Arvind
remind just basically yesterday so
that's something which I think really
would be nice to him I didn't catch so
much in this in this presentation which
isn't a criticism but just seems like
another thing to put keep in the Opera
sure was I was hurt occur I say you
already know I'd like this work if you
had that conversation
I really missed the days where I could
open a socket to a port less than 1024
and know it was going to be secure that
was awesome come a long way since then
and and been said exactly actually a lot
of what I was gonna say and that the in
society we have this notion of elevated
trust and and as we negotiate and as we
as we communicate with somebody
our level of trusting them comes up I
think there's a few AV documents gonna
come up talking about that as well but
we're missing that in the protocol space
and and yet we users do this all the
time right when you log into a website
frequently you don't log in first I was
just doing some United searches a second
ago right they didn't ask me for my
password and talked out to the point
where it's time to commit I also
remember back in the day is read go to
HTTP sites and use them for a long time
then
it's like you had to submit your credit
card and a lot of times they didn't even
put the submit your credit card you know
number in and until you you just said
trust me the following link will go to a
secure site but we have this notion and
people have this notion of elevated
trust all the time companies ask of us
all the time now I need your two factor
authentication before it didn't why we
don't build that into sort of even more
based protocols I don't know and why we
don't assume that maybe both sides need
some swim set of elevated trust because
they're certain sites I certainly won't
give a credit card to you even though I
may go browse to them I think you're
first oh thank you STP from and CSE so
thank you for revisiting this topic I
think it's very important topic
generally and I've heard a lot of
discussion in the my client's about
endpoint security and considering
different types of endpoints and
classifying them and stuff and I would
just like to highlight again the class
draft that is an individual submission
at the moment which talks about the
capabilities and limitations of endpoint
security solutions so before we read you
that work I'd just like to direct people
to that and and I would also say that
sorry I mean and I would also say that
there's another draft that goes with
that that's also got class in the name
that talks about a taxonomy so that you
can describe these endpoints different
name different endpoints have different
characteristics and so when you are
connecting them you can expect different
behavior and I just wanted to highlight
that again before any work in that same
space just gets redone under a different
name Paul Turner in the definition of
thing 1 and thing 2 and I understand it
thing to now is in flux where would you
place the IETF protocols or the
communication mechanism that they enable
being used as an attack on the endpoint
to compromise an employment so so you've
got the endpoint assuming to be
compromised but if the network is being
used in the protocols Europe being used
as part of that communication it you you
considered that as part of the money
well I I think probably mostly not
unless there's some technical detail
that's kind of interesting but you know
I can send you an email that that's
threatening that doesn't mean there's
anything wrong with RCA 22 and its
derivatives and so so III my initial
reaction would be I can't think of a way
in which we'd end up there but maybe it
may be but if you're looking at a threat
model it's not about solving but at this
point it's about considering that threat
well we have this understanding for
example as we encrypt connections if
somebody is able to use those as an
attack mechanism to get to a compromise
at the endpoint so just it's something
to consider sure I mean I guess I would
argue that just because something's
encrypted just doesn't mean it's an
attack so no tiger can send packets in
care or encrypted or absolutely agree I
mean clearly I mean if you know if 90f
protocol enables a better DDoS
reflection attack because of packet
sizes or something that definitely is
something we need to consider and I'm
not sure as to whether the fact that we
turn on encryption makes things bad is a
possible thing that we should be
contemplating here if that's what you
meant but maybe it wasn't well no but if
we're thinking about the point that the
endpoint can be compromised and this
body focuses on communications is it
important to look at what contribution
does the communication have to
compromising at endpoint as part of that
threat one so just it's again something
they to consider as part of what's been
a pretty broad you know view which I
appreciate sure Laura and slim blade
thinking about maybe breaking thing to
down into thing to a and thing to B or
thing to a is the equipment software and
implementation is to do something and
thing to be is the service or the the
entity that's actually operating stuff
so
I believe the attestation and what we're
going after in rats and eat his thing to
a it's the implementation but a lot of
the discussion here around is is around
privacy and trusting the service and
with your credit card or your data
that's thing to be so the equipment and
the implementations could be great but
the guy that's operating the service is
selling it out the back room to somebody
else or he forgets to do software
updates or something like that so that's
really more that almost seems like
server auth or service off which is I
consider quite different from
attestation and I think we're gonna I'm
hoping rats and eat stays away from the
service part and just sticks to the
implementation part okay kakoton I just
want to try and attempt to and clarify
about all the previous presenters Ming
was trying to say I don't think
necessarily it was work that should be
done but probably the idea is that here
we have we assume the end system
engaging protocol is not being
compromised I think there's like a third
assumption which is that I am NOT an
attacker the person sending the
transmission so so I think so the
consideration is an example you said
like you know why would you think
encryption is a bad thing I don't think
anybody wants to say hey encryptions bad
let's stop doing it but then it does has
negative security impacts as well as
positive I think yesterday they're
mentioning for example researchers can't
see why ot devices are doing because
it's all encrypted so then it has
privacy implications you have devices
now sending your data out to who knows
where and you don't know because
everything's encrypted no that doesn't
mean we should stop encrypting things
doesn't mean maybe even we should think
about this but I think that's the
general concept and as you look like you
were answering that point was that yeah
I was trying to get in there because I
feel increasingly uncomfortable in that
discussion because it started off with
to me like okay there challenges with
endpoint security but I hear people
saying oh that
be the reason why we then
man-in-the-middle our existing protocols
to make things even worse but I I would
like to offer an alternative on as you
know I work for arm and we also have our
friends from Intel in the room we
constantly increase or add features to
hardware providing extra security
features and of course it's a it's a
race against lots of the attackers who
are very very motivated commercially
funded etc etc but we will definitely
appreciate support from also from this
community in making use of those
hardware security mechanisms we have
lots of open source projects and I can
send pointers to the list on what we do
and if some of you guys who care so much
about security want to improve endpoint
security help us to improve some of the
operating systems the firmware on some
of those other mechanisms rather than
just writing one document after the
other and say oh the work is so bad so
let me suggest that we don't have the
breaking TLS discussion in unless the
80s want to do it all over again and so
in general for me in this work we
assumed thing one is still necessary and
I think for me that closes off some of
those discussions at those funny non
optimal crypto things some people might
like to do so I'm Debbie Cooley from NSA
I'm gonna take you out of the weeds and
back up to the space where you belong
here so determining what threat is is
applicable to the system you're in
depends on what you have purview over
right so you have access to this space
and you need to consider the threats
that are applicable against that space
you're begun to reach into the endpoints
in the IETF where you perhaps haven't in
the past and so the endpoint now comes
into the into the purview where it may
not have been in the purview before so
you it needs to be a holistic look at
threat to base on what the system is the
attacker is always going to be one up on
you always right because you have to
protect
everything and he just has to attack the
thing that's the easiest and he wins
right at that point so you have to
spread your resources out amongst the
whole thing and he gets to pick the one
thing that you've missed right so the
first thing you need to decide is
exactly what your space is what part
does the ITF have the most ability to
affect and then you design your threat
documents your threat statement of
threat to meet that if you want to delve
into the endpoint security case which
you have already started to do then that
comes into it and then thing two becomes
part of the game yeah mostly I guess
where I would phrase it differently is I
don't think the ITF has reached in there
the definition of endpoints has changed
over the last decade or so in ways that
have some impact on our threat matter so
so we need the endpoints to be good
right so the thing to statement needs to
be true in that we need the endpoints to
be not compromised I'm not sure I agree
in general no no positive statement
right so I need I need my endpoint to be
a good thing I need not to have an
attacker inside of it so so one of the
things in discussing this we we've been
talking about but haven't come to
something some definition of is maybe if
you think about this as a protocol
between multiple parties if they're all
compromised probably it's game over but
if one of them still isn't maybe there's
something we can do better than we're
doing there so that if that party has
access to everything then I would still
say game over it depends we may be able
to do better than nothing as far as I
guess but I do think you need to look at
things holistically it's just a
one-size-fits-all game right so it just
depends on what the protocol is and what
it affects based on its gonna determine
what you need to care about and it's
really unclear whether we can come up
with something generic enough and then
reduce it to something simple enough
actually
useable does those are all unclear
things yeah all right to be clear we're
cutting lines at the folks that are in
the queue right now okay so today your
game so from Symantec so I think it's
very clear that if you have a prime of
just naming stuff so somebody said what
is the common language to discuss what
is an endpoints actually it's even worse
we don't have a long way to describe an
attack surface internal attack surface
external attacks from other forces we
don't have a model to describe the
attacks and then back to the gentleman
from arm I think that very good points
they are doing stuff on the yard where
people are doing stuff India Brazilian
people are doing some in the application
and on top of that there are other
things you need a suit party on top of
that so we don't have a mother to only
sticky look at the security for all of
these pieces together so I understand
the debate what does it mean for
protocol designers I'm too young here to
discuss that the only thing I can offer
so the work we're doing with mark over
there is try to put words on things so
that at least we start from the same
baseline and I promise you it's already
very hard so if you are interested
please help but at the same time please
you and Jerry give us input what you
need from us I don't know maybe we have
a way to find a good collaboration
mother Thank You Kathleen we already so
I do think we need to go into two and
that we have been already I think where
I differ from Deb's comment is that I
mean ideally we'd keep everything secure
nobody would ever get in but work like
sack and then rats helps us to detect if
something has been compromised so if
there's some sort of change and your
posture assessment or system hygiene
whatever phrase you want to use in the
sacrum sense and that can be signaled
you can detect and then thwart an attack
before either privilege escalation
happens or lateral movement within a
network happens and so you know the
detection piece is something we should
consider
right so you may not keep your system
completely secure but being able to
detect that attacker and thwart them as
quickly
as possible you can look at like
Lockheed Martin kill chain or a mitre
attack and it does benefit you to catch
them early and and that work has has
made a lot of progress in recent years
because the time to detect the tax has
gone way down and it's it's really you
know detecting change so if we could put
more energy into things like stack them
and make it really work and rats I think
those would be big gains and would help
against you know if this is in our
threat model then then we can show that
we're doing real things to aid in in
that objective so just following the
previous comment about ITF workspace so
historically ITF has been the space that
we've been focusing on identifies and
proof of possession so all the way from
ISO Camp Eggers Iran then Hawkins doing
iv1
right IPSec everything's but I the only
way I can prove Who I am is possession
of privacy I think we should extend that
to proving my state so if I'm talking to
you this up besides showing you showing
me your proof of possession show me also
proof of State and and this is what the
rats people are doing this is what the
PCG people have been doing since 1999
again it's a it's a it's a consortium
but but I think the threat model should
address the information modeled rats is
doing oh the other way Iraq maybe the
rats information model needs to inform
the the threats document its yeah person
for me it's not clear how broadly
applicable some of these things are but
I think there definitely you know inputs
that need to be looked at and stay and
yeah there's bits probably that are
cropping up all over the place that are
relevant is yeah and so I guess we have
a mailing list it sounds like we have a
thousand opinions so even yari Brian Ted
thanks for bringing this to us we'll
continue talking it's great that we're
thinking and taking fresh eyes on the
problem and Steven there will be a
mailing list coming where we can
continue to discuss this
we'll post something to sag so we can
continue this all on a dedicated vehicle
okay so timewise we're now in the Open
Mic portion anything you want to talk
about come on up while we're waiting for
those ideas where are the blue sheets
could the blue sheets come up I see one
where's the other blue sheet okay it's
there if you could sign it
all right at the mic going once going
twice
alright thank you so much have a good
rest of the afternoon
and it should be