that's funny
but that is like
hi if you're here for something other
than Zack dispatch oh where you would
like to be otherwise welcome um
Kathleen Moriarty Richard Barnes
together we are sick this bet all of us
together
I say we will dispatch to you all right
note the note well alright so logistics
I guess the first presentation will fall
out of the normal format and Michael
Richardson is gonna talk for four
minutes and present for four and the
rest of them have a 15-minute time slot
I think we're gonna be 15 minutes
presentation if it's a nice discussion
yes anyone have last-minute
modifications or proposals for agenda
items last call before we launch into it
all right seeing no agenda bashes
Michael Richardson please join us on the
stage there's a pink X up here with your
name
we got the bigger than in this video hi
hello okay
hi I'm Michael Richardson and I have
been working on a document called
bootstrapping key infrastructure and
it's an extension of RFC 70:30 which was
produced by the PKK's working group and
in the process of doing Interop testing
we discovered some hoops ins next slide
so RFC 70/30 runs over HTTPS and lets
you view certificate enrollment using
CMC methods and throughout the document
it believes it's running over sy and
rather than HTTP as a result it asks you
to put content transfer encoding heading
your headers in with the say base64 and
and then asks you to basically for stuff
that could be binary and so that was a
bit confusing so it turns out that it
turns out that there are no actual real
implementations out there of it that
actually put the content transfer
encoding header in because it's actually
deprecated by all the HTTP documents so
implementers are left wondering does
that mean that I should put binary in
the in what's there or base64-encoded
and the answer is the document said to
base64 encode it so they did with the
result that people were like oh okay
it's basic C 4 encoded well is Bruschi
base64 encoded even though it doesn't
say it and therefore we got into
confusion things and it also makes it a
little more confusing because people
like to run things with curl which is
really hard to dump binary objects into
it but really easy to jump base64 things
in and people don't always realize
whether they're providing a convenient
encoding to curl or whether they're
actually that's what they're
transmitting anyway so this is a
document that basically shrimps to
clarify these four four points two of
them errata were raised by Shawn Turner
next slide actually
the content part two of them are raised
by by Sean Turner on this topic there is
an ASN one complaint about the document
that it does it wrong and I actually and
not I have no idea if it's right or
wrong and I need help on that and then
finally there's a typo that apparently
in extra space that apparently when
implementation believed was mandatory
and insisted was there and then they
realized it was just it was a
typographic issue in the document when
they tried to interoperate so those are
four things that just a simple
clarification document on it I don't
think it's worth revising the best Ness
document next slightly I don't believe
it's worth revising the document are
doing abyss at this point you may have
seen my zero zero zero one documents
which went on the assumption that
content transfer encoding was actually
being sent we actually could upgrade
everything to binary if only we could
change the what was there and after a
fair number of feedback we realized this
was impossible it's got to stay the way
it is and we just need to document it as
this is broken in the following way
deal that's it any questions you know
four minutes for questions if anyone
would like to ask clarifications about
the verification stuff or tell tell this
group where the document should be
processed so just to recall the dispatch
options we could form a new working
group from this document yeah you could
pull the ball we could dispatch the
existing working group right maybe
sponsor or we could tell you to go away
are you telling your they ya gong yeah
my suggestion is either to send it the
documents of lamps which vaguely has
impaired and P kick stuff and probably
has the asn.1 clue to fix the other part
or ad sponsor it and I believe Alexei
has volunteered it just be better folks
think that's appropriate Martin um non
Thompson I have a slight preference for
going to an existing working group if
you but an existing working group if you
if you can find one that
is willing to take on the work some of
these working groups don't really have
the charters for it which makes it a
little tricky so I don't really mind I
also prefer that because I think it will
get the better early review on the a s
and one thing that it needs rather than
happening at and discusses so um the
thing that occurs is perhaps you could
monkey patch this in some way using
content encoding to avoid that base64
issue but I don't know if we have a
base64 content encoding so that that
would be new work and so it might you
know content transfer encoding is not a
thing in HTTP so yeah let's not pretend
that happen but we might be able to do
something that will for those that
implement this correctly up to the new
standard won't result in any confusion
terms so of the four or five actions
that are defined all but one are posts
and so you have to the client has to
somehow guess having never spoken to the
server before like whether it accepts
this new format or not and that turns
out to be non-trivial unless we I don't
know we go LPN or something I don't know
what but do know me
I think it's do not fix just yeah so
just document it yeah
all right so the hi I'm Sean Turner the
joke comm is we should just rename lamps
P kicks wait forever but I think you
should probably send it there since it's
already kind of the P kicks thing even
sorry shouldn't you should send it to
lamps lamps and you should rename P
kicks or lamps Topeka X Prime or
something great like that made long live
forever I think we should definitely fix
these things I think I don't know I was
considering whether we could use the
HTTP except header to try to tell the
server what you support there was
something that Mark Nottingham suggested
at one point that maybe there's some way
we could figure out how to do that I
don't know if that'll work but it's
something to propose and I guess in the
errata that I submitted there were some
suggestions for workarounds about should
be except to do this so that so maybe
those weasel worrying work and maybe it
won't fit and that actually works great
for the response
and I actually implemented it but it
doesn't work for the post and then I
went oh so I will step out of the way
because I know I'm no expert
hi Berman didn't you we can say lamps
and that that's okay I'd love to hear
folks are directing conferred Lance I
would just remind we probably need to
have a charter conversation yeah exactly
so Rick Sol's the other reason that send
it to lamps is that's where Jim shod and
Russ Housley hang out and they are the
asn.1 experts so thank you for making my
point for me
month olds back on the post issue there
is now say that talks about content
encoding and client requests and I think
that we're almost in that area and so
there's a there's a bunch of text about
how to deal with that in that RC I can
send it positive which document is this
our seed med mid that I can't remember
off the top of my head but I'll find it
for you and send it off 72 72 30 series
or or something else 70 to 30 so but one
of those you mean yeah something
something in the HTTP area yes
okay about about content negotiation for
post is what you're saying for okay
exactly what are you talking about
okay this is so the speakers know
there's echoes off of this wall so it's
weird
I can hear it I can hear him both
directly and off the wall and off the
speaker so it's just really weird yeah
Martin speak up so Michael it sounds
like your preference is to go to lamps
there's some comments from the floor
that dispatch this to lamps Russell's a
standing up is he coming to the mic as
lamps chair okay Hades I'm looking to
units I'm like a pause block um okay
great so well consider this dispatched
two lamps then thank you
next up is dave carroll or some
controller Ike
okay it's like yeah oh they're up I
can't see there should be a quicker
there if you want try driving yourself
does this not work
alright umm so I'm here to talk about
controller Ike this is something we
started doing in SD when work and it's
been growing in the routing group a lot
of interest in it it is basically a key
management protocol there what is it
Ike is basically a key management
protocol that will drop in in place of
standard Ike except it works through a
controller you know the concept is there
is no peer-to-peer direct messaging at a
high level it's pretty simple so what
we're doing is a different exchange just
like you know the idea is to try to make
it similar to diffie-hellman you would
do in Ike but we're doing it through a
controller and we're trying to keep the
scale of the messaging down yeah so the
problem we came up with that we had to
address was that we had we're doing
large-scale networks we were doing
10,000 plus nodes in a full mesh and
there was too much hike going on the
amount of traffic over the network was
too high the complexity just was not
manageable as an N squared and so by
coming up with a controller based model
we've reduced the messaging to order n
control basically each peer creates a
different public value sends it to the
controller controller collects these all
and sends them all down the concept is
very simple where this gets interesting
is when you try to synchronize if you
obviously you'll have to do rekeying and
when rekeying happy
you have the problem that keys get
distributed to different periods at
different times for redundancy reasons
you'll want to have multiple controllers
the state isn't always the same and so
the draft that we put forward is
addresses the synchronization and shows
how you can handle that with a
centralized controller base to key
exchange yeah and the key there is no
peer-to-peer messaging what isn't it
we're not pushing this as a replacement
to Ike obviously I guess stood the test
of time it's around but in certain
models this is we find this it to be a
little more ideal it is also not a
two-way attribute negotiation protocol
you can you can end up with two peers in
Ike that we may offer different things
and the other wants in in this there is
much more of a limit
you've got to but but in this model
worth coming from a centralized
controller and so we're not as worried
about needing to negotiate completely
disparate options there is a small
ability to negotiate a hierarchy for you
know you may have a couple of algorithms
and you can negotiate down I won't go
into the details but it's in there and
the other the other key to this is we're
not providing the secure communication
to the controller so this is a protocol
that is embedded in something else in
the VIP Telos cisco the the Pella
sp1 products we have our own protocol
that is secure in the routing working
groups we are working with bgp insecure
bgp messages and that's all taken care
of as part of the communication to the
route reflector
so why do we want to do this so the key
for us is optimization we reduce the
complexity reproduce the messaging from
N squared to n but there's there's other
attributes to this that are really have
been really helpful for us in SD Wham's
so one of the one of the keys that we
found is we have customers that want to
do control over a managed secure network
they may have an MPLS link that's
provision they have whatever they have
but the data doesn't necessarily go over
that same network and this allows us to
do control over one messaging over
another the other side of it is we work
at at least one customer that had some
very odd shaped networks they had links
that were not bi-directional and so you
have a case where two peers cannot talk
to each other by directionally but they
can each talk to the controller and so
we can provide a way to do key
management and still have a one-way
IPSec tunnel so where is this being used
I'll throw it a few drafts here these
are things that are being pushed forward
in some other working groups I know
IDR I think it's tomorrow is gonna be
talking a lot about security
architecture and directions that this is
headed and this is it hopefully intended
to be one part of that architecture
Wednesday got it not tomorrow and you
know and this has been discussed drafts
with this have been presented in best
it's been discussed in IDR even the I to
NSF work has looked into this and this
could fit in very well with the I to NSF
infrastructure though not as the not as
the messaging portion just the
configuration much like Ike who will
skip by that
so when is when is stuff happening there
are currently two implementations of
this draft that are known to be there to
be fair and honest they are very
incestuously related so maybe it's not
quite - but the stuff is working it is
going it's also currently under
consideration a number of working groups
that are looking to try to integrate a
controller based key management for uh
for SD lands for overlay networking and
then this is kind of my last slide I've
tried to do this rather quickly and the
next question is one can we do something
else something to move forward Erika
scroll so I guess first answer to a
clarifying question on when you say it's
not in squared
it's n what do you what units are you
counting in messages okay cuz it is N
squared in helmand calculations are
still N squared sin squared data
transmission as well right because you
have to send every grace to send and
October since and out everybody can
write so if those are unidirectional
connections they still one squared right
it's 2n everybody sends a message up to
the controller the controller sends a
message down to everybody else but that
message can if that's the addressing
data in messages right anyway this is 2n
it's order n again if you're counting
messages versus bytes things are very
very different but anyway so on your
pain I mean so this is like by the way
skip um in case nobody here people don't
remember history this is basically the
same protocol that Sun originally
proposed Friday SEC and was and we ended
up selecting Ike and as we've skipped
you're paying a lot for this which is
you're not getting PFS and you have the
odd protocol design without confirmation
so I guess I guess as I said of my email
um an alternative design is to do
effectively is to basically do key
establishment only when you need it and
then basically overhead you're paying is
whatever messages you're sending in
addition to the actual communication
you're setting because I assume you do
intend to send packets right do intend
to send data packets right exactly um so
not necessarily bidirectionally
understood but you don't need but on
there there are plenty of designs which
don't require by commercial
communication and still get you better
guarantees than this does so you know
I'm not trying to push forward that this
draft is the be-all end-all protocol for
a controller based model but I would
like to start the discussion on a
controller based model not using the
peer-to-peer well I guess I would
encourage you to sharpen I encourage you
to see the requirements where I wasn't
stating the design you're looking for um
because it seems to me that the
requirements bit won't back out of this
don't necessarily get you to the
conclusion you just got to okay I'm not
sure what requirements are well you're
saying you don't want to do peer to peer
but why I'm slow say again you said you
don't want to do peer to peer but what
we source are you conserving i I don't
always have peer-to-peer bi-directional
communication I'm conserving Methodism
Natives it's not just like propose an
alternative hypothetical here imagining
everyone has bi-directional connectivity
to a controller one one design you could
adopt is to do normal Ike directly
between the normal Ike from one peer to
another but tunneled via those
controller connections right as well so
so that you do normal Ike full mesh but
over the controller connection because
you have bi-directional constant
connectivity that way so I guess I I
think kind of what occurs asking is like
how does this design differ from that
one given that both of those use the
controller to route messages between the
various endpoints well at that point you
know again now you're doing N squared
message
and you're doing it all through the
controller which is going to become
quite a bottleneck I this this is where
we came up with as a more optional I was
right that so my follow up that might
clarify what Richards and my question is
do you have a goal to be able to work
between split brain controllers where
there's multiple controllers and they no
longer the partitions in parts of the
network and still have things happen in
other words do you have an idea that you
might also be doing ike between
controllers to build meshes between
networks that were partitioned as for us
from there on their control links I have
implementations that do that today we
work we work with multiple and other
local controllers where each peer may
only talk to one of the controller
doesn't look like IP to between the two
controllers it does not do i ke to
between it does something very very
similar to this so please Holly said
Jesse so one of the use cases for the
controller is bgp route reflector and
our redundancy built into it and we do
this point emotionally it is been there
past 15 20 years being truant and the
idea and we've have we've had many
services VPN services based on this
controller last but not least a VPN and
there is requirement to be able to add
security features to evpn and leverage
that controller and this is one of the
draft that we are introducing in the
best and ideal working group and it is
getting good traction and the idea is I
have the controller I'm doing this
signaling for my VPN and many other
things I'd like to be able to use the
same controller to
to leverage it for point-to-point
tunneling soda so the signaling
connection is point-to-multipoint the
signaling but the tunnel
IPSec tunnel that they set up as a
result of their signaling his
point-to-point and the work in terms of
how the signaling is done as I said
we've introduced a trap in best and
we're getting fairly good very good
interest on it then the downbar from
choo-choo I I strongly support this
proposal I think the IPSec have been the
industry for many decades right
primarily is peer to peer however in
today's environment for example for
enterprise going to the cloud or
Enterprise going to multiple clouds you
have an edge device it's no longer just
one connection to make here we're
talking about multiple connections I
have an edge device I may have five 10
tenants connected to my edge device each
attendant in to talk to their peers
right so from one edge supposedly if I
have just simply 10 no that's not
talking about 100 nodes Network 10 node
Network if I had to talk to connect with
all my dear so that means I have to have
9 connection to all my peers but if I
have 5 tenants attached each of them
need a cassette so that's 5 times 9 so
for one node today I have to support 45
peer-to-peer key management that's a lot
of work and in addition to that for SD
one or the device connecting to the
multiple cloud there's always always a
controller doesn't matter it's not just
for this particular purpose for other
purposes neither controller so as a
device today you already have a secure
connection with the controller through
that secure connection you can
distribute all those key informations
not directly key information per se but
rekey mechanism all those kind of
requires to rekey so that make the whole
network scalable otherwise just
unimaginable OneNote probably have to
handle hundreds of keys and that's just
not manageable by a small virtual device
especially I support this maybe this
exactly mechanism doesn't have to be the
one but it's controller paged IKEA has
to be in something to be discussed idea
so we have about a minute left per
person before needs to start wrapping
this up so please be breathing okay yeah
you have mirror culture effect Alyssa
this was presented in nitro NSF and I to
a surface has this document about using
a controller to initiate IPSec and you
have two modes or cases and one with I
can run without like a class installed
and we saw this is kind of a middle
ground and what I'm missing is what does
this give you that the I less that case
it does not give you so so in the I -
and it's a flow projection the eyeglass
case is simply having keys produced at
the controller and pushed down to the
ends so the controller now owns or knows
every key used in the network there's
certain obvious limitations to that sort
of model in the past I've spoken in I to
NSF about trying to integrate this into
that flow and since then this is
somewhat evolved with the routing groups
and the notion would be that I to NSF
would be used to configure the static
configuration for either an IKE or a
controller Ike but then the actual
dynamic messaging would happen through a
route reflector not through the I to NSF
yang model I think that's a much cleaner
design with what I to NSF has put
forward but I don't see where we need
both that both this and that's too many
ways to get to the same thing so does
this need to be revisited in Knight to
NSF after developments yet
the document is pretty much done so not
with this document if somebody wants to
extend it later I can assess maybe the
home I so so the architecture that's
currently being put forward in best as
far as these dynamic routing models has
a configuration server that configures
nodes as they come online they need to
do some sort of ztp or something else to
connect to the network and they get a
configuration pushed but then there's
the dynamic routing where they send the
overlay routing to the RR and that would
be a more ideal place to send key
management updates yeah so I think
insert dispatch here and we're not like
building the protocol it sounds to me
like there's some confusion about the
actual requirements here maybe you put
people is by me and since designing
aches is kind of like difficult and
getting em right is not easy but they
could be really useful to get like a
somewhat clearer statement about how
this problem domain is sufficiently
different from other problems that means
that we can't lovers and they already
have and I think then exchange you and I
had earlier suggest to these I don't
understand this properly I'm telling my
fault but um so I think interest
dispatching this what we were helpful BJ
said we have a clear problem statements
that actually make clear like what this
use case how it's different and
potentially in ways that are more
constrained in a way in perhaps
bandwidth in ways that are less
constrained insurers have any controller
available right and then we can see what
protocol actually makes sense from a
super-intense asterick Union we hadn't
you know presentation of tha gave me
some time ago I remember and conclusion
was that we said that I need to do which
I paycheck so we don't want to do it the
night basic crew so if somebody
could propose that that's a solution to
that we are not going to take it like
this again me because this doesn't have
anything to check the other problem I
have disease is that it's assumes like
arrow saying you don't have really
requirements this assumes that your
whole network is stuck because they if
you have if you start building this
network one by one you have one node
that you add one node then even a dog
then
her unsecured okay because every time
you add a note you need to send that one
note sent a packet to controller
controller sent a packet to everybody to
tell us
oh that's happening you know public key
here and then somebody else it says
again so every time you set up notice
and end packets and you add in notes
it's n times in so into it so but your
if of course if you have everything
ready you have 10,000 notes there you
can send the 10,000 you know perfect
case at the same time and you know the
network starts the other problem I have
there is that you have to always you
know you know the benefits for Ike is
that you create the keys only when you
need if you have 10,000 nodes there you
don't have to trade in Harran SS when
you boot up you create only those it
says if you need it when you talk to
somebody and in most of the networks or
environments you don't need to talk to
everybody in the network every time all
the time you talk to you know handful of
people who are no next to you are all
discography so you have very you know
strict requirements that are not really
you know or or use case is very specific
this kind of you have static network
where everybody happens to talk to
everybody all the time and you create
the whole network in the beginning so
let me address both of those actually
this works really well in dynamic
networks when you start bringing nodes
online the node simply has to contact
one source the route reflector as it
were in there in the routing model and
update it with its diffie-hellman
information as well as the overlay
routes that it knows alright and the
overlay router is regularly sending
these updates to all the other routers
so it's it gets to them anyway he's not
adding to any load we had you know if
you have 99 nodes and you add one more
it's simply the next update from that
controller is going to have a hundred
entries instead of 99 it it done tends
to work really but that that still sent
a hundred messages 100 nodes
Bitsy's you know yes yes because because
you send periodic messages with Ike
doesn't you actually generating much
more traffic
because who sent every now and send you
have hundred messages to everybody
telling that they you know you were you
were sending the controller was sending
99 messages out anyway yeah it's the
latest status update here's the latest
update on the routes here's the latest
update on if you being at home in a
message sees your send over their
lifetime of the network I think that
actually is bigger than what they go to
what you do when you actually create the
ITSs Phil hamburger it strikes me that
this isn't so much a key exchange as a
message flow and I'm very interested in
this and here's why quantum resistance I
mean other moment but no solution for it
you know there are proposals but the
only thing that we could deploy today
will be Kerberos and this actually if
you look at the protocol level it's
looking pretty close to clear Kerberos
and so I think it's interesting to look
at as a fail-safe in the quantum
resistance world and so I'm interested
in that point of view as far as where it
gets dispatched to I'm pretty sure that
this is not an ad sponsored draft so I
think that it's a working group it
sounds like it's not IPSec so the
question is whether it's a working
report not anything at all so so just to
add real quick we've done you know a
bunch of thinking about quantum
resistance with this and if it needs
more work but yes when they cut the
lines here and again please be brief
Sunnis since you're doing a performance
optimization here I was wondering
whether you posted something about the
details of that performance improvements
because I was caught a little bit
confused on the discussions on the
scalability aspects which I didn't quite
see in like in the number of notes that
were mentioned I don't I would like to
see some of those details clarifying
he's doing a performance optimization
I'm maybe he has already written up
something about the details on the
performance gains that he expects to see
but I'm just not aware of those thank
you just from that mike is super hard to
hear up here okay for everyone
how many sensory I think there was a
misunderstanding by the other gentleman
who was here and talking about if you
add a note then you're gonna end up
sending tons of messages that's not the
case when you add a note that note talks
to the rot reflector which is the
controller and gets the information from
the controller so you're not sending any
other messages and the saving is on the
ingress notes or the note that you keep
adding to the network those can be a
very low power low low end notes that
don't have the you know the CPU capacity
of sending or n messages and in this
case we are just the note send a single
message to the controller and whoever
comes up taps of the controller and gets
that message and they get their public
keys and calculate the Cherokee dan yeah
thanks again Harkins so I noticed that
there's been some people coming in the
mic and talking to you about better ways
to do this you know Eric head of
suggesting territory isn't Alaska I'm
sorry I don't know your name
we're talking about you know different
ways to solve this problem or to do it
better or something else so it looks
like there's enough interest in this
kind of a problem and so I think when is
probably you know real soon now and
probably right now but I think we're I
don't see why I can't go into IPSec this
is no more of a weirdo key exchange them
like the G DOI stuff that we did so it's
it seems like if process is the reason
we wouldn't do this it seems like a
really
poor outcome for the ietf it looks like
there's enough interest and do something
like this looks like it solves a problem
so I mean let's put it in IPSec if we
got to change the Charter than let's
change the Charter it's so what well I
mean I would I would have to say you
know I don't want to disagree with the
IPSec can be working working group
chairs but to me this is an IPSec thing
yeah we're using the sole easy purpose
in just a second you know we're using
this solely for the purpose of wreaking
IPSec it's know it's providing a
function that I provides it's providing
a function that the GUI stuff did you
are using yes we're not using IPSec he
allows you to create ESP pockets if your
key he is as much of I can DC's yes you
can use multiple key management
protocols to create IPSec SI or from a
ESPs keying material an ESP no sponsors
but but that's not make it that doesn't
make it I basic and the people in the
IPSec can make group are interesting
IPSec which includes arc and they were
not interesting on this because they see
that they're only you know very small
piece of this is the ESP that is common
what they are going now
so as I said heap has his babies using
ESP it has exactly same common you know
understanding that this one I mean I
don't want to have a heap coming here
jido is actually using I person to
messaging between the you know peers and
it's actually using like person to frame
that's why it's much more concern that
there was lots of people who were saying
oh do we actually want to do that the
option was to have a separate you know
working group or or and we decided that
it still has some most of the same
people would be interested that's why
it's in there I wish I can make again
since it's a dispatch group I think we
should first which consensus is of some
work we should do from istea perspective
and heard a comment about adding one new
node or trigger so many messages I just
want at one more point that in like for
example use SDI as an example
all the notes have to get controller to
dictate who we can communicate you
because we're talking about the overlay
Network I'm here in Montreal I have my
period in Dallas and I don't just talk
to Dallas maybe I'm not even allowed to
talk to him the controller has to
dictate who I talk to
so it makes more sense I have a
controller dictated I get controlled a
key so that they can send to the control
group but that's just one more
requirement that thing we should okay
thank you speak we're gonna try to wrap
up wraps up here yeah I mean so there's
I think still some lack of clarity among
many people in the audience part about
what the requirements are we heard some
talk in passing about the overlay
Network and maybe an implication that
the second is really bad and maybe the
implication that with overlay Network
you need to actually need to give every
node the key from every other node which
would get into some the scaling and
number of messages questions that were
raised so it's not really clear that the
people in the room have the information
that they need to make the dispatch
question maybe we should have more
discussion maybe we should have a
mailing list that we can do that or do
you want to keep it on sexist nuts yeah
yeah as you guys like and I think we
could have some discussion on psych
dispatch because it's still discussing
how to dispatch it or if you'd like a
new list or you can have a more focused
discussion more focus group I'm sure and
I'd say you've gotten a lot of good
feedback there's a really active
discussion so you know some of the
points that came out for revising their
requirements so that they were clear and
a revision of the draft would be helpful
if the ABS want it on a separate list
that of course is is an option or we
continue to leave it discussed on SEC
dispatch for a while until it's found at
home but it there's their interest I'm
comfortable leaving it on SEC dispatch
unless there's a desire to have a view
[Music]
okay so nothing for now except revised
and defined requirements more clearly
right and then we see you figure out
next steps okay thank you thank you oh
I'm Tom Baker I'm here to present on the
mathematical mesh so internet security
is broken it's broken because we keep
being told it's broken in the news and
if you look at what we do here we use
very little cryptography that isn't
described in Bruce Schneier blue book we
don't use anything from the red book
we've improved some of our algorithms
but we're still approaching the problems
in the same way the things like s/mime
open PGP the user spending too much
effort they're not using them and
they're not going to change so we've got
to change our approach and if you look
at the problems out there most of the
breaches of a data at rest and we focus
on transport we've got to look at the
data at rest problem as well because
that's where the breaches are the
approach that I want to approach apply
here is meta cryptography I want to go
beyond the PGP Canon and one key
cryptography des allows you to solve a
lot of problems you know ATM systems
were made possible by debts however two
key cryptography allows you to do more
because you can separate out the roles
when encryption and decryption of
different keys different people can do
it so if one key cryptography is good
and two keys are better why don't we try
yeah so it's about moving towards more
keys more separation of roles more
separation of duties and this allows you
to do some really cool stuff like have a
cloud service
that with all the encrypted data but can
encrypt stuff but doesn't have the
ability to decrypt because it doesn't
have any other it's the key manager it
doesn't have acne actual keys so the
solution I've come up with for this is
more than just an application it's
really a platform and when you look at
what you need to support this and make
it usable by end-users you need to do
three basic things you need to be able
to join together that all their devices
into one Gestalt so that they can read
the word document read the Excel
spreadsheet read their email on any one
of them now people aren't going to use
PGP if you can't read your email on
every one of your devices you currently
do so you don't have a way of doing that
key portability you have to have a way
of establishing trusted relationship
with other users and you have to have a
secure control plane messaging to
support all of the above
and the thing is that when you've got
all that infrastructure to support this
one application well you can use it to
secure almost everything else or to make
the use of anything else
easy when I show this to Dave Clark he
said well SSH can you do something about
making SSH easy to use because thing
about SSH is ok it's not that difficult
to use however if you make a mistake in
the wrong time somebody's got to get on
a plane to fix it and I've done that so
I've designed it in such a way that you
can reuse this thing in other stuff and
it's designed with the deployment
strategy that even though this cloud
computing multi key cryptography is
where I want to end up that that's not
the first application I'm looking to
sell it as the bunch of technology out
there I'm going to go through a summary
of just a few of them but there's more
technology there and it can be used and
it's all MIT license is all unencumbered
as far as I'm aware it should be good to
go
so one of those technologies is PGP
fingerprints revisited allow us to
represent any output not just an md5 as
a base 32 encrypted screen and apply
this to content digests to nonces
encryption secrets
Jameer secret sharing h max allow you to
present that data in the same syntax now
you're asking why aren't these URIs well
they're not you are eyes themselves but
you can put them in any URI and here's
what you can get from you putting it in
you your I so we have here an encryption
key and we've added to it a domain okay
so that is a u RN with a domain it can't
be resolved by a regular browser but if
you take the fingerprint the content
digest of the encryption key and you
slap the well-known service on top now
we've got a locator we can pull an
encrypted document and then use that
encryption secret to decrypt it okay so
now we've got a URI that allows you to D
retrieve and decrypt the information
let's just that as a QR code and now you
can put something on your business card
that links to a PGP fingerprint that's
actually actionable locatable and so i
use this type of technology to connect
devices to a personal mesh or contacts
to a mesh account and you could also use
it though on applications like put a QR
code on an invoice or a bill or your tax
return links to electronic copy there
off and all that data in the cloud is
all encrypted so even if the crowd is
breached the data isn't one of the
technologies is the replacement for
pkcs7 now this wouldn't be essential in
itself but the reason that I needed to
fill
with it was because I wanted to do the
multi key cryptography stuff and bowtie
and finish there wasn't much pkcs7 left
and so I get rid of the legacy and I
designed it so that you can stack
envelopes together to make a container
so you can now do blockchain type
integrity checks you can create a Merkel
tree as you add your envelopes the
container take the envelope out give it
to somebody check the signature on it
and now you've got one signature check
one signature on the container can
authenticate any message so it's a way
of doing incremental authentication you
can also do incremental encryption so
one key exchange at the start of the log
file can be used to encrypt a subsequent
entry and these are all flexible you
know their options not requirements so
what can we do to create applications
out of there well in the mesh I use
these to support my mesh accounts mesh
accounts belong to the user not a
service so when you go and you start up
the mesh you create accounts for
yourself and then you decide whether you
want Google or Microsoft or whoever to
support them and you want to change you
can because they're designed to be low
switching costs we could use the same
exact technology for your server logs so
that you can get to GDP our compliance
or rather make it cheaper to get to
certain types of GDP our compliance
where you're trying to make sure that
you know exactly who is reading your
server logs and who is analyzing them so
what I'm trying to do here this is
almost zero trust cryptography but not
quite I'm trying to distrust each party
as much as possible by separation of
roles so if I buy a piece of equipment I
attached it to I mmm mesh I don't want
to trust any key that the manufacturer
has put in there during manufacture but
I certainly want to make the use of such
a key
in particular if it's put in there
during manufacture in such a way that it
can't ever come out and so I use the
same meta cryptographic techniques that
allow me to split keys
to combine them and this is all
technology that Matt Blais table and
medicine and others developed in the
1990s and didn't get used because it
wasn't part of the PGP Canon and so it's
about moving forward beyond that kind to
do something else so as I mentioned I
have a messaging plane here now the idea
here is not to replace smtp well not
immediately but to have a mechanism that
is limited to sending control messages
that is guaranteed to be end-to-end
secure this is guaranteed to provide
certain traffic analysis resistance
capabilities and is also abuse resistant
every message that is sent as a message
is access controlled at the sending
service and the receiving service so it
doesn't prevent spam absolutely but it
makes it very difficult to make a profit
sending spam now I apply this to manage
that secure contact exchange to manage
the connection of devices to a personal
mesh but it can also be used for other
things yeah 50 line application is
provides us with two-factor
authentication a few more lines allows
us to go beyond two-factor so say I want
to add somebody you know say I'm adding
some payee to my bank account my bank
could send me a message to say do you
really want to use to add this person to
the account yes or no I can say yes and
that goes a signed statement that is a
second factor authentication because
it's bound to the device but it's also
bound to the semantics of the
transaction that are actually accepted
which is something you don't get with
the numeric code second factor
authentication
so I've given you a brief and you know
we'll win tour of a bunch of Technology
and I hope that it's not being too
insensible but the question that I've
now got is where do we go from here
yeah and releasing this stuff there's
already the Alpha is out there on github
and I need to start releasing this in
the fall because that's when
universities start and that's when
undergrads and graduate students start
looking for projects and so I want to
get this and you know I want this to
become a standard somewhere the ITF
looks like it's probably the best fit it
may not be you know if the ITF doesn't
want it I'll have to take it somewhere
else so the question is you know is this
ready for ITF work you know do we need
to look at it as an RTF thing first
if should we start the working group you
know should we do it as experimental or
whatever but you know I'm coming here
now because I'm gonna start deploying
and the minute that I start to get users
I'm going to be protecting those users
I'm not going to be wanting to make
changes that might introduce backwards
compatibility so well unless there's a
real value to doing it so you know speak
now or hold your peace yeah so that's it
so comments people's on us all I have
two questions first question is IP our
second question is how does this fit
with existing security protocols who
pretty much assumes the one or two key
model okay so on IP are there is no IP
are on any of the stuff that represented
today that I'm aware of
I'm aware of prior art that would
invalidate most claims that go back for
to the 1990s as I said this was the
basic techniques were developed by Matt
glaze table and pedis and others
this is threshold cryptography there's a
fairly well-established literature so
I don't believe that there's an IPR
blocking issue there or my code is MIT
license so it's open source in the most
open source license now as far as
integrating with two key cryptography
now you can use the mesh to distribute
private key pairs to two devices views
with s/mime or with PGP or anything else
the only restriction that you have there
is that you would have to be using if
you're going to make use but if you just
want to distribute RSA keys you can if
you wanted to use make use of the freaky
stuff within PGP we could extend PGP or
s/mime to make use of it however you
would then have to use elliptic curve
diffie-hellman or find some other
threshold cryptography scheme the
threshold cryptography schemes I use
they're currently using IDI for 48 the
CFR G curve and I'm using that for
signature and encryption I can use curve
X as what instead but because it's
Montgomery I have to write a different
set of code I didn't want to do that for
expedience reviews I can take offline so
you killed use this with open PGP you
don't change encryption at all the only
thing that changes is decription alright
Thompson thanks for bringing this here
this is really huge and that is kind of
what I'm trying to get to and if in my
opinion at least if the ITF it takes on
work of this nature it's kind of a major
project in the sense that WebRTC was a
major project or sip was a major project
or something along those lines so I
would suggest at a minimum this requires
above and it's good that you bring it
here and having the discussions
but it also suggests that if you say
you're not willing to change your your
code there might be a problem because
there's going to take a little while to
get this thing working
oh absolutely I'm absolutely willing you
know if somebody will come to me and say
we need to change that or whatever I'm
perfectly willing to do that
however if somebody came to me today and
said hey Phil I read your drafts and you
know if you just changed this or you did
this this way yeah I could make radical
changes under the hood and the cost of
that would be zero if however we go down
the line and it's kind of like people
you know did you yeah so I'm just saying
you know please don't wait until people
have started to adopt it to read the
drafts and then come and say oh but you
need to do it in sn1 it's kind of like
yep so I'm absolutely happy to make
changes you know I mean at the moment
you know this is kind of like the
autistic world according to Phil yeah
I'm aware of that and I am I want to
have as much input as possible I'm just
I do have a question for you um how many
other implementers do you have
interested in at the moment to have no
implementers but you know I'm coming
here to say you know I mean one of the
requirements for a buff is that people
have to have seen it which is why I'm
presenting here before yeah um thanks
for presenting this um budgeting stuff
here um I guess I was sort of seeing
something same things Martin was asking
I guess this would be a little easier
for you to assimilate if it weren't all
one monolithic thing I understand that I
understand you think of this components
but it's hard for me to reason about it
that way so you're realistically we're
not gonna replace SSH however much one
might not like it and realistic
I mean realistic we had this since
normos installed base of like of like
things right and my experience I'm sure
yours has been is that you know those
things don't don't die easily so
absolutely this is not about replacing
SSH but what you could use here is
instead of use it I mean the problem
with SSH from my point of view is people
use it but they don't necessarily use it
securely and if you look at some of the
guides for how to secure SSH that are
out there on the web I mean it's like
mail yourself the private key so that
you can have it on your devices and it's
kind of like so you but you could use it
for is to distribute the SSH keys so
then you can use them it's got backwards
compatibility it's just that I could
have used instead of the Dare envelope I
could have used pkcs7 I could have used
their said Wan I did Jason and that type
of stuff sure yeah I guess so what make
me me it easier at least for me to
understand situation um I mean I think I
understand the threat hold stuff like
poison we weld but we can either
understand your vision I think if I
understand how it fit in with the things
like sort of committed to later or not
yeah honest pill on the mailing list you
said that you believe that this was also
applicability to the IOD environment
that I was curious on whether you could
have elaborate on that a little bit to
the what the Internet of Things right so
yes so I could one of the things that
the reason I think that Alice needs some
wit Mayo
connecting all the devices to something
that she controls is that right now I
have an enormous number of IOT devices
I'll be talking about this on my
Thursday rant on the Pecha Kucha session
so I've got about don't tell the wife
okay so I have an incredible amount of
IOT stuff and I have an enormous amount
of accounts with services to manage them
and because of that I don't have an
Internet of Things
none of my devices will talk to each
other and it's got worse not better you
know I have all these nest devices and
they used to talk and now they're not
going to talk and so what we can do with
the so if every device has a set of keys
for encryption or authentication and
signature that are layered into the
device when they join my mesh then they
can talk to coordination you know
dashboards that I control and I can get
to the point you know what I want to do
is to drive up to the house and for the
doors to open the lights to go on and so
I need that intervention scripting but
right now I can't have it and we can't
have it because the model that everybody
has is you can the device connects up to
the service in the cloud to an account
run by the IOT device provider and then
my hub in my house connects up to that
hub and then when the Internet's out my
house is offline so in the IOT world
this is a way that you can avoid
depending upon that service and a way
that we can get from this current not an
internet of things things that just
happen to have Ethernet or Wi-Fi or
Bluetooth but aren't internet because
they won't work with each other and the
thing is that it will be easier and
cheaper for you to use my stuff as it
from toolkit than to invent it yourself
Thanks
hi Sean Turner
hey Phil I think you've been doing this
for maybe longer than I have so I would
say that based on your pitch right now I
would say that this work is not
applicable to the IHF because it didn't
really sound like you were willing to
take changes if you this work gets
adopted by the IETF
you might not even be the author of the
working group drafts if there was a
working group
so whatever the working group consensus
would be to change it we change it so
maybe you just misspoke but I just want
to make it clear
like you do understand that if this were
to happen oh absolutely uh you know
there's two types of changes that happen
here right one of them is somebody says
okay we want to do this functionality we
want to add that yeah that stuff
perfectly fine if suddenly comes to me
and say oh that's great but I want you
to do it all in sn1 an email you though
that's the problem the rights of the
working group consensus is we want to
come up with some new encoding scheme
and call it unki Squa sn2 or whatever
like that's just the way it will of the
working group yeah I guess I guess if
you understand that that's ok and I
think everyone here does yeah I mean if
there's a group of people who are
willing to do it and implement and
deploy I mean like yeah but you know if
it's kind of like right the point is
that right now if you had some idea that
you you think would radically improve
the functionality and there was no other
reason rather than your personal I could
do it I mean we all know that the
standardization process sometimes
introduces silly chains that we don't
understand or don't like like at the end
we had one thing that was a bit string
and it was like please change to a
boolean I mean like sometimes things
things gotta happen but you kind of got
to do it if that's the consensus oh yeah
it's basically like the same with
security requirements where we ask
people to read the drafts early rather
than late I'm just making that point
that you know please read the stuff now
don't wait for two years for me to have
users and then for me to say yeah that
would be a really good idea for us to do
then but you know oh you know legacy
deployments great but it's also a tract
rich sauce yes both ways so part of me
feels like this is sort of like
contributing to global warming because
the oceans are getting all boiled away
and maybe if there were a simpler
smaller piece that could be split off
and it seems that potentially the UDF
stuff because I know other groups have
wrestled with naming key
openpgp i think was the last one the guy
trying to do it um so i recommend
pulling that work out skipping the fact
that it's got 75 possible use cases and
it's the solution to world hunger and
just address it's a way to distribute a
name keys that is no web compatible oh
yeah i mean that would make great sense
and the fingerprint piece could actually
be pulled out as a separate unit the
other stuff kind of depends upon the
fingerprints as a fundamental
infrastructure so I would take this
single presented as an iw conference
actually and talk to the self sovereign
people I think you'd have a lot in
common with them and there is a at least
conceptually there is there seems to be
some overlap with what they try to do
I'm not advocating that stuff myself but
I think well in humane a little bit
maybe but I would actually go talk to
this out so learn identity people they I
think
let's I'm not touching the word self
sovereign identity go go go for self
sovereign identity you look at the stuff
that they talk about it it looks a lot
like this they they're trying to address
sort of the same problems again and
again I I don't
I personally run with that crowd sigh I
couldn't tell you more about the details
but I do know that they meet at this
conference cycle in in Silicon Valley
called the internet identity workshop
and I think that in that slide the
answer to the question of where go talk
to them first I think before you know
deciding this needs to be in ITF this
needs to be in the idea
thanks Brett Jordan I really like this
thank you for doing this work I think
it's really great I'd love to work with
you on it whether it's here whether
somewhere whether it's on the moon I
don't care I think there's some really
neat things that could solve a lot of
problems so thank you for doing the work
thank you
hi so personally thank you for bringing
this kind of here kind of chatting with
that and listen the community I think
that folks have poked at interesting
parts of exactly what you're suggesting
I think that there were tactical
suggestions in terms of responding about
kind of scope what about this what about
that but I think the overriding thing
that resonates for us is this is a big
thing there is no way we can move we can
move forward with something of you know
the full scope we were even a narrow
scope without a bomb so we would
strongly encourage you to oh yeah I mean
I anticipated that I know one of the
things I am trying to grip the reason I
brought it here was that the
precondition for having a buff has to be
that there's in the right people at the
buff and that they've actually looked at
the technology beforehand so I didn't
want to a soar above here because if I
did you know then you know nobody would
know about the work so you know I'm very
happy going forward with a buff I if
people have you know my current research
concern on it is working out how to
scale because at the moment I've I've
gone run the numbers I can run a million
users but this is targeting a billion so
if people could help me on that right
now I'd be very grateful but yeah I mean
a boss would that would be my preferred
way ahead so a quick question while
you're at the mic since the next step
for this could be a bath should we set
up a separate mailing list specific to
this work to track it I think I would
make sense if you're up for that
absolutely yes I've been very going back
to the IPR piece I've been very careful
to only discuss this on less that have a
note well equivalents and so I want to
make sure that we maintain the IPR
situation thank you
great so mailing lists and stuff thank
you thank you very much all right so the
summary from all of them all right so
the first presentation was if anybody
wants to talk about it afterwards meet
me yeah and we'll announce the list name
whatever it is or Phil will on
the suck dispatch list so you can follow
along thank you so from the first the
extra from Michael the decision was that
we would dispatch it to lamps for the
controller Ike the go forward there was
to specify requirements revise the draft
based on feedback and to continue the
discussion for now on tech dispatch to
figure out next steps and for Phil's
presentation on mathematical mesh that
go forward is this needs a buff it's a
large body of work and the go forward
discussions will be on a separate
mailing list announced on this one soon
so is there anything else blue sheets
did everyone find them and where are
they have to return them you can't take
them home all right so just to be good
wrap up with the blue sheets if you
figure out oh ok so the blue sheets
didn't make this side of the room can
are they just sitting somewhere on a
chair oh right ok I'll bring em around
for you ok thank you
although now we're done thanks thank you
everyone