[Music]
it's TCPS Roman into some recipient
place
town or leave X or
other presenters name my first there
okay this is TCP I'm welcome my name is
Marco Dixon my name is Lucy my name is
Michael chauffeur so can you do the next
slide
ah maybe I can this is the node well it
applies not only to this session but to
every session so you have seen it we
don't need a note-taker
thank you for Richard and Gauri for be
willing to do that
Micra is doing the JavaScript and if you
are going to the Mike state your name
and make sure that the note takers can
see your batch if they don't know your
name so that's the agenda we give
awaking working group of status update
we have the talks or presentations
regarding three working group documents
RFC 21 40 bits the RFC 793 bits and a
document which is at the end of the last
call period the converter draft and
after that we have several presentations
regarding non working group documents
one is about hi start plus plus then two
presentations regarding yang on gory
walls says something generic regarding
conditional control and at the end we
have a presentation regarding the new
TCP proposed TCP a feature called TCP
export is there any requests for
changing anything that's not the case
then we will follow that a Jemma
we have a couple of documents the first
one is the shepherdess Michaels past the
Micah Micah
yes so the first document that you're
about to finish is deity chicken
converter one so for that I have started
a working class code you see here on the
slide that I've put in there but almost
finished almost means that I'm basically
waiting for confirmation from felt that
he's or a pretty comprehensive review
and has been addressed other than that I
think we are find that this my blend is
too close to work in coop last call once
I have this confirmation from foe and
then we will move on you don't have a
presentation on this draft later in this
session but as I said I'm going to close
to work in coop last call
once I have to conversate confirmation
from fault that all comes addressed and
finally I've done this on the list
already I would just want to give the
heads up we have seen as part of the
last call an IPO declaration I assume
that you're all familiar with that and
so if there's no comment on that we
assume that that's not an issue okay so
then we have a document accurate easy in
the working group last call for that is
planned soon soon means we hope to get
it done such that the working group last
call ends before the next ITF we have
generalized ezn the document has been
updated we have the RTO consider
document that hasn't been updated but
since the last IETF but we found two
reviewers Gauri and Jenna have said that
they will review this we have a document
checkered Shepherd for it is Yoshi fumu
for me and so we hope that we get
something done by the next IAT Evan
opposite the mic I
gone generalized ACN it's being ready
for working great law school for about
six months three IDs now what's
happening you've got a list comment on
that one you've received a list comment
on that one from you okay check the
listing there's a comment on that one
and so please work on it then we have to
base document 793 and 21:40 we have
presentations regarding them and the
last document eCPM rack has been updated
it seems to be stable and we will figure
out how to progress that document hi
this is Praveen I had a comment on the
rack document so it seems to be stable I
think we gave some feedback and that's
been updated so I think it would be very
it's very close to last call in my
opinion other than minor editorial fixes
it seems ready to me so what do the
chairs think about that basically that
says share that you so we will contact
the authors and see how to progress that
um it would be good if you can provide
the feedback to the wrist or to the
authors probably better to the list I
will do that thank you
that's the last slide so this means we
go to the presentations one note we have
a packed agenda so please try to stay on
your time limits
the first one is Michael on our C 21 40
bit okay yeah 21:40 piece update - 2140
next slide please
oh yes I can do it now I do it but that
doesn't really work I just try to focus
no I mean it works but in this aligned
way that's good got it
okay I guess one important thing to
point out about that slide is the number
o six which means that this thing has
gone through several updates and reviews
and comments in this group already
before adoption that was because at that
time we were asking for PCP and that's
no longer the case now it's
informational and adopted as such quick
list of some updates that we made we
reissued it with the correct name we
cleaned some often references to T TCP
there was a lot of some some well
ancient texts in in this draft that
really had to be removed from from 21:40
moved references to the informative
section and updated section to updated
to clarify that there is no impact on
interoperability and updated appendix B
as per request so regarding next steps
we as two others thought it through we
don't find very much we believe this is
pretty much ready
except there's one thing that we would
like to include the document discusses
in Samba sharing and temporal sharing
right sharing assemblage when you have
parallel ongoing TCP connections they
would share information between them and
temporal is connection is over new
connection comes and you should learn
something from the previous now it just
talks about these things and it doesn't
really say anything about time
what does later connections mean right
it doesn't discuss timescales it doesn't
discuss what is successful sharing its
resolve party CP convergence so the we
plan to add a short section on these
things
the next version that will talk a little
bit about how long TCP information is
valid which is very much dependent on
what information it is to give you an
example
RT t bar for example that reflects the
current traffic behavior and it's
probably something that a week later
makes no sense at all tier 4 states okay
week probably is too much too much for
that as well but it does reflect the
state from the pier and the past state
so unless the path changes and unless
the pier is upgraded or changed that may
be well it for a long time you know it
may actually even make sense to keep it
for a week to just try it so these are
two very different cases and if you have
some very long lasting state this may
also benefit from special consideration
there are some constants that you may
find all the time I've never worked you
know if something never worked in a week
on the same path with the same host with
the same destination and the host is
maybe not the mobile one staying in the
same place at some point it may make
sense to Jo and start adjusting them so
there are some ideas that come from a
previous draft from Jo touch this
automatic adjustment of the initial
window this is just an example
considering the initial window right now
we have this experimental initial window
10 we have some most using larger values
we have some hosts using smaller values
a question is simply if you could be a
little bit more dynamic I think this is
a good slide to remind readers that this
is an informational document so we're
not proposing
an algorithm that would be you know
recommended for anybody to implement
it's just a description of possibilities
well so if you know for instance a very
large initial window never work to one
destination for a long long time it
probably isn't really useful to keep if
the sender's congestion window always
gets much larger than the initial window
is and why limit it to ten maybe if you
do pay spacing as well the interesting
thing here is that adding send some
dynami city to this would automatically
do an experiment and auto adjust to the
environment so you that is in line with
this other draft from Joe if you would
have an old and a slow network
connection that has a small a small note
that might just never increase its
initial window even over weeks a month
so that this draft talks about you know
long timescales my own office machine
where the network is prepared your own
permanently upgraded together with a
backbone that might dynamically change
the windows so these considerations may
make sense regarding these things there
are different types of feedback that can
influence these distant Emma City
currently this is all convergence based
the end values affect the future
predictions simply by how the statistics
aggregate but there are other ways that
that could be done we would call them
implicit and explicit implicit will be a
matter of tracking well initial
conditions persist over a connection I
suppose it could be a very specific
thing like looking at a particular
packet exchange again this will be just
a discussion of these possibilities and
that's it I think it's last slide
questions comments
so very fast em ya hunger talk I'm going
to talk later but and I'm curious to
know what sort of numbers you have from
other RFC's just these time periods or
whether you're gonna say oh we can do it
in future so did you come across any
numbers to say how long you think a past
valid I did not okay
how many people have read that document
okay so give it a read um I guess you
want to change you said you want to
update the document yeah I think so this
yeah okay so then we are looking forward
to in your region thank you
alright so that - where's can you hear
me yes they're trying to get the slides
up I can see them so yeah I'm Wes and
it's nice to be virtually meeting today
I haven't been able to make it in person
for a while but have been working on RFC
793 biz for quite a while and thought it
was really important to try to talk
virtually about it today because well I
think it's needing to get ready for a
working group last call soon because
it's getting at a point where the things
we've identified to do are pretty much
done and there's not a lot of churn
happening so but that's
I'll go to the next chart and I wanted
to take a minute just to because we
haven't been talking about this at the
past few meetings much just give the
background so people remember what we're
trying to do so
RFC 793 everyone hopefully knows is the
TCP specification it's been around for a
very long time and was never actually
updated fully although a lot of things
updated partially and so several years
ago working group decided to adopt an
attempt to update it and to make that
tractable we said going in sort of the
approaches to not open up any new topics
really but just to focus on dealing with
accepted errata so things that have been
submitted over the years and collected
through the arts the editors I ran a
process and then the area directors have
talked to the work groups usually and
market them either verified or held for
document update or rejected we're not
going to put the rejected ones into the
document then we collected all the other
rfcs that update parts of 793 and tried
to make sure that those updated parts
got reflected and you know most
importantly were we're not opening us
this up like there was some discussion
early on about changing the semantics of
something like the options link to do
long options and stuff like that oh
we're not not chartered to do that in
this document so let's not talk about
that today the goal though that I've
been using as editor of the document is
to
trying to patch in the exact text from
all of the relevant documents wherever
possible as you'll probably notice in
reading it that doesn't always lead to
the the most smooth a flowing document
but the hope is that it prevents us from
adding any mistakes so next chart so I
posted a revision 13 that you can find
on the ITF site now and if you check the
diffs you'll notice there are only very
small updates and those are pretty
boring so adding a section reference
about triggering this error report
functionality for different ICMP types
there's one open issue that I have some
notes around and we'll talk about in a
little bit and then I had been marking
the IANA considerations as like a to-do
thing to to analyze whether there were
any registries that needed to be updated
or something like that but I did sort of
a check on that and didn't think that
there was anything further than needed
to be done there so I just sort of took
away that to-do item so with that update
the only thing I think that's left to
fix is this issue that we'll talk about
next I have a revision of 14 it's in
work you can find it on the in the git
repository that this look at URL there
points to and have already made fixes
there to version 13 based on Gregg
Skinner's review that went to the
mailing list also Michel scharff's
reviewed the mailing list a few days ago
and a couple of other small things that
I noticed so the the bullet at the
bottom is actually already outdated
because yesterday I
I added a commit that addresses Michael
sharps review so if you go to the next
chart one of the things that I did
recently a couple of versions ago or
revisions of the draft ago that I wanted
to make sure people were aware of what
we're talking is all of the requirements
language in the spec wherever it says it
should a must should not must not things
like that I labeled and then with like
unique IDs so we have like must one must
two must three and then you can find
those labels in an appendix that lists
all the conformance requirements and
that was borrowed from RFC 1122 that had
a similar table of requirements and then
links to the section numbers where those
were discussed labeling the specific
requirement sentences rather than the
sections is the main change here so a
couple people said that that seemed
useful so I did it and I didn't think it
was going to be very much work and it
turned out to be more work than I
thought but it is done now so the next
chart this is an issue and I'm hoping to
get maybe a little feedback from the
room on this talking about it with the
chairs we had three different readings
of what RFC 1122 says so maybe one of
them is correct
thing I'm going to propose though after
looking at a bit more detail myself is
my proposal is that we actually don't do
anything what I'm going to talk just
briefly to convince you that maybe
that's the right
insert so I had something I'm worked to
do in the document because I thought
there was an issue around what's called
error report functionality in RFC 1122
describes it now that's kind of a funny
thing already
because in TCP stacks with the socket
interface we don't exactly have
something that matches the error report
functionality though they're sort of
ways that that what's described happens
so it's it's sort of a generic
functionality anyways now RFC 1122 to me
looked inconsistent in one of the
aspects of describing this error report
functionality because there is one
section that says these reports must be
triggered in the case of excessive
retransmissions
so when the there's there's you know
threshold for giving up and there's
another threshold for notifying
application and also notifying IP that
there seems to be a connectivity issue
so it appeared for me that the text said
you must trigger reports when you hit
that first threshold where there it
looks like there's a connectivity issue
and then I found another place in the
document so the section numbers are here
in case you want to look them up in RFC
1122 there's another section bullet D
and I say the second one because they're
actually two bullet d's in that list
there's a editorial bug in 1122 so
that's that's even more confusing than
it needs to be but that second bullet
seems to say you should trigger the
error report and
of course i was confused by this and
discussing it with the chairs a little
bit one of the things that came out is i
think there's a possibility that we
could interpret this as you must
implement the functionality and you
really should generate the the error
report and for reference I wanted to
look at Linux and Windows error codes
and see what's done here and actually
couldn't find anything corresponding to
this terms of an error that's generated
for the application to receive in either
case so I think that it may not be the
most relevant thing to spend a ton of
time on but my proposal is basically to
do nothing if people have written stacks
all these years based on the 1122 text
and not been confused then maybe my
initial confusion was just almost this
area so I'd like to ask for feedback on
this do we do you think there's
something to be done here can we leave
it alone
so this is mrs. Michael speaking from
the floor I would agree
effect all sections and I personally
agree do nothing good so if there's
anyone else but of course we'll relay
this the mailing list and check out that
Oh Gauri
Gauri fast even less helpful
I haven't read but I probably agree from
reading 1122 previously it's got these
problems and I think you're doing the
right thing I will happily read again no
you pointed me to it thank you I could
talk some from the floor just reading
the text could it be that they should
you were referring to which you think is
inconsistent that should is so the
sentence is tcp should and then at the
end when our one is reached and before
our two so in this condition is assured
in the other one it's a must
that's possibility too
yeah
my guess is though if we don't know for
sure that that's what is meant and if
stacks aren't doing this we probably
don't want to change what the spec says
okay so if you buy that I'll move on to
the next chart
Michael sharp watch some great comments
and we don't need to go through them in
in much detail but I sort of summarized
them here so you can see that they're
fairly minor so adding cross-reference
deduplicating some text there was some
really historic language in there left
over from like the pdp-11 days and stuff
so at that I have removed in the
repository copy and I also removed all
the stale glossary terms about the
ARPANET and things like that which
weren't actually referenced in the rest
the document anyways so I think Michael
and his review agreed these are quite
small things and in general it's fairly
stable and in in good overall shape
which brings me to I think my last chart
the next one we're thinking the next
steps I'm pretty sure we're converging
so I'd like to propose that we're doing
it working group last call soon so that
people can check if we really are
converged to a good place and I was
hoping that we could identify some
specific reviewers who will you know be
on the spot to take a close look at the
document and I was also wondering if we
should request any early cross area
director reviews specifically so that we
don't have anyone surprised that we're
revising the core TCP spec somewhere
else and wind up with difficult IETF
last call comments or something so I
think this is the opportunity to
a stirring for reviewers yeah thanks
essential address and I agree so I'd
like to open the floor here first of all
are there any comments on what Wes has
just said on the stability of the
document and may I ask who has read a
recent version of the document so for
the record that is two three three
okay that is probably not good enough
for going to work in coop last call but
we do need reviewers for this document
so and I'm now asking the room all their
volunteers who would want here to read
this document and I can personally say
it's it's easy to read so it's it's it's
pretty okay so don't be worried it's
it's a good document okay so I see
channa thanks a lot I see Gauri anybody
you've shown in the past has been a good
reviewer luteum yes I we had a private
conversation I hope that we convince him
as well anybody else okay
okay
pravin on shebar also agreed so that's
excellent so then I think we have a
decent list to stop this and are to be
hope that we get reviews relatively soon
the final question that Wes has raised
is there something actually a little bit
for our ad on the question whether we
should really ask for crotch area
revenue I personally actually agree with
less that is something we my - in order
to get really feedback from some of the
other areas that obviously heavily use
TCP so what I'm asking maybe's in the
room so are there any any thoughts on
whether we should do that or if that's a
bad idea or when we should with it I'm
not sure it's necessary because they
mainly use TCP and you don't change the
interface say and there will be at least
and I believe in ops review at the very
end which is probably the most helpful
one so that will help me anyway so I'm
not sure if it's necessary yeah I mean
the discussion that we had with versus
whether ops and also security area which
we should ask earlier because we don't
know what will happen there and just to
speed up maybe the process yes I find
your comment about people who might be
using TCP a little bit ironic I don't
think there's anybody IETF who doesn't
use TCP but it behooves us to get it
right and if the application developers
find something that we didn't find we're
really screwed up
okay as I see that in netf last call
covers at all yeah sure I mean we for
sure we all understand that this
document is essential for the IHF as a
whole and the ITF last call will be
essential for this document so that's
the Landis would be yeah we've just have
to discuss the the best way to approach
that and to to make the process as
smooth as possible
and to ensure that at the end of the day
we have an excellent document so are
there any other comments on on the
process here seem to be the case so if
my conclusion is that we have certain
agreement here in the room on proceeding
that's to display that this we will
reach out to the reviewers and then once
we have to read feedback we will think
about starting a working group last call
of course it depends a little bit on on
the timing of the reviews and the amount
of comments that we get but in general
at least my intention would be that we
get this off the table as soon as
possible maybe already around the next
meeting or early next year so that would
be my plan okay then there are no
further comments or and thanks a lot
less and let's move on so the next
presentation is about the converter also
remote sorry look
I know and then maybe the more doesn't
work yeah you have to tell how can you
change this right right well point it to
in that direction not work
yeah okay then you have to say I'll
change the slides hello good afternoon I
am someone from Korea Telecom and in the
meanwhile generosity combo dropped is in
the in the Working Girl rustic or so I
asked my sis kaikora telecom and data
has prepared some proof of concept of
the generosity compare implementation of
the rear 5g so I will talk about about I
will talk about today about some
deserted theory POC please no previous
it's number three and go to the number
one
the usual motivation of the general TTT
speak um but protocol is to provide the
rod the number of current TCP enable -
crying - uses multiple TCP because the
number of client had multiple much
participe is much more large number of
than the number of servers so actually
the crime I just wanted to benefit from
the amputee CP at least on the fraction
of the end-to-end past even in the in
the wireless or wired or something
something like that but there's a figure
yeah it looks like a somewhat yeah Roku
not there but anyway so actually the
company protocol profile the generic one
because we can convert any kind of TCP
options and for example TFO sack or
something timestamp or even even
including the MP TCP so we are now in
the TCP I'm working group so it is can
be it could be offset to window
generally so next slide please so a
basic enjoying of the Girardi combo
protocol is an application level
protocol and it is reasoning on the
specific TCP port
similarly web service is pure subtract
test and all of the commands and the
reefs responses are encoded in the TR v
format and though it provides the more
extensibility the other than the other
kind of approach the protocol like a sax
or open IP encapsulation or something
like that so actually the first comment
are sent through the scene hey wrote and
this information contains the actual
destination IP address and port
information and because it uses on the
middle of the three-way handshake of
regular TCP it provides the diversity to
me but minimize the delay to establish
new connections and also the same act
message provides the responses when the
one up to three handshake
and because we don't use the any kind of
encrypt encapsulation or proxy like
protocol on top of the application so if
we call it our praying transport mode
between the Christ and the converters so
what am i our clients can run what TCP
options supported by the server and from
the clients vice versa so it allows the
tried to bypass all the TCP options to
the server side in the middle of the
converter next slide please
so I simply example here so there's a
client on the left side and the server
on the right side and the converter
proxying the meter side so whenever were
crying over to make a real connection at
the TCP they they shouldn't have to
three-way handshake
starting with the same message so sin
contains the server IP and the port
number and the command is to connect is
sent to the camera and convert and send
the same message to the actual server
based on the information of the current
TLP current connect information and
rating for the select from the server
and the combo is turned back to the
client about the scenic MSS are using
the okay div and actually this Oh
extensible extending 50p option so
actually after that actual data goes
through the data go through the
comparator to the server where another
direction so actually on the data
there's no need to include any kind of
PRP x-ray please
so put a proven concept that is MKT
prepared later
so it's collaboration to increment that
engineering about the based on the
trapped but on all six but now out
button on I by the way huh but in the
cry side we uses open source Krantz
rivalry and the y Shakti sector to see
the compare rocks on our Wireshark were
some engineering analysis which is
casting that you are a up there and we
compared our art if you combat a
protocol with the sax wasn't five
protocol and the I it works on the we
are incrementing on the Android new
smartphone Samsung Galaxy S 10 with a 5c
model and the we uses engineering
version of the firmware to modify some
of the system command over routing
routing primary so for the generality we
used open source acts integration for
the SAS version 5 we uses the Red Sox
which is commercially users in the KT
telecom to our subscribers and as you
can see in the in the bottom the left
hand side is shows the effect indicator
5 the only mode and the right hand
bottom side is shows the Wi-Fi + 5 g
first Wi-Fi the same time and we can use
the multiple TCP together that's right
Chris so the majority actually we tested
in the in the actual real commercial
fighting at 12 on once 10 dollar amount
3.5 gigahertz new radio control and user
playing separation motor to 5c core and
all the transport IP protocol is ipv6
and and for the Wi-Fi we used to edit
that 11 ax for the Wi-Fi 6 and we reuse
those together for 5 10 to Wi-Fi and
though we compare
the latency for the rtcp set up time for
posterity and the socks and the actually
the matching is 40 TFP time to first by
the time from the promoters in send and
receive the connection of sessom effect
acceptance from the one of the our
gateway proxy servers so monitor come to
the center we in the in Decorah telecom
datacenter we used toast the generosity
combo a protocol supported hack hybrid
access gateway which is modified by that
there's a restaurant for the Cossacks
who uses some commercial version of the
mobile entity proxy and we compare it
that so as you can see in the graph the
most is the generosity compared
multipass mode actually at this time we
uses the Wi-Fi as a primary route route
so we can get a twenty seven millisecond
in average shorter agency and photo
privacy 64 millisecond for the director
RTT converter agency and the photoshops
compared to the generosity you can see
the for the purgatory case more than the
three times more than the latency is a
more higher in the football multiple TCP
mode of the Assads short shorter than
the HOV mode it's because the in the mid
multiple TCP after thusly we handshake
out the artistic collection the sax
protocol procedure is called pseudo some
portions of us asked for two purposes of
fancy and some portion of from another
portion of the procedure call suta Wi-Fi
is why the the references is a much
smaller tend to fight you anymore okay
next right is so other instances and us
right and we compare the signaling of
the diversity convert and the SAS refi
and the inter web site from the commode
toast crime site to the proxy
we requires around LTTE just the TCP syn
synack and the egg and the pod from the
combatants proxy site to the server we
neither one RTT
and by the way sucks out of 5 because we
are using the other education mod we
need the flow ITT's when the client to
the proxy side each because enrich the
ferocity because some of the sucks first
seizure functions requires some
processing time it can be not piggy
backed by idea push message each at
least the PO RT t it can be a motor
diversity and the press random and make
it precise to the server because the
velocity so but just well compared to
your activity in the in the figure the
genetic can be are much less shorter
shoot later speed and thus at Spotify so
uh this is a difficulty and that's right
and custom thanks a lot or are there any
questions on that presentation I would
have one mostest document Shepherd
so are these prototypes or is this
production deployment or do you plan for
doing a production deployment of that so
actually we have a commercial service
based on the identity and if it is
possible actually I'm from the KT rare
so I need to talk about that the
advantage of the generosity and I would
like to ask my marketing did not enter
yeah in the Samsung or so also the best
vendor so so so so are there any
questions you see just out of curiosity
so you're using open-source socks on the
converter so you can what you don't have
a so called syndication in just in this
signaling graph yes actually
because I because we need some time to
implement this one so actually we can
insert some identification message in
the TRP together whiskey a scene or
scenic or something like that so we are
preparing of the that is that another
draught and actually we need a time so I
didn't fermented at that kind of an
authentication for this one yes and the
one more thing is no socks button six
try to support zero ITT kind of sir you
might already know it so you might be
interesting if you compare thought six
and then combining actually in the soft
spot of six into in the routing area
were inferior right yeah yeah yeah
actually it requires an additional extra
handshaking after the PCP and shaking so
it is totally art it is much more better
than Thea yeah that's about six I think
so yeah I wish you to compare up that
yeah together yeah greater might be
interesting yeah okay thank you thank
you thank you for the talk and the point
of information Sox six is being
considered as a possible work item in TS
v WG so comments on Sox six and its
usefulness would be really appreciated
over there that's not so sorry i
presentable to the presenter as well six
fully but the last time I indicate Katie
try to make a somewhat similar to the
subspecies
yeah alter connect and the
identification and the mess mess so the
trustees are at the same time just one
procedure so we can see we can so that
the returns these are shorter than the
actual sass was a five so yeah actually
yeah that make well yeah yeah but yeah
yeah okay thanks to my comment about
that yeah the experience on six
is is well appreciated here yeah thanks
a lot is really very useful information
we often do this in TCP M if we finalize
the document it's always good to have
feedback from potential users so thanks
a lot for this very useful data and as I
said before for this document is about
to finish the only pending thing is is I
have to find flow basically and then we
are done with the document and we will
ship it to di is Qi then so thanks a lot
thank you so if it's terminates the
section of presentations regarding
working of documents so the next one is
praveen miss I start plus plus and his
remote hi can you hear me yes hi
everyone today I'm going to present hi
start plus plus it's a modified version
of slow start for TCP work done with
others but present in today next slide
please
so first let's quickly recap hi start so
traditional slow start for TCP has a
flaw so it does exponential increase but
it can potentially overshoot the ideal
sending rate by a lot and this causes
massive packet drops and then TCP spends
multiple round-trip times recovering
from those losses even if you have
logically algorithms like rack sometimes
this hands up causing retransmission
timeout so high start is a paper that
was published which had two schemes to
solve this problem
so the Cole here is to exit slow start
early before the Mass Effect packet loss
happens so the paper had two algorithms
one was based on deal increase and the
other was based on entropic at arrival
the original paper suggested that the
sender run both of these algorithms in
parallel
and then exit slow start early the
problem is that the inter packet arrival
algorithm does not really work well
because there is a lot of act
compression happening
both on the receiver because of things
like RC as well as I meant LRO and as
well as the network doing ACK
compression the dealer increase
algorithm works but we find that it has
a lot of false positives
this happens because of latency
fluctuations on wireless links it also
happens because there could be a large
burst from another flow that could cause
transient queue build-up which could
last multiple round-trip times and then
you and then the fluid ends up exiting
slow start very early and then
congestion avoidance will take a long
time to ramp up next slide please so
what is the deal increase algorithm the
goal is to keep track of the minimum of
0 delta T in each round so four rounds
where so we keep track of this minimum
oddity until the condition window is
higher than the minimum ssthresh value
this is to ensure that slow start does
not exit too early there's some
protection and high start for not
exiting slow start early so the first
few rounds we know not eyes it's lost
out even if delay is increasing once
that condition is met then we calculate
bt a based on the last rounds observed
minimal T and if the current round our
GT is greater than a certain threshold
from the last minimum observed our
treaty then we exit slow start and we
capture the value of insets Thresh I'm
loading down the constants that is used
in the current implementation and
windows I I believe that the constants
are very similar in Linux based on
mailing list discussions next slide
please so why is this not sufficient the
problem here is that even if you do this
only for the initial slow start the slow
start could exit prematurely because of
the two problems I mentioned so what
high star plus plus does is introduces
Limited slow start right after
the TCP flow leaves slow-start
so basically what we want to do here is
for each arriving AK we want to still
grow the congestion window but not
exponentially so this is an additive
increase its large additive increase and
this will continue until the congestion
signal happens the next congestion
signal happens and then we enter
condition avoidance so this is a phase
between slow start and congestion
avoidance we do limit reach slow start
the Ellis's divisor we picked was based
on experimental results in the lab
simulating various possible bottleneck
buffer links buffer sizes as well as RTT
and bandwidth next slide please so when
we posted this draft to the mailing list
there was a very interesting suggestion
by Anil Cardwell so thanks to him so on
high bdp links this can still cause the
congestion window to gross too slowly if
even if we do limited slow start so the
idea is to basically also start
computing the congestion avoidance based
congestion window and take the max of
the value computed by limiter slow start
as well as condition avoidance this
basically we were able to force this
condition explicitly and we observed
that for hi V DP links this does end up
helping so the ramp up is much faster in
cases where we exit too early due to
high start next slide please so the
current status is that this is deployed
this is on by default for all
connections I am talking to you from a
system that has this on by default the
fix for the high BP links is also now in
preview so we expect to be also turned
that on for the next release the draft
was actually posted to the mailing list
so please review and provide us feedback
they already had one review but I would
be I'd appreciate it if more people
could review this and provide us
feedback in future we would like to
compare the other proposals for
improving slow start which is VBR
startup phase as well as
bass chirping which used to be a very
recent research on doing slow start by
using pacing and then any questions and
I will also like to ask the chairs
whether we can wrap this document in TCP
m9 questions Jen I endure kind of doing
this presentation Praveen it's useful I
was going to say that you said you're
using a system that uses this right now
but you must have startup phase so we
don't quite know how it went but I
limited that I was going to ask you if
you had any any any traces that you
could show where you could could show hi
surplus plus behavior it seems quite
promising and obviously you've done
measurements and we've seen this you've
probably seen a million traces when we
super useful to see a few places to
understand exactly what the dynamics are
I'm also quite interested in
understanding the convergence dynamics
of icer plus plus with other flows work
as well thanks John oh that's great
feedback so yes we would like to present
more results on this we do have lab
measurement data we are also currently
working on metrics that we could collect
more data from the wild to be able to
compare actually in in production
systems data from in production system
to see how effective this is so we are
currently working on techniques to do a
very effective comparison from both lab
measurements as well as in wild
measurements so yes I will try to get
you that data by the next ideas I
appreciate her thank you much I was also
going to ask you a separate question
this is so high sod basically tries to
figure out how to leave early and that's
useful but also work that can be done at
the beginning of I start this is still
continuously all of these except for
page chirping we
this exponential increase that happens
at the beginning have you thought about
changing that aspect of it so
exponentially increase actually is very
very helpful so yes because you're
starting out fresh yeah you can use a
higher initial congestion window and
pace but even then for high bdp links if
you don't do exponential increase then
it's very difficult to figure out what
the ideal sending rate should be
experiencing making it more aggressive
no we have actually we find that it's
already too aggressive that's the reason
like high start helps a lot and that's
why Isis is also so effective because
under the righty of network conditions
we find that this overshoots the idols
and rate almost all the time so so it's
actually too aggressive already so
that's the reason we are doing high
stats just a last comment I'm basically
I'm trying to clarify my point which is
high sod is a way to leave exponential
increase what I'm talking about is paste
shopping for example doesn't do that
exponential increase up front it does it
but in a very different sort of way I'm
trying to figure out if there are ways
to combine those things where high
surplus plus helps you leave
remove when you when you then believe
that you've you've sat you to the
network but you start off in a different
way but yes certainly possible at least
for this draft the goal was to actually
document the implementation as this so
currently is intended for informational
status but I do agree that there's a lot
of like possible more possible research
here to make slow start better is an
individual asking if you run this on any
network source ee marking to see if that
avoids the bursty behavior it's
beginning your chain so unfortunately
easy and is not widely deployed and we
don't turn it on by default so we don't
have data to suggest if it's it will
help but certainly none of this changes
response to congestion signals right so
if you get do get explicit congestion
signal we will exit slow start so and
again we will exit low limit or slow
start as well whenever
there's a condition signal so none of
that changes but no we have not
experimented with ECM okay I would like
to see some experiments was easy and on
evening I would comment that is what
China China said about this using pacing
and combining it with high stealth and I
see they are totally incompatible
because I start realizing building clear
team and pacing on the other hand tries
to avoid building
q so it's hard to measure something you
don't build so any other questions
that's not the case thank you for that
Praveen you're asking for working group
adoption so the document is clearly
within the scope and can be taken at
some point of time we would like to see
measurement data before we do this yeah
thanks I will work on that thank you
okay thank you so the next one is also
remote presentation about jingle pings
for TCP clients and servers yes I can
hear me yes we do okay great remote
stuff is working pretty well today
we are trying to bring up the slides
okay great I can see them and I'll just
say next is we need to move along so hi
my name is Kent Watson and I'm typically
in the net continent mod working groups
but today I'm presenting to TC p.m. a
draft that's been adopted by the neck
off working group for defining gang
groupings for TCP clients and servers my
co-author Michael Scharf is has helped
me with this and I think it was adopted
we see see the TCP mailing lists during
the adoption poll after 104 next slide
please
so firstly it's understood that within
TCP you know their simultaneous opens
and you know peer-to-peer protocol
there's not really a client or server
but nonetheless here and we refer to
terms client and server the client is
the peer that's initiating the
connection and the server's the peer
that's receiving or accepting the
connection having the open port it's
also noteworthy that within the net
cough and were Tresckow protocols
sometimes the client is the controller
or network management application
whereas the server's the device which
would be a router or switch or firewall
for instance next slide please
this is actually a problem that the
Netcom porting group has been trying to
solve for roughly five years the problem
being how to configure Netcom from
rushkoff clients and servers using gang
data bottles so you know designing the
gang data models that would produce the
configuration hierarchy and in many
cases translates out to CLI that could
be executed on routers and switches or
firewalls or or even now the protocols
are being used by higher-level
applications and so it actually
initiated off with one draft being the
Netcom server draft and then quickly
folks said oh we let's also have not
just neck off but we need to do rest
comp as well and then we can't just do
servers we have to do clients and it
became larger and larger my slide please
just a little bit about yang beta models
I I think some of you may
have a passing understanding of gang a
note certainly popular within the ietf
of late but not everyone is up to speeds
so just quickly yang is an ITF
replacement for SNMP MIPS it is a way to
describe data it's a data modeling
language yang is Tanaka Andres Kampf or
likewise XML JSON as for instance and
mythos - SNMP XS D is to XML ASTM dot 1
is to Pender ber encoding and avian F is
to binary
hopefully that makes sense next slide
please
ok so just going back to the history and
interestingly this slides not formatted
it supposed to be pretty ASCII our
symmetric tree there but nonetheless in
the 2000 sorry in the ITF 102 time frame
the net off work group had the following
hierarchy of adopted working group
drafts so the the the names that you see
there are actually draft names you would
prefix each of them with draft - IETF -
neck off - and then the the name to get
the full draft name so it's actually a
hierarchy of drafts the the top 3 each
are just defining a single grouping and
then the bottom four are each defining
to definitely two groupings for the one
for the client and one another for the
server and in some cases a third
grouping representing a common a common
grouping or certain amount of
configuration parameters are being
shared by both the clients and the
server's again this is what we had in
the one or two time frame the note on
the right hand side is just mentioning
that in case you're not aware the Netcom
protocol is has a mandatory binding to
ssh and then then there's optional
protocol binding to TLS and the rest
cough protocol has a mandatory binding
to http which of course is HTTP on top a
TLS so well you don't see the dependency
arrows quite well quite right that's
what they're trying to illustrate there
next slide please
the yang models at that time defined
knobs within the SSH in TLS groupings
for keeping lives of course if you're
having I mean we within those protocols
there's actually there were the standard
protocols is the client initiate that
there's would be that the controller
application initiate the connection to
the device but with RFC 80-71
we introduced this notion of a call home
which what really happens is the devices
initiating the underlying TCP connection
to the controller application and then
immediately the protocols flip and so
while the controller application begins
as the TCP server for instance it then
presumed or resumes acting like the SSH
clients or the TLS client on top of that
accepted file descriptor socket this is
critically important because sometimes
the devices are being deployed behind
maps and network address translation
type firewalls that it makes it
impossible for an external system to
initiate a management connection to the
device so for the device to initiate the
connection becomes critical and but
similarly it's necessary in some cases
for the device to be able to ensure that
the connection remains up that is
persistent connection and hence actively
testing the aliveness of its protocol
appear becomes important and we felt
that we could use the keepalive
mechanisms as they're defined already in
SSH and TLS to do that for us
however broadband and broadband forum
and Nokia were implementing this and
they discovered that TLS keepalive are
not very well supported in the open SSL
library that they were using even though
there's an RFC for defining TLS keep
alive open SSL has not implemented it in
fact they they partially implemented it
and then decided to remove that partial
implementation so it may not get back
into open SSL anytime
and nonetheless Nokia and broadband
forum were you know asking if we could
then enable keepalive set the TCP layer
which seemed reasonable there is
actually a discussion with a TSV area
and you know Spencer Dawkins and others
participate in that conversation we we
came to the conclusion that supporting
keepa lives on every layer of a protocol
stack is critically important and and
hence there's no reason to not enable
the ability to configure keep a lives
also at the TCP layer but then the
question was how to do it and next slide
please so in the 103 time frame we
started to discuss how we might be able
to create additional protocol you know
groupings yang groupings for these other
layers again this graph is not the
pictures not lending up nicely but
essentially a TCP client-server draft
that would define groupings for TCP and
likewise HTTP and HTTPS the idea here
being is that then each layer having its
own grouping can define the
configuration for the keeper lives at
its a layer and this actually is quite
good because every protocol has slightly
different ways of configuring against
keep lives and so enabling the
configuration Beco or the definition of
the configuration to be co-located with
each protocol layer was right way to go
next slide please
that particular slide the previous one
you don't don't go to it but it while I
didn't say it at the time it was kind of
representing and is a relationship so
for instance if you instantiated in the
instance or the HTTP grouping it would
in turn instantiate an instance of both
of TLS and HTTP groupings and then in
turn they would instantiate an instance
so that TCP so Kevin is our relationship
to use an object-oriented comparison but
we found that actually there has a
relationship was better so in again that
slides not
quite right but you're on the bottom
there are sort of flat lists of the
various protocols that can be then be
composed to represent the various
protocol stacks so for instance you
could have TCP over HTTP by just
grabbing the groupings from those two
drafts or alternatively you can have TCP
over TLS over HTTP just by inserting
also the grouping from the TLS draft in
between the other two so the composition
becomes quite nice so that's the current
that's currently what's been published
in the 104 time frame next slide please
and just took a little bit in detail of
what what the current draft defines it
is defining three gang modules there's a
common yang module and in that yang
module is defining two groupings there's
a common grouping and then there's the
what's called connection grouping so
it's the connection grouping that's
being used by the other groupings the
purpose of this factoring out of the
common grouping is so that in case maybe
someday in the future
TCP M would like to define a system
grouping that would represent for
instance the TCP configuration of the
operating system itself and so we have
this common grouping that right now the
only thing is defining or keeper lives
there's the connection grouping and it's
only thing it's doing is using that
common grouping if there's no additional
configuration beyond that then there's a
second module for TCP client and you can
see that it's it's well actually it's
not easy to see on the slide I'm sorry
about that but it's a it's defining
essentially what is the remote port
address and sorry a remote address and a
remote port as well as optionally a
local address and a local port and then
it's using the TCP connection grouping
so that's where it inherits keep your
lives and then there's a server but the
slide is messed it up pretty badly so I
won't try to speak through it but a very
similar idea worse where it's inheriting
some of the configuration from the
common grouping hopefully the next slide
works please next slide
ah it's not that much better so it's
supposed to be shown here is the
flattening of all those useless
statements from the previous slide into
the tree diagrams and I think we might
be able to see the top one there's the
the client grouping and you see the
remote address the remote port local
address the local port and then you can
kind of see the keeper lives but it gets
pretty terrible
unfortunately I that's very difficult to
see I really apologize for that the
what's important here those in its
difficulties is to see in blue
hopefully it's showing blue for you the
local bindings supported that's question
mark so that's a feature it's basically
saying you know does this device support
the notion of allowing the local address
the local port to be configured at all
or is it you know for the client for
instance or is it always a hopper system
that can wild card you know randomly
select what the local address and local
port should be based on routing
parameters or wildcards also and I know
you can't see it but in the keeper lives
there's the idle time and probe interval
both of these are currently you at 16s
and the resolution of those are seconds
so I thought actually Michael thought
that this would be interesting for the
working group to discuss if that
resolution was correct and accurate as
opposed to say 70 seconds or
milliseconds currently we're thinking
seconds is reasonable for the purpose of
keeping lives for TCP clients and server
connections next slide please
also not showing very well in the screen
okay so this here's an example and XML
is being shown but with anything that
you do with Yang you can also
simultaneously support JSON and in fact
there's another working group Cosi that
implements Seaborg which is a binary
representation of instance data that
conforms to the gang data bottles
but in this example at the very top at
least we can get through some of it
there's a remote address and notice here
it's actually using a host name so on
the previous slide was every question I
thought I heard some feedback on the
earlier slide it defined this remote
address type as what's known as an eye
net host which then allows for values as
either either being domain names or IP
addresses whether or their ipv4 or ipv6
so in this example of showing that it's
actually a hostname whereas and you
can't see it very well but down below in
the server it the local dress is the IP
address 10.20 30 to 40 and that
particular type is actually a specific
IP address is defined as an IP address
so there's no availability for it to be
configured as a as a domain host name
there also in this particular example
you can see at least the top the local
address 0 0 0 0 that's how it couldn't
defined in a specification for
designating wild card address and
likewise the port is just 0 for
designating wild card address next slide
please
so this is an eye chart we won't try to
go into but the wasn't trying to be
impressed upon you is that at the very
top in the middle is the TCP common
grouping and then off to the left is the
tcp client and off to the right is tcp
server and then there's sort of a
hierarchy of SSH and TLS and HTTP
modules sorry groupings that are that
are dependent on them also and then you
know mostly this is feeding into the SSH
sorry the net confer rest off drafts I
mentioned earlier but there's also a
syslog draft there's a pset draft
there's a management connectivity draft
and now I understand in the Seaboard
group they're working on they want to
add a UDP client server as well as a
DTLS client server so there's sort of
what I guess I'm trying to impress upon
you is that a strategy
that's been put forth in this particular
draft of having these three modules
representing a common a client and a
server that that strategy is it's part
of a framework and the framework is
rather robust and it's been shown to you
know be able to support the composition
of some fairly complex configuration
hierarchies that's the main point of
this slide next slide please
okay and this is also the last slide so
the next steps before the authors at
least and also from the net coughs
working groups perspective at least what
our primary intentions are for
supporting the configuration of net
cough clients and servers we think we're
done of course you know we'd be willing
to sort of allow the certain
functionality or the feature set to be
published as an initial RFC and would
hope that T CPM actually would take over
the you know any future updates to that
RFC using business you know business
updates as they would see fit but but
before we can you know think to do a
last call or anything like this we want
to first verify with T CPM whether or
not the model even as simple as it is if
it's general and good enough for all the
situations and which TCP yang models
could be used and I guess that I'll
leave that question to the room or if
there's any other comments or concerns
that it'd be happy to hear them thank
you for the presentation about questions
Mathis the thing that the only thing
that bothers me about this I mean the
yang stuff is such seems to be fine but
this group spends a great deal of effort
making TCP idiot-proof in the sense that
the API doesn't expose things that
people might think they could improve
and therefore break things
and and keep allies fell into that
category you generally generally people
who want to muck with it don't
understand what they're doing and they
actually don't want to muck with it now
there are some exceptions but in places
most places many of the places where
people come up with exceptions that be
careful because the ietf is huge for
example in BGP at one point TCP live
this was used to indicate BGP liveness
and it was realized that they needed to
have a separate connectivity
instrumentation protocol and not rely on
TCP notion of liveness for B gp's
liveness and and I suspect this we've
been very careful here about that kind
of thing the knobs are you put it in the
right gear and then you remove the
handle that's very much the mentality
here and and so I have a little bit of
concern about whether or not this is
going to invite people to cause
breakages because they try to adjust
things that they shouldn't adjust can
you stay here mycotoxin from the floor
reading the description of keeper life
so you're specifying a time and after
which the TCP connection gets dropped if
there is no response from the pier its
idle time time 60 I don't know whether
60 comes from the very put in is in
seconds the outcome is in seconds though
I don't know and the other one is isn't
the it does they keep a lifetime or if
you have no response it's their
exponential back-off and if it there is
then this formula is wrong because it
does assume that you don't explain
back of the timer another bad
the keeper life is back often in other
timers but not keep alive but my
impression is that it was designed not
to along I'm getting ours boys this is a
long time ago this 20 years ago that
this was worked on very hard the the
design of the keep alive is not to
determine if the network is is healthy
it's to make sure that connections which
are completely passive where the other
end goes away eventually get reaped it
was solving that problem not determining
whether or not the network is healthy
and so sailors turn on keep alive to
make sure that if the client just
evaporates and the server has no pending
data the server eventually dies it's
it's not the usual liveness question
that people think about okay so just to
respond to a couple of comments I've
just made
I didn't go over cuz the picture was
rather garbled on the screen but there's
also a feature statement for whether or
not the server supports keeping lives at
all which on a client or server basis
key enable are disabled so on a per
implementation basis if they don't want
to support those configuration knobs
they can completely disable them and
they won't be available for users to
configure secondly there's the ability
you can keep alive as doesn't defined as
what's called a presence container which
means if you just put keep you eyes but
don't configure any of those three knobs
underneath then the default values kick
in
so there's hopefully same default values
and again people wouldn't muck with them
and get themselves in trouble lastly
that description statement times 60 it
maybe I need to revisit that and it
could be wrong especially in the light
of exponential back-off finest statement
yeah miracle even just to answer a
couple of things so people life is
actually something that comes up very
often in people can do wrong because you
can configure instead of the 60 second
you can configure I want to keep a life
one minute once per millisecond right
and that breaks your network so it's
really something that you should be
careful about there is an exponential
back-off that's when like you
or keepalive fails you don't get a reply
then you exponential back-off but if
it's running everything is fine you just
can overload the network easily so but
I'm glad that you said that there are
defaults and that you can take idea and
disable it and probably also put a big
warning in it don't do anything stupid
here right so just be careful okay thank
you thank you next presentation is
Michael you get ten minutes hi my name
is Michael speaking here is individual
and that is a follow-up presentation
also talking about yang so next slide so
actually it would have been good to have
the presentation that you have just seen
in the last IDF meeting because this
would have simplified a lot and there
was a little bit my mistake that this
happened didn't happen so but in general
we see that there is this trend in
certain other working groups that people
feel a need to configure certain
parameters in yang most notably the
things that you can configure by a
socket
options and the keeper lives are
actually one such example there are
other ones as a example there is at
least one yang modular out there that
configures the MSS which is also
something that some snakes exposed for
example by a socket option so you see
TCP parameters in in yang modules
increasingly and that somehow raises the
question to us as TCP and working groups
or what do we do with that and is there
a bigger problem to work resolved and I
explicitly raised this as an open
question because I believe that we
should discuss this I have not fully
came to an conclusion but in general if
we look at the TCP stack we do not only
have the parameters that are exposed by
a socket option but obviously we also
have configuration parameters and
typically that this is it is subdivided
into a global configuration of the
stacks such as whether you enable for
example is yen or SEC and in many states
you also have interface specific commit
for example something about the MSS or
maybe relate to the MTU or other of
loading related parameters so there's a
bunch of parameters out there and this
raises the question so is there
something to be done in this working
group so next in the last meeting I
promised to come up with a survey if
something is doable because there was
clearly a question in the last meeting
whether there this is something that is
actually doable and what I've done in
the most recent version of the draft I
have looked at a couple of stacks of the
four different ones in order to identify
if there's any commonality in in the
configuration between particular beyond
things that can be configured by a
socket API and produced CEO on the slide
is a summary of what I came up this so
I've looked at four different stacks and
not all of them are configured by yang
so I've also looked at some host
operating systems and I've tried to
identify a couple of configuration
parameters that are common and you can
see there are a couple of them as a for
example that's not a big surprise
stacks that support for example the
section typically have boolean or
similar to a boolean parameter to turn
that on and off and the same applies to
other standard optional TSP
functionalities such as timestamps for
example path MTU discovery Zn and there
couple of other other parameters so you
see that there is some comment and the
commonality in what you can turn on and
off for example of course the exact way
how you do that so for example that it's
a boolean parameter or whether it's an
enumeration so that depends a little bit
on the system but there is at least four
very basic functionality there is a
similarity between stacks at least for
these very basic things and that
obviously could bring us to a young
modeling folder for that so we could at
least for such simple things we could
decide to propose a young model that
includes those
parameters such as sex so I've shown
here one such example so we could be
fine for example a boolean parameter in
yang for enabling or disabling and SEC
and then there would be an standard way
in Yang and for having that
configuration the benefit of doing this
would be that this could be used in
various other yang modules as opposed
for devices or for example also and
other protocol environments as a test
would be for example one such profile
but this could be useful
it could reference those standard
definitions if they feel that there is a
need to to deal with such TCP
configuration and parameters and the
proposal here would be just to define
the grouping similar to what you have
seen just in the previous talk so we
would not define a full data model here
we would only define groupings for
certain parameters and because this
allows to reuse defensing in a lot of
different use cases I've looked at other
parameters there beyond what I've shown
in the previous table the other ones
that are often available in sticks but
the exact way how its configured starts
to them depend on the different sticks
so you can see examples like the delay
back time or the initial Archie own or
some very basic parameters of the
retransmission engine are often
configurable in in many stacks but the
details start to be different so and if
you look at the ended in individual a
how to configure that each stack has
found a different way to configure that
of course as in those cases we could
come up this one reasonable way to model
it but the risk that this does not have
a one-to-one mapping to the specific
configuration of a stack gets higher and
then of course there are huge areas of a
TCP stack that are very specific to the
implementation examples of wakes and
everything that deals this puffers
always flow controls that a lot of
heuristics out there and that are
typically very specific to the stake
also for example debate how congestion
control algorithms are implemented
obviously very specific to this text and
it's very hard to come up as a common
set of parameters so at the moment I
don't try to enter that space because
yes you huge risk to boil the ocean and
going there and as I said this what I've
shown on the slide is what I promised to
do in the last meeting here I was gonna
make a comment on your last slide about
the fact that horse takes over all right
what we did in I'll see gosh I forgot
the number the the tcp extended
information mid is the introduction
specifically says that if you have
precise knowledge about how the
implementation works you can understand
precisely how the variables are defined
but the variables are defined in ways
they're sort of generic if you don't
understand the details of how the stack
works you can only just make sort of
generic assumptions about them and that
the standard for the instrumentation was
not to preclude specifically not to
preclude evolving heuristics and so
there's always example language of that
which you're welcome to steal yeah yeah
sure of course I mean that is quite
related work I've looked at the document
I've not really I'm not
reusing the heuristics because this
would be operational nature and I'm not
fully irradiated okay anyway as I said
what I've done here is what I promised
last meeting so as I've basically
completely rewritten the document I've
also added a new cause so I'm looking
for co-authors who have a background in
that space and we shall belong here to
help me this that if you look at the
model right now you will see it's not an
actual yang module
it only has text right now but one of
the potential next steps would be to
formalize what I just said to come up
with actual yang cooping definitions
along the lines
just presented so that would be the
naturalistic next step if people here in
this room believe that this is something
that's valuable and as I said I mean the
key question that I have is specifically
also to implement us in the room if they
feel value in further working in that
space along the lines of that what I've
said or if the general feeling in the
room is that this is probably something
that gets too complicated as in the last
meeting there was a very mixed feedback
on that and that's why I'd like to open
the floor to this question again so
pleased if we could comment if you find
this useful or please also feel free to
comment if you think that this will not
go anywhere
so that would be excellent to see it not
and that's the last statement that I
want to say feel free to comment so
intended status is informational well at
the moment they're not struck because
young models typically our standards
track I've said last meeting of course T
CPM has pretty high bars for standard
strike that is definitely a fun thing to
think about a few standard strike
because that would be the default in the
rest of the idea for your modules but
yes of course I mean standard striking
TCB and has a certain implication and
that is definitely something we would
have to think about Michael Jackson my
critics and I can't comment on the
usefulness of it but yeah I think what
would be useful is to include the to
make the congestion control module
selectable anything on loss recovery
Lots recovery wreck the issue with that
is then we would probably have to have
for something like a list of congestion
control algorithms or like that and
other coming up with a standard
specification for that is something that
would definitely require some thinking
but I mean I can give it a try at least
make it selectable
even if people can use platform-specific
various
Mahesh eternal Donny two comments one to
the point of usefulness absolutely if
you don't do it as you've seen other
models I want to define the parameters
they need and then you'll be left with a
scattered list of parameters that other
models are other authors are going to
find difficult to locate to the other
question of standards track absolutely
if you're going to include yang module
even if it's just groupings and no
containers you absolutely it has to be a
standards document thanks okay thank you
okay thanks for presentation chorus next
and I'm going first I'm going to be
talking about a draft what jeers draft
fare has t sv w g CC and y TS v WG
because it's supposed to refer to all
transport protocols why here because T
CPM has clue about how to design
congestion control which is what CC
means so um let me tell you a little bit
next slide so this is not of you and you
probably noticed the IETF has said quite
a bit about can just control over the
years so it's clear if you want to
design something that just congestion
control or maybe doesn't which document
to look up isn't it no well I spoke to
John at the quick interim and we thought
yes the answer to this must be true
there must be a couple of documents we
could just point to and we can just
write quickly a four-page summary of
these are the key principles not the
details but the key things you must do
if you design a congestion control and
then we could write this document it was
so short that maybe mean we don't have
to publish it we can just include it
various places and say play well and do
this um they took more than four pages
when I tried one more time so I've done
some work and that's what's in this
particular internet draft and the draft
revision started with zero zero I just
kind of consumed RFC's I I thought that
each RFC would be about one thing and
then I discovered that many RFC's talked
about something for a few paragraphs and
then another RFC talked at the same
thing for a few paragraphs using
different language but I looked at 26
and there's probably a few more and then
I got fed up because it's a lot of time
and then I went back to it I thought
maybe there's something useful here so I
wrote 0 1 which was the same text made
more coherent by getting other people to
read it and also find me leaving it for
a while
I think way shorter so I thought oh yeah
we're onto something good here and then
I thought actually I resent this at the
ITF which is where we are now and
there's still a few annoying typos
I have roles in my xml version I'd be
happy to fix those if people think this
is useful so what is it so um
section three of the document is the
first bit where there's important stuff
it talks about the principles of
congestion control if you're being in
the ITF for a while you remember there's
a BCP written by this on this by Sally
about 20 years ago and that probably
isn't the best document to tell somebody
how to run the internet but it might be
so let's try and write down some
principles I picked three major
principles there's a diversity of path
characteristics out there so be aware of
that when you design something there's
something where flaws are multiplexed
and congestion happens and that's
important to know about and it's
important to avoid congestion collapse
which is where Sally's main point this
is the real thing that uh Turley has to
be avoided and the second one is a
little bit about understanding but
starving or the floors out about how
your portion the bandwidth between them
but there are things in there we have to
read this of course if you're interested
section 4 then provides some guidelines
on performing congestion control so this
is extracts from the musts and shuts of
various RFC's and it talks about
connectionless initialization what means
to have a retransmit timer what an
initial window might mean which is a bit
difficult to define actually so maybe is
worth trying about using path capacity
but bursts which we tried to ignore for
a while but we probably shouldn't be
ignoring in the internet but we don't
want to be too prescriptive but we do
need to say a little bit but timers and
retransmission responding to potential
congestion which we could call an
incipient congestion which might
indicate it's not the same as persistent
congestion why we need to use saw start
to get more capacity or what that might
mean about network signals entrusting
them and about protecting mechanisms
what it needs to be on path and off path
which I noticed this ITF people started
using different words for so and might
be nice to have some definitions for
these well ok
my basic thing when I'm standing here is
how I done it and should I just and file
that and walk away from it or does
anybody else read this would they like
to read it do people care enough that we
should actually update this and write
this as a proper document I'm happy to
go through everything we have at the
moment as input and work with other
people to make this into a real guidance
document do people care who would help
me or I can happily write other things
so this is Richard so I think it's not a
very quick presentation and I think it's
great it would be great to have a
document that is written in modern style
to point people to who have not been
exposed to all the things and that is
going on in real well that works I guess
thank you so this is Michael from the
floor a threat to document on I do care
okay thank you we are drones is an
individual I wish I would have read this
document before I got here because I'm
gonna have to read it tonight
so thank you for making this document
and I would like to see it carried
forward if you're looking for the wisdom
in it and it may be in another version
there's still quite a few loops and
things in this one but thank you thanks
for writing and then one question is you
didn't mention fairness in this draft
and then you might be tricky things but
I'd like to understand who this is
intentional or not intentional
I mentioned multiplexing and the idea
that you have to multiplex and the idea
you had not to starve I'd mentioned that
roaches can do things to help you
achieve these goals i if i didn't
mention furnace it was because I didn't
find RFC keywords mixed in with the
furnace that I thought had to be in here
but that is the sort of thing which we
should talk about because I'm it's
important to say something probably we
should say something about fairness even
if it says something that isn't a must
or should do it
but Briscoe I'd support this as a
checklist no I probably wouldn't support
it as trying to tell people the wisdom
that you just mentioned the congestion
control designers have got because
that's just going to be going on forever
you know it isn't and also different
people have different opinions on that
and you know it will just become a churn
of nothingness yeah okay so now we're
getting there especially no the
gentleman's joined at the back of the
queue and this all started in London
with a with the quick intern and I'm
trying to think about how strong can
quick actually say you do any congestion
control that you like providing it's
reasonable and then what the heck is
reasonable so I don't want to Bible
about how to design congestion controls
but I would like to have some kind of
reasonableness certainly useful I think
it's very valuable to have like one
document that has links to all the
necessary principles as well as links to
other documents that describe control so
I am very supportive of this happy to
review it and help make progress you're
hoping to make progress thank you yes I
also second the idea it's a very good
idea it's not exhaustive yes and I would
suggest using the words capacity our
location and not wood furnace has got
too much I just maybe if fenneis didn't
actually appears a word anywhere maybe
that was not unintentional I have a one
of my favorite papers I accidentally
used the word fairness you know King
will read it later so it's just so wet
okay I believe in fairness I don't
believe in equality oh yeah
like let's not go that rather go cheats
reminder it's all Matt's fault so I I I
feel partly responsible for this but
only partly gory you did the work but
thank you so much for doing the work and
I am very high I am happy to see this
work happened I'm happy to review and
more than to be I'm happy to help by
contributing text and by helping shape
the I I agree that I maybe I didn't
understand Bob correctly but I actually
don't want a checklist in the sense that
checklists are going to be in exhaustive
they're not gonna be exhaustive and
that's they're failing in some ways it's
like it's never going to be exhaustive
so what's the point of having a
checklist if I wanna have considerations
that's useful to me in this sort of a
document maybe this could lead to test
Suites and other things that actually
implement checklists no not that I
we've done this before I definitely
don't want to instigate that work here
again but but beyond that I think it's
it's super useful as a way to think
about what is reasonable I think that's
a conversation we've not really had
we've had conversations about perfectly
fair but not what's reasonable so I
think I wanted to try and translate his
comments because because I think I agree
with it the problem with the word
checklist is it implies that there's an
algorithmic binary decision and that's
the that's not correct and in a better
world as considerations yes thank you so
I think you got your feedback that this
is a useful document and I would suggest
get the dog to get the discussion to the
meeting this because we are limited time
so anyone you need something can I ask
which mailing list because I joined that
group you'd shared this group I got I
can we please not do this on to mailing
list this is this is killing my brain
having multiple mailing list and a chair
yeah I don't do it
you want to do an ICC RG discuss the
standards implications of datum so I
mean I again honestly it is there
anything standard sweaty here yeah it's
all the shoulds and musts at tri-c from
all the standards in which standards
wage let me ask a different question
what can we sort this out nodes we swap
us out after we meet with us and I'll
get you so we have a last presentation
[Music]
anyone who has not signed the blue
sheets now is the opportunity my name is
Carlos Gomez I'm from UPC and I'm going
to present this new draft entitled TCP
at poor micro farad is Jonker craft from
the University of Cambridge so first of
all let's go through the motivation for
this new document it is well known that
the latex allow reducing packet overhead
and some conditions however it's also
true that the latex may be detrimental
to performance in some scenarios so
let's assume segment that carries a
message of up to one image as if the
message does not elicit an application
layer response and the second data
segment is is not transferred earlier
than the delay ACK timeout then the ACK
for the segment will be unnecessarily
delayed and gives me until a number of
negative consequences so for example if
the sender uses the Nagle algorithm the
sender may be prevented from sending
more data while awaiting the ACK and
this may lead to high in the performance
in in high bitrate environments as
reported for example in the DNS stateful
operations RFC and the reason here is
that in high bit rate environments the
RTT might be below one millisecond
whereas the delay that timeout is
typically 200 milliseconds then in
another domain which is the Internet of
Things or IOT devices or many
typically exhibit significant resource
constraints in terms of energy memory
and other resources and a device and IOT
device that sends a segment needs to
keep the segment in a buffer until via
Karev's
however the memory resources cannot be
released until the react which is
delayed arrives and due to this delay
there might be problems if there's not
much memory available which might even
lead to packet drops if subsequent
packets need to be sent meanwhile also
IOT devices run typically on simple
energy limited sources such as simple
batteries and depending on the technique
used by the device for energy
conservation for example if the device
uses a radio interface the device might
stay with the read interface on awaken
consuming energy while awaiting the arc
which is delayed so the delay
contributes to increasing the energy
consumption and decreasing the lifetime
of the device in addition the delay
might interact negatively with layer 2
mechanisms in some IOT technologies
whether some specific opportunities for
transmission and reception of packets
and if due to the delay some opportunity
is lost it means that the next
opportunity will only arrive after some
longer delay which then in turn
exacerbates the previous two issues so
we might want to consider solutions and
we might think ok can we for example try
to disable delay tags at the receiver if
at all possible and the answer is that
perhaps no that's probably not a good
solution because the receiver may
interact with a variety of devices and
the attacks may still work as intended
in many connections and even considering
a specific sender perhaps the sender may
offer a mixed traffic pattern where the
attacks may work as intended for some
part of that traffic so a conclusion is
that a solution to this problem should
be at the segment granularity so what we
are proposing in this document is
what we call the AK pull mechanism and
it would make use of one of the TCP
heavy Reserve beads which is defining
the document as the active flag this
would be more specifically the sixth
date of the 13th bite of the TCP header
and the mechanism would be as follows
the sender if the sender wants to
request an immediate AK for DT segment
then it sets the at poles like and on
the receiver side upon reception of a
data segment with the approach lock set
and the receiver if it conforms to this
specification it must send the ACK
immediately there's a question okay then
after the internet graph submission
deadline there was some nice discussion
on the mailing list
there was good feedback many good
comments that were sent on the list I
would like to thank everyone for that
and I've tried to summarize the feedback
on this slide so one point is that of
course one of the TCP header reserve
bids is an expensive resource and we are
well aware of it so that means that we
need to carefully assess the pros and
cons of this proposal or some perhaps
some alternatives then also the use of
the maximum AG delay option was
suggested however with that option we
understand there might be two issues one
is that it's a an option that would not
be a solution offering sorry a solution
at the second granularity and on the
other hand this option entails another
head of 28 bits which might be not so
good in some scenarios such as IOT then
there was another comment or suggestion
like perhaps we might redefine the push
flag as having the octal semantics this
could be phrased as a tcp me not delay
acts for data segments with the push
flag which in principle would be allowed
by RFC 1122 then there were some reports
about how is actually the bush flag
being used in the Windows and Linux
implementations
they said the push record the message
boundary and
at the receiver side neither windows nor
nor Linux sandy acts immediately upon
receiving semijns with the bushwhack set
so it means that in these
implementations that push flag is not
being used as having the opossum antics
then there was some concern raised that
there are application such as RPC or web
that use many small packets with the
push flag set that do benefit from delay
tags because then it's possible to
piggyback action replies and in those
cases if we really find the push like us
having the ad pull semantics then this
benefit would be lost
therefore perhaps having a separate
attack pool flag would allow having both
things with the law using the latex in
those cases where it's useful and also
separately supporting the ability of
requesting immediate act when needed and
finally there was another point made
that selfish devices might want to
always use this mechanism therefore we
might need some clear rules or
recommendations on when this should be
used or would be allowed finally there's
a security consideration at least one to
be done here which is that there's a
possible do s attack as a result of this
at pull mechanism especially on resource
constrained receiver goodbye an attacker
may send a large number of messages to
the victim note requesting an immediate
attack for each in order to contribute
to depleting resources from the device
for example energy resources one
approach to avoid this attack would be
just ignoring the April flag so other
well comments questions yes so when I
read this draft it was not quite clear
to me what the exact about the exact
exact problem space was that you want to
address
so you mentioned IOT and the other the
other aspect that I was missing was next
we do have a couple of mechanisms like
for example tea sack and TLP which could
be exploited to exactly this this point
unilaterally
you
don't need any change on the on the
server side to extract this information
more quickly if you actually need the
low latency so I'm wondering why those
aspects have not been in in in this
draft and why they were deemed
unsuitable okay thank you I will
definitely look at the mechanism
suggested and regarding the problem
space actually there's there seems to be
a problem in different domains and there
are two examples I mentioned one is the
IOT another one is height high bitrate
environments
perhaps there are some other scenarios
so this is perhaps some general problem
I was exactly gonna say that I think
this is more general problem as we
haven't got much time I'll leave it
there but support worker in this face
but things like act right control from
the sender as well is it could could be
folded into some noise so maybe we need
to start working on requirements for
this before we really close to cool and
be the cue after last but very brief
statements only we are running out of
time
yes in a second this the really tough
part of it is in addition to sort of
having a better requirements statement
is actually getting data there's a
parallel problems in both SCTP and quick
and partials partial solutions it turns
out one of the things that one of the
lessons from quick is that this actually
matters a lot in certain parts of the
internet and for certain applications
having that data rather than speculating
about why why it's important will change
this conversation I have this it bugged
me for 20 years and finally doing
something about it would be great I
think we won't know how much it hurts us
thank you
Michael took some from the floor I'm not
that much concerned about the security
issue you raised because as an attacker
I can also always send you to placate
data and I get sex for each one giving
you a
how you can elicit an a community just
read well duplicate Li transmitted and
out by it again it costs you one bite
more and you get an AK okay going fast I
think we did something similar with SCTP
in the I bet and before we charted that
we did lots of analysis and why might be
useful because we put back pressure so
some of that analysis has already been
done for SAT P thank you just really
quickly I support agree with what Bob
said I don't think the mechanism here is
necessarily the one that we want to use
but I think it's worthwhile doing the
requirements discussion thank you just
point that the attack time odds are
reduced now in existence it's no longer
200 milliseconds it's down to like 40 or
50 so the impact of a delay direct
remote is less now compared to before
the second was yeah so if if the receipt
wants to indicate the hinge to the
sender that there is no subsequent
package sent right so in that case could
make you as a hint rather than a forcing
mechanism we thank you thank you for the
feedback thank you
this is then F questions no okay
that thank you all this closes TCP M in
montréal
[Music]