hi welcome to the t's working group at
IDF 105 I'm Luke Berger Kevon theorem
next to me and we are lucky enough to
have actually have Matt Hartley in the
room he's off at remote he really does
exist
we always appreciate his help whether
remote or local it's great to have him
here
our agenda has been posted there really
hasn't been any significant change
that's been posted we are doing etherpad
as usual I asked everyone to jump on and
help us capture comments that are made
at the mic you don't need to capture
everything that's spoken during they
hate the slides that's captured in the
slides and the videos and it's really
the discussion that's important to
capture in the notes we are at the IETF
you didn't notice which means we have
our note well we have rules that govern
our participation and our contribution
to the IETF if you're not familiar with
it please take a look at that URL on the
bottom but basically everything you say
here or at any meeting at the IETF it
becomes part of our record we're
streaming we're recording please say
your names as you come to the microphone
that's helpful for those who are remote
as well as for when you go back to take
make sure we have accurate minutes I am
on Jabbar and if anyone else wants to
jump on Jabbar that's great but
sometimes I don't always come on it
always able to monitor so well that's
chair but if anyone has a comment remote
we welcome that whether you come in
through me echo or through jabber
so moving on to where we are on
documents we have no new RFC's and we
just had one RFC that moved into the RFC
editor queue on yesterday
that's the to each apology that is a was
a very major piece of work it's
important piece of work and we're really
happy to see that progressing we have
some other documents that are being that
are going through the normal is cheap
processing and so it's always but again
to see the work of the working group
heading towards publication of course
that's why we're here we have a couple
of newly adopted documents I believe
they are both on the agenda okay we'll
go through in a moment any document
that's not on the agenda we have two
sessions today the first ones one year
and now so good you found us that's
excellent
the session information changes between
the sessions in particular the audio
stream will change there everything else
stays the same including thankfully the
room
we do have a beverage break for 20
minutes between 3 and 3:20 we do intend
to take that break it is our hope that
we can run through our agenda faster
than what we have listed but we also do
have this extra long time the ex is
actually more time than we requested so
we'll take advantage of it we don't have
to leave early but if we leave early
that's also okay our agenda is pretty
tight particularly the first session
this is loaded with documents that are
have been accepted by the working group
as well as the designs in activity that
we talked about I believe that the last
meeting or talked about last couple of
meetings our second session we'll move
on to non adopted work and particular we
have a little bit of a section on
slicing and 5-g related activities that
I'm sure lots of folks will be
interested in and that's that lay a hot
topic we've had no liaisons or
communication since the last meeting I
just realized I meant to go and check
Arata I'm not sure if we had any errata
that came in but we should mention that
that's my bad
Pavan says we didn't have any so that's
didn't miss anything here that's good as
usual just a reminder we have a formal
IPR process that we've adopted in the
working group that says we will hold a
working group
whenever we adopt a document and again
before we submit for publications but
the IceCube location will pull the
working group to for disclosures of IPR
we do encourage everyone to use the
mailing list it's a great place for
discussion it's a great place to make
sure that your colleagues are in sync
with the activity that the progress
you've been making on a draft and it's a
great way to report those private
conversations that happen inevitably
happen between authors and that's it for
the first so much for the idea of
reloading loading everything up to start
we look at the status of working group
documents now this is the set of
documents working group documents that
are not in the agenda today so we'll
walk through the status of each of these
in the next few slides first up is the
AC TN yang document no changes since the
last ITF in previous meetings we agreed
that we would wait for the generate key
models to progress to the publication
stage and then revisit this we are not
there yet so in the meantime if we can
get in a few more reviews that would be
very useful
next is the enhanced VPN document there
was a revision published for this early
this month there was a section added for
covering inter domain and inter layer
network scenarios the authors intend to
add more details and operational
considerations we do have some work
relevant to this coming up in the second
session so this topic would get
revisited again
next is the PC native IP document there
was a revision published for this in
April this carried primarily some a
tutorial changes the authors may make a
few changes to the document based on how
the scenarios document progresses
through the publication stage there is
there was an open question on if and
when the status of this needs to be
changed so we would let it stay as is
for now and revisited at a later point
in time
next is the PC CC use cases document
there was a revision published for this
in July there was some text added to
state that this is a living document to
catalog the various use case of PC CC
and that there is currently no intent
from the authors to publish this as an
RSC this point of debate would be
revisited at a later point in time when
I guess we run out of more any more use
cases to add the if the last revision
date contain
a new section for beer the PCE CC use
case for beer and the author's do intend
to add cover the multicast SR policy use
case as well in upcoming provisions this
is the RSVP RM our extensions draft
there was a section added in the new
revision covering Express links at this
point they are requesting the authors
are requesting further review and
feedback from the working group so
please do give it a read and reach out
to the authors on the list if you have
any questions or concerns with approach
being taken next is the SF aware
topology model there haven't been any
changes to this since the last ITF but
the authors do feel that it it's mature
enough to warrant a young doctor to take
a look at it so we'll make sure that
happens next is the long-standing key
metric recording craft at this stage
last year we were on the verge of
killing this but the authors of
miraculously turned this around they did
publish a revision yesterday and asked
for the authors there are no more open
issues and they are ready to take it to
the last call I did skim through the
document then seems like all the
outstanding comments have been addressed
I would request the working group to do
the same and reach out to the authors if
there are still any concerns we do
intend to take it to the list pretty
soon next is the tea service mapping
document again only no changes since the
last time but there are a few
outstanding items from early this year
that need to get a dust the authors have
promised that this would be taken care
of in that coming revisions next is the
tutorial document that we have for using
the tea topology and towel modeling
tunnel models this again falls under
sort of a living document bucket there
is currently no urgency to take it to
the next stage the authors do have I
have identified they have identified a
few
or scenarios to cover so please do
review them as they come and reach out
to the others if there are any
particular scenarios that aren't
currently available in the document the
last document in this deck is the path
computation data model there they were a
few this seems to be an outdated slight
but yeah there were some comments that
were received on the list from I believe
Olivia and Julian they were a couple of
use cases that are added but those did
not translate into any young model
changes the authors do have a few open
issues on the gate that need to get
taken care of and they do believe that
this would be ready for a young dog
distributive or the next idea that's all
we have in this deck let's move on to
our first present of other day that
would be correct
just say good afternoon the working
group my name is tarick
and I'll walk you over a quick update
over the working group documents on the
first slide so I'll go over the updates
from the last time we met I'll present
some open issues and finally we'll talk
about the next steps X piece so the
first document is the yang - te which
covers the tunnels LSPs constructs and
attributes that model on the device as
well as on off the device or a
controller next please
so the first open issue the this this
model or this document went through a
round of yang doctor's review and we got
recently comments the author's will be
going ahead and the first feedback we
got this is on the right track and and
we will be addressing the cons that we
got next these the second open issue is
a discussion that happened on the
mailing list and with regards to a
tunnel name collision tunnels can be
configured on the device they could be
configured on the controller they could
be learned or State on the controller or
learnt or State on the device itself and
we have we have an issue where the name
of a tunnel that is learned can collide
with a tunnel that's configured either
on the device or the controller and we
have a proposal that we discussed on the
list as I mentioned and we'll go over it
on the next slide please so as I was
mentioning the name collision can happen
on the controller if the controller
learns of
from different devices with the same
name what we had suggested is for
learned tunnels or four state tunnels
from devices we will append the ingress
ID to the name so that it's unique so an
example is a tunnel r1 - foo will be
distinguishable from r2 - foo where r1
and r2 are the ingress routers the
second case an operator can configure a
tunnel name matching and automatically
create a tunnel on the device with the
same name we have to have them
distinguishable so we are proposing a
configured prefix the prefix can take
for example Auto as value or string and
then we can distinguish for example a
tunnel auto - bypass link one from a
tunnel bypass - link 1 which is
configured so the one on auto - is
auto-created and the bypass - link 1 is
configured by the operator so this is
this is one way we could distinguish it
in the in this case the third case is a
controller has a configured tunnel with
a name and then it learns a tunnel with
the same name and what we're suggesting
is we have penned the prefix the same
prefix we are introducing can be
configured with a different value on the
controller for example remote so in this
example on the bottom I show in remote -
r1 foo remote - r2 foo will be the
distinguished from r2 - foo for example
which is configured on the controller so
the gist of the proposal is that we have
a prefix and we prepend the name with it
so it becomes distinguishable next
please
the next draft is the RSVP model draft
we have two modules in it the model
covers the attributes of the RSVP
protocol and signaling parameters per
session per neighbor and per interface
next please so for this draft it went
through a round of doctor's review
comments and we got the feedback and
addressed it so we had some knits to
address added nets we had state
containers which was in conflict with
nmda and we removed that we had to
expand some names of Leafs some
pluralization of nouns there as well
we added some normative references for
imported mod modules next the second
update the four four sessions of RSVP we
had a single list and we were putting in
this list two types of sessions IP RSVP
sessions and rsvp-te sessions the key of
these two sessions as defined into RFC
2205 and 3209 they're different P so one
suggestion was for the ease of lookup of
a section a session to use the actual
real key native key that rather than
having a index that we needed to a walk
to match on the specific session so we
the proposal what we've done is we split
into two lists one list for RSVP IP
sessions another list for our zbt
sessions and we introduced the native
keys for each type of session next did
you include support for the upset cars
PPP RSVP types the desk or the security
the IP security yeah this was - - oh I
admit doesn't ring no okay are you
hinting that we should or okay whether
whether or not this actually supports it
I think you might be okay for the
session that the center template might
cause you a problem okay
it's worth double check I will double
check thank you so we added a couple of
our pcs with our GP model specifically
to clear sessions specific session or
all of the sessions and the clear RSVP
neighbor we have a hello session
established with that neighbor and we
wanted to clear it again it's a specific
session or all of the sessions the
notifications we piggybacked on the
publish/subscribe model and we added a
section and draft to talk how we can
leverage that
max please with with this the next steps
we for the first draft we've addressed
all of the yang doctors review comments
there we go with another round of
internal review but we will be asking
soon for working group last also we
asked the working group if you have
anything for example now Lu had pointed
out the IPSec support please raise the
issue before we call we ask for working
group last call the second draft the ete
tunnel modeling we had as I mentioned
received some comments from the yang
doctors review we will be addressing
those and we will be requesting a
working group last call after that the
last two documents there we are going
through another round of review for them
before calling for yang doctors if you
with this I close my presentation
questions yeah hi this is true from far
we have the question regarding the name
collision and especially the first point
in the name collision which was
regarding the controller learning the
tunnel name from devices which is the
same right and you using r1 r2 so do you
have little bit more details about where
will our one string will come and and
how would you where is this coming from
r1 exactly of the source as a string how
would you figure it out so that's a fair
point so one one proposal was to use the
source address which we have already in
the model but we think that you know it
can be a DNS name or or maybe a
configurable name on the of the Ingres
itself but so far we said the source
address is going to be appended for
example if you think that's not
user-friendly we should look into the
different option I'm feeling like why
did we put name as the only key and not
put source and name together as a key
that's another but maybe it's too late
that's another yeah it's a fair point so
we have one list that contains all the
tunnels from all the devices we could
split multiple lists per device but we
wanted that the model itself to sit on
either a device or the controller so
this is why we took this approach this
problem shows up only if the controller
is trying to put everything in the same
data scope and the assumption is that
the controller knows whom it's getting
it from and it will take the
corresponding source ID n dependent how
you know the society I mean the
assumption is that there is because you
are getting the data out from a
particular source you use that
particular source ID am dependent it's a
fair point thank you for raising it
Thanks
so next up I'm chief you know from water
networks I'm here to give a quick update
to tu topology model documents the first
one is Larry Harvey model so this is a
working group document so we have some
changes since last revision this model
hires some dependencies there are two
other document with depend on when is
the IDF ki-jung T types
another one is 32 party so post
dependency models have been changed
since last revision so we updated our
model to align with them then each of
those two documents has two modules so
we need a line possibly all the other
modules there another piece of changes
would be the trying to resolve doctors
reveal comments this is an ongoing
process we have fixed the editorial
errors and we will start still
discussing the other comments which is
ongoing so particularly this is one we
need to explain the relationship in the
hierarchy of our topology to the related
dependencies we have argumentations we
have a difference
so we also imported some several types
model so this is need to be resolved and
another issue this discussion was
brought up in last IETF so it's about
performance metrics unity reaction or
link and the discussion was that usually
for the accurate when we delay
measurement we need the clock
synchronization but in on some system
such kind of mechanism is not there in
that case the system where yours a
two-way measurement to do the estimate
divided the two way
delayed by two so in that case the
two-way measurement measure could be
useful so crack you have more comment on
this okay okay thank you Greg University
City yes clock synchronization is
important for accurate delay measurement
packet loss measurement and delay
variation are not susceptible to Quogue
synchronization so so we've had a few
discussions that we also talked about
this during our weekly meetings so the
current approaches that we still keep
that two-way matrix value of there and
so could be yours for dependence
situation and them so that we keep the
model at this
actually it would be useful if quark
synchronization the question is that how
it can be determined that's a
interesting question and problem where
the clock synchronization quality is
sufficient so it may be the clock
synchronization does exist the quality
of the clock synchronization maybe not
at the level requirement because there
might be some applications for example
Auto reliable low latency communication
in 5g that requires very high quality of
clock synchronization what I want to say
is that using two-way measurement to
calculate one-way metrics is useful
what's important is that then it has to
be specially noted that this one-way
metrics is calculated based on two
metric measurement case one says me
Rakesh Francisco so do you have both
one-way and two it populated or you only
have one or the other we have both you
have both so in some cases if you only
know one way then you don't have the
two-way so it has to use that value okay
because if you are how to wait then you
can divide that by two and that could be
one way and that's how you can compute
the one way but you're saying it's one
or the other depending on how the
measurement is done yeah actually what I
want to know is that there are been
developed measurement methods active
measurement methods that provide both
one way into a matrix so for example t1
and stem protocols you can do one-way
and two-way measurement
so hold on there so uh right so back to
laser modeling right so internal
modeling
do you see any changes need to be added
to this actually it's very good question
[Music]
for stent protocol is a simple two way
after measurement protocol we do have a
portion that I have a separately the the
synchrotron synchronization model
separate the rights of it again as I
mentioned I think that clock
synchronization and quality of clock
synchronization it's very it's a
separate question and it something that
I'm not aware of methods to quantify it
and how to monitor it how to measure the
quality for their performance
measurement we can discuss how your
model related to stampy and model which
is IBM working group draft right so
please be reminded this is a team
although we are not this is not
performance metric for measurement model
right so internal te T matrix here yes
so we are using the three types so the
krupin's there and if if you have
something need to be added that that's
probably more troublesome because it's
already passed Rosco so and then if it's
okay you can live with this then I'll
take a look then
yeah I was not aware of that but I think
it will be good if ma if model that
measurement protocol produces is easy to
map into their model that characterizes
link performance
so after
with I think we can move on to the next
step then the next model SR I star model
also arguments the nursery unicast to
poly model and that could be a te so we
in that case we were inherited from te
then after last revision we also tell
some changes to align the most recent
the spring I saw young model so we took
their latest grouping and use that we
also have this model revealed by young
doctor and we have a fixed some
auditorium problems and then now we
still discussing some issues to be
resolved when is the one comment is
about constraints and some of the
attributes relatively to ice are we
added those constraints to our model but
I think in the better way would be to
add those into the coping we are using
fun so this is the ice our spring be our
model so we talk to the houses up after
days so we're trying to see if we can
move those changes to the base model and
also there is a discussion but the URI
format user ID so this this is we don't
have much we can do now because this is
the base network to partly model which
we inherited so about which tree which
kind of format we want to use is you are
I only want to use the screen but it's
already there so it's just to whatever
we can and after that to the match
yes and we'll move to the next step
that's it hi everyone this is truth I'm
will be presenting two presentations the
first one is on the Vienna yank so I
think this we know that VN is the
customer facing yang model which she
uses lots of things from the T topology
and the d tunnel model the relationship
is as shown in the figure though nothing
has changed here the main changes in the
document is we added a introduction in
the introduction section a details about
how this model can be used in the 5g use
cases and this is something that is
being gonna be discussed specifically in
the second half of the tease you have
some topics on 5g so we also linked it
up in the a CT and VN yang and we hope
that this young model can be a basis for
virtual network even in the 5g world
apart from that the changes were mostly
editorial so far and we've made some
clarifications in our diagram make the
pointers to the JSON examples little bit
clearer so that people who read the
model can understand how this model uses
the connectivity matrices of the T
topology to show the relationship
between the million members in the yang
model itself one change was that we were
using the LTP without reference so we
changed that we have
now using a reference so that it has to
be asked configured in the topology
model and apart from that in the yang
model we added reference statement to
make sure that wherever we are referring
a leaf we have a pointer to a draft or
an RFC so these were the changes but the
main thing is the open questions that
were discussed on the list and we don't
have a resolution on that maybe the
first one is pretty straightforward it's
just a understanding question but that
led to the bigger question which is can
a VN member be from P to PE so the
concern came from currently we define VN
as a list of VN members and where a VN
member has a source and destination a P
and a P according to us is a logical
identifier between the C and a PE so we
always expect the C customer-facing
information to be a key part of our
definition of VN member but for some use
cases folks are saying that they want to
create a virtual network first and then
attach the customer-facing information
later so set up for instance a set of
tunnels which are starting from P to P I
am NOT attaching customer information
now let me set up a set of tunnels and
then when I do the customer mapping I
can do the C mapping easier so the first
question is should we allow this and if
we allow it what will be the possible
ways to do it and some of the possible
solutions that I could think of we kind
of wrote it down and we had some
discussions but we did not have any
resolution so this is something that we
want to work on between this and the
next idea and hopefully close on this
actually what do you suggest that you
change the API I think it makes sense
but I refer to the figure pair and I
figure floating of the actn4
work actually the supportive you know
for AP supported the customer view and
operator view for the an opponent could
be the C and it could be the P so we
already covered that yes
yeah so that's why just changing to AP
will solve the problem but I think the
bigger problem we should focus on is can
we have a VN member without any customer
with just p2p so so ap is a identifier
between C and PE you need to have at
least some C information what we really
want your requirement is let us have
just p2p we are member without having
any attached C II so so that requirement
we want to drill down a little bit and
see how we can solve it so it's not the
matter of what you call l1 l2 whether
they are called ap or whether they are
called endpoints I think the main
question is should we allow e to PE
tunnels as a VN member yeah
yeah you agree that that's the main
issue here you are yeah okay yeah no
have I explained the second issue
well because it's coming from you maybe
I'm misunderstanding this will be a good
time to hash it
yeah but secondly issue since you know
you follow the ACM for my paralegal 14
you support a custom view and operate of
view so you need to distinguish if you
change if you have each other so how do
you do that actually the solution you
may propose you may introduce some
indicator whether it is custom view or
it's operator view another choice is you
may introduce the additional maybe we
call the node ID and to support this p2p
connectivity yeah that's maybe the
loopback one so you are fine with these
solutions but I think the bigger
question to the group would be that that
what's what what do you think about this
requirement first and then we can
further drill down on solutions
sorry so just want to confirm so when
you mention the Lubeck actually it is
already defined in the model you can
actually yes you can use it as it is
without making any change it's just an
identifier we have done that for
instance when you configure a vrf you
can you bind the loopback interface to
the vrf it's just like that like usually
it is for the customer-facing interface
but your loopback interface can also get
binded to an vrf so I am kinda equating
the concept of the there you don't need
to change anything it's just when you
when you don't know the information bind
loopback later on
attach the actual customer interface
when you have it something like that
yeah I don't know which one is a good
pasture choice Chester when another
option actually you can introduce some
indicator to distinguish whether it is
custom view or yeah that's another
solution that make it clear what is it
referring to like make it ap can be in
between it could be just see endpoint or
it could be a P endpoint so that's
another solution which is coming for you
why do you limit your comment actn why
isn't this a generic comment oh why did
scoped actn it's a that's nothing in the
discussion I heard specific controller
based yeah no no I think that this is
the moto ad as I comment on it is that I
want you this the model should be
generic remote oh not a couple ways that
a city and framework but I just a few
example because you know that arrived
from the ICT and framework so there's
some example there's some figure so we
may actually yes yes so we obviously
could be used in many configurations
right so my understanding is that you
see VM as a node which has basically
links open-ended links right and it's
isn't it's the
the responsibility of what you call tea
service mapping to assign sees to to
year so if it's all done it should be
decouple to write it it doesn't have to
come as a single thing you can talk
about VM like for example like an
abstract apology or set of tunnels
independently from the users of that
so according let me make sure that I
understood your comment correctly you
are saying that it's already there like
we can do this right now is that what
you meant
yeah I I think that the VM as the
service doesn't include clients of the
surahs it's actually the model that
map's clients for the service it could
be done at the same time or later or it
could be changed at any time all right
you can take one C and put another one
without any any modification of VM all
right so I think it's perfectly legal to
think about V and without seas
okay thank you Daniela so I think the
requirement to make sense but I quite
agree
surprised with ego because I think the
PI ap doesn't necessarily imply the sea
in the sense that you can have with the
AP has one-to-one mapping with the P
node and a sort of oak with nothing
appended to it it'll all go see from
away just a question what is the
difference between a p2p VM memberid and
why not using a tunnel model because I
see a little bit I understand the V
remember between attachment points I I
try to understand why not using the
tunnel model for p2p D do
we want to talk about that once again
[Laughter]
yeah so this one is the recently adopted
document so I'm sure you all have would
have read it and it will be fresh in
your memory and what does this model do
if it is not that we define the
performance monitoring telemetry
information so these are the two yang
models which augment the T model and the
VN model and it includes the performance
the performance monitoring parameters
which you could subscribe to and apart
from that it also has this scaling
information so most of the changes that
we did in the recent this was to
describe the scaling but much more
clearly because I think the performance
parameters were pretty clear but the
concept of what is scaling and what do
we mean by these terms that we are using
that was not here so we worked on
improving and adding clarification for
that added a terminology section etc and
also why are examples described the
network autonomics part and what do we
mean in the context of this document
there was a comment with respect to what
is the right reference for the
notification mechanism the security
section I on a section and all the other
yang style guides and references etc
thanks to everyone who commented during
the adoption process
while we made these good changes to the
documents so regarding the terminology
this is something that we kind of put
down in our document the key performance
data that's pretty clear these are the
set of parameters performance parameters
delay delay jitter things like that that
we are monitoring on the VL level and T
level we describe what is scaling in our
document that is either you are scaling
in your resources or scaling out so
within the context of a tea tunnel of
how your resources can be modified
that's what we mean by scaling and with
the intent what we meant was put
conditions like while you are monitoring
these parameters you could also put
conditions that this condition on that
parameter should be met and at that time
I should scale in or scale out so that's
what we meant by the the scaling
conditions and the intent that we put so
by combining the actual data in the yang
model plus these conditions for scaling
and scaling out we are meeting the
requirements for network autonomics
within the limited scope of the T and
the VN model so that's how is with
respect to the terminology so hopefully
this can help clear up some confusion
that was there earlier so this part
hasn't changed
we are simply augmenting these models
adding performance parameters putting
the scaling conditions etc with respect
to scaling which is the one which we may
have to drill down a little bit so
basically how we are setting the scaling
condition you are mentioning whether you
need to scale up whether this is a
scaling out condition or a scaling in
what kind of metric you want to monitor
at the time of scaling what is the value
when it reaches that threshold that's
when the condition is hit and also you
have a ability to put
multiple conditions that you can be
monitoring multiple parameters so
whether it's an aunt condition or
condition min max things like that we
could combine multiple performance
parameters and threshold values via the
scaling operation type and of course we
did not we wanted to make sure that
there are some durations involved that
the threshold must be read must be met
for a particular time and there should
be some cooldown time before the same
conditions get hit again to solve those
problems we had put these parameters and
this is one example where you are
scaling for while monitoring the two-way
delay metric with a threshold value of
300 milliseconds and scaling conditions
for utilized bandwidth for again some MB
and by combining these two conditions
you are saying that when this particular
condition is met I must scale out in
this particular manner so this is still
work-in-progress this is the thing that
we have we are open to suggestions on
what is the best way to model this and
if there is any suggestions from the
group we are all yes thank you so when
when the client tries to configure
scaling of the tunnel right basically
defines conditions defines thresholds so
according to a model I assume that you
have to take their leaves from their
model and configure them properly right
but what if if client has something in
mind like combination of say two leaves
that you didn't envision stuff like that
so it would be very awkward so you have
to go and modify the model so it means
basically what you're trying to do is
envision the logic of the client of
doing such thing so well what I think
the better way to do this is what
net mode guys doing what
for example we try to introduce
basically some automation based on young
which doesn't do it in the form of logic
rather than in terms of configure
beliefs defines the thresholds defines
the combinations of different things
that triggers particular event and
actions according to this event greg-
tzt in our discussion in IBM working
group and with their feedback from those
or using active measurement performance
in the field on the network so what we
learn is that min and Max are not very
useful metrics minimum and maximum mean
is a little bit more useful but what is
most useful is a percentile and usually
they do three levels of percentile 95 99
in 99.9 and these may be used as
thresholds so once you have a test
session you can determine their
percentile of the test session and
compare it to the threshold
stampy and model stamp stamp
it's a working group document IP game
thank you craft about the te telemetry
generally this model is augmenting the
Tito Nova which is a very general and
the technology free model so we have
also the plans to integrate those kind
of technology specific
performance monitoring parameters here
or we allow the augmentation for the
technology specific performance
monitoring parameters right now in T's
of course we we don't but we hope like
now if there is an interest we can take
some work to seek out which can use this
as a base and add any technology
specific things onto it right now we
don't have anything but yeah if there is
an interest we can further talk about it
what we can take you Zika thank you
thank you
emitter woozy from away and presenting
the dimple assessing an extension for
schirmer's protections on behalf of
quarters and what is the use of this
document is document as we recently
adopted as a working group document at
the beginning of this year and we have
some just submitted before this that you
have a new update with where we are try
to address some comments we received
earlier working group adoption one of
them was clarifying the difference
between SNP share mesh protection and SM
RMS reservation as already defined in SC
48 72 and another comment we got was
about what to do for APS configuration
we have also worked with some new
co-authors on how to describe
notifications and we have new coders
that provided input to this update so
what is the problem we had arrested with
notification what happens is that since
the protection part that is reserved is
shared by multiple protecting Alice
pizza it could happen that the failure
on protecting Alice pin number 2 will
make unavailable for protection
switching a protecting LSP number 1 and
we want to notify the
Edendale end of this protecting LSP that
this part is no longer available such
that it doesn't try to activate this
part as the activation will fail and and
the solution we have found is that we
may be the solution could be that the
node where the text susanna Binion
available send a pattern or a
reservation error with the sakoda policy
control failure harder preempted them
and also it's set the past state remove
flag must not set it because the reason
is that we want to notify the end until
ended area the protection part is not
available but we don't want the LSP to
be tore down and we would like to get
that's the solution we found but our
discussion we were not under percent
sure and we wanted to get feedback from
the working group about whether we have
resolved the problem and this exactly
the right way
or to implement to notify the endpoints
not to activate a part but without
tearing down the state and then when
issues become an away available back
again so the protecting LSP number two
is no longer active you get the APS and
then you go back to it put pattern
reservation yes Perry from juniper I did
not read the draft but something caught
my eye
why wouldn't you use soft preemption
notification so soft preemption like
resource not available and that would
not tear down the LSB and maybe we can
take it off okay yeah yeah almost not
aware of this option okay yeah we can
think about that yeah it is not to tear
down and to let the end as the LSP is
not don't try to activate it with ApS
that's that's intention yeah okay good
suggestion thank you okay then the
second open issue that we are discussing
is about the SNP preemption priority in
edo edo tree there are the rules our
order is that in case of competition
between two different protocol SP trying
to assess the same resource the first it
will be used SNP preemption priority and
if they have the same preemption
priority will be the aps priority and if
they have the same address parity we
will use the LSP D&D failure to decide
which one of the of the two LSP will
assess the resource and but after
SanDisk we try to encode the SNP
preemption priority defined in a tomato
tree into GMP less at top and only
priority but it looks like they are
quite different because the MPLS a top
priority in all priority unrelated to
the activation on the state so to the
setup of the LSP while the idea is that
when the s and the protection LSP is
preempted we want to keep the state
again as before so the ID our feeling is
that we should not use the GMP let's set
up and all the priority but we should
have a new object that carry the SNP
preemption priority and then we have two
options one is to define a new object or
the other option is to define a new
field within the protection
object and we don't have any strong
opinion about which one of the two we
prefer like we will appreciate any input
from from the working group on whether
you have a preference I think that the
advantage of they did put they using the
existing object means no new IANA
location but may have impact on existing
implementation so we don't have strong
opinion but maybe others may have
already defined we had a new flex yes'm
the idea here is to add a new field
where you configure and I think is the
three bit preemption priority bill yeah
yeah the next comment is about issue is
about ApS configuration here the
situation is a little bit difficult
the APS protocol is for further study in
808 or trim and the meaning of this is
that the protocol itself which is using
the plain the protocol and message
format is technology and or vendor
specific 808 or 3 is generic and it
means that since there is no generic ApS
protocol means that every technology can
define its own one and for example in
Ooty and we have it's basically vendor
specific and and we need most of the ApS
configuration is can be done before any
LSP is a tapa so there is no impact on
gmpls
the only issue that may have an impact
on the GPS is the fact that ApS protocol
message when they request activate a
given protecting LSP they need to
identify the protection a lesbian and we
think that may make some implantation
meri use the gmpls LSP dent if I just
identified the LSP or sort of a shinky
like that other implementation may
define an ApS identifier and this ap
identifier needs to be configured when
the LSP is set up and this has an impact
on RSVP D because that's the time where
you assigned is identifier
and since this is not discussed in the
itu-t data plane we are evaluating
different options so for which we have
not fully not only photos are in
agreement so input from the working
group is really appreciated the one is
to kill say this outer scope since it's
for further study in edo edo tree and
let every vendor figured out what to do
another option could be to define a new
object and say is the content is vendor
specific third option could be to define
a new object which is a sort of TLV
structure where you can say some types
are allocated for standard tracker in
case of we have a standard technology
specific aps we can develop we can say
for this specific aps protocol that's
the the days of the structure of the TLV
and some other can be for example expert
review or private allocation for vendor
specific aps so i mean any opinion about
what's the best approach because we
don't have a standard reference for the
aps so we do have these three options
the please open issue we will get input
and then we want to resolve this open
issue and get further feedbacks and
comments it seems to me that you're not
being consistent and you look to see
that to make sure you're recognized that
you're proposing are aligned with with
those RFC's in particular how you notify
about errors and faults and protection
switch over
yeah well 4d yes the reason is that in
the 40s 72 sm r LS the protecting
Laspisa actually turn down when you have
a preemption and no that's most my
understand notifies okay
when you don't have to change state in
the intermediate nodes that's why the
notify was used because then you can
directly target that and they get a much
faster switchover so your suggestion is
to use notify instead okay okay okay
symmetry as well okay yes okay and not
saying you're not doing something a
little new that's why we have the draft
but okay thanks for really doing okay
for the notification we will review that
and try to align that that's a good
suggestion
but for preemption priority with the
little bit different because yeah and I
keep yes and there is nothing about that
because the preemption priority for SMR
is relying on gmpls a top priority but
and that's with the fact that the
preemption the prior the LSB is
preempted and removed from the from the
control plane and here what we want is
to keep in the control plane and not
activate that in the data plane and so I
think is often - okay new feel the
Redeem protection of okay okay okay and
then what what about a PS configuration
I mean it's just trying to allow people
to add their own just basically to if
they need to configure not everybody
needs to really add a new object because
if you rely on the GLSL expediently fire
to identify your LSP in the data plane
you don't need to configure anything but
some many some people it may implement
ApS and using one byte ID and then you
you cannot get it but I know she has
repeatedly said we have to be very
careful not to be standardizing ahead
of what the standard body that own these
new technology is doing so I think we
have to be a little careful here so I'm
I'm a little bit worried about the
options of two and three yeah that
context so I think if we do do two and
three we have to make sure that we're
well aligned with the IQ TMS okay
because at this moment in time there is
no protocol definition in the specific
so you prefer to keep it out of scope I
suspected that don't embrace it okay you
could say Deborah tell her I haven't
following this one that ITU is this
really the assumption and it's what my
cutie the situation is the following
eddo eddo tree it doesn't define any ApS
protocol the sections is for further
study so there is no generic protocol
that applies to every technology so we
in engineering gmpls we cannot define we
have maybe to go specific and the only
technology that is today defined for j4
SNP is OTN SNP or you SNP and in that
case we don't have any aps protocol
defined we didn't agree on the format so
idea under the way everybody is
deploying G SMP with its own SM people I
think their opportunity lays on I to say
we're doing this doc to document it it's
when it's not working group yet but we
had the requirements this is working
it's--that's lays on and asked asked the
question if what their expectations are
because the other is we should maybe do
a vendor specific one you or the authors
be willing to draft the liaison
okay yeah okay okay okay thank you okay
good afternoon this humming from Holly
and I'm going to present the
interworking between the GM PRS and the
central or centralized controller system
so this worker is the 30 the in last
month's and we have brief quick update
in July to capture and incorporated some
offline feedback from different
operators and vendors so the main
changes we also capture the open issue
on the list between before the working
group adoption to enable more
interworking scenarios who is more
explicit text descriptions on different
scenarios so this time we updated by
adding more details mainly on Marty Tom
a scenario and we are continuously
working on adding the multi layer as
well so let's see what has been changing
so far in the last update so basically
we originally were focus on the kind of
GMP RS domain what we have have been
enabled on among the devices but now we
are also received some feedback saying
that this architecture should be general
general enough to allow the interworking
between the non-gm pairs to me and the
GM parents to me so the red block is
something we add to the figure saying
that the architecture on the perspective
of architecture the system can allow the
interaction between the GMP RS and
non-gm pairs but all the scope of this
draft west still emphasizing the
interworking between the controller and
the GMP RS domain which is a red power
part of this figure so and it is also
worth noting that controller is a kind
of generic term used in some in the
system and it can be either the SDN
controller or the traditional ms/ms
system and the difference is between the
difference is mainly about the different
protocols used between the controller
and network devices so and then we also
update the scenarios by providing text
on how to do the service provisioning
and especially for the multi domain
cases and from this page and the next
page we are providing that has to enable
both end-to-end service provisioning and
also pass segment solution so this pay
tree is about the end-to-end narrow and
we have two we have two domains both
enabled in GM PRS protocols such as we
can run the r3 Apte protocol for
signaling and in this given this
architecture is a normal staff for
provisioning and setup the RSP is to
trigger the provisioning request from
the orchestrator to one of the
controller by using some existing young
models in the restaurant protocols
specifying IDF and also them and then
the controller can transfer the kind of
configuration to the head end node which
is purely you done by piece app or not
net calls protocol and then both the
controller and the log history there are
a ton of this itani in their job and the
whole RSP enable would be covered by the
head end notes and by using the RSVP tea
protocols to do the signaling work
and this processor can also be changed a
little bit to make an alternative
procedure and make best use of the
controller saying that the to say the
first step is still the same to trigger
the provisioning from the orchestrator
to the controller but the second step is
slightly different because the both of
the controllers in the domain can
initiate their respective head and now
the to start off the gen PRS signaling
and we also assume that there is GMP our
signaling in the domain and also we can
we implies as the ero label is included
the Internet's heater from the
controller tools I had a note so this is
what we have been done so far to make
the scenarios descriptions more complete
and we have also we have also have some
considerations on provide more detailed
about the multi-layer and the protection
risk to toleration and also the
controller reliability which has three
subsections in the current draft need to
be treated all the text and we are also
targeting all adding more descriptions
all non-gm parts domains are working
which may introduce some different
issues than the previous version of
traps that's how the date update
yeah I may have asked this question
before but I don't know our
responsibility o ask again yeah so this
work covers initiating the cannot set up
all that lets me set up from the heaven
just like if you see the adaptors it
also include transit position and coming
to you both provisional into em yeah it
can be done
end to end or segmented so I see a log
segments being provision at every domain
but do you also passes work also include
the scenario very active go program
every oh yes yes yes there you can do it
so from the controller to each shop and
just stitch it stitch every hop to form
an end to end the RS billion thank you
thank you
you're gonna this is hi I'm Adrienne yes
so that we have a design team for
revising RC 3272 which is the te
architecture framework document that is
about a hundred years old next slide so
we're supposed to be revising it because
technology has changed our understanding
of te has changed and broadened and
recent discussions in in a number of
working groups in this area have become
I don't know confused about the term te
so we worked out that the terms in the
document that exists are not adequate
for today and the references are
considerably out-of-date so we plan to
revise it
next slide so the chairs gave us a
charter to make the update as a full
revision not tweaks to strengthen the
definitions and include new definitions
as we needed and reference ongoing ITF
work so the design team will produce
regular updates and reports to the
working group the time interval was not
specified zero is a ray
number by oh yeah so we were instructed
to report in Prague which we did but
that was really only as we were setting
up and then produce an initial draft in
time for Montreal which we have not done
next slide so what have we actually
achieved not a huge amount we met in
Prague and decided how we would work and
how we would split up the work and then
we converted the current RFC to cram
down to give us something a base
document to edit and I did most of that
AC created a github venue for us and put
the mark down there and a few of the
teams started to make some changes or
whatever the magic term you used for
doing stuff in github but then next
slide we got stuck I think probably a
lot of the responsibilities to being
stuff is mine I completely failed to
bother to learn what github is and
there's a real lesson there about
choosing your tools it's only worth
choosing tools that the people who are
going to use the tools will use I think
that team may be sufficiently large that
we all know someone else will do the
work we are all busy people and we just
didn't do anything so no draft not even
close to having the draft ready to post
next slide so I present the chairs and
maybe the working group with four
options option one reboot which we've
kicked the team that we currently have
to do some real work option two is
kicked that same team but used different
tools and techniques and hopefully
deliver option three replace some or all
of the team including probably me an
option for simply give up on the idea of
revising this RFC discuss to you
personally the design team differently
or the same or and please don't answer
let me answer for me but then I think
individuals in the design team should
answer individually for them I think we
should try for option two because I
think that this is work that would
benefit the area on the other hand I'm
not getting the sense that there's a
huge desperate desire to actually do the
work from so option for does kind of
tickle away anyone else design team you
want to say something even brisk and I
think it's actually in my opinion it's
asking too much from design team the the
topic is huge it's in my opinion net
amount Stoica okay several volumes of
books so and basically to do it you
either have to do it real seriously or
you use option for hi rhetoric from with
Jennifer's part of the design team I
thought there was enough
changes to review at least so that we
can publish and zero zero draft partly
they take the blame myself as well
because part of the design team but I
think we can deliver a zero zero version
so I'm leaning to two or one pleading
guilty as well in non-contributing
efficiently as far as understood option
three looks quite pointless because you
need to find replacing people on the
first set of people failed to take the
time I have afraid options really really
quite fast to option for so for me
between I'm one and two it's up to the
leader but I agree with deserve a second
chance to try one more or two first I'd
vote for trying one or two before
anything else obviously we'd like to see
the work progress we charter because I
think for a reason we don't really care
what cooling uses so whatever helps the
most productive I guess I'm not leaning
into the mic enough sorry I was saying
whichever tools the the team wants to
use is their call so for me option one
and to the I'm not sure the difference
between reboot and rebirth if you get to
choose your tool although that is the
difference yes so the difference between
one and two is if you'd like an internal
thing for the team
yeah I think I think the difference is
eternal from my standpoint that's a tea
decision whatever works for you guys so
I guess I'm going to need some doggy
treats and a little training in other
words we'll proceed with the union of
option one and two at the discretion of
the design team which will continue to
be led by you which you'll have to tell
us form of doggy treats you'd like yeah
Julie treats that we should handle I
need somebody young enough to know what
github is and patient enough to teach me
I could probably help you with you know
young I don't have as great beard as you
okay thank you we have six minutes and
we have the next Danielle you're up next
I guess we can get cookies early and
maybe come back if you know we can start
you want to start going not only if you
want to squeeze into seven minutes or do
you want to wait until I we're gonna
stop we're going to break early we will
have to start on time because there are
people who