oh no back you get back to the manage to
know
[Music]
eric is taking books not so many that we
have some open mic Tim but nobody was
any we will have some we want some
feedback on like amputees if you invert
you do the work so that could be some
discussion I can when you you think it's
a pity
[Music]
okay hello everybody welcome to GTV area
you made it until Thursday yeah
I'm New York Ruben Magnus :
we are we have also in this session we
have to note well you should have seen
it already but maybe you want to reread
some parts of it maybe you want to look
at the code of conduct again that can be
useful from time to time keep it in mind
this is our agenda today we just started
you have a chance to pitch the agenda
basically right now if you want we have
as usually a couple of slides about what
we did in the last couple of months and
what the working groups are doing right
now then like I have a point where I
would like feedback from the community
about where in the IETF to do multipass
work because it's coming up in different
places and I want to make sure that
people are aware and talk to each other
so maybe you have better ideas than I do
and then we have a talk by Christian
about congestion defense in depth and
finally we get an update from Robin
which is a remote talk he presented some
quick based logging schemes last time
and he has pushed out two drafts and a
lot of work and so we thought we'd give
him some time to update on what he did
any questions about the agenda as always
we would like to thank our review team
we got quite frequent reviews in the
last couple of months and that's always
very helpful you can see it's not like a
huge load
[Music]
but it's it's important to have those
previous in quickly and yeah some some
good feedback from these people thank
you very much and this is also the
useless light which is like kind of
summarizes very briefly our view about
the current status of each working group
the one thing to mention is that there's
one working group less but also big
thanks to everybody who worked on this
working group and did the work in this
group so we closed it successfully and
have there are seats out there now if
there are no questions I'd go on also
just to to be a little bit proud of
ourself
this is like the documents that we
published in the last couple of months a
bunch of them are in the editor queue
right now and for new our seats out of
transport area yes I just mentioned
stuff that's related to transport this
is the right one okay
just to mention stuff that's related to
transport most of those things had
happened already because it's Thursday
the the only thing that's so on tomorrow
is Mapuche and it's usually there are a
couple of transport related discussions
there are presentations there but like
you can also go back and watch the
recordings there was ICC a tree with
some interesting TCP related and
congestion related
talks there was something which just
touch transport quite a lot in dispatch
that's called webs web transports so if
you haven't heard of that yet maybe have
a look at it and pen and she also didn't
have me at right no it did yes just yeah
okay it's over sorry but of course it's
related
in general I make one point on the web
print works thing they also had a site
meeting here and it seems like the
outcome of that site meeting is going to
be they're going to think about maybe
doing a bath in Singapore I don't know
what area they're going to send that to
but if it doesn't end up in the
transport area even though it's got
transport rate in the name we should
make sure that there is encouragement
for transport people to show up because
it definitely needs transport are those
on it during the passage dates Ganassi
to add to the web transport topic we
have just created a mailing list web
transport ITF it's currently under the
applications area but like yes I Brian
said there will be transport components
and more love to hear from people
knowledgeable who all send emails to
lists about the very list Colin Perkins
also in the meat's transport ipols loops
continues yeah loops was a transport off
so I hope you all guys okay that gets us
to my point where I really need some
feedback from you guys so we do have a
couple of efforts where something
happens with multipath and it seems that
it's getting worse so that if there's of
course MP TCP however they are basically
at the end of their Charter they don't
really have a new work item right now
and there are people interested in
amputees being general but it doesn't
look like they have any standardization
work should you so my big question is
should I close a working group or is
there another option but we also have
had a lot of discussion about making
quick multipass capable it's even in the
Charter it will not be an aversion one
of quick but it will come up again and
there has been a proposal for multi pass
DCC P and he's working group and of
course there are other discussions which
are related to multi pass in Panaji and
ICC or gene
yes a the important point here that I
want to make sure that people are
somehow think that everybody knows what
what the other people are doing that
good thoughts are brought to the
different groups and not only discussed
in one part of the community and that
also maybe you know we don't do the work
twice we solve the problems once and
then can apply it somewhere if
applicable and the other problem I I
really would like to address is that
also new people from outside because
these protocols become more mature so
more people get interested in it that
they know where to go that they have a
place to ask the question that they know
there is the place where this discussion
will happen in the IETF and it's like as
easy for them as possible to find the
right place and I have one more quick
slide which is basically kind of the
questions a little bit broke them down
so do we need a new group in the ITF do
we need a group in the ITF what did you
about MBT CP what did you about
multipass quick is it useful to split
the work in some way or it should we
make sure it all stays kind of in the
same place David Mark David brought one
of the chairs of TS vwg and help and
hence with a not quite enlightened
self-interest in moving work elsewhere I
would really like to see one form for
for multi path topics that would make an
enormous amount of sense could I suggest
a non working group bath for Singapore
to go over all of these possibly along
the line and he might even think of it
in along the lines of The Dispatch
mechanism we she used in other areas but
at least for Singapore a multi path
interest bath might be a good way to get
everybody in one place and have a better
discussion say great question the buff
would make a lot of sense if it's a
cross area topic do you see that this is
coming up a lot outside of the transport
area
not sure probably not have not pitted
early I lies I hurt
could you go back here to slide it had
all the options on it so I have a
variety of opinions and they change a
lot right now so I think MPT TV should
probably could be closed if there's any
sort of maintenance stuff that pops up
you know is ticket TS vwg or tcp em
whoop sort of preternatural homes right
um I'm I'm I I sort of saw the DCCC beep
multipath proposal I didn't hear about
setp frankly I don't really care about
either of those two so I I don't
so however unsurprisingly I care a lot
about quick so I I think actually so the
multipath work effect the main one right
that we're going to do is is for quick
and and in my mind at least it needs to
be done in quick because it ties in a
lot with the protocol details right and
with with TCP M and multipath tcp tcp
was already a you're quite established
protocol one could say and by the time
we did multipath tcp and so there wasn't
i think it was okay to have it as in a
different working group but doing
multipath quick in a working group that
isn't the quick working group i think
will be very difficult
um i would rather just give quick you
know a third slot or something like that
well maybe we keep the second one and we
use it for this um we absolutely want to
learn from what multipath tcp did um we
don't want to reinvent the stuff there's
a lot of the problem I see is that
there's a lot of sort of architectural
thinking that was done like already
before the ITF work started in trilogy
and elsewhere right and so um it would
probably be good to figure out what the
principles are that underlie multipath
TCP and apply those to quick the
protocol mechanisms in multi-party CBR
but actually because they had to be
because it was TCP and we needed to get
through middle boxes right um and so in
quick we can hopefully do this a lot
cleaner and simpler
but but those those principles I think
would be valuable to figure out what
they were if I could only remember and
and see how we can apply them so so that
could be something that I see crg could
do or you could have a joint joint
session or a workshop or something I
don't know if it's a buff so in theory I
would like to do it exactly that way I
think that's the right way however in
practice what we have right now is that
we already have for example the problem
that some of the they take or TCP people
don't show up in MB TCP anymore and we
have the problem that some of the court
you see people don't show up and quick
anymore so we really have to make sure
that the right people show up at the
right places and I'm not sure if that's
the right the perfect solution for it
but very quickly before I get out of
line so I think that's sort of an
artifact of how the things of all trades
so multipath TCP for a long time has
been a proxy protocol right they're not
really a TCP protocol and so it's not
sort of really surprising that the TCP
folks aren't there anymore and I think
you would probably so and in quickride
we we don't really have a lot of
participation from TCP connection sort
of recovery people because we really
haven't done much we just like the bits
go and and got the underlying protocol
correct I think now this will probably
ramp up especially with China's and
Martin's work on the simulator and then
the Q log stuff that we're gonna see
where you can actually do congestion
control work with quick because we
actually have a protocol now that runs
so I'm hoping that I'll sort of correct
itself but maybe I'm optimistic
Spencer darkus Mary thank you for
bringing this topic forward to address
what it seems like to me that yeah to
the extent that we can come up with
principles that anybody like the point
was not to do quick right the point was
to be able to do quick and prove that
that was then there we can do in their
transport protocols which may even be a
different variant versions of quick the
behave in different ways so I think that
trying to think about things at the at
the principle what were the principles
level
it's really worth doing and then you can
feel what you know if you it seems like
to me that like questions like how do
you how do you pick which paths to use
for which packets win but maybe that's
not tied to a protocol so that maybe
Wesley maybe maybe there are things like
that that you can spin off if you ask
about course area possibilities I we've
had conversations in the idea for a long
time about applications the pop out that
want to manage their bench pass
themselves even though they're not
transport protocols and I would hope
that security and operations people as
well but still card critical
technologies one other place where
multipath work is already being done is
the network coding research group and so
I've actually been that connected to
quick as well somehow or is that
completely independent independent okay
so I've actually been running multipath
routing and transport to aircraft for at
least 15 years published a paper back in
2004 at the I Triple E military
communications conference so practical
background in it but not a lot published
just going to first principles I mean
it's the job of routing to concatenate
links to create paths it's the job of
Transport to then use the paths with
which it's presented but then if we want
to do better than that
it might also be the job of Transport to
give routing a hint about the kind of
paths that it might like and it might be
the job of routing to give Transport a
hint as to the kinds of paths that it
was able to construct so I think this is
intrinsically a a cross layer topic and
it's not just that we need the different
people to talk to each other it's that
we need the different protocols to
talk to each other we need ways of layer
3 giving layer 4 hints and layer for
giving layer 3 hints and I don't know
where within I ATF is the right place to
talk about these cross layer hints the
person was up in a tree had standing
right behind you and raising this in my
brain to a co-chair of panel G so it's
all apparently on the list there as like
sort of like problems and requirements
we are actually kind of a venue for a
for problems in requirements and whatnot
for a subset of the multi path problem
which is exactly the subset of the multi
path problem where you are doing exactly
the kind of hinting that Stu was talking
about but it like so the from what I've
heard in the line so far I had a
slightly different opinion when I got in
line the hat is actually kind of messing
with my brain the V it sounds like a
multi path interest bath is probably a
good idea for Singapore um one of the
outcomes of that could be hey look it's
the usual suspects in the room we need
to have I think we call it a multi path
interest boss you're gonna get a ladder
outing people showing up and that's a
good thing um just to make sure that
like the when we're talking about the
principles that we're talking about the
principle is in the same way as to were
the as to where to work ends up after
that it's definitely in the transport
area somehow but I don't want to have
the buff that we haven't had yet in the
mic line right here um a reflection on
sort of a difference between NP TCP and
MP quick as I'll say a little bit less
pejoratively the Moores did the the way
that that TCP was multipath was
constrained by the design of TCP in a
way that the way that quit will be
multipath is not necessarily designed by
be constrained by the design of quick
way just the network okay yes it allows
to stutters the network the constrained
which yeah I agree with that um quick
does not have the same set of
constraints right so it has quick has a
much larger
in design space that it can explore for
how it does multipath and Van itself
suggests to me that there does need to
be some work separate from quick on sort
of design principles and like transport
independent design principles I think
that's a that's a work that we have to
take on I have no idea where to do it
I'd like to discuss that in a bath in
Singapore so give him Christian as the
next speaker and he said last one in the
mic land across in my plane that's where
they can jump in las going to ask a
really quick clarification question so
when you say multipath do you think it
is in scope for a transport session to
use path diversity that is deeper in the
network than the first hop or last stop
so do i target multi path or multi
interface because multipath TCP
originally tried to do multi path but
will actually deliver this mostly multi
interface and I think for quick the
interest specifically now is a multi
interface support right it just sort of
to see if that's if this is what you
mean or whether you actually move multi
path or not sure yet so I actually had
multi interface in my mind but there
also might be pass stuff that's cross
transport right so that's coming up as
well
this is I think that this problem
statement is this is way too broad which
which relates to something that lasts
just said
first there's the multi interface versus
multi path and I didn't understand that
but I think it's important to
distinguish those things MPT Cebu NP TCP
was right to be chartered as a separate
working group because of a ton of
protocol work to be done then that's
primarily what happened we did not
discuss the condition controller really
that much it was a separate document and
it was fine and you could replace it
with whatever you want that was
effectively what the the protocol
document said I think that's appropriate
similarly if you think about quick as
the next thing that's that we want to
think about doing multipath in I agree
completely with loves that's where the
quick working group is where the
discussion ought to happen and where
that we I don't think that we need to
charter an MP quick working group
because what I'm trying to say here
there is no requirement for an
equivalent of the MPD City working group
in in terms of outside of that I
actually don't know what is left to be
done if all we're talking about here I
mean if you don't know about doing multi
power DC CP and I said again this is all
protocol level work that we're talking
about not condition control work or
anything like that I don't think it
makes sense to have them in a common
place just because they have the word
multipath in front of them because the
work that I ultimately doing there is
protocol work you want the protocol
experts to be in that room so you want
the quick experts to be in the room
where MP click is happening you want TCP
experts in the room at MPT CDs happening
so I don't disagree but I think there
are things left that like may come up in
future more when people use these
protocols even more which is like for
example congestion control this
questions about scheduling and smaller
optimizations interface questions which
pass to setup when right at or if at all
and these questions are all very similar
some of them might clearly be more in
the research area than in in the
transfer protocol but then as you're
standing there do you think there it
would be space for another multi pass
research group in the IRT F because it's
also it's also my parents also covered
by other groups a little bit I mean
there's room if you create room for it
you let us call it that's not my place
to say anything there right but I again
I don't know how that this overlaps here
so in terms of the condition controller
that could go into IC crg the scheduling
itself I I would I would not touch it
with a ten-foot pole because I've done
work on that aspect of it and it's it's
difficult to nail down any particular
you you won't come to consensus or
anything that's meaningful there it's
ultimately going to be left to
implementers to do what they do in terms
of scheduling it might be valuable
research but that's not going to be
valuable enough to create a research
group for so but you I mean actually
that's a right point - right relay a
comment from Robin max from the Java he
said like the the MP quick authors of
the proposed MP Creek multi pass and be
quick draw
they are the same office as for MP TCP
right and so the problems I have here
and I try to press down on this light
was that I want to make sure that those
people who have the expertise even so if
they've been working on a different
protocol actually come to the to the new
working group where this work is done
and currently I see that this is like
off not happening because we have too
many places where we do the work even so
it's different protocols and they need
to do we have places for them the
problem is we have too many places and
the same the same base problem is for
the second point on this slide where
people who are interested in MB TCP and
as soon as I close the embassy working
group they will think outside of the
idea if they would think we don't have a
place for it anymore so I want to make
sure that they can kind of look at the
agender and know where to go and no
where to talk to these people because
everybody is still around and open to
talk to you right so that's a problems I
have yeah so so I can I can speak to the
in terms of MPD's if you work where that
should happen I have a very quick opener
which is I think yeah TCP MRTS vwg both
are wonderful homes for continuing work
that's all we've done in the past sed B
when it closed it moved to TS vwg and
that seemed natural and here we have two
potential homes and they both seem
natural but in terms of the how to get
the right people in the room we've
struggled with that and quick as well
the lost recovery document I've tried to
bring it up to TCP M and present it I've
done it several times but we have a few
people engage in Gauri's there and Bob
is Babas in all of it but then there's
the force of TCP M is not there right we
have a handful of people who are in
order DCP more there but you're not
getting the views from a lot of other
people in TCP M I don't know how to
solve that problem besides encouraging
people to show up if they're interested
they ought to show up and they ought to
engage so I mean like even if I mean
quick right you have this the same
problem but like you could have we could
have split up the quick working group
interest in a quick quick mapping
working group and a quick core protocol
working group which could have addressed
this problem but maybe cost other phone
whatever so quick mapping in terms of
the you know a cheapy mapping put the up
yeah so like this could have addressed
the problem we have right now like I
don't want to change it I'm not
producing it right but
that like this is what I'm talking about
because making decision about who had to
do the work and how to frame it is
actually called implicating by people in
the room yeah in the multi part case I
honestly think that the protocol work is
much more than anything that you do
above it like I don't think there's a
lot of abstraction work to be done like
you said the scheduling and the
condition controllers are independent
the condition controller can go to ICC
are gee I don't think we'll do anything
useful which as a scheduling that leaves
the protocol work and that should be
long in the protocol homes in Baku Baku
few questions of besides agreeing with
Larsen's a previous speaker I believe it
actually having a both it's a bad idea
and why I say so it's totally dependent
on what is your overall timeline you
would like to address his work if you do
consider this work to be used also
inside of other SDOs essentially above
would eliminate this or from 3gpp Ellis
was a really seventeen because
practically you cannot do envy DPP
anymore beef before at least March next
year so forget about having any type of
multipath quake it was already lost in
really sixteen other groups like BBF
also wanted to have such a work being
done again I'm not going to be done so
anyway I don't think that like no matter
what we do there will be no MP quick
work before next March
is not to be you will not even be able
to start anywhere visit problem your can
start work right people started working
on it already so yeah we will not have
an official okay as a participant and
one of the company which originally
proposed this part you simply not going
to be able to propose any work even if
the work can continue in the next year
just my field I
Perkins speaking as an individual um
just in response to that I don't think
if if we have above to discuss that this
sort of thing is gonna make the
slightest bit of difference to the
timescale of the quick work yeah
anything to do with multipath quick as
protocol specifics clearly has to go to
the quick working group I will all that
allows chip in for the timescale of the
chip of the quick working group but I
would be surprised if everything is
finished and ready to do multiplayer
work in that timeframe
Mike don't open issues and quick anymore
in terms of the multipath congestion
control work I mean yes obviously we can
move you know we could do that sort of
work in ICC RG in many ways that would
make a lot of sense
we could also you know potentially you
know there's been some discussion of
potentially moving you know single perf
congestion control up into IC crg rather
than trying to do it in the TCP specific
way in a quick specific way for example
and there are potential advantages to
doing that there's also a potential
disadvantage which is that it ends up in
the IRT F which means that everything is
done as an experimental protocol or as a
informational document and not a
standards document and maybe that
doesn't matter and maybe the IETF is
okay with referring to information all
our experimental documents for the
congestion control and doesn't doesn't
worry about having stands of strike
congestion control algorithms but it is
only something that we should consider I
mean there's one more difference like
IETF documents have IETF consensus and
IRT documents don't yes yes so I mean it
changes the type of review it changes
that the type of document we get and and
maybe that that matters maybe that
doesn't matter get given this particular
problem domain it's not like a lot of
the internet runs on standard congestion
control anyway can we generalize
congestion control multiple most of eff
congestion control across
the transport protocols or other
protocols specific differences enough to
cause problems I'm not sure we've we've
investigated that well enough to know
the answer maybe we can I don't know
similarly you know things like half
awareness routing if you see you reach
retransmission scheduling a I think we
perhaps need a conversation to figure
out how general this can be and how much
it is unavoidably protocol-specific
if we're trying to generalize things we
should understand whether it's possible
to generalize them so I think that
that's kind of a long-winded way of
saying plus one so a longer discussion
in Singapore David scan Ozzie
I really have to eat this one yeah it's
Kedah see google this sounds to me a lot
like a premature optimization in the
sense that the reason we form working
groups in the ITF is that we have people
that don't have a home and so we take
those birds of a feather and we help
them flock together to make a bath
working group so everyone is happy and
sing Kumbaya yeah
but the but in this case like I don't
see anyone with a draft saying I don't
know where to put this like if people
are doing this work it'll go to the
right place say quick multipath we'll go
in quick so on and so forth right where
I said I would close MP TCP right yeah
and I am not and the reason we closed MP
TCP is that there is no more things
happening and if they come back we will
reopen the working group that's a common
pattern at the IETF you don't need a
place for these hypothetical Jess I
might come one day and so I mean like I
again agree but it doesn't address the
problems I have it doesn't address that
people with the expertise we need have
to go to multiple groups and potentially
have to say the same things over there
right and it doesn't address a problem
that people come from come from the
outside don't know where to go because
they don't know the inner structure as
well as we do so I understand the
theoretical problem you described
I have never seen it in practice what
water I don't see these multiple working
groups were that aren't talking to each
other we have it we have it in practical
practice we have it in mp TCP because no
TCP we show up anymore and we have it in
quick because the transfer people don't
but you creating a new working group
will not get people to show up like I'm
I work on quick and I will keep going to
quick and if we do multipath in quickly
I will go there if I don't go to NP TCP
I won't go to this other or working
group either like at the end of the day
or maybe I will choose to depending on
the drafts they are but I will go for
the drafts in the agenda not for the
working group so but you would go so you
would go to an working group that is
chartered to do MP quick work right
because you want to do that and if
that's happened to be the same working
group that works on some kind of TCP and
extension I'm not proposing that I want
this group right but then you would go
there yeah and then leave halfway
through but and people do that all I've
done like for example I started this
particular meeting in another session
because I wanted to see that and then
came over here we're all busy there are
conflicts and that was always be the
case it's i if you want
cross-pollination and I've it's been
said before you want to encourage people
to review and that's very hard but
adding process and working groups is not
how you solve this I don't know how to
solve it but I don't think this will
help generate a map I'll be brief
because I want to leave time for the
next speaker but but basically I mean
what not said there is no evidence that
the guy were doing multi paths are not
participating in quick they are
so there is no problem to solve there
there is something that could be said
about adding ICC ology look at the issue
of multi-link congestion control for a
theoretical point of view that will be a
very interesting because that's the kind
of stuff that gets picked up I mean if I
look at the work that quick did on
congestion that values teams do yeah in
here we they do we know but in practice
it
in practice they pit the research that
has been happening and they put it in
that code so having that in Isis he or
she would be very nice yes okay thank
you very much for the input it might be
it might we would every just go on as we
are but I also had people who would be
interested in a I've said this already
did yes I need it in I heard also people
who thought that like having a border
come communication and discussion would
be useful however I think the community
needs to propose something here so if
you're actually interested in this and
you can scope it in a way that you think
it will be useful discussion then please
work on that and now Christian I you
need slides right
that's low it's working
[Music]
prisons okay good afternoon so a couple
of months ago I wrote a little piece
about congestion control and
specifically about congestion control
and the new transport protocol that are
developed in the application space
[Laughter]
speaking about congestion
okay so basically the the plan is the
following in there
the way we have been doing transport
pretty much until the last two three
years was that if you wanted transport
was thought of as TCP and France and was
developed mostly in the kernel I mean
yes there were examples of protocol
develop in application space a bit big
current comes to mine but they were kind
of specialized when it was original
practice and so the result of that is
that if you want to change say the TCP
retransmission algorithm what you have
to be that tool to participate I mean
metaphorically nothing with actually
measure your size but they the idea is
that if you want to check in some scenes
in the Windows camera that I know well
well I mean there will be quite a
process before you do that and similarly
if you want to checking something in
Linux you can definitely check that in
your own branch and do your own copy but
if you want to have that in the main
distribution
there'll be some process I mean people
will check what have you been doing
show me the the RFC was that new
algorithms it is defined or there is no
I've seen then I want to see your
simulation I want to see something I
want to get face and what you are doing
so there is effectively a gatekeeper
that stands before between you and and
imposes friction that limits the amount
of crazy innovation that you could do
and the good thing is that application
level transports solve that I mean if
you look at the the quick interrupts
spreadsheet you see nineteen
implementation they walk on about four
counters so clearly there is
independence and they can do that
because the way you ship transport is
with implementations as the library so
you do application update and for
example if the Google guys want to
update the transport running in Chrome
shipping on Windows 10 they don't have
to ask permission to Microsoft they
don't have to wait that Microsoft
implements TCP first open they don't do
that they just update the code and they
ship it is there and Google is an
example but you could see any kind of
application if you have an app and it
speaks to a server and you can update at
the same time the server undercutting
your up you're good to go you can do
what you want so this guy here the
gatekeeper has been removed okay so yeah
generally our diva may disagree with you
now or severely under labor Jen I want
you to actually use me
[Laughter]
mineralize I'd not generally but there
are a couple of points but I can read
under later if you'd rather okay later
so I would say that being able to do
that kind of innovation is actually very
good when there is no question about
that and and in fact what we have done
by going into I mean letting people do
this transport at the application level
is open new opportunities for
development and research and it's not
like there is no need for that I mean we
are mentioning multipath before but all
open of migration estimating which link
you go to how you mix real-time to have
it in a non real-time transport how you
deal with loss independently of
congestion how do you deal with the
fading of radio links etc etc all these
are problems that are partially solved
in the transport that we have but in
fact this work to do okay and because we
have this application level transport if
you are running a research lab for
example you can tell to your grad
students that hey take that and and try
and they don't have to be compiler
kernel they just have to be comprise the
app they can try 25 valuation of the
Argo is in a single afternoon so that's
quite okay
and I'm sure that because we have done
that we are going to see many mortices
PhD master whichever being written being
walked on and loss was telling me that's
that's actually something to happen so
that's that's very good so don't do not
ever quote me in saying that I think
it's a bad idea it's a really good idea
next but there is this guy okay and
assume that you are working not in a
research lab you are working for some
kind of coma
company and you are developing a new
version of the transport that you are
going that's going to go between your
application and your server and what is
these guys gonna tell you
let's cut you Google you beat Facebook
no back to work it's absolutely going to
tell you something like that or some
variation of that okay and and that
could go very wrong very quickly I mean
the first way that can go wrong is
competitive congestion control so we
know that we have seen that already
remember the time where brazo were
competing on how many TCP connection
they could open at the same time so that
they could have n times the congestion
window I mean if you have application
level transport that's much easier just
had to change a constant in the code to
get the same effect already you can see
people I mean that was actually in the
Google quick code it was there is a
factor in the Google quick code that
says how many cubic congestion control
many cubic conscious Corrections do you
want to emulate and you can compile with
a tractor and he said the default was to
I believe but you could set it to 4 or
16 if you wanted okay and someone is
going to invent a super fast version of
the new TCP that is not bothered by
these stupid losses in the network and
goes as fast as you can I mean they'll
do that I think they already did
actually but yes ok but now with they
can put that in there up and ship it and
that shows the competitive congestion
control that's not the most interesting
suppose that you are managing your
bottleneck and you you do some smart
sensing which we can do that and says
damn I'm copying with a cubic connection
and they are bursting my database
congestion control what can I do well I
know the specifics of cubic I know what
I can do I can do a spike of traffic
very briefly then I go on doing what I
was doing before I know the spike of
traffic would have caused a loss in the
cubic in the in the bottleneck and the
connections gonna back off and now I can
have the network of myself okay and and
maybe others something like that
actually but now what will be our best
two-qubit you can absolutely do to be be
are you look at the idea technique and
how they are doing you know that they
will be sensing at one specific point in
the flow at that precise point you send
a spike talking about cough and they're
gonna back up for six transmission
windows that's great
for the next six transmission windows
you get the network for you and that's
what I call address on your congestion
control and I think that's a new idea of
research in which we can find many PhDs
okay that's gonna happen I mean because
you don't have any gatekeeper to tell
them don't do that and you only get
keepers are the network geyser okay so
you know if you give brilliant new guys
new tools stuff may very well happen and
goods poem is an explanation of that but
basically if if you have an application
that keep winning local congestion
control because they are doing one of
those smart adverse higher congestion
control stuff what will happen is that
the users of the other apps are going to
be pissed off because the application
doesn't work and they are going to
chorus
lines but very good if you are going to
have one of those competitive things
that emulates 256 connections it will
have some kind of an effect on the
network bottleneck between two networks
etc etc now normally I don't expect that
to have more than local effects but with
a little work and a good software update
who knows okay we have seen software
updates already bringing down big
companies so it can very well happen at
that point you want to call back the
master sorcerer but is not there anymore
so hey and that next slide so who's seen
a streetcar named desire
yeah and so that's this lady blondie
well she's at the Alice's I always
depended on the kindness of strangers
it's kind of what we do in the network
we cannot depend on the kindness of the
transport level developers and I think
that we should not do you should not be
doing that anymore we should stop for
the principle that one way or another
the end-to-end developers are kind of
off because their interests are not
aligned with ours and if your network
manager you have to believe that
actually defending against this kind of
stuff like a competitive congestion
control or adversarial congestion
control is something you want to have in
your network and that's really my call I
chorus guys it's time to think about
that
and start implementing the defense in OS
in depth they have to be implemented
probably at the access point in the
network but probably also points that
are sensitive as well that's Jenna now
I'm sure yoga with me
after all that thank you Chris and Jenna
Inger I think this is a very important
question and I think it's an important
question because we are as you point out
going into sort of a new space where we
are gonna have potentially an easy ease
of develop development and deployment of
congestion controllers and that's going
to change things somewhat it's not clear
to me how much so let me let me be
specific here you might remember that
about I want to say almost 15 15 to 20
years ago
video applications started to get
deployed on the internet and they were
deploying their own condition
controllers in the application space yes
and again people were crying murder at
the time and we seem to have survived
that I'm not saying that that
necessarily means that we will survive
this but I do want to just remind people
that this is not the first time you sort
of seeing this problem where we are
concerned that people might start
building random stuff and it will bake
everything that we love the thing I
wanted to disagree with you at the
beginning was you pointed out that it
there's a gatekeeper and I agree with
you that there has been a bit a bit of a
gatekeeper in the Linux kernel but for
most server providers when you're
talking about congestion control for the
most part on the internet we're talking
about content providers like Google
cloud providers etcetera etcetera now
not having something in the kernel has
not stopped them from deploying whatever
they want to deploy so not having
something up streamed into Linux has not
stopped them from experimenting and
deploying maybe as a good example if you
look at Akamai Akamai deploys fast
there's a whole bunch of condition
controls that have been deployed at
server found and server deployments that
aren't basically in upstream linux as it
is and there are measurements there are
various things that are done there and I
I guess I what I want to say is that the
colonel isn't has not been in the past
the gatekeeper of this this particular
thing it has been people who deploy
stuff
so yes is Google a gatekeeper of this
absolutely it is it's a gatekeeper of
what they deploy on their service his
Netflix a gatekeeper of this yes they
are because they control what they
deploy on their service and it's not
typically what's in in-stock FreeBSD or
stock Linux so I think that the
gatekeepers are different and in that
sense those gatekeepers have not changed
fundamentally but they have they have
take the Google cloud now the guy who
can change the congestion control is not
the runner of the Google cloud it's
every single app that's running in a VM
someone again that's not very different
they can already do that with TCP is my
point
they have root privileges on the thing
that they run and they can absolutely
change the controller there they can
deploy whatever they want in fact yeah
sure that's true and in LED and should
we panic we can yeah so the line is
closed for now so I was lost in so I I
what I'm trying to point out here is
that thinking about the kernel as a
gatekeeper I think is a fallacy because
the people who are gatekeeping at the
kernel were not and are not experts in
congestion control this is a
long-standing problem and the second
thing is what you're talking about here
with isolation of users and so on I
agree with you that's a useful strategy
for doing things it's already happened a
fair bit yes
it's what happen yes it's a good thing
yes like I saw it first
I'm worrying about these things makes
you an excellent candidate for Transport
ad please
[Laughter]
[Applause]
so I used to worry about many of those
same things and I'm so chilled out a lot
and there's some reason for it right so
what one reason is right so this is sort
of roughly two kinds of applications on
the Internet right there's this the ones
that ship enough bytes to really do some
damage and then there's the ones that
don't right
so the long tail what the long tail does
who cares right because the data just
have enough data to actually do any
damage
really they might sort of cost himself
and if he runs problem for a particular
user that runs that Abin and they get
annoyed but dinner is not that harm from
those codes and then there's like the
guys who shape a lot of data right but
those funny enough for all the people
who quite carefully monitor what happens
to their traffic because you know their
revenue stream pretty directly depends
on that really working well and not
causing the customers trouble and and
that feedback loop is is I think what is
actually now the protection that we have
for the most part and then when I got
back what China said that we do actually
see over the last 10 20 years that that
access networks a sort of isolate users
to an upstream link so you can at best
sort of harm yourself and we saw that
when like BitTorrent went to that pad
right because um the the work calls
would die if somebody turned on
BitTorrent and and that was not good and
then they fixed it was all self
interference the network wasn't really
in danger here other than you know
traffic using peering links and it
wasn't going over before that's a
separate story so that that's sort of
it's it's a self interference is a
problem but but the Internet is not
really at a danger here
but but transport 2020 I'm a retiree
come on that means you have time a
second a lot of those things I actually
thought about this problem on and off
for two decades and Matt Mathis I'm
sorry there are a bunch of different
mechanisms that defend the internet and
up until fairly recently
[Music]
every code in TCP wasn't good enough and
if you pushed harder and congestion
control you took more losses and
therefore ran slower and so there was
this built-in mechanism the recovery
code has gotten good enough from the new
and they're stacks and sublet protocols
where this is no longer true and it's
yeah I know I know
I thought about that too where I have
actually run some TCP implementations
under situations where they were
sustaining above 50 percent lost because
Seawind was pegged at some large number
and they just ran happily along fixing
all walls you can do this but there are
other things those topological
constraints access links are a small
fraction of the core if the person you
hurt most is the person in the next
office and they're likely to come knock
on your door and there's a whole bunch
of mechanisms like that that tend to
defend the Internet the things that
worried me I'll be perfectly honest I am
NOT on the VBR project and I fretted
about VBR one in some of the situations
where it could get in trouble in the
public Internet and the the telemetry
that we had that the BBI team was
looking at very carefully is whether or
not running a b b BL in parallel if we
were in the bowbully the bbr flows had
lower round trip times which meant lower
queue occupancy and so there was a
single metric that we were looking at
that actually gave us confidence that
would work hurting the internet anywhere
we don't really have a way of observing
that data and so but it's a big concern
but people were paying attention to it
very much yeah I think what's up there
yeah no I but I agree that people who
are shipping large application etc do
pay attention and they are not on the
business of clocking the Internet you
can imagine pathologies where a widely
deployed game has got bad congestion
control in it and it's not until you get
hit a million users that you discover
that it's implicit DDoS or is anything I
didn't measure the common case is
actually deliberate DDoS and they don't
what you think I have experience with
video conferencing where RTP is the
similar thing because it's a transport
that runs in the application layer now
in that case in the beginning even I
mean you're talking about congestion
control
there was no congestion control at all
because everybody tried to use it as
much as you can and they had the
mechanism inside to get over packet loss
at up to a certain percentage so they
didn't care much and I said maybe the
other one one would use a trait that
I'll be able to show that my product
worked better okay so I think it's a
very important problem by the way this
happened mostly in the safe environment
because in h.323 there was a gatekeeper
because before we can start the call you
wait to ask for bad words from someone
it was not enforced but at least there
was the process of the application tried
to abide for you but the moment you
leave it open to them to decide whatever
they run they can do whatever they want
they don't wouldn't ask you what to do
then if they if they don't if they won't
care for what they network is about and
they can get over losses then why should
they care at all so I think it is
important to have some enforcement for
that what I think and maybe to have some
proactive condition comes to control
instead of the weighing whether to just
give them or lose it we even lose
packets or do something about it Victor
vasilia so few thoughts first many of
you might remember I think about a
decade ago BitTorrent decided that they
no longer want to use UDP and media
including I think major press raised
panic about BitTorrent switching to the
super aggressive congestion algorithm so
glad that and this is basically
continued this is kind of reminds me
because out of all
congestion control algorithms I seen
deployed in practice or even published
within last ten years all of them feel
buffers much less and Kubik task
case and in average case and we dis
includes videography one as I said when
Oh almost every iteration of PBR
everyone including the one with horrible
bugs where congestion control ran afoul
steel was had media and art et better
cubic the second thought is I don't
believe those gatekeepers ever existed
and I think a lot of people already
mentioned that well one if you look at
the congestion control algorithms in
linux kernel's there is a lot of them
and I'm not sure all of them are
rigorously tested and I mean even those
are regularly tested like TCP cubic had
an awful bug which just made it in
certain traffic just like basically
simulates slow start like semantics in
certain conditions and that Bach existed
for like ten years and we only found it
when we found similar bug in our quick
cubic so and I believe that the level of
gatekeeping is overstated and unfund
'mentally sockets with IP brought to you
GT existed for over 40 years and the
internist has not collapsed so that's
basically my sauce but I do agree that
if we deploy a QM or wisely this will be
better not because of I'm afraid of
collapse but because this would mean
people would be able to run a congestion
control algorithms that are more robust
to stochastic loss which is not induced
by themselves and that was one of the
problems that PBR tried to address a
special in version one and III see
that's a very important point I mean
that's point I should have made is that
the other big reason of deploying a so
they
between users is a basic unit enable
freedom of innovation for those users
and that's that's kind of the flip side
the story but if you know that yourself
then your you can try what is the best
for you you don't have to be compatible
with Kubik yeah
the thing about VBR versus T a cubic
competition is that I'm not sure how
well understood it is but it's extremely
parametric as you scale your TCP buffer
from like half BGP to ten BGP you will
see what either one or other
dramatically just suppress other's
traffic and that was a big problem with
PBR VLAN but it worked kind of fine
because most buffers were kind of in the
middle and PBR v2 a lot of heuristics to
make this work even better so we have
just peed a little bit up so if you
don't state anything that was stated
already that would be helpful
Andrew McGregor currently at fastly but
formerly an SRE at Google is hurrying a
system that did everything on that slide
and it's well documented well enough
documented to serve as a worked example
of how you might do this it's not the
own it's called bandwidth enforcer it's
not the only searchy that Google has
another one balanced enforcers for
Google to Google traffic the other one
which I'm not sure has a public name but
serves the similar purpose for traffic
facing the Internet
I'd like to point out that traffic out
of Google compute engine has to run the
gauntlet of both of them
and so it's so it's well controlled I
think any responsible CDN or cloud
provider is going to have an external
facing global on the siient congestion
controller or some sort because
otherwise your own mistakes you can take
out a large fraction in the internet and
all your customers with them it's safe
you go on the day we accidentally
globally booked deployed bbr to about 80
percent of the internal traffic
I know not supposed to say that but you
know I don't work and now it's in the
minute but we did that and the Kubek
traffic didn't stop
and that wasn't all bad one four four so
that was also partly just the fact that
they worked into out to be somewhat more
compatible and perhaps you know is
obviously the case hey Colin Perkins
with no hats
Ronnie mentioned RTP and video streaming
earlier I'm gonna be a little cynical
and probably get fired as chair of the
errand can't working group to saying
this but I don't think ITP congestion
control matters on the basis that by the
time you hit persistent congestion the
user has given up because the video is
unwatchable anyway I'm also tempted to
say that all the traffic is video anyway
the on/off dynamics of MPEG - completely
break congestion control well it doesn't
matter cause it's all application limits
it and all the large providers we have
monitoring in place to see if it's
causing problems that's it
I don't entirely disagree with you I
think and I think to the extent that
this is a problem it's a worse problem
that than we think in that everything is
moving too quick and quick encrypts
enough of the transport headers that we
have no visibility into where for this
is actually a problem on that you've
read
hi my name is David skinned Ozzy and I
used to be a gatekeeper so these days I
have this laptop and using it I can
check in code to Google quick and as you
say the kids with the magic of read
discs could break things last year on
the same time I had the same laptop that
Eric had which allowed me to check in
code checks and you and kind of the
actually now at Google we have tests
whereas there there weren't any so the
gatekeeper is probably better and Google
quick I mean I remember a really funny
bug where the apple kernel got into an
infinite loop and some connect cases
when you were doing TCP fest Oakland it
just happened that in that infinite loop
there was a call to send a packet out
there was a network in Switzerland that
was really unhappy with them for a while
yeah so on all your points about how
this is getting worse like I really
really disagree I saw some people pitch
some I personally think worse they call
companies telling now telling us that
hey look we make all your traffic faster
were when you look deeper was just a
thing that in the kernel disabled
congestion control that was in TCP that
said while I completely disagree with
your premise I fully support your
conclusion if you want to go around to
router manufacturers telling them ah the
world is about to end
please deploy it um continue that we
might be able to solve buffer bloat that
way I are not speaking as an employee of
Google or as a citizen Internet user in
Switzerland you actually as it turns out
of this slide back because I didn't do
anything except for a remind Christian
that he had to do slide so I have no
idea your name is on it I'm trying to
name name being on it
I agree actually that there is a little
bit of a problem I think it's maybe a
slightly different problem I want to go
back to something that some other Google
guy said maybe Matt I think yeah I think
it was not I think to some extent the
[Music]
security and reliability here or flip
sides are the same thing they're all
essentially transmission safety problems
and the work that has been done to
in some networks isolate users or
isolate processes from each other or to
isolate good traffic from evil DDoS
traffic is all kind of the same work to
the extent that putting better aqm in
the internet makes that work better it's
a good thing to do on its you know
anyway I will say as a former researcher
who spent a fair amount of time trying
to get cloud platforms to throw packets
at things as fast as I possibly could
all of the ones that I did did seem to
have some sort of outbound and with
policing and I'm I suspect that almost
all of it was there for abuse so the
nice thing about you know the abuse role
of internet that we have is that the
defenses that we need in order to keep
it working minimally well also seem to
be pretty good gatekeepers against
congestion collapse yeah Thanks thank
you well thank you for your attention I
I accept them in the point that we have
many more defenses today then people
would think and it's great I accept that
it will be very hard to do something
more aggressive to the intelligence
should be cubic as we know that and so
that we should not panic but we should
do isolation because it's a good thing
yeah okay that was less depressing than
I thought - more fun we have one more
Top Ramen are you on I think so here we
perfect yes you can start right away all
right great
so an object on queue lock quite quickly
for those who are not institute law yet
next slide please
so the main motivation is this we want
to help debug quick implementations it's
difficult to make this kind of
visualization and tools just using
packet capture files because they don't
contain things like ingest control
information so skip the next slides and
then go to next slide the next one so
what we proposed to help that will make
tooling development much easier if
everybody would just pretty the same
time flung of course
we call q log it's a relatively simple
scheme based on JSON because we want to
make web-based tools and we wanted to be
human readable for people not using
house tools and so skip the next slide
and so we presented that at the end of
last year and the bid is a surprise to
me a lot of people seemed quite
enthusiastic about that a lot of people
had some interests among those was media
and she said why would you do this just
for quick and hp3 why can't we do this
for more than those protocols and so I
got the chance to present some of our
talks on that last time at IETF in
Prague a couple of months ago again a
lot of people seemed interested but it
was deemed a bit too early to talk about
doing maybe above for a working group we
should get some more experience using
quick as a kind of an incubator to get
some more insights and so that's what we
left it off last time and so we have
been doing that since so next slide
please
what we clearly have is two different
drafts two documents one that we're
calling the high level schema which is
basically the protocol agnostic to
general purpose part of what we're doing
and then the other draft is a quick
specific stuff the second one is very
easy to understand right quick has
packets it has it has packet numbers it
has stream frames that have lengths and
offsets it's basically us going through
the quick documents and copying over
things into into a JSON format it's very
long and it's very boring the left one
is a bit more interesting next slide you
can see it is kind of the metadata that
helps you interpret the offense on the
right side so the simplest form is that
is that we have like a title and a
description of the current file but the
most important field there is the
protocol type as you can see if that is
the current values quickest betray that
means the offense in that part of the
file or from the other document but so
if we would expand this to more
protocols next slide we would change the
value of the field and suddenly you
which you would have for example tcp of
hb2
of course first kind of the high level
approach which taken out to still have
something protocol agnostic while
working on a quick specific thing I'm
going to give it a little bit more
detail on that just some examples next
slide so in the high-level schema for
example some people were worried about
the overhead of JSON so we have some
file size optimizations that you can
skip loading the same value in the same
file multiple times we also like to make
this very flexible so for example we've
already with Facebook they feel that
they have a lot of custom events
specific to their implementation we
support that they can also walk those
without a specific schema the bottom one
is I think one of the most interesting
things is that we want to do an
end-to-end lock so you have not just
client and server but you also have
several in-network intermediaries that
you want to log if you do that with
pcaps you would probably end up with
four individual files without much
context and it would be difficult to
bundle them together so one of the
things that Q log does is allow you to
aggregate different traces into the same
queue log file and then provide some
context so for example here we have the
fantage point saying from which point of
view was this trace taken this can also
allow us to add different protocols into
the same file for example let's say you
have an h3 to a Mississippi it needs to
be to implementation
you would have a CP to traces from a
user space implementation and then TCP
level traces maybe from the kernel and
you could combine them in the same file
to nicely keep everything together next
slide we have other things that make you
really want to keep things in one file
so we talked to for example China
Iyengar from fastly and he said you know
we're probably gonna have talents of
queue logs and we're mostly interested
in for example the ones that have a high
packet loss rate and so what we have now
is like a summary field on top that that
has some aggregate information for this
file so you can very quickly just sift
through all these files without having
to download them in full to find the
ones that you're looking for the second
thing is again with the tools
if you're loaded this you're probably
going to zoom in on this particular
section you're gonna filter some stuff
or you're going to change the colors if
you don't want to share that with a
colleague you would have to take a
screenshot right now right so instead of
doing that we say let's just embed those
settings into the Q log file as well so
you can just share the adjusted Q log
file with the colleague they can open it
up in the same tool and view the exact
same data that you were looking at
before so there's just a couple of
examples of what is in the high-level
schema next slide in terms of the event
definition we currently have about 50 40
events I think it will be about twice
that by the end some of the most
important ones I think of course the
ones that are not in the typical packet
capture so the things related to
congestion control or when packets were
lost that kind of stuff but of course
next to that we also log your typical
packet Racing type events next slide so
for example we have of course a typical
packet received offence where you just
log the received quick packet with each
constituent frames for example here
there's an ACK frame being logged this
iframe is aking packets four to seven
using this we kind of notice that it's
not enough in all use cases for example
we had this case where we clearly saw
the acknowledgement frame coming in and
after that it was still logging a packet
lost for one of the just act packets
right which is very weird that should
never happen and we found out that it
was agony realization where we parse the
AG frames but we don't immediately
process them so there was kind of a long
time in between those two sometimes and
it was time enough for the loss events
himer so you come in and declare the
packet lost even though the AG frame
just wasn't processed so the only way to
really solve that next slide is to add
yet another defense more explicit events
specifically for packet acknowledgments
because those
receipt of the egg frame and the package
acknowledged might not be directly
correlated so this one example I
recently did an order to talk with a lot
more information which you can find in
the youtube link on the bottom of slide
so as you can see we've made a lot of
progress on the text I'm happy to say we
also made some implementation progress
next slide we currently have five
different quick stacks that are
outputting Q Lord directly what I forgot
to say what last slide is you might end
up with 80-plus events but I do not
expect everybody to implement those
eight events most people will probably
have enough with about 20 of those
events and so a lot of these tools are
outputting Q log but they're definitely
not outputting every possibility like
events they're outputting the the main
basic set that is supported by our
current tools those tools are not
current really extensive right now we
mainly have one that is being used a lot
is when you're seeing it's for people in
congestion control memory but we are
working very hard on new tools I'm
working full time on new tools that will
come out over the course of August and
September so expect to see a loft
movement in that space next life is so
the nice thing about having other people
look at this is that we've been getting
some feedback from other implementers it
seems that for a lot of people the
overhead actually is quite okay Facebook
reports that they're logging 20 billion
quick events per day I don't think
they're actually logging Q log events at
that scale yet but it's nice to know
that it's possible that it's a possible
way forward someone mentioned that they
would like to use Q log as a way to
implement tests so instead of augmenting
the code with unit testing they can just
look at what was happening in the NICU
log and try to devise test failed or
succeeded that way which i think is a
very interesting use case and then the
the last sentence there was very
interesting for me because when we
started this I asked people
why isn't anybody doing this yet why
doesn't this exist and a lot of people
said well it's a lot of work and we
don't really have the map
next slide so I think you what really
helps take away a bit of that overhead
in terms of work we recently did some
some work on sp3 prioritization so in
this the top visualization each row is
an individual Q log file one web page
load so each vertical rectangle is one
quick packet and I really like this
visualization because it immediately
makes clear the differences between
different prioritization approaches
right
and yet it only took me about a day to
create this visualization based on the Q
log formats so it's a lot of profit for
not a lot of work the bottom one is even
faster this was implemented by one of
our pageant students in about two hours
and really helped us to debug the
prioritization implementation as we were
going so I really like that Q log
enables this kind of quick and dirty
fast visualization that helps implement
one of the some of the complex systems
as well so we've got a lot of good
feedback we've also got a lot of what I
would call constructive feedback next
slide so there are also people that say
that there is some overhead I'm a bit
ashamed to admit that our own
implementation gets very slow if we
enable all the queue logging but that's
because we're using javascript and a
very crappy logging framework but still
there is a cost some people still don't
like json some people their
implementations aren't fit to output
queue long as we have it right now and
then one of the most important ones is
the one at the bottom is even besides
the possible performance of red there is
also a certain maintenance burden in
adding this morning now something
changes in quick you don't just need to
update your business logic you also need
to update your logging code and so they
would rather wait until things settle
down a bit I think that's quite ironic
coming from people implementing quick
write but it's still a very good point
to make so next slide we've seen that a
lot of stacks that have these
reservations right now still are trying
to move towards key log they mainly do
that by using what
calling converters so they have some
kind of an internal watering format they
write a small program that transformed
it into Q log so that they can use the
tools this works just fine I think it's
a good approach I think it's a nice way
to eventually maybe get the browser I
put into a cute or compatible form as
well because I don't think they might
want to implement you log directly but I
am a bit worried about the maintenance
burden for these converters down to one
so that's about what I had to say next
slide of course I'm a bit biased but I'm
very happy but what we've been able to
do in Korea knew we were going I'm very
happy with old support from the
community
thank you everyone has been great
however next slide there remains some
serious open questions the one of the
major feedbacks from last time was that
we need to think about privacy and
security sadly that is one of the areas
that has you know will last the least
amount of progress since then one
because I'm not an expert on that until
because we haven't really had a lot of
feedback on that so if you have opinions
on that and ways that we can integrate
this into the format please let us know
and then it seems like this is working
quite well for quick but it doesn't mean
that it might work well for other
protocols as well so that's maybe a
discussion we still need to have next
and last slide so maybe we don't have to
have all these discussions right now we
also don't have time so please join us
on github we also have a brand new Q log
mailing lists thank you for that Maria
I'm also planning on landing launching
the quick tools of info website which is
going to gather all the liquid cooling
that exists not just ours but everything
that other people have made as well to
work as kind of a central hub if you
want to go further in and that feel free
to add Q log not just your quick stack
it would be fantastic to have someone
try to do this for other protocols as
well if you're able to do that and of
course we should be surely the only ones
making open-source visualization tools
feel free to do
finally I don't know what people want in
terms of next steps is this something
that should be a working group above or
not at all please let me know so thank
you thanks a lot we take a few short
questions to say sorry I've not had time
to make the Google quick tracing
compatible appeal we're working on but
they still have time I wanted to know
about extension from quick to other
protocol from our old very old logging
format was designed to be compatible
with TCP and quick and it didn't make
anyone happy nicer TCP nor quick people
because it turns out that while
protocols are similar in some level
they're also substantially different in
many important ways just wanted to note
that but this is really more Thank You
Jana Inger thank you so much for your
work this is super super cool
and I'm glad that you put this summery
stuff in you've got every clackety
keyboard it's lovely
we have a note-taker here so so the the
mini all this is is is it's great to see
you continuing to do work on this and I
will be soon starting to work on on
integrating quickly with Q log as well
so I hope to be engaging with you on
that soon in terms of the question of
both working group etc I honestly think
that the work as it's going along is is
is great I think that there should be
just more iterations on on how want
people integrating and then as people
start using traces which hopefully will
happen as people started do more
performance testing
which again we are trying to get the
quick implementers to do more
performance testing shortly that that
there will be evolution at that point
and I think there's an organic
engagement that's happening right now
that is wonderful I don't think that
formalizing this in any other way is
necessary at this point because I'm also
not sure what the outcome of such a
process would be but those are my
thoughts I was just gonna say in thanks
again but you should be showing up here
well if you can find us my flight next
see we can do about Singapore Robin
thank you for this thank you for giving
the talk at 11:00 p.m.
I'm like as somebody who like really
encouraged you to bring this forward I'm
kind of shocked and amazed at how far
this has come in one meaning cycle this
is really really cool I will reiterate
what Johnny said given the amount of
progress that's going on sort of on the
code naturally I would I would the next
step sure keep keep on keeping on making
it better as a tool set will we'll come
back and backfill the how can we
generalize this to sort of like
transport development logging stuff
later I actually had a question about
about privacy and security stuff but
since we're kind of short on time I will
take that offline for you again thank
you very much I'm I'm kind of shocked
and appalled at how awesome this is
thank you very much Robin unfortunately
we will close this meeting with a sad
news Sally Floyd is in the hospital and
many people in this room knew her very
well I guess um so we will ask you to
come to the front and take a picture for
her and we will send it to her as memory
thank you
some light I guess maybe over there
[Music]