we starting there but now are we okay
and
this is going to be the TSB WG working
group please don't leave if you think
you want to know the group because this
group will be good and fun can you hear
me I found an on button yeah okay I can
walk around with this we are organizing
the second of the TSV WG meeting
thoughts is the transport area working
group we have an agenda uploaded we have
a note-taker over here and a backup
note-taker is perhaps okay we have a
primary note-taker that's okay we will
need a jap ascribe partly because one of
our working group chairs your notice is
not here so could somebody volunteers a
jabber scribe place over there Chris
[Music]
okay um David do you want to see if your
mic works
okay so we'll talk about the agenda here
briefly here's the note well reminder we
have three three major items for the
agenda today we're going to start with
the elf 4's drafts of looking at Gogol
this meeting is to figure out where we
are in terms of readiness of those
drafts working group last call there'll
be a number of presentations here the
what's what's on the slide may not be
exactly what we do in terms of slide
decks although Bob wins a prize because
he's he's almost first up
and let's see the just-in-time
psychometric I think was under ten
minutes this time the some congestion
experienced is second major item we do
today and then we are going to try to
leave some time down at the end for
discussion of some proposed new work on
DC CP multipath as we get started here
we're going to explain exactly what
we're going to do on how we're going to
conduct the l4s discussion anybody want
to bash the agenda we will be enforcing
some cut-offs in particular I'm quite
certain we could spend this entire
session and probably until four o'clock
today discussing everything there is
about l4s that's not going to happen
there will be there will be a time cut
off and apologize in advance to people
who are going to get cut off at the mic
lines based on what I think is about
what what we think is about to happen
but we are going to make sure that there
is time for for the SCE presentation
today and we are hoping to get to DC CDC
CP multipath you'll see this man is
david black in case you don't know him
and I'm Gauri Fairhurst where's Eddy as
we said his remote
mmm-hmm just when I need them it's not
going 40 yeah that's okay ma'am
fortunately we got to the prom Pierre is
serious
you're the manager good does anybody
know them thought that the magic opening
me open a new tab sequence on a
Chromebook all right control what
control T control tenant guard let's try
that I can start anyway counter okay I
shall tell you a little bit how we're
going to run the l4s part of the
discussion today the this part we'll
start with a quick review of the an IP
our discussion that we've seen on the
list I shall say before I said before
anything else is said this is what the
chassis of the IP are staring down at
the mailing list if you have IPR
concerns please read the IP are
associated with the documents in the
tracker and please consult people who
understand IPR concerning the way in
which you view IPR we will not make a
determination but we would like to
summarize I'm just summarizing which me
after summarizing Bob will present the
current status of the drafts which have
been asked to go to Wickham group last
call these drafts were brought to the
working group I think in 2016 in Buenos
Aires if you remember rhinoceros and
they were adopted in Prague
so what No thank you for the detail
adopts in Prague and now we consider
that it might be an appropriate time for
this working group to ask are these
documents ready for a working group last
call we need to have a working written
last call to judge consensus we do have
a working group last call to judge
technical issues only when the documents
were complete a working group last call
when we consider progressing them and
documents can go through multiple
working group last calls or simply
returned to the working group after that
process so in no way just this terminate
the process but it's the beginning of
the end of a
or perhaps at least the end of the
beginning
absolutely okay so there's been some
recent discussion on the list and
offline about IP our discussion I'm
going to quick summarize that but I
first need to put in disclaimer
you're looking up chairs are not lawyers
this slide deck does not contain legal
advice if you want legal advice you need
to talk to a lawyer your chair is the
ietf disclaim all responsibility for any
legal consequences of using the
information this slot in in in these
slides to make decisions that involve
legal matters okay hang on it should be
okay no idea but I hit the right button
here also works okay so the history our
discussion is a toka raised concerns
over some defensive suspension clauses
in the Alcatel Lucent IP IP IPR
declarations broad conditions was
unclear whether the declarations
superseded the previous IPA and terms in
a previous IPR note this isn't resolved
both when the apparently still apply we
summarized discussion that was on the
list you'll need to go for the details
there's a link in the slide deck we can
go find that the terms that we saw in
those IPR declarations we're similar to
terms that we've seen in other IETF IPR
declarations that's not a statement
about good bad right or wrong it's
simply a factual statement that there is
similarity okay
relationship of IPR
to the draft the 8 qm couple dual q--
draft is a framework for coupling a QMS
with nan-oh
imitation appendixes Bob Brisco who's
been have an involvement posted his
analysis the list quote he quoted extra
exhibitor from that is the claims cut
all cover non-essential and
non-preferred aspects of a QM dual Q
coupled we've got a list here I'll turn
it up a cake of a tournament ations of
Aiken dual Q coupled you can find a pie
- and a pen describing pendeks a of the
draft curvy red described in Appendix B
with there's been discussion the working
group that's made it pretty clear that
FQ could be used to do this and there
may be others all this is just me
provided as as information every
participant needs to make up their own
mind about applicability or lack thereof
of the patents to the drafts we're
talking about and level of concern to be
placed on the IPR the contents of the
IPR notices in alcatel-lucent any
questions oh I love seeing empty Micra
lines after legal nonsense okay with
that I think Bob is up Bob okay you need
to think about how let's see how many
slides do you have here 21 okay yeah
please please please be please make good
use of time because yes we need all the
background but we really we need to
spend the time on discussion yep okay
yeah it's about this redraw should work
we think try that never worked bingo
right
so I'm gonna take a bit longer to
explain
l4s background because the sort of heat
around this debate may have encouraged
some other people to get interested so
the motivation for l4s is ultra low
queuing delay for all internet
applications with the emphasis on all
the idea being that by changing TCP
that's the problem so it includes
capacity seeking and the sort of
performance we can get is something like
100 200 microseconds over the Internet
at the median COO delay as you see there
a 50 this plot is a plot of Q delay on
the horizontal axis in milliseconds if
you can't see that and log of the
percentile on the vertical scale it's
called a cumulative log cumulative
distribution function and the tail is
important this is the real message for
this slide that for particularly
real-time delivery you need the higher
percentiles to not have high delay
otherwise most real-time software will
buffer enough to be able to pick up that
tail and so getting the tail down to in
this case 8 milliseconds at the five
nines percentile is important probably
wouldn't buffer to five nines you'd
probably buffer to three nines or to
nine something like that and and just
lose the rest
the other interesting thing that's
important at this slide is well there
two more interesting things firstly this
is with really hammering the link it's
in there's two queues here and it's
there's 300 web sessions per second
hitting this link on in each queue so
600 web sessions for a second with a
range of flow file sizes and all the
rest of it details are all where I'm
looking to read them out
and the other main point is that it is
data center TTP or what's now called TCP
Prague but this was done with the data
since TCP that gives you the benefit
it's really the end system that gives
you the benefit not the queue all the
queue has to do is have a ACN marking
threshold for the N system to bounce off
if you like and as you can see that it's
the blue one is there is the one from
David sense DCP so it's about an order
of magnitude at every percentile and
that's the trick it's because it's got
smaller sorties so you can have both
lower delay in the queue let's parents
in the queue and still full utilization
right moving on to coexistence which is
going to be a theme throughout the the
problem is that because of those smaller
sore teeth it's more aggressive and so
one solution is to use the dual queued
couple they um and that allows you to do
this without flow inspection if it has
two queues and they're coupled together
in such a way that there's a squaring in
the congestion coupling that means that
the l4s marking is more aggressive to
counterbalance the more aggressive
congestion control you can see the P
versus one of the P sort of get the
laser pointer which I guess also I don't
know which one to point that I'll point
of this one the P versus P squared there
and then one over P versus root P right
next the where buried this in to the
slide deck it's always been possible and
that is to use an FQ system for
coexistence to solve the coexistence
problem so if Q X X X where X X X might
be coddled pi whatever so if you want to
do l4 s at an F Q X X X system it's a
simple patch put FEC t1 mark with a
shallow threshold
Aram Eric the demos a put this code into
Mecca Caudill quite early on and then
you you base your marking on the
immediate cue not on the stateful thing
that's going on in Caudill or pie or
whatever that's for the classic traffic
Eric Eric by the way didn't didn't do it
on FEC t1 he did it just on a PCT but
it's a simple thing to do it just based
on east t1 i'm web added a description
of that into the offerors architecture
document right so that's the end of the
recap implementation status gradually
getting more and more implementations
the transport protocols I'm not going to
read this all out you can read it in
your own time just highlight that VBR b2
has been added to that as well as and
TCP progress being updated I'm gonna
give more detail on that by the way you
gave me 15 minutes and five minutes and
the five minutes is sort of been
subsumed in these slides if you like
yeah in addition we we we got through
our piece faster so I'm going there's
some components of the transports that
are generic across them all and can be
used our things particularly all note
there we've now got a freebsd version of
echo ECM from Richard J Omega an ongoing
work on the start up with paste chirping
and also a lot of progress on stuff like
a window or come up to that progress in
the cable industry on chipset
implementations for cable modems and see
MTS's with talk of products later this
year in this will often time frame
the Chilkoot couple back here and we're
trying to get that into the mainline of
Linux it's been submitted once and going
for again very shortly hopefully and the
Linux patch for fq l 4 SF q code like
that not going to go through this this
is just a list of links so you can find
the code for those things from the
previous slide that are open-source
they're not all open source on the
previous slide and that there's a link
no there isn't
I'll come to that there's a home page
Angra right
just a brief report back on the
hackathon L sorry Andrew I just wanted
to ask are you aware of anybody working
on putting off for air support in to be
special Q disk that is used bottom level
of the lummix Wi-Fi stack you'll need to
get close for the mic sorry Andrew but
Gregor are you aware of anyone working
on putting l4s support into the special
cutest that lives at the bottom of the
Linux Wi-Fi stack because you can't put
a normal Q disk on a Wi-Fi interface and
Linux anymore I'm not aware of anyone
doing that yet I'm not sure ahead time
and I'm and I'm pretty sure that the
other person what the other of the four
or five people who could do it who's
sitting in the room doesn't hit Tiny Tim
okay you're not coming for Mike okay so
report from the hackathon Koon brought a
test bed over from on the fly and also
the SCE team brought their test bed over
we put the two together so the big
highlight of this hackathon was two
teams working together on this in in a
professional way I should add
thank you very much right and managed to
get some Flint regression tests done
that is running regression tests on
tests that Jonathan specified to see
whether putting our press in there made
any difference
and as far as we got it didn't make any
difference that is our first didn't make
any difference
so that's having up an elf Ross node
before and after you coddle no than the
embarrass orders but a lot of problems
with the limits colonel during that
hackathon I won't go into any more
details due to lack of time as I said
Richard chef Feniger did a freebsd a
korean ecn implementation michael I
should add was not involved in the
implementation he was there as the sort
of gatekeeper of FreeBSD to make sure
all Richardson do anything silly and we
had our first accuracy and interrupt
over the internet between Linux and
FreeBSD so two working together they
both had the same bugs that personally
makes them easier to fix precisely they
both got bored reading this back at the
same point still work talk about the
supply cat window and also paste
chirping was integrated into the ns3
implementation that's still not open but
hopefully very shortly but I have said
that before right you wanted a bit more
detail on TCP probe pieces this is an
update of a slide I presented at ICC RG
in March there's a few differences on it
but the main thing I want to highlight
is obviously that TCP Prague column but
this also shows that some parts of it or
quite a few parts of it the majority of
parts of it are actually in base TCP not
in the congestion control module and
it's sort of reusing parts that people
are doing for other things
I guess the the obvious thing to
that people focus on is the stuff that
isn't green and we have now got a
working implementation of scaling down
to a window below 2 and below 1 and if
that got 2.2 of a packet so facing down
over five round-trip times and this is
going at 300 micro second round trip
time so that you can actually not just
build up a queue in order to do that
that's more per datacenter work and been
talking more about our ttv independence
but haven't done any more on it and in
terms of implementation then the big
open issue which i'm going to talk about
is reno friendly if there's a classic
ATM bottleneck I've got a slide on that
right couple of slides on recent
developments the dual PI squared
implementation has largely been
unchanged for quite a quite years now
but we've been changing the scheduler
over to weighted round robin and also
we've put a management shim if you like
on top of the parameters so that you can
put in to human Rieman understandable
parameters the typical round-trip time
the max round-trip time and it will
calculate all the sort of proportional
integral controller parameters for you
and the maths is in the internet draft
on how it does that in pseudocode but i
should emphasize that for the internet
it's zero config you know this is for if
you you were having to reconfigure it
for some different scenario but the
defaults work just fine for the internet
ii recent development all the other
stuff going on is posted a new draft
documenting the docs askew protection
function that's not intended for
consensus at the ITF it's just
saying what DOCSIS did so that it's
openly available in the ITF and the
emboldened phrase there is the most
important bit there's an objective
definition of what your flow behavior
has to be in order to avoid being
rejected as you go into a doctor's link
so how what's the sort of maximum
aggression that you can still get into
the low latency queue so just to
emphasize it's not one of the core of
elf race drafts it's not even on a tspwd
jar draft you'll probably go into the
independent stream mullet it's it's been
accepted but it's in the cube and the
the overload protection that's in the
dual queue draft would be a sufficient
alternative but it's this is this is
perf la vie queue protection function so
it kicks out particularly it will be how
you flows but you have got a sort of
bulk overload protection as a basis and
it's really I guess part of the l4s
experiment to see whether it's necessary
to have per flow protection much as I
suppose you could say the internet
experiment has determined whether we
need per flow rate control for the
voluntary compliance with TCP
friendliness you know it sort of that
has determined that we don't really need
per flow rate control the el Faro's
experiment will determine whether we
need purp low latency protection or not
or whether the inherent incentives for
yourself are sufficient - you don't want
to run your own latency but this is
obviously more for accidents and malice
right I won't go into how the algorithm
works because we're short of time
because I want to get on to these issues
a little bit of history about the number
one open issue I believe actually 3168
ecn in a FIFO so if you have an a QM
that behave
like I've said that obviously 3168 says
and you're in a share Q and D see TCP or
TCP Prague or quick Prague or whatever
competes with existing TCP friendly
traffic is the world going to collapse
and history of this we we chose the UC
t1 code point back in 2016 knowing full
well this could be a problem thinking
that it may not be a problem because all
the academic studies that showed that
there was no deployment of such readers
or we thought they showed that then in
fact only a few months later
Padma boomer Apple did a study published
a study in mapache which the slide the
black part of the slide there shows
where there was C on the Internet at the
time sort of dismissed it is probably fq
coddle but the the controversy around
this as made us think well yeah actually
that is not a very scientific assumption
we ought to check that so sort of the
greys have not come out on this there's
dark gray and light gray on this but
there might only come out on though yep
so as I said what if that assumption is
unsound and really we're currently at an
uncertain state in the in the left hand
bubble where there are a couple of CD
ends who are doing testing looking for
these these CES they have been found I'm
not gonna identify here they are I
didn't actually ask whether it was okay
to identify who they are but I'm not
going to say
I'm also not sure whether even when they
get results they'll be able to tell us
or even you know tell anyone but but but
unfortunately layer thirteen comes after
layer or you know you have to get
results before the lawyers alas accept
questions on whether you're allowed to
release them and so we have devised and
test on how to look for these these
raters once we get the results of the
tests if we get the results so that's
that's the sort of ground truth side of
it what is on the internet at the moment
then there's so that's more like
prevalence and then the quantify flowing
balance is more like their harm in other
words the risk is a combination of how
much of it is there and how harmful is
it when it is there and so the next side
we've got some measurements on how
harmful it would be when these flows
join each other in a single cue Jake I J
:
I just wanted to self-identify Akamai
has been running a few tests with me
seein on the internet and we have
observed EC ease in the while we are not
sure where they're coming from
it's we're still looking at it I hope
maybe one day if I have to have to to
present something in my party about it
but we have not proceeded to that point
yet thank you yep so Jake it's bit hard
to hear up here but you're saying that
you see some easy unmarked traffic yes
obviously we so we've seen specifically
what I was looking for on the download
was echo the echo response right so we
are we have some production traffic
being served with ecn enabled and on
those devices that we put up I was
looking to replicate the the Apple
results with Argentina and France it's
hard to tell whether flows that do not
see an ECE are uncongested or don't have
an AQ m and path but we do see all of
the servers that we put up
some wild eazy-e mercs Thank You rod
crimes if there are any operators or
other people in the floor that could
help Bob or myself get some of this data
we are both very interested in that and
I'm just reaching out to if anybody
knows any place that would be willing to
help collect some of this it's very
valuable
yeah and actually the other CDN did do
some thinking well actually I think I
can say this because the yeah there is
some other day to hear from apples
original study and that Argentine
Republic 30% CE Marking by the way
that's 30% of devices so at least once
the e mark in 12 hours that's not 30%
marking right but they did do some
digging into that and identified the ice
be involved and we are trying to get
hold of the people to to see where
whether that is like a fq caudal
deployment or you know or whatever it is
and similarly the reason we're going for
CD ends is we're looking for what it's
more likely that single q ATMs are in
the downstream whereas fq coal more like
to be in the upstream however cake is
also in the downstream at the other end
of the access link pinching off the
access and that would be caught
potentially causing c e and echoes back
that jake may be seeing that you know we
don't know where these seas are coming
from so there's all the way to be done
and just before I go for the next slide
about the level of harmless would cause
the idea of this is that once you've got
the prevalence and let the level of harm
you've got an assessment of the risk and
so I'm sort of laying out a process that
we're then got a spread of possible
scenarios if there's a high risk then
definitely well put some code into you
know the
all the star Prague l4s code to try and
measure this and it's going to be
difficult we'll get false negatives and
positives in the worst way you know it's
just transfer what when you say there's
a risk and you need new code is that a
change to the three specs which are on
the table or is that a future spec for
the transport the specs currently assume
the high-risk case yes but we haven't
thrown it in the code okay that seems a
reasonable experiment to go forward
Korea if we don't find much and the harm
if it were found or if it were added in
the future to the Internet is relatively
low then possibly sufficient would be to
put advice in the l4s drafts to say do
not or limit this experiment over your
network eg bigot by disabling on CDN
ports that are going into your network
do not put our l4s traffic from a CDN
into your network particularly if you're
sorry I'm the end of that sentence is if
you know you've got you've deployed also
see 3168 ATMs in your network obviously
if they're it's cake and fq coddled
that's going to be safe because they're
in per flow queues so they're not gonna
I've run them right so these are the
results we've got for a range of link
rates along the bottom for 200 Meg and
within each link rate a range of
round-trip times for the unfairness
between DC TCP an ETA and cubic in the
dual pie
it says the dual pie squared l fresh but
they're both in the PI squared IQ and
they're poked in as if it's a classic a
queuing they're not using the L key we
mark the VC TCP traffic with these two
zeros put it in the other kit so the
worst case there is about something like
that
one that was not very useful yeah I
pressed the wrong button the worst goes
there between that one and that one I
think is about 20 but in most cases it's
about 10 along here and it gets the the
sort of good news if there is any good
news in this slide is that in a severely
congested environment I get closer to
5050 at lolling rates and low entry at
times so let you digest that in your own
time
I should add I put on the list this
morning a copy of a paper we're
preparing for a journal with a whole
load of performance measurements for l4s
across all these linked rates and
round-trip times and with different
traffic models with different congestion
controls and all the rest of it and I
sort of attached it to the end of a
paper so that the because the paper
describes all the experimental scenarios
and the original paper just had a
selection of the plots but what we've
done we've put all the plots just stuff
them on the end of the paper so you you
know we can't be accused of selecting
results if you like me whereas when you
put in a journal paper of course you can
select results and I'd like to see
results like that so we always show not
just queue delay we show utilization
queue delay drop rate fairness etc etc
because you can always focus on the good
part of any one experiment okay so
there's the less loss detection issue
which is a particularly if you do finish
up in the next five minutes that we
couldn't pick there I think at least
discussion submission which you probably
ought to go to the main discussion as
opposed to be done done while you're up
here with slides I would I represent
what what your view is
we'll pick up again I'll just search
clean yeah
so there are objections to this
requirement that an L press source also
has to measure or detect loss in units
of time and at the moment it's a must we
have discussed a way to change the
ordering switch to change the wording
there there are three real objections to
this same requirement one is
particularly David's objection that it
could be interpreted as a prohibition of
using three view back in an environment
where you don't need to do this anyway
because you've got a a link technology
that doesn't reorder stuff and so I'm
sure we can deal with that with wording
the other is a architectural concern
that it overloads one code point with
two meanings and those two meanings
being low queuing that I am loath
resequencing delay and then really the
the augment against that I would make is
that yes that is strictly two different
meanings but they're both low delay and
what would be the value of finding two
identifiers for those things you know
it's sort of worth conflating them and I
put a bit of discussion on the list
about the the possibility you might ever
have a case where you wanted one and not
the other that you know if you were
short of memory for the resequencing or
something like that and and that
discussion I'm sure might continue and
then there's an objection primarily from
Michael Schaff that one experiment
shouldn't depend on another and the
underlying concern here is to avoid
having a potentially successful
experiment depending on a potentially
failed experiment and bringing down me
the dependent one
that's not such a concern here because
if RAC files and that's unlikely given
it's widely deployed already this aspect
of l4s can be relaxed Alvarez doesn't
like we depend on this requirement no
it's just we can we can relax that and
we can talk about that and also it's not
a dependency in a formal normative sense
is not a normative reference to the
right draft its dependency on the idea
behind rack so we are willing to
consider a shirred instead of a must of
this requirement and maybe warm what
would happen if you didn't do it and so
we can have that discussion Thanks
that's what is cooking it aside and then
just of not going to read all this this
is all the drafts that have been updated
in the last cycle and the new one the
queue protection 1 and then adopted one
in nsh so as you can see quite a lot of
ASCII writing going on as well as code
writing you might write your code in SQL
suppose just common we're short of time
but we're OK for time so ok so what I
think no I'd like to do is offer a bit
of time to talk about these drafts and
it's sometimes the case in the ITF that
the mailing list explodes with ideas and
thoughts about what we've been doing
just before working group last call and
it's sometimes that the mailing list
dies out and you can hardly trace what's
going on when we get to a working group
last call this case and quite a bit been
going on
so what let's use a little bit of time
to try and talk through the different
things and we made a list as chairs of
things that we thought we saw
and this may be a totally useless list
but we're going to show it anyway
because it may help some of the people
and if your comment directly matches one
of these or we want to come back to it
then please say so but generally let's
have a discussion about these drafts
particularly relating to whether there
are significant issues remaining or what
the things that should be clarified at
this stage before we hung on whether to
pass them to the working group last call
status so one who was going to be first
Jake your queue shorter going
Jake Holland I would add one item to
this list which I was thinking yeah yeah
I would add one item to this list which
is admission control for untrusted
marking on the admission control on the
classifier yep okay um the IQR
recommendations state this is research
currently a something that we should be
thinking about how to control floors not
obeying with the traffic contract there
the scheduler is expecting and what
would you suggest we do in this space we
have a a document that was put forward
by Bob which in its like that which I
very much appreciate which is revealing
what one of the operators is trying to
do right now but that's an information
on what they're doing do you think we
should be doing some working group work
on this there is an interesting question
i I I just would like to see it I don't
have an opinion on that at the at the
moment I just would like to see it added
to the list as a concern that has an
impact on the congestion control aspects
of this thank you noted thank you
Christian yeah it's something about the
evaluation of the l4s experiments okay I
have noticed that Bob slides
always present comparison of l4s against
cubic which is not designed to minimize
and 2 ND days I would very much like to
see comparison of l4s against delay
based congestion control algorithm such
as PBR presumably baby are the two of
them via the general idea is compared to
congestion control algorithms are
specifically designed to minimize delay
by opposition to those that are not and
this is Bob Brisco that is the question
if you try and compare with baby RV one
things like your rape fairness it's not
you that's problems its wake you for be
BRB to now to come out we can start to
be able to do that but that's why it's
not appear
Johnson Moulton I have to get very close
tonight because the chairs cut here okay
better okay
so I have four different topics to bring
up that closely related points a B F and
G yeah so um Jonathan Wharton okay so on
point F honestly eighty-one one states
that IETF approval is required for
experiments involving congestion
response differences and congestion
marking differences as these could
involve effective redefinitions of the C
II and ECT one code points in other
words I see 18 1 1 does not itself
modify our SVC what the six eight to
permit these behaviors itself for best
desires and point G on incremental
deployment this obviously requires
compatibility with our cc-16 8 compliant
a QMS this has not been demonstrated and
there are serious theoretical concerns
which we have validated by experiments
as of last night which of course speaks
to point a I was too gay to you on one
states very clearly that effective
congestion control is required with
coddle now being the most deployed aqm
the default parameters of code l and the
vertically low latencies that l4s
targets we found that within 10
millisecond RT t path a senior
related DCP Park flow would require four
seconds for cuddled on its default
parameters to reach a controlling
marking rate okay less is not active
cuddle appear cuddle yes this is the
caudal algorithm itself acting on a
single flow and if multiple l4s flows
were going through a single queue
controlled by cuddle then the time
required to reach the correct marking
rate would be similarly multiplied so
this is I just need to clarify are we
talking about widespread deployment of
cuddle without fur queue I'm talking
about widespread deployment of cuddle in
total I'm if we include fq canal then it
is extremely widely deployed now because
it's yes default in most Linux and Mac
OS 10 devices okay I think we can agree
that taking four seconds to control the
congestion induced by a 10 millisecond
RTT flow is not effective congestion
control now moving on to point B fair
queuing a QM is pretty robust by itself
introducing fair queuing would be
reasonably effective I think but there
is still a concern where you have two
consecutive bottlenecks as presently
occurs quite frequently when you have a
last mile link that's controlled by a
dump iPhone followed by a consumer
equipment box which is implementing fq
code L or something similar
and for my experiments we have found
that you can have quite a large delays
bike induced in the DOMA FIFO until the
the aqm downstream is able to control it
so again this comes back to our four
seconds to control it that's four
seconds of assistant queuing in the last
mile link it does sound like an FQ
Cottle may have issues that need to be
looked up hmm I think that's all I have
to talk about at the moment okay does
anybody have this can be a discussion
people can follow up if they wish but
yes next in line yes my name is Peter I
stood with the SD team also I'd like to
raise two concerns we have one is to
highlight topic II we have a strong
concern about using ECT one as a global
classifier RFC 2474 which is the DSC PRC
to section seven the Security section
talks about how dscp relies on its D s
domains for its security relies on
protection at the borders as well as the
integrity of the domain itself so with
with using ECT one as a global
classifier there are no domains so
that's we'd like to highlight that
concern okay and this consensus to use
this was agreed in Berlin in this group
we can look at it again okay and second
and finally is topic H regarding the
implementation status what we what we
didn't want to do is come in broadside
the team with results that they haven't
seen yet so we we won't do that but what
we will do is confirm that there are
issues on the five dead x-series kernels
of the current repo where TCP Prague is
overreacting to to seee marks and we saw
that in our in our test results
and we would also say that we want to
make sure that the current code base is
running on a five deck series of Colonel
and not 3.19 so that we can be testing
on a colonel that isn't isn't AOL so
that we feel that that's very important
for our testing and lastly we didn't get
too much to our interrupt testing but in
the next few weeks as l4s is reviewed we
hope to do that that's it that's all
okay David black speaking from the floor
as an individual as Bob sort of hinted
this concerns open issue number two
which on the slides is C and D and I'm
going to take a reverse board the whole
point of the single ends that I'm
definitely speaking as an individual on
this the whole point of the l4s
experiment is to go look at something
that is an experiment that you're met as
a whole and from what you've heard from
previous speakers the the the Q the
interaction between floats that all
forces is is trying to address can occur
in any Q anywhere in the Internet sir
netskope that experiment makes an
enormous amount of sense the
resequencing tolerance I have been
complaining about in this remark the
third IETF in a row where I continue to
complain about lumping that in it's been
hard to understand what's going on I
want to thank some of the folks on your
team for a little for helping enlighten
me a little more here what I believe is
going on there is that there are certain
linked technologies we are using RF
signaling particularly over wireless
where on a multi channel or multi bearer
link you get different loss rates
different bit error rates things like
FEC and retransmission come in and if
that hits the lanes asymmetrically well
then all of a sudden you've got a week
for this you've got a week for the slope
for the slowest Lane and there's a
resequencing buffer and
delays now if that understanding is
correct what's going on here this is not
an intranet wide problem it does not
happen in data centers we have
experience in my company in looking at a
center optical plant where we gave up
testing for bit error rates at 10 to the
minus 18 because the errors just weren't
happening there better things better
things to do with the equipment needless
to say the underlying cause of the
resequencing effect is not there in that
class of networks I believe what's going
on with the resequencing is it's not
internet right it's specific link
technologies in specific networks mostly
access networks and ought to be solved
with some kind of network specific
approach as opposed to lumping this into
one experiment at where where the goal
is going to be we're going to get
everybody than the Internet to adapt all
their endpoints to deal with these link
technology specific and network
technologies that are problems
I believe that latter approach is a
major mistake david topic was raised by
the chairs a number of previous things
saying if this is the intention then we
need cross error review before we can
proceed is just bob want to speak about
the text the text we talked about is in
appendix Bob do you want to clarify
whether the intention is to deal with
reordering or the reordering is a future
vision that can happen because you do
this the latter definitely and I also
want to make it clear that may from I've
heard David say this in number times and
maybe something just clicked in my head
as to something that David hasn't picked
up on that we're not we're what we're
saying is that when a link I think has
the capability and the possibility of
not doing resequencing on packet with
the identifier that
there4s not with packets from all n
systems is that understood
I understand that this is proposed as an
internet wide service that would
presumably be rolled out to and be of
interest to a large population of of n
systems yes I understand that Yuki you
can't get in trouble if you didn't set
the the code point that said that that
says says go ahead and resi go ahead go
ahead and omit resequencing but i still
believe that that this is that this
still has a major scope problem and it's
not same experiment ok because then
given given that relaxation is only four
packets with the ACP one code point the
relaxation for the links the resources
that this requirement is requiring to do
this loss detection in time have to be
modified in order to change their
congestion control to set the ECT one
anyway
so you know that's why we're said
there's an opportunity here to use a
time-based
lost detection which happens to be
deployed in across TCP versions now in
Windows vs the limits and all the rest
of it in rack so they're in it seems
like a good opportunity that that's the
rationale anyway and we can have the
discussion on the list maybe I think
you're I had to have a glass half empty
versus glass half full discussion I see
the opportunity I view it as an
opportunity for a separate experiment
not one that ought to be lumped into the
offerors experiment I concur with
David's view as chair that this is a
different experiment to the one we
originally charted and I'm not sure that
is required experiment that has to go
with this and if we do it then we must
go to interior and we must
then apparent the implications on
interior and dry so so we if do we need
to unpack this here as part of the
alchemist bundle and this is a thing we
should talk about today the the el
Faro's drafts just say the the source
should measure loss detection and detect
loss in time units doesn't say anything
about what links must do so that in that
sense it's not saying this is a link
experiment but it's saying that someone
else could do that experiment with l4s
traffic it's in our next to the speculum
does it need to be that it doesn't need
to be there no all it says at the moment
in the annex is that links could do this
it doesn't in any normative sense or
shirred or anything like they just as
they could all right I suspect part of
this is also will come up with time if
we see quick widely deployed with PT or
best detection and Reich widely deployed
that does time a base think we will
maybe see a general reduction of the
reordering requirement in the internet
but that is a philosophical debate about
what might happen in the future rather
than what has to be in the spec and and
the point here was to say if a link sees
a packet with the l4s identifier it
knows that it's got that behavior rather
than there's some fuzzier possibility
that it might have it unfortunately the
moment you seen knows you've wanted to
experiments together no no you haven't
you've just a we're not saying do that
experiment at all we're just saying
we're opening up the possibility for
someone else to do it later it's not
Jenks in line area are you on this topic
Jake okay okay I I'm not I'm not sure
there's much much much else much else to
add there I guess I think it as one
questions might give us part of that
Bob is that an X part and parcel of the
draft and hence the annex is
experimental because the drafts
experimental dirt or quasi annex
intended to have a different status with
respect to the rest of the graph well
the Alex is informative okay this is
just one possibility would make me
happier I'm still not satisfied what if
we pulled that annex and I think this
another couple of informative annexes
out of the that L fresh draft put them
in a second draft that is very clearly
marked as informative and that there
will be no normative reference from the
LS trap with out annexes to this new
informative draft I can I can take it
out completely yeah we don't have to say
that links could do this the issue is if
the issue is the issue is not so much
the links could do this it's the it's
the you have the transit the transport
protocol must have this behavior
participate in our government that that
that part is in the normative parts of
it and then in the annex it says what
limits could do if but but what I
suggested in the talk is we could make
that must into a sure I would suggest
you consider removing the paragraphs
resubmitting them if you want to later
but avoiding making any statement about
the reordering apart from what's
actually happens when you use l4s maybe
concerning the CEO whatever I don't that
bit is fine speculating the future in
that affects another area is a much
trickier thing to put in an exp draft
okay like to rethink this then because
there's a lot of people that really like
that aspect under a lot of people across
the idea who like that
and there a lot of people who also pray
maybe don't like it but this could be
the document that tests that if you wish
our advice is let's think carefully I
guess I guess I would characterize it as
there's a lot of people who like it
technically and there's a lot of
people who dislike it procedurally if
you think people like it write it in a
separate draft I think okay and back to
Jack oh yeah
so J holin this list is as I see it a
list of the technical considerations
I think there's and I I agree these are
you know the the more important aspect
of this there's one other sort of set of
issues that I would characterize as
editorial considerations I raised I
raised a point on the list recently so I
don't know if you want that in this list
also the list of potential issues with
regard to advancing the draft I you know
I I only have an individual hat and it's
I don't know whether I'm being too picky
but in terms of the sort of goals as
stated by the RFC editor in my opinion
there were some significant editorial
issues worth addressing before removing
the draft forward so I would also
request adding that to to the list
although I wouldn't it if you want that
Jerez separately as a non technical
issue that's fine okay Jake and let me
just be sure what you mean by editorial
do you mean that sections shouldn't be
in a particular order or text needs to
be corrected or do you mean that
sections should not be in a document
no I this refers more to word choice
characterization I can respond to that
and this is excellent feedback there's a
sad to think about ITF process that we
don't get people often sending those
comments in as the group of documents
progressed through the working group and
they're very much appreciated by the
authors on the chairs
what group must call it is exceedingly
good time to make sure that all
words that as good as we can make them
Irish see a litter will tidy up and
we'll fix but it's our job to get the
drafts as best prepared as possible so
yes please send those to the list well I
sent one section review to the list I
was waiting for some feedback it there's
been a lot of traffic on the list so I
understand there may be some delay I was
waiting for some feedback in and sort of
other opinions on whether this is a
useful contribution or whether there's
some sort of because I believe if I
continue on the path I have started it
will be quite a lot of feedback Pope's
getting to the mic hi Jay I suspect this
is one of the emails I've started and
not finished and I think I've sent to
you but I haven't but yeah I've accepted
and enough also said you don't need to
go through the rest of the draft
pointing out stuff I can do that that's
my job you know I've got the idea of
what you don't like yeah okay likewise
just because I don't like it doesn't
necessarily mean it you know it's a it's
a questionnaire consensus but I wanted
to raise the issues and I hope it's been
helpful would you would you rather I
said what you obviously don't want to
say that it's basically too high P so oh
yeah much hype in it you know yeah yeah
that's the general nature of the please
reduce the height or else either your
working group chairs will tell you to do
so or your ad will tell you to do so but
for sure it won't make its way through
the full process but but but this is
normal this is this is part of preparing
a document for actual standards okay
so any more questions
in that case I think it's time for a
helmet I get thrown put my working group
chair back a hat back on so got two more
ears to listen and judge please come and
join me because if we start asking
questions I want to know the answers
given first of all could you indicate to
me all right we have three drafts do we
have list of the three drafts somewhere
yeah we will we will be doing hums and
at least I'm gonna be down walking
around the floor to find listen so first
thing is I'd like lists of drafts up and
I'm going to ask who's read a the
current version or a recent version of
these three drafts that the three trusts
are listed here so let's go for l4s
architecture could you please raise your
hand if you had read this version or a
recent version of this document could
somebody tell me how many people got
Hansa it looks like a quite a large
number okay in more than twenty fifteen
to twenty okay right and guess what the
next month question is have you read the
l4s ID please raise your hand if you've
read the l4s ID slightly fewer than the
architecture maybe about fifteen okay
and the dual cue the Jill couple deck um
oh yeah okay so we have a maybe fifteen
to twenty there as well so the first
pronouncement from the chairs is that I
believe we have sufficient number of
people reading these documents that the
working group can know consider what
happens
oh just me and where's
could comment if he needs to just remind
it to wises the document Shepard
where's does want to comment that's good
I yeah one of the things I noticed is
that we had ten cottages and we way were
maybe one more very clear extra one and
a couple of ones that I think are
probably sub-bullets under the testing
issues but the one thing I actually
noticed I was keeping a score and no one
brought up a topic J which was the IPR
we want to do we want to assume that
things are better with that now or not
whereas this is David I think some of
the IPR cephalo needs me so may need
some soak time so let's let's hope that
this is a sign that it will that it will
not be playing a leading role in the
future there's people at the might you
know broad crimes I believe the people
that would like to speak to that issue
on the IPR are not present and will
probably speak on the list is that
subject comes up I know that took a
whole and Jorgensen was planning to do
so but the timing is bad for him today
so I believe Toki hurlan gurgenson was
planning to talk about this today but
the timing was bad for him was this
session so he will probably comment
later yeah and we already have some
input from him some more and more input
will be welcome okay and Wes yeah that
was really all from my summary I thought
it was good discussion so then in this
case I propose that we take the sense of
the room using a hum to do
if we should put these documents into
the working group must call for comments
stage the stage will open a formal
process for people to comment on the
documents please relate such currents as
you think about whether your you think
they're ready because if the comments
you provide should be related to
sections of these documents to see if
they are ready and fit for progression
by the working group um we would like to
know if you think those documents are
ready for evaluation in a working group
last call
please hum if you think these documents
should go to a working group last call
now please hum now if you think these
documents should not go to working group
was coal no okay so if you didn't huh my
the way and you wish to come and speak
at the mic please do but first of all
ask David what he feels the sense of the
room was I heard weak hums for both
alternatives there was also hums against
in Java but just from Dave said there
was also a hum in Java for against but
just from Dave okay
I still I still across the floor to see
if our ad wishes to say anything okay
so based on this that it's this seems to
be some people's list to see it is not
ready so I think the reasonable thing
here is to give those people a short
time a few weeks to send those points
what's this cause it is not read it
cetera and have a discussion on the main
list to resolve that this sounds like a
very good approach we will not start a
working group
last call for this document this idea we
plan to do so but we will shall give a
few weeks for people to respond to that
plan and explain whether this is a good
idea or not so if you think that that
plan is not a good idea
please explicitly comment on the mailing
list to the chairs to help us decide
what to do and Magnus yes and I mean if
you have things that are technical
reasons why it's not ready ensure that
that also gets raised thank you I see
shall be next it's a no working group
draft and coming around presentation by
on on list Draft Morton T s BW g SCE
please come and tell us about it working
well enough okay
my name is Jonathan Martin I already
heard me at the microphone and I'd like
to talk about some congestion
experienced and alternative proposal for
the use of the ECT one code point so we
would be defined ECT one as some
congestion experienced as a
high-fidelity congestion signal and you
can see the table at the top of the
slide lists the three existing code
points in use buying IRS three three one
six eight and the extra one and we also
use a spare bit formally known as NS in
the TCP header for feedback in that's
what third draft is about we retain all
other our SVC one six eight details for
full backwards compatibility and that
means that if an SCE endpoint
communicates with a nut with a non SCE
endpoint it automatically falls back to
standard behavior if there's a non SCE
middle box if then we also have standard
behavior we have multiple instances of
running code available okay so now
design philosophy is based on the three
following quotes principles which are
illustrated by these quotes first do no
harm
heterogeneity is inevitable and must be
supported by design effective congestion
control is required
so first for backwards compatibility
which is part of our do no harm and
heterogeneity acceptance normal additive
increment and multiplicative increase
and multiplicative decrease principles
apply so we have a normal congestion
window surveyed a TCP friendly response
to loss and the TCP map and to
congestion experience marks and existing
middleboxes treat packets that a matress
SCE
as ECT and are still able to mark c e on
them
existing endpoints ignore our signals
this is completely harmless it's a
transparent fall back to standard
behavior the meaning of congestion
experience is thus preserved and that
means that SCE becomes a soft cruise
control signal because we still have the
ability to a multiplicative decrease on
a standard C II signal or a loss if
there's a big change a big reduction in
the path capacity this is a big
advantage of a DC tcp which only has the
one code point to do it signaling on and
therefore has to use it still has to
emulate the multiplicative decrease for
that scenario this gives us more
flexibility in what we do as our
response and here we have a
demonstration of what happens when we go
through a standard metal box these are
two flows both endpoints happen to
support SCE but the cubic flow is not
using the SCE signals only the Vino SCE
flow is
and you can see that the two flows are
proceeding approximately equal in
throughput and this is what you would
expect from a Reno versus cubic
comparison anyway and the latency is
also reasonable there are spikes of up
to 5 milliseconds at 8 switches and I
think you made a second path that's very
little the way we apply se signals in se
is a signal from the network to the
endpoints the network boxes don't need
to know anything other than it is an
ECCN capable transport so se is a high
fidelity congestion control signal which
we apply as a marking ramp the
probability of amp based on Q surgeon
time or Q occupancy if you prefer high
fidelity means that we have many marks
per RT team as opposed to standard
marking which is many RT T's per mark
applying of course a steady-state
situation we can easily add SCE marking
to an existing ATM algorithm and that is
what we have done for reference
implementation and this is easiest to do
if fair queuing is also implemented we
will talk more about this later
a simple threshold function is a valid
implementation grant functions probably
perform better and seeing marks are
still relevant you can see to the right
of the diagram is the region above 5
milliseconds surgeon time in which code
L does it marking so we have full
Becker's compatibility of an SCE middle
box with existing RFC compliant flows
the response to SCE
is signaled to e SC e which is the
former NS bit which is released by the
the historical status nonce some
specification this is completely
orthogonal to the ECE NCR cwl bits which
are still treated as with our three
three one six eight and when this bit is
set it indicates that the currently act
seconds carried an SCE mark the receiver
logic is very simple immediate and
almost stateless so it's easy to
implement the patching of implementation
to do so is a few hundred lines
including including some with auxiliary
things it's simple the center response
it may ignore it as existing
implementations do this is backwards
compatibility
we have DCTC theme which influenced the
DC TCP response but to an SCE signal
instead of a seee signal and as the it
reacts the ability to do a straight
multiplicative decrease to a standard
RFC they one six eight signal main OSCE
modifies this response to be less severe
the we scaled by the square root of the
congestion window instead of by student
we also have in progress a cubic SCE
response which also deals was the fact
that cubic can grow at greater than
linear rate we exit so start on a single
SCE mark because we need to do that as
soon as a congestion signal is received
and here we have a demonstration of an
ideal scenario where Kubek is competing
with you know us SCE as before but this
time in with the middle box that
supports both fair queuing and SCE
marking and here we can see that the SE
flow in orange is neatly using the space
the capacity left over and by the
sawtooth in the cubic flow mia cowan
just a quick question on the graph and
also the Ella bar and for the redirects
or a cubic only flow do you also have
any AQ m in a bottleneck yes the cubic
flow is receiving Cee marks in which a
key mi using anabolic this is effective
we're using cake so it's effectively
kado and the threshold marking special
thresholds basically the standard
parameters 100 millisecond interval 5
millisecond target thank you so you can
see that there are no multiplicative
decreases in the green OSCE throughput
chart and this is because it is reacting
sufficiently well to SCE marking to
avoid the need for ze marks the green
trace of the bottom shows the the
latency of the SCE flow itself and you
can see that the peaks of it are lower
than the purple trace which is the cubic
internal RTG that last with
queueing but pinging the sink you as the
data is that right or what was the pink
the pink is the cubic internal agency
that the flow latency yeah and you're
using F chip we're using fair queuing
and you've got a ping is the ping in a
separate queue or in the same queue
something else
the two flows gets there / queues in
this case the two because it's fair
queuing so the bottom flow right at the
bottom yes in dark purple is a separate
measurement flow which is using yet
another for queue using a separate queue
yeah so this is measuring how fast the
queues rotating rather than the time
through the of the traffic yes yes right
okay so it's not the scheduler tix yeah
okay all right so here we also have se
use performance in a single queue with
SCE support and as before we have a
delayed start of the second flow so one
has almost reached the link capacity and
the second must then compete and we can
see that it converges this is just like
FK I'm sorry not speaking as char here
maybe I should go down there but this
was just like FQ I mean this is just two
Q's is it not or is this something I'm
missing etc this one is single without
fitting right okay and you can see it
from the caption on the right yeah yeah
but this is where SCE and you can see
that was just the SCE response we do
have convergence so we don't only
support fair queuing we prefer it of
course
however with questions were based on the
list about how we could do this with
dual queues and we observed that any
traffic data fire such as a dscp you may
be used to direct seu traffic into a
special
Lyons cute and so such that conventional
traffic would default to the first queue
for robustness against mr.
classification it is straightforward to
arrange things
the conventional queue does not mark
with SCM and therefore if SCE traffic is
misclassified into the conventional
queue then it just receives standard RSC
3 1 6 8 behavior and this we think is a
major benefit of using of the
unambiguous signalling provided by
putting SCE on a different code point
than CD now if we put SCE and
conventional traffic into a single queue
then as standard SCE
yields very politely to the conventional
traffic you can see the Amish trace at
the bottom shows much lower than the in
the cubic flow computing with it at the
top now this may actually be useful to
some people if they want a scavenging
transport we leave that up to you
however we have an alternative approach
as well by modifying the SE marking
probability ramp into this two-stage
format some of our seniors benefits can
be realized without realizing multiple
queues there are some compromises in the
performance the current implementation
is not an odd three you have to
configure the level at which that kink
in the graph appears but SCE can coexist
fairly with conventional traffic and
with the same queueing parameters run
smoothly in competition was itself the
vamp parameters are chosen at the single
queue bottleneck node in question which
means that this is a network
administration decision and doesn't need
to be specially set up after the
ends nerves and here is what happens
when you have conventional and SCE
traffic computing with this setup it's
not ideal but you can see that SCE is
getting more throughput than it did in
the previous example and then when we
put two SCE flows together you can see
that they run smoothly for the most part
there's a little bit of a glitch at the
end where probably a stray see
e-marketing but you know that these are
tweak these sorts of things can be
tweaked later with more experience now a
really important matter is that we have
a running code in fact we have multiple
instances of running code four months
ago at the end of I 80 f-104 we already
had a Phoebe SD sender a Phoebe SD
receiver and a Linux based middle box in
fact - even two implementations there
today we have Linux senders as well a
Linux receiver with a better feedback
algorithm and we have even have a Phoebe
SD middle box
thanks to this report that we got from
Logan from Africa
so Albert continues to mature desert
diversify and character they
characterize ever all of our work and as
part of that we found some interesting
things about TCP pacing first something
fundamental which also I think applies
to other high fidelity congestion
controls the tie fidelity congestion
signaling is very sensitive to
burstiness of the traffic because these
bursts
collect transiently in the queue and
cause this congestion signaling a
clocking is not sufficient to avoid
these bursts
especially when you have delayed acts
because delayed acts naturally leads to
packet pairs so pacing is effectively
mandatory when used with high fidelity
congestion signaling in connection with
this Linux actually exempts the first
ten packets in each flow from pacing
this is quite a nice feature it prevents
slow start from working with SCE so we
patched it out this one line fixed we
also found that the transition from so
start to congestion avoidance requires a
halving of the send weight normally this
is provided by the first congestion
signal experienced by the flow whether
that's a loss or a c-- e-- mark so what
we have to do instead because we don't
have a multiplicative decrease all the
time we use modified spacing scale
factors which enforce a throughput
change at that boundary and we expect to
continue experimenting with that so if
we we have also a yeah we have a public
repository containing SCA code it's
based on the Linux 5.1 next net next
series kernel and I forgot to put the
URL on the slide but you can send us
revised slides and will happily posted
I'm sure we can we'll post a link on the
mailing list as well
please do post is very nice to Cory and
please do post and where we can get the
patches or whatever you're working on I
guess they weren't up streamed the
change you're talking weren't up
streamed they were your own versions yes
we have a complete git repository okay
excellent post-up please know my
question is accurate ecn is some of you
been working on here as well
how does actually see and figure with
what you're doing because you seem to be
reusing other bits
well accuracy in takes over the NS bit
for the three-way handshake and if it's
negotiation is successful we found that
a QC n was not actually useful for our
purpose
so we declined the a QC n negotiation
and use the NS bit thereafter as if it
were not some essentially hmm the reason
why occasion was not useful to us it's
because the the three bit field it
produces counts EE marks which we
already have perfectly adequate feedback
with the RSC three one six eight but
what we need is feedback of the ECT one
code point yeah which is provided only
by the TCP option in that case en DRA
and TCP options have their own problems
yeah I'm previously easy t02 ECT one was
a non-normal transition which we didn't
engineer to MU Daiko easy and I guess
because that's not expected in the
internet this is true and so of course
we will need some experimental status in
order to formalize this as an experiment
however we believe it's mostly harmless
Andrew McGregor I'm quite concerned
about your notes about pacing and the
requirement to space
it's out in that manner because that
says to me that this is going to
interact extremely poorly with a with an
aggregating Mac if you end up dropping a
few packets into the same Mac into the
same Mac aggregate then and the for
example is Wi-Fi the access point is
congested so there's gaps between
aggregates effectively the network
reboosts the traffic for you and that's
going to end up behaving poorly because
if you don't land in the sand at the
same aggregate you minimize the
performance of the Wi-Fi this is
something we have recognized and
something we will need to explore
reasonably soon probably and the other
thing is I observe we have two proposals
for how to do something quite similar
who are using radically different
evaluation methods and different
congestion controls and all the
experiments please you know use the full
matrix in both cases because otherwise
we can't evaluate me a cool event and so
first two quick comments and equities
and while I know that the discussion
about this should actually go to the TCP
I'm working on but like one big part
about equity CN was compared to what
like data in a TCP for example is using
that occurred easy and actually has a
negotiation face so you know for sure
that the other end is supporting it that
was a very important point and the other
point was also that the assumption is if
you use the etc1 code point and the
option is not available which you can
test for then you need to opt out of
that experiment eventually while that
mechanism still ensures that the
traditional way the solution thing is
feedback accordingly so that's kind of
the assumption for all experiments we do
and with the assumption also that like
maybe this whole option problem becomes
better in future and then you can use it
everywhere so it's a deployment thing
yeah I'm sure that's something we can
have a discussion about in TCP yes
I have rather a couple of questions
because like looking at listening to
your presentation looking at the
diagrams a little bit the message I got
was that what you propose works very
well with fair queuing while you don't
have any guarantees that they will be
effective in applaud or whatever however
if you use it without fair queuing it's
more as giving a approach and then you
presented that you can be more
aggressive but then it look to me that
the more aggressive part also means that
you get like more queuing delay which is
not the perfect that you're looking for
so for Mila but the confusion was if you
this only works well with fair queuing
is that the message you can agree to is
that not what you wanted to say you may
notice that off the diagrams in this
slide deck only one of the most
forgiving yeah but like the other graphs
didn't show to me the benefits you
wanted to achieve so I understand that
it doesn't pressor system but it doesn't
really show us any benefit to me
well you might look at the the total
throughput of this synovium until it
glitches of course basically we
eliminate the sources and we get better
food yeah so but that's only if
everything would be using SCE right the
previous graph you showed again this is
something either you use fair queuing or
everything in the whole world has to use
SCE only one that's like the two cases
where it's really beneficial well
it still works even if there's boxes in
the network that don't understand SEO at
all it's still safe to use yeah yeah I
understood that part
I mean if you have a network that
internally wishes to use se form of an
optimization then it can deploy a seee
without requiring the rest of the
internet to also deploy a C or FQ or
anything like that I think that's
important can I make John can I make one
point if you could go to the graph with
the Reno SC verse cubic single q with
SCE marking where we have the threshold
set just to make the point that this is
80 milliseconds so that throughputs
you're seeing there are what you might
expect anyway between cubic and Reno
just to make that point if you look at
it and say oh it doesn't look fair
that's part of what's going on here as
you're talking about cubic versus Reno
at 80 milliseconds anyway quick
administrative announcement Mike lines
are closed and people will stick around
I think we'll try to fit in the
multipath DCC P presentation the end so
if we could keep queuing ain't quick
here that would help all concerned I've
read the drafts and I'm still missing
the kind of problem statement and the
space that you were exploring in
addressing the problems that you want to
solve so I'm not quite clear if the
problems that you're trying to tackle
here are universally applicable to the
Internet at large including low latency
environments and that's one part the
other part the other comment I want to
make is it has a feel that the use of
the of the NS bit for - bit has feels to
me like you're jumping at a solution or
a signaling mechanism
is readily available without first
everything if that would be the best
option available because one observation
that I've think I've made is s EE and
also in the accuracy n slash data center
TCP environment the normalcy mark both
have a much less severe marking
semantics than regular C II so I was
wondering what are really the
differences between SCE versus at the
l4s architecture with with equities yen
marking because from my point of view it
seems that the signalling aspects are
really a secondary problem and shouldn't
be on the forefront we should discuss
first what type of problem you should we
want to address
mmm I'm sure we can address those in a
future version of of the documents but
the I'd like to draw your attention to
the last line on this slide where we
have the unambiguous signaling semantics
on the different curve points so we can
make and implement DC TCP without
leaving it unsafe for general use to be
a to be a little more or pointed there
was a chart that went up during Bob's
presentation about what happens when you
run a RFC 368 a QM on a set of traffic
some of which is using TCP C II mark
someone's using DCTC PCE marks and their
problems there and what those are
basically saying is that for SCE seeing
means C e means CEC RSC 3168 and
therefore you can't get into that
particular problem scenario right I just
to agree with Miriah this is this is
trading off some of the this proposal
appears to trade awesome with the
performance at particularly the latency
performance proposed for l4s in order to
gain some safety and so that's really
the to me that's that's an interesting
question of consensus to consider like
how bad is the safety effect
particularly with regard to the 3168
interactions and and that's that's what
I would like to see most discussed on
the list as well as as conditions of
sort of malicious use in Europe in its
various scenarios in the admission
control okay Jake I take the comment and
then there's a different trade off here
and we need to talk about that on list
and also we should not that the raziel
so the a b ii proposal to use the same
code point which is no RFC status which
we need to coexist with so this doesn't
take a free call point it reuses a core
point which we recently standardized but
and we can do lots of things here and
please use the list to discuss this
we'll take one last comment and then we
will decide on what to do the draft or
not the draft the code repository is
cited in the test draft for anybody
looking for it's actually in the drafts
it's in the tester app and the other one
there is a missing implementation that
was not in the slides that there's
actually a hardware implementation of
SCE running today in 25 gigabit switch a
year thank you and this achieved this in
we learned about that actually today and
the ports that are that it achieves far
below a millisecond of RTT with big
improvements in the link level beat rise
needed to support one thing whatever
that application is so that's a big
things for us
okay thank you very much and I would
like to thank everybody's worked on
worked on agree to both the Alvarez and
and SCE work and all the hackathon work
I think I think a very interesting
productive weakest has been transpired
okay we we are over time so I think we
we probably get to formally close the
meeting here however if you're
interesting leap at DC CP we're going to
go ahead and have that presentation
Marcus you here okay cool
oh here's to presented so let's let's
give people about 30 seconds of those
who wish to exit for whatever reason can
and then we'll go ahead and for those
who are interested let's talk a little
let's talk about some completely
different multipath DC CP hang on one
more thing where is it there it is click
on that okay cool so just to clarify and
the TS vwg meeting has has formally
finished and this presentation we would
have included they will get a gender
time next IETF and since the room is not
currently needing to be vacated we will
let them proceed to tell people what's
going on and maybe you get an insight
into and this new topic and if the
Secretariat come in and tell us we have
to leave then you'll be cut immediately
fair enough
so thanks for those staying around my
co-authors are not here anymore
so I'm on a bernstrom and I will be
presenting our work on multipath DC CP
as a way of carrying UDP IP traffic over
a multi connectivity networks so a quick
summary of the motivation so we had the
markers from Deutsche Telekom had the
first presentation of this as the
previous IDF with a bit more details on
the motorway
but we have multiple ongoing
standardization efforts and other
organizations so in 5g for 5g 3gpp is
standardizing the 80s SS steering
switching and splitting and you have in
the broadband forum the hybrid access
which is for multi connectivity networks
and they are using MP TCP to carry the
TCP traffic but there's really no
solution for how to carry the UDP
traffic and for operators like Deutsche
Telekom they really see you know the
need to cater for both TCP and UDP if
they're going to deploy any type of
solutions for these multi connectivity
situations and of course with the
increase of quick traffic that we may
expect in the future
carrying UDP traffic could also get
increasingly important so the goal with
this work is to look at the multi part
solutions for caring thing UDP traffic
in this context complementing MP TCP and
you can check out the last presentation
as I said for some more details so this
is an overview of the MP DCC framework
so you have a sender and the receiver
you have a virtual network interface
that takes you connects you to the IP on
the other side and then you have DCP
tunnels you add sequencing information
on top similarly to MP TCP and then you
tunnel over the DCP flows so this is the
basic architecture and this was also
discussed in the previous presentation
there are three drafts related to this a
draft on the multi path DCP protocol a
draft on the framework the role
framework and the draft that Maps the
DCP header into the UDP header so that
you can get through networks because DCP
is not not generally passing through
middle boxes so these are the three
drafts related to this ongoing work
we have worked since the last time quite
a bit on the the implementation and
experiment side so there is a prototype
available inside the Linux kernel
unfortunately not open source at the
moment I know the Deutsche Telekom
people are working on that internally
and then we also have a mystery set up
where you can evaluate the residential
and mobile use cases so the way this
architecture or the setup looks is that
we also have a number of scheduling
components because the key issue of
course for carrying the multipath
traffic here is how do you schedule over
the different paths and as compared to
multipath TCP when you carry UDP traffic
you also have the issue of what do you
do at the receiver side in terms of
resequencing do you let the UDP packets
through do you make sure that some of it
gets reordered because you may now have
different delays on the different paths
that your traffic is going over so we
also have a number of different
algorithms that we have looked on on the
reordering component of this framework
so what I wanted to do today is just to
show you some short sample of those
results that we have been working on and
in relation to the presentation last
time as I said we mainly been working on
updating the implementation and on some
measurements there's been some smaller
updates to all the drafts improving on
the language spelling things like that
for the multipath framework draft there
also the requirement section added but
in terms of the draft we of course need
to include some more detailed
specification for the multipath protocol
we had some feedback regarding UDP
options for the header conversion draft
that needs to be taken into account and
also further aligning with the
discussions in 3d PPE and the broadband
forum
make sure the requirements gets right
but let's look at a few sample results
so this first one is from the NS three
simulations with UDP traffic looking at
what happens both for switching and an
aggregation scenario and here we have a
scheduler that prioritize the Wi-Fi path
as long as this path is available and if
not it moves over to the the LTE power
port so in the top graph it's the the
switching scenario so then as expected
here the path is has enough capacity to
carry your your your traffic so as
expected initially all the traffic goes
over Wi-Fi when the Wi-Fi disappears it
takes some time to detect this because
we're now not using both the paths
inauguration mode once the loss of the
Wi-Fi interface is detected the traffic
moves over to the LT path and once Wi-Fi
come back it the end moves back to the
Wi-Fi path on the lower graph here you
see what happens when you are in
aggregation mode so this also shows you
one of the benefits of actually using
aggregation or using a splitting also
for a flow that does not need the
capacity all the time but you see that
when you have the Wi-Fi path quality
going down before you lose the
connectivity to Wi-Fi so the scenario
here is that your you're moving so
you're in Wi-Fi coverage initially and
you're moving out of Wi-Fi coverage and
you're moving back into Wi-Fi coverage
and we can see that when we have the
aggregation then of course things go
much more smoothly because when your
Wi-Fi path is getting worse you're
actually gradually shifting over the
traffic over to the LTE path and
similarly when Wi-Fi is coming back its
smoothly going back over there so this
is kind of one one of the goals with
some of the initial
has also been to look at the difference
between these different mechanisms
between just having the switching or
having the splitting aggregation modes
and how that impacts performance so this
is just one of the examples from the end
the three simulations here is a second
example that is from the testbed
measurements and this is also looking at
the handover scenario in aggregation
mode and in the first scenario we have a
handover that is triggered similarly by
this this path that has the shortest RTT
having the delay going up and we're
using a shortest RTT scheduler here so
what happens when the delay on the
faster path increases then the algorithm
as expected moves over to the second
path which has a stable latency in this
experiment and to the right side it's
another handover scenario where you
actually lose the connectivity on one of
them on the the cheapest path completely
and then you immediately switch over and
traffic goes over the second path so the
two two scenarios here are just two
examples of different scenarios one
where you have a latency spike on the
path and the second one where you
immediately lose the path and this is
also immediately visible to the protocol
in this case and as a third example this
module shows this graph shows a bit also
the impact of the reordering module on
the receiver side so what we look at
here is the packet delay distribution so
the digital in the wrong button the
jitter that you see at the receiver side
in the packets that arrive and we now
look at some different scheduling and
reordering mechanisms so
the blue one here is just a dumb
round-robin or weighted round robin 8020
share scheduler and of course then you
would get a lot of delay differences in
the packets that you receive if you use
some more better scheduler like the
shortest round-trip time first or even
better the OTAs which is a scheduler
that tries to also take into account how
long it takes to send your packets over
a path the queuing in the Sun buffer
trying to equalize the arrivals you get
as expected that's reordering but of
course the most efficient is if you also
have some reordering component on the
receiver side and in this case it's
using one of the adaptive reordering
mechanisms that we have been playing
with yes Jake Jake Alan I just wanted to
report that on jabber media Co is
reporting that they may not have to
disconnect the remote participation
shortly their equipment needs to come
down another room is still I think she
has one more slide and then we wind this
up yes so let me move on to the
conclusion then so this was just a quick
showing you some of the results that we
have so we now have a implement
prototype implementation now also some
industry simulations to test things out
and some of the first experiments look
quite good so we are tested both the
switching and aggregation scenarios
we've also done some measurements with
the congestion control UDP flows running
nada the congestion control for
real-time media that is being worked on
in orem capped on top and and then of
course things gets more complicated and
more interesting so that port needs a
bit more work and one issue here is how
these things will relate to 3gpp and how
we can get some of these solutions into
3d PP in time and my colleagues at
Deutsche Telekom is having lots of
discussions with other operators and
vendors how to approach this whole
problem space and we will try and
continue working on the drafts and happy
to receive any feedback we have also
the drafts up on github so you can make
pull requests you can send those mails
or any comments and you also have on
this slide link for a paper that we have
recently put together which has some
more detailed experiment results there
was a presentation material for I ICC RG
that has a bit more results available
and also the previous presentation at TS
vwg for more background information so
thanks to everyone for sticking around
okay thank you very much
apologies that we have we wound up doing
this clearly we're going to ask for more
time in Singapore and we'll get you
better gender slot in Singapore I
believe the Secretariat wish to
dismantle the room so if you could leave
that would help them
you