thank you
hello everybody and welcome i hope that
you have enjoyed your lunch break and
that you're having an interesting and
educational day so far
i'm really glad and delighted to be here
with you today at besides munich where
we're gonna have the chance to explore
one of the places where the finest
concepts of data science and cyber
security meet
before doing so i'd like to really
quickly introduce myself to you my name
is dimitris prasakis and i'm currently
pursuing my masters in cybersecurity at
georgia institute of technology georgia
tech in the us
i'm also working as a security engineer
at trade republic in berlin where i
specialize in cloud security and
infrastructure security my interests
also lie in ai and privacy and
especially where all these worlds
intersect with each other
and one of those intersections is what
we're gonna
see here today together
our agenda is made out of four parts the
first two of them are introductory we're
gonna talk about malware analysis and
about sandboxes and we are also gonna
talk about machine learning and
introduce the concept the tasks
classification and clustering the third
part of the talk is the heart of the
talk my your framework it's a malware
analysis framework
with ai and we're gonna explain how it
works step by step and we're also gonna
have a decision for
questions and discussion
so without further ado let's start
and let's talk about malware analysis
in cyber security there is a job title
malware analysts and these people their
day-to-day job is to analyze malware and
they do this with the help of certain
tools called sandboxes
a sandbox in short is an isolated
environment in the context that
everything that happens in the sandbox
can't escape it if we execute a program
in that sandbox it can't infect the host
right so that's the first thing it does
and the second thing it does it is that
it has the ability to study and monitor
the behavior of what is being executed
inside of it so instead it takes a
binary malwarebinary as an input it
executes it studies it and then produces
a text report and this report will
contain things like
network requests made or metadata about
the malware
but today we care in particular about
commands this malware tried to execute
and we're going to talk about windows
malware specifically and windows api
calls
apart from sandboxes the second
introductory point
is the task of classification
classification is a machine learning
concept
is the task of
taking an observation
something about we don't know the
category it belongs to right and putting
it into some
pre-known category into some class to be
more formal
so let's say that we download an
executable from the internet right
the task of classifying this executable
to benign or malicious to
good or bad is called classification
and in machine learning we classify
objects with the help of
classification machine learning
algorithms and one of the most known
ones is k n and k nearest neighbors and
it operates based on the folks saying
show me your friends and i'm gonna tell
you who you are
or in other words show me your nearest
neighbors in the vector space
and based on their class i'm gonna
predict your category and we see here
the example where
this observation up there
gets classified as a benign program
because the nearest neighbors are benign
apart from classification we have other
tasks in machine learning and one of
them is clustering
and unlike classification which is a
supervised kind of learning because we
feed our algorithms with labeled data so
we fit the algorithm with data that have
labels
clustering is a task of
is a kind of unsupervised learning we
feed our algorithm with unlabeled data
and the clustering algorithm tries to
create
groups of those unlabeled data clusters
which we are going to equate today with
the concept of classes
let's see how all these three concepts
sandboxes classification and clustering
bond together under a framework for
malware analysis called my year
but before doing so i would like to talk
about a very interesting statistic
every day
almost half a million new malicious
software and potentially unwanted
applications are registered
i would like you to think about the
volume
how much volume of malware this is we
need to understand this malware we need
to study it
so that we can attack it right before it
attacks us
we can't do that manually we don't have
enough manpower we don't have enough
bandwidth right malware analysis is a
very energy-consuming process and it
takes time
there is therefore an imperative need to
automate this process as much as
possible
excuse me
and this is where my year framework
comes into play
my year framework is an open source
framework for malware analysis with
machine learning
and it is used to do mainly two things
to discover new clusters of malware in
other words to take all these half a
million
malicious software every day and try to
group them into clusters
that contain malware with identical
behavior
and to also classify unknown malware
observations into clusters that it
created and we're gonna see how this
happens in a bit
my ear framework looks like this a
simplified version of it we talked about
the first concepts right
so we take all marvel binaries we pass
them through sandbox produce some text
report and we talked about clustering
classifications
we want to cluster and classify classify
those malware reports
but in essence clustering and
classification are statistical
algorithms right they don't understand
text files
so this is where the second step
embedding of behavior comes into play
we take those text files and we
transpose them into mathematical objects
into vectors
so that we can later classify them and
cluster them
there is also a step in the middle the
step of prototype extraction is a very
beautiful idea which we are going to
talk about in a bit
so without further ado here what you see
is an xml encoded malware report and i
modified a little bit for the sake of
the presentation and for understanding
better what's going on
we see three snippets of instructions
the first one
is something you're going to see many
programs do
the program tries to load the
windows kernel into the process memory
and also it reads the time nothing
malicious about this snippet of commands
right
but if we scroll a little bit more down
and we
study the next snippet the next sequence
of instructions we're gonna notice
something at least suspicious
the malware tries to copy itself
from the location it is
to a windows protected area called
system32
and while doing so it also renames
itself to a windows well-known process
cscs rss.exa
and after doing this
it also modifies the windows registry
keys so that it runs every time window
windows start up
so that's
not something a benign program would do
right why would you copy yourself into a
protected area and then put yourself to
startup you may do the latter but
especially
those commands in combination show some
malicious behavior
and we see another example another
snippet
where the malware just
tries to check if it's being debugged
and malicious programs usually do that
excuse me to
understand if they are being analyzed
and in this case
they try to shut down their malicious
behavior and conceal themselves they try
to hide themselves from the malware
analysts
there is an important observation to
make to be made here from this example
that behavior is often manifested as a
sequence of instructions
which we formally call as q grams
so a q gram is a synonym for a
behavioral pattern let's say
and we saw two examples of two grams
because they are made out of two
instructions
and this concept of q grams is important
because it's what enables us to
embed the text files into the vector
space
we want to do that first of all so that
they can be read by the clustering
classification elements but also because
embedding the reports into vectors will
enable us to
express their behavior in a geometrical
way
right
similar reports similar malware are
going to be closer in the vector space
and vice versa
we embed the behavior using a
mathematical function called embedding
function
which looks like this
we're going to explain in an intuitive
level what this does simply
it gets an input which is a malware
report a sequence of instructions right
and produces an output an n-dimensional
binary-valued vector where its dimension
represents a q gram it represents a
behavior
for example imagine that we have the
dimensional space right the x dimension
z dimension the x dimension and the y
dimension
we may embed
this behavior this q ground
in the x diamond in the z dimension
excuse me and say for example that the
malware tries to copy itself into the
windows protected area rename itself and
put itself on startup
if the value here is one
or otherwise if it's zero the malware
doesn't try to do it
and we may embed this behavior
the model we're taking for debugger on
let's say the x axis right if it's one
the malware tries to do it if it's zero
the malware doesn't try to do it
imagine this for n dimensions in the
n-dimensional space
right
something really
interesting happens when we embed
malware in the vector space like that
because each dimension represents a
behavior right similar reports
will be closed with each other as we
said and they will form dense clouds
into the vector space if we look at the
sp this space from far away we're gonna
see clouds clusters of malware and each
cluster has malware that
behave in similar ways and this exact
distribution is what we are gonna attack
in order to exploit the malware before
it does that to us
before talking about that however let's
dive into a very interesting topic of
computer science computational
complexity
algorithms take time to be executed
correct
and especially machine learning
algorithms scale in a super linear way
let's say in polynomial time
depending on how much data we give them
that means that they are quite slow and
we want to execute this framework
every day so there is an imperative need
to reduce the time of the framework as
much as possible there are three things
that we can do
either buy more memory and more cpu
but this is limited right
and by default we have some physical
limits as well we don't have quantum
computers for example so that's that
option is out
the second thing we can do is
use faster algorithms but again
machine learning algorithms are refined
like they are as good as they may get we
we may be able to modify them slightly
depending on the program problem but
mostly we can't really reduce how much
time they take
the last thing we can do and that we are
going to do
is reduce the data that we fit the
framework
so what if
instead of feeding the framework with
half a million reports every day
we fit the framework with
let's say compress them with a ratio one
to ten and we feed it with
fifty thousand reports
this is where very interesting and
beautiful idea from 1989
the idea of prototype extraction comes
into play
instead of analyzing all these initial
model reports all these data points what
if
we could
extract representatives what if we could
choose certain data points that would
represent all the others
we call these data points prototypes
and luckily enough there is a prototype
extraction not the optimal one but a
good enough one that runs in linear time
so we take our reports and we try to
compress them into small
set of reports which we call prototypes
and instead of feeding our
classification and clustering algorithms
with the initial reports
we're gonna cluster the prototypes
themselves and propagate the results of
the algorithm back to the initial data
points and see we see
here we see the five reports right
that we extracted before the five
prototypes excuse me
and they are being clustered into three
clusters one on the top right one on the
bottom left and one on the top left
one would say
it doesn't really match makes much sense
to create a cluster of one person right
like we do on the top left why would we
do that why would we create a group of
one
and we would agree with it with whoever
claimed that right and this is why the
algorithm takes a parameter and we say
that if a cluster has less than m
members if our clustering algorithm
creates a cluster with less let's say
than two members
we are gonna reject this cluster we are
gonna put it on the site
and we are gonna keep these data points
for future reference maybe tomorrow
where we're gonna have new malware
reports
some new prototype is gonna be extracted
on the top left
and as a result maybe a new cluster will
be formed because it's gonna have more
than m members
and the same exact idea applies to
classification
we draw our decision boundary and we may
say that if a new observation falls here
for example the closest prototype is
this one as a result we are going to
classify our
new observation into this cluster but if
it falls
more than dr distance away let's say
here
we reject it and we keep it for future
reference
we described the simplified version of
malia
we described how we embed malware into
the vector space how we extract
prototypes out of them and how we can
use these prototypes to classify and
cluster
faster the malware
what we didn't talk about however is how
we can make this framework recurrent
we said that it's gonna be executed
every day let's say and
analyze half a million malware right
this is where our last concept comes
into play
the idea of prototype incremental
analysis
excuse me and the framework looks like
this
so the first steps are the same we take
the molar binaries we monitor the
behavior we embed the behavior
and then instead of classifying the
initial data points we classify the
prototypes
on the rejected
prototypes from the classification
we run the algorithms of prototype
extraction
and we extract prototypes out of them
and then we feed these prototypes into
the clustering algorithm
and these new prototypes maybe will
create new clusters with the yesterday's
prototypes
and so on
what we described basically is this
algorithm this is the heart of my ear
this is the entry point the main
function of it
and
it invokes all the other three
algorithms that we talked about
and this way
our model gets stronger and stronger
every day
our framework can
create new clusters of malware and as a
result it can identify
new malware and
in this way
we can attack the malware before it
attacks us
the talk is based on a paper called
automatic analysis of malware behavior
using machine learning it's written
i believe by two german professors and
one austrian professor
about 10 years ago but it's still
relevant
and it's very interesting if you enjoyed
the talk i urge you to
give it a read because it also has some
concepts that we did not have the time
to
talk about today
i want to thank sneha for guiding me and
helping me prepare for this talk today
thank you sneha i really appreciate it
and i also want to thank besides munich
for giving me the chance to be here with
you today
and explore one of the places where the
finest concepts of data science and
malware analysis meet
i would love to connect with you i have
a qr code down here i hope it works it's
not the malware i promise
you don't have to believe me though
right so
you can search me by sorry
right
correct
so
yeah you can also search me by my name
and i would love to hear your questions
and discuss with you
about what we presented thank you
awesome thank you very much any
questions just come in front here please
and ask your
questions just come in front
thanks
so we can hear you online as well
hello hi hello first of all thank you
very much for the very impressive
introduction of your system i have just
one quick question about it where do you
get all that information related to the
malware from because i mean it's a huge
amount of data you need to
put into the system
and are you do we have any sources or
where do you get
so from usually we get those that's a
very nice question actually we get those
from honeypots right
we
a honeypot is
something like a sandbox we could say
that we exposed the internet right and
it has some vulnerabilities and
attackers may get
access to this honeypot and try to
install some malware
but they failed to do it because this is
how handbots work so we take this
malware symbol
and we
throw it into my ear so honeypots
usually is the way how we gather those
apart from that also self-reported
malware from people or things that
either viruses already detected let's
say okay perfect
[Music]
any more questions
i will suppose it was clear then
awesome thank you very much i'm sure you
are available for q a later on yeah i
would love to talk with you thank you
very much