so
[Applause]
hello
perfect
good morning everyone
hope everyone is doing well
and thank you so much
for helping us and supporting us with
this community for security
so here i sneha your humble
uh host for today welcome you to besides
munich 2022
and i wish you all have a great day
today it's going to be fantastic and we
are going to make it super awesome
we have some ground rules today and the
very first ground rule is
you have to wear mask all the time this
is not just for your safety but it's for
everybody else's safety as well
so masks should be on because we are a
community and our idea our
responsibility is to make sure that
everybody in our community is safe and
sound
when we are talking about this community
we actually derive this entire meaning
and this actually goes with our
principles at b sides
besides security this is a group of
community of engineers security
researchers hackers individuals just
like you all
almost around 13 years ago
these individual ingenious people they
somehow couldn't make it to the
mainstream conferences
and they thought that no their voices
needs to be heard
and that's when they started a new
community called besides security and
today they are present all over the
world and we are humbled to be a part of
it
besides has been
a great part for us
and i would definitely like to say
for every one of you please give a huge
shout out and applause for besides
munich today thank you so much besides
munich for helping us share the ideas
and knowledge
what we have done so far
sorry
is i would like to give you an overview
of the entire achievement for the year
we are a small set of organizers we like
to call ourselves as the besides munich
team we have incredible 20 sponsors who
are the backbone for the conference this
year
and especially thanks to their support
we are all present here and we do have
some great stuff lined up throughout the
day
apart from that sorry we had this year
57 cfp proposals call for papers that
was like super amazing 57 papers well
there's one thing that i definitely need
to tell you there were actually 58
papers but there was this one paper
which was so super genius
none of us like i'm telling you very
frankly whoever is present in this room
no one of us was qualified to judge that
paper the title of the paper was
laura ipsum
that was fantastic and it was the huge
paragraph
so
unfortunately we did not select that
paper and hence we have 57 papers this
year
out of which we have 31 awesome speakers
who are present here who are going to
rock your world with the share of their
knowledge and some amazing
demonstrations and some super amazing
ideas and some of them are also going to
share how they perform the research but
they failed but we'll let you know what
are the lessons they learn which is
fantastic
it's an amazing power packed knowledge
sharing session the whole day that we
have today yesterday we had four
ingenious hands-on workshop which was
again amazing and those who were present
at the workshop i'm sure you had fun and
you learned something new and if not new
you
at least had to polish at least got to
polish your skills
so today's agenda is pretty simple
we start with the remarks
i'll be here talking right now
and after that we have the keynote the
fantastic keynote and the morning
sessions wherein we have the morning
talks then we have some coffee breaks
then again the mid-afternoon sessions
lunch break evening sessions
closing keynote and there is one special
session this year that we have
it's called heartfelt goodbye
and what exactly this goodbye would be
we will let talk about that in the
evening because talking about something
that is going to end
is always difficult
but there's always this excitement that
there's something new that is going to
begin so
please be here with us
next so about us a quick overview so
just just give me a raise of hands of
how many of you are here for the very
first time very first time for besides
munich
wow that's a huge number
how many of you all
came to know about besides like a few
weeks ago or this is your first besides
ever doesn't matter which country
wow that's a huge number
that is amazing so let me just introduce
quickly to what we are how we grew so in
back in 2017 we started a small
community conference wherein we had only
75 people to 78 people attending the
conference we had 10 talks ingenious
presentations and only three workshops
and we grew and today we have over 380
registrations we have amazing
presentations more than uh 57 proposals
this is how we are growing and now we
are also expanding how are we expanding
that's in the evening you will come to
know
before that before i leave this stage i
do want to give a huge round of applause
to the entire organizers team that is
present here
dagmar morton jen chris anna and of
course me
right
oliver engmar max silvio
stefan and a very heartfelt
thank you to nicole unfortunately she
did support us during some reserved
timings itself she's not here at this
moment with us today but for next
conference i'm pretty sure nicole will
also be with us
apart from that
we have our lightning
striking amazing volunteers you will
find them in the blue t-shirts
a huge shout out to them can i have a
round of applause for all the volunteers
please thank you
thank you so much
and before i wrap up there's one thing
that i definitely want to say morning
sessions are really amazing but you know
what the actual fun is when the good
things are kept for the last and today
for our closing keynote we have one such
amazing lady who would be presenting us
sharing us the knowledge she is the
author of best-selling books who which
basically helps you guides you and
supports you in performing secure
security implementing security in devops
operations and how do you shift left and
calculate your success
and the talk would be presented by tanya
jenka
so before
i go
orbit uh goodbye to you for now i would
like to give a huge round of applause
again to all of our sponsors especially
the platinum sponsors
thank you so much we also have gold
silver and the brown sponsors thank you
all so much because of you
plenty of things were possible today and
thank you so much for your support
so one more thing and i'm damn serious
here now this is where i get
talking about the real business code of
conduct we do not tolerate any
inappropriate behavior
if you see something
you should say something
if you find that there is something
wrong if you hear any
racist any derogatory statements from
someone please speak up please reach out
to all of us who are wearing these
orange t-shirts we are here to help you
okay
no
illogical behavior we are one we are one
community we respect each other that is
what we are and again
i'm super serious about this one masks
on i know i'm not wearing a mask right
now because we have huge distance and
i'm wearing the mic
it becomes difficult to talk
so speakers are given a liberty
to not wear masks on the stage
inside this room and the other track
room you're not supposed to eat or drink
if you want to eat something you can
step outside and eat but please keep
your masks on all the time
and yeah just a heads up for the today
evening session
we welcome you to join us we welcome you
to help us grow so please be present and
if you're interested just reach out to
us because this is how we grow
whenever i wanted to
uh
ask something how do i progress in my
life in my career there was always this
question whom should i ask i've always
dreamt of having a community a group of
individual people who think alike like
me who support my ideas and there has
always been this question with me that
how do i get this information from but
to be true uh to tell you the truth i
was also intimidated like oh my god that
person's like super awesome
he or she they are at a great level how
do i go and ask them
i always took a step back from asking
that question and always in my mind i
thought that would there be someone who
would be willing to answer these
questions who would not laugh at my
silly questions and say that's okay i
have an answer for you
i always had this huge question and i'm
pretty sure some of you also especially
the ones who are freshly out of your
graduation and college you have this
question
is there someone who can guide me
is there anybody out there who can guide
me
and the answer is yes and to give this
answer today i would like to call upon
the stage our keynote mr thomas shrek
who is the phd holder and the professor
at the munich university and today he
has decided to take this mental and give
us all an answer how do you grow in your
career what are the risks what are the
downfalls even if you fail that's okay
always treat your failure as success or
at least a learning
and if not nothing you can definitely
write inspiring quotes on instagram that
also works
so without any further ado i would like
to have a round of applause for mr
thomas shrek thank you so much thomas
[Applause]
i think my mom's get off
good luck thank you
so
let's see if the technical work is
working
okay perfect
yeah thank you very much for the nice
introduction
and also for the besides munich
how you called organizers to invite me
to give this keynote
so when they asked me about can you give
the keynote i was asking myself what
should i talk about
it's always always the same thing what
do you want to do and for me when i was
young and listen to keynotes and still
doing listening to keynotes i always
think how should a keynote look like it
should be inspiring it should be giving
the new sword so the first obvious
choice was
let's talk about cyber but i hate this
word cyber so here's the
normal slide like about all the cyber
buzzwords around there and i will not
talk anymore about cyber so you have set
one so the next
topic which came to mind let's talk
about blockchain because i don't know
how it's you how you are doing but
i get a lot with this buzzword so every
manager coming to me every company let's
do something about blockchain blockchain
blockchain blockchain i can't hear it
anymore so here's the obvious slide deck
slide about blockchain i will not talk
anymore about that
so
then we had a
really good talk with the business
organizat organizers
and we discussed about
what can give back to the community
so
i i grew up in a large organization you
know
sometimes very bureaucratic organization
and
every time i went there i was like okay
this is really the way
people are doing that
so i learned a lot when i joined
communities
as the introduction was saying
communities are so important you learn
things and you get new ins and
inspiration and so on and therefore we
said okay
let's talk about communities so why
can't i talk about communities
so i joined very young with a community
and i was there as a yeah newbie
first time attendee
however you get called
and then i was at this large
organization called form of internet
response and security teams which is the
largest organization for security teams
in the world i was there on the board of
directors for six years and were the
chairman for that
and believe me or not
it's
it sounds great but it's a lot of work
so i know what the besides people are
doing in the volunteer time i had
professional staff
around so
i want to use this opportunity now that
you give them all and not only the
volunteers because near forgot about
thanking the whole organization team are
a lot of our plows because what they are
doing is amazing and they're doing all
that for you so please give a lot of
applause to them now
[Applause]
so i want to share the experience i had
with communities building up communities
running communities learning from the
communities and so on
so this is also a bit of a personal talk
so when i was finishing university i was
i thought i know everything
and i learned the total difference when
i joined the first organization first
company
and i was very overwhelmed i learned new
buzzwords every day
and i was like oh god university have
not prepared me for the job
and what did i do wrong with with what i
learned and so on so i was really
i was really sometimes a bit nervous if
if i'm as an engineer doing the right
thing
and
back then when i started we had not had
this company cultures where it was still
hierarchy driven and so on so i looked
at the topics what what we're doing on a
daily business
and i always thought is it really how
this work is it not really boring is
that not a lot of problems and on so i
had a lot of questions every day
and all these questions were not really
answered by my teammates because
those were the ones were doing that all
the time the same thing so i said
question not what they were doing
so i felt really alone i felt alone with
my questions
i was like there
am i in the right place am i doing
something wrong and so on so the
question came to me
is there anybody out there who has the
same problems i do who has the same
perspective on topic than i do
and that was
for a large i think for over one year a
huge topic i thought about i i
questioned myself and so on
so
is there anybody out there by the way
which band
no one
pink floyd right so my favorite band
so it was obvious choice
so is there anybody out there and i can
tell you yes there are there are a lot
of people out there you see it here in
the community there are a lot of people
out there and there are a lot of people
out there in in the whole
in the whole
industry we have who are doing work who
do volunteer work who share experience
on their own but you need to find that
you need to engage with them and what i
want to do today is to discuss with you
about my experience i had when i joined
those communities
learned grew failed
and
in the end were able to run off one of
those communities and spend a lot of
time in there
and it's a it was a great experience
it's still a great experience and i want
to give you
i hope that you when you go out of this
of this talk today that you yeah have
ideas about
what what may you what you can do uh
also to give back the knowledge you have
so how's this talk structured today i
have three important topics which i want
to cover the first is what is this about
so what is about communities what you
really should learn from communities and
so on the next one is what you need to
do
so how can you
give back what you experience what you
learned and so on
and last but not least what you gain
so what you can get out if you do that
if you do it and on so let's start about
what this is about
so who if you
are part of a community
so who so the people that still
have her hands raised
who are part of the community so
who thinks that's a lot of work being in
a community
okay that's interesting
i have a totally different perspective
on that
so when i talk about communities what do
i mean
so
i'm there are a lot of communities out
there there are this super exclusive
globs where companies pay
five
five numbered membership fees annually
and then there are the more industrial
driven organizations who are okay are
based on volunteers and then there are
yeah communities like b-sides or others
who are totally volunteering like yeah
b-sides over and on
so we have a very
we have a lot of different people like
the isaacs who get a lot of money every
year they have professional staff
working on topics and you have those
larger communities which which get money
from sponsors and running it and then
you have the total volunteer driven ones
and i can tell you one thing in all
those communities there's one
thing which is common it's all about the
people who are engaged with that
so if it's if even they have a lot of
money
they are in the background people who
really think this is the thing which we
need to drive
this is important for me so they spend
their whole spare time in this community
building it up and so on and that's
always the same thing
but why do you do that
so the first thing why are doing that is
learning
so
for me when i joined after this one year
thanks to a former manager of mine one
of those communities
i came there for five days and i can
tell you i went back home and i was
totally
full of sugar and totally overengaged
and so on because i gained so much
knowledge during that week and that's
mostly because the nice thing about this
community is
there are people there who are in the
industry for way longer
and who are willing to share what
what um
what say experience what say faults are
so i grew up in the caesar community and
the nice thing about the caesar
community is they are always in the
background so caesar people very don't
talk about in the public how cool they
are they are not in not on on stages
doing huge keynotes they are in the
background and
securing our network our internet and so
on and when i went there there were all
those people who were in the business
for 30 years 20 years and when i talked
with them and showed them i'm really
happy to learn from them
they gave back
all the knowledge they have to me
and i was lucky that two of sam which i
call now friends
took that opportunity up and and helped
me support me to grow where i'm i am now
but it's not always
one way it's not always that the
orders give back to the younger what i
learned is that as a young engineer
i question topics and questions hey is
that the correct way doing so
is it really what we did as a best
practice for 20 years
something which should be done like that
isn't there new technology out new
new thinking in the uh in our society
where we need to adapt our brushes and
the
exp a good experienced person in our
community is seeing this potential that
people are questioning and hearing
and not just saying no no no we have
done that for 20 years we know that's
working
and that's the wrong attitude to to
tackle topics you need to listen to the
people
understand what you if it if that's
maybe something what you're doing for 20
years or wrong and accept that you may
be wrong
so
the former team i was running it was
always
important for me that i listened to what
they are doing what's it what say what
say
what's the experience they have and so
on and for example when i was doing
programming
i was really bad in that
and there's one person here here in the
audience who need who i think hated to
read my code overflow
so
and for me it was important that i was i
was not telling him i'm the older one i
know what i'm doing that i listened to
him and said okay you're better than
that so please do so
so learning is not always about one way
orders giving the experience to young
words it's also the other way that all
the older people are listening to the
younger people understanding hey maybe
they are right or they're not or we are
wrong and we should change
what we are doing so that's an important
very important question
and i choose this picture by purpose
because
in our global society and especially
what we are doing on the internet we
also need to listen to other cultures
what i've experienced in some
communities is when there are people
from other cultures since the western
uh in the western culture approaching
you
they always say okay yeah
what are you talking about in africa i
don't care what you're doing africa and
this is also which we need to so uh yeah
we need to improve because
our cultures are so important the
technology decisions which we are doing
so it's not only learning
between us it's learning listening to
other cultures our societies and so on
and with all the crisis we are kind of
seeing that's getting more and more
important
so the next thing it's not about it's
not only about sharing
so
for example the organization
i was on the board first it was known
for the huge conference so they had an
annual huge conference people around the
world came there but it was mostly only
known for this conference and i hated
that
because there are these
c-shirts around there who really want to
engage in
on a daily on a daily business of
working each other so if there's an
attack on going
there are structures in in blaze where
ceasers can communicate to each other
and say hey we have this problem can you
step in
so i don't know who if you are isn't are
in the response but in zero response is
not tied to one organization it's most
of the time or you have a community
which needs to work on that so this is
so keen that
you
have ways in place when you need to work
with each other that you say hey i have
a problem and then you step in and
support those people
if you go through management for example
so i had this sometimes when you do my
report to my manager and my managers
that then to the next manager can we
talk with this company it takes ages and
when lawyers are involved then it takes
forever
so direct connections to each other are
so important so building up a network in
the community is so keen
so you should not only go there and say
great i will sit here
and listen
and then i go home you should be in
there
go out talk with the speakers talk with
others build up a network because this
network is so keen on daily operations
and it's not only being there at a
conference it's also
doing the conferences joining a mailing
list
give talks somewhere so it's it's keen
because when you have this fire fighting
happening
you need to
use this
this network
and help each other
and there are various communities out
there
where you can do that but they're also
something which is called trusted
communities trusted groups
and those people
are
those communities are
sometimes called fight club so there are
they have fight club rules i am not
really huge fan of these fight club
rules but there are communities who are
individuals and these individuals share
their knowledge share their operational
work sometimes when i open my email box
and i've seen what the tags are ongoing
in this main list i was like wow who
should how should i process that all
this information we have
so
you see this is ongoing this is
something which is helping each other is
so important
so this is what
you are able what is this about learning
from each other
sharing the knowledge
supporting each other when there are
things happening
but
as i said before
you also need to think about okay how
this community is working
so
you come here you listen to talks you
already learned that there are here
people volunteers
who supp who are organizing all of that
there are sponsors who are paying the
money says that we can be here to
conference hotel and so on
but imagine
if there would be no volunteers doing
that no sponsors and no speakers and so
on nothing would happen
so you would
instead of going to
munich and
talk to each other you would need to go
to the office or her home office
and do your work so
only because of volunteers as
this is possible
so
what can you do that this
can be
improved the situation we have
yeah first of all share your experience
so i think all of you have on a daily
basis
um yeah
something is happening in your office
you build a tool
you had an incident or you had a good
hack
but you never want to talk about because
as for example with me i always search
for example oh
i was really doing a bad job there so i
should not talk about it
or oh i don't have the time to prepare
talk
or whatever you find as a next
as an rule that you don't do it
and that's wrong
so first of all what i learned is
um
talking about failure is often more
important than showing off
so i i'm for example now back in the
academic field and i can tell you one of
the worst things about the academic
field is that you only share great great
great papers in big conferences and then
you gain again another
point that you're good talking about
something
but for example in the academic field we
don't talk about failures even
there should be those talks
the industry is a bit better here but
not as it could be
so
talking about failure especially in our
field is so important because everyone
can learn and leverage from that
next when you work on something and you
think okay i don't i'm not really sure
should i publish that or not
do it
i don't know how your company policies
are and so on but put it on github
and share it on twitter
talk about it
that's very important give go to a
conference talk about it then you get
feedback and maybe find people involved
in that i have seen so many cool
projects
dying on a laptop's hard disk because
people have not wanted to share it so
for example my students when they come
to me to write their final thesis i
always say i don't want to have this
source code on
a usb stick or on a cd
and not kidding still on cd sometimes
put it on github
tweet about it because that's maybe no
one is interested in but maybe there are
then you said then you build up your
profile
so
what i want to encourage you is that
everyone who is here now in the audience
will submit the talk to next next year's
b sites
even your manual can be selected
[Applause]
if you not get selected
it's an experience you have you get
feedback and so on
so that's important share your
experience then
help others
so
you are here
because you want to learn something
but it's not only about learning it's
also that we as people are very complex
we may have our personal problems and so
on
and that's so keen in a community when
you have a smaller community
you build up friendship
and therefore it's important that you
listen to others maybe they
say
ask for help you don't understand that
they're asking for help
so you need to listen to them carefully
understanding what the problems they
have and then they
help helps them
and this is something which i
experienced quite often
so i had personal problems i had
problems in the shop and so on and i
have always people i can ask
out of the outside of my company
within my company and so on
and this important thing what i wanted
to give
or what i want to share with you is
first of all if you need help if you
have a complex problem for example you
need to solve you should not be alone
just ask just experience people or
people you trust and tell them hey i
have this problem can you help me
or if you have personal problems because
you don't really know how your career
path is ongoing there are a lot of
communities outside supporting you on
that so ask for
help
and more important be there if someone
is asking for help
so
talk to them
and and use this time i know we are in
this industry we are all stressed out
and we're doing a lot of work on a daily
basis and then you oh and now it's 9 00
pm and i still need to talk with this
one guy because he is asking for help
and that's the total wrong
the total wrong attitude to it it's
something when you help someone you may
later on when you need help this person
may help you as well and i can tell you
i i was at the situation quite often
and it was always very important for me
that i had someone to talk a talk
so
now to the last point
now i told you about what's all about
these communities i talked about what
you need to do or what you should do and
so on
but what do you really gain from that
so first of all knowledge
and as you know knowledge is keen
in our society it's
very important
that you that you gain this knowledge
and
for i can tell you from my experience
that's the most what you get from a
community is exactly that knowledge
so
what's what what kind of knowledge so i
can give you now some examples um so
i was working on a on something within
my former company so i said we were able
to detect
some uh attacks
and i had a problem with
privacy so the way i wanted to do it was
from a private perspective wrong
and i knew that but privacy is important
for all of us so i was really there for
three months i have not found any
solution
so i went to a conference and discussed
it with a friendly circle as it's a
luxembourg czert and i talked to
alexandre i had this program and just
told him what problem i have
and he looked at me oh that's quite easy
just use that in that algorithm and that
is the data structure then everything is
solved
i was like wow this was a very easy
answer so i went back home implemented
that and it worked
and
yeah this knowledge that helped me on a
daily basis and that's just one example
another example is
uh when i was when i became manager
i never really were a good people
manager
and some of the audience can tell about
that
so
i didn't want to discuss it internally
and also the team i
i was in there was totally different to
other teams so i couldn't really ask for
help within the organization
so
i went out there and discussed with
others who were running successfully
teams like mine and said okay what are
you doing what you how how how do you
solve that in that problem
or how do you tackle that
uh and so and they gave me wonderful
ideas about
what you can do and that's also
knowledge it's not only about technical
knowledge it's also about how you
yeah manage people how you
how you grew your people and so on
and last but not least
building up friends
so for example my best friend i
i met
uh at a conference or first of all i met
him with on a mailing list and i thought
who is this who is this person who is
asking so stupid questions
but being biased
and now he's my best friend because we
found out that hey we have the same uh
we have the same technical interest job
interest but also private interest and i
can tell you for sure
that
all of us are bit same not only
only in the industry but also in our
private field so you gain
friends and like
i i must say
when i
when i look into my friendship most of
those people are
within
my community so these are the people i
trust a lot
i i talk on a daily basis and even i
have private problems
i have them because
they knew me they know how i'm working
and so on so this is what you also gain
a lot of friends which you can use
the whole career path and later on
hopefully also when you retire you can
do nice trips with them and so on
so that's also important that you just
don't just look at the look at hey this
is just a job
because our job takes the majority of
the time we have on a week
so you should share that with friends
and not with with people who you just in
there for eight hours on a day so this
is what i want to talk with or talk
about um
what i learned why for me communities
aren't so important and so on
and i hope you get
your yeah you gain something out of this
talk that you learned about something
and that you
submitted a talk next year
thank you very much i hope you enjoyed
it
[Applause]
does anybody have a question for a
wholeness
it's a great
opportunity some questions right now if
you have please step forward
so first of all thank you for your talk
when you mentioned uh we should talk
more about failure uh it reminds me of
something that i read i think in uh
this book from uh
i think it's called it and fragile but
basically the guy makes this argument
that we have this a big graveyard of
failure behind us so when you see like
say book authors uh we have like someone
that releases a book and we have like i
don't know ten thousand people that
never released a book but tried to
publish something uh could you please
discuss a bit more how would you
approach that how could we discuss more
failure uh give maybe some ideas
so you you can approach that on on
various levels i think there is a
conference format out
i can't be called the name where you
just talk about failures
uh i think that's one approach the
second approach is within organization
you what you can talk is that you do uh
what you can do is on a weekly basis on
monthly basis you have uh an evening
where where you're only allowed to share
failures you did
and then on a daily on a daily job basis
uh you may do a
instead of doing a scrum or dailies and
so on you also talk about in the dailies
about what did what did not work and how
you solved it so you need to facilitate
a culture where you discussed it
and way more important is that from a
mindset you need to allow your allow
failures so it's quite often that people
think okay if it if i fail
i'm doing a bad job
it's quite obvious
it's quite obvious it's
um uh opposite sorry obvious i said
opposite it's you need to understand hey
when i'm doing a failure it's totally
fine that it's a failure and now i need
to understand doing lessons learned
about what i what i did wrong
and honestly when i have a small child
at home
and she is doing the whole day failures
i can shout at her
and say you're doing it wrong or can i
can just show here why she did it wrong
and that's
like a mindset chef we need to we need
to do and i can tell you our society
unfortunately still doesn't allow
failures
so starting
to change in our society that failure is
allowed is the first thing which is
important to do
but a great question
okay thank you very much and enjoy the
rest of the day
do
oh both
as well
test is
uh
hello
so
business
hello
okay so take your seats please
i guess we'll give you a minute
a few minutes
okay
let's wait for the few hours
okay great so
we are one minute in delay
um yeah i'm very happy to introduce the
next speaker and the first regular
speaker connor morally who will talk
about the mac os
endpoint security framework
what it is what it can do and i'm very
much looking forward to this
thank you good morning
back in 2019
apple at the worldwide developer
conference announced they were making a
dramatic change to the way they were
dealing with the kernel space on their
mac operating systems today i'm going to
be dealing with one of the results of
this namely the endpoint security
framework or the esf
i am a senior researcher with secure
within their countercept team
prior to being part of the research team
was a threat hunter four years
i have produced multiple white papers
and proof of concept detection codes and
presented at a number of international
uh conventions
so what are we going to be going over
today we'll be going over what exactly
the esa is
why the esf is important to the
detection industry
how can we
in the industry utilize the esf
some of the issues during implementation
and some of the solutions that i found
to these issues
my device poc solution which i code
named esfang
and briefly going over a use case
against the return pressure agent
so first off what exactly is the esf
so the esf is developed as a
kernel-based telemetry acquisition
system by apple and it's
been developed as a way for a one-stop
shop for telemetry needs from the
security industry as you said it works
in the kernel space and because of that
it actually works fairly similar to the
way the etw works inside the windows
operating system
in many ways it succeeds the open bsm or
the open basic security module by sun
systems that was used primarily for
auditing purposes
prior to esf and one of the great
results of esf is that it allows for
real-time event acquisition for
direct intervention on
real-time
interception
but what does this exactly look like so
the image on the right here gives a very
basic overview of how this works from
the user space at the bottom with a
endpoint security application feeding
into the kernel space and getting
messages from the kernel space for the
telemetry
and on the left is a demonstration of
that information which uh from every
single event type includes multiple
low-level
data points including the parent process
id
path environmental variables cd hashes
and so forth
but why is the usf important
so
during the presentation at the worldwide
developer conference in 2019 they
announced they were going to deprecate
text or kernel extensions primarily this
means that they were removing
third-party current extensions from the
kernel space
meaning that uh third-party security
vendors could not use their own kernel
extensions for telemetry acquisition
because of this they introduced
something called system extensions which
is their way of allowing kernel
extension
proprietary apple kernel extension
access from the user space using
something called system extensions
equally before esf came along open bsm
as i said was a primary auditing tool
but it was quite clunky to use and
fairly difficult to integrate there's
lots of documentation on the problems
with open bsm so i won't go into them
but needless to say earsafe is a much
easier solution to getting these
telemetry points
so let's have a look at the old way of
how monitoring worked
so at the bottom we have the user space
top kernel space on the left the logs
so what would happen is is that
third-party vendors would have their
monitoring program hooked into a
third-party kernel extension running in
the kernel space and acquire telemetry
via that point
then using open bsm hooks they would
hook into log files and acquire them
through an auditing process run them
back to the monitoring program for
detection
uh processing
the new way is slightly different
so as we said the system extensions work
in the user space
and they work on frameworks that were
introduced by apple to directly access
kernel space using their proprietary
kernel extensions these work out as the
network extension framework
endpoint security framework or esf and
the driver kit framework and using a
amalgamation of the three you have very
high visibility over the low level
telemetry of the operating system
however we're focusing on the esf and
from that it actually hooks into the
endpoint security current extension
getting developed by apple so it allows
them to have this proprietary pipeline
from the user space system extension to
their maintained kernel extension
but why make the change
so the one of the primary reasons
that apple made the change to remove
canon extensions was for increased
stability and security
so by removing third-party kernel
extensions you avoid things like the
black screens of death but equally you
avoid third-party malicious kind of
extensions from being introduced into
the operating system
this means that they have much greater
control over what is happening in the
kernel space and it just eliminates a
lot of the overheads and a lot of the
problems that are being encountered with
less stable current extension that we're
finding in the wild and it means that
everything becomes very uniform
one of the things to note about kernel
extensions is that even though they've
been deprecated they can still be used
they're just you have to dramatically
reduce the security profile of a mac
operating system in order to do so
primarily you used to be able to
introduce current extensions on the fly
on demand however now you have to
degrade the security profile that's
running then you have to
turn on canon extension and then reboot
the system which means you can't just
inject them as you would
but how can we use the esf
so
this slide's a little bit messy so i'll
just walk you through it so in the
bottom right you'd have the main code
running in the user space of your
program you would then create an
endpoint security client object
this would then subscribe to the
endpoint security kernel extension with
the event types that you want so you
specify the event points you want like
file creation or process creation or
anything to that sort of thing
the endpoint security kernel extension
then crea populates an event message
queue in the kernel space and then pipes
that out to your endpoint security
client which you have already subscribed
which you use to subscribe to the kernel
extension
then on on each message a callback is
generated which you can have a callback
monitor and then each message that's
received can be processed back into your
main code for detection purposes
but what are some of the issues with the
esf use and what are the solutions so
during my experimentation with esf back
in
early 2020
there were a number of solutions that
came out from multiple
researchers and vendors but there were
some very primary issues that came out
with its utilization
namely a bottlenecking issue uh system
verbosity and a real parent process id
issue i shall go through each
individually
first of all a bottlenecking issue so
this was actually something that i was
banging my head against for
a couple of weeks even a month two
months and effectively what was
happening was is where you were doing
exactly the same experiment
you would get different data points
being populated and you'd have different
numbers
and it didn't really make any sense as
to why
so you'd conduct the same malicious
experiment using the esf telemetry
acquisition but you'd always get you
always get mismatched data points and
you'd have data points that were being
missing for no particular reason and
equally from a detection perspective
this means that it's inconsistent and
therefore the data points are unreliable
and it was a very long-standing reason
before i figured out exactly why this
was
primarily the issue was caused by the
kernel level q so you may remember from
the previous slide i said that the
kernel extension inside
for the esf would populate a queue
within the kernel space but what was
happening was is this queue was being
overloaded because the amount of data
that you were subscribing to was simply
too much so if you try to subscribe to
too many event types the queue gets
overloaded and suddenly drops data
packets which then don't come back to
the user space but there's no indication
that this happens so although the data
packets are dropped from the kernel side
because the kernel side is obviously
secure and it's isolated you don't get a
notification that this has happened
which is which is problematic
two primary solutions to this are a
development solution and a
esf proprietary solution i'll go over
the event muting first so event event
muting is a function that was built into
esf
and what it does is it allows for
specification for events to be dropped
inside the current extension space
now what this means is that through
process path or process token you can
specify particular event types to be
dropped on the kernel side and not
published into the event message queue
inside the kernel extension
because of this it means that you can
avoid overloading
however it's quite a blunt tool back
when i was experimenting with it because
you either had to specify an entire
process path again assuming it hasn't
been hijacked by anything or you had to
do it by a process token which only
works for that instance of the process
it was either too much of a sledgehammer
or it was too um unspecific it wasn't
targeted enough so for
a um
viable solution event muting just wasn't
specific enough for effective filtering
multi-client system however did turn out
to be very effective so whereas you
would have a
endpoint security client within a
process subscribe to event types instead
of having one client subscribe to
multiple event types you could have
multiple clients subscribed to
individual event types which equally
generated their own queue within the
kernel space and by using this method
you don't get overload and you get all
the data you require and you can
conglomerate them into one data set and
then run it through your detection stack
by crops referencing which was very
effective
one point to note is that um the
original development was on sdk 10.15
for catalina this was when esf was
introduced but between 10.15 and 10.1
5.4 the sdk was suddenly updated one
with a number of new event types they
equate something called the sec num or
sequence number in the es message so
whereas i was saying before there's no
notification from the kernel that silent
drops have occurred that is still the
case but by using the sequence number
you can see whether there's a gap in
those sequence numbers to see whether a
message has been dropped due to
overloading so it doesn't alert you per
se but it does allow you to filter that
data and detect when it's happening and
from that do diet things like dynamic
rebalancing in order to prevent overload
system verbosity um if you look on the
image on the right you'll see that the
original uid is zero this is the system
user id on the on the system on the
operating system um and because it works
at the kernel level it ingests all the
processing and all the file information
for the system as well including system
daemons and system level
propriety management systems
and this creates a problem because we've
talked about the bottlenecking issue
before the simple amount of data that's
being processed by the esf when you take
into account the system events is
extremely high
and because of this you end up with a
sort of overhead issue where you have to
either filter out these system level
events or you have to
allow them but then do additional
filtering for anomalous indications
so one of the things again is that you
could do it either before or after
collection so before collection as we
said would be by event muting but as
i've said before this is quite a blunt
tool and to use this for this sort of
activity it means you'll be dropping
the only way to do this would be to drop
all processes running at the system
level which can
introduce ignorance of system level
compromise which could be very dangerous
so instead you have to look at
client-side filtering but then you look
at the bottleneck issue that i mentioned
before and even when you start to filter
down the event types into individual
clients you still run the risk of data
events being dropped simply because the
system level processing event generation
is just so high so it's a becomes a
balancing act between the two
um there's no real
one-size-fits-all solution for this so
you have to sort of balance this
dynamically as well as possible
parent process id issue so this is an
ongoing issue in the mac operating
system
primarily this relates back to
identifying where the original process
was spawned from so this actually goes
back to things like xpc proxy launch d
and more recently something called
running board
so you may see at the top there's a real
ppid of -1 this is actually by using a
ppid solution um
but as you can see because it was
running on a newer operating system the
result has actually come out as -1 which
is
incorrect data just to demonstrate that
this is actually an ongoing issue that
there isn't really a permanent solution
for at the bottom you can see that there
is launch d being launched um xbc proxy
being launched uh launched by launch d
but that doesn't necessarily indicate
where an original process was called
from the reason for this is because of
how
cross-process communications work in mac
os it's not really that easy to identify
what process was initiating another
because it jumps through these other
programs so when you start to go back to
the process chain that can be gapped
due to these underlying system processes
as i said there is no real future-proof
solution the real reason for this is
that apple keep changing the way that
this cross-process communication works
for process um spawning
so any time a solution is made for one
operating system version it can be made
obsolete by the next update which as you
can imagine is
fairly frustrating
the current solutions that i was looking
at the time were true tree by john
bradley and launch xpc by patrick wall
launch xvc was actually a solution that
was implemented in
my esfang solution
but it doesn't take into account running
board at the time which means that as
was demonstrated by the minus one real
ppid
it is not a fully fledged or conclusive
solution to this
as i said this is an ongoing problem
that there isn't a one-size-fits-all
solution for yet um and it it was beyond
my scope to to try and figure that one
out
so looking at the solution that i
developed or my psc poc which i code
named es fang
so first of all i need to shout out to
patrick wardle chris ross and omar ikram
they back in the early 2020 really set
the stage for how esf could work the
sort of telemetry acquisitions and
really basic
um fundamentals of how to ingest esf
data and my plc was based primarily off
of their work and then expanding on it
and introducing capabilities and
solutions that i mentioned before for
some of the issues that i encountered
my solution was actually developed early
in 2021 um and it was based off of 52
event types back in sdk
10.15.4
the
primary reason that i did this was that
the old solutions had a fixed definition
of what event types it would ingest and
as i said before
this meant that overloading could occur
because it was a fixed number of event
types which you couldn't necessarily
deviate from which if it was causing
eventing you couldn't
change from the rigid structure
however the solution that i put in was a
dynamic solution so this allows you that
each boot you can specify which event
types you want to subscribe to so you
can have multiple espang instances
subscribe to different event types or
you can have them subscribe to multiple
event types or group types like
file
file creation data or file metadata um
uipc data um cross b
cross
process communication port data and
things like that
um
using the solution you can avoid the
overhead um the bottlenecking issue
i when i started this had never coded in
objective c before so doing
multi-threaded processes to achieve this
as a standard solution was actually a
bit outside the scope but it is it
should be easy to do moving forward from
any objective-c programmers out there
one thing to note is that because this
was not done with an apple developer id
it is a plc code so sip has to be
disabled or system integrity protection
so esf cannot be accessed with sip
enabled unless the program that you're
using has been signed by an apple
developer id so if you want to use this
for testing purposes you have to disable
sip on your system so this isn't viable
for production level systems
the other thing is that it was designed
for json output for upstream integration
so
all the output is put into json format
so it can be easily piped up into a
database for further detection
processing and easy acquisition by um
elastic or threatening teams to those
data sets
so let's go over the merterpretty use
case
use case
was done on mac os
11.2.2
i used esvang to collect all the data
and this is for the agent only so this
isn't to do with the metasploit
frameworks capability that can be piped
through the interpreter agent it is only
for the native interpreter agent
capability
this is only done on the post exploit
phase so i'm not interested in how the
agent got onto the system only what the
age you can do once it is on a system
and this was done only against a single
host so not against an enterprise
interconnected
sort of demonstration so it's not
necessarily representative of a real
life attack but it's to demonstrate what
esf telemetry is capable of
so the overall findings again the graph
on the right is very small it's
it's a representation of all the
commands that were executed and the data
that was generated as you can see from
the top solution is actually webcam
streaming which is not opsec obviously
and as you can see it generates a
massive amount of data but as you move
further down you can see that some of
the data some of the commands generated
seemingly none of very little event
types but i will go through some of
these to demonstrate some of the data
values that can be found
so during the install you can see that
uh open
read directory and protect were the
highest event types that were generated
through esf for merterpreter
installation
now memory protect and um memory mapping
for new processes you expect this to
occur and memory protect being that high
is actually not that anonymous even
though it's quite a high number but if
you turn this against what a normal
process would do on the mac estate it
actually doesn't stand out as that
anomalous especially when you look into
the internal data
the open event however is slightly more
anomalous alongside the fc ntl or file
control events the reason for this is
that during during deployment the amount
of file that it accesses in order to
enumerate number of system
enumerate the system information and
equally to change certain file access
controls can be indicative of a
temperature deployment so actually
looking at these two specific event
types does allow you to process profile
interpreter installation
on a mac operating system
so breaking down that slide a little bit
further in total 259 data points are
generated during an interpreter
installation
but 259 data points doesn't necessarily
mean that they're great data points
quantity is not always
an indicator of quality
but if you have enough data points with
enough cross referencing you can
generate more accurate processes
profiles and higher fidelity as long as
you know what you're looking for and esf
during my experimentation showed that it
had both quantity and it had quality
event types so by filtering the two
together you actually get a very
accurate representation of when
anomalous behavior has occurred
but let's look at some of the other
event types that are generated and
against what sort of commands
so on this slide again so this is to do
with file open events so on the far
right you can see webcam stream
of 478 and it's not operation secure so
that stands out like a sore thumb
process listing is slightly different so
for each process that's running it opens
an individual file for each process to
see whether it is whether it is running
um when you look at that event type
individually you can actually filter out
that scanning each individual processes
file which is quite easy to profile
if you already know what processes are
running on the system you can just scan
for
is asus is a process scanning for all
the running processing files and detect
against that
the screen share and system information
follows the same sort of
process so in order to enumerate and
gather information about how it's going
to screen share it has to open up a
number of system files and system
information it does the same way as it
does for process listing instead of
using general system information
commands from the bash terminal and
instead accesses a number of system um
files on the on the operating system in
order to enumerate that information
notify right this is a really
interesting one so edit file when it
targets an individual file to edit it
writes the information the file and you
get one writer then
upload is slightly different so when you
upload using meterpreter instead as it's
transferring the data from your
attack machine to the compromised
machine each packet is appended to the
file
routinely as it's received which
generates this nump this huge number of
write events to an individual file but
the write a size is quite small and it
actually corresponds to the size of
network packets being received from the
interpreter agent
so from this you can actually target one
processor targeting one other file in
the right event and doing it in very
small increments
repeatedly especially if you filter out
things like uh internet browsers and
things like that you very quickly can
isolate when this is occurring
io open is another interesting one so
this is to do with driver or hardware
access
and again you'd expect to see webcam
stream 220 because it's hijacking the
webcam streams
data feed
but screen share again because it's
hijacking the user interface uh display
feed it equally generates io event types
and again io kit is not something you
see commonly it's quite a
low generated event so finding any io
kit events outside of system uid is
quite anonymous and makes it very easy
to identify when malicious behavior is
occurring
this is a list of some of the valued
event types done against other that i've
isolated from other investigations
against things like uh max shell swift
sliver
merlin and other attack frameworks one
of the interesting ones uh one of the
primary interesting ones is on the right
there for pty grant uh the reason for
this is that peter where guard is for
pseudo-terminal generation so for a
dynamic user session instead of piping
the command through a bash terminal like
you normally would instead max shell
swift generates a pseudo terminal which
is a master slave comparison and
actually executes the commands that way
which is slightly weird and you don't
see that very often
so in summary
esf is extremely powerful and it's very
clear that apple is taking the time to
really look over the problems that are
occurring
during its use and equally to refine the
event types that are available
during s d progression from sdk 10.15 to
sdk 10.1 5.4 the number of event types
increased but equally so did the
capabilities of detection when the
system wasn't necessarily doing what it
was meant to
because of this um it's actually quite
nice it's actually quite reassuring
knowing that apple have made this not
really optional due to the deprecation
of kernel extensions from third parties
and the fact that they're actually
maintaining this
shows that they realize that they've
taken that control away from the
security industry but are actually
taking steps to provide all the
information and the stability that is
required
as we said some of the teething issues
to begin with have been addressed but
there are still more that exist and
during more and more experimentation
they will rear their heads as we go
forward
as i said earlier um compared to prior
solutions especially developing your
internal extensions or using open bsn
which is very clunky esf is very
streamlined it's very easy to integrate
into your existing stack
and because of this it makes integration
and development on it very easy from a
security development standpoint
looking at the use cases and some of the
other experimentations that i've done in
the past it does mean the detection
capabilities that are available are very
high and it means that moving forward we
were able to create better detection
profiles based off the esf telemetry
that is available at equally expanding
event types that they're they're
allowing
the the final point to note is that as
as i've mentioned the number of event
points that are generated especially
because the system level and even
because of the low level temperature
that's available is very very high and
because you don't have control over the
canon extension itself filtering is
absolutely essential and it becomes
not optional and it's one of those
things that we're just going to have to
deal with moving forward in when
developing using the system
that's my email uh that is the github
with the esfang source code if anyone
has any questions please feel free to
email me afterwards um we do have some
time for q a so if anyone has any
questions please
so if anybody has questions please come
in frontier to the first mic
just come to the mic yeah yeah thanks
okay uh
so uh thank you for the talk uh i was
wondering from a perspective from a blue
team uh what kind of events i'm kind of
i'm um i can find when i look at the
telemetry because uh i'm more familiar
with the windows events and sometimes we
can find like credentials passwords
what's not good so we have to remove
them do you know if there is something
in place that remove this pi data or do
i have to do it with myself so yeah
that's a great question so you'd have to
do this all manually the events that are
generated by the current extension
themselves are raw so when you get them
from the esf client side they can't be
tampered with from the current extension
side so it would will have to be
filtered on the client side itself
and there's no way of doing this further
up the chain
okay so if i decide to ingest this in
some like uh splunk so i have to take
care of this yes
okay
okay cool thank you very much no problem
yep
you mentioned that there's the user
space component that is registering for
for the filters or for events sorry yeah
uh two questions basically is there also
a unregister element that i can for
example call if i'm doing a red teaming
assessment and i got i gain access to
this user space component can i then
call an unregistered event that i
basically disable monitoring for that uh
so because the event monitoring has to
be done together and it's done by an
individual endpoint security client
object inside the process there isn't a
way to unregister them from an internal
process unless you hijack it yourself
and then basically destroy the object
and recreate it you can't do it from
external because it's an internal uh
code object all right then the other
question is also solved
are there any other questions
yep we have time for another question
nope
okay
thank you very much thanks for listening
ready
okay everybody take your seats please
we'll continue
in a few seconds
okay awesome so let's continue with the
next talk i'm happy to introduce to you
daniel feister who will tell us how to
mess with edr systems
okay
[Applause]
so good morning besides first of all
thank you to the team from besides
munich for the organization
and for giving me the chance to speak
here today
welcome to master of puppets how to
temper the edr
my name is daniel i'm the founder of the
company infosectihole with which i
mainly focus on offensive security
service on windows
and i also spend a lot of my time
in researching learning and in the area
of antivirus products cdr products and
the windows internals
today we take a look at the mitre
subtechnic imper defenses
motor disable or modifying tools
and we focus on how can we disable the
main functionalities from an edr
by targeted control tempering of
specific key components from them
but we want to achieve this without
relying on an uninstall password or
token uninstall software uninstalling
the product generally
or by using the windows security center
i would like to point out when i speak
about edr systems in that presentation i
always refer to products which are also
in cloud including an antivirus module
so an epp edr combination
also i would like to point out it's also
only my personal research my personal
experience
and the shown strategy or concept
applies to multiple products on windows
in the first step we try to get a better
understanding from the different
components from edrs in user space and
in kernel space we learned a little bit
about their functionality
and important house the relationship
between the different components in user
space and kernel space
in the second step we want to use the
gain knowledge to find a way or to find
more or less the key element
depending on the product
to permanently disable the main
functionality from an edr
and permanently get rid of
prevention by the antivirus module and
permanently get rid of detections and
telemetry footprint host isolation read
time response and edr sensor recovery
feature by the edr module
so we have big plans
at the end of the presentation we should
more or less able to depending on the
product to disable the edr
so this presentation is not about zero
days
it's more about learning a little bit
about the windows internals and how do
edr products work on windows so there
can be some situations where it also be
possible to do some activities in
unprivileged user way but normally you
need a privileged user
in high integrity or system integrity
level
but despite um everybody which has fight
around with eds knows that despite you
have a privileged user
most well-known edr products can still
be very annoying
and be a problem
normally it is not possible to simply
uninstall the product
because if the blue team has done his
homework correctly
um you have to know the uninstall
password to uninstall the product and as
mentioned in the intro we
want to achieve this without relying on
an uninstalled password
so imagine the following scenario you
have landed a successful fish and you
were also able to escalate your local
privileges
my case i was able to use the print
exploit to escalate to system integrity
context
and by having a look at the process
structure of the compromised machine
i saw that there is another interesting
user session open
so believe it or not in my case it was
one from the domain admins
and i knew okay
could be maybe could be easy to get
credentials by dumping elsa's process or
to impersonate as domain admin by token
stealing
but the problem was that i
created a many alerts in the admin
console from the product the blue team
was informed and i get isolated from the
machine
and that was the starting point more or
less from my journey
digging deeper into the windows
internals and edr products and find a
way to disable the main functionality
from them
so we start with the user's base
component of a media and have a look at
edr processors
normally edr or the processors from vdr
products are executed as process
protected light processes
this means that even if you have
achieved system integrity context it
shouldn't be possible to simply
terminate the process
but in the meantime there are a few ways
how we can deal with our ppl processors
from red team site
so
one possibility can be to use the more
or less the concept of a driver with the
with a null access vulnerability like
the msc afterburner rtcor 64 driver
so when we have a look at the picture
the first step we try to escalate
our unprivileged user to a local
privileged user in high integrity or
system integrity context and by this we
should have the privilege to load a
driver on windows
and
the by loading the rt core 64 driver
we get also right access to kernel space
because of the null duct access
vulnerability
and um compared to user space in kernel
space and windows there is no isolation
between the different code sections
this means that theoretically we would
have
whole access to the whole access from
kernel space
in this case we will use the one level
driver to attach to the e-process
structure from the ppl edr process
and we temporarily patch the ppl flag
and can then use
uh different kind of tools to terminate
the not longer protected process
so for example ppl killer uses the rtcor
64 driver in his code
or maybe cuts
brings his own device driver
also an interesting way depending on the
product it can work if you are able to
execute process hacker in a privileged
way
depending on the product it is possible
to directly terminate
the ppl process in the system session
without removing the ppl flag in the
first step
the conclusion of process tampering is
that
there are ways to temper the process to
terminate the processes but from my
observation this termination was always
just temporary so
if you terminate the process a few
seconds later or at least a minute later
the process gets restarted
and ddr is is back there
because of this in the next step we take
a look at the user space component and a
closer look at edr
services
so we have to identify the service
which is connected to the protected
process
and the protected service and the
protected process more or less builds
together the user's base component but
similar to protected processes even if
you have achieved system integrity on
windows it's not simple possible to
pause stop or disable a protected
service
but important
in also important in our situation when
we have a look at the recovery tab from
the protected service we can see that
the service is the component which is
responsible for restarting the process
the ppl process after terminating
conclusion on services
um we learned a little bit about the
relationship between protective
processes and protected services
uh similar to processes is it is not
possible also not possible to
temporarily
disable the service
but
maybe we can use a find a way to still
disable
the service
because of this in the next step we take
a look at the user base component and
edr
registry keys
so you have to identify the edrec key
from the user's base component normally
you can find them under control set
current control set services
and there are two interesting entries
so um launch protected and start entry
because time is a little bit short
we will focus on the start entry
and by the start entry we can have
influence on the initialization behavior
from the protected service
this means if we would be able to change
the end the value for the entry for the
start entry from the value 2 which is
equal to autoload to the value 4 which
is equal to disabled it should be
possible to disable the protected
service and furthermore the user space
component from the edr
but the problem similar to processes and
services from the edr even in system
integrity it is not possible with most
products
and
depending on the product when you try to
tamper the red key you will create an
alert in the web console that's what
this was the problem in my journey and
the reason why i was isolated from the
compromised machine
so the interim status at the moment we
are not are really able to permanently
disable the edr or the user space
component but we learned a little bit
about the
relationship between the different
components and user space
and we see that direct key could be more
or less the key element
by changing the value for the start
entry to permanently disable the user
space component but at the moment it is
not possible because the rec key or
their keys are protected by a temper
protection a mechanism by the edr
because of this in the fourth step we
make our first step into kernel land and
have a look at kernel callback routines
so since the introduction of kernel
patch protection hk patchguard it is no
longer possible uh officially possible
for
er vendors to set their hooks in kernel
space
so they are forced in users base to use
users based api hooking
but despite patch guard they can use in
kernel space a mechanism which is called
callback routines
and register different kind of callbacks
to realize different kind of tasks in
user space
so for example they can use the process
notify routine to register and realize
telemetry collection in context of
process creations
also they can use the process notify
routine to realize user space dln
injection and furthermore realize user's
base api hooking
but more important in our situation now
kernel callbacks routines by adr
products can also be used to protect
their own registry keys so this is more
or less could be the the key element for
the register for the tempo protection
for wreck for the registry keys
um in this case the product is using the
cm register callback function
but we will see in our first
pre-recorded demo because i have to
blur every sensitive information we will
see that
not just the cm register callback can be
used they also use all the callbacks to
uh protect the red keys
and in the first demo we try to patch
the process notify callback temporary
key disable the user space component and
have a look at the impact
so for first plausible check because at
least we want to
dump
okay
okay that looks better
uh for first possible check to see that
the enterprise component and ddr is
completely configured and at least we
want to get credentials from the elses
process we execute the pre-compiled
version from mini cuts which you can
find on github
so we execute it and we should see that
you get prevented by the anti-wireless
module and the file gets deleted
in the next step we make a short
possible check in context of
the temporal protection so
at the beginning we try to
terminate the protected process
by executing process explorer and system
integrity context but we are not allowed
to do this
also in case of the protected service
even in system integrity we get an
access denied
and if we try to tamper the value for
the start entry to disable the user's
base component to the value of four
we also get an access tonight and
depending on the product now we will
have created an alert and you get with a
high probability isolated from the
machine by the blue team
because of this we use a very nice
pc which you can find on github it is
called cheeky blinder it's not from my
side
i called it in this case pari.dxe
and
in the first
step we will use that poc to load the
driver with the availability the rtcor
64 driver to get access to kernel space
so we load the driver the driver is
initialized and in the next step we list
all the registered process notify
routines
on the machine
and the blurred one on the lower side is
our routine from the adr product in the
next step we will use the poc to
temporarily patch the callback
and after reopening the registry it
should now be possible to change the
value for the start entry and to disable
the user space component because temple
protection is now no longer
active
so we change the value to 4 which is
equal to disabled and we have to reboot
the machine
after the reboot we see at the lower
right side that now the edr product is
no longer registered in the windows
security center and also by having a
look at the structure from process
explorer we now see no longer blurred
sections because and there are no longer
processes by the user-based component
also if we check the status from the
user's base component we will see that
the star the service is now
stopped
so it looks very nice maybe we have
until now reached all of our goals
but this is not the case
because after the reboot we have a few
problems
we again
list the registered callbacks on the
machine
and we will see that all the previously
patched callbacks are re-registered
again
this means in case of prevention and
detection based on kernel callback
routines and furthermore windows uses
user-based api hooking we can have the
problem of prevention detection and
especially telemetry footprinting
so again when we execute mimi cuts we
get again prevented
and despite the user space component is
disabled
we still have the problem that the blue
team can use the isolate function to
isolate our compromi compromised machine
so in a few seconds we will see that we
lose connection to
our compromised target
so what's the conclusion from the first
demo we saw that we can more or less use
a concept of the willable device driver
to get access to kernel space
remove or patch the respective callback
temper direct key
change the value for the start entry to
4 and by restarting the machine we can
permanently disable the user space
component
but we also saw that only disabling the
user space component do not really have
a strong impact in reaching our
previously defined goals
and
no matter after
if you have rebooted the machine and you
would
again patch all the callbacks from the
edr you would still have the pos the
problem that um host isolation
the recovery feature
and
um the last one
yeah
the features which bluetooth can be used
in the web console is still active so
the biggest problem is that despite the
user's base component system is disabled
and you patch all the callbacks you
still have the problem with the host
isolation
even if you would not do a reboot and
you were um you just want to temporarily
patch the callback
um
you still have the problem that um also
your your host can still get isolated by
the blue team
so not really
efficient from
this point
and we have to take our last step
in the final step we take a look at the
edr mini filter driver
and the mini filter driver is the
component which is responsible for in
general registering callbacks
from the edr
and that is always also the problem why
even if the user space component is
disabled the mini filter driver is a
separate component is still active and
but is after the reboot the callbacks
get uh re-registered again
but the good thing is that the mini
filter has its own registry key
and
has a similar structure to the user
space component
this means
that depending on the product the
minifilter driver can be more or less
the key element
to
permanently disable the main
functionalities and get rid of
prevention
host isolation return response and edr
recovery
feature to check this out we will have a
look at our second demo
where we try to tamper the mini filter
driver
and permanently get rid of prevention
detection
telemetry collection
and so on
so we start at the point where we have
stop remember we get isolated from the
machine
so we will lift the containment and get
back connection to our compromised
target
and very important
now we uh
want to re-enable the user space
component in the first step
and only disable the minifilter driver
and to and because we want to check what
is the impact if we only disable the
mini filter
so we patched
list the callbacks again we see that the
process notify routine is still there we
query the user space component service
which is currently stopped
and we check the status from the mini
filter from ddr
and we see that the mini filter is still
running
so we open the registry
and
re-enable the user space component by
changing the value
from the start entry back from from fork
to the value 2.
but we're not allowed why
remember we have did we did a reboot so
we have to to patch the callback one
time again
and reopen the registry
so we patch it again
the process notify routine reopen the
registry
we now re-enable in the first step the
user's base component
set the value back to the value 2
and then we go to the mini filtered key
and change the value to 4 which is equal
to disabled reboot the machine
and after the reboot we see that now the
adr is still not
registered in the
windows security center but then when we
have now um look at the process explorer
we see again blood sections reasonably
this is i have to learn because um there
again uses base component processes
active
uh quality starts from the user space
service we see that the service is now
again running
but the mini filter driver is now
stopped
and
at least we check the impact
by disabling the minifilter
we see that no longer callbacks are
registered
we try to isolate the machine
again
looks like the temple protection is no
longer active
so we can change the value however we
want
without creating a detection
or creating a footprint based on
telemetry
and finally we can execute mimi cuts and
get credentials
very relaxed i would say
isolation is still not happening so it
looks like that isolating the machine is
no longer working
okay so what's the conclusion from the
second demo
we saw that compared to
disabling the user space component
depending also on the product
this mini filter has a much stronger
impact in case of reaching our goals
and to permanently
disable main functionalities from the
edr
and permanently get rid of prevention by
the antivirus module
detection footprinting host isolation
and so on
at the end of the presentation i would
like to point out that in my opinion
this is not really based on availability
more it's based on the concept from the
windows architecture
and i think every
vendor
excluding microsoft has to play on the
same rules
on windows
so many thanks for your attention
[Applause]
cool thank you very much
um we have some time for questions
any questions
yeah please just line up at the mic
and whoever is faster
testing testing seems to be working
your almost last sentence was every
vendor except microsoft has to play by
the same rules yeah
can you go through the accept microsoft
thing yeah i think the
difference is compared to third-party
vendors that
microsoft is i think not really
only forced to go in user space so
because since the production of patch
card officially it's not allowed also if
even or maybe if you use a patch card
bypass then you can also go in kernel
space
but i think that
from my experiences
microsoft has
a very deep or deeper visibility
because
it sits it adds more visibility into
kernel space compared to other vendors
so
follow-up have you looked into
cutting them off
or their edr products
do you need additional criminal space
disability disabling capabilities or
no at the moment i
i have only researching in the area of
mini filters also i also write a blog
post about elon drivers so
i had a look on different components
but not on etvs when you mean this one
etw
that will be the topic for my next
project
looking forward to it thank you
thank you
so how do you think they would go about
to fix this um do you think there's any
probability within the
kernel space or from the isolation
perspective and do you think windows 11
could fix this is there anything on the
way with tpm
2.0 to fix this
and what do you think how hard would it
be to um for
somebody interested in pen testing to
learn this um do you think there you
could make a lap about this or anybody
learn this or is it just
too oversimplified here
no you can definitely learn it i also
use it by myself
for sure you have to be very sensitive
because when you do a failure in the
kernel space you will create a blue
screen of death
but
if you know the product very well
you can use it depending on the machine
so
maybe when you are acting a very
sensitive machine it is not
maybe good when you do this
what you can do about
i could observe that well-known products
are
blacklisting uh begin to blacklist the
drivers which have vulnerabilities this
one way
but
it is possible to use different pocs to
maybe flip some bytes and get bypass
by that
by that detections
another possibility would be
there is a software vendor on the market
i will not say the name
but
they focus on a mechanism to get
which is based on the web fiber weap
variable and um the products have the
possibility to include this code into
their code and by they will realize when
there
is
something changed or tempered
they can
re-enable it or repair it in
on the machine
and do you think um windows 11 will fix
something about that or with tpm is
there any way uh vendor could facilitate
it to protect um in
in any kind it's a good question so at
the moment i had another deeper look at
windows 11
but i think generally
with the drivers
you only can use drivers which are
released
for july 2015 afterwards it is more
it's harder but there are still drivers
which you can be can be used
um
on windows 11 i can't say too much
because i have too less experience at
the moment
thank you thank you
wonderful any more questions
okay cool thank you very much very
interesting thank you
thank you
[Music]
a few
last participants
yes
okay welcome everybody back after the
break we have now ethan and javier here
on stage to i saw on the slides you're
fans of kitties yes that is correct and
you will tell us
some details about
automotive security
so i think i just handed over to you
because we are a tight schedule and you
have a lot of awesome slides
yep thank you thank you
so let's get this started um
hello everyone
thanks very much for being here we hope
that you're enjoying besides munich
after such a long jog town
so our talk is going to be obviously
about hacking i mean you guys can see
the picture there's two hackers on the
on the slide so
let's start with the introduction so who
are we i'm javier i'm a hardware
security specialist on the embedded site
i am from cadiz from the south of spain
i
enjoy reverse engineering products
because quite often more than not
i'm disappointed with the features that
devices have and i always want to
improve them myself right like why not
if i can
and i do like cake when it's not alive
has happened sometimes and i do like
barbecues i mean
barbecues are good
uh hi my name is ethan riggs
i
am from california in the u.s and i just
graduated from college about a year ago
and it's a mechanical engineering degree
and a
math degree but the math degree was more
for fun honestly
but over this last year i've been able
to work with javier a lot
and i've been really lucky to work with
him in automotive security engineering
specifically in the hardware and a lot
of the embedded systems electricity
parts and
i would really like to have that i'm
looking forward to more
so why are we here
okay well
current day car hack has become kind of
mainstream
you could see examples up there of
people who post things like
hacked on their dashboards like look at
me i've done all this work or whatever
uh a car is hacked um
that's that and that's uh was mainly
popularized in the 90s that's can
injection injection it's not all that
difficult you can tell because you could
probably look up a guide for it you
could probably find something to do it
um
in about 15 minutes or so
but
further than that
the reason why it's so simple is because
a lot of the mechanisms for security on
the ecu
are pretty simple and they kind of uh
they don't need to be but they
are because the ecu's are so lightweight
and they are so resistant to noise
because they have to be they're in cars
the cars are going to be jostling around
there's going to be a lot of noise there
has to be
i might have said that already whoops
but on the uh and this goes hand-in-hand
with diagnostics which are also pretty
simple um once you understand what
they're doing because they're talking
exclusively codes once you memorize them
it's you can read it like you read
letters on this or like you read words
um
yeah
what we'll be showing you specifically
is
three specific uh
what are the hacks
yeah some
let's call them floss in the
implementations of the state machine for
diagnostics right and to add to what
ethan was saying these two pictures i
find them personally funny you cannot
see the hacked here but it says hacked
here so you have to believe that one
typically these people start thinking
that they can inject a cam frame and
they put an ascii string right so it
shows up here now they're car hackers
and that's the first and the last tweet
you see about car hacking that they make
because
automotive security is actually not as
easy as just injecting
so
let's talk a little bit about the
automotive diagnostic protocols and this
is just a heads up we are not going to
waste waste too much time on that
and so the the diagnostic protocols
usually are based on a request response
scheme
where the tester or the device that you
connect to the car
is a client and the duty the device
under test which is the ecu acts as a
server
right
and then like a most things not
everything unfortunately
it requires like certain
authentication it has security measures
for some functionality right
so
security access which is going to be the
target of our talk uh
which is uh the service id27 hex
uh
it is the the the tool that's used most
commonly to retreat to restrict a
functionality right
so such as if you want to update the
firmware on an ecu you will
most likely hopefully need to perform a
security access
challenge response right the same thing
if there are some
things that could be critical such as
the beam right it should not be easy it
should not be easy to spoof the beam by
just changing it right or there might be
some other operations which are
restricted to the manufacturer such as
adding a new key fob like sometimes when
your car
you have a key lost
or you need a new key i mean you have to
go to the dealer and then the dealer
wants to charge you like 200 euros for
adding a new key
right that's because they have tooling
that is specifically required to do that
right i mean and security access is
actually so
relevant to automotive security that
there's even a market for selling and
buying security access algorithms
okay so
thank you
um
how the actual security access protocol
works is you first
you have the tester you have the thing
that talks to
the ecu or the diagnostic sports the dut
the device under test um
and it starts off with the tester
sending a
uh
request for security access which you
can uh which means there it is request
for security access which is that top
left uh option right there
the
uh
the dut recognizes that as you can see
right here receives it and then it
generates a 32-bit random seed
this seed is random and it's once again
four bytes which is important and will
come into play later um
then sends that seed back to the tester
where the tester receives a c and both
of them they calculate uh
using an algorithm that is generally not
known uh a key that you will have to use
to unlock it it then proceeds to
calculate the key send it to the tester
or send the tester sends it to the dut
my apologies um
and after it sends it to the duty the
dut
tests the key against the key that it
calculated on its own
and if it's correct
it has two states that it goes into it
go it says either security access is
granted or on the other hand if it was
incorrect they increment the wrong
attempts counter and they
don't give you access
okay
this is important because as i mentioned
they're kind of random but more
importantly that changes based on your
security level um
and most likely based on the dut so
if you're trying to get access to the
very lowest level you can generally get
access or you have one key for that and
then if you get access to the next one
um
a higher level um you probably won't be
able to get access with the same key and
even then they're oftentimes random
on top of that the
security accesses often times change
based on what level of security that you
want which is a little bit different but
if you're going in for a default
diagnostic section uh hex 10
you are
pro might not be able to do some things
that require a
a programming session
finish which is which is hex 13 i
believe
a diagnostic session is 10.
so to add something and maybe this helps
understand a little bit about the
security access different levels think
of a building right an office building
so and all the doors have a key like a
physical key like the one you guys most
likely used to get in your house so now
there's gonna be a let's say lower level
by lower i mean like more
more restricted so it would be the
inverse if we're talking about actually
reverse engineering so a higher level
key which allows you access to a
building so you get into the building
that's a security access algorithm right
usually that's the most simple
uh so now you got that so you got into
the building
now once you're into the building
you can have access to different
compartments offices right or rooms if
you wish
now the key for those rooms will be
different
and you can obviously not attempt to
open the an office door if you're not
already in the building right so that's
what it means by switching different
diagnostic modes diagnostics mods could
be a standard session which is zero one
right then you have you can perform
certain security access levels which
would be equivalent to getting inside
the building then if you change to as a
standard session or a programming
session right which maybe you need to
perform the this security access before
it allows you to change to that session
then you could use
a different uh more secure hopefully a
security access algorithm right
and i also mentioned before that um the
wrong attempts counter increment and
this is important because that prevents
brute force attacks
after you have three or so it depends on
the manufacturer but then it locks down
for generally 1 to 30 minutes just once
again prevent proof forcing
so
just a for
the for the ones of you that are
familiar with uh coding a little bit i
will explain it nonetheless this is if
you can read it it might be a little bit
too small but i'll walk you guys through
the code this would be
so the first part of the security access
uh challenge right response so one thing
that we need to mention
is that security access is divided into
two different parts one is requesting
the seed and the other one is providing
the key
they are separated usually you will see
them one after the other but you could
very well request a seed
read the ecu bin and then send the key
they do not need to be sequential
so what does the request
do this is the code from a duty the
bystander test perspective so you just
provide like the data which would be
like the
the raid uh contains the level so then
the
the duty checks for the level because as
we said earlier ideally there would be
different uh keys different algorithms
right
now when it checks for the label
the first check it does is
see if that security access level is
locked because the tester had too many
wrong attempts
right so if it's locked then it returns
false it tells like yeah see you later
like you've got to wait out the time
if it's not locked
then it will create a
random number
usually it's four bytes i mean there's
different algorithms right but let's go
with the standard
it will create four random bytes and
then it will just send those
four random bytes so that's as far as it
goes for the requesting the seed parts
now the second part which is actually
now the tester uh cthan showed by before
has calculated the
the reply the response and sent it so
the check key function the verify we
call it here
again we'll just
use the seed that the ecu itself
generated earlier
perform its own calculation because
obviously the ecu knows the algorithm
right
and
then it would just compare
if the result that it got is the same
that the tester sent
now
if it was the same then yep oh good
right there you go you got security
access if it was not correct then it
would increment the wrong attempts right
because remember we got here because it
wasn't yet locked so what happens when
you
up and you just like give the wrong
reply
wrong attempts increase
so
hacker kitty knows something
i don't think i personally noticed it
but i trust him he has a cool hacker
hoodie on he's attacked the planet
behind him he seems like he knows what
he's talking about
yeah
we'll we'll see what the kitty found
probably in a little bit
okay um
the next thing is man-in-the-middle
attacks specifically um
man-elemental attacks similar to can
injection
they're they're not really new they were
around in the 90s that they're used for
a lot of attacks and it's oftentimes
very effective
but
specifically
because they were developed in the 90s
at the same time
kwp2000 and uds were also designed so
you might think that they may take into
account this um
this popular attack but
obviously you probably guessed by the
fact that we're presenting on it they
they didn't
it's still it's still very widely used
in
the
current systems
yeah
which you can tell from security hijack
which are um
uh which was uh my apologies um
presented on in 2016's black hat and
defcon 24 by javier
about
this attack which uses a man in the
middle
on ecu's that are still being
manufactured today
and
it's the standard man in the middle
attack and it has three steps to it
first of all you forward all traffic
from the tester to the duty and from the
du2 back to the tester until there was a
security access and then after that
um the tester goes tester and the duty
go through the steps that i mentioned
before about getting security access and
then it disconnects and suddenly without
the tester there
you have all the security access that
the tester just gave you or would have
had access to without them in the middle
there
so
to make it like a perhaps easier to
understand with letters that even i can
barely see so i can't only imagine like
what you guys can see there so let's
imagine you can see them
so here there's the tester side there
would be the money in the middle
attacker there would be the duty here
right so tester sends the request for
seat right for security access the money
in the middle forwards that doesn't
touch
the ac receives the request so it
generates a seat
that the money in the middle attacker
forwards it doesn't touch
now the tester gets the seed it does its
calculations that we learned earlier
the money the attacker forwards the
result
now the ecu verifies the seed and when
the ecu sends a positive reply and only
when that happens
then the man in the middle attacker
kicks
the tester says goodbye and takes over
diagnostic session
so to the eyes of the duty
this the money in the mail attacker and
the tester are the same because there's
like literally no validation there's no
authentication there's nothing
so
you end up
having a secured a
diagnostic session like having security
access
without needing to know the key or the
algorithm
so
let's talk a little bit about the pros
and cons this will be more obvious later
so the pros of this attack where the the
immediate one is that an attacker does
not need to know the key or the security
access algorithm like you just don't
care you just like
take a hijacker session that's the name
right that's where name comes and the
operation is easily repeatable with
consistent timing i mean if you have a
tool that let's say performs a firmware
update right and you're going to use
that
to
hijack its session right then you can
measure how long does it take for that
tool since you press start on the
flashing process until you can get a
hijack the session right when the
security access happens so it is easily
replica
you can do it like easily over and over
consistently now the only con
is that for every time you want to
hijack a security access session you
will need to have the tool so if you're
going to be working on a project where
you're going to
attempt to hijack a session let's say
twice a day for a month you're gonna
need the tool for a month right so
that's the only
the only con
um
now
security hammer is a
a programming attack that or software
attack that javier once again developed
and it explore exploits poor
implementation project uh practices in
state machine logic
specifically for the diagnostics
and
before i really explain what exactly sec
hammer does i kind of have to explain
the uh implementation practices that it
exploits um
so
i want you to first think about
the tester it's set uh and the final
step when the tester sends the
key to the dut
the dut gives you two options you can
either have the right answer or the
wrong answer but what if
you didn't send that final answer then
you didn't get a right answer or a wrong
answer this might be what hacker kitty
was trying to point out earlier as well
but
back to set hammer
if you instead of not sending anything
you asked for
another seed
you weren't right and you weren't wrong
but you still get another seed
and then you do it again and again set
hammer does it thousands of times until
you have um
thousands of seeds and with that you can
look at uh
randomize these randomized seeds that i
mentioned earlier and you can see
if they are really random you can try to
look for some sort of pattern in them
and just gather general information on
them
yeah
so
we are running a little bit tight on
time so we're going to have to speed it
up nonetheless
again another blurry
image
hopefully you guys can see some of it so
basically this is an example of sega
hammer
on the first line we just start a
standard diagnostic station well not a
standard
zero two
so it says wait wait okay we got the
diagnostic session then we request like
seed
level one
yeah here's your seed seed level one
here's your seed seed level one i mean
on the wait time because we are using
the standard but we could go way faster
you can see that well you cannot
probably but the ecu takes it from 855
microseconds to reply we're waiting 30
milliseconds we could narrow this down
to one millisecond so we could be
getting around
500 seats per
per second perhaps
i mean like this is pretty fast and
pretty powerful
and like ethan said with this you can
actually get a feeling of the
randomness right in the security access
the seed key algorithm which until now
was not really possible
now
does it always work so
they we tested more than 40 cus
including my own car i mean like we have
tested like issues on the bench
different cars
all the stuff of the 40 38 were were
vulnerable and one of them we didn't
consider it vulnerable because it was
just repeating the same seat zero zero
zero zero like no matter what you unplug
it we plug it always the same seat so
we'll just say it's not vulnerable
and
now
this is important some seeds actually
they a little bit accounted for this not
like a lot but they did
so
they
actually if you request them the seed
again they send you the same seed again
now there's ways around that
we need to remember that diagnostics is
actually a state machine so
if you are in a diagnostic session right
and you ask for a seed then if you ask
again and you get the same seed you need
to change something now what can you
change
you can
request perhaps security access for a
different level because that would
overwrite the seed value right again
we're thinking about poor
implementations here so they have an
embedded systems they have only one
variable for seeds so when you replace
it with a different security access then
that gets replaced right
or you could try switching to a
different session right that diagnostic
station because we also said that
security access does not carry
over two different diagnostic levels
uh
so or you could just like let's go now
full here you could just
disconnect and reconnect from the ecu
right that takes longer but still that
would work
and the thing is that you don't get
locked
right like with typical security access
if you send three wrong attempts you're
gonna wait out
from 10 seconds to 30 minutes
with this method you don't get locked
out you just get like all the time all
the seats
and now sac puppet combines the sec
hammer that i mentioned and the man in
the middle attack um
it's divided into three
primary parts um first of all
it analyzes the randomness it gets the
randomness and it generates uh figures
out what kind of seed or picks out a
specific seed that it wants to use using
sec hammer then you go over to the man
in the middle part and it forces that
seed
once you're in the man in the middle
attack so that it pulls out a specific
one now once man in the middle has given
you uh that seed and you've using the
process that we mentioned before
found the key for that seed
you can use set hammer again
and force that same seed and now you
have the key
and you can get access to that level
whenever you want without the tester
using just sec hammer because you know
exactly what the c that you can get and
the key
so to add a little something to what he
has said so basically what we're going
to do is we're going to use egg hammer
we're going to figure out if the
randomness is good we're going to figure
out if there's a number that gets
repeated
more often than the others or the most
repeated number in the randomness
or we're going to figure out if there's
a pattern if there's like a counter that
goes up and since reset then you know
the initial value and then you can see
it going up all these are true cases
now if you find that value that you
already know then you're going to use
the man in the middle and what you're
going to do he will explain in a second
is you're gonna force your own seed
right and then you're gonna get the
pre-calculated uh
reply from the tester and then you will
use seghammer again to try to force the
the ut to give you the same seed that
seem to appear most commonly right or in
the pattern
sorry
okay
sec puppet follows a very similar thank
you um follows very similar patterns was
before there's uh requesting to succeed
for security uh for security access um
goes uh the mail in the middle then more
middle forwards it requests uh the duty
request
receives that seed request
um and then it responds
with the seed
calculates it um
before it
uh receives that seed
we force the seed force to seed very
specifically
sorry
so it forces the seed very specifically
um
as i mentioned earlier forces the seed
for um that one seed that we want to
have that one seed that we're going to
recreate and reuse every single time and
then once it gets that seed then it
sends it to the tester and the tester
then
calculates yeah it calculates using um
the algorithm that we don't know and
then we save that key we save it so that
we can use it whenever
so really quick
so here would be right when the duty
sent say its own seed
we would the money in the mid attacker
would replace that seed with the one
that we found out that gets
a mostly repeated right or the most
common one or the one we want to find so
then when we give that seed that we want
to give to the tester the tester uses
that seed and then it gives us the reply
to that seed
what does that mean
the pros
i again
an attacker does not need to know or
care about
keys or algorithms right with this
method
uh
this one
unlike security hijack requires a
one-time access to
a testing equipment right just to do
their money in the middle attack to get
your seat precalculated
and now the cons the
the biggest one obviously is that the
target needs to be vulnerable to safe
hammer
right if you cannot analyze the
randomness the source of randomness
then that's not gonna work too well
right or if you cannot get it to give
you many seats right fast
and then the target needs to have like
poor or predictable randomness because
it might be successful to a seg hammer
but it might actually have
good randomness
and a few use cases for these attacks
one would be this is more
a
rather fun test for testing than for an
attacker it would be like testing the
issue randomness source right like if
you get a
like an ecu front tire one and they are
telling you or you having your
requirements like yeah the the it should
be like truly random and then you
perform this test and you see it's just
sequential based on a timer on the
microseconds that's the seed right or
the ticks
have seen
then you can tell them like yeah this
does not meet whatever another one would
be like reading and writing memory or
flash offsets that are like off limits
in the sense of if you get like one of
these tools from ebay that allows you to
flash your ecu you could do security
hijack or you could do a sec puppet or
anything
and then
you could try to read into the ram range
with that which that tool does not do by
default right or any other tool
and then performing operations that are
not supported by the testers like if you
know like the payload to send to
execute a specific action but the tool
you have in your hands does not do that
you could hijack the session and then
send your authenticated command right
and that was it we were a little bit
over thank you very much for attending
everyone we hope you enjoyed the
talk
and if you have any questions feel free
to reach us out we're going to be around
yeah so if you have any questions we
have a
microphone in front
what would oh maybe you can walk up to
the microphone in the center
okay
hi good talk
um given that the system would be
vulnerable to the sec hammer could you
just go ahead and do something like like
rainbow tables just pre-computed uh the
precomputation of all the seeds that you
send
um to the testing device and then simply
save it and then basically use the one
that that that you want to use just when
it appears
so that would be doable
yeah the thing is that that would take
too much time because let's go to
this would be for the sec puppet attack
right because on sega hammer you just
get seats but you want to
have a tester pre-calculate the key
right i mean we're talking about the
scenario where you do not know the
security access algorithm or you do not
know the key so you will have the tester
and the best you could do is like
automate the testers starting the
process whatever right or if the tester
has literally a command to authenticate
right
uh then you could just like hammer the
tester
with your own seats yeah that would be
an option i think i mean it is doable
but it will be very slow that would be
mostly useful if you have a subset of
let's say
20 most repeated seats right then you
want to create a table for all those 20
seats that is doable but if you want to
do the whole
four bytes calculation that's going to
take some time i mean if you're sitting
in the middle uh you could be seeing all
the traffic going on and never sending
the response as you just did so even if
that could overcome the good randomness
um so you could work maybe with that so
that was just i know yeah i mean that
should be global yes thank you so it
sounds like you have something to
discuss afterwards off the stage
so i have to kick you off the stage you
kicked out the security
no
and we will prepare here for the next
talk
thank you very much everyone
and here we will have our next talk
about usb fuzzing
and give us a minute to build up okay
thank you
yes
okay
let's wait until the other people are in
and i think they're a bit late but
that's okay lunch break
thank you
uh
okay
okay then i see most of the people have
arrived and changed so you are now
listening to fuzzing usb from
andrei konovalov
and i wonder how you
discovered this topic but i guess you
will
show us and what
what your research will be about this
okay no problem okay then i'll hand over
to you and have a good talk thank you
okay
let's say you own an android device and
an android phone and of course since you
care about security your android phone
is locked it's protected either with a
password or a pin code or pattern
now let's say you somehow misplaced your
phone so for example maybe it was stolen
from you maybe just lost it or maybe it
was even confiscated by law enforcement
and now the question is can these people
who now have your phone somehow unlock
it and access the data that is stored
inside
and there are a few non-technical
approaches they can take to achieve this
but we're going to focus on a technical
one and since each android device has a
usb port maybe there is a way then they
can somehow attack it over usb
well normally if you just start plugging
in
like usual usb devices into an android
phone you will unlikely to get any
meaningful result to achieve this goal
but if you manage to find a
vulnerability inside the usb stack that
is running inside android then
theoretically you could use this
vulnerability to overtake the the
android device and does unlock it
and this was the focus of my talk so
hi my name is andrei and i am a security
researcher and i mainly work with the
linux and android kernels
and my talk is called fuzzing usb with
raw gadget and essentially this talk is
about trying to find a particular type
of vulnerabilities in the android usb
stack
so i'm going to start with describing
briefly describing the usb attack
surface but the part that i'm gonna
focus on are the usb drivers
then we're gonna look in i'm gonna
explain what fuzzing is and we're gonna
we're gonna look into how to apply
fuzzing to usb
after that we're going to check out a
few ways to emulate usb devices but the
way that i'm going to focus on is based
on the linux usb gadget subsystem
and
the main topic of the talk is i'm going
to show you how i used a new
kernel module that i developed called
raw gadget to do fuzzing usb to fuzz usb
drivers within a virtual machine without
any extra external dependencies so it
can be used in any type of a virtual
machine and it does not require any
additional hardware
and finally we're going to look at how
to trigger usb box with raspberry pi
zero and i actually have a raspberry pi
zero right here and hopefully we're
gonna get to the demo where i will show
you how to trigger one of the box that i
managed to find
all right all right let's start so first
let's check out the architecture of a
typical linux usb host i've split this
architecture into three parts on the
bottom part we have the hardware layer
in the middle we have the kernel layer
and on the top we have the eurospace
layer
and i'm going to describe this
architecture from the bottom to the top
so every linux device every linux host
device has a usb port
and this port is physically connected to
a piece of hardware that's called the
usb host controller
this cost controller knows how to
communicate over the usb wire
and since each hardware device in linux
is supposed to have its own driver the
host controller also has a driver in the
kernel
then this host controller driver is
connected to an abstraction layer called
usb core and behind this abstraction
layer we have the drivers of different
types of usb devices so for example we
have the hid driver and hid stands for
human interface device and this is a
driver for keyboards mice and other
types of input devices
besides that we have drivers for my
storage which is our which are flash
drives and we also have drivers for
video devices and other like there's
there's a lot of them
so this abstraction layer the usb core
abstraction layer allows a developer to
write a usb driver
regardless of what controller of what
host controller driver is in use
and finally on the very top on the user
space we have some user space
applications and user space daemons
so for example when you plug in a
keyboard and you start pressing the keys
these keys are going to be shown in the
text editor you're using and this text
editor is part is also kind of
considered a part of the attack surface
and it's running in user space
so here the goal our goal is that we
control the usb device and we want to
somehow attack the linux usb host by
controlling the device
and we can actually attack each of the
layers that we have we can attack the
physical ports so for example there is a
device that's called usb killer and when
you connect it to a usb port it's going
to charge itself from the usb
power lines and then discharge 200 volts
over the data lines and essentially just
electrocute the usb port and maybe also
the part of the boards maybe the host
controller
and then there are attacks that can be
used like on the very top the user space
level for example there was this old
windows attack where you plug in a flash
drive into a device and there is this
autorun file that is on this flash drive
and windows will just run it and this
way you could execute arbitrary code on
windows
so since i work with the linux kernel i
targeted the kernel layer
and the parts i was interested in are
the usb core and the usb drivers the
reason i didn't really care about the
host controller driver is because
different use different
linux devices might have different host
controllers and i wanted to find bugs in
the linux kernel that would affect every
linux device there is so i wanted to
find bugs in the part of the kernel that
are present on every linux device
all right to find this box i wanted to
use an approach that's called fuzzing
and fuzzing is a way to find bugs and
computer kernels in computer programs
and can also it can also be applied to
the kernel
so i have this definition for fuzzing
fuzzing is you is fitting in random
inputs into the program until the
program crashes and it works like this
you generate a random input you execute
the program and feed this input in and
then you check did the program crash
for example the program could have
seg-faulted
and if the program i mean if the program
didn't crash you just generate a new
input and you keep going
and if some point the program crashed
that means great we have found a bug
because we generated an input that
triggered a crash in a particular
program that is a definition of a bug at
least one of the definitions
so for example if we have an xml parser
we would be generating random xml files
we would be
feeding them into the parser and would
be checking for parser crashes and at
some point if the parser crashes then
perfectly we actually have found a bug
both a bug and a reproducer for this bug
in the form of an xml file
right how would we apply this to usb
if we look at the definition again so
first we replace the word program with
the word kernel because we're trying to
attack the kernel but then there are two
parts of this definition that we need to
address
so first we need to figure out how do we
feed data into usb do we use any special
hardware maybe we use some virtual
machines maybe we use some other stuff
and the second thing is we need to
figure out is what kind of inputs does
usb accept in general like what data
with do we feed in what's the protocol
and
i want to start with the second part and
talk a little bit about the usb protocol
and the most important part about the
usb is that it is cost driven that means
the device when when the device is
connected into a host the device cannot
just send data by itself it needs to
wait until a request from the host so
here on the right i have a device and on
the left i have a host and let's say we
plugged in a device into the host so at
this point device cannot start
communicating the first communication is
happening from the host site and the
host has the device like what kind of
device are you and the device for
example responds i'm a keyboard
and this response is actually done
i mean the device sends a few structures
to the host and these structures are
called usb descriptors
these descriptors encode information
about the device so for example they
decode the class id which is a keyboard
and they encode the device manufacturer
and so on and there's there's quite a
lot of stuff
so
now again the device cannot just start
communicating and now the host asks the
host knows how to handle keyboards and
now the host asks the device like what
kind of keys do you have on what what
purpose do they serve
and now the device responds i have this
many keys intended for this purpose
and the device and now the host has
alright you're now connected to which
the device will respond okay this is
didn't fit into the slide
all right so the key part here that the
device only responded to requests from
the host
and this is actually happening so for
example if you plugged in a keyboard and
you started typing in keys you started
pressing on keys the keyboard cannot
just tell the host by itself that this
key particular key is now pressed the
host need to ask for it
and this is it works like this so the
host just keeps asking the keyboard like
which keys do you have pressed and it's
asked like any keys pressed here the
keyboard says no any keys for executive
versus no and at some point you press
the key and the keyboard the keyboard is
going to respond now i have this
particular key pressed
all right
so the key part about the protocol is we
cannot just send data right
so the way a usb file would work is
first it would wait until a request from
the host then it would generate a
response to this request and send the
response back
and keep doing this in a loop until at
some point in time it the fuzzer also
needs to monitor the host for crashes
and if at some point in time the host
crashes that means we managed to find a
bug
okay this is like a high level higher
level overview of how usb fuzzing would
work
now let's go back to challenge number
one so we need to figure out a way how
do we fit data into the usb
and i started looking for ways of doing
that and the first way that i found is
to use the face sensor board and i
actually have it right here
so this board allows emulating arbitrary
usb devices
and essentially this board has two usb
ports one on the left one on the right
and one of them is plugged into a
computer that you control and another
one is plugged into the computer you're
trying to attack
and then on on the computer that you
control you can run a python library
that allows you to receive usb requests
and provide responses to them
and this way you can emulate devices and
of course since we can emulate devices
we can use these these boards for
fuzzing
the problem with this approach is that
it requires hardware and fuzzing with
hardware is challenging
so for example
we need to monitor our host we're trying
to attack for crashes and if it crashed
we need to reboot it and doing this with
hardware is is difficult
since that it would be great to have
some kind of approach that works inside
the virtual machine
so i kept looking and the next thing i
found is the usb redire module in common
and qam is a type of a virtual machine
and this module allows the host
to inject arbitrary usb traffic for the
guest kernel that is running inside camo
and this can also be used for pausing
and there is actually other it's called
virtual usb fuzzer
and yeah it uses this qmo usb reader
module
so the great thing about this approach
is that we don't need any hardware we
only need camo
but this is also a problem because this
approach depends on qmo so we cannot use
other types of virtual machines to do
this kind of fuzzing
and
this was also a problem for me and the
reason was that i wanted to use a fuzzer
called syscaller and i'm going to talk a
bit more about it later but the key
thing about this caller is it it mainly
runs on google cloud engine and google
cloud engine is another type of a
virtual machine
and that google cloud engine does not
have the usb reader module so this this
approach is great but it was not quite
what i was looking for
so i kept looking
and another thing that i found was the
linux usb gadget subsystem
and this subsystem essentially allows
you to take a linux based board like a
raspberry pi zero that i have right here
and turn it into a usb device so there
is a way to configure this board so
whenever you plug it in over usb
it pretends to be a device and the logic
of the device is controlled by the
software that is running on the board
right and most of the linux based
workplace most of the popular boards
that exist they have the support for
this so the beaglebone black also tested
and i had an android board that also
worked and the raspberry pi boards also
work
and
theoretically if we if we have
this kind of device we can also use it
for fuzzing probably because it allows
you to define usb devices and the
problem here is that if you're using an
actual linux based board we still
require hardware
but maybe maybe we can figure out a way
to get rid of this hardware requirement
so let's try to take a look into the
architecture of the gadget site so this
this
this particular feature of these boards
is called this board pretends to be a
usb gadget so let's take a look at the
gadget architecture and try to figure
out a way maybe
we can do something about it
so on the left i previously shown you
the architecture of a usb host and now
we're going to look into the
architecture of usb gadget
and here we're going to start from the
upper part so from user space and the
logic of the usb device that is being
emulated by linux based board is
driven by a user space application
then there is a gadget driver in the
kernel and this gadget driver defines
the type of the usb device so for
example there is a gadget drivers for
emulating keyboards there is a gadget
driver for emulating video devices and
so on
then similar to the host we have an
abstraction layer called usb gadget core
and behind this abstraction layer we
have the device controller driver unlike
the host controller driver this driver
is for the device controller that knows
how to communicate over the usb wire
while being a device not being a host
right and then we have the usb port
which is supposed to be plugged into usb
host and this part on the left allows us
to use a linux based board to emulate
usb devices
so now the question is if we want to use
this approach for fuzzing we need to
figure out which gadget driver do we use
and if you use it just the driver for
keyboards there is of course this of
course means that we can only connect
keyboards which is not very useful when
when we're fuzzing we want to connect
all kinds of devices
so i started looking and i found a
driver that's called gadgetfs and it
allows emulating almost arbitrary usb
devices and the keyword here is almost
the way gadget device works is
when it starts it asks the user space
applications for the usb descriptors of
the device it's going to emulate
and then whenever this this gadget stack
receives a
usb descriptor request from the host the
gadget fs is going to respond to this
request by itself without asking user
space
if it receives other types of requests
it's going to pass them to user space
and ask them for response and then
give it back to the host
there are two problems with gadgetfs the
first problem is that
gadgetfs does not pass all usb requests
to user space it responds to them on
their own
to some of them on their own and that
means that if the same usb descriptor is
requested twice we cannot provide
different responses
and providing different responses would
be very useful for fuzzing because this
would be likely to trigger bugs in the
host
and another problem which is actually a
bigger problem is that gadgetfest has
validity checks for the usb descriptors
that we provide to it and that means we
cannot send mall form descriptors to the
host we have to we have to send the
correct ones and we want to send
malformed descriptors because we want to
trigger bugs
so initially i wanted to remove these
countries from gadgetfs i started trying
to change the gadgetfs code but it has a
lot of legacy code in there also the
interface is a bit unusual so it was
hard to adapt gadgetfs instead i just
implemented my own gadget driver this
took some effort but i managed to do it
and this driver it works similarly to
gadgetfs but it allows you to emulate
arbitrary usb devices and the key
differences are that all usb requests
that these gadget drive received
they're passed to user space to get the
response and then there are no sanity
checks on usb descriptors
and i actually mailed this request to
upstream so i i mailed the linux kernel
patches and they were accepted in
version 0.7 i think it was released it
was over a year ago
right and
i have a github repository in case you
want to check it out with some examples
and instructions on how to run raw
gadget
all right at this point we figured out
how to we have our own
new gadget driver that allows us to
emulate arbitrary usb devices we still
have that problem that we need hardware
to do that so what we could do here is
that this part of the stack the gadget
part of the stack is going to be running
on our linux based board
we can take a separately physical usb
host we could plug this board into the
host and then
run the fuzzer as a user space
application and this is a way to use the
linux usb gadget subsystem for fuzzing
for physical fuzzing of usb hosts now
the problem is that we need hardware
right
and is there any way we can get rid of
the hardware as it turns out there is
linux actually provides a solution to
this and this solution is called the
damage drivers
so essentially linux has virtual host
and device controllers that are
connected to each other within the same
kernel
so previously we had the gadget part of
the stack running on the linux based
board and the host part of the stack
running on a separate host device but
here we can actually run both parts of
the stack on the same device or like
within the same kernel so this all would
be running within the same environment
and this is actually the key slide of my
talk so
we have our fuzzer running as a
eurospace application
we use row gadget to emulate arbitrary
usb devices we use the damage drivers so
that the usb device devices this fuzzer
emulates they're going to be connecting
to the very same kernel the fuzzer is
running on
and this way you can do fuzzing inside
the virtual machine or inside you can
take an android phone and you can just
run raw gadget and virtual damage
drivers inside
and you don't need any external hardware
you're going to be fuzzing on an android
phone internally and you're going to be
reaching usb drivers from from within
the kernel
right
all right and yeah this this was the
approach that they ended up using and
i actually integrated this approach into
syscaller syscaller is a kernel fuzzer
that is developed by google and it was
initially developed to target the linux
kernel but right now it targets a bunch
of different kernels
and it has a dashboard you can check out
the dashboard the dashboard shows
thousands of bugs that this fuzzer has
found and all of them are public you can
check out debug you can check the buck
report you can check out the zero
producers so essentially
dc programs that you can run to trigger
a particular bug
and i integrated usb fusing into cisco
and
so far it is found over 300 bucks in
different parts of the linux usb
subsystem some of them are in drivers
and a few of them are in the usb core
layer
and the only thing that i failed to do
so far
is to actually exploit a linux or
android device over usb so there are 300
bucks and these bugs affect some of the
drivers but not all
all of these drivers are present on an
actual linux on for example in ubuntu
and
when it comes to android android also
restricts the set of enabled drivers
severely so mainly maybe only a few of
the bugs they actually affect android
but the ones that do affect android i
failed to find a way to exploit them at
least so far
now i want to get to the final part of
the talk which is i think this is the
most the most awesome part
so first
when using his caller to fuss the kernel
whenever c scholar finds a buck it
generates a reproducer for this block
and a reproducer is essentially a
sequence of actions
the father can do or like the the
the father can do to trigger a
particular bug
so
syscaller has a utility a tool to run
these reproducers it's called csx proc
so essentially when this caller
generates reproducer you can run csx
proc
and trigger the bug and it works with
usb as well because we're doing the
fuzzing in vm we take in the reproducer
with fuzz
we run it in the semi-vm and we can
trigger
the debug that the father has found
but the key thing here is that the
interface between user space and the
kernel is stable and it is stable in the
way that we can use any type of a device
controller or device controller driver
so which means we can take raspberry pi
zero so we can take the reproducer that
was generated inside the virtual machine
we can copy it onto raspberry pi zero
and we can plug this raspberry pi zero
into the physical host
and this way we can replay the
usb communications we generated in a
virtual machine with physical hardware
right
okay actually let me let me try to show
you do you still have five minutes this
should be enough for the demo so here i
have a separate linux laptop
all right
and i also have raspberry pi zero so
what i'm going to do is i'm going to
plug this raspberry pi zero into the
laptop and let it boot
so
what i'm going to do now is it's it's
this demo is kind of weird because i
need to show you the screens of both my
laptop and the laptop i'm trying to
attack so i'm going to be using a
web camera
to
record the screen of the laptop i'm
trying to attack
okay let's see if this works
okay we can see something
all right so this laptop is running
essentially it's ubuntu kernel and the
kernel version is quite new
we see it it's from april 22nd so
essentially it's one month old
all right so what i'm going to do is on
this laptop where i plugged in the
raspberry pi 0 i'm going to run the dmsh
minus w command
it's having trouble to focus
the message minus w command which is
going to show us the kernel lock in real
time
right and
i'm not actually so for this demo i'm
not running the simple the the most
basic version of raspberry pi zero i'm
running the version with wi-fi and it's
called raspberry pi zero w
and
i configure this board in a way that
when i plug it in it boots and it sets
up a wi-fi point so instead of using a
bunch of wires to connect to that by
zero i'm going to be using a wi-fi
connection i'm just gonna ssh onto the
board
okay now let's see
if we get if we have the
wi-fi connection so on some technical
conferences actually this demo has a
problem uh we do have it because wi-fi
is being
attacked all the time it's very hard to
connect but
it worked
all right
now we have ssh onto raspberry pi zero
so on the left
we're gonna see the part of the screen
that is recording the kernel lock of the
device we're trying to attack and on the
right we have the connection onto the
raspberry pi zero that is plugged into
this device
so first we need to insert the raw
gadget module and now what we're going
to do i have collected the reproducers
for the usb bugs that's this color found
and i have them
right here so this this
this is a special syntax that cisco uses
to describe reproducers so essentially
csusb connect
means that this
particular line is going to
emulate a type of a usb device and the
type of the device is described by all
of these arguments
so what i'm going to do is i have this
run script and this route script
essentially runs sees exact proc that i
showed
here so i'm gonna do run
reprose csbot
and it takes a little bit of time to
initialize so essentially what is this
is going to do i have about 300 391's to
be exact 391 different
usb devices that will be
replayed one after each other and this
raspberry pi 0 is going to be connecting
these devices to our physical host
and let's hope that this works
okay now it's started so as you can see
on the right we have the log from the
from the
part of the code that is emulating usb
devices and on the left we can actually
see in the d message that
these new devices are being connected
and if we wait for some time i'm not
sure
yeah at some point i think this
particular
this particular sequence of crashes so
at this point you can see that the the
messages stopped that usually means that
we managed to crash the usb stack that
is running on the linux laptop and if
you could look
look
i don't have the mouse here
okay okay now we got something so
actually the mouse is broken right now i
mean the the touchpad broke because
touchpad is connected over usb and will
likely kill the usb stack on the machine
so you can see a part of the stack trace
that is that was triggered and
yeah this is just some generic stuff so
probably something something something
bad happened
the problem with running reproducers
like this is that some of them corrupt
memory and without running a memory
corrupt detector a memory corruption
detector on the device it's
hard to tell what exactly happened
all right we're running very long time
so let me let me
quickly finish the presentation
yeah this was the demo so it worked
all right so the summary is that i try
to attack
android and linux devices over usb and i
tried to find bugs in linux kernel
drivers
so the result of the work is that i used
row gadget and i use the dummy virtual
controllers to that allow
fuzzing either or in a virtual machine
and on device and this was integrated in
this color and we managed to i managed
to find a way to run this reproducers by
hardware without any additional hassle
and yeah by using raspberry pi 0 and row
gadget we get a very cheap tool for usb
attacks so essentially
phase density costs about 80 bucks this
tool costs about larger pi zero only is
only for ten dollars you can buy
and finally the one final not very
important that cisco is hiring so just
in case you want to work on linux kernel
fuzzing or linux kernel security in
general there is a team and at google
and they are here in the munich office
and they are looking for a new team
member so if you want to work on cisco
this is the place you can apply
so with this thank you and we have no
time for questions so just in case you
can catch me at the break and ask
qualifications
i'm yeah no it's working um thank you
andre so um we don't really have time
for questions on the audience but um
maybe you can yeah answer a few
questions outside yeah yeah i'm going to
be right outside right now and so you
can't ask questions and our next talk
here will be
regarding
building an ica ics firing range within
your home kitchen with moritz and
nico so stay tuned in five minutes we'll
be back
cool everything works
yeah it's
you can take this off now right
around a little bit low on time
thank you
is
um
okay
okay um so we closed the door i think we
can start nico and moritz
we'll be talking about the kitchen
within series or something no let's see
let's see um thanks everybody for for
being here and thanks for having us um
we're going to present in the next 30
minutes a project that have been we've
been working on moritz and i for the
last year and a half
and i was building a firing range for
industrial control systems
um we did that in our kitchen because of
corona so there was no way to do it in
the office and that's why that's that's
that's why um we're going to you can see
we didn't bring so we actually created a
model we didn't bring that but we're
going to show some
some videos of it later and then for
everybody to take away as well the
lessons that we learned so if you're
planning to build something similar in
your kitchen then you know what to
do and not to do hopefully
um so roughly that's the the agenda for
the next 30 minutes um we
try to get everybody on the same page
what we understand is firing ranges what
we understand as ot or operational uh
technology then mods will talk us
through how the building of the ics fire
english actually um unfolded we're going
to demonstrate it and then the lessons
learned and then at the end the
questions
about us i'm niko i'm the red team lead
for nvizo
i've had my fair share in ig security
and i focus on ot security as well in
the past two years
and most of you
my name is summers i'm part of the
software and security team and r d team
at nvizo and i'm an iot and ics
enthusiast and i try and get a hold of
as many devices as i can try and break
them
um a few words about nvizo
it's it's a company that's roughly nine
years old originally founded in in
brussels a noun office in frankfurt in
munich um
we have 150 colleagues at the moment so
it's um it was just a very small subset
obviously um but what's interesting is
that in viso it's dedicated to invest 10
of the revenue into r d and that is how
we can fund this project and the time
that went into it um so that's um that's
how good that that happens
now firing ranges um what do we
understand as fine range of course it's
it's somewhat a controlled interactive
environment um it's an abstraction of a
real environment think of a toy train
for example instead of having the real
train of course to play with it should
be as realistic as possible and that's
what we try to do as well so you will
see that we built a a model of a basket
bridge so a bridge that has leaves that
are lifting so we tried to move letters
as closely to the real thing as possible
it should be reusable so we want to use
it for trying out stuff um in our
context it's i.t security so we want to
try out attacks for example or defense
mechanisms
and of course if we run an attack
we should be able to do it again and
again and it should have that playground
factor so it should be something where
we can approach things from different
angles and just see what happens if we
try that way and so on
why
do we need a fire range
so the first that comes to mind and that
was our motivation as well at the
beginning is for training purposes
so we've done a lot of id security ot
security was fairly new to us back then
so what we wanted to do is to train our
people as well and ourselves on how to
approach ot next networks and how to do
security assessments on those
the the lab itself the way it turned out
is very suitable for awareness trainings
as well because it's very visual so if
you run an attack for example then you
can make some some lights stop blinking
or the bridge leaves are not moving
anymore something else is happening
there's a buzzer going off so for
awareness trainings for example um very
useful for testing if you had any o2
components for example pll plc's that
you want to try out that you've never
played with before you just plug it into
the lab or the firing range configured
and then make it work and then last but
not least for further development of
tools for example for forensics
so we actually used that lab for
forensic training as well which
you'll see then at the end as well very
briefly
now
ot and ics operational technology are
computing systems that are used to
manage industrial operations for example
the manufacturing process and the subset
of that uh industrial control system so
the integration of hardware and software
components to control processes for
automation and humanitarian institute
mentalization
we do see two candidates here
on the slides on the right hand side you
see a programmer programmable logic
controller it's very difficult for me to
say that plcs which is essentially the
core unit if you will of some automation
process so it's it's the cpu that that
runs
was connected to to sensors and
actuators that drives for example
conveyor belts and so on and then on the
other side that's an hmi human machine
interface where the operators normally
oversee the process they can start stop
processes or react on errors and and so
on so it's just the interaction with the
machinery behind it
now um i bet you're all familiar with it
the what many might not be familiar with
is that there's a difference between
security requirements
for operational technology and i.t
whereas in iit normally you would
probably argue that confidentiality is
has high priority so you don't want a
customer database for example to leak to
the internet that would be very severe
of course if you shut down that database
i um
in regard to availability then that can
have some impact but it's probably not
on that same level whereas in ot it's
very different confidentiality usually
doesn't play a big factor but
availability does so if you think about
power plants for example if they just
switch off or steal
a steel mill if that
is corrupted somehow the process and you
need to restart that might take days so
there's a financial impact obviously but
also the the production behind just the
delay it takes to get every everything
back up and starting so availability is
key
now attacks against ics this is the
sun's ics cyber kill chain it usually
comes in what
as far as we know it comes in two stages
the first stage usually goes against the
it network so the way we know it there's
a resource development phase at the
beginning then delivery where for
example phishing emails are sent to
somebody working in the office
they click the attachment
the the payload installs
on the workstation ensures persistence
and establish c2 communication and then
the the adversary can act through the c2
channel and um yeah their objectives
whatever it may be now if the attack
goes against ot then this is also true
so we are that that stage where we have
a foothold on the the enterprise um we
then recon where is ot located we
identify possible jump servers or dmz
that we need to pass through in order to
get there once we're there we locate the
targets we develop capabilities testing
them so that might be payloads that we
want to download on plc's for example
then we download them install and
execute the attack which could be the
disruption of some manufacturing process
for example
the objectives
of those attackers are commonly either
the the permanent loss of view of
control for the operator so that they
can't see the process they can't
interact with it anymore it could be
temporary only for vm control again but
also safety which is a very important
factor and the same of course for
manipulation and the safety aspect is
also very different to what we have in
i.t there's rarely at least i don't know
of any attacks against i.t
infrastructure where you would say
safety was a concern safety of people
specifically and we had a case in 2017
um which happened in saudi arabia i
guess a power plant where they found a
malware that targeted safety equipment
it didn't succeed but the assumption is
that if it would have compromised those
safety systems
it would have then disabled some of the
procedures that would have triggered in
course of emergencies for example if gas
is leaking um into the outside then
those safety systems would prevent this
now if you modify or manipulate that
then you couldn't or you wouldn't
prevent it so this would not only be
then of course
um an issue for the um the the provider
here but also for everybody that lives
around the power plant if hazardous
gases are leaked to the outside
now morris is going to talk us through
our ics-5 range please right
thanks
so how did we actually go about building
this ics firing range well let me maybe
first start with uh what we had in mind
what were our driving motivation behind
building this so as niko pointed out we
have a difference in security
requirements in ot
comparing to i.t right
and we then have to adapt those
differences obviously into our
approaches to performing security
assessments right
so
most importantly what we have to do to
pay attention to is of course the safety
aspect we can never know really what is
the safety impact of of hacking a ot
device if we don't have accurate
depictions of the documentation of what
actually those devices do
so what we want to do and what we then
succeeded to do is to build a
playground where we can
perform internal training
and to then perform research and
development on this
so
we developed the concept of a water
treatment plant which was comprised of
three
uh water filtration units and then
as
actuators pumping stations which pumped
water from one filtration unit to the
next one
and to back this up and to
represent a more or less realistic
environment that drives this we had also
scada and an enterprise network behind
this fully virtualized
so when we worked on this we were then
contacted by a client who said well we
really like what you're doing we would
like to have this for us as well
because we are actually operating
critical infrastructure and as part of
this they operated bridges pasco bridges
and they wanted to have this such a
playground for their own digital
forensics and incident
response teams
to find out okay what happened
post-compromise
and this should be also a mobile
solution so they can
then do those trainings at different
sites
so we adapted our concept to
to do basketball bridges
and this was our very first concept
so here you can see it's basically an
aluminum frame on wheels
in the very top there you have a scale
model of bascule bridges
then in the lower half there's a front
and a back side in the front side you
see rot equipment such as plc's
power distribution power supplies and
the back there the
the area that you can't really look into
because there are black panels there
should be the virtualization server
so uh we were familiar with building
virtual environments uh we were somewhat
familiar with assembling stuff but not
very much with 3d printing and um
yeah just uh designing this this bridge
for example so that's what we started
with
you can see in the center there's our um
our cad model of the bridge um you saw
there were two bridges right so the
other side is just a flip version
and we 3d printed those so
what i would like to point out here in
particular are the most prominent parts
so here you can see the bridge leaves
which are lower and race there are
switches that are our sensors which
detect whether our bridge is now in a
fully opened or fully closed state and
of course we also have traffic lights
and a road barrier that goes up and down
and when all of this works it's synced
so that there's a process where the
bridge opens and then the traffic
barriers are down and the lights
indicate that no traffic should happen
here
and it should all hold and then they go
back down again the road barriers go up
again and then traffic should commands
there
as we said as part of our title we built
this in our kitchen this is my kitchen
and that's my oven actually much to the
dismay of my wife we did this in my
kitchen just to keep those prototyping
intervals very very short
so typically i would design a model in
the evening kick off the print this
would take hours and hours and hours and
sometime in the afternoon it would be
done on the next day and i could take it
out of the printer and try and assemble
it and see if it works or if i have to
adapt
anything about it
so
at that point we got a model but it
couldn't really do anything on its own
so we needed to do more to it we first
assembled it
then we got a hold of those aluminum
profile beams and built the frame and
the back plate for the electro cabinet
inside
we put all the ot equipment in there
wired everything together
installed the bridges and wired them
those are roughly 50 individual
connections
that we then put down to the ot
equipments
we put
panels to it because they look nice and
they of course
hinder you from actually reaching into
it while it's operating you shouldn't do
that
some sweet backlighting we put in there
so you could actually see something
because it was getting dark
and we did a lot of testing an awful lot
of testing many hours were put into
debugging all of this
and we at some point even had to recite
using an oscilloscope as you can see
here
to debug the motor control signals
because they were not really in sync and
they were off
so we had the physical build but this
only gets you so far what we were really
interested in was actually powering it
with a fully virtual environment in the
back right so let's get to the network
infrastructure that was then used for
example for kill chains
this should again be somewhat realistic
and should be extendable
so here's our network infrastructure
those are four networks
the networks in the dotted rectangle
they're mostly virtual while the ot
network down there is
mostly physical
let's go through all of those
they were implemented in an e6i server
and they all use opn sensors for
segmentation and segregation so just for
routing and for the firewalls
now let's let's see so in the enterprise
we had an enterprise network we had a
domain controller and a main joint
office workstation which we heavily
abused for initial foothold in our kill
chains
so there would be for example the case
where we had a phishing mail and this
the attachment of this phishing mail got
opened and then it was compromised
there was also a web ui that would allow
office workers to then have a look at
what the process is currently
like in the
uh at the bridge
then in the skydive network we had an
operator workstation which would allow
you to
more closely
monitor what's actually going on in the
process taking place like what are the
individual pieces of the bridge doing
there was an historian which actually
grabbed production data and stored it in
a time series database and a jump post
to which we will get back later
the dmz honestly stays very empty for
most of the time and still is we plan to
put a
windows update server may be there but
we didn't
and then in the ot
network we have of course all our rt
equipment
so there are four plc's one
rather new model so there was an s7 1500
they were all siemens plc's that was the
area supervision that one would
orchestrate the other ones then there
are two more or less budget models s7
1200s
they were the lifting substations and
they drove the leaves and the barriers
and then lastly we got a later scene
model the s7 300
which is if i recall correctly close to
30 years old
and that drives actually the lights
and of course we have the manual
override hmi so where you can actually
tap and change stuff around physically
we also built in a cctv system using
raspberry pi's and pen tilt cameras
and here's one last
virtualized station so that's the
engineering workstation that will be
used to actually program the controllers
and that would also be
more or less the last step in our kill
chain where which we could compromise to
then
effectively compromise the plcs because
this one could program those right
so
knowing about this let me show you what
it really looks like when we all
assembled it
let's see if the video works
ah nice okay
so here you see the model on top and it
will just start its cycle of lowering
the barriers and here we can see in the
hmi that what you see on screen is
actually sync to what's going on in the
bridge model
so now for example they are raising
again
taking a look inside we can see a whole
bunch of wiring stepper motors
uh and actually
also active cooling
we had to do this a whole bunch um over
the whole firing range because it got
really really hot
then there on the back you can see a
desktop case so that's our esxi server
there's the big switch and an ap for
wireless and easier debugging
and that's pretty much it and that's
what it does all the time and now at
that point we can go there and try and
compromise it
then we have some backup slides in case
the video wouldn't work you can skip
those
now for the lessons learned what did we
learn we learned a whole bunch
first of all regarding the ics lab setup
we learned that especially with the
hardware compatibilities and
dependencies that you've got
assembling such a fire range can get
somewhat complicated when you're not a
domain expert we are not
ics engineers we are not mechanical
engineers so those were things that were
rather new to us
you have to take several things into
account right so power supply what kind
of power source do you need what kind of
protocols do those devices support what
kind of protocols are relevant to your
cases to your scenarios maybe
so this can get uh
this can be quite a bit uh then the the
software licenses are quite pricey we'll
get into this later
and a practical thing that we figured
out was that the stepper motors they
tended to overheat and that was actually
very bad for 3d printing
again we didn't really do this prior to
this project so this was all new to us
we are not mechanical engineers so
especially the part with the bridge
leaves opening and closing this was
quite challenging for us to develop
to design and then to implement and to
make sure that it doesn't break because
it broke a whole lot
and then factor in the fact
that printing is very time consuming as
i said i would kick off a print
at night and it would maybe be done in
the afternoon next day we had prints we
had individual parts that took up to
three days to print so 72 hours and if
anything goes wrong you're done it's bad
and also if you're not an expert in 3d
printing you will run into a whole lot
of problems
ranging from from a to z so we had for
example problems
with the prints not sticking to the
print bed so the print would just go and
the filament would go all over the place
but it wouldn't be there where you
actually needed it
and then to have
models that you can actually adapt to
your needs and to to modify further you
would do this in cad
again we didn't know cads prior to this
so this was also required a whole bunch
to learn
but also there were practical challenges
so uh this is this is the firing range
it was 80 centimeters by 120 centimeters
in size uh only the frame was in meter
in in in height
and if you factor in the wheels and the
models it's more like one and a half
meters so every time we wanted to move
it anywhere we needed to get a very very
big van
which was mostly empty but we needed it
to put it there upright so we needed the
vertical space
and then also we had problems with the
models right so here you would see that
the the road barrier would collide with
the lights up there
it wasn't very nice the stepper motors
were heating up there was the wiring
which was all over the place
and there was very little clearance for
the moving parts
this was iteration one so we iterated
one more time and their iteration two we
addressed all of those problems here you
can see those lights are set back so
they don't collide anymore there are
actually fans that we built into it so
there's active cooling and you can just
let it run for hours now it won't every
heat which is nice
if you want to do maintenance or if you
have to do it there's a central back
plane where all the wiring is just going
which is nice and of course the
clearance we have way more clearance
here and then no more parts scraping on
other parts so that's great
what's the bottom line though
we started this in january 2021 we put
more than a thousand hours of manual
work into it
more than 900 hours additional to the
first 1000 hours which is net 3d
printing time and a whole lot of this
time was overnight
and over the course of the whole project
we burned through more than eight
kilograms of filament
we spent roughly eighteen hundred
eighteen thousand us dollars
on the whole project most of this for
hardware but as you can see three and a
half thousand euros are use dollars just
for licenses
which i hadn't expected
in the beginning but here we go
and we actually destroyed some stuff
over the course of the project so there
were two stepper motors that we actually
burned through one plc that's died
presumably from faulty wiring
uh and one motor driver that also died
due to 40 wiring and at times we lost
parts of our sanity to be honest
and at that point i would like to hand
over to nico again about what's next
what is next
thanks for watching
okay
so you
if you paid attention i'm sure everybody
did um the video differed the video that
we showed differed from the 3d model for
example um so if it wasn't clear we we
actually created two iterations the
first one where the problems the rules
that that most mentioned and then to
make it better we created a second model
so there's actually two models what we
should be doing is creating a third
iteration to address some of those
points that
are still not
not that great so for example mobility
is an issue you need still to rent a van
to transport it and it was supposed to
be very mobile it really isn't at this
moment um so it could be for example
that the disassembling of the entire um
firing range is somewhat easier um maybe
yeah that parts could be taken out
of it um also the modularization is
something that we we had in mind for
example so we talk about basket bridges
now but maybe we want to have a small
town or toy train or something running
on top without changing the hardware
underneath because it's
most likely going to be very similar so
we just
would replace the the top on the model
i.e the bridges with something else and
then download new software on the plcs
and then it should be done so this is
something that that could be done in
third iteration whether or not we're
doing this we have to see um
it's not clear at this moment what we
certainly will be doing is develop more
scenarios so this the intention of this
firing range was to use it for training
and we've used it for forensics training
in ot for example so we had a two today
workshop on this which were quite great
um but we currently don't have scenarios
for example for penetration testing or
red teaming in ot so this is something
we want to to work on as well um
similarly uh monitoring and detection ot
i think is a topic that's very
interesting and
and many people are interested in
interlooking that as well even in our
company so for for this developing a
scenario would be very
worthwhile
now if if you're interested in ot or
want to know more about this project
we're here to answer questions of course
we're going to be outside you know after
this talk you can reach us
via these email addresses um if you want
to know what nviso does for ics there's
a page for that as well and otherwise we
have two twitter handles and a block
that you can look up on the block there
is a series um about this fire range as
well so
parts of what we presented a bit more
detail as well in some in some areas and
just check it out and
see for yourself
good
any questions
thank you
thank you thank you
so do we have questions i'm sure for the
audience the front microphone if you
want to take any questions
so
okay i see chen
please come up
telecool so thank you very much for this
um i was wondering
what other materials did you consider
when putting this model together like
did you did you think about legos or
something like this or did you go
directly to printing
i think we lego was in talks there was
some talks about using a bit more wood
as well to to get some parts done i'm
not sure what we did not decide on lego
in the end
to be honest
not sure
i think it just looks cooler if it's 3d
printed maybe it was occupied by
children or something yeah as well
yeah
i think the probably the possibilities
are it's just a lot more possibilities
to
create stuff if we have a 3d printer
then we're fully in control of how it
should look like and
especially the smaller parts than they
are needed
and i'm a long time no lego player but
i remember there were no real bridges
moving bridges so you only had trains
and stuff
okay um do you have any similar projects
like
other companies doing similar test
ranges firing ranges that you exchanged
ideas with
honestly we no we didn't we know that
not for bridges but but of course
siemens for example they they have
developed um
also test environments for for traffic
controls for example
but it's a different price range as well
and i'm not sure if they
they would disclose too much about their
projects towards us
but no
actually don't know
maybe over you find somebody from
siemens over a coffee
so do we have any other questions
one coming up
so
most of the ics or the ot environment
will have some physical control
over the process not only that some
malware can shut down the process while
building your fire range did you also
consider physical controls like you
detect some attack or something and then
there is
somebody who is putting out switch or
like why triton did not succeed and also
scenarios like that
so that's the hmi if
you meant that so that's the hmi photo
control so for example uh if you
uh consider the titan thing it tried to
uh shut down the safety system but of
course it did not succeed there were
also physical controls on site and all
to avoid this
were you considering this
to build in the firing range because
that would be more realistic in an ot or
ics environment right yeah
so
we can't put everything in that model
that's i think um probably that's
difficult um so we we um restrict
ourselves to the couple of plcs that we
have in the hmi um to and build the
stars around that so additional hardware
equipment we did not plan for at least
in these situations so far
yeah yeah this is why because it would
not be practical to imagine that okay
only through an enterprise network you
get into the ot network because there
would always be some physical control
over the processes as well sure so
you're saying that the the attacker like
they so they skip the it part and they
go straight to ot and and
uh
carry out the attack from this is that
no i meant like there would be some uh
physical control that
cannot be reached by attackers to avoid
such scenarios and maybe in these kind
of projects we can also consider this it
could be it could be implemented in this
show yeah i mean it's it's also
extendable if this is a project for fuji
i think it's a good idea to include
thanks
and are you going to put this on the
internet for us to test as well
i mean you need that i guess you need
data
for forensic analysis so you just just
put it on the internet and wait for us
to test it maybe we'll think about it
yeah
okay
okay then thank you very much thank you
and before everybody heads out for lunch
break
we have
lunch outside and you can also use the
upper floor so to have a bit more space
and i think we will continue here in
this room at two
o'clock so after one hour of break and
see you then
[Applause]
[Music]
um
i don't think that we're gonna magic one
up in the next
[Music]
yeah and i think we have time
hello
oh too many things
so
it is two o'clock so she we should get
started with the next talk
in the
where are we in the ballroom in the
ballroom um today we are here as a
community
we're making connections
we're exchanging information
and guess what else wants to make
connections and exchange information
good answer blockchain
so today uh our speaker sebastian
baniskew is going to talk to us about
not quite water under the bridge a
review of cross chain bridge hacks and
so sebastian take it away thanks so much
for the introduction
this talk is put together by some of my
amazing colleagues listed here
and i'm just sort of distributing the
knowledge
so a bit about myself i've been working
in security since 2011. held various
roles at various companies
and i've been in the
blockchain smart contract auditing scene
since uh 2018
and it's been a hell of a ride
who i work for
i work for quan stamp which is the
company the logo there in the middle
uh we're one of the leaders in
smart contract and blockchain security
we've secured
more than 200 billion in
assets in smart contracts we have a lot
of clients
a lot of revenue
and most importantly we're hiring so
stick around until my last slide that
one
has a very interesting piece of
information on it
so why is this talk relevant
um there's been a bunch of bridge hacks
over the past
year
so just in 2022 alone there's been more
than uh one billion worth of crypto
assets stolen
from such systems
here are at least just a few of them the
ones with the ones which are like most
important
and we're going to go through
more details
as to why these kind of things happen
and why this kind of thing is so hard to
get right from a security perspective
so here's a bridge
it's pretty simple like you'd say like
why the heck is this thing so hard to
get right
you have an actor
on the left side you have
a smart contract system like ethereum
that it interacts with
and it basically wants to send assets to
a different chain
and on the other end
this actor or someone else might want to
receive those assets
denominated in something else on the
other chain
now this is like the essence of it
the
going into a bit more detail you see
like when someone deposits like this
actor on the left
deposits maybe some ether
it interacts with a smart contract
called the custodian
and there's a communicator
in the middle which is an off chain
component
it could be a traditional whatever
server application
that is watching
what is happening on the chain
once it sees that someone has deposited
funds in this contract it initiates
a debt issuance call to the debt issuer
contract on a different chain and this
debt issuer here on the right hand side
it means some
tokens which should be the equivalent of
the ether that the first actor put in
right
so again pretty simple
the opposite path so starting from right
to left the actor wants to redeem back
the ether deposited after having used it
for some purpose
so it
burns these tokens that it got called
ace
it sends them to this depth issuer
contract
the communicator is also watching the
debt issuer
and when it sees that someone has burned
these tokens it initiates the fund
release on the custodian side
so the actor should receive the
corresponding amount of eth on the
ethereum side so this is depositing and
withdrawing
now
you notice from the previous slides the
bridge structure contains like three
main components
two contracts
which are the asset custodian the data
source
and the depth issuer the oracle contract
here
and a communicator which is an offline
off chain component
which we call the oracle
and there's
therefore
a huge attack surface when it comes to
like
the
uh web free space so you have
the custodian
the depth issuer the communicator any
interfaces that they use and the network
itself they could all be subject to
attacks and in the next slides we're
going to go through examples of attacks
for each of these layers
and bear in mind that some of these
attacks i won't name names because it's
not
professional but some of them are uh
referring to the hacks that happen
in the in the past the ones that are on
the
one of the previous slides so for the
custodian
we have something which is called the
call relay attack
and here depending on the bridge
you might have this asset custody smart
contract
which is accessible
by some privileged addresses because
they need to manage them somehow and
maybe maximize
the the
profit of the project or something so
what the attacker goal in this case was
was to take over
this asset custody contract and be able
to
take puns out of it so the way in which
they want they did that was that there
was this function
that was
in the ascity asset custody smart
contract called
change custody address there at the
arrow at the bottom
and this function
should not be callable from the outside
so there should be some access control
in place that prevents anyone from
calling it
but
what the
attack or like what any user would have
would be allowed to do was that they
were allowed to call
functions of this form right there was a
function name
three parameters
two byte strings and one unsigned
integer on 64 bit
so this was something that
was deemed allowable from the access
control policy because
there were just
one or two functions which were fine to
be called by anyone
now
the nasty part
is
that the attacker
found a way found a hash collision
on some random name that they put
together using this signature here so
they just randomly compiled
a function name and some parameter
values which had a hash collision
with this function name
the way in which this contract in the
middle here works this cross chain
communication contract
it whenever it says call this function
it basically hashes the signature and
looks it up in a hash table
and due to this hash collision
it was the attacker was able to
figure out okay
if i have this function well it's just a
random name there but xx123
and some parameter values is going to
have a hash collision and i'm going to
be able to call this
function which i'm not supposed to call
and change the owner of the asset
custody to my own address and then i can
just take the funds out
so yeah that's that's one of the attacks
moving on to another attack transaction
replay
it's again on the custodian and
depending on again the custodian the
bridge that is implementing
you need to present proofs
when withdrawing assets so this kind of
markle proofs
they get issued so let's let's go step
by step the first step is that you
deposit an asset to the custodian
and in the second step the debt issuer
sends you the debt token we've seen that
on the
original slide with depositing then
withdrawing you do burning the depth
token to the depth issuer and in this
case the depth issuer gives you a proof
that you can then go and send to the
custodian and say here's the proof give
me my money give me my tokens
the
the mistake in this case was that the
verification of the proof
uh didn't take into account one of the
fields
so the attacker was able to change one
of the fields
and resend the proof again and again
it was a valid proof but it was
different from the previous ones so for
each replay the attacker got the same
amount until it drained the custodian
going on to the depth issuer so in case
of the depth issuer the attacker goal
would be to bypass the signature
verification right
and
arbitrarily mint
these tokens right
so
the attacker what what they did in this
case it was again a very specific
implementation of a bridge which
received as an input parameter
over here not sure you see my mouse yeah
it received the signature verification
contract address right so this was an
input parameter
but it should have been pretty fixed but
this is the way in which the system
worked
they were just receiving this as an
input parameter and of course this
signature verification contract was
unique
it was a trusted component what the
attacker did they deployed a fake
verification contract
and they passed that
as an input parameter so this fake
verification contract said it's always
good whatever you do
you passed the signature verification
and this way the attacker was able to
basically initiate these kind of uh
withdrawals
without or like this disminting without
deposits without actually
depositing any money in the custodian
moving on to the communicator layer
there
the attacker has the goal of tricking
the communicator into forwarding invalid
messages and minting tokens
so
for this particular attack
the communicator
was watching the custodian
and was watching if someone deposits
funds in the custodian there's an event
which is emitted
i'm going to check
how much i should emit i'm going to
check the address of the custodian is
correct
unfortunately
for multiple withdrawals or like yeah
for multiple it was looking only at the
first event for the address of the
contract which emitted it what uh an
attacker did was they deployed a
malicious contract which emits the same
events it looked the events look the
same except for the fact that it's
emitted by a different address
the problem with the communicator it was
only checking the address of the first
event
and then only looking for the other
events that came afterwards so the
attacker basically issued a bunch of
fake events from these from this
malicious contract and was able to
uh drain yeah basically get a bunch of
funds that they were not entitled to
moving on to the interface level
here there's a bunch of attacks which
we're going to look on the first
is um
you have this situation where
a legitimate user here at the bottom has
approved
a contract
to
allow them to to basically
execute some kind of
function call
for a particular token and this is quite
broad
so what an attacker did there was that
they
just crafted out of this execute call
data generic function they just crafted
okay transfer from user to me right so
they were able just to
easily craft
this function call inside of the call
data
which led to of the legitimate users
tokens being transferred to the attacker
so the attacker could do this for
multiple users who have approved
um
their wallet
uh this this interface spending money
from or funds from their wallet
in
a similar attack
where again the user has approved a
third-party
contract for
allowing people to deposit
with permission basically here
you're allowing someone to
spend money in your name
it should only be meant for tokens which
implement this feature but there are
tokens which do not implement this
feature and do not give any
uh warning
as to the fact that this function called
failed so if someone calls this function
deposit with permit
into this contract it's just not going
to say anything
it's not going to return anything and
the error
was in this
third-party contract where they did not
check the return value so they didn't
check
that the return value is explicitly
successful they just assumed that if it
doesn't complain then it's successful
right so missing
uh return value validation and this way
the attacker was just able to say like
hey i'm going to deposit all of these
funds from the legitimate user into my
account and that's how they got away
with
all the funds from legitimate users who
approved
finally the network layer
this is something that hasn't yet
happened but
might happen in the future
there is this thing called the 51 attack
which allows you to reorganize blocks
and
what you can do is launch such an attack
on a level one chain
then you deposit assets to that
custodian contract
and you receive the debt token
afterwards you take that debt token
and withdraw those funds
out of an exchange or something you re
withdraw them transform them into fiat
or dollars whatever
and finally you cancel that deposit
transaction in step two because you now
can reorganize the chain right
and depending on how long
these steps this this withdrawal process
takes
you could afford to pay for such an
attack because one hour of such a 51
attack on the ethereum main net is
somewhere between 1.5 and 2 million
if there are sufficient funds an
attacker might be incentivized to
actually pay this
for a certain amount of hours depending
on how fast the bridge enables someone
to transfer funds to deposit and
withdraw
so in summary there's a lot of
bad things that could happen with
bridges
we saw things on the custodian layer
we saw things on the depth issuer layer
i'm not going to go into all of these
but basically
you might have recognized that these are
not totally different from your
classical security mistakes like missing
input validation
not checking return values and so on
right
the communicator layer is this off chain
component which is basically watching
and triggering smart contracts on both
sides
and there's a many things that could go
wrong we only went into one or two
things in this presentation but
there's a longer list and probably it's
not exhaustive
there's the interface
where
basically it's not necessarily bridge
specific but
there's a lot of things that could go
wrong with allowing people to
deposit in someone else's name
or allowing external contract calls and
then finally the network layer there's
the 51 attack
but there could be other problems as
well
finally just want to say we're hiring we
offer great packages and if you're
interested in this kind of stuff finding
bugs and smart contracts we'd be happy
to to
get in touch with you
thanks so much
[Applause]
so do we have any questions for
sebastian that we have a runner coming
forward
so it
looks like a lot of stuff you mentioned
is like you said input validation stuff
like that that could be remediated with
like good programming practices
um is my assumption correct that if you
do all these correct then the problem is
the custodian and you there's no way to
do that one trustless because it is off
chain
so
can we ever get rid of and not the
communicator because that is option is
there ever way to make that component
trustless as well or will that always be
a linchpin in the entire setup how and
there's no way to secure it even if all
the rest is perfect
yeah that's a very good question thanks
so
this architecture which we've mainly
looked at during this talk
is something which is being used
generally right now there are projects
out there which are taking a
totally different approach they don't
use this architecture they use something
else where they don't have this kind of
trusted off chain component
and
well those kind of things are not yet in
production but they are working towards
a solution
which does not does not have this kind
of um
trusted
third party which is off chain all right
if you want we could i can give you more
more details uh in the break and another
question if i may um sure for example in
in terms of web applications we have
stuff like ports right academy do you
have equivalents for like if you want to
learn about smart contract blockchain is
there any like playgrounds that are easy
to get into for someone that is not
familiar yet totally yeah there are
multiple actually there's things like
well um
call them offline ctfs because they are
always going on right you just have like
a playground
where there are some contracts that you
can just
exploit toy contracts
and there's like multiple
difficulty challenges right and there's
like things like you know damn
vulnerable linux sure yeah there's
something like that for smart contracts
or google damn vulnerable ethereum or
yeah
damn vulnerable defy it's called yeah so
um there's there's all these kind of
things and also there are training
programs free of charge
because
there's so much interest in um getting
more security experts in this field that
people are no longer charging for
training
everything is sponsored by all these
projects which have suffered such hacks
and and like the amount that they need
to sponsor these academies is nothing
compared to the amount that they could
lose so everything is like sort of free
of charge so you can pick it up really
easily
okay thanks
thank you
please come up with your question
hello
for someone that is completely new to
this type of hacking i have a question
how much of hacking smart contracts and
and blockchain and cryptos
is about
actually cryptography and how much is
about more of this type of logic
books
that's a good question um
i think
probably more than 95 percent is about
this
okay and probably like five percent is
about the crypto because
um
the actual cryptography which is being
used
that is being actively researched by
many research groups at top universities
and many of the world's
leading cryptographers
so the actual
hash functions
encryption
um
proofs and so on everything
is based on many many years of research
from
universities
and now we're just like working at
implementing applications on top of that
okay so we can say something like
if you'll invest more time there
learning about solidity you are doing a
very better investment that by learning
i don't know cryptology
something like that
um
depends right um
if you're a brilliant cryptographer and
you might invent something amazing i'm
not
then it might be worth doing that but i
think like if you don't want to do that
then definitely learning something like
the solidity or other programming
languages being used for smart contracts
is a very good return on investment okay
thank you thank you
any other questions
yeah so i have a bit of a controversial
question so your company is like doing
these audits for the contracts
so you're making money by doing the
audits and stuff but
like i've read this idea that
it's something like a bit like a reverse
but bounty scheme
because in the end there is an incentive
for you
to keep like some kind of bug in the
contract
and then in a blackhead form exploited
so you know what i mean yeah i do i do
totally and so it gets philosophical in
everything but like you're part of the
industry
and what is your
thinking about this how this could
improve
in a way where it's better for everyone
like your auditors can do your job
others can do their job and everybody
can trust the thing in the end yeah no
that's a very good question thanks so
i think it's always this kind of
trust issue when you're working with a
security service provider
it's not specific to the space it could
be like when you're pen testing a web
application right for any company right
you might withhold some kind of attack
that you can then
use to exploit of course like maybe in
web 2 the damage you do is not directly
financial but it's reputation damage or
so on
but basically the idea is that
what we're doing
if we were doing that if we were would
be withholding and exploiting
there would be a huge reputation damage
to the company itself and it would cease
to exist
right
we
are
well in relative terms a young company
like we've been around for five years
and we have a reputation
for being one of the best
so if you have a like the longer your
time span is and just keep in mind the
oldest
auditing companies in this space are
like five six years old so there's no
uh there's no others which are like have
been around for longer doing this
specific thing there's been there's
companies who have pivoted from doing
traditional security to smart contract
audits and they have been around for
longer they have a longer track record
but definitely this kind of track record
and knowing that the company has been
around for longer
helps with this kind of trust issue
because if
let's say you somehow managed to
um trick someone in trusting you and you
do this kind of thing you you withhold
an export you exploited
probably in a few months to a year your
company is no longer going to be trusted
by anyone because your audits always get
hacked you know what i mean so that's
what i think the way to balance this
okay any other questions
okay i have
a curiosity question
so suppose i wanted to exchange a large
sum of money and i knew it was going to
be a cross blocking kind of exchange
um should i just avoid that altogether
or what can i do as a consumer of this
entire process
definitely get advice from professionals
and don't just do it
um
sort of on your own because there are
way more problems sort of attacks
economic attacks that someone could
use
to
do an arbitrage on something that you're
doing right so if you're exchanging one
token for another
you have a lot of parameters which might
be like the margin that you're
willing to lose in the exchange and if
you don't properly set that margin
you might end up uh
being arbitraged by
there's an army of bots out there just
looking for these kind of opportunities
so definitely ask someone
for these kind of settings right and
then like this is in addition to all the
security issues that might be there
right
so
i'm not saying there are definitely ways
to do that i've done well i don't i
didn't transfer large sums of money but
i've done that myself
with
no
let's say issues afterwards right so
it's possible but you really need to to
uh be careful because like we've just
presented let's say
i don't know six seven hacks but keep in
mind there are like dozens and dozens of
bridges and some of them have never been
hacked yeah
exchanges exchanges on their set
themselves are bridges as well they're
just a different type of bridge they're
not from
chain to chain they're from bank account
to chain
super
any other questions then
all right thank you so much sebastian
thank you
so
don't worry you have plenty of time
yeah
wrong paper
foreign
okay
is everything under control okay
all right
so
we're up with our next talk
um so
our conference is called the layers
one of the subtitles is layer six and
this is really referring to the osi
model which is the presentation layer so
we thought it would be fun to call the
conference layer six it's our sixth year
layer six presentation yeah okay so you
get the joke um but layer six is really
concerned with protocol conversion
encryption decryption so on and so forth
and when we saw this talk
the talk is mime is broken
we thought
this is a definitely a layer six talk
and we have to have it so today i'm
going to introduce to you stephan ulrich
he is a software engineer security
researcher likes jogging and biking and
he's going to tell us why
mime is broken and what we should do
about it
okay
so on okay
yeah uh welcome
uh yeah my talk is today about uh why
mime is broken and okay the screen is a
little bit off let's see
um
so uh about me i'm yeah i'm the security
engineer security researcher fellow i'm
working uh 20 years plus at genoa gmbr
near munich
my focus of the work is not on breaking
things but on protecting what's already
broken
and i did a lot of firewall development
focusing on the application layer i
did eight years of collaboration with
academia and research projects
focusing on
defending against attacks via
meal and web and i'm currently involved
more in product and research strategies
uh yeah i'm back in again
it's a company
exactly 30 years old now with
360 plus employees in various locations
inside germany
we are a subsidiary of the bundesliga
and we build security solutions for iit
and ot and our focus is on sectors with
higher security requirements so public
sector critical infrastructure
structures
regulated industry
e-health etc and yeah of course if you
want to help you're welcome
uh the motivation of my research like i
said i did a lot of firewall development
at the application layer so i had to
implement application protocols and the
best way or the preferred way to
implement application protocols is to
actually look at the standards
not many do this actually when
implementing these protocols
yeah but when looking at the standards
and trying to find out how to implement
these
uh the problem is that these standards
are
typically very flexible and very complex
and they are unnecessarily unnecessary
flexible and complex they leave way too
much room for creative interpretation so
there are lots of edge cases with with
no clearly defined behavior
there's no defined behavior of protocol
errors there's a lot of short instead of
must be implemented
and they are partly conflicting with
previous standards of course all of this
conflicts kind of the security
as a result are that we have different
implementations which
interpret
uh especially edge cases in different
ways and this can of course be used by
attackers
so if the analysis system like a
firewall interprets the content
differently then the end user system
like in our case a male user agent uh
then we can pass attacks through the
firewall
so the focus of my
research in this case is
it's mime
mime is kind of a standard for rich meal
so what we have today structured male
binary attachments non-ski characters
uh and uh
what i explore here is how to use
different interpretations of mime to
bypass security systems so these are
analysis in mail filters firewalls
intrusion detection systems antivirus
versus the interpretation by mail user
agents or web frontends
i'm looking into bypassing milva
detection by content
using the icar test viewers and uh
bypassing detection or attachment
filtering by file name so if we can
make
the firewall belief that we have a
different file name
it's not a dot access not a zip then the
firewall will pass through the mail
there's similar research for http one
there's all this ports figure stuff
about http dsync attacks which are
targeting the server side
uh i did a lot of research on the http
site too but for targeting clients so
sending malicious responses or
unexpected responses by the server and
by passing firewalls this way
this research here
uh was primarily done in 2015 to 2018
during a research project
but i freshly updated it to make sure
that all the attacks still work and they
do
so um yeah to explore this topic
um i created a lot of different mails
with
different test cases so
nearly a few hundred males for
continental assists or
nearly 200 meals for bypassing extension
blocking
um
these males
if exported as a files or mail directory
and also as uh packet capture file to
check against intrusion action systems
and then i checked against several
systems like various mail user agents
various antivirus and male feather
products
uh some intuition detection symptoms in
firewall i won't mention here because
it's not a free one
and some libraries
okay
a short introduction into what mime
actually is
in the beginning there was about uh
before 1994 five
there was only esky there were only ski
males these had a line
length limit of thousand
thousand bytes and there was no kind of
structure no attachment or similar
inside 1996
we got these
mime rfc
which defined different aspects of how
to serialize
um structured information and non-sk
information into the original limits
so um yeah binary data uh structures
data like attachments and of course like
i said uh this is a standard which is
flexible which is complex underspecified
and has lots of room for creative
interpretation
a year later there were some additional
standards
one is called
disposition how to specify a file name
is how to specify if the attachment is
inline or external
and
there is
another standard for encoding of
non-ascii characters into
structured data like file names or so
for some reason they
didn't include this in the original one
so they needed yet another one which
implemented a totally different encoding
for
some reason
okay
if you look at the source code of a mail
we see the different standards applied
here
so
we have the subject which is an
unstructured header field
and there we see error of c 2047 so this
one which is about encoding characters
in the header what we have here is with
q is a
quoted printable encoding which means
that the characters the non-ascii
characters are encoded in some kind of
hex value so this
equals c dry
a c3 means
that it's a character
hex c
three and then we can look in the
utf art utf-8 and calling what the
second actually means
okay
uh then we have this kind of mine
preamble here which is
hidden in modern male clients so
basically all male clients we have today
it's only for the old male clients
so this is everything before the first
part
because we have here a multi-part male
which is defined in rfc 2046
and we have a boundary here defined to
split the male into different parts with
the final boundary
here uh
yeah then we have
for some parts we have a name so we can
have a name given in this way we can
have name given in this way this is
actually
rc2231 which has this kind of encoding
for long file names
which we can split over multiple
parameters because like i said the
uh limit for line lengths in male is a
thousand characters
and which has this kind of hex encoding
here which looks similar to what we have
in quoted principle but again it's
totally different because we have uh
here we have an equal sign here we
percent percents and so and yeah for
some reason they needed to make
everything
differently and then we have quoted
printable encoding here for the content
and base 64 encoding here uh for the
content of the attachment
okay
i show some selected examples of how
this
can be used to
create
edge cases
uh which are
theoretically allowed
or
especially not as they are not
especially forbidden by the standard
but where the
interpretation is
ambitious so
uh for example in this case you can
define two content transfer encodings
this is similar like attacks in http
where we have two content length sellers
with different values
and because we have two values here it's
not clear how this part so this is basic
before how this gets interpreted and
depending on the mail client we use it's
uh gets interpreted in a different way
and depends on the analysis software we
use or the library some manage to see
this and some
don't see this so sorry carter ids
doesn't see the attachments the right
attachment in this case
oops
slight variation
of this
we have one
field only but we have multiple values
inside
again some male clients
understand this and just take the base64
because it's the first one
no male client actually uh
unders
takes it it takes the last one but uh
outlook and apple mail
don't understand this at all and just
assume there's no encoding done
um
we can play similar games uh with the
content uh
with multi-part
male so we have a boundary c and we can
have two boundary definitions and uh the
correct one would be a bar here so this
is the first one and here's this is as
the last one and again depending on the
major client and depending on the
analysis software
we have different results
same thing again one field multiple
values and here again it switches
first
what was on this side and apple mill was
on this side he has a node switch and
it's the same with the various software
so we see here see
a majesty new which behaves the same as
pearl mime tools because it's used
inside
uh yeah and then uh different
area
uh the area of encodings there's a b64
encoding uh base64 basically means that
we have three bytes binary data
mapped to four byte ascii data so it's
already it's taken the first six bit
then the next six bit and so on until we
have uh have
20 24 bit three bytes uh binary and
mapses to 32
bits
which
uh are playing ascii
and if you have less than three bytes
and we have a padding so in this case we
have four bytes here which means we have
two bytes padding because we have to
fill in uh the last two bytes you get
six bytes and here in this case we have
two bytes this means you have one byte
padding and this padding is done with
the equal sign here
and
the standard or the rc
is not clear
in this case
if
what we have should be encoded in one
piece so that we have only a single
padding at most a single padding at the
end or if you can actually have multiple
pieces
it suggests that was maybe done this way
but there is no short or even better a
must
and that's why we have different
implementations so we have thunderbolt
apple mail which just accepts that it's
okay to do so
uh we have mode
just take the first part and you have
outlook which i don't know it takes the
first part and then says garbage and i
don't
actually know where this garbage comes
from
um
yeah and if you have a look at the
analysis software also the libraries we
see that most of these
plainly fail to see what major male
clients actually can do
but we have more encodings we have
quotable printable which is in the
standard tool but we have
also encodings which are not in the
standard but with a which are actually
uh supported by some male clients there
is this why ink encoding and this is an
encoding which comes from the area of
youth net news i don't know if somebody
still remembers it's
some 15 20 years ago
this time was it yes very efficient
encoding more efficient than base64 and
that's why it was used on usenet to
transfer transfer binary data
and because thunderbird
can still function as a news reader it
implements these encoding
but nobody else does and no analysis
software is able to see this
other is interesting encoding is uun
code this predates mime this predates
why ink
too
uh it was used in former times uh in
plain text meals to include some binary
data uh so we had some kind of file name
here inside the
part and then you had this encoding and
then there was an end and this encoding
is very similar to base64 only it's
mapped slightly different but the idea
is the same
uh yeah and this is actually a widely
supported in coding so we have major
milk clients which can do it
and we actually have major antivirus
products which can do it too
but
there are lots of variations so we can
have different transfer encoding times
vm sometimes we need the begin and then
sometimes you can skip it etc etc and uh
they all work slightly different so
there's lots of room
for
passing
bypassing analysis software
and then we have another strange feature
of mail which is comments in mail header
in mail fields
so the standard actually says that one
can place combat this is this part with
the parentheses around it
in several places freely inserted and
outlook
takes this to the next level it's
basically nearly everywhere this stuff
can be inserted and it simply gets
ignored so outlook sees in this case
this
i
bar as a boundary
all other
implementations don't see this bar and
yeah clam
can see it and there's this
firewall which can see us and there is a
python library but everybody else
cannot see this
okay this is about uh content filtering
and then we have the specification of
file lamps
uh
two few uh two small examples
uh like i said we have this uh rfc 2023
one which defined a new encoding for
file names and which defined how that
these can be split into multiple
parameters
uh so there is an
index for the parameter and uh yeah i
can split it over
multiple source indexes the order
actually does not matter which is
explicitly
specified as a standard
and
yeah
um like once see i can see thunderbird
apple mail not all supports this kind of
outlook has no idea what the standard is
at all
and the funny thing if i use a microsoft
exchange
it even transforms
this encoding this write encoding into a
wrong encoding because outlook does not
support it
but
i have this another standard this rfc
2047 which was
defined for
encoding of characters into unstructured
male fields and it specifically says
that
these encoding stuff should not be
quoted and should not be used inside of
content type of content disposition but
funny thing is
most supports this
and
yeah many analysis software supports us
too but there are several variations of
the topic so if i use some
strange encodings like otf16 it gets
weird and
i have
again ways to bypass firewalls
or analysis systems
okay so how to apply this knowledge in
the practice
a small thing i
create a mail
and i check this mail with a virus total
so
this mail
has
inside here base64 encoding uh
a zip file and the zip file contains the
ica test virus and like we can see there
are so the ground truth 38
products in
a virus total
can actually parse this male and can
detect the virus inside so
nice
let's see
if we make a small change we add another
transfer encoding here and we can see
the
number goes slightly down if we switch
the order it's not much different and if
we
specify a content transfer encoding
which is
something which doesn't exist like the
x66
then yeah it goes down but there are
still a lot of
scanners which will
simply have a heuristic and
see this is base64 encoding and will
try to analyze it
okay
small step
uh
we don't use a single chunk for our
base64 but we are actually multiple
chunks for two bytes so we get an uh
padding uh one character betting after
after each chunk
and now the number goes way down and
even if we take uh back all this stuff
we did before here is it still very low
and last step
uh we just
add
multiple boundaries here with different
implementation and now
we have
no antivirus product
supports it anymore if we look at the
meal in thunderbird we can still
normally just extract it have a look at
it
and if we
remove this content transfer confusion
here it's still only one antivirus
product which will see this
okay
slightly different area
dkim signatures i don't know who is
familiar with
dkim and dmarc
the basic idea is that we want to
protect us
against the spoofing of the sender
and the visible sender inside the mirror
is inside the mail from header and jmark
basically says that this from header
must the domain as a from header must be
aligned with uh either
send a permitted framework for spf or
jkim signatures and taken signature is
actually only a
it's a cryptographic signature over
parts of the header and over
the body
and
we can check this and it's independent
from the transport of the mail so we can
redistribute the mail and this uh
dickham signature does not change at all
which is very nice
but
the ecom standard relies on
mime
being not broken
and
the dkim standard itself is
insufficient too so there
are no requirements which header fields
like content type like uh
subject or so need to be protected there
are some recommendations but these
recommendations are insufficient
there
is a way in the standard to protect
header fields to make sure that no
critical header fields can be added
but there is no requirement to do so
which means that
typically implementations like in openg
chem or so
or
basically in any product we see outside
are broken
they don't properly protect the headers
additionally
dcam allows us to sign only parts of
samir the idea is that
some
software could add some food and the
signature should be the same
and they say that this is a security
problem but nevertheless they allow it
okay so what we can can we do
this is a mail i got um about
oh six years ago
and uh from um
uh deutsche bust which
is a classic sender a typical center for
spoofing
and uh we have to say the signature here
and the deconstruction it says that uh
not the full body is signed but yeah
only up to a specific part like here at
the end
uh the mail although
they can picture also says that we have
some fields signed here
but uh
these are only included once that means
the existing field is including but
i can freely add
additional fields these are not included
in signature
so what i can do is here i can add
another date i can add another two
header i can add another content type
and i can freely
put stuff at the end which means with
this change content type
i have a different boundary which means
all this part up to this boundary is
seen only as a mind preamble is not
visible in the middle client today but
instead this part after that is shown
and
if i deliver this mail
i can see that this part is shown and i
can see that daycam is still okay and
the the properties of mail show that the
date has changed the message id
uh is i didn't know if i changed it in
previous example but i can see for uh
that daycam and denmark both pass
so final words
are there any solutions to this problem
yeah
maybe the problems are hard to fix there
are zillions of mime implementations and
scripts in the wild is often broken
there is no money pulley on
implementations which can could be used
to enforce a minimal quality
we have such monopoly browsers
one can try to block
such edge cases
but this can cause
unbearable qualitatory effects we have
i've seen this in the practice
uh there's simply too much junk in the
real world and um in
dubbed operation beats security it
worked before we installed instead the
firewall there's a way to sanitize the
wheels but this can break stuff too so
it will break jacob's signature pgp and
s mime signatures i've seen this too
and
ultimately one can simply lock the
problems
and then hope that somebody cares
actually about the locks
thank you
[Applause]
so do we have any questions for stefan
and his very optimistic outlook on mime
so steph and i have one question and you
kind of addressed it in your last slide
if i am an administrator of an email
service what what can i do is there
anything that i should
do today to protect against
attacks like this
i think there's no good answer to this
[Laughter]
because
actually we've built in our product all
the other protections against these
attacks i have shown and we had to
make a lot of these protections uh
optional because there are a lot of junk
mails outside which are not spam meals
which are real males but which are
actually invalid
okay there's another question
i'm loud
hi um have you have you taken a look at
sometimes when you forward an email with
attachments and then in different kinds
of email clients or webmail clients they
get unfolded
even though
it's an attachment
have you been looking into this kind of
scenario because i
used to fix
a bug in a webmail client where there's
an attachment and
a forward with an attachment and they
were unfolded and this kind of helps
sometimes
mitigating also or some bypass some
firewall rules
yeah forwarding meals is it
a strange thing they are there there are
two options to follow the mills the
inline forwarding at the forwardings
attachment
and uh supporting this attachment is
supposed to just uh put in the urgent
email but one can actually modify it and
then there are different problems on top
of this because if the original mail was
transferred over a path which is
eight byte clean
and uh then i forward this mail and the
the next pass is not eight byte clean
which is a traditional password smtp
then i might need to rewrite everything
so it can
it could be used to kind of sanitize but
it will then also it might also break it
might break the signatures this might
break pgp and as my signatures
you mentioned that you generated a lot
of test cases
are you aware of any publicly available
weaponized frameworks to exploit these
issues so that i can target specific
setups and generate a mail that will
bypass these checks now i'm not aware of
any other research in this area in this
steps but if you want to start
successful
come to me and i give you test cases and
the framework to generate these
awesome thanks
all right um i'm that should be the last
question we've reached 15 o'clock please
give stephen a hand
her mind is broken
and we now have a 30 minute leg
stretcher break so go out get some air
and come back for the next talks
[Music]
nobody has rung the bell
which means people are continuing to eat
not realizing it's only two minutes
before begin
tension builds will they get into the
room in time will we have enough time
for this whole talk we will don't worry
but i do hope someone rings the bell
the bell is a very powerful tool
it's soft yet commanding
philosophy on bells
at b-sides munich
layer six
you heard it here first
i hear the gentle bell ringing
now it's a more insistent ring
come to the room
ring my bell
[Music]
ring my belly
join us folks have a seat we're about to
begin
so
all right let's get rolling so welcome
back from break
we are about to have our next talk um
according to our next speaker um johan
silam
25 of internet traffic is bot traffic
and it's not like the friendly bots that
you see in the television shows but it's
bad bots and so we're going to learn all
about bad bots today and what they can
do and how they do it
so johan is a security researcher and
one of his favorite sports is table
tennis so keep that in mind when you
talk to him after about his very cool
talk so without further ado
take it away johan
thank you
so hello everybody nice to meet you
my name is uh as
jane said
i'm working for improver company
uh and this talk is going to talk uh to
be about uh advanced bot landscape
so before we start i give you a short
introduction about myself
so
secret researcher with four years of
experience in cyber security
i spent the major part of my time
analyzing malwares but more recently i
spent time on the web application
security i tried to understand the
advanced particle system try to see
their behavior if there are ways to
detect them or even block them
so this is the agenda of the session
today
first we will see together the advanced
particle system
then i will show you the internal
structure of an advanced bot
and lastly we will see together a few
efficient techniques and the detection
that we can provide
so let's go
but before we start sorry
short definition of bots
bots are softwares that automate action
on the internet
um there could be good bots for example
the google googlebot that's cooling the
web in order to improve its search
engine result
and you have bad bots for example the
ones that are scanning
all
the internet in search of vulnerable
websites
the difference between the two is the
content of the server being reached by
the by those bots for example a bot
that's not respecting the robots.txt
file at the root of the website will
definitely not be a good bot
okay so the market of bad bots is huge
the market just talking about ticket
scalping it was estimated to be roughly
eight billion dollars in 2017 and we can
see that the market of bots is growing
general uh web scrapper uh software
market was evaluated to half a billion
dollar uh and this was like almost this
year
you have communities gathering
hundreds of thousands of people
exchanging advices about bots selling
bots buying bots
and there are many ones that i'm going
to show you
in this presentation so this is such a
huge market
that very efficient bots can be very
expensive here is the example of a bot
called the wrath aio
out of stock in its own website
and on the recent market you can find it
for no less than one thousand seven
hundred dollar
here aiok means all in one
that is this bot is able to uh to scalp
actually it's an advanced sculpting bot
to all to two
all sites
uh developed with the shopify framework
uh okay so now let's talk about about
traffic in terms of numbers so i've been
spoiled a bit but it's completely okay
so
bad bot traffic was measured to be
roughly a quarter of all internet
traffic in 2020 where a good bot is only
representing 15 percent of it
and when we drill down into this
we can see that
more than half of it is the fact of
advanced bots so uh what do we mean
exactly by advanced bots
so we have a few things in mind
the first one is a usage of headless
brother browser technology
this is a technology that enables the
rendering of web content almost the same
way as a real browser would do an
example of such technology is selenium
for example
we have in mind the rotation between
anonymous proxies most of the time there
will be a residential one because they
are harder to detect
and also advanced anti-detection
mechanisms for example the ability to
mimic a human behavior
during the solving of captcha
we'll see an example of that later
okay so what's the purpose of advanced
belts so they can be used for many
things including carding the fact of
creating checking
stolen credit card numbers found for
example in dark web and test it against
e-commerce websites
credential stuffing
the fact of taking combo list of
username and passwords from the dark web
and check it against a large range of
websites in order to find at least one
match
scalping
the fact of purchasing automatically a
large amount
of premium items from websites in order
to resell it later at a higher price on
the result markets
so this damages the reputation of the
ecommerce website and also generate a
loss in the long term for the company
because
it destroys the strategy of premium
items and generate frustration for the
customer
denial of inventory
the fact of
for example making a website unusable
via the massive usage of dummy cards
and so on
so among all of those types of um about
activities scalping has become so
popular that night has become a kind of
a sport
so this is a video taken from a youtube
channel called butting with burger
showing one guy
using two different bots advanced bots
actually in order to scalp uh
the premium release of one specific
company
so he's using on the left side about
called cyber io and on the right one red
set uh tokubot
so each of the land that you can see
it's pretty difficult to see i'm not
sure if you see it well
is a
scalping task operation
and the their status is evolving
initially it's connecting to the website
then
filling the form and
eventually solving the captcha and do
the purchase operation so what you can
see in the left at some point the lines
turn green which means that the full
flow from the connecting to the page
monitoring of the price and the solving
of the captcha was entirely successful
and on the right side you can see that
it stays black
at the last stage it's not possible to
read because it's too small but it says
px banner
this tells that the security vendor of
the website was able to detect this
traffic as uh non-legitimate and was
able to block it
so this video is roughly a year old
and this shows that
in real time the bypass of the security
vendor by advanced scalper actually
called cyberio
so i showed you this this uh gif in
order to show you that this is an actual
concern to be able to block this kind of
traffic plus this kind of advanced
softwares
okay
so
one of the challenges of this research
was to get access to the files of the
bots
because
very often bots were out of stock in
their own websites
and even sometimes on the recent market
they were not available
so at least for you
set sources that were very useful to me
in this investigation
so first you have general hacking forms
for example uh hack forums crack.io
node.2
fraudster cruise install.live all of
those
are hacking forms in general and
when you so you can search for specific
tool or you can see a new tools that are
coming out you'll have one post
describing the tool and most of the time
eventually you'll have a link to an
archive that's stored either to unknown
files or mega file upload
you'll have of course to be careful
because those may give you a small gift
uh they may be also infected by malwares
so you should analyze it in a specific
environment
okay
so here
other kind of marketplaces that were
very useful
so as i said scalping has become
extremely popular now you have even
marketplaces that are dedicated for a
type of scalping oh okay for
example
ticket bots so ticket scalping or
sneaker scalping here
okay
sometimes
we were able to get access to the source
of a bot
in github it was the case of cyber io
for example or
behind misconfigured server we were able
to get access to the file of
one advanced bot called the kegel
okay so once using all of those
techniques we were able to gather
something like 40 advanced spots so only
advanced
we try to answer a few questions
what are the statistics
in terms of programming language the
term of headless browser technology
what's the internal structure of these
bots
and what are the efficient techniques
that they are using
so i'm going to show you this now
so
uh
the great majority of them were
developed either with electron framework
or even sometimes with a.net
written with.net framework
and when we uh drill down and see what's
the headless browser technology behind
we can see that puppeteer is the most
common headless browser technology used
here
but we can see also other ones selenium
is very popular.net browser but we have
also other ones like essential objects
jigs browser which is uh for java
playwright etc
now let's look at the internet structure
of an advanced bot so of course there
are many different bots so it's not
possible to do it for all of them but
the idea is to take the ones that are
the most successful so we go on discord
channel we try to see which bot are the
most expensive the most recommended and
because
often attackers
break
their outcome
on those challenges say that they were
able to escape this and this premium
release
so i decided to pick a bot called the
project destroyer
so a bit more than a year ago it was
worth one thousand dollar
it has the ability to scalp all of those
kind of websites that you can see here
and the reason i pick it is because it
has many functionalities so most of the
evision tricks that i will show at the
last part of the presentation are part
of
this bot
but in general the idea of bots are the
same be able to connect to website
without being fingerprinted be able to
perform automated actions in a
simultaneous way
at a very fast pace
so um we could split this is a very
simple version of this uh of this bot so
we could split uh in the left side
what's
the input what to provide with this bot
and on the right side what is inside of
the bot
so
to be provided to the bot a list of
proxies so usually ipport username and
password
a valid key for a captcha solving
service
for example capmanster a list of
profiles so including billing
information names addresses etc the
attacker may have several ones
and then inside of the bots
you have the headless browser so in this
case it was a puppeteer
um
usually you'll have also additional
modules that will improve its uh
ability not to be detected for example
in this case a puppeteer extra plug-in
staff
then you have an evasion module
that would be responsible for all of the
tricks to
uh to to make the bot hard to detect
you have a profile management module
that's responsible for storing the
profile provided by the attacker proxy
management module that will be
responsible to store the proxies check
if they are valid measure the speed and
solve them according to according to it
you have a cookie jar so it's an
interface provided to the
to the attacker
to generate valid cookies for the target
website so most of the time
uh 24 hours up to 48 hours before the
release of primary items the attacker
will have to generate a batch of cookies
and then they will be consumed during
the scalping operations
you have a capture management module
that will be responsible for extracting
the captcha from the page
send it to the third-party service
and then retrieve the answer and solve
it in the client side
and you have the operation module
so in the operation module most of the
time you have one folder for each target
victim that you have for example in the
case of project destroyer you have 37
folders
so it will contain the script in order
to click on specific button to
to fill a form etc
and then to call the other
components
okay so let's zoom in and see what
happens in one specific task so the
headless browser
here puppeteer is started
with with as i said a feature in order
to make it harder to detect for example
set
the webdriver to false
then
the bot will craft plausible device
attributes for the bot to look like
a real device i will show
some examples just later
then the bot will pick projected cookies
and proxy for the
specific target
then the bot will monitor the price uh
of the premium item that it wants to
purchase in a loop if at some point the
price is below the threshold that is set
by the attacker in the task then the
purchase operation will happen
when the captcha is provided to the to
the bot it will be sent to the third
party and the captcha will be solved
okay so now let's look at a few
efficient techniques and some detections
that we can provide
first of all it's not actually uh
evasion it's a code protection so the
code of this bot was quite strongly
affected
when you try to
expand it this way and execute it you
will crash with this specific error
so
what actually the code does it checks
the difference of string representation
of functions when the code is
not non-touched and when the code is
being debugged
so i had to understand which part of the
code was responsible for this check
disable it
and then i was able to detect the other
tricks used by the bot that i'm going to
show you now
so
one of the tricks that they used was to
add non-mandatory http address to the
fields of the requests
so here for example you have a list of
uh
seven different fields that are
non-mandatory http header fields
and uh there are randomly a certain
number of those fields are added to the
request that will be sent for one
specific scalping task
so this is done in order to make
the bot looks like a slightly different
device each time it's performing a
scalping operation
so this is not actually javascript code
i deofusculate it and show it in like
pseudocode
okay
another small trick that's worth
mentioning
it's called the address jigging
so
the bot is extracting the addresses
provided by the attacker
and then it's parsing it and
finding the keywords associated to roads
avenues lanes streets etc and then
slightly modifying it in order for all
of the scoping tasks even though they
are directing to the same address
eventually to look
different
for any uh security device that would
try to find scalping operations
for example there is another function
that will add a leading zero before the
numbers of the addresses
okay
another important
topic that can be discussed related to
advanced bots is the ability to to stack
capture solving services for example
there is a tool a new tool called aycd
autosol
that can be integrated with some
advanced bot including cyber io for
example
that burns uh the attacker to uh to
prioritize different uh
skeptics are solving service for example
first the capture will be sent to a cap
monster and if the captcha cannot be
sold by this specific service it will
jump to the next one and so on this
maximize the probability that eventually
the
scalping operation will be successful
okay so now let's look at a few
detections
that we can provide for this bot
so instead of the code i was able to
spot this specific section that's
responsible for
crafting uh device attributes plausible
for for the bots so here you see the
available hath
so this is supposed to uh represent the
size of the screen of the device not the
size of the window and it's set to be
random number between 1 000 and 1 600
pixels
uh but it's like uniformly randomized so
there are values here that don't
correspond to any device on the planet
most likely uh because it's uh
really precise so if someone really is
really paying attention to what happens
on the specific device uh he would be
able to detect that this is probably not
a real device but
about
so this is a flow in the in the code of
the of the bot
as i say here in the documentation this
is the size of the of the screen
uh okay another thing that we can do is
extract the snippet of code responsible
for uh the solving of captcha in the
client side
so
eventually the bot is using a
function that will generate a busy curve
in order to solve the captcha so this is
more or less how it will look look like
so
you can see the curvature is pretty
smartly done you can see the
acceleration the deceleration so a
simple device will not be able to to
detect this as legitimate but if you pay
more attention you can see that a real
human will not draw curves like this it
will be more irregular so we try to just
to to to check if it was actually true
if we were able to to see a difference
between
real traffic can fake traffic
so to do so
uh we decided to measure the
acceleration of the curve
um
so
this is the graph that we obtained we
can see that the average is set to
open one pixel per millimeter square
with a maximum value to roughly open 15.
so we try to do the same with a human
curves and this is more or less the
graph that we obtained
with an average higher up to open 15 and
a maximum to open five so the question
here is not if we can detect bots using
this kind of technique this bot actually
using this kind of dating is how much
time do we need in order to be accurate
enough to be sure that this is indeed
a bot
okay so as a conclusion
the managers of market bots
is
large and
expanding today
uh then uh there is a predominance of
electron uh framework for about
development and the puppeteer as a
headless browser technology and lastly
it's a cat and mouse game which means
that um knowing the code of the opponent
being able to understand the tricks that
he's using is a great advantage in order
to help the detection
for the detection of those of those
tools
uh that's it are there any questions
[Applause]
so do we have any questions for johan
and the bad bots
silence
um i actually have a question about
the one of your slides could you go back
to the slide where you had the
captcha
services the captcha beating services or
whatever they were there was a list
list
yeah
this okay yeah this this one
so um i'm looking at them and there are
three there and on the right hand side
there is balance
0 49 984 do
what is the balance for
so
the attacker has to register for each of
the services that will he will integrate
with aocd auto solve
so
he'll have to pay for each of those
services and then each time they are
requested then the balance will
will decrease
so when the balance is set to zero so
you cannot use this service so probably
it will skip automatically to the next
one
uh-huh okay so then do these services
cost different like per time of use is
there a different price between the
different services or are roughly the
same
um so the prices um
are
roughly the same they can like they can
vary uh a bit but more or less it's uh
it's uh something like open one dollar
for uh for each request something like
that okay
interesting
and then
you talked a lot about scalping um in
your presentation and
to me uh i'm very old-fashioned scalping
to me is where i go to a concert and
there's somebody standing outside
holding tickets up and saying please buy
my tickets and the concert is sold out
and i pay a bunch of money for that
what does scalping mean in sort of this
realm in the in the bot world
um
so
i said that scalping is uh
okay it damages the so first it's uh
something that's uh
uh almost everywhere in the market of
bots and actually this is where the most
advanced but we can find the most
advanced bots because um
they need to have a very strong
interaction with the website it's not
only about like sending one request it
needs to keep a communication be able to
move from page to page without being
spotted as a malicious bots
so as i said uh scalping damages the
reputation of uh companies when they're
successfully
attacked and that's why companies really
try to invest uh in order to be able to
protect again those threats
so this is why
this presentation is
like slightly oriented with a scalping
but let's say
okay and then what is the target then of
a bot that's in that is engaging in
sculpting
what's the target yeah what what is that
um so there are many targets so i show a
few of them so for example uh website
developed with shopify from works but
there are amazon of course ebay
walmart
adidas also i mean
if you go to any of the markets that was
listed above you can see the list for
each of the bots that you want to
purchase
you will see the list of targets that it
has the ability to um
to attack okay
i think we have another question up here
yeah um
yeah thanks for your
talk and i got a question about bot
protection i work on a software service
product which is very very attractive
for
people who are trying
logins from
database leaks
and
for us the invisible recapture from
google was the only solution
to protect our lock-in
against bots
and automated attacks
do you know how safe they are
like a recapture i think it's a top of
the notch or one of the top of the knot
solutions
but
do you have any experience
so recaptcha is relatively strong but of
course i mean they are always the the
machine learning tools that are
currently used
by
third-party capture services are
stronger and stronger even at some point
what they do is they just automatically
send it to a specific person that will
solve it manually so this is i think the
case you have like a tool called death
capture that's doing both of it it's uh
so if the captcha is simple it solve it
with machine learning if not it sends it
sends it to uh to someone usually in
india
that will uh
that will solve it so it's a it's an
ongoing challenge to be able to um to uh
to
improve uh
capture strength
um
but there are many different ways to try
to detect but not only about like
captcha this is like the the end
solution that
actually companies now are trying to to
avoid because it's time consuming also
for the consumer it's bad user
experience
thanks
hi uh you talked about uh randomizing or
pseudo uh minimizing the shipping
address for
some scalpel that is trying to buy all
the sneakers on the market for whatever
um
has anyone tried
talking to the shipping guys of ups and
stuff like that because it sounds like
an integration with those guys can
provide a feedback loop to actually
detect them
um so this is an
interesting topic
i don't think that's okay so it's
probably below i don't think that uh
this is something that we did um
indeed this is uh this is something that
can be done but i mean i assume that
people are uh sometimes
writing shortcuts for also addresses so
uh it may lead to false positive um
uh one option probably would be in the
logs of the um to propose a service for
the website to to aggregate the logs and
check if there are any uh
um aggregation that can lead to
detection of scalping operations this is
can something that can be done
eventually more at the level of the
log analysis
okay thanks
do we have any other questions for johan
all right we're okay go for it
uh hi
so um
with this technique let's say uh
professional sculptors are to say what
quantity of product might this person be
looking at
and then how
this person actually gets than
things
once the quantity sometimes it can go up
to 50 different box of
let's say sneakers that cost each of
them 100 or even i don't know a bit more
so it can be sold at much higher price
so you can see in mac resell markets for
specific brands
the prices of items can go up to a
thousand dollars so when you have 50
bucks so you multiply the two numbers
you can you can make like um
a very large amount of money so
this also explains the price of the bud
that i showed you brought the io uh two
thousand dollar this is an investment
but eventually um sometime it pays off
all right we are getting to the end of
our time so please give johan a round of
applause for bad boss
so i'm going to give you
thank you thank you very much
hmm
yes
all right
we're on with our next presentation
which i'm super excited about so mitre
we've heard a lot about them the past
few
years they have a new addition to their
tool set
the attack flow
so uh today we have marcus osterlo here
with us from avis i.t security he does a
little offensive he does a little sock
and he enjoys bouldering so if you want
to talk to him later you have some
things to talk about anyway he's going
to talk to us about attack flows so take
it away marcus yeah thanks jen for the
nice introduction
yeah welcome everybody to my talk about
how to measure id security uh by using
micro attack
yeah some words additional words about
miss
myself
i have a master's degree from the world
university book on iit security
and i'm pretty into like jen already
told you uh into the offensive part
and used my knowledge to um currently
building up socks and blue teams so they
get uh from the attack perspective a
better um
a better
view on the on the defense in general
yeah so why should we measure security
so let's talk about the motivation
imagine um
you have a bigger it environment let's
say in a company
and in this idea environment you have
distributed responsibilities like you
have some guys that are managing the
clients you have some guys that are
managing the service web applications
and so on and so forth
and
yeah those guys are also doing um
some changes in their environment
and as a security team i'm not directly
into control of this so i can only see
the results of those changes
or by talking to the people
and get the informations
so
it would be great for me as a security
practitioner practitioner to get
these changes directly on a regular
basis so i can um state for instance
assumptions about my environment and say
hey i need for instance this very
important firewall rule and say that my
environment
my environment must be like this
and or for the security operations
center
you have a use case for instance and you
want to check if this use case is still
working all the time because you're
getting the right logs and there's
nothing missing
so um
would be great to have something to
measure this and to verify this so that
we can build security on confidence from
our security perspective
so
for this let's talk about mitral attack
first
so what is mitral attack in general
mitral attack is a framework
with generic attacks in it those generic
attacks are categorized in different
tactics or so-called tactics here this
is uh the upper line here
where you can say i have something like
initial access so how do i get into the
company execution so i get my code
executed and so forth so on and so forth
and then we have the generalized uh
attacks
that were
on a described on a very generic way
here
and so what can you do with it because
it looks
at the first glance like a boring table
okay it is sometimes but um
you can do with mata uh attack modeling
so much was all also doing this for you
so it is modeling some attacker groups
or attackers in general
and let's see how it works so for
instance i use for the initial access
for a company i use the phishing tactics
techniques and then i get execution via
the native api for instance then
for persistence purposes because i get a
foot into the door and i want to keep it
there i create an account for me so i
can come back because the system is
reachable about over the internet
then i
can probably set up um
or do a privilege escalation to get
system rights on the system uh by doing
um a dll injection and then i can get my
credentials uh during the credential
dumping phase
so like this you can
general model
your your
infrastructure
but um oftentimes
in compliance driven companies i see
that my mitral is a bit misused because
this is not a checklist
because each and every technique here
can be is only a generalized attack
description
you have
multiple layers under android for
instance you can um do the native api
execution by using powershell or by
using um
c-sharp or something else that you can
imagine so you have many many multiple
or multiple ways in general to to do
your actual attack
so
um because we can also use mitral by
adopting it on a on our company for
instance uh made an abstract picture of
that so we can um play through some
scenarios for us and say hey come on i
take the the tactics
and uh derive techniques from that and
to bo to model um scenario for me
yeah let's say an attacker is doing some
reconnaissance
previously then he is setting up an
email and say hey i will do the initial
access by doing a phishing attempt
do adding
an attachment to have uh execution
probabilities so that i for instance
execute the command line and dump
dropping my code on on the machine
then on the machine itself uh it comma
calls back via for instance https thanks
to let's encrypt uh fully encrypted uh
to our command control server and then
gets uh the next attack steps
okay now we're on the machine
we can say hey come on uh we want to kee
we want to stay there and doing some
persistence um
for instance like i said before we just
use a
dll injection because we found a program
or a service that is searching for a
specific dll and we know to notice that
okay so now we're system on a windows
client for instance
and um the next step is for us
for privilege escalation purposes
after that the next step is uh do uh
moving laterally so when we assist them
we can simply dump um
elsa's
if we do the right steps before and
jump to the next box and here we found
for instance some text files for the
next machine and doing some collection
and
exfiltrate the information
to a different server in the internet
and so you can adopt all the
tactics with derived techniques and play
with micro attack in general to get a
get a feeling and the
overview of your attack landscape
and play something through
so um okay we saw now uh mitral attack
and but how do we measure
so
uh in the past we um
we did uh security testing for instance
like something like red teaming where we
hired external red team
and said hey come on guys hack my
company and give me a report about that
and tell me how do i
how i can improve that
and then um yeah this is good this is
very important but it's most of the time
it's doing only annually so you have a
snapshot of one time in the in the year
about your current security state
only one or two
different um ways into your company so
the next
candidate might be penetration testing
which is a more
focused approach where you can say i
want to
test this machine or that machine or the
entire network this web application and
so on it's also good
but
imagine you have five pentesters and 800
machines that doesn't scale
so
then
also a candidate is vulnerability
scanning which is also great because
it's a broader approach but
vulnerability scanning is more focused
on the cves and in general so you can
just
patch the system and you're fine you can
measure it with that which is good so um
it might be a part in the general
security program here
but you can't just
test with it some architecture problems
for instance and there are different
offenses for defensive tours
that are mostly working like black boxes
where you automate your test behavior
but
what i
would
say to use or what what might be
interesting to use that we as a security
practitioner practitioners model our uh
expectations about the environment and
say hey guys we want for instance this
firewall must be there or the web
application must be authenticated like
this
and uh or or this cm rule must be
triggered under these conditions
so it's more like the mindset of the um
of the software development life cycle
where when you use the test driven
approach and say hey
i write a test for it and check if it's
if my condition that i want to have is
there
so how can we measure that with mitra so
we simply use mitra
and put it into for instance atomic red
team
um
this is one one way to do this um so
let's dive into it um so what is atomic
red team atomic red team is actually a
micro use case that you can model within
a
simple yaml file and run it
like in a
it's actually attack in general so
you have different sections here in
a
atomic red team case
the first one is the input arguments
imagine this like variables for a
function
then you have to check the prerequisites
then you run the attack itself and
you're cleaning up the system to become
the previous state again to be clean
so okay
let's
show this on a
small example
let's say we have some source files here
because we want to run a stager which is
written in c sharp
and have an output file somewhere in
temp
then we have a prerequisite that we need
a special compiler and also the access
to this compiler um so and then the next
step is to compile the code and run the
attack and after that
remove all the files that we generated
like this okay
this is a atomic test which is great
but for measuring it's not enough
because
we need criterias without criterias we
can't measure anything and we can also
validate anything so we need at least
success or failure criterias to say um
this is a successful test or the it's a
failed test
so when the atom when the attack goes
through
the test is successful itself but it's a
failure for us because the attack is
working
so
let's look at the example here again
we have at least three different
criterias here so we need to uh get
the the
compiler must be existing and we need
access to this compiler because i can't
block it by for instance applocker and
then attacker not are able to use it
potentially and then uh i want uh the
stager to do what the stager is doing
uh connect to the commanding control
server and
load the next
stage
and then we have a successful attack
in general
so
this is also nice um
let's zoom
zoom out a bit more
because yeah atomic tests are good and
great to have a test scenario but it's
very very limited on one point so if you
want to run
a chain of attacks with a bigger
scenario like we showed before that you
can definitely model
you need chains and each and every chain
has
the success criteria and a validation
step so when the chain fails somewhere
you know why
another thing is that some micro attacks
are not really possible to
to get modeled like this so imagine you
modeling
create a count like an attack it might
be interesting on different systems
but it's pretty limited so you can model
it like for a zoom use case to test it
that i create an account doing something
in between and delete the account again
otherwise i would just mimic
administrative behavior which is not
intentional though
so how can we use this methodology
in general
you must choose your must conditions so
you have to be focused on that you
gather them and then you prioritize them
so the most important
you will implement other because we have
uh all everyone has only eight hours a
day so
we have to model it like this and focus
and to start with a bunch of of the of
those cases for instance then we create
the cases so write our expectations to
our environment and say hey it must be
like this
then we run the test we validate the
test
and then we improve our environment and
then we can go on and on and on and
create even more of those tests and then
we can measure in the end our
environment like this
so how to express this
in numbers for instance
we can use it with mitra with metrics
and say we have a
technique here
we have model
in general
five
tests like this
we are mitigating four of them and
alerting only two of them the goal
should be to to mitigate and alert every
five of them but sometimes it's simply
not possible because you have way too
much
way too much way
way too much false positives
and another a very
important aspect is that you focus on
your environments so
for instance the windows environment
then we have the clients for it and we
want to model those tests there and see
if they are improving or changing and
how the current security posture is over
there
so then we also can measure this over
time
making
a regular iteration about this so the
time intervals is up to you so you can
run it daily you can weekly monthly but
not daily
and you have different
categories here
the red ones are the attackers
successful so i have to do something
then the tech is mitigated i have
counter measures for this in place
like hardening stuff here
then we have monitoring
so we at least getting the logs and can
read the logs
after the successful attack
but this is a prerequisite for the get
alerted thing so um that we have a vm
alert for instance and say hey now we
are also getting
a notification when this happens even
when when it's mitigated
so we can also go a bit deeper into this
that we can
write down some cases
uh pretty briefly so um
let's
take for instance the elvis as us
dumping via
run dll
here the attack is successful we
categorize it in mitra and we defined
countermeasures we have a risk scoring
within it so how important is it how
fast and do i need to act here
and we have the scope for me a system
here is the whole system like the
environment of the company and local is
more the the local machine it's only
affected there and you have some
guy that is responsible to mitigate or
to do the stuff behind the successful
task
okay so
we are coming finally to the end of my
talk
so what are the advantages of this
strategy so we have a reproducible
methodology to measure our security
posture in general
so uh also we can recognize changes
there
so if one of the divisions is
maybe not intentional at all and changes
some security
uh uh settings
then um yeah we want to recognize this
and we want uh to get notified here
and
we also um in general um
uh getting the monitoring gaps because
with this approach we can also test our
theme use cases on a regular basis and
we have not only isolated the text and
we can um yeah model more uh
sophisticated scenarios for us to test
those and the most important things is
then your your security posture gets
verifiable
so thanks for your attention now i'm
open for questions
[Applause]
okay
hello
hello thank you for a nice talk uh one
question about
in case of you using the atomic red team
framework to
measure detection in the area of er
products
where
set you deline or split the line in case
of i would say in case if you dump
credentials from the else's process
you can execute your atomic
[Music]
i would say um artifact
and it's more or less the the idle case
but compared to when i use the same
technique with from a framework like
cobalt strike or brute rachel where can
i set the line that i say okay yeah it's
okay we see this but compared when i do
the same technique based on in memory
encryption other things i do not longer
see this technique where can i say okay
um it makes sense it makes sense to do
it um
in this way or to say um
we we see it at this point but not
longer after we use cobalt swag or
other tools
yeah
generally you have to prioritize first
that you can say um these are the texts
that are um
more probably for my environment um you
can use the the tactics from
a cobalt strike and you implement it
first when you say this might be an
attack that is
that takes place in my environment and
then you have to model this um yeah when
you have a deeper memory stuff that you
have to model okay you need to more a
bit more work to
do to do
yeah or to to work on this case but then
you you use the framework to get to to
prove the visibility to prove the
detection so
when i execute the artifact from atomic
rectum i will
maybe uh the dr products we see this
um but um
especially in case of elsa's there are
now of
many ways to dump it in a different way
so for example you open um or you search
for
um an open handle which is already open
in case of service host process and then
i do not long receipt but how what can i
say then um
is it enough or should i say okay
i know there always be a way to bypass
or do it but um
from my own experience it's always hard
to find
um
the line so okay until this we see
everything but then and it's made makes
no longer sense or
yeah
it depends
yeah the the one thing is that you have
what you already stated is that you have
uh different perspective and angles that
you must implement that that you want to
see
and then you can trigger those and then
you can detect this but when you also
detect this then you have some kind of
zoom use case let's say
and um you build it and then with atomic
red team for instance you can uh trigger
this uh use case and that's the more
than uh in this scenario more uh
the better idea actually okay
because you don't have
all the time though in the world so
okay
thank you
hi question regarding the
test case input files basically
so you define it and then you just run
it has anyone already provided a large
library of predefined test cases that
you can just use yeah
atomic red team is a
repository on github where you exactly
have this
many predefined use cases that you can
use and build up
how many use cases do you have
a question i did
several hundreds i would i could say
question two the example you showed was
about windows right summer deck on
windows so this is executing on one host
machine how well does this work on a
network
centric perspective something that spans
multiple machines
um there you just set up a test machine
for that and then you penetrate the the
your environment like the network
i would set it up like this
okay thanks
you're welcome
any other questions for marcos
all right then please give marcos a hand
thank you very much
wait
we have to
thank you very much it's our speaker
so i'm gonna
so
it is 16 24 so we have some minutes
before um
our last speaker
i'm going to stop my timer so i don't
cancel
i would like to try an experiment if
you're willing to
the day we've had some very delicious
but
sleep inducing food we've had some
exciting talks yes we have
but i'd like to try
a
game that is corona friendly but
and also um
gets your blood moving
um and is actually a little bit
very competitive
so the idea is this
what you need to do is to stand up and
face somebody near you and play rock
paper scissors
so if you don't know how to play rock
you'd make a rock a paper or scissors to
the person in front of you
um and when you do this uh paper covers
rock scissors rock paper scissors with
the next person
and let's see
if we can get this done within five
minutes
so
without further ado please get up find
somebody and rock paper scissors and
let's see if we can make this happen
just once
winner goes in front loser goes behind
yes
it is freaking amazing to see so many
people still here at the end of the day
powering through
please give yourself a round of applause
do we have bananas or no yes or no we
have bananas okay
so before our last round we are going to
power through with some questions were
you paying attention in the introduction
this morning that's the master question
so
if
okay
yeah we'll just go from here so first
question there are five questions you
can win
a banana
if you get the questions right so the
coveted b-sides munich
comeback banana is could be there for
you first question
which year was the first b-sides munich
organized
yes
yes she gets a banana
okay well she grabs her banana
how many cfp submissions did we receive
this year
58 is
correct the answer well done
catch you banana
okay
how many
virtual speakers did we have today
yes
three oh my god she is collecting
bananas in the corner people
okay
second to last question
number
of
workshops this year
four i heard four is that correct one
two correct get your banana
and then last but not least
why layer six
say it very loud
presentation layer winds with a loud
voice thank you very much all right get
your banana
[Applause]
so uh thank you very much thanks for the
energetic round of answering questions
and now it's time to introduce our
closing keynote speaker i'm super
excited to have her i've been a huge fan
for quite a while but i think you are
the one up to introduce her so
sneha without further ado let's do this
thank you so much jen
and to be fairly honest i take it as an
honor for myself to introduce her
because she has not only been a friend
to me but she has also been a mentor and
she's not just my mentor she takes up
the responsibility to mentor everybody
on every monday of every month of every
year
ladies and gentlemen it's really honor
and i'm so excited and stoked and happy
to have tanya jenka here today
although she's virtually present today
but she is here on our stage
to guide us through the entire process
of how
while performing security
how do you still keep engineers your
friends and not enemies
so
please give a huge round of applause she
should hear it right there in canada
that we are missing her here and we
appreciate that she took the time today
and is honoring us by guiding us how to
keep both these security worlds right
together in one place and nice and
happily so please give a round of
applause to tanya jenka
[Music]
hi everyone i really really appreciate
snea and the entire besides team having
me here and thank you for letting me
present virtually
because sometimes you just can't make it
to the place you really want to be at so
this talk is called adding dats to ci cd
so adding das as in like a dynamic
application security testing tools
sometimes people will say oh yeah web
app scanner and i sort of mean that yes
but
i started writing this out and then i
remembered when
people first started adding vasts to
pipelines where i worked and i was the
person adding them and it didn't happen
exactly like this but it felt a bit like
this
so i was like i've added the scanner to
your pipeline and the software
developers were like it is too slow this
is taking forever and then we went
through the results and there was a
false positive in the tool because i was
using a free tool it was perhaps
like it i thought it was amazing at the
time right and i i'm like but i found
eight real bugs automatically
um but they're like it's too slow and it
felt like one false positive breaking
the build is not acceptable so then i
was like i should change the name of
this talk from just adding dast to ci cd
without losing any friends because if
you don't have a good relationship with
the software developers and if you're
doing devops with the ops team you're
just
so not only are you not going to be able
to have coffee with the cool kids but on
top of that it's like really really hard
to get your job done without i'm taking
off my sweater because when i talk i
like move around a lot and i get really
warm um
but it's it's really hard to get the
things you want done without ticking
everyone off if you're not careful and
so we're going to talk about different
ways that you can do that
so you can put this tool in a pipeline
and get really good results but also all
the places not in a pipeline that you
can put it
but still automate it and still get good
results and a whole bunch of just other
tests you can do etc so like who's this
person that's friends with snaia
so i am a giant nerd and i'm the
director of developer relations and
community at bright security um i
founded the wehack purple community
where you can take a bunch of training
courses for free
about software security my obsession
i'm on the internet i wrote a book
called alice and bob learn apsec i did
basically
so the main gist of this slide
is that i'm a nerd on the internet i've
been a nerd for a really long time and
i'm hoping that you will sit through my
presentation and give me a chance
because you're like she seems pretty
competent so that is me where i have
slightly longer hair
okay
so what problem are we trying to solve
because
all of these talks that you saw were
trying to solve a problem and what we
one of my main things i want to solve
just in my career is insecure software
um it's causing data breaches around the
world it's the number one cause of data
breaches
it's not the number one cause of
software security it's not the number
one cause of security incidents it's not
the number one cause of people having
their money stolen it's people stealing
all of your data which is the most
damaging type of security incident you
can have um i would like us to not win
this occasion every year so every year
verizon which is an american company
makes this breach report and they've
been doing it since 2008 and pretty much
every year
insecure software wins
the worst title of being the number one
cause of data breaches and
i want us to do better
um another problem we're trying to solve
is if we're going to work in a devops
shop and we're going to try to make
their software more secure
we need
our tools to be accurate need them to go
really fast and whatever we can do we
need to automate so there's going to be
way more devops people than security
people it's just a fact there's way way
way more software developers than appsec
people github released a report in
january
that said so it used to be one to one
hundreds there'd be one abstract per
person for every div
now it's 500 to 1.
those are not great odds so we need to
do we need to be accurate but we need to
also be fast and
try to automate
and so
if we want to do devsecops so us
security folks doing security in a
devops environment
we need to test from multiple angles
so we can't just do one test and be like
i'm sure it's fine
that's not good enough we need to have
good relationships between security dev
and ops and i don't mean that like you
have to give them hugs or you go grocery
shopping with them but i mean that we
have to be able to work with them and
have a good relationship so i can say
things like hey did you see those test
results and the person answers you know
something like yeah i did or i got the
email i haven't had a chance to read it
yet or yeah i've been meaning to talk to
you
i need them to not answer with go to
hell tanya you broke our pipeline again
i need to maintain a good relationship
so i can get my job done
i have worked at places where the
security team and the software
developers were like that's just er all
the time and i spent like half of every
week just trying to put out
angry emotional fires
of people that didn't trust each other
that didn't like working together etc
and so if you have a good relationship
you get twice as much done
and then the last thing is
i want bugs fixed as soon as possible
and i don't mean i want them fixed on
monday instead of friday i mean if we're
following the system development life
cycle so if you're doing waterfalls like
this it's like requirements design
coding testing release if you're doing
agile you do that same thing but you do
it in a circle and you release a whole
bunch of times if you're doing devops
you do the eternity symbol where you're
like yep got it got it releasing it got
it releasing it got it release it and
you just continue to release over and
over again even more often than agile
and so automation is our only way that
we can keep up with those people and i
want them fixing those bugs as soon as
we find them or as soon as they have
time i don't want things waiting until
later i don't want the software
developers or the operations folks
thinking like is tonya ever going to
tell me what's wrong is she ever gonna
do a test like where is that lady
i want to be there for them and know
i want them to know that i can help
and so
fixing books as soon as possible in the
system development life cycle the reason
i want that is because it is way cheaper
it's way way cheaper that way
so
what are so today we're going to zero in
specifically on das so
right security bought my company a few
weeks ago and they make a desk and so
when they're like oh or you know you're
gonna start applying to companies what
you want to talk about i won't talk
about that and how people can do it
right because i see a lot of people buy
tools and they don't do it right and
they don't get good results i want
people to get better results
so what the heck is fast so it stands
for dynamic application security testing
what it means is that your app needs to
be running
so it could be localhost it could be a
web server it could be a container a
platform as a service it doesn't matter
but your app is running like you can see
the software in a browser
and then it sends requests
at your app to try to find security
vulnerabilities your app responds and it
goes back and forth like this it can
also do apis where it sends requests to
your apis it receives the response it
goes back and forth and the idea is it's
sort of
a computer conversation
and it just keeps trying to find all
your vulnerabilities and it does this in
an automated way so it's like hey how's
it going oh it's not going so well oh is
it going like this okay yeah and then
from that conversation it starts
crafting better and better tests
it automates this for you so you could
just like sit back and be like oh okay
this is happening that's good
it's different than static testing or
software composition analysis that
requires a copy of your code
so i used to be a pen tester and they
wouldn't give me a copy of the code
so i had to do all my tests in a dynamic
manner where i was trying to talk to the
app either manually or with a das tool
but the idea is it interacts with your
app to try to find out what's wrong
and so why did i
decide to zero in on that so when i was
a software developer
for around 17 years i briefly took a a
break as a sysadmin and then came back
to software my true love
and basically
i started when i moved into security
with a dynamic scanner i found it way
easier than static analysis or software
composition analysis i found it easier
than trying to figure out because this
is the secret it's the secret i thought
it was the easiest one and i find a lot
of people who are first getting into
these things they find it easy too
i also so maybe i'm not supposed to
admit this but like the first time i ran
a dash and i found vulnerabilities i'm
like i'm a hacker
it felt very exciting and i know that
might sound silly because i'm like you
know in my mid-40s and i've been doing
this a long time but i don't know how to
explain whenever i find stuff i'm like
yeah that's right i'm awesome
um but the last one which is probably
the most important one is that your app
is out there sitting on the internet
your api unless it has a gateway in
front of it or a bunch of firewalls in
front of it is out there sitting on the
internet
and on the internet anyone can point a
dash data and scan it if you have a waff
or you have other defenses you could
probably shoot away but most the
internet doesn't have a web application
firewall or a runtime application
security protection tool so like a
shield for your app most of the internet
doesn't have that
and so that means basically anyone with
very little skill can just point a
dynamic scanner at you and find
vulnerabilities they are usually
exploitable and so it's the most obvious
place to start because that's where bad
guys start unless you're open source
they don't have a copy of your code
unless they're an insider threat they
can't test from the inside so a das can
just test from anywhere on the planet
and it doesn't take very long to find
problems and so i want us to fix those
problems first because they are the most
evident to people that might be
malicious and so what is devops so this
is a very short and small summary
so devops is spoiler alert it's not
paying one person to two jobs that's not
what it is
so basically devops is a newer way to
create software it's a methodology and
it's a culture so you follow certain
processes people act and feel certain
ways and you often use certain tools to
reinforce it so we're going to talk
about it a bit more so sometimes people
will say it's people products and
processes
i don't really like that i like the idea
of us following the three ways of devops
but i digress next slide so so first of
all if you're doing devops you usually
have a ci cd so it's continuous
integration continuous delivery
or continuous deployment depending upon
how you're using it but it's automated
software
that tests and releases your software
and your infrastructure to different
environments
so it takes a copy of your code and
builds it and tests it and then it's
like oh i'm gonna put it on a dev server
i'm gonna test it again oh i'm gonna
build it like i'm gonna take that
artifact i'm gonna copy it to the qa
server i'm gonna run even more tests and
it does this with your infrastructure as
well it can actually build the
infrastructure and then plop your app on
it and test them together and it's
i think it's quite nifty
so then if we want to do devops there
are the three ways of devops so sort of
like the three rules you need to kind of
do these things if you want to get all
the value that you can of devops and so
the first one is efficiency for the
entire system and so when i see that i'm
like not just your part tanya
you have to like share with everyone and
so that's important
fast feedback and so then i added to
that that is accurate and gets to the
right people
it's nice if there's fast feedback
it gets to the right people but if
there's fast feedback but it's totally
inaccurate
or like you can't actually see it or you
have to attend 20 meetings to get a copy
that's not fast
and then the third way is continuous
learning and improvement of your daily
work sometimes people call this risk
taking but the idea is is that you step
back from your daily activities and
exert effort to making your daily
activities even better on a regular
basis usually every month
the last thing i want to say about
devops is that not all security testing
needs to be done in the pipeline for you
to be doing devops so you can do brief
checks in the pipeline
and then do
like slow checks overnight like there's
a lot of different options and so we're
gonna talk about that
so let's talk strategy for putting a
dynamic scanner in your ci cd
so the first one that i see the most
often one that i i did at the beginning
that made all the other dads pretty
ticked off at me was to run my desk on
full blast
and then lose all your friends so what i
mean by this is
turning it on saying do every test
you know
catalog all my different links test
every single part of my whole app as
thoroughly as you possibly can and then
it might run like six hours or something
and no one's impressed by that if the
pipeline previously ran 18 minutes and
now it runs 6 hours and 18 minutes no
one's going to be very cool with that so
this is not the one you want to do
in the release pipeline so the release
pipeline is the one that everyone's
using to release all their code
so what you could do instead of this is
that you could take a copy of the
release pipeline put it underneath in
your cicd software
and then make it so it doesn't release
or just releases to one safe place where
you can do security testing and you put
it there and you run the security test
and then that's it and then the results
go to the software developers or go to
the security person so that they can see
it and take action
so that would be a better way to do it
so you're not blocking production you
can still get a very thorough test done
so sometimes this is called a parallel
pipeline or an asynchronous pipeline and
you can run it nice and long and slow
and you can run it like every night or
every friday
and have those results get sent
somewhere for someone to manually look
through that
so the next thing you could do is you
could refine your scope by using a har
file so
r
h a r stands for html archive file so if
your software developer or sorry your qa
team are doing something
using something like selenium to do
automated tests of your app you can get
a copy of that file that's a har file
that they're recording when they do all
of that cool automation you can feed
that into your dynamic scanner
and then it will just do that test you
can basically make your your test 30 of
the time like instead it's like 70
faster or even faster than that because
you're just testing whatever new feature
you're releasing or you're just testing
the new code or you're just testing what
the qa person thinks is important
and is this complete coverage no but
this would be part of the coverage you
do so it's like we're just going to test
this in the pipeline very quickly it's
going to take six minutes
and if you break like if you do get a
high or critical illness we're going to
break the build
but for all the other testing we're
going to do it outside the pipeline and
we still might come to you and need
fixes but this is what we think is an
emergency and so it goes in the pipeline
another thing you can do so when i first
showed this app this um slide to people
they're like you can't just test only
what you want to test tanya i'm like
sometimes you can so quite often um when
i work places we'll have specific
vulnerabilities we're targeting or types
of bugs that we're targeting that are
really important to us that we feel are
particularly dangerous or we see a lot
of and so in the pipeline i might just
test for those like just injection or
just cross-site scripting and that's it
or maybe we have like a new
um security policy and we just want to
target in on security headers and like
no one's using security headers so we
just test for that it's like you know
what you're breaking the policy you know
we're all looking for this so you can't
go to prod but then i do my other
extensive testing outside of prod and so
that way what you could do is slowly
eliminate a certain type of bug
and then in a few weeks you change to a
new vulnerability that you're looking
for and that would be really really fast
thing you can do that i think everyone
should do every single time
is only do technology specific tests
so let's say you have a wordpress
application or website
you would only do the like you you would
do the wordpress sites
but you wouldn't do an mssql test
because you would be running postgresql
because that is what wordpress runs on
you wouldn't do a ruby on rails test
right because you're using wordpress and
so on and so you just do the technology
tests that are specific to what you're
doing and so i always want to do this so
if i'm scanning an app that's made in
node.js
and it's using mongodb i definitely want
to do all the specific tests for those
and i'll do other tests that apply to
every type of website but i'm like oh no
ms sql no wordpress tests no this know
that and i just throw them in the
garbage because i know they just don't
apply
like if you're in azure you don't need
to do aws tests right
and so this is something that i
generally do all the time because
our time is valuable we're busy people
um i wanted to say a quick note on
testing apis if you want to test an api
with a dynamic scanner in a pipeline or
not in a pipeline it's very very
important that your schema file or your
definition file your open api file your
swagger file whatever you want to call
the thing that defines your api
it needs to be complete
and you can complete it using a linter
and so some dynamic scanners have a
linter built into them like bright does
there's a few that do that and so you
just open up your api or there's
separate like
software things that just lint your api
and they're very very thorough
and so basically you use one of those
and you open up your definition file and
it will tell you things that are missing
and so i used to be a dev and i did all
of the mistakes that i tell people not
to do now
because i went to college in the 90s for
software development and so
i never learned that had to learn it on
my own
and so it will do things like so like
let's say you've declared a vulnerable
uh you've declared a variable and the
variable is date of birth so usually
people will be like date of birth type
date and that's it
but the scanner needs to know what's the
maximum
date what's the minimum date does it can
it only be in the past
um like can a person be 5 000 years old
what is the format of the date etc so if
you don't fill those out the dynamic
scanner can't test that for you
and so
usually if you just take an open api
file or swagger file and you plug it in
most dash scanners like kind of barf
they don't know what to do and they're
like yeah it looks good to me i guess
because your file is not complete so you
need to use a linter on it to make sure
it is complete and when you make it
complete like when you add the maximums
and minimums and the file type the
formats etc
you're making your app more secure so
your api will be able to defend itself
because it has input validation
available to it now because you just
defined that
but without that that means someone like
me could go in
and say oh okay so um yeah i'm 4 000
years old how's that for you okay cool
and that might break your application
eventually and so it is important to do
linting on your api definition files
okay so the other thing is you don't
have to put everything in the dash so
what you could do let's say you've
decided to record a horror file and
you're only going to do technology
specific tasks
and then you're going to do
other things so what are other ways that
you can use a task that's automated that
goes with ci cd so we talked briefly
about how you can make a copy of the
pipeline and not release it anywhere
just put it somewhere that you can do
security testing you can even like
create a container load it up add your
app to it
do all your testing then release those
resources out back into the cloud
and finish and just have your test
results so you can do that without
blocking releases but what other things
we could do so first of all you can have
scheduled automated regular scanning so
i like to do this at least once a month
for all my apps that are currently in
production and all the apis so have
scans like a scan runs every night of
the month
and that report comes in and someone
looks at it and decides if it thinks
those are real vulnerabilities or maybe
some of them are false positives
depending upon the type of tool you're
using
and then put those things in the backlog
and then go talk to teams about it so
if you have 30 apps you could run one
every night
and you just have to look at one report
per day except on mondays you have to
look at three reports but the point is
is that then you would be able to make
sure every app is having thorough
testing
and it's still automated it's happening
while you're not at work no one's
waiting for those resources so this is
the thing i see a lot at a lot of
companies
another thing you can do is want to
offer manual scans so
last year i helped some companies do m a
some mergers and acquisitions and
they're like we're gonna buy you know
these companies and so i went and i just
used the desk camera on all the
different apps and i was like
okay so this one's gonna cost like tons
of money to fix i found like
100 vulnerabilities this one i only
found six i think we could fix this very
quickly i don't think it will cost that
much etc and so i used a whole bunch of
different types of scanning tools to do
an assessment for them of the state of
security at that company and then they
renegotiated the price
and whenever i get a tool the first
thing i do is play with it manually
because i want to know like how it works
and how i can make it go faster and how
i can make it find more things
and so usually whenever you get a tool
the first thing you do is manual testing
so there's still space for that in our
industry there is still people doing
that every day
another thing you can do so every pen
tester ever basically
they use a das tool and they do manual
testing so they'll use a scanner that's
usually what we call it like oh yeah i'm
still doing quick scans to like check
and see if there's anything that i might
have missed with my eyes
but sometimes the dash scanner will find
something that manual testing doesn't
and vice versa so you get a much better
more complete result when you have a
person who's a security expert doing
manual testing as well
but it's expensive and it takes weeks
and so you have to choose where you do
that like most companies can't afford to
do a pen test everywhere so you use a
lot of dynamic scanning quite regularly
and then you do like spot pen tests or
just the ones that have to be pci
compliant or whatever the case is where
you work
i want to remind you that you still have
to do other types of testing we can't
only do
dynamic testing so there's static
testing where it just looks at the code
that your team wrote
which is called sas there's software
composition analysis where it just looks
at your dependencies your libraries your
frameworks any code you your team didn't
write but that is part of your app to
see if it's known to be vulnerable
there's i asked which is interactive
application security testing where
basically it's a binary and you put it
inside your app and it tests as you use
your app
there's oops wrong button there's secret
scanning where it just looks through
your entire code base and it tries to
find secrets so this could be an api key
an api secret a password a connection
string etc anything like that that
shouldn't be kept in your code it should
be in a secret management tool
and so that is really cool
we want to do these tests as or some of
these tests as well
so these are places where you can do
dynamic scanning so you could do
security regression testing with unit
tests because the unit test
basically your ide creates a little baby
mini web server and you can do security
tests there for the first time then you
can do dynamic scanning against your dat
like your dev server or your local host
then in the testing phase you can do you
know full blast test
i didn't mean that for it to rhyme but
it just does um and you could also do a
manual penetration test in a pipeline so
release
the release
phase and maintenance phase is where you
use pipeline so that's where you want to
tune your das and just do certain types
of tests and you could do scheduled
weekly tests
after it's released into production
um i was talking about like how the
first time i ran a desk how i felt so i
felt kind of like this
a little like that i really was like i
am a hacker now this is awesome
and so uh i feel like it's really fun
and i know that i'm silly and that is
okay
but
when i
first ran one it was just so fun and i
felt so amazing that i found security
vulnerabilities that as a dev i never
found before and so
then as a dev i started doing scans and
i started teaching other devs to do
scanning and you could find a lot of
stuff
so
with a quick conclusion because we only
have two minutes left
we need to do dynamic scanning because
any person on the internet can do a
dynamic scan of our app and we need to
keep ahead of those people
automation is our friend but if you are
at b-sides you already know that
dynamics testing in a pipeline it has to
be fast and it has to be accurate
or no one's going to want to hang out
with you at lunch all the devops people
are going to be like no there's tanya
she broke our pipeline nope this seat's
taken missy
we can do dynamics testing outside of
the pipeline but still be devops
friendly that is okay we're not breaking
any rules
other types of testing are still needed
so we can find as many vulnerabilities
as possible and make our app as safe as
we can
and basically i'm pretty silly
that's a thing you probably have picked
up on already anyway i have a couple
free resources i want to give you
uh some some are free the books are not
free but everything else is free so
first of all
i have a podcast we had purple podcast
where this season we're learning little
tiny security lessons so you can
subscribe on any platform or watch it on
youtube um
these are all books about devops except
mine which is about security and i have
a chapter about devops
i think we can't do it right i mean i
think we can't do security right unless
we're doing it right and i think devops
is the most efficient and effective and
quite frankly fun
way to make software
the we hack purple community is free
there's like no upsell or anything it is
just free we have little meetups on the
internet sometimes we meet up in person
we have articles we have blogs we have
lots of conversations and problem
solving and we have a ton of free
courses in there and so everyone is
invited to that
every monday this is what snail is
talking about on twitter is cyber
mentoring monday where basically we use
this hashtag and we respond to so i
always do a tweet to try to start off a
thread but basically people reach out
and say i need a professional mentor and
other people
from within the industry swoop in and
help them and sometimes they become
their mentors sometimes they become
their friend sometimes they have a
virtual coffee with them and suggest a
bunch of books that really change their
career and maybe it could help you
resource is bright so bright has a
highly technical blog with a lot of
information about like every type of
vulnerability and how to fix it that's
pretty handy
and resource is me
i am she hacks purple basically on all
the platforms you can think of i have a
newsletter a website or youtube blah
blah blah blah blah mostly i hang out on
twitter
and with this i'd like to say thank you
so much thank you to the entire b-sides
organizing crew because without them
this conference would not happen thank
you to all of you for attending being in
person is an important way to do
community building and thank you to the
entire international b-sides community
that encourages different cities around
the world to do this
i'm tanya jenka and thank you so much
for having me
thank you so much tanya that was
fantastic
i guess she deserves a louder round of
applause can we have a louder round of
applause please for tanya
that's fantastic
thank you so much tanya is still with us
do you have questions for her
if yes please do come forward
any questions for tanya
yes please
so thank you for the nice presentation
it was really
enlightened i would say
just one point when you mentioned that
someone needs to write the test for the
apis like i'd describe them
usually who is doing that i'm trying to
imagine like
uh is a security person that's doing
that to some from the keyway team so who
is actually describing the api so that
when we run the dust we know that
it's complete
ideally the software developers would do
that part ideally
so every organization is different but
where i've worked is generally the
software developers that are responsible
for adding those parts
but quite frankly usually it's the
security team that notices they're
missing because when i was at dev
or a software developer i say dev a lot
i like i didn't know to do that i was
like it works it does all the things my
client asked for it's perfect and it
wasn't until i became friends with an
ethical hacker and he's like actually
it does do all the things you need it to
do but it does a lot of stuff it's not
supposed to do and i'm like really
and so um usually it's the security team
that starts asking for linting it it
really depends because there's a lot of
software developers that are very
security obsessed
and so they might start doing it
themselves but if you want everyone in
your entire organization to be doing it
you usually have to provide a tool for
all the software developers give them a
lesson on what you expect from them
because otherwise what you receive will
be very different depending upon what
type of experience each step has
does that answer your question yes so
just to confirm do we understand it i
would need to enroll the developers or
to sell this idea to them say hey as
part of the development process we also
need to think about to writing tests
that the dust can use or tool
that would be it oh so they don't have
to write a test the das writes the test
what they need to do is lint their
definition file so you open it up in
something like 42 crunch or bright or
something else like that
and then it tells you this api
definition is incomplete
and it'll actually give you code you can
copy and paste and it'll say stuff like
okay so this is a string cool what's the
maximum length of this string what's the
minimum length of this string are there
any uh like which characters should be
allowed in the string and so you'll say
let's say like lowercase a through to
zed uppercase a through to z and then
zero through to nine
then it won't let any other characters
in there does that make sense
okay now it's clear thank you
okay thank you that was a great question
hi tanya uh i love cats though thank you
a lot um
question about about trying to scale and
trying to roll out
dynamic software testing is awesome and
i want to offer that to my dev teams so
i go to the people that prioritize stuff
like that into the backlog and then i
have
five pos sitting in front of me of which
i need one volunteer
and all of them think
if i go
and volunteer for this i can throw away
all my road map for my products and
features
how do i how do you get over that first
step of them being scared of you
um i so
when the first time i was on a security
team i had been on the software
development team at that same company so
they all already knew me by name like i
already would eat lunch with them or or
hang out with them so they all already
knew me
so it wasn't as intimidating for them
but then when i went on to the next
company
none of the software developers knew me
and so what i did was is i started
giving little presentations about the
things i wanted
and so the presentation would always
start with like this is a big problem
that i see and i wouldn't say like at
our company i'd be like on the internet
it'd be like there's you know like
injection vulnerabilities on the
internet this is how it works and this
is how scary it is and like let's do one
together and then i'd be like but we
could stop it from happening here and
then i'd show them what they could do to
help stop it like i can test for it and
find it you could prevent it in the
first place
and i would kind of just try to show it
to them and make them as excited as i
was if that makes sense and like show
them my passion about it and right now
you're like oh she seems like a really
good presenter yeah i sucked i was
really not good when i started i've been
doing this for like eight or nine years
now and so when i present i'm really
comfortable and i'm not like super
nervous where i feel like i can't
breathe and my heart's beating super
fast but even when i was like not very
good at presenting
they could tell i really really cared
about it and that's why i was showing
them and so the first couple times i
presented
i really thought i was gonna die but i
didn't clearly because i'm still alive
um and and it turned out like they
wanted to know if that makes sense and
they're like yeah you seem really like
worried about this i am and so that's
what's worked for me
is just showing them the thing
sometimes people
like i've worked at places where the
security team says we do this now and
you have to do that and they don't
explain it and i find it doesn't go very
well so i always try to explain
why
we want to do it
how to do it
and i will help you and then if someone
gets stuck i just like run over to their
desk and help them and i keep doing that
until they're like i don't need you
tanya go away stop being like hovering
over me i got this
and then eventually
the software developers are better at it
than i am
and they don't need me anymore for that
thing
but for me i've had a lot of luck with
presenting the problem and like this is
what i think can help and i need all of
your help to get this done
does that help you
hopefully yeah we'll see
but thank you okay
good luck
i actually have two presentations that i
open sourced in my github so if you go
to github.com and then slash she hacks
purple
i have a
a project there of presentations where i
teach you
how to give my presentation to your
depths
and so i have two so far there and a lot
of people have told me like yeah i
wanted to get the devs interested and so
it's like my slides it's a video of me
doing it then it's a video of me saying
what to say for each slide and what
you're trying to accomplish and then i
have a description of the whole thing
and so you could try one of those if you
don't know what to present because i
didn't know what to present when i
started
yeah
are there any any other questions
if there are no further questions or
pane is still here does anybody have any
other question
all right great tania thank you so much
for explaining us because when it comes
to product security dust scanning the
entire ci cd pipeline is super critical
for everyone not just the engineers or
the developers but even for the security
professionals or the security engineers
call call it like that
sometimes um there's one quick question
for you
with the dust scanning involving in the
entire pipeline
how do we basically handle these
vulnerabilities in a way that we are
still friends with the developers and
not just bombard them
because sometimes it might happen that
we say oh that vulnerability is super
critical it's it's got like the cvss
score the night like say for example 9.6
you need to fix it in two days or one
day
so how do we still try to deliver this
how do we rely exactly on dust scan
whereas
and how do we convince our developers
that you know
even though it's a high vulnerability
the tool says it's super critical
but based on this
can you explain how do we maintain the
relationship still happy and nice
so i usually try to give
the developers a license for the tool
i'm using so that if they want to they
can test it earlier so if they want to
when they put it on their dev server or
their local host they can run the test
themselves so when they get to the ci cd
pipeline it's like a double check if
that makes sense
i've had a lot of developers say they
feel it's embarrassing if they break the
build
and so they would rather have access to
look at it themselves first so if i can
afford it i get them all tools or
licenses
and then another thing is is i usually
start
with not breaking the build i work up to
it so first we're just running scans
manually and i'm showing them results
and asking them to fix things then i
start testing a little bit just like a
couple of things in the pipeline and
then when they and i just alert i'm like
alert this is a high alert this is this
and i try to have
um sort of two different service level
agreements once we start having one so
at first it's like anything that was
already there
you know you have months to fix
but any new vulnerabilities that are
higher critical you're not allowed those
so i will break the build if a new
critical vulnerability comes into it so
at first no breaking
and then at first i'm only breaking on
new things that are very high then new
things that are just high
and then new things maybe that are
medium depending upon what level that
you need
and then the stuff that's in the backlog
the stuff that was there before we had a
scanner
i give them more time and we talk about
those
over time because they're already out
there and prod and us not letting them
go to prod with those old
vulnerabilities that are already out
there doesn't really make a lot of sense
like i want them to fix all of it now
but i know that they can't especially
if they're currently doing a project
and no project time has been allocated
to do security bug fixing another thing
i do is i go talk to all the project
managers and i tell them
i want to be at all your project kickoff
meetings and i want to have a two-week
sprint
at least one that is just to fix bugs
and so maybe like four months in or
something we have a sprint where for two
straight weeks or three weeks however
long your sprints are all you do is fix
bugs that i found and so i get ready in
advance so they have lots of work to do
during that time and then they just fix
lots of bugs so by the time they go out
to production with everything
it's like pretty good do you know what i
mean and so i try to get there earlier
and be there and talk to them the whole
way through the project and i don't mean
every single day but like check-ins
quite regularly
and then by the time they get to the end
it's usually really good with legacy
software it's different so software
that's already existed i try to be a lot
more patient because usually fixing like
a dependency
it could mean you know if the dependency
is really old like we saw during log4j
in december
it could be a really like it could be
like a complete re-architecting of the
whole app to update that and so
sometimes i negotiate if it's really
really really bad i'll say okay well i
need five thousand dollars from your
project team so that i can put a like a
web app firewall or a rasp or something
in front of your app because it's so
dangerous having it on the internet
and then you have you know this long to
fix things but if you won't let me put a
laugh in front of it then you only have
this long to fix things and then they're
usually like we found five thousand
dollars tanya
um so i try to like negotiate with them
and realize that they have other
priorities and i'm just one of those
priorities
and then things usually go better and
there's some teams where they're just
like no go away you're wasting my time i
want to talk to you and those are the
most difficult ones and that's where i
have to be like mean tanya
and i like first start off really nice
but then eventually i'm like i'm here to
bother you because you still haven't
fixed those things and like five
separate times i visited you and
eventually i'm gonna visit your boss
right like
like you're forcing me to do this
because you're not holding up your end
of the bargain like is that what you
want because that's not what i want that
sucks we'll never be friends if i just
talk to your boss every time and
sometimes they'll give in and then
sometimes i have to talk to their boss
and if their boss says like well i'm
fine with it i'll talk to the bigger
boss and eventually i'll try to get them
to sign off on that risk so i'll say you
don't want to fix these things you know
you feel times more important than that
cool but you need to sign off that you
are accepting the risk on behalf of the
organization because for me this is
completely unacceptable and i do not
accept this risk and when we're in the
newspaper someday with a giant breach
it's cool your name's going to be in
there it's cool
and then usually someone gives in
and
i've worked places where they don't and
there's one place where i resigned in
protest because i just wouldn't fix
anything ever and i just didn't want to
change and i didn't want to do any
security and i was like i won't work
here
and that's it
so that's the grateful lesson that we
still are learning and i guess we are
still going to learn the same lesson for
next couple of years till the time each
and every company decides to shift left
and consider security as an integral
part and not an external part of the
entire ssdlc process itself
but that said
thank you so much tanya for sharing your
insights and such amazing guidance and
advice
and we are so happy and honored to have
you here and we wish that next year
maybe we can have you physically present
at the event
we wish you all the good luck
thank you thank you
wow what a fantastic day we had today
it's super amazing i mean i'm still so
energetic i know i would also want to
like sit down and absorb all the
knowledge that i have abso like received
today it's it's amazing and the best
thing is
finally after two years i get to meet
you all i get to see you network with
you
and speak with you not just through some
third party platform but like physically
we are looking at each other in flesh
that was so awesome today i mean i don't
know about you all but i'm super happy
and finally i would love to say that but
with caution that maybe our lives are
coming back to normal again or maybe
this is the new normal
hopefully next year we wouldn't have to
wear the masks
but
i'm nobody to say about it at this
particular moment
before
we wrap up completely
first thing i want to do is to thank of
course each and every one of you
but before that i would also want to
thank all of our organizers
and i would request our organizers to
come forward
please
and please provide give a round of
applause
thank you jen
[Applause]
oliver
dagmar
silvio stefan
engmar
chris
and the one and only martin
we all the team of besides munich we
thank you
but
we are not complete yet
we would like to call upon stage our
lightning rod volunteers right here
right now volunteers please come up on
the stage
sartha gayard mikhail cooper
eduardo
and reinhardt
well i see one thing that this year the
stage is little small right do you all
agree
yes
right yeah unfortunately next year we
are having an even bigger stage
[Laughter]
with this i would also like to take the
opportunity to thank all our sponsors
who are present here today
thank you so much for being the backbone
thank you so much for believing in us
and i hope next year the sponsors list
for us will also keep on increasing the
community strength that we have will
always keep on increasing and i
tonight along with my team
would anyone of you like to say a few
words today
before we close up
anyone
[Music]
we want to thank neja for making
everything happen a big round of
applause
there's actually one thing
that i would want to share
every year things grow things evolve
sometimes there are endings and
sometimes there are new beginnings but
one thing we should know is that every
end is basically a new beginning
and today we would like to ask you for
the
new beginning itself
we are looking for someone to join us to
be with us to be the team besides munich
and if you are interested
please join us
unfortunately this is not working so i
cannot really change the slides
otherwise i had a nice slide which says
please join us at volunteers besides
munich.com
this is not working um
this is the reason why we need you
at least the clicker gets working
so yeah we're done
i can go again on this like oh yes there
it is
so yes absolutely
so you're most welcome we definitely
need your help
support to grow
and let's get together and next year
let's have even bigger besides munich
and with that
i would like to thank you all along with
the entire team thank you so much
namaste
[Applause]
that's a wrap
is
[Music]
you