thank you good morning
back in 2019
apple at the worldwide developer
conference announced they were making a
dramatic change to the way they were
dealing with the kernel space on their
mac operating systems
today i'm going to be dealing with one
of the results of this namely the
endpoint security framework or the esf
i am a senior researcher with secure
within their countercept team prior to
being part of the research team was a
threat hunter for years
i have produced multiple white papers
and proof of concept detection codes and
presented at a number of international
conventions
so what are we going to be going over
today we'll be going over what exactly
the essay is
why the esf is important to the
detection industry
how can we
in the industry utilize the esf
some of the issues during implementation
and some of the solutions that i found
to these issues
uh my device poc solution which i code
named esfang
and briefly going over a use case
against the return pressure agent
so first off what exactly is the esf
so the esf is developed as a
kernel-based telemetry acquisition
system by apple and it's
been developed as a way for a one-stop
shop for telemetry needs from the
security industry as you said it works
in the kernel space and because of that
it actually works fairly similar to the
way the etw works inside the windows
operating system
in many ways it succeeds the open bsm or
the open basic security module by sun
systems that was used primarily for
auditing purposes prior to esf and one
of the great results of esf is that it
allows for real-time event acquisition
for
um
direct intervention on a real-time
interception
but what does this exactly look like so
the image on the right here gives a very
basic overview of how this works from
the
user space at the bottom with a endpoint
security application feeding into the
kernel space and getting messages from
the kernel space for the telemetry and
on the left is a demonstration of that
information which from every single
event type includes multiple low-level
data points including the parent process
id
path environmental variables cd hashes
and so forth
but why is the esf important
so
during the presentation at the worldwide
developer conference in 2019 they
announced they were going to deprecate
text or kernel extensions primarily this
means that they were removing
third-party current extensions from the
kernel space meaning that
third-party security vendors could not
use their own kernel extensions for
telemetry acquisition because of this
they introduced something called system
extensions which is their way of
allowing kernel extension
proprietary apple kernel extension
access from the user space using
something called system extensions
equally before esf came along open bsm
as i said was a primary auditing tool
but it was quite clunky to use and
fairly difficult to integrate there's
lots of documentation on the problems
with open bsm so i won't go into them
but needless to say earsafe is a much
easier solution to getting these
telemetry points
so let's have a look at the old way of
how monitoring worked
so at the bottom we have the user space
top kernel space on the left the logs
so what would happen is is that
third-party vendors would have their
monitoring program hooked into a
third-party canal extension running in
the kernel space and acquire telemetry
via that point
then using open bsm hooks they would
hook into log files and acquire them
through an auditing process run them
back to the monitoring program for
detection uh processing
the new way is slightly different
so as we said the system extensions work
in the user space
and they work on frameworks that were
introduced by apple to directly access
kernel space using their proprietary
kernel extensions these work out as the
network extension framework
endpoint security framework esf and the
driver kit framework and using a
amalgamation of the three you have very
high visibility over the low level
telemetry of the operating system
however we're focusing on the esf and
from that it actually hooks into the
endpoint security current extension
getting developed by apple so it allows
them to have this proprietary pipeline
from the user space system extension to
their maintained kernel extension
but why make the change
so the one of the primary reasons
that apple made the change to remove
current extensions was for increased
stability and security
so by removing third-party kernel
extensions you avoid things like the
black screens of death but equally you
avoid third-party malicious kind of
accentuation being introduced into the
operating system
this means that they have much greater
control over what is happening in the
kernel space and it just eliminates a
lot of the overheads and a lot of the
problems that are being encountered with
less stable current extensions that
we're finding in the wild and it means
that everything becomes very uniform
one of the things to note about kernel
extensions is that even though they've
been deprecated they can still be used
they're just you have to dramatically
reduce the security profile of a mac
operating system in order to do so
primarily you used to be able to
introduce current extensions on the fly
on demand however now you have to
degrade the security profile that's
running then you have to
turn on canon extension and then reboot
the system which means you can't just
inject them as you would
but how can we use the esf
so
this slides a little bit messy so i'll
just walk you through it so in the
bottom right you have the main code
running in the user space of your
program
you would then create an endpoint
security client object
this would then subscribe to the
endpoint security kernel extension with
the event types that you want so you
specify the event points one like the
file creation or process creation or
anything to that sort of thing
the endpoint security kernel extension
then crea populates an event message
queue in the kernel space and then pipes
that out to your endpoint security
client which you have already subscribed
which you use to subscribe to the kernel
extension
then on on each message a callback is
generated which you can have a callback
monitor and then each message that's
received can be processed back into your
main code for detection purposes
but what are some of the issues with the
esf use and what are the solutions so
during my experimentation with esf back
in
early 2020
there were a number of solutions that
came out from multiple researchers and
vendors but there were some very primary
issues that came out with its
utilization
namely a bottlenecking issue uh system
verbosity and real parent process id
issue i shall go through each
individually
first of all a bottlenecking issue so
this was actually something that i was
banging my head against for
a couple of weeks even a month two
months and effectively what was
happening was is where you were doing
exactly the same experiment
you would get different data points
being populated and you'd have different
numbers
and it didn't really make any sense as
to why
so you'd conduct the same malicious
experiment using the esf telemetry
acquisition but you'd always get you
always get mismatched data points and
you'd have data points that were being
missing for no particular reason and
equally from a detection perspective
this means that it's inconsistent and
therefore the data points are unreliable
and it was a very long-standing reason
before i figured out exactly why this
was
primarily the issue was caused by the
kernel level q so you may remember from
the previous slide i said that the
kernel extension inside um for the esf
would populate a queue within the kernel
space but what was happening was is this
queue was being overloaded because the
amount of data that you were subscribing
to was simply too much so if you try to
subscribe to too many event types the
queue gets overloaded and silently drops
data packets which then don't come back
to the user space but there's no
indication that this happens so although
the packets have dropped from the kernel
side because the kernel side is
obviously
secure and it's isolated you don't get a
notification that this has happened
which is which is problematic
two primary solutions to this are a
development solution and a
esf proprietary solution i'll go over
the event muting first so event event
musing is a function that was built into
esf
and what it does is it allows for
specification for events to be dropped
inside the current extension space
now what this means is that through a
process path or process token you can
specify particular event types to be
dropped on the kernel side and not
published into the event message queue
inside the kernel extension
because of this it means that you can
avoid overloading
however it's quite a blunt tool back
when i was experimenting with it because
you either had to specify an entire
process path again assuming it hasn't
been hijacked by anything or you had to
do it by process token which only works
for that instance of the process it was
either too much of a sledgehammer or it
was too um unspecific it wasn't targeted
enough so for
a um
viable solution event muting just wasn't
specific enough for effective filtering
multi-client system however did turn out
to be very effective so whereas you
would have a
endpoint security client within a
process subscribe to event types instead
of having one client subscribe to
multiple event types you could have
multiple clients subscribe to individual
event types which equally generated
their own queue within the kernel space
and by using this method you don't get
overload and you get all the data you
require and you can conglomerate them
into one
data set and then run it through your
detection stack by crop referencing
which was very effective
one point to note is that um the
original development was on sdk 10.15
for catalina this was when esf was
introduced but between 10.15 and 10.15.4
the sdk was suddenly updated one with a
number of new event types they increased
something called the sec num or sequence
number in the es message so whereas i
was saying before there's no
notification from the kernel that silent
drops have occurred that is still the
case but by using the sequence number
you can see whether there's a gap in
those sequence numbers to see whether a
message has been dropped due to
overloading so it doesn't alert you per
se but it does allow you to filter that
data and detect when it's happening and
from that do diet things like dynamic
rebalancing in order to prevent overload
system verbosity um if you look on the
image on the right you'll see that the
original uid is zero
this is the system user id on the on the
system on the operating system
and because it works at the kernel level
it ingests all the processing and all
the file information for the system as
well including system daemons and system
level
propriety management systems
and this creates a problem because we've
talked about the bottlenecking issue
before the simple amount of data that's
being processed by the esf when you take
into account the system events is
extremely high
and because of this you end up with a
sort of overhead issue where you have to
either filter out these system level
events or you have to
allow them but then do additional
filtering for anomalous indications
so one of the things again is that you
could do it either before or after
collection so before collection as we
said would be by event muting but as
i've said before this is quite a blunt
tool and to use this for this sort of
activity it means you'll be dropping
the only way to do this would be to drop
all processes running at the system
level which can
introduce ignorance of system level
compromise which could be very dangerous
so instead you have to look at
client-side filtering but then you look
at the bottleneck issue that i mentioned
before and even when you start to filter
down the event types into individual
clients you still run the risk of data
events being dropped simply because the
system level processing event generation
is just so high so it's a becomes a
balancing act between the two um there's
no real
one-size-fits-all solution for this so
you have to sort of balance this
dynamically as well as possible
parent process id issue so this is an
ongoing issue in the mac operating
system
primarily this
relates back to
identifying where the original process
was spawned from so this actually goes
back to things like xpc proxy launch d
and more recently something called
running board
so you may see at the top there's a real
ppid of -1 this is actually by using a
ppid solution um
but as you can see because it was
running on a newer open system the
result has actually come out as -1 which
is
incorrect data just to demonstrate that
this is actually an ongoing issue that
there isn't really
a permanent solution for at the bottom
you can see that there is launch d being
launched um xbc proxy being launched
launched by launch d but that doesn't
necessarily indicate where an original
processor is called from the reason for
this is because of how cross-process
communications work in mac os it's not
really that easy to identify what
process was initiating another because
it jumps through these other programs so
when you start to go back to the process
chain that can be gapped
due to these underlying system processes
as i said there is no real future-proof
solution the real reason for this is
that apple keep changing the way that
this cross-process communication works
for process um spawning so any time a
solution is made for one operating
system version it can be made obsolete
by the next update which as you can
imagine is
fairly frustrating
the current solutions that i was looking
at at the time were true tree by john
bradley and launch xpc by patrick wall
launch xvc was actually the solution
that was implemented in
my esfang solution
but it doesn't take into account running
board at the time which means that as
was demonstrated by the -1 real ppid
it is not a fully fledged or conclusive
solution to this
as i said this is an ongoing problem
that there isn't a one-size-fits-all
solution for yet um and it it was beyond
my scope to to try and figure that one
out
so looking at the solution that i
developed on my psc poc which i code
named es fang
so first of all i need to shout out to
patrick wardle chris ross and omar ikram
they back in the early 2020 really set
the stage for how esf could work the
sort of telemetry acquisitions and
really basic
um fundamentals of how to ingest esf
data
and the my poc was based primarily off
of their work and then expanding on it
and introducing capabilities and
solutions that i mentioned before for
some of the issues that i encountered
my solution was actually developed early
in 2021 um and it was based off of 52
event types back in sdk
10.15.4
the
primary reason that i did this was that
the old solutions had a fixed definition
of what event types it would ingest and
as i said before
this meant that overloading could occur
because it was a fixed number of event
types which you couldn't necessarily um
deviate from which if it was causing
eventing you couldn't
change from the rigid structure
however the solution that i put in was a
dynamic solution so this allows you that
each boot you can specify which event
types you want to subscribe to so you
can have multiple espang instances
subscribe to different event types or
you can have them subscribed to
multi-event types or group types like
file
file creation data or file metadata
uipc data um cross-beneath cross
processed communication port data and
things like that
using this solution you can avoid the
overhead um the bottlenecking issue
i when i started this had never coded in
objective c before so doing um
multi-threaded processes to achieve this
as a standard solution was actually a
bit outside the scope but it is it
should be easy to do moving forward from
any objective-c programmers out there
one thing to note is that because this
was not done with an apple developer id
it is a poc code so sip has to be
disabled or system integrity protection
so esf cannot be accessed with sip
enabled unless the program that you're
using has been signed by an apple
developer id
so if you want to use this for testing
purposes you have to disable sip
on your system so this isn't viable for
production level systems
the other thing is that it was designed
for json output for upstream integration
so
all the output is put into json format
so it can be easily piped up into a
database for further detection
processing and easy acquisition by um
elastic or threatening teams to those
data sets
so let's go over the merterpretty use
case
use case
was done on macos
11.2.2
i used esvang to collect all the data
and this is for the agent only so this
isn't to do with the metasploit
frameworks capability that can be piped
through the interpreter agent it is only
for the native material agent capability
this is only done on the post exploit
phase so i'm not interested in how the
agent got onto the system only what the
age you can do once it is on a system
and this was done only against a single
host so not against an enterprise
interconnected um sort of demonstration
so it's not necessarily representative
of a real life attack but it's to
demonstrate what esf telemetry is
capable of
so the overall findings again the graph
on the right is very small it's
it's a representation of all the um
commands that were executed and the data
that was generated as you can see from
the top solution is actually uh webcam
streaming which is not opsec obviously
and as you can see it generates a
massive amount of data but as you move
further down you can see that some of
the data some of the commands generated
seemingly none of very little event
types but i will go through some of
these to demonstrate some of the data
values that can be found
so during the install you can see that
open
read directory and protect were the
highest event types that were generated
through esf for temperature installation
now memory protect and um memory mapping
for new processes you expect this to
occur and remember protect being that
high is actually not bad anomalous even
though it's quite a high number but if
you turn this against what a normal
process would do on the mac estate it
actually doesn't stand out as that
anomalous especially when you look into
the internal data
the open event however is slightly more
anomalous alongside the fc ntl or file
control events the reason for this is
that during during deployment the amount
of file that it accesses in order to
enumerate number of system um
enumerate the system information and
equally to change certain file access
controls can be indicative of a
temperature deployment so actually
looking at these two specific event
types does allow you to process a
profile interpreter installation on a
mac operating system
so breaking down that slide a little bit
further in total 259 data points are
generated during an interpreter
installation
but 259 data points doesn't necessarily
mean that they're great data points
quantity is not always an indicator of
quality
but if you have enough data points with
enough cross referencing you can
generate more accurate processes
profiles and higher fidelity as long as
you know what you're looking for and esf
during my experimentation showed that it
had both quantity and it had quality
event types so by filtering the two
together you actually get a very
accurate representation of when
anomalous behavior has occurred
but let's look at some of the other
event types that are generated and
against what sort of commands
so on this slide again so this is to do
with file open events so on the far
right you can see webcam stream of 478
and it's not operation secure so that
stands out like a sort of thumb
process listing is slightly different so
for each process that's running it opens
an individual file for each process to
see whether it is whether it is running
um when you look at that event type
individually you can actually filter out
that it's scanning each individual
processes file which is quite easy to
profile
if you already know what processes are
running on the system you can just scan
for
is asus is a process scanning for all
the running processing files and detect
against that
the screen share and system information
follows the uh same sort of um
process so in order to enumerate and
gather information about how it's going
to screen share it has to open up a
number of system files and system
information it does the same way as it
does for process listing instead of
using general system information
commands from the bash terminal and
instead accesses a number of system um
files on the on the operating system in
order to enumerate that information
notify right this is a really
interesting one so edit file when it
targets an individual file to edit it
writes the information the file and you
get one writer then
upload is slightly different so when you
upload using meterpreter instead as it's
transferring the data from your
attack machine to the compromised
machine each packet is appended to the
file
routinely as it's received which
generates this nump this huge number of
write events to an individual file but
the write a size is quite small and it
actually corresponds to the size of
network packets being received from the
interpreter agent
so from this you can actually target one
processor targeting one other file and
write it then and doing it in very small
increments
um repeatedly especially if you filter
out things like internet browsers and
things like that you very quickly can
isolate when this is occurring
io open is another interesting one so
this is to do with driver or hardware
access
and again you'd expect to see webcam
stream 220 because it's hijacking the
webcam streams um data feed
but screen share again because it's
hijacking the user interface uh display
feed it equally generates io event types
and again io kit is not something you
see commonly is quite a
low generated event so finding any io
kit events outside of system uid is
quite anonymous and makes it very easy
to identify when malicious behavior is
occurring
this is a list of some of the valued
event types done against other that i've
isolated from other investigations
against things like
max shell swift sliver
merlin and other attack frameworks one
of the interesting ones uh one of the
primary interesting ones is on the right
there for pty grant
uh the reason for this is that p3 guard
is for pseudo-terminal generation so for
a dynamic user session instead of piping
the command through a bash terminal like
you normally would instead max shell
swift generates a pseudo terminal which
is a master slave comparison and
actually executes the commands that way
which is slightly weird and you don't
see that very often
so in summary
esf is extremely powerful and it's very
clear that apple is taking the time to
really look over the problems that are
occurring
during its use and equally to refine the
event types that are available
during s d progression from sdk 10.15 to
sdk 10.15.4
the number of event types increased but
equally so did the
capabilities of detection when the
system wasn't necessarily doing what it
was meant to
because of this um it's actually quite
especially quite reassuring knowing that
apple have made this not really optional
due to the deprecation of kernel
extensions from third parties
and the fact that they're actually
maintaining this
shows that they realize that they've
taken that control away from the
security industry but are actually
taking steps to provide all the
information and the stability that is
required
as we said some of the teething issues
to begin with have been addressed but
there are still more that exist and
during more and more experimentation
they will rear their heads as we go
forward
as i said earlier um compared to prior
solutions especially developing your
internal extensions or using open bsn
which is very clunky esf is very
streamlined it's very easy to integrate
into your existing stack
and because of this it makes integration
and development on it very easy from a
security development standpoint
looking at the use cases and some of the
other experimentations that i've done in
the past it does mean the detection
capabilities that are available are very
high and it means that moving forward we
were able to create better detection
profiles based off the esf telemetry
that is available in equally expanding
event types that they're they're
allowing
the the final point to know is that
as as i've mentioned the number of event
points that are generated especially
because the system level and even
because of the low level temperatures
available is very very high and because
you don't have control over the current
extension itself filtering is absolutely
essential and it becomes
not optional and it's one of those
things that we're just going to have to
deal with moving forward in when
developing using the system
that's my email that is the github with
the esf rang source code if anyone has
any questions please feel free to email
me afterwards
we do have some time for q a so if
anyone has your questions please
so if anybody has questions please come
in frontier to the first mike
just come to the mic yeah yeah yeah
thanks
okay uh
so uh thank you for the talk uh i was
wondering from a perspective from a blue
team uh what kind of events i'm kind of
i'm um i can find when i'm look at the
telemetry because uh i'm more familiar
with the windows events and sometimes we
can find like credentials passwords
what's not good so we have to remove
them do you know if there is something
in place that remove this pi data or do
i have to do it with myself
so yeah that's great question so you'd
have to do this all manually the events
that are generated by the current
extension themselves are raw so when you
get them from the esf client side they
can't be tampered with from the current
extension side so it will have to be
filtered on the client slide itself um
and there's no way of doing this further
up the chain
okay so if i decide to ingest this in
some like uh splunk so i have to take
care of this yes
okay
okay cool thank you very much no problem
yep
uh you mentioned that there's the user
space component that is registering for
for the filters or for events sorry yeah
uh two questions basically is there also
an unregister element that i can for
example call if i'm doing a red teaming
assessment and i got a gain access to
this user space component can i then
call or unregister event that i
basically disable monitoring for that uh
so because the event monitoring has to
be done together and it's done by an
individual endpoint security client
object inside the process there isn't a
way to unregister them from an internal
process unless you hijack it yourself
and then basically destroy the object
and recreate it you can't do it from
external because it's an internal uh
code object all right then the other
question is also solved
are there any other questions
yep we have time for another question
nope
okay
thank you very much thanks for listening