uh welcome
uh yeah my talk is today about uh why
mime is broken and okay the screen is a
little bit off let's see
so uh about me i'm uh yeah i'm the
security
engineer security researcher fellow i'm
working uh 20 years plus at genoa gmbr
uh
munich
my focus of the work is not on breaking
things but on protecting what's already
broken
and i did a lot of firewall development
focusing on the application layer
i
did eight years of collaboration with
academia and research projects
focusing on
defending against taxvier meal and rap
and
i'm currently involved more in product
and research strategies
it's a company
exactly 30 years old now
with
360 plus employees in various locations
inside germany
uh we are a subsidiary of the bundesliga
gambija
and we build security solutions for it
and ot and our focus is on sectors with
higher security requirements so public
sector critical infrastructure
structures
regulated industry
e-health etc and yeah of course if you
want to help you're welcome
uh the motivation of my research like i
said uh i did a lot of um
firewall development uh uh at the
application layer so i had to
implement uh application protocols and
uh the best way or the preferred way to
implement application protocols is to
actually look at the standards
not many do this actually when
implementing these protocols
uh yeah but when looking at the
standards
and trying to find out how to implement
these
the problem is that these standards are
typically
very flexible and very complex and they
are unnecessarily unnecessary flexible
and complex they leave way too much room
for creative interpretation so there are
lots of edge cases with with no clearly
defined behavior
there's no defined behavior of protocol
errors there's a lot of short instead of
must be implemented and they are partly
conflicting with previous standards
of course all of this conflicts kind of
the security
uh the result are that we have different
implementations which
interpret
uh especially edge cases in different
ways and this can of course be used by
attackers
so if the analysis system like a
firewall interprets the content
differently then the end user system
like in our case a mail user agent
then we can pass attacks through the
firewall
so the focus of my
research in this case
is um
it's mine
uh mime is kind of a standard for a rich
meal so what we have today structured
male binary attachments non-ascii
characters
uh and what i explore here is how to use
different interpretations of mime to
bypass security systems so these are
analysis in male filters firewalls
intrusion action systems antivirus
versus the interpretation
by mail user agents or web front ends um
i'm looking into bypassing mirror
detection by content
using the icar test viewers and uh
bypassing detection or attachment
filtering by file name so if we can
uh make
the firewall believe that we have a
different file name
it's not a dot x is not a dot zip then
the firewall will pass through the mail
there's similar research for http one
there's all this ports figure stuff
about http dsync attacks which are
targeting the server side
a little a lot of research on the http
site too but for targeting clients so
sending malicious responses or
unexpected responses by the server and
by passing firewalls this way
this result here
uh was primarily done in 2015 to 2018
during a research project
but i freshly updated it to make sure
that all the attacks still work and they
do
so
yeah to
explore this topic
um i created a lot of different mails
with
different test cases so
uh
nearly a few hundred meals for
continental asus or
nearly 200 meals for bypassing extension
blocking
um these males uh if exported as a files
or mail directory
and also as a packet capture file to
check against intrusion action systems
and then i checked against several
systems like various male user agents
various antivirus and male fetal
products
some intuition injection symptoms in
firewall i won't mention here because
it's not a free one
and some libraries
okay
a short introduction into what mime
actually is
in the beginning there was about uh
before 1994 five
there was only esky there were only esky
males these had a line
uh length limit of thousand
thousand bytes and there was no kind of
structure no attachment or similar
insight
in 1996
we got these
mime rfc
which defined different aspects of how
to serialize
structured information and non-sk
information into the original limits
so
yeah binary data
structures data like attachments and of
course like i said this is a standard
which is flexible which is complex
underspecified and has lots of room for
creative interpretation
a year later there were some additional
standards
one is the callback outcome disposition
how to specify a file name is how to
specify if the attachment is inline or
external
and
there is uh another standard for
encoding of non-ski characters into
uh structured data like file names or so
um for some reason they
didn't include this in the original one
so they needed yet another one which
implemented a totally different encoding
for
some reason
okay
uh if you look at the source code of a
mail we see the different standards
applied here
so uh we have the subject which is an
unstructured header field
and there we see rfc 2047 so this one
which is about encoding characters in
the header what we have here is with q
is
a code printable encoding which means
that uh the characters the non-ascii
characters are encoded in some kind of
hex value so this equals c drive
a c 3 means
that it's a character
hex c
3 and then we can look in the
utf art utf-8 encoding what the second
actually means okay uh then we have this
kind of mime preamble here which is
hidden in modern male clients so
basically all male clients we have today
it's only for the old male clients
so this is everything before the first
part
because we have here a multi-part mail
which is defined in rfc 2046
and we have a boundary here defined to
split the mail into different parts with
the final boundary here
uh
yeah then we have uh for some parts we
have a name so we can have a name given
in this way we can have name given in
this way
this is actually
rc2231 which has this kind of encoding
for long file names which we can split
over multiple parameters because like i
said the
limit for line lengths in male is a
thousand characters
and which has these kind of hex encoding
here which looks similar to what we have
in quoted principle but again it's
totally different because we have a here
we have an equal sign here we percent
percent centered so and yeah
for some reason they needed to make
everything
differently and then we have coded
printable encoding here for the content
and base 64 encoding here uh for the
content of the attachment
okay
uh i show some selected examples of how
this uh
can be used uh to
create
edge cases
which are theoretically allowed
or
especially not as they are not
especially forbidden by the standard but
where the
interpretation is ambitious
so
for example in this case you can define
two content transfer encodings this is
similar like attacks in http where we
have two content length sellers with
different values
and because we have two values here it's
not clear how this part so this is
base64 how this gets interpreted and
depending on the mail client we use it
gets integrated in a different way and
depends on the analysis software we use
or the library some manage to see this
and some uh don't see this so sorry
carter ids doesn't see the attachments
right attachment in this case
oops
slight variation
of this
we have one
field only but we have multiple values
inside uh again some male clients
understand this and just take the base64
because it's the first one
no male client actually uh
unders
takes it detects the last one but
outlook and apple mail
don't understand this at all and just
assume there's no encoding done
you can play similar games with the
content uh
the multi-part
male so we have boundaries here and we
can have two boundary definitions and uh
the correct one would be a bar here so
this is the first one and here's this is
as the last one and again depending on
the meal client and depending on the
analysis software uh we have different
results
same thing again one field multiple
values
and here again it switches
first uh what was on this side and apple
mill was on this side he has a node
switch and
it's the same with the various software
so we see here see a majesty new which
behaves the same as pearl mime tools
because it's used inside
yeah and then a different
area
the area of encodings there's a b64
encoding uh base64 basically means that
we have three bytes binary data
mapped to four byte ascii data so it's
already it's taken the first six bit
then the next six bit and so on until we
have uh have
20 24 bit
3 bytes binary and maps these to 32
bits
which
uh are playing s key
and if you have less than three bytes
and we have a padding so in this case we
have four bytes here which means we have
two bytes padding because we have to
fill in
the last two bytes you get six bytes and
here in this case we have two bytes this
means you have one byte padding and this
padding is done with the equal sign here
and
the standard
or the rc
is not clear
uh in this case uh
if
what we have should be encoded in one
piece so that we have only a single
padding at most a single padding at the
end or if you can actually have multiple
pieces it suggests that must may be done
this way but there is no short or even
better a must
and that's why we have different
implementations so we have some about
apple mail which just accepts that it's
okay to do so
uh we have mode this just takes the
first part
and you have outlook which i don't know
it takes the first part and then there's
garbage and i don't
actually know where this garbage comes
from
[Applause]
yeah and if you have a look at the
analysis software or the libraries we
see that most of these
plainly fail to see what major mail
clients actually can do
ah but we have more encodings we have a
quota with printable which is in the
standard tool but we have uh
other encodings which are not in the
standard but which are actually uh
supported by some real clients
there is this why inc encoding and this
is an encoding which comes from the area
of houston news
i don't know if somebody still remembers
it's
some 15 20 years ago
this time was it
yes very efficient encoding and more
efficient than base64 and that's why it
was used on usenet to transfer transfer
binary data
and because thunderbird
can still function as a news reader it
implements these encoding
but nobody else does and no analysis
software is able to see this
other is very interesting encoding is uu
encode this predates mime this predates
why inc
too
uh it was used in former times
in plain text mirrors to include some
binary data so we had some kind of file
name here inside this uh part and then
we had this encoding and then there was
an end and this encoding is very similar
to base 64. only it's mapped slightly
different but the idea is the same uh
yeah and this is actually a widely
supported encoding uh so we have major
mill clients which can do it
and uh we actually have major antivirus
products which can do it too but
uh there are lots of variations so we
can have different uh transfer encoding
times vm sometimes we need to begin and
then sometimes you can skip it etc etc
and uh they all work slightly different
so there's lots of room
for
passing
bypassing analysis software
and then we have another strange feature
of mail which is comments in mail header
as in mail fields
so the standard actually says that uh
one can place combat this is this part
with a parenthesis around it uh in
several places freely inserted and
outlook uh takes this to the next level
it's basically nearly everywhere this
stuff can be inserted and it simply gets
ignored so outlook sees in this case
this
i
bar as a boundary
all other um implementations don't see
this bar and yeah clement can see it and
there's this
firewall which can see us and there is a
uh python library but everybody else
cannot see this
okay this is about content filtering and
then we have the specification of file
lamps
two two small examples
like i said we have this rfc
20231 which defined a new encoding for
file names and which defined how these
can be split into multiple parameters
so there is an index for the parameter
and uh yeah i can split it over
multiple solutions the order actually
does not matter which is
explicitly
specified as a standard
and
yeah um like one see i can see
thunderbird apple mill not all supports
this
kind of outlook has no idea what the
standard is at all
and the funny thing if i use
microsoft exchange
it even transforms
this encoding this write encoding into a
wrong encoding because outlook doesn't
support it
but
i have this in other standards this rfc
2047 which was
defined for
encoding of characters into unstructured
mail fields and it specifically says
that
this encoding stuff should not be quoted
and should not be used inside of content
type of content disposition but funny
thing is
most supports this
and
yeah many analysis software supports us
too but there are several variations of
the topic so if i use uh some
uh strange encodings like otf16 it gets
weird and uh i have
again ways to bypass firewalls or
analysis systems
okay so how to apply this knowledge in
the practice
uh small thing i
create a mail
and i check this mirror with
virustotal so
this mail
has
inside here
base64 encoding
a zip file and the zip file contains the
icar test bureaus
and like we can see there are so the
ground truth 38 uh
products in uh
a virus total
can actually parse this male and can uh
detect the virus inside so
nice
let's see
if we make a small change we add another
transfer encoding here and we can see
the
number goes slightly down if you switch
the order it's not much different and if
we
specify a content transfer encoding
which is
something which doesn't exist like the
x66
then yeah it goes down but there's still
a lot of
scanners which will simply have
heuristic and uh see this is base64
encoding and will uh try to analyze it
okay
small step
uh
we don't use a single chunk for a base64
but we was actually multiple chunks for
two bytes so we get an uh padding one
character betting after after each chunk
and now the number goes way down
and even if we take
back all this stuff
before here is it still very low
and last step
uh we just uh
add
multiple boundaries here with different
implementation and now
we have
no antivirus product uh
supports us anymore if we look at the
meal in thunderbird we can still
normally just extract it have a look at
it
and if we uh
remove uh this uh quantum transfer
confusion here it's still only one
antivirus product which will seize us
okay
slightly different
area are
dkim signatures i don't know who is
familiar with
dkim and demark
the basic idea is that we want to
protect us
against the spoofing of the sender
and the visible sender inside the mirror
is inside the mail from header
and j-mark basically says
that this from header
must the domain of the from header must
be aligned with either
senate permitted frameworks for spf or
daycam signatures and taken signature is
actually only a
it's a cryptographic signature over
parts of the header and over
the body and
we can check this and it's independent
uh from the transport of the mail so we
can redistribute the mail and this uh
dickham signature does not change at all
which is very nice
but
the ecom standard
relies on
mime
being not broken
and
the dqm standard itself is
insufficient too
so there
are
no requirements which header fields like
content type like
subject also need to be protected there
are some recommendations but these
recommendations are insufficient
there
is a way in the standard to protect
header fields to make sure that no
critical header fields can be added
but there's no requirement to do so
which means that
typically implementations like an openg
chem or so
or
basically in any products we see outside
are broken
they don't uh properly protect the
headers
additionally
dkm allows us to sign only parts of
samir the idea is that
some
software could add some food and the
signature should be the same
and they say this is a seriously
security problem but nevertheless they
allow it
okay so what can we can we do
this is a mail i got um about
oh six years ago
and uh
from uh
deutsche post which
uh is a classic sender a typical seller
for spoofing
and uh we have to say dickens signature
here and the deconstruction it says that
uh not the full body is signed but yeah
only up to a specific part like here at
the end
uh the mail also uh the consequence also
says that we have some fields signed
here
but
these are only included once that means
the existing field is including but
i can freely add
additional fields these are not included
in the signature
so what i can do is here i can add
another
date i can add another two header i can
add another content type and i can
freely uh
put stuff at the end which means with
this change content type
i have a different boundary which means
all this part up to this boundary is
seen only as a mine preamble is not
visible in the middle client today but
instead this part after that is shown
and
if i deliver this mail
i can see that this part is shown and i
can see that decam is still okay and
says the properties of mail show that
the date is changed the message id
is i didn't know if i changed it in
previous example but i can see for uh
that daycam and denmark both pass
so final words
uh are there any solutions to this
problem
yeah
maybe the problems are hard to fix there
are zillions of mime implementations and
scripts in the wild is often broken
there is no money pulley on
implementations which can could be used
to enforce a
minimal quality
we have such monopoly browsers
one can try to block
such edge cases but this can cause uh
unbearable correlatory effects we have
i've seen this in the practice
there's simply too much junk in the real
world and
in
dubbed operation beats security it
worked before we installed instead the
firewall
there's a way to sanitize the wheels but
uh this can break stuff tools or it will
break taken signatures pgp and s mime
signatures i've seen this too
and
ultimately one can simply lock the
problems
and then hopes that somebody cares
actually about the locks
thank you
[Applause]
so do we have any questions for stefan
and his very optimistic outlook on mime
so steph and i have one question and you
kind of addressed it in your last slide
if i am an administrator of an email
service what what can i do is there
anything that i should
do today to protect against
attacks like this
i think there's no good answer to this
because
actually we we've built in our product
all the other protections against these
attacks i have shown and we had to
make a lot of these protections
optional because there are a lot of junk
meals outside which are not spam meals
which are real males but which are
actually invalid
okay there's another question
i'm loud um hi um have you have you
taken a look at
sometimes when you forward an email with
attachments uh then in different kinds
of email clients or webmail clients they
get unfolded
even though
it's an attachment heavy have you been
looking into this kind of scenario
because i
used to fix
a bug in a webmail client where there's
an attachment and
a forward with an attachment and they
were unfolded and this kind of helps
sometimes
mitigating also or some bypass some
firewall rules
yeah forwarding meals is it
a strange thing they are there there are
two options to follow the meals the
inline-four wedding at the forwarding is
attachment
and uh supporting this attachment is
supposed to just uh put in the origin
email but one can actually modify it and
then there are different problems on top
of this because if the original mail was
transferred over a path which is
eight byte clean
and uh then i forward the smear and the
the next pass is not eight byte clean
which is a traditional path with smtp
then
i might need to rewrite everything
so it can
it could be used to kind of sanitize but
uh it will then also it might also break
it might break the signatures this might
break pgp and as my signatures
you mentioned that you generate a lot of
test cases
are you aware of any publicly available
weaponized frameworks to exploit these
issues so that i can target specific
setups and generate a mail that will
bypass these checks now i'm not aware of
any other research in this area in this
steps but if you want to start searching
come to me and i give you test cases and
the frame vector generates these
awesome thanks
all right um i'm that should be the last
question we've reached 15 o'clock please
give stephen a hand is broken