production
uh this uh talk is uh put together by
some of my amazing colleagues listed
here
and i'm just sort of distributing the
knowledge
so a bit about myself i've been working
in uh security since 2011
held various roles at various companies
and i've been in the uh blockchain smart
contract auditing scene since uh 2018
and it's been a hell of a ride
um who i work for uh i work for quan
stamp which is the company the logo
there in the middle
uh we're one of the leaders in
smart contract and blockchain security
we've secured
more than 200 billion in
assets and smart contracts we have
a lot of clients
a lot of revenue
and most importantly we're hiring so
stick around until my last slide that
one
has a very interesting piece of
information on it
so why is this talk relevant
there's been a bunch of bridge hacks
over the past
year
so just in 2022 alone there's been more
than uh one billion worth of crypto
assets stolen
from such systems
here are at least just a few of them the
ones with the ones which are like most
important
and we're going go go through
more details
as to why these kind of things happen
and why this kind of thing is so hard to
get right from a security perspective
so here's a bridge
it's pretty simple like you'd say like
why why the heck is this thing so hard
to get right
you have an actor
on the left side you have
a smart contract system like ethereum
that it interacts with
and it basically wants to send assets to
a different chain
and on the other end
this actor or someone else might want to
receive those assets
denominated in something else on the
other chain
now this is like the essence of it
the
going into a bit more detail you see
like when someone deposits like this
actor on the left deposits maybe some
ether
it interacts with a smart contract
called the custodian
and there's a communicator in the middle
which is an off-chain component
it could be a traditional whatever
server application
that is watching
what is happening on the chain
once it sees that someone has deposited
funds in this contract it initiates
a debt issuance call
to the debt issuer contract on a
different chain and this depth issuer
here on the right hand side
it means some
tokens which should be the equivalent of
the ether
that the first actor put in right
so again pretty simple
the opposite path so starting from right
to left the actor wants to redeem back
the ether deposited after having used it
for some purpose
so it
burns these tokens that it got called ac
eth
it sends them to this debt issuer
contract the communicator is also
watching the debt issuer
and when it sees that someone has burned
these tokens it initiates the fund
release on the custodian side so the
actor should receive the corresponding
amount of eth on the ethereum side so
this is depositing and withdrawing
now
you notice from the previous slides the
bridge structure contains like three
main components
two contracts
which are the asset custodian the data
source
and the depth issuer oracle contract
here
and a communicator which is an offline
off chain component
which we call the oracle
and there's
therefore a huge attack surface
when it comes to like
the
web free space so you have
the custodian
the depth issuer the communicator any
interfaces that they use and the network
itself they could all be subject to
attacks and in the next slides we're
going to go through examples of attacks
for each of these layers
and bear in mind that some of these
attacks i won't name names because it's
not
professional but some of them are
referring to the hacks that happen
in the in the past the ones that are on
the
one of the previous slides
so for the custodian
we have something which is called the
call relay attack
and here depending on the bridge you
might have this asset custody smart
contract
which is accessible by some privileged
addresses because they need to manage
them somehow and maybe maximize
the the profit of the project or
something so
what the attacker goal in this case was
was to take over
this asset custody contract and be able
to
take funds out of it so the way in which
they want they did that was that there
was this function that was
in the ascity asset custody smart
contract called
change custody address there at the
arrow at the bottom
and this function
should not be callable from the outside
so there should be some access control
in place that prevents anyone from
calling it
but
what the
attack or like what any user would have
would be allowed to do
was that they were allowed to call
functions of this form right there was a
function name
three parameters
two byte strings and one unsigned
integer on 64 bit
so this was something that
was deemed allowable from the access
control policy because
there were just
one or two functions which were fine to
be called by anyone
now
the nasty part
is
that the attacker
found a way
found a hash collision
on some random name that they put
together using this signature here so
they just randomly compiled
a function name and some parameter
values
which had a hash collision
with this function name
the way in which this contract in the
middle here works this cross chain
communication contract
it whenever it says call this function
it basically hashes the signature and
looks it up in a hash table
and due to this hash collision
it was the attacker was able to
figure out okay
if i have this function well it's just a
random name there but x x one two three
and some parameter values is going to
have a hash collision and i'm gonna be
able to call this
um
function which i'm not supposed to call
and change the owner of the asset
custody to my own address and then i can
just take the funds out
so yeah that's that's one of the attacks
moving on to another attack transaction
replay
it's again on the custodian and um
depending on again the custodian the the
bridge that is implementing
you need to present proofs
when withdrawing assets so this kind of
markle proofs
they get issued so let's let's go step
by step the first step is that you
deposit an asset to the custodian
and in the second step the debt issuer
sends you the debt token we've seen that
on the uh
original slide with depositing then
withdrawing you do burning the debt
token to the debt issuer and in this
case the debt issuer gives you a proof
that you can then go and send to the
custodian and say here's the proof give
me my money give me my tokens
the
the mistake in this case was that the
verification of the proof
uh didn't take into account one of the
fields
so the attacker was able to change one
of the fields
and resend the proof again and again
it was a valid proof but it was
different from the previous ones so for
each replay the attacker got the same
amount
until it drained the custodian
going on to the depth issuer so in case
of the depth issuer the attacker goal
would be to bypass the signature
verification right
and
arbitrarily mint
these tokens right
so
the attacker what what they did in this
case it was again a very specific
implementation of a bridge which
received as an input parameter
over here not sure you see my mouse yeah
it received
the signature verification contract
address right so this was an input
parameter
but it should have been pretty fixed but
this is the way in which the system
worked
they were just receiving this as an
input parameter and of course this
signature verification contract was
unique
it was a trusted component what the
attacker did they deployed a fake
verification contract
and they passed that
as an input parameter so this fake
verification contract said it's always
good whatever you do
you pass the signature verification
and this way the attacker was able to
basically initiate these kind of
withdrawals
without or like this disminting without
deposits without actually um
depositing any money in the custodian
moving on to the communicator layer
there
the attacker has the goal of tricking
the communicator into forwarding invalid
messages and minting tokens
so
for this particular attack
the communicator
was watching the custodian
and was watching if someone deposits
funds in the custodian there's an event
which is emitted
i'm going to check
how much i should emit i'm going to
check the address of the custodian is
correct
unfortunately
for multiple withdrawals or like yeah
for multiple it was looking only at the
first event for the address of the
contract which emitted it
what an attacker did was they deployed a
malicious contract which emits the same
events it look the events look the same
except for the fact that it's emitted by
a different address
the problem with the communicator it was
only checking the address of the first
event
and then only looking for the other
events that came afterwards so the
attacker basically issued a bunch of
fake events from these from this
malicious contract and was able to
uh drain yeah basically get a bunch of
funds that they were not entitled to
moving on to the interface level
here
there's a bunch of attacks which we're
going to look on the first
is
you have this situation where
a legitimate user here at the bottom has
approved
a contract
to
allow them to to basically
um execute some some kind of
function call
for a particular token and this is quite
broad
so what an attacker did there was that
they
just crafted out of this execute call
data generic function they just crafted
okay transfer from user to me right so
they were able just to
easily craft
this function call inside of the call
data
which led to of the legitimate users
tokens being transferred to the attacker
so the attacker could do this for
multiple users who have approved
um
their wallet
uh this this interface spending money
from or funds from their wallet
in
a similar attack
where again the user has approved a
third-party
contract for
allowing people to deposit
with permission basically here
you're allowing someone to
spend money in your name
it should only be meant for tokens which
implement this feature but there are
tokens which do not implement this
feature and do not give any
warning
as to the fact that this function called
failed
so if someone calls this function
deposit with permit
into this contract it's just not going
to say anything
it's not going to return anything and
the error
was in this
third-party contract where they did not
check the return value so they didn't
check
that the return value is explicitly
successful they just assumed that if it
doesn't complain then it's successful
right so missing uh return value
validation
and this way the attacker was just able
to say like hey i'm going to deposit all
of these
funds from the legitimate user into my
account and that's how they got away
with all the funds from legitimate users
who approved
finally the network layer
this is something that hasn't yet
happened but
might happen in the future
there is this thing called the 51 attack
which allows you to reorganize blocks
and
what you can do is launch such an attack
on a level one chain
then you deposit assets to that
custodian contract and you receive the
debt token
afterwards you take that debt token
and withdraw those funds
out of an exchange or something you
withdraw them transform them into
fiat or dollars or whatever
and finally you cancel that deposit
transaction in step two because you now
can reorganize the chain right
and depending on how long
these steps this withdrawal process
takes
you could afford to pay for such an
attack because one hour of such a 51
attack on the ethereum main net is
somewhere between 1.5 and 2 million
if there are sufficient funds an
attacker might be incentivized to
actually pay this
for a certain amount of hours depending
on how fast the bridge enables someone
to transfer funds to deposit and
withdraw
so in summary there's a lot of
bad things that could happen with
bridges
we saw things on the custodian layer
we saw things on the depth issuer layer
i'm not going to go into all of these
but basically
you might have recognized that these are
not totally different from your
classical security mistakes like missing
input validation
not checking return values and so on
right
the communicator layer is this off-chain
component which is basically watching
and triggering smart contracts on both
sides
and there's a many things that could go
wrong we only went into one or two
things in this presentation but there's
a longer list and probably it's not
exhaustive
there's the interface
where
basically it's not necessarily bridge
specific but
there's a lot of things that could go
wrong with allowing people to
deposit in someone else's name
or allowing external contract calls and
then finally the network layer there's
the 51 attack but there could be other
problems as well
finally just want to say we're hiring we
offer great packages and if you're
interested in this kind of stuff finding
bugs and smart contracts we'd be happy
to to
get in touch with you
thanks so much
[Applause]
so do we have any questions for
sebastian that we have a runner coming
forward
so it looks like a lot of stuff you
mentioned is like you said input
validation stuff like that that could be
remediated with
like good programming practices um is my
assumption correct that if you do all
these correct then the problem is the
custodian and you there's no way to do
that one trustless because it is off
chain
so
can we ever get rid of and not the
communicator because that is option is
there ever way to make that component
trustless as well or will that always be
a linchpin in the entire setup how and
there's no way to secure it even if all
the rest is perfect
yeah that's a very good question thanks
so
this architecture which we've mainly
looked at during this talk
is something which is being used
generally right now there are projects
out there which are taking a totally
different approach they don't use this
architecture they use something else
where they don't have this kind of
trusted off-chain component
and
well those kind of things are not yet in
production but they are working towards
a solution
which does not does not have this kind
of um trusted
third party which is off chain all right
if you want we could i can give you more
more details uh in the break and another
question if i may um sure for example in
in terms of web applications we have
stuff like ports rig academy do you have
equivalents for like if you want to
learn about smart contract blockchain is
there any like playgrounds that are easy
to get into for someone that is not
familiar yet totally yeah there are
multiple actually there's things like um
well i'll call them offline ctfs because
they are always going on right you just
have like a playground where there are
some contracts that you can just
exploit toy contracts
and there's like multiple
um difficulty challenges right and
there's
like things like you know damn
vulnerable linux sure yeah there's
something like that for smart contracts
or google damn vulnerable ethereum or
yeah then damn vulnerable defy it's
called yeah yeah so um
there's there's all these kind of things
and also there are training programs
free of charge
because
there's so much interest in um getting
more security experts in this field that
people are no longer charging for
training
everything is sponsored by all these
projects which have suffered such hacks
and and like the amount that they need
to sponsor these academies is nothing
compared to the amount that they could
lose
so everything is like sort of free of
charge so you can pick it up really
easily
okay thanks
thank you
please come up with your question
hello uh for someone that is completely
new to this type of hacking i have a
question
how much of hacking smart contracts and
and blockchain and cryptos
is about
actually cryptography and how much is
about more of these type of logic
books
that's a good question um
i think
probably more than 95 percent is about
this okay
and probably like five percent is about
the crypto because
um
the actual cryptography which is being
used
that is being actively researched by
um
many research groups at top universities
and and many of the world's
leading cryptographers
so the actual
hash functions
encryption
um
proofs and so on everything
is based on many many years of research
from
universities
and now we're just like working at
implementing applications on top of that
okay so we can say something like
if you'll invest more time there
learning about solidity you are uh doing
a very better investment that by
learning i don't know cryptology
something like that
um
depends right um if you're a brilliant
cryptographer and you might invent
something amazing i'm not
then it might be worth doing that but i
think like if
you don't want to do that then
definitely learning something like the
solidity or other programming languages
being used for smart contracts is a very
good
return on investment okay thank you
thank you
any other questions
uh yeah so i have a bit of a
controversial question so your company
is like doing these audits for the
contracts
so you're making money by doing the
audits and stuff but like i've read this
idea that
it's something like a bit like a reverse
but bounty scheme
because in the end there is an incentive
for you
to keep like some kind of bug in the
contract
and then in a blackhead form exploited
so you know what i mean yeah i do i do
totally and so it gets philosophical in
everything but like you're part of the
industry
and
what is your
thinking about this how this could
improve
in a way where it's better for everyone
like your auditors can do your job
others can do their job and everybody
can trust the thing in the end yeah no
that's a very good question thanks so
i think it's always this kind of
trust issue when you're working with a
security service provider
it's not specific to the space it could
be like when you're pen testing a web
application right for any company right
you might withhold some kind of
attack that you can then
use to exploit of course like maybe in
web 2 the damage you do is not directly
financial but it's reputation damage or
so on
but basically the idea is that
what we're doing
if we were doing that if we were would
be withholding
and exploiting
there would be a huge reputation damage
to the company itself and it would cease
to exist
right
we
are well in relative terms a young
company like we've been around for five
years
and we have a reputation
for being one of the best
so if you have a like the longer your
time span is and just keep in mind the
oldest auditing companies in this space
are like five six years old so there's
no
uh there's no others which are like have
been
around for longer doing this specific
thing there's been there's companies who
have pivoted from doing traditional
security to smart contract audits and
they have been around for longer they
have a longer track record but
definitely this kind of track record and
knowing that the company has been around
for longer
helps with this kind of trust issue
because if
let's say you somehow manage to
um trick someone
in trusting you
and you do this kind of thing you you
withhold an export you exploit it
probably in a few months to a year your
company is no longer going to be trusted
by anyone because
your audits always get hacked you know
what i mean
so that's what i think the way to
balance this
okay any other questions
okay i have
a curiosity question
so suppose i wanted to exchange a large
sum of money and i knew it was going to
be a cross blockchain kind of exchange
um should i just avoid that altogether
or what can i do as a consumer of this
entire process
definitely get advice
from professionals
and don't just do it
um
sort of on your own because there are
way more problems sort of attacks
economic attacks that someone could
use
to
do an arbitrage on something that you're
doing right so if you're exchanging one
token for another
you have a lot of parameters which might
be like the margin that you're
willing to lose in the exchange and if
you don't properly set that margin
you might end up
being arbitraged by
there's an army of bots out there just
looking for these kind of opportunities
so definitely ask someone
for these kind of settings right and
then like this is in addition to all the
security issues that might be there
right
so
i'm not saying there are definitely ways
to do that i've done well i don't i
didn't transfer large sums of money but
i've done that myself
with no
let's say issues afterwards right so
it's possible but you really need to to
uh be careful because like we've just
presented let's say i don't know six
seven hacks
but keep in mind there are like dozens
and dozens of bridges and some of them
have never been hacked yeah
exchanges exchanges on their set
themselves are bridges as well they're
just a different type of bridge they're
not from
chain to chain they're from
bank account to chain
super
any other questions then
all right thank you so much sebastian
thank you