so hi everyone welcome to this panel
discussion on collateral freedom using
local train to change centers incentives
so before before i get started sucks
that's the boy I'm honest I really
better ignored my mind because I'm
struggling but before I get started
substance any of these the amazing panel
that we had and I than I just wanted to
speak to kind of netbook for a minute so
you'll notice that there are four people
up at six chairs I am mad at Matt but
that's not the reason why there are
scared there are as chairs so the people
in the audience can come on up here in
front of conversation fishbowl style and
I guess the way that that works the way
that works is that anyone who wants to
come sit we're going to do just a brief
initial congregation to each of the
folks that are seeing up here and then
as soon as we're done with that people
who come on and hop in and the protocol
is that for these sort of two I guess
they're called hot scenes and then they
call them on seats in a fishbowl which
seats in Congress but you could tap
someone
lawyers not speaking who's in one of
these pairs have switched places with
them I know people will pop up and join
the conversation I should also tell you
that I'm very aware and quite chagrined
that despite having taken a pledge
personally to be more aware of gender
balance on panels of tech conferences I
am ended up organizing a panel but is
all men and I am I can only say that I'm
that I'm following burden that it's a
both learning experience about the
planning process also a reflection on
how many amazing people who are here I
don't yet have sort of on my radar I'm
so glad to be feeding me and with that I
I will just start so my name is Dave the
problems and I am part of a small team
of technologists in Washington there are
three of us and we work on a variety of
issues where computer science expertise
is needed by leaders in nonprofits and
in government so we're called Robinson
you following the washington convention
of extremely creative major
organizations my partner's Harlem you so
may may may know and we had the very
great privilege and pleasure to work
with the open Internet tools project on
work that surveyed users of censorship
sore convention tools in china mainland
china and collateral freedom was the
name of that would work reflecting our
poor finding and will come back
add substance but let me just introduce
these amazing votes so at gym Callie to
my immediate left is the CTO of Renesys
which has met many of you will recognize
that beams name of the firm from some of
the most informative blog posts that you
probably have a read of Internet freedom
that are not only a reticence is no blog
awesome their graphics end up all over
the place because they really do occupy
a unique niche in terms of traffic the
transnational flow data amongst
autonomous systems on the internet and
we're all very fortunate to have their
help in leuven a day behind what can
also be their theoretical and roberto
conversations a bunch of salient facts i
feel very lucky to have gin with us
today and he'll talk a little bit about
some of the inferences that they have
been able to draw from sometimes they
have observed to jim's left his ox who
is one of the who's who of course ox is
a pseudonym and a literary reference
which he may illuminate for us odds is
on the development team for lantern
which is a relatively recent addition to
the arsenal of purpose-built censorship
circumvented software tools and finally
to his left steve schultz is a program
officer for in that freedom at the
Bureau of democracy human rights and
labor at the State Department which
means that he is intimately involved in
the grant-making activities at statehood
support the development of
freedom tools and so having just just
interviews let me just do a little bit
of stage setting and then let let these
folks way in soon we when we were doing
this reporter on collateral what became
collateral freedom at the end of 2012 we
basically used a snowball method a small
sampling method to survey about a
thousand mainland Chinese users of
censorship their convention tools and
I'll tell you my expected we would
discover what I expected they were going
to tell us is that the most heavily
encrypted tools that were purpose-built
to empower people to circumvent barriers
like the Great Firewall would be the
most widely used but what we found and
the report is online and I would
encourage you to look to it what we have
them something close to the office to
actually tour and what we have very
limited time with each person because we
of course you know we don't behave we
didn't want to be tracking who exactly
they were because it's in population and
we didn't want to be but remember risk
and so we figured that whatever we have
better take less than five minutes for
people in complete so what we ended up
with was a list of tools going down and
then columns going sideways for I use
this tool within the last 30 days I'm
used in more than 30 days ago or I have
never used this tool and what we found
was that most of the things that I
thought would be most widely used in
fact had lots of former users so tour
had lots and lots of forum where users
but only a handful of current users of
my mare Wisconsin again stovall sample
hidden population are not statistically
representative no one knows what the
sampling frame is so take it with a
grain of salt all that said we didn't
have diversity across a number of
dimensions including geography and the
seed sources from which the respondents
were referred and the all the findings
that I'm going to describe them that are
describing the report were consistent
amongst the sea cruise so that is some
non statistically robust data which is
consistent with the possibility that
this is representative but we again are
not really in a position to know but the
thing about it was that when we looked
at what people were currently using I
have the most users in the within the
last 30 days time frame the the single
most widely used tools something called
go agent which is a proxy server that
runs on top of Google's App Engine
infrastructure and is actually designed
so bad if you are a user and you want
then censorship barriers you basically
pretend to be a software developer and
upload this prefab machine image to to
go where course as a developer you get a
free sample of their amazing
infrastructure and run a server for a
little while before they start to charge
you so this is a system designed so that
you go ahead and upload that server and
what you have is a proxy server in
Google's cloud now everyone thinks how
is google so it's blocked in China right
and the answer it turns out is that it's
complicated and some of the things that
especially businesses rely on are not
consistently liked in China and in fact
continue to be reachable and the baddest
because of the and this gets into
details of how Google's encryption is
implemented but the bottom line is that
if you can reach any part of Google's
infrastructure the Essex your web
connection then you can use that
connection to reach any other part of
Google's infrastructure and going to
takes advantage of this we know that if
the Chinese government wish to block all
data flowing to or from google but it's
technologically trivial for them to do
that they know which IP addresses they
would need to drop the packets and you
are from and similarly after gotov the
runners-up in terms of most used tools
for VPN and again
actually seen a demonstration that the
Great Firewall can block the entropy
half of protocol level meaning then
without knowing in advance which servers
are VPNs they can look and see who's
making a VPN connection unblock them all
and they did it for a period of hours or
days some months ago and you know they
don't do that eager even though it's
clear that they know how and there again
what you're seeing is something that we
observe well you know VPNs are relying
on my business you are integral to the
foreign direct investment that comes
into China and for that reason the
opportunity cost of disrupting them is
quite high and that's where certain we
felt that we really learn something
through this through this survey
research which is that apparently
economic disruptiveness or economic
importance how much disruption would be
caused by blocking this tool is a better
predictor of its efficacy at least in
China specifically as a circumvention
tool then the degree of technological
stealth an apprentice to the party
because these most these most effective
tools were not the stealthiest and we've
seen some exciting further discussion of
this positive of this idea what it might
mean for future work in Internet freedom
and I think without I'll turn it over to
Jim to offer some thoughts from there
from the further Ennis's perspective all
right so very good this it's an
interesting topic this idea
benefit that is in a sense what it means
if I understand the concept is that by
people doing what they're going to do
anyway in other words be self-interested
in selfish and a funny that censorship
goes away as economics it uses people to
act in ways that promote and open
Internet all it requires all things
scare quotes is that it open Internet be
pinched to the right people as the
economically sensible self interesting
thing to do so let me back up and say a
few words making about how Renesys
approach some of this problem with data
if you don't know Renesys real well
basically what we do is we study the
routing of the internet just letting the
performance of the area from very
argument where the places around the
world we have either hosted as machines
or these days being installed as virtual
servers attempting to figure out
basically the complete map every day
everybody who's connected to everybody
on the internet at a provider level and
also to understand the pieces of the
address space that they are bringing to
the internet so sort of what does
everybody rain to the party if you think
of the internet
Global party so every day we drank all
the providers in the world who is the
most important to everyone mrs. man in
the world so we did a study and we had
an interesting hypothesis which was that
there was a chronicle frontier diversity
that would be important in understanding
how vulnerable place was disconnected in
a flash like the Egyptians shut down or
the entire country of Syria going off
all at once right companies aren't
supposed to leave the internet all at
once we're supposed to kind of trick
allow regional damages so they kind of
cable but we put me it was very simple
we took every autonomous system on the
end of that and we try to assign them to
a country if they could be so somebody
like Google is not be like level three
is not let something like Turk Telekom
kids that's a Turkish chaos as we
classify all these into their country of
origin and we said pick any country how
many of those providers in that country
actually have the demonstrated ability
to do business with somebody outside the
country like direct and in the routing
table that's something you can just look
up and find it you say well here's Turk
Telekom I see them in the routing table
talking to TIA talking to
whoever was safe good there in the 10
people in Turkey speak to the outside
world in contractual relations we said
licious counties simple counting right
I've my daughter great statistics
background and we try to see whether
there were obvious cut points and they
found out that basically what we do is
we propose a system by which if you have
one or two providers that talk to you
outside oh that's it that's really such
a severe risk that would be places like
Yemen or Syria with North Korea there's
just this one being in town it's one
provider typically and if they decide to
turn off the internet internet senator
know it goes up from there cup like
rather arbitrarily of 1040 if you can
make it past 40 that you're a country
like Canada that has so many providers
that have individual relationships with
foreign providers that we hypothesized
such a country is less like
risk we would do that over the course of
the next year and if you are blog you'll
see some of the results that we came up
with their it does seem to bear out that
the come the countries that have left
the internet by and large are the ones
that have a very rare degree of frontier
diversity so that's something concrete
you could take back to the community in
every country and say what's going on
here if you look at it in the right way
is that there are specific companies in
your country that are rency they had
struck some deal with the government
they have some monopoly right there the
only licensee for the international
gateway and well that may work for the
government and it may work for that
company it's not the best thing for
everybody else because it makes the
entire country more susceptible to
accidental shutdown nothing else also
makes for susceptible to cyber attack it
also makes it worse the central
government shutdown the point here is to
talk to a business community to find
them all people who are not that guide
to frontier and say thanks content
providers you guys have internet that's
terrible and it's largely because you
can't directly talk to the outside room
if that case could be made to enough
smaller providers
country so that they could petition for
redress and say you want to buy
international services from level 3 I
don't want to buy a telecom Egypt to
them resulting a circuit from level 3
it's a market then the hypothesis is
that more and more countries would be
dragged up this hill towards increasing
diversity and then hopefully regardless
of what specifically happens day to day
in terms of policy regulation you would
have that reservoir of diversity so that
in case something were to go terribly
wrong you would have enough on that kind
to the outside world to survive that to
be resilient and to continue operating
thing exists continued training london
exchanges when your internet connection
is is fragile event feels over to your
backup provider I'm going to stop there
because I think that's the basic the
basic concept play that falls into I
walk category so the lantern project is
a bit of good censorship simulation tool
what cloud with a hypothesis has been
very simple to the work
you know what when we look at the world
we can service also determine different
kind of censorship so we were comforted
charm for example the sensor in country
through their relationships without eyes
peas content providers and that's not
the plan to understand what we're
looking at is what happens when tans and
national politics place them inside of a
sense it comes from two months to get
access to content outside of the country
on government consuming and uh and in
order for that to happen basically all
the different solution welcome to more
lists and we need something outside of
the sensor country that carbon dioxide
server and we need some way for
something inside of it since I country
to learn about the existence of that
proxy server and you need afternoon to
get that person software that they can
use in order to communicate that Maxie
server oh that's not always the case and
what's that President starts using my
proxy server you need to be able to
communicate with in such a way that the
sensors can't figure out what's going on
and something like that proxy server so
on a daily basis our life is already
concerned with Keenan these proxy
servers are large and failures to get
them to people that the sense it can't
just like a block so to all these lot of
dreams is very important so specifically
whether you are software
pressing the links ingredient which
works because he tends to be able watch
because the country blocks email
categorically doesn't have a lot of
criminal damage once they have any
quailed studio software if I Amazon's
pacers which works for similar reasons
to what David's early explaining about
google's app engine or sled slightly but
the basic point is that the only way
that they can prevent us from the studio
software in iskcon would be to shut up
shut down all honesty which would
imagine what businesses once our users
have that software they communicate
about proxy server using protocols that
look more or less like the protocols
that people use when they were stood in
the way so very rare essentially happens
when site which again works because the
sensors are going to categorically block
what an epic because that would have
severe consequences so certainly a tall
mountains what I believe is extinct
boring but the reason that works is
because of some structural features of
networking and specifically because our
to count them both that they want a
sense of us that they don't want to
censor it is actually outside so someone
we look at involvements that happen
china and one of the things that we want
to make sure it doesn't happen is as a
vulcanized engine because the water that
content services community into the
sensitive countries the lord of data
comes from blocking leads so that if the
amount of traffic that stands in a
national boundaries besting small then
you can shut down so so that that's what
i would be feeding boys italy impacts a
lot of this initiative is a lot of head
so looking ways that we can take and
especially a vertical of things that
might be used for quote unquote
legitimate uses so aluminum so as David
mentioned i'm steve schultz i work at
the State Department I work within the
global programming and in government
programming needs grant-making we have a
lot of have a lot of code words and so I
have a couple of remarks in my current
role but I also wanted to take a step
back because before joining the
government i was in academic and i'll
throw out a few ideas that are maybe
Chum for more conversation and maybe we
can get some folks up on stage to
discuss them as well from where I sit we
are very excited about this notion
by the collateral freedom paper I think
being actively experimented upon by
projects like lantern by other projects
like I'm sure some of you are familiar
with the folks at great fire and freeway
ball that are experimenting with
different techniques seeing how
repressive regimes respond and said I
think it's I think it's a powerful
approach to anti-censorship tying that
policy consideration back to the
economics back to the fundamental
benefits the fiscal benefits to regimes
in two individuals finding ways to make
those interests align and I think it's
also important in this world I'll start
to drift a little bit into the higher
level I've empower pontificating but I
think that it's important to note to
note that the the economics of the
internet are at once familiar and new I
think that the economics of the internet
so we economist have this notion of
network effects that is an idea that's
been around for a long time around
different products the idea is the more
people that come on to a particular
platform more value the platform has as
a whole so the more people that by fax
machine is the more valuable
buying a fax machine is because you can
talk to other people you can send faxes
to other people and you see this a lot
in information technology of various
sorts but in other economies as well the
internet adds another layer or layers to
that quite literally in that we have the
infrastructure layer we have the content
layer and we have other neurological
layers in between and innovations are
happening at all of those different
layers and those are adding to the value
the economic value and the social
political value of the network and in
many cases I think when repressive
regimes seek to shut down activities on
the internet when they seek to censor
they are trying to avoid they're trying
to stop the activity that they don't
like without stopping the additional
benefits some of which are often
unexpected benefits you know spin-off
ideas that would never could have
happened if we didn't have the this poor
infrastructure of the internet and so
the question is are there ways that we
can structure the way that the internet
works our policies around the internet
that make that kind of thinking and
choosing more difficult and you know
historically one of the policy
considerations we've got and I'm not
primarily a policy guy although I'm
happy to talk policy both
one of primary policy considerations
we've had when it comes to the Internet
around the world is access universal
service as we call it in the United
States and we heard this morning about
how of course still more than half of
the world is not connected to the
internet access to the Internet is
critical but it's also critical giving
back to the point about the
balkanization that that access is a true
access to the full internet so it's not
just universal it's I don't know it's
unitary access maybe that's not the
right word something something along
those lines but that access to the
Internet means access to the internet
and in many cases I think that the
repressive regimes that are trying to
shut down access to information access
to different tools for communication are
trying to break that unitary notion of
without breaking breaking the notion of
individuals have access to some network
so I think going forward the question is
if a clot on freedom approach is going
to be productive and really effective
how do we make those that would seek to
pick and choose the ways in which the
internet is used and usable feel the
full force of that collateral damage the
collateral damage of the network effects
the cloud of them and of the unexpected
uses that they're not immediately
experience I don't have a perfect answer
to that question but I think it's a
matter of realigning again
send it with with those specific
decisions so that so that you the doing
good and doing well in this case and
aligning with each other and sometimes
we can make technical decisions and
sometimes their policy decisions how
much of one of my favorite RFC's of all
time is our I've seen 3271 wind surfs
the internet is for everybody which I
would have come in to everyone which is
a really a policy statement in the
technical clothing but I'll be that I
kind of threw a bunch of ideas out there
and I wish we could compare dance on her
favorite are seeds I'm not prepared to
people caught up you like to try the
conversation and the meantime I'll just
say that as Steve mentioned the work of
great fire on work and I would like just
to make sure that we're all aware of the
view before that they are doing so in
specific what they did when Reuters I
big Bloomberg but several Western media
outlets were blocked in China what they
decided to do was to mirror the blocked
content at at amazon URL so you have to
imagine that this is https secure 80 us
amazon.com something right and with the
beauty of this is that although a sensor
can tell that encrypted
traffic is going to this amazon web
address the sensor can tell which David
it is and so the sort of difficult
choice as steve was indicating is
whether to block the whole thing or not
another example of this was a list of
engineers involved in the creation of
the great firewall which was censored
but then was weird on to get up and
there was a brief period where the rain
firewall blocked connectivity to get but
as you might imagine this caused an
uproar among Chinese software developers
and only lasted about a week and now at
least as up last time I heard about this
github is readily accessible and driving
including the secure page on github that
has this list of these engineers some
people are saying there should be denied
entry to the United States and so on and
so I I think that it is exciting to see
people do lieutenant I should save a
great fire they think they said look
this is why we're doing this that we
think this is going to work in a
different way so you know I see it as a
strategy that is being added to you know
the strategic arseling I think also that
one place that it's taking us is toward
more attention to cloud providers to
play a central role in all of this and I
think then for people in the room are
elsewhere it neither are working for
working with these organizations there
in addition to have an enormous impact
through just the basic engineering
decisions that they make in a way but at
least for me having worked on the survey
was a definite
/ spended but and so I'm just sure just
stop talking until somebody stands out
is that the right way that yes yes I I
not never better could I do that I'll
just talk to paralyze all ready yet yeah
that's a good sorry I'm sniffling a
little bit here while I'm talk but just
that just to elaborate on the Amazon Web
Services great fire of that war case
because i think is interesting in a
certain points to some questions about
their that's going to go so as as you
said great fire org and helped a couple
of news organizations in a number of
other organizations mirror there's
they're blocked sites audience web
services based on this principle that
you know too many chinese companies are
using amazon web services for the
chinese government to block the whole
thing and therefore you know this is a
good tactic Wow now we have an
announcement that came out of here last
year amazon is moving this business into
china right which is then going to place
the company under Chinese jurisdiction
and so on and that's that's where sort
of the Amazon collateral freedom kind of
principle starts to for from st. github
collateral freedom principle because
github doesn't have a commercial
first in China right it's not kind of
salivating about all is this it can do
in China and all the prophets it can be
by doing business with Chinese companies
amazon you know sees a big attacked you
know market in China wants to do a lot
more business or a lot more Chinese
companies but in order to do that
there's there's a worry you know amongst
those who have been using Amazon Web
Services not just great fire the others
if you know to host content that they
want to keep on blog abul that the
Chinese government made say okay you
want to come into China you now need to
respond to our West to take down certain
accounts or you know to to cancel
certain accounts or whatever you know
oriented or information about certain
users or you know etcetera etc and it's
when a company starts having a big
business interest in a country even if
they're not hosting the content in that
jurisdiction they start having to make
compromises and you've seen this with
quite a number of other companies and so
there is a question of whether great
fires amazon web hosting strategy is
going to work you know as amazon guest
further along and you know amazon it's
not remember the global network
initiative
it hasn't been willing to kind of have
dialogue or sir to make public
commitments around do they have a
process for handling government requests
do they have plans new transparency
reporting do they have plans to have
dialogue with the human rights community
about how there can handle data how
they're going to handle takedowns you
know how they're going to handle these
issues in a responsible manner they are
not among the companies who are having
that conversation you're not going to
see the pier having that conversation I
don't think far as I haven't seen it
again this and you know so so that's a
real problem that as some kind of
seemingly unblockable companies start to
get full you know how off now last now
we've seen Google actually make some
commitments which is why you know people
are still using those services but it's
tricky and so I'd be interested to hear
some of the panelists comment on this um
Canadian sighs thank you this one you
know the lot of men con web services in
China is so very early stage it's by
invitation only you know for making the
announcement
they have a feeling that I'm feeling
kind of fading out what exactly is I
don't know if you need to talk at this
point but a couple of business in detail
would show you welcome to interpret
nezam which one amazon would not
currently owning or loving
infrastructure in China actually
partying of peas to handle affordably
which has potential implications for a
relationship relationship and the other
text in bit is that they are segments at
this component that serves completely
from the desk of a nationally of us
often so you you have us you signed up
your account with that can you manage
authors and services services that
you're plotting with areas all the world
that simon doesn't work for china is
subsiding what exactly that means at
especially interesting might recover bad
badtz you're saying remaining enemy
label so any company
san jose could you identify how many
were confident systems I used to be with
yahoo arranged over TLPs international
law enforcement so I including
disclosure of contention and you know it
gives her run around in China you have
to provide insurance law that's the
presidential you know an urn you would
be able would you imagine it being to do
this is here in the United States and US
government shut up and said the
consistent with you as long as and I'm
sorry about to do it he thought you just
that he would have sat in china now has
online services you know they have her
name with a local guy me just like
everybody else does write a song when
they will live microsoft a 65 china
partner 21 by annette has a requirement
you can launch it was deserves in china
unless you have a little joint venture
that's fifty percent or less only five
a u.s. national I guess the question I
hope you like is and it's just as a
practical matter one wallet on China has
been very economically effective for
China and you look around the world in
companies that have a world of the
Internet in the way of China has haven't
developed competitors to the us-based
market in the way that China has you
know sina sohu i do you know it's
extraordinary market and by protecting
that market and all the players in that
market that comply with local regulation
and the US government of a teacher named
of WTO and not compelling them to allow
cross-border traffic consistent with WTO
obligations um his just exacerbated is
something on the economic benefit of the
wall off while behind on over the WTM so
I'm curious to see when you hear from
any of you I mean I'm not seeing
anything and suggests that the great
firewalls and he would react
for China and we see all kinds of other
countries looking to follow China's Li
like Brazil like India great nation
Russia all looking to this model of
being able to control the track
manageress diction is speech in their
jurisdiction and the additional economic
benefits are blocking out the
competition I would yeah I would so I
think that's an excellent it's a great
point about the trade barriers issue
this is something that you str you know
has made a request for consultations
with the Chinese about their WBO WTO
obligations for cremated information
services as far as I'm aware it didn't
go anywhere because what WTO victories
allow you to do is impose retaliatory
tariffs of a bottom line is that the
United States is not interested in
getting into reciprocal retaliating
carrots basically the Chinese even if
because of their derogation of WTO
obligations we may be legally entitled
to do so under the WPO treaty framework
but i think and i mean the balkanization
concern i think i would without in any
way apologizing for smiling upon being
those sort of ladder and the newer
balkanization efforts that we're seeing
out of places like brazil i would
distinguish those from what we see in
china in a couple of respects that
strength is getting likely to matter I
mean one is that as far as I'm aware the
Brazil well I guess yeah you can ask the
question so if they say you know users
have to put you nokia Brasilia users you
have to store their data
and facebook says well that's not our
practice then what right it's Brazil
going to block is actually Brazil going
to block facebook as far as I have heard
and I don't know maybe others I don't
even I don't know following it yeah
so so sodium city is this something
where they're saying you know people in
Brazil are saying look if you don't put
your servers here we're going to block
Brazilians access to you so the dialogue
is still ongoing about what the remedies
would be you don't put your servers in
their zone the challenger leaves in a
Brazil situation is that companies like
Facebook or Kobe or like Microsoft who
actually have staff on the ground there
they don't realize that people that can
go to jail the people who are in a clear
are the folks like to get cups of the
world who don't actually have step on
the ground and result necessarily answer
you can plow Brazilian law I have
anybody on the ground the date right so
I be naturally with the puppy lives I
mean at the end of the day for bill
decide that it's going to say no you
know you need post comment on brown
where you can't do business here the
folks that actually are going to have to
comply but for have staff on the ground
country and try and operate from
offshore and imports energy I'm curious
oh we've got a joke can I piggyback on
that and then this is it too sorry I I
don't have a meeting with the hands and
1212 minutes thank you oh thanks I'm
sorry my job so we're going until
quarter we're going after that down huh
what after the development we've got a
healthy okay great I was just curious
from the from the Renesys perspective
looking at frontier if a China
looks significantly different from a
Brazil look significantly different from
some of the other places where we've
seen these types of proposals or
proposals in this family Florida right
so when one thing I've heard a lot of
today just sitting various sessions is
this concept of a elephant or the
unicorn right the outlier in the series
who is so large that while they donate
conversation the physics don't apply the
same way as everybody else so Google
Facebook these are the whales content
china is definitely the outlier the fact
that they've achieved critical mass and
they managed to keep the frontier
we closed and yet we look at it we
classify China has the lowest risk
category for disconnection and hardly
that's just the numbers I'm supposed to
play straight with my model which says
there are a lot of a ton of systems in
China actually there's a reasonable
number of them that mostly because of
Hong Kong have what looks for all
intensive purposes to be direct
connection to the outside world although
most intermediary internet or China is
dominated by the big carriers it's it's
a little unusual in that we actually
have we have to resort to other means of
detecting what potentially pyramids and
economic problems and fragilities may be
lurking there in China and just had this
big example of it was a huge dns problem
in china shortly ago where there's a
great fire mobile ish and everything has
walked free for everyone and that's a
for us that was a footnote in our model
that said there is structural richness
China's economy working they're ready to
be diverse but at the same time there's
this is truly one of a kind system and
post from above largely in
let me just sort of pick up my men to I
think one of the real questions here is
outside of China what other countries
that are kept in two sets your are
susceptible to these dynamics in such a
fashion they could really think about
how closer coupling between freedom
traffic for lack of better term
commercially significant traffic as a
promising approach I would look to you
know potentially middle market countries
where competition for FDI is you know is
Keenan is a high priority lists like
Vietnam for example as potentially
promising places in terms of providing
you know and some of it is pretty basic
right i mean everyone has amazon but has
anyone taken you know stuff that's in
that the language of that kind of made
it available via this mechanism you know
that's that's I think a question that
could be asked you to have a number of
and i think you know i mean brazil's it
if it's a fascinating case because right
there they have this appetite for that's
when I think you know if the sort of sad
story of balkanization takes off you
know then we have a subsequent question
which is you know to what extent of
these other countries have the kind of
venture technical talent that China has
that allowed it to rebuild essentially
replicas of somebody on these services
and I mean perhaps Brazil does but I
mean there are probably a lot of
countries
don't and now daddy wants to say sir oh
I remember when you first so Danny Ryan
I work at the FF and I remember when we
were first talking about this one of the
attacks against the Google mediated
censorship system that we came up with
was China dropping off censorship
certain mention tools thoughts of
American school children so that that
would force the Google to actually fix
their system because schools would
complain the very sense the wells get be
around to but well seriously the
censorship a lot of what this bitching a
ride issue is really an issue of can the
sensors he loved the content from this
valuable content and this to pass this
one is clearly there is a economic
incentive for them to do that because it
lets them complete a policy that they're
pursuing and keep the good bits flowing
but the other thing I mean one of the
most worrying developments in pervasive
censorship that we see is actually not
about the expansion of censorship that
the narrow so that they know if you
bought YouTube a whole country it rises
up as one once there
videos about believe you can if you can
block at narrow URL you could block some
other image it's when the recent HTTPS
is so important then if you minimize the
effect to everything else then that it's
a better censorship system from that
point of view it seems to me that this
this approach falls into that subset of
something that they know they already
have to do which is to peel away the bad
content and left a actually calls a
limited amount of collateral damage for
the other materials that think of their
target yeah I I mean I think that's it's
it's crucial that we have a way to make
that argument I mean I think it's in
some way it's different it's a sort of a
slightly different class on on what the
challenge is is how can we make that
kind of narrowing you know harder to do
and that's why that's why it as you said
she gets so so important but I mean I
wondered whether there's other do you
guys have just purchased we're just
playing music oh my that's perfect just
one more time yes come so it was one of
them one of the interesting things that
we look at going to count
you were still flashing on Australia but
we're interested in pap that's a lot of
talking about today is your traditions
of client-server you know somebody must
be excited as the present with company
or happy and in that that also tends to
call amended the pattern of what you see
what companies like to use because that
so simple as infrastructure provides
nice control features one having tea
Tamia is interesting for kids in some
ways it's more difficult deal with if
there's collateral damage if you've got
always been someone would recommend
illegitimate that becomes more
challenging though for the sensors that
governor we have it now is that there
are a lot of business users for a pap
sort of collateral so it's something
that President really loved to seen
trades in spots about what potential
applications may be really nice to see
sort of explosion pvp music by business
because that actually increase the
viability of attachment
today we're hearing yeah yeah I'm just
going to quickly call up on that point
by saying that one thing that's
interesting about the peer-to-peer angle
I'm sorry I manifest from also from
Lantern is just that not only is it the
case that there are these companies that
have services that remain on block
because there's this collateral damage
but you also have BitTorrent that's
unblocked in all of these regions so
there's this collateral damage to
blocking even things that aren't
necessarily see initially as
economically important but in the case
of China may actually be particularly
economically valuable from the
perspective of the Chinese government
not having a vested interest in
protecting us copyright law for example
so you have this huge influx of value
into China by keeping BitTorrent
unblocked and would you circulate that
that has entered maybe into their
thinking on whether or not I don't know
i don't know but i think it's
interesting that that's the only other
example i can think of of a service that
stays unblocked and I'd have to guess
that it is due to the same collateral
freedom thesis that there is is cost to
blocking it that's real agent another
sort of baby else in like a week form of
the hypothesis also would just be that
these are folks who know how to filter
and block and impose constraints inside
their domestic
are going to be an arguably the world
leader among the countries in so doing
and and yet you don't see any effort at
all to block this this this peer-to-peer
infringement activity we asked a
question back damaged group some of the
work that we've done is involved Mikey
reputation right so the reputation of
particular blocks this is obviously in a
security context you want to know for
example time in a fresh allocation of my
piece pace at which to round of service
I want to know is that block that he you
know is that fresh and clean or has it
been really driven around at least two
cents family I would imagine that the
collateral damage concept could
unfortunately go the other way somebody
who has a very valuable high-value
service might say legitimately I don't
want any of you guys up next to my IP
address space flexing close by addresses
because of the potential that I'm going
to attract blockage because of the newer
do you ever do see that at being
concerned on behalf of the cloud
providers it makes logical sense I
wouldn't put you to know to bring back I
have a example that it's strangely
similar to this I noticed that linkedin
has just opened the China a Chinese
operation and I remember they were
earlier on they were making discussions
about whether to send servers in or how
they were going to
and one of their big problems earlier on
was that they're one of their biggest
features in the West was that you could
connect your Twitter account and the
problem was was the folks in China were
using LinkedIn as a way of getting a
mirror to Twitter that was blocked so
leeton was actually being blocked
because it was acting as a as a
underground railroad for 44 tweets and
and so the question that they were
asking is well should we shut this off
and of course you know our response is
no keep it up but the wider past is that
at that point linkedin as a complete
service was going to be was going to be
Bob to China I don't know how they
resolve that but I know that apply my
shiny thought they posted a blog post
last me this is what I was referring to
they say I think they're Chinese service
has limited features like it doesn't
offer all pictures I i think the restive
i think that was actually the solution
that they went to from that period which
is they were basically created a
sealed-off bulldogging within their
service so that are trying to people
coming in from the Chinese mainland
didn't have access to what the rest of
just a little reminder to the MP as
first question was there
yes if about not walking full countries
for putting our region's that's
interesting to Chinese some of the today
sort of
there to hold one community in countries
where the rocks are not
regions and arguments annotations so I
think I not sure if I caught both
questions back to this question
specificity yes we can track things down
to the city level we got a great example
the Venezuelan instance recently where
there were some routing outages very
brief they were affecting particular
province to province world problems were
and it turned out that they believe that
probably the government had taken off
one of their main facilities was inside
the address block that was unrounded and
so it was quickly put back up so it's
true you can you can't exercise fairly
specific control over which region we
want to affect which sit in one with
that have issues specific to use alpha
higher provided by a fighter obviously
and yeah you see that a lot the model of
the name was really about
country-by-country disconnection is sort
of the kill switch concept to death but
you're right it has become a much more
subtle game since Egypt as
point all right so I think we have time
for one more question if it's the last
one or not only thing everyone were for
being here and if people want to talk
more about this oh I'm sorry there sorry
baby last second buddy TI p value the
maze were denied service by Rackspace
when we try to get hosting with them but
no real reason given me maybe we were we
would be violating terms of service or
maybe they didn't want us hurting their
their other customers also I too I
wonder so sort of variation on that if
there's a danger of us tipping the
collateral value on in some cases for
example we use digital ocean languages
digital ocean they're pretty cheap we're
all pretty poor I bet some of the other
I bet some of the other organizations
like dice used it'll ocean I have no
idea what percentage of their total user
base client face we are but there might
come a point where just blocking digital
oceans IP space might become not a
collateral not sufficient collateral
damage
and then by way a final comment i do
want to refer back to Rebecca's comments
about how sustainable these current
experiments with flower of freedom are
and to what extent they align with
business incentives because I think a
lot of this will come down to not just
how do we proactively try to align
freedom and freedom traffic for lack of
a better term with the economic
incentives of nation states but with
very large companies that operate within
those jurisdictions and face issues with
people on the ground so likewise you
need to look at the alignment of
economic incentives there and I breathe
it we have a looming potential challenge
thanks to everyone and we're all still
interested in this stuff after the panel
so feel free to continue our
conversation folks thanks everybody