I think we ready to get started so
welcome to our topic which early stage
you weren't too small to think about
user rights and so your startup and
trying to figure out this stuff my name
is Nick Grossmann i work at union square
ventures this is Jenny tomasello works
at Cloud Fleur we're going to do more
reference in a second this is days and
every real estate expert in berk the sea
to have ever known first we wanted to
know who in the room who are you guys
who are from startups if companies ish
lawyers and what other categories that
were interested in happiness activists
nice that's really interesting more
lawyers and more activist than I was
expecting that's fascinating the lawyers
who you work for you work for startups
do you work for big companies any work
for another great friday locker just me
we can also mean Taylor got a little bit
i think we've been thinking that we'd be
speaking to people from startups about
startups but we can also talk about how
folks who are outside of companies work
with company
okay so first we'll just be quick
introduction my name's Nick I work at
you to purchase a venture capital firm
based in New York City investors in a
lot of social and collaborative
platforms like Twitter Tumblr
kickstarter etsy peer-to-peer networks
and I focus on public policy and
regulatory issues that affect our
companies and the broader internet to
work with all of our companies I work
with a lot of activists and academics
and folks working in DC in the different
countries on whole range of policy
issues and the reason that I'm here and
the reason that we care about this topic
is that we often get asked why do
investors have an interest in the in
user rights above other things that they
might have interested in a company and
virtual for instance province and the
answer for us is that you know as more
and more people become members in
internet communities in development
better and better understanding of the
rights and that they have and that's
where the relationship they have with
those platforms the more people start to
think about their relationship with
their data in their speech and how the
various platforms you interact would
mediate that we believe that it's going
to be more and more and more and more
and more important for any company on
the Internet to develop odd about
policies that are pro users and to
respect to user directly
and develop a positive trust
relationship so it's and that the
companies that do that will also create
a more sustainable business in the long
so that's our perspective nothing hi I'm
Jamie Thomas Allen I mean policy and
investigation at cloud flip it's a
strange title professional proper now in
its ok policy and investigation is an
interesting role at our organization
because it's one that requires many hats
so it encompasses your traditional trust
and safety or inbound abuse complaints
those types of issues law enforcement
liaison works subpoena compliance PCI
compliance privacy issues incident
response so I oversee all of those types
of those types of issues so anything
that could be related to trust and or
safety and the reason why I think this
is important is because it's not a
question of when you're going to have an
issue or
horseman is going to arrive it's a
matter of if and you need to be prepared
a lot of startups these days are
launching products that global very
quickly and people forget oh my goodness
this data in other countries that we're
collecting has different types of
regulation than it does in the United
States or oh wow we have a bunch of this
data that has value to a black market or
it has value in certain types of
criminal ways either it's got user data
that can we use the feature to things
and passwords are compromised that can
be used against other sides for you can
either that could be used to facilitate
other types of criminal behavior not
because you designed it that way but
because it just happens to facilitate
that type of user generated content or
that type of discussion and then it may
be of interest for law enforcement
either from a strictly for receiving
legal process or from either a wiretap
or a pen register traffic trace type
scenario so it's definitely about being
prepared for the animal and we won
everybody knows what cloud flurries
sorry about that a cloud player is a
website optimization company and we
provide security services to prevent and
distributed denial-of-service attacks so
essentially we provides Tehan services
and deduct
attention services in a tremendous
amount of internet traffic flows both
ways through class letter too that's
correct we are not hosting providers so
we sit in the in the middle in the
network a network service solution
provider we currently are seeing about
5% of the internet and measured through
my page views so it's a considerable
amount of internet traffic over it's one
rock sugar or too many websites that are
c2i Evernote I think of the token
engineer in the room so please be gentle
however know it is a service for helping
you remember anything you want I think
part of reason I'm here is that Evernote
is it's in the minority of Internet
companies right now that is a product
that is built with privacy first when we
were getting funding in 2007 it was next
to impossible to get any money for
anything that wasn't focused on like
another way to brag about your dog
the kids once you have dinner we were a
the antisocial Network building
something that was just for the ninety
percent of your life where you weren't
blogging about stuff I think from my
perspective not everyone needs to go
that route but it is only June option
and I think the most important thing
that we've learned is that being
transparent with your customers with
your users turned all following the same
thing about what you will be doing with
their data and what you will be doing
what their rights are is extremely
valuable we have tried to do that from
the very beginning and and the trust big
built up with our users of overtime has
a lot of time it doesn't have to be like
he doesn't have to be respected users
privacy being transparent and honest
about what you are doing with user data
it is not necessary
have to decrease the value of your
company you can become a successful
large company while still selling
transparency and user privacy has parted
wrong so I'm actually encouraged that
there are so many employers in the room
and activist also to the socket and Jake
earlier that's Jake about how man this
is such an exciting time to be someone
who specializing in Information Law I
mean I can I can't imagine a better
field at my place where they're more
interesting jobs to be found in one of
the observations that I have as we were
talking this morning is that no matter
what kind of company you are like clouds
there's a proxy that that loads of
internet traffic flow through or if
you're ever never sort of a private
place or people or if your social psych
like Twitter or if you're a marketplace
like Etsy or craft night side like
Twitter there are innumerable issues
around user rights and privacy and
censorship and shaping and speech that
are that run the gamut from being very
straightforward and even the ones that
are very straightforward talking
I'm very forward to being very complex
and so we were hoping to structure the
conversation today it's just by walking
through a bunch of the issues that tend
to be faced by internet startups as they
grow ranging and we wanted to start with
the sort of more straightforward issues
around security and dealing with mahaan
forcement and then move into some of the
more complicated issues about shaving
speech you know certain kinds of privacy
and so on and so this is a small room I
would encourage you guys to interrupt
and ask questions really um between you
know I'm just a guy who have to work
with a lot of guys who know things but
these guys actually no lemons so with
that where should we start well what do
you guys want and we have obviously we
have things we wanna talk about are
there any high issues that you guys want
to hear about since we're going to get
the opportunity to make this interactive
and make it conversational hi and please
if you to do so intercom to Jake Brewer
external affairs for change network so
our platform is kind of like inherently
built for users to challenge power which
is awesome also presents all kinds of
challenges one of the things that we've
had a lot of issues with is just court
order
user data sharing
and when we actually would comply then
when we actually fight it and then to
the point that fighting it too much with
me you know could mean essentially
killing our company it's not we think
that much money so we're kind of in that
weird stage of being big enough to sue
is like a fish start up on a very small
company and so this is a lot it's a very
risky area for us but it's happening
more and more so from that perspective
and dealing with quarters and if there's
that challenge right there's a certain
amount of how much do you have faith in
the legal process I mean from from our
perspective I mean some people at but I
mean that it's it comes up right whether
or not that the there is the technical
perspective of is this legal process the
function of this legal process correct
right did they give us a subpoena that
was dated properly that had you know
that it was signed appropriately the
that we are all over the technical
aspects was all credit of this issue
another record so on and so forth and
then there's the content aspect what are
they is what they are asking for
inappropriate is that something that
you're willing to fight of people fight
sort on the technicality or that it's
overly broad or
of that nature at clouds that we have
very clear policies on how we deal with
legal process if we receive any legal
process be a subpoena or what have you
we intend to give notice to our customer
before disclosure of content of the what
they're requesting unless ordered not to
do so by the court have you yeah right
so when the time so notify the or so in
them in that case functionally we don't
have it's one of those things we don't
have an issue with law enforcement right
it is not our role to either impede law
enforcement or overly assist law
enforcement they have they have a job
that we respect you know we appreciate
the assistance that they provide our
customers we understand what they do we
don't have an issue with the function of
law from the perspective of you know
quarters have due process that their
judicial review so all you know offer
that perspectives if we feel that
they're overstepping their bounds or
that it is an in based on the
information that we have in its
information or belief that this is a
fishing expedition or it's what they're
asking for is inappropriate and that's
something that we
considered fight we've made it very
clear that if we received requests
actually in our most recently published
transparency report at closet calm /
transparency we leave a little plug for
a fancy report but we've made some I
never statements right CloudFlare has
never released our ssl keys or our
customers ssl keys to law enforcement or
any third-party request and we have
never we've never even out you know user
credentials things like that and those
are the types of that we've made it
really clear one of the things that
we're going to fight we're going to
fight any sort of legal process that it
does not have judicial review or due
process involved you made that very
clear but besides that from a corner
perspective there's a certain amount
worry you can have unless it meets those
angers that you decide your own company
and you have you really consistent with
those policies you can't be like oh well
on this case we're not going to do but
this case we'll fight it you respond we
responded right we're okay so you talk
about attention with technical
I guess that's that's one of the things
that we've had felt like that if we get
a subpoena that's the language of what
they're asking for like I know I could
interpret it in the way that they may be
intended and satisfy it versus they talk
about use the language like email when
we aren't an email provider because they
have some boilerplate like what do you
do in that case we're like it's pretty
obvious like what they intended like is
it is it appropriate to they say be
jerks about it and just push back to
push back on top of that you know yes I
mean it technically is appropriate for
you do it it depends on your fear your
company's perspective right if you're
looking for a way to push back on the
whole process that you can push back on
technicalities ago don't you
specifically asked for an email account
we don't have email you know you respond
to sorry I should start this with this
disclaimer I'm not a lawyer I do not say
on TV I'm not your lawyer so obviously
you need to run this all buying your own
counsel but from our perspective you
know we've seen two different things
that come please do they either say
there's technicalities and so you don't
respond to certain pieces of information
because a lot of law enforcement are
educated on your technology around other
people's technology and so they will
send you that traditional isp telco
subpoena attachment right they asked for
like call records or you can choose to
educate law enforcement and try to build
a relationship of trust instead
appropriate boundaries and say look we
know that you guys have a job to do we
respect the government if you know we're
not contrary it is nothing
just for acquisition believe the
government has a purpose now trying to
make your government better by getting
out there and voting right people but
these pieces of process are appropriate
with due process and judicial review and
so from art from our perspective so when
we receive a subpoena or we receive a
court order was an inappropriate
attachment you know I said completely
pushing back and saying okay we're not
to respond at all we do use that as an
opportunity to educate those people in
law enforcement to say look what you
were asking for is not appropriate what
you need to do is narrow the scope of
your attachment what you need to do is
have an understanding the technology
what we do because we're not going to
give you what you've asked for what what
do you need to conduct your
investigation not what do you want one
of the things that we do is we provide
education to law enforcement to the FBI
on cloud service providers like this is
what the technology means do not issue a
warrant for this server in a shared
hosting environment right because this
is not going sure this may help you in
the sense that maybe that content that
you're looking for is there but you did
just be something out of service like
you don't do that what do you actually
need don't send me a subpoena requesting
abuse complaints and support tickets you
really need that content I highly doubt
you need that content I'm going to push
back on it I'm going to ask for warrant
for anything that any content related
requests but in general no we use it as
an opportunity to educate law
enforcement and it's actually paid off
really well as we've got better more
narrow scope process going forward
and we've actually heard from other
folks that said you know because you
guys were consistent with the
application of your policy and you
educated that side of the need for order
it didn't surprise me the next time when
I went to a different service provider
and they asked me for 2705 or and I mean
what I'm supposed to do so it helps so
you guys so kind of toddlers now any
employees serving the large amount of
internet traffic Evernote is logan's
you've been there since day one we've
been there since it was 35 employees
we've spent a lot of time with it in USB
port folio talking with small companies
about how how do you even get started on
this stuff and you never dealt with any
situations before how do you develop
sort of a philosophy towards these
things and you know how do you start to
get prepared how have you guys seen you
know your approach to that formed
especially during the early days so we
were building everyone in 2007 we knew
from the start certain things that we
want to do to make sure that we will
provide a baseline please or privacy a
lot of that is internal controls you
want to make sure that
people have access to user data you want
to have on everything they do they want
so I'll let that sort of on the
technical side but on the on the full of
software both side we also knew we had
to decide what like what our promises
were to our users and that's something
that like when you're just building the
neat stuff is hard to stop and think
about what what are the implicit and
explicit promises active users it took
us a while to actually write books down
we summarize them our CEO of hosted
officially on our blog in 2011 that we
have three logs kind of office to
Commonwealth Office things but a lot of
the one was your data is yours our
philosophy is we are we are custodians
of your information we do not own your
data therefore it's not ours to to sell
or resell or monetize we are you are
paying us to to alter data your data is
is protected we will make our best
effort to protect the integrity of that
the data is private by default only if
you go out of your way to explicitly
sure that someone has become public and
third law was your data is portable we
from the very beginning said that we
must make it possible for you to take
all of your content out of Evernote at a
moment's notice and take somewhere else
so with either of our desktop
applications there's a menu item to say
exported
the most portable form that i could
think of HTML documents interlinked with
all images and things like that so that
you could talk about your a
fifty-thousand-dollar governor
accountant leave tomorrow if you wanted
to that was important for us part of it
was important philosophically the
founders of our company had left the
Soviet Union during Soviet days and
their their attitude with any any
country that you'd want to live in as a
country that you could leave and that's
that was sort of deep in our psyche but
from a business perspective from from a
cold calculating capitalist perspective
that is very very important to give
confidence that it is safe to invest
their time and effort into into what we
are doing to to make people feel like
that we were going to pull the rug out
from them from under them at some before
you know realistically this being in
Silicon Valley like we weren't just
about of funding selling off furniture
this day we wanted to make sure that the
people felt like putting hours and weeks
and months of their life into our
product was was not a risk of their time
not a risk of their privacy they
completely
I think a lot of companies don't really
have a chance to sort of reflect on what
that relationship is with our users and
I don't think it's I don't think it's
one size fits all there are going to be
companies that that they they they tell
you that they will take all your phone
records and then send you it repeats at
every month that's not concurrently
immoral like if if that is a contract
that you want to get into it a company
like that's that's okay as long as
transparent as long as like you know
what you're getting into you're getting
free pizza and that's that's it that's
where I trade off to you I don't think
if that's that's wrong but on the other
hand that needs to be obvious that that
needs to be like explicit and that's
what they're selling a rational person
can evaluate the pros at automatic it's
interesting they bring that was we have
a lot more children in teenagers and
Millennials I guess also all my stuff
people are growing up in an age where
your identity has they think has very
low value they don't understand the cost
of treating their information about
themselves for a service for some free
service and you never there's no such
thing as a free lunch and everybody says
that but it's true you know if you're
providing your personal information
these are going to use it for some
thing and there are laws out there to
protect children under the age of 13 but
in general you know we've got a whole
bunch of people who are growing up in an
atmosphere of well here I'll just give
out my email address for this service or
here's some information about myself
what school I meant to or should go
ahead go ahead tagged all these pictures
my face or what have you and it's
unfortunate because I just don't think
they can appreciate the value of their
identity and the value of their privacy
right now and so we do have a certain
amount of responsibility as custodians
of data to not be big brother and say
okay well I'm going to tell you what you
shouldn't should not do with your data
but no sound be daddy I guess I get a
guess in that case but um but i think
that there's a certain amount of
responsibility that we are doing no harm
right we're doing no evil with a data
when we say that we're custodian and it
try to be transparent and say look this
is what we're doing it would be clear
and conspicuous and just try to be
better net citizens because people have
fairly low expectations right now well
so okay so there's this idea that as a
young company you need to make a
contractor the users may have an
understanding into users about what deal
they're getting
for what role you're in play but there's
also in every start a whole lot of
uncertainty about what you're going to
be you're going to make it want me to
whether that's in finding the data fear
internal analytics or you know using web
traffic data to learn to protect against
certain magic attacks or other
unforeseen possible innovations that
could come from using the data that
you're reflecting interesting ways how
do you square the need for professor
they're consistent was with a sort of an
openness to on using innovations
opportunities it's interesting that
cloudflare initially was launched as a
web security company and in building ads
infrastructure it turned around the day
one out who were seen yet because that's
in thinking from security mindset and
the way that we build our infrastructure
we also created this ability to provide
website optimization and we were you
know we were CDN and then sort of change
things and it kind of changed our
offerings but we still try to keep the
general Vision the same and I think one
of the key things to keep in mind as a
start-up and for those of you who
attended trustee cons about the original
Jamie
idea I believe Marshal Hoffman said this
during her presentation but she said you
know don't make promises that you can't
keep or that you don't know that you
can't keep right if you want to try to
do this transparent and notify your
customers when things change and be
respectful of that relationship in the
data that you have be yeah you can't
make a promise that you don't know you
can't keep so how often does this sort
of thing come up with earlier stage
companies of the human like you've got a
10 person organization or van is privacy
one of the topics or is that the 48th of
the port number brings up after in a
butcher monetization strategy now you
acquirement users in mobile one yeah it
really depends on the company so clocks
Lars a USB port fellow company and one
of the reasons I think we've been so
interested in CloudFlare as as a
platform that investment is that they
have these values very to debate into
into the black one and so in that case
it was very very high on the list of
things that we have talked about in and
in other in other cases in just less so
so think about we need that debug legs
and the Kickstarter or four at sea or
even at the beginning you know Twitter I
don't think people thought whole log
about privacy indications of clear David
with their
so so it really depends and I think we
are really mindful of the balance
between sort of privacy and opportunity
or trust and creating trust while still
leaving it the opportunity to create
interesting new things so you know some
investments that's more from Center than
others but it's I think the manager
significant so if you're trying to enter
start a forester who's starting to
encounter or maybe some of these user
rights or privacy or trust issues and
you don't have full executive support
one of the things that's been really
helpful this is not a club or but
previous experiences as well as talking
with other startups is making the keys
for what that brand reputation hit will
cost if it comes out that you do not
support your user rights that you are
not there as a trusted entity and that
you that privacy
main concern because when there's a
breach people are going to jump ship but
go to the more secure and what they
believe to be secured competitor unless
you come out and are very forthcoming to
your two basins that you know it we have
this incident something occurred we're
trying to make it right it's follow-up
so how would or should a small company
best communicate with their values this
morning he won't have a track record in
fact in the news articles that you stand
up their users when i'm looking at their
party vendors I'll discover their legal
trends that often was a pretty
unfriendly written to communicate values
how
suggest nothing being the question of
how you ready to talk to a mess
fantastic went on both sides of the
table with that and typically the
startup that is able to answer the
questions by handing you know they
handing you a package with the answers
already done like that that is an
indicator they have a level of truth
they actually thought about it anyone
who takes your questionnaire and is just
sort of gradually filling by the time
man a lot of that involves technical
aspects but fill out as the policies and
the internal controls in the auditing
those are those are questions that he
would be asking a vendor and a company
that can't articulate that upfront
clearly with a structured well written
30 page PDF is not is probably not
really Adam sure enough staged I would
trust them for anything for that
obviously if if it's company that's just
doing like that the vendor this just
doing icons and making didn't ask for
as soon as employee dating service daily
user data especially starts touching
third party service it becomes extremely
important to get that point I've been at
the table when we've brought in the
first person like Jamie I'd Evernote so
I mentioned that you might be interested
in some day being at a startup I can
tell you that the first day that someone
shows up to be the privacy person at a
startup there's there's usually a movie
with some glazed eyes with the
executives and it tends not to be
because they they don't care but because
the expectations of people from the
outside about what you're spending all
of your time on versus the expectations
of what you're doing a 40-person startup
that really hope you can make payroll in
whatever the amount of hours that you're
able to spend on writing out the exact
workflow that you would go through if
you get exactly this type of support
from the government before you've ever
had that subpoena before it's just
completely unrealistic that they're
we've been someone that that a patty
start that was worrying about that at
the same time they're trying to get
which will lead to release out and
training in front of the service stop
crashing and things like that so I think
that in general when you see it small
companies he has startup that gets some
bad we're not getting privacy right not
getting security right there's always a
lot of snark oh my gosh I can't believe
it a positive gotten that wrong from my
perspective the almost feels like my
gosh I can't believe it if the one
doesn't get it wrong it's hard because
you have to get everything right to stop
bad guys all it takes is this crew yo on
one thing to get a wrong and the intense
the intention is I found usually good
it's just don't have time or resources
to really work on it and you're looking
for the right person to come in and help
you get actionable stuff done fast and
you often see companies forming these
policies after in response to something
that happened great so one we were
discussing earlier it was there was a
situation Kickstarter where there was a
project that got funded where the author
of the book had made it was a a guide to
getting laid
dude the throw thing and the guy have
made some sort of unsavory comments
about women somewhere else and the
project that fact and what happened
people got really upset and put the
question to Kickstarter what's our role
in either supporting a not supporting
this type of project right so that's
like a very specific case that tests
your sense of your role as a platform in
moving things are certain direction sir
you know and having an agenda in
addition to soar your basic
responsibilities and I think it's pretty
hard to and what they ended up doing was
issuing an apology is that they hadn't
they felt like they should have hold it
in they didn't it's very complicated and
that gets us to the complicated section
of the conversation but the point I just
wanted to make is that I think it makes
a lot of sense to try and think of our
as early as possible what kind of
company you are and what kind of
questions are most likely to come up
most immediately so in some cases
remember and it's very obviously you
know people's innermost thoughts are
recorded here so that security Israel or
issue you should have a pub sort of
which go into this with a perspective on
that with I think a lot of the more
nuanced things it does make sense to
have an incident you know trigger the
conversation that gets you the point
breeding
policies and you know one of my favorite
things about the Internet is that we get
to experiment and one of my great things
about companies is the way that watching
them respond to crisis and there's this
notion of the service recovery paradox
where if a company bought fails and then
recovers gracefully like them more than
if they had never failed in the first
place and so I think you see a lot of
that these kinds of policies within to
answer your question a little bit as
well it you do need to figure out what
your company's values as Mission
missions are but how do you communicate
to that how do you communicate that to
your customers I mean it's leveraging
its really how important is that is it
so important you need to start
communicating that on day one if you
guys know what your core values are then
yet you will you will start
communicating through your blog post
you're doing communicated through your
PR are your social media and all of that
it just becomes any tentative speaking
engagement anytime you guys are going to
meet and talk about it because it's
something that you're probably you know
what Mozilla is about right because they
evangelize ad just in everything that
they do you know it's something that I'm
constantly we talk about a lot how is
really important you know ever no talks
about how this is a key part of their
their services you make it part of your
marketing use it becomes part of your
brand and so you just communicated early
and often and if it changes you
communicate that as well and just be
honest and your
you're you want your customers to be
evangelists they're more willing to
forgive you make a mistake when you
apologize it's not about admitting fault
it's just about admitting responsibility
responsibility and we don't know but
just a question of ethics a week we
posted or CEO posted on our blog in 2011
exactly what our privacy values were and
these interviews about night I think
that even if even if it wasn't something
that somebody was doing girl it's never
too late to really make it was it and
when we asked users who are using
Evernote for free and then started
paying us what the reason that they
started painting this was the number one
reasons just like the company they want
to support it anything but it is
legitimate to establish that trust for a
long period of time and money thanks for
the remarks i think is an interesting
panel but i do want to push a little bit
messy photos if you're talking about
these issues in terms of marketing and
communication but fundamentally we're
talking about human rights issues here
we're talking about people's legitimate
rights so i wonder if perhaps the sector
and perhaps small companies and big
companies in this sector are getting a
little bit of an easy pass on largely
because perhaps user data isn't and
privacy isn't really the most tangential
type of human rights harm that can be
affected so you know the question then
becomes do you learn from mistakes and
suggesting or is there a proactive
agenda here where small companies who
want to be evangelic evangelical about
these issues can band together and think
about ways to push back both at the
government level and also on this idea
that like we'll just iterate and
eventually we'll get this right I mean a
transparency report from if you compare
transparency report they all look
totally different there's no
standardization so the data book that it
becomes somewhat hard to decipher or
gather meaning from so the question then
is are we getting our companies in this
sector getting it kind of easy in terms
of any other sector where there's
human rights implications and secondly
where is the innovation happening is it
just about putting impound before this
there was one transparency report that
was showcased that had charts and
flowcharts and colors and the big
innovation was that they used they
packaged data in a different way so I
mean is there innovation as protective
of rights are we here innovating about
marketing I think was it go back to you
before arm essentially a company's the
engine and sorts out yes I mean even in
that previous session right they were
trying to come up with a standard way of
reporting so that we're comparing apples
to apples are in the know just oranges
so we see that happening we see this
push to get startups to be to think
about these issues because a lot of
times it's easier to think about it from
a user right from a privacy perspective
than from a human rights perspective
human rights is a very charged word or
phrase it so it's really hard sometimes
if you just walk in and say to your CEO
hey let's see what human rights
violations well you know that's a big
deal but from a clown player look from a
consular perspective you know there are
situations where we have people using
our services websites that use
cloudflare services to protect their
speech because they are under constant D
das or that they're constantly under
attack in some way and we did a lot of
pressure from governments from third
parties that say hey you need to take
down that say because we consider that
to be terrorists speech and that was
something where you know we have to sit
down and say okay if somebody comes to
in foreign government you know US
government owes manner it says you know
you take this content down now because I
said so is that something we're going to
fight for and we decided you have it is
something that we're going to fight for
you know it me is never in this is one
of our my number statements with
CloudFlare made the decision that we
will never and we have never taking down
a customer's website or move the
affected their content are shaped their
traffic because of a because of
political speech issue and that's
something that you know I think there's
room for that type of conversation of
all right when you're dealing in
especially user-generated content that
human rights issues do come up but
they're not going to be framed that way
because I you can sing it if you that
phrase human rights is very frightening
to to executive staff heading that
there's there's things that might be
right that aren't necessarily human
rights I mean if they like our bar bar
in our insistence that you can export
your dinner service like the ability to
get your pie recipes out I've ever known
like I'm proudly have I think it's the
right thing I do is not like this was
not so I think it's they get that the
average startup doesn't really feel like
most of what they're doing really
touches on human rights per se but I
think the thing that would really help
for small companies having gone through
this a few times co really help the
small companies is is some simple check
checklists and boiler plates for privacy
and security that they could follow
without having to figure it out from the
whole block and not have to take the
entire universe of every single security
risk and every single privacy issue
come up and solve them all like is it
literally when you've got ten people and
you barely material for two months like
like something that they could they
could take a twisted time I so I've got
a couple talks lately trying to walk
startups through security and like it
when you have this many employees you
should be doing this which we envision
this realistically you're talking about
doing this like I think if there was
something for for privacy that would
that would help that that some simple
road maps but that's not going to be a
one size fits all I think that not every
company is is going to have to have the
same constraints around what they do
with date i think the the right to be
forgotten as an example if that sort of
his home for us people spend months
putting together thousands of things
that they are members or for their lives
than everyone and the ability to go in
and delete that casually with a single
click of a button is kind of dangerous
like that's dangerous for the end user
because someone gets into their come and
happens to know their password could do
a tributary someone who who
the number of people who say they won
flows their accountant and ask for the
next day to reopen it it's where we
spend probably two ftes of support just
remedy those situations and I guess to
me that one's not a black black and
white I think the the ability for user
to go through a process and choose to
remove the information they put together
and every element should be there but
the ability to make that perennial will
I think that super easy I actually think
that goes against the interest of most
of our users so we have it be a
multi-step process and it just liked all
the nodes you put the trash into the
trash montano close your account that's
not because we want to retain users
that's because we want to prevent
someone from accidentally doing
something catastrophic to what they've
put together and I think that's that's
it going to be a different balance for
different companies I think there's also
a sense of know your customer right if
notice we're not from the sense of you
need to have real ID but you need to
know the types of cancer as I eat your
platform if you're 54 head is highly
used by by activists or by people whose
rights are can be infringed or they're
under attack or something like that you
also have to make sure that you
prioritize features that constantly be
more secure make sure that they have the
abilities two factor authentication make
sure that you're communicating to that
when there are a phishing attacks
targeting CloudFlare customers there
things like that where you need to make
sure that you are protecting your
customer because they are under attack
and being able to build things from a
feature set to protect
did you know that they are that class
where there they are under threat so I
think one to answer this question all
day but I think 11 issues like tools
let's start up your fuel on open source
the new got lots of open source for web
servers and data stores and so on and
and a lotta I would hope that at least
some portion of this could get reduced
to reasonable policy and reasonable
tools to help implement it and that's
going to take a while but I think Apple
any one thing then there's another set
of issues that there's just not
necessarily a clear answer to it's like
privacy broadly it's just
extraordinarily complicated a lot of it
in the situations that aren't really
understood and we have informed sort of
norms around and then the last one is I
think a lot of these relationships are
still be visible so one examples we're
talking under there's apple asked tumblr
to take not safe for work gay content
out of their mobile app and they did by
filtering out a tag and that you know is
very sort of complicated situation where
you know they're basically being put you
know in forced into sort of the
censorship roll through by wizards
relationship and using some sometimes
accrued mechanisms to do it and maybe
not communicating the right way that I
think a lot of companies are we learning
learning hard lessons that way and
oftentimes you
dynamics at play around visible we try
to take a very neutral stance on things
because it's about providing the service
it's a network solution you know it is
not our role to be the arbiter of
content we're not policing the internet
from that perspective we are providing a
way for customers to optimize website in
to kill a DDoS attacks than being said
you know we get a lot of pressure from
supply to our customers sometimes from
third party at tight abuse entities that
say what you've got you know you've got
people were using your service who did
details for hire now that abuse does not
come through our service but you know
the traffic doesn't come through a
service but they say okay well what
about that one I you take down why don't
you not serve them not allow them to use
your services you know why why don't you
take down this political speech by one
he takes out the same site why don't you
take down you know anything that could
be viewed as as bad but it's important
for us to be as objective as possible
good we're providing a service that
helps infrastructure and it becomes a
very slippery slope when you start
making subjective decisions we're there
to not proof of a piece of your actual
stories
one in terms of a challenge for younger
stage startup companies and dealing with
third parties whether it be using third
party to store data or border services
and that they may have leverage under
those third parties to enforce their own
companies manage that challenge the
other niggas would ask you as really
unsafe of these were thinking about
needing capital raising capital is there
are all investors are going to take the
attitude that very user protected
policies are equivalent bar they our
investors going to push back and say
you're actually really what the
possibilities are
and
so I'll take the second one first and
every investor is not the same and every
Messrs in fact very different and you
know the you want to be very careful
picking who you work with it was back in
your country and what you know what
their mindset is so I can only speak for
ourselves and tell you what the things
that we think about it and we care about
but but that's our that's a real issue
for sure whether your company's private
or public from your perspective you know
how you apply pressure to third parties
think that that's a that's a challenge
when you're small right because you're
not using market pressure and it's a lot
of time the pressure as well i only have
X amount of dollars I've gotta use I've
gotta use this week has been through
I've got to use somebody in the cloud
I've got you something i don't have got
stretch for money as far as i can and
it's about i think one of the best thing
that you can do an early stage is be
able to evaluate your risk now would be
able to say okay I'm doing as much
diligence as I can on this company there
are some basic security controls that
are out there and whether or not you
grab some sort of due diligence
spreadsheet you know to send those in a
answer these questions for me do these
basic security controls are you you know
ISO 27001 just ask those basic questions
but get a sense of what their control
and and you know what their privacy
policy is if they've got control over
your data or your shipping user data off
but they're going to respond to a law
enforcement or give the information that
their parties or monetize it well then
you've broken your contract with your
own customer being smart about that
relationship trying to find vendors that
are like-minded and sometimes you won't
but you've got to be able to say okay
identified who they are and when it's
time to move will move but yeah it's
difficult trying to at least establish
talk to them about their controls you
mentioned earlier defects in subpoenas
and over broad request for information
things like that I'm just curious how
many times have you gotten completely
paperless requests for information with
a wink I know Mozilla got a phone call
from Homeland Security a while back
asking for certain things to be done and
it responded with a letter and Homeland
Security just went away but it didn't
stop Homeland Security from making the
effort over the phone and I was just
wondering if this is something that you
see on a regular basis or if it's rare
and I don't mean just Homeland Security
by me any law enforcement agency um do
we give it a formal request yes we will
receive an informal request was when
people say hey you can you know keep
reminding as if
oh well you sent me this is our policy
here's our subpoena or subpoena
processes started before they go okay
thanks and come back with process
sometimes those conversations mag
rephrase really have I had a
conversation like that where it was
malicious where they were trying to get
information without extra sort of
process part of that may be because
you're really talked about it a lot like
this is our policy this is what we do
that we're very consistent about it a
lot of times the conversations are folks
that don't know what our policy is and
they just need the competition fiscal
policy is or they're just getting a
heads up because they want to make sure
that they're sending a tailored
attachment so we've never had a wink
wink nudge nudge can you give us an can
we give us information with Allison can
you give us a customer information a
billion i have not had that head of
requests that also really hard nosed
about activism and i think in the
initial handshake with each of the
organization to figure out what your
procedures and look harder and think you
figured out about the only thing i think
may be relevant would be retention
requests we are going to be serving you
with this and we would like you to
retain the data so that they're you when
we do get the payor to you 48 hours from
now it will still be there that's
probably relevant for for some
organizations and there's that voluntary
emergency requests where and there is an
emergency situation they can send you
this you can it pretty much that you can
voluntarily provide us with this
information because its emergency and
and we go
that's good to know but we are not going
to give it to you and I think a lot of
companies have different policies when
it comes down to if there's that
imminent harm I know it it's different
for closure because we're novelistic
provider right we don't have content or
laws and things of who posted this on
the site at this time but there are like
social networks to think where it's like
this person is threatening to commit
suicide right now we need this IP
address maybe their address information
so we can make sure that they are not
going to kill themselves are bomb threat
or some sort of school threat something
like that those emergency request do
exist and companies do respond to them
with information because they know that
legal process is going to follow up
rarely does it not and in those stories
their imminent threat of life or death
we don't get those because have a type
of content
so you talked about the position of
wanting to be as objective as possible
always the kind of being as open as
possible I suspect that is essentially
the easiest thing to do in terms of what
your legal position writer you're kind
of like how you deal with whether two
min rights whether that's just privacy
or whatever else it is the easiest thing
to do is step away from those
responsibilities to their you can owning
i love the three points so I guess what
I'm curious about is not necessarily
with y'all but have you seen any great
examples where people do take that next
step and say we're an open platform we
try to stay out of this as much as
possible we also have a view from
somewhere and we are like we're pushing
this in the right direction or we're not
like actually have some kind of
subjectivity in their their staffing or
editorial or whatever they call it
curation something that that allows them
to have policies and platform kind of
stances that gives them some flexibility
while also contain mostly open most
acceptable use policies in terms of
service give platforms the ability to
make those calls there are a lot of a
lot of service providers that will take
down phishing sites that will take
down you know hate speech because they
part of their terms of service they've
remade into their terms of service so
what so I'm very familiar those examples
I'm actually only other Gretchen okay
like so things you do want and kind of
pushing more than that darling is
anybody thinking about creating space
like guide but as soon as you touch
something right and you actually create
liability under sites if you like where
to promote something we create a symptom
now we now we're to login for it right
so you haven't been business of
cultivating acting truck charge said I
try to activate activists so we
definitely take down ATM charge a sec
yeah I guess I can make it more context
but there's also many things that you
think are actually very good see go
further but touching them and making
sure more of your users might see it or
maybe getting it to more people actually
also creates liabilities Timaeus yeah
yeah so I'm curious and you see is there
anybody doing it like extraordinarily
well that is kind of like for lack of a
better term is totally subjective like
promoting good while mitigating stat
right that is easy like the hate speech
line but now there's a whole other I
should be so hard like time
if the answer's no it's just interesting
to but I'm just curious no okay so every
marketplace that I know of does them to
control what kinds of things happen in
the marketplace whether it's air being
me your uber or Etsy or Kickstarter
right and so there's this something that
guides the behavior of certain direction
whether it's a set of standards or
inspections or sort of guidelines on on
that I think you raise an interesting
question link at what point does doing
that introduced actual legal liability
to the platform Andrew might know the
answer to that being the expert lawyer
in the house but there's you know the
section 230 of the Communications
Decency Act which lets platforms you
know releases platforms from my building
user-generated content I think you know
limits to that I'm talking specifically
about promoting specific things
promoting good right it's more than
jissa I'm guiding you with our
guidelines we want to try to break this
there's a certain that like I'm going to
attract this type of customer because we
shape you with our Terms than I already
know this is type environment that we've
created you're specifically saying you
find something that you like that's good
ain't you promoted anybody who's doing
that well a lot of my show useful is a
lot of marketplaces do it but it's yeah
you know it's different it's one thing
for etsy to promote wedding accessories
and for you to promote overthrowing the
government well means differently it's
june june / it's okay that usually like
a targeted marketing thing i think you
do promotion
in the marketplace but this is different
you thought of a content marketplace in
some ways right so they're used to it
but they will often pick a cause they
agree with and promotes it in a big way
right and claps are I would say also did
this with every fight back like they
helped us build like math so the that's
more of a this not that's a specific
example rated as part of our sort of
general philosophy impact factors months
ago day we fight back and there's
certain things that we do but specific
to like in general always this thing
yeah so I mean I think it's interesting
to your point it's like we would come
out in favor of like open internet or
something on behalf of like our company
stance on that but like a user starts a
petition right and it's like a
user-generated content than you then
don't want to take further that's
actually like soon to your point
actually section 232 goes away soon is
like let's say our staff might work with
that person to optimize it right that
actually changes that long because
companies cakes games all the time me
there's lots of letters and connects to
ET where you know we sign in oh yeah
where we say that this is wrong or the
day we fight that we participate we
provide a nap and those things like that
because
something that carnival arts company is
taking this stance about something and
the company through that all the time
what you're saying about I don't know so
yeah there's a bunch of questions well
as 11 is at what point do curatorial
action on a platform impinge on user
rights and and then there's another one
which is to what except you protected
legally from doing things like that but
to do things like that and then related
is to what extent that those have a
brand impact where you may be legally
you know in the clear but it puts you in
complicated position in terms of your
identity draw like slightly different
questions but if you ever seen a great
example somebody okay well so oh 440
introduce yourself to major bridge for
an online service to provoke
user-generated
as long as it calls attention to it
you're getting Academy who your cover is
very very dangerous to mess with the
content in any way moreover I so pair
going to my clients right now that
anything you do to encourage anything a
user generated content from if there's
any potential copyright violation in
connection about user-generated content
you've just put yourself on with
possibly for thousands this copy radios
for billions worth trillions of dollars
in santa cruz right as copyright is the
one thing that's carved out of the
federal election project that is carved
out in this region but not all regions
well federal intellectual property start
out every question as to what else is
cardell i hit other regions
that is extremely difficult to a balance
with maintaining a usable service free
of obviousness bound we started to see
people you notes within Evernote
publishing them and using them as base
the spam like URL like go here then it
talks about some pharmacy canada and
then click on that you apply something
they can post it on facebook because we
have a good reputation and pharma canada
calm is not and figuring out how to
police that involved inspecting the
content of news accounts both from plus
alcohol the standpoint that we will want
to be in that business and also from a
legal standpoint that if we were to
inspect the content of accounts for this
purpose that we would lose protection
around
the basis we implemented moderation
policy where users would have to report
that particular thing was spam and then
that was the only signal that we would
use we would not look at the content we
can only look at complaints of abuse and
that's worked pretty pretty well we've
been going to do that although what we
found pretty quickly is that children
are terrible terrible people because
most of the spam reports are for
communities yes yes hashtag children
mature enough most of the spam reports
are for educational materials you know
this is the syllabus about Harrison
Bergeron and you know children to spam
spam spam spam so we had to we had to
find to adapt pretty carefully to make
sure that the content moderation was not
itself than a meetings per views you
have a music teacher said that's all
right now we did say oh we're only using
for commercials down so if we get a
sufficient number of reports member like
the addresses that are labeled as
commercial spam if we look at
links where contact information to buy
something somewhere else that we know
will disclose that without but if we are
not we eventually labeled it report spam
we didn't want to get it too we don't
want to have a text box where you could
say other things that you don't like
about this content because we don't want
it we didn't want to be in business of
having someone typing in that this is a
violation of my copyright or you know
this is this was a picture of me when I
was a kid David like we didn't want to
have a mechanism for that because the me
the little discretion that that has to
impose on our staff to be able to
purchase doing of commercial redirection
just that we're not the liability region
because for efficiency reasons your
staff didn't happen and I remember
policy yet for that we have official
policies for how to deal with all those
things and those tats all our privacy
policies in terms of service but we
didn't want and support staff to have to
go through unstructured tickets on on a
spam reporting
to that so we wanted to go through the
formal policies to define exactly what
the steps are for someone to do it
formal take down based on the content is
one of the independent process separate
from spam tracking which is a bit much
more responsive because the veteran is
just people voting more aircraft Jamie
and then I think we're going to wrap up
so I wanted to make just one final
overly broad point the policies that you
set now to protect your customers data
within your environment whether it's
implemented privacy by design whether
it's anonymizing data or minimizing the
data that you say so Roy you lead you to
putting in human rights protection
because you never know who's going to
use your platform so if you start off
early thinking about user privacy
thinking about protection and securing
your users data and the way that they
access your service you're going to
eventually protect human rights as well
so just something to consider I think
we'll leave that thank you for all your
great questions this was fun and we'll
be around thank you very much thanks