Steve Smith from the FBI who is the lead
engineer and again a group of engineers
there I believe anyway he is here to
talk about distributed denial of service
and thanks for coming Steve thank you
I'm actually going to continue to wear
my coat today but just because it
presents the proper image but more
realistically because it's freezing up
here I want to talk about both
distributed denial-of-service attacks
and also just generic denial of service
attacks sit a couple parameters around
what I'm going to say today this is not
a technical discussion this is more of a
policy and procedural discussion one
where I'm going to be looking for input
from you so the most important thing
from my point of view is that if you
have something to say about this topic
please do what have we seen recently we
being the federal government not
necessarily we being everybody in this
room this is something I'd like
corrections on changes to additions etc
if you have something to add a whole lot
of stuff whoops we need to get on the
screen here which one is it this one
okay there we go a lot of increases in
activity recently recently being the
last 60 to 90 days it was the previous
occurrence that we've seen maybe one or
two multi-hundred node network of do us
zombies or slaves in operation in any
given time now we're seeing many more
than one why is this happening well
increases in ease of use is my guess of
a lot of the the tools so we can enable
a lot more script kiddies to get
involved with this particular activity
we've seen a lot faster spread of the
knob service activities and cross sector
application what i mean by cross africa
application is previously the average
attacker would stick to one particular
type of activity as in i know how to
route a linux boxes rape based on the
Red Hat distribution so I'm going to do
that this time actually we're seeing
networks where we've got everything from
Windows machines through
you know digital UNIX being affected by
the amount of service tools which
bothers me a little bit because it means
people are reaching a little bit further
down into the bag of unfortunate tricks
this is the interactive part of the
conversation and I need help from you
guys here is what do we do about this we
being a federal government the United
was set up by the President to
coordinate the federal government's
response to certain types of activities
one of the things that we do is respond
to certain types of attacks on computer
networks now what does respond meaning
the federal government parlance it means
that we collect information we
distribute information yes I know the
FBI is really well known for doing that
part but we also try and get stuff out
to people who are the victims of these
attacks one note on the bottom yes I
know we need to release source on the
fine DDoS tool that is a favourite topic
in the government at the moment this is
what we do with a few of the issues that
we're facing right now open amplifier
sites by what what I mean by the open
amplifier site issue is those who
familiar with nets can org and the other
is that go out and look for directive
broadcast amplifiers whether they be
technically correct or not is that
something that's worth approaching I've
talked to a few of you in an email about
what's the best way to deal with that
type of activity is it worth people
approaching it trying to get these
amplifiers shut down typically you know
folks will send email to the the owner
the registrant of particular either
logical domains or IP space etc saying
hey you've got an open amplifier site
shut it down we all know how effective
that is in a lot of situations there is
the possibility if people think it's
worthwhile that I could end up having an
FBI agent go knock on doors of
registered owners a particular IP space
now whether that's going to be the
actual user is a different story
entirely but at least it would start the
process of bringing to people's
attention the fact that these things are
a problem if you folks believe that they
are not enough of a problem to warrant
that type of activity or if
fool would be received so negatively
that it would actually hurt the efforts
to shut these down I need to hear that
kind of feedback amplifiers that are
already used in crime this is a
situation where for instance if we have
an attack that's happened on name your
large site or individual users at
universities etc we already know where
the network is of affected machines
through investigative opportunities
through sources etc what do we do now in
red we approach them in person will go
up to the registered owners and try and
trace back from there saying hey who's
actually got these IPS and here's what
we've seen this is what has happened you
may want to take corrective action
should we notify VN upstream provider
would that be a more timely notification
it takes me several days in a lot of
situations to get somebody out the door
to a site to go visit them would ISPs
NSPS you name the word we want to use
for the upstream provider being
interested in that kind of information
that kind of notification is that
something that would be a service to
your customers would it be a service to
you amplifiers not yet used in crimes
believe it or not the FBI actually does
occasionally find out about these things
before they're used typically we'll find
out about them when they're in stage of
building a network so we'll get to watch
it grow as we watch it grow we then have
to notify all the people who we've seen
the particular actors take advantage of
is that something where it would be
worth warning the individuals who are
affected by email a phone call or an
upstream provider I'm including upstream
providers in both of these things
because I think the most efficient way
that I can get information out is to a
smaller group of people and let you
choose what to do with it from there on
is that something that's of interest
just looking at this page of stuff
that's up on the screen here is there
anybody who'd like to add to it make
comments on it and if nobody in this
group makes comments I think we should
take a caffeine break
I have more or less hi rob chakra
Chelsea data I just like to make one
comment about this and I think you know
in a lot of these cases whether it's a
distributed denial service or you know
spam one of the most effective tools is
a shame and I don't see anything here
that that shames anyone is doing the
right thing with their network you know
that's Canada work makes things known
publicly orbs and mass make things known
publicly and we have a place to point to
and say you know this person is running
their network badly they're not a good
next citizen don't be their customer or
you know go tell them they're a bad
person and you know that is useful
obviously it's limited but its place to
start absolutely now I can't advocate
using one method over another especially
those that are commercial commercially
based but i'm interested in effecting a
second group of citizens if you're
sitting in this room you already care
enough about your networks in the way
they function and i think you're going
to pay at least a minimal level of
attention necessary to them that's going
to notice some of the things that you
just discussed what I'm interested in
doing is seeing if it's worth getting
the attention of those people who pay
the money who owned the networks you
walk into the company that's got the IP
space that's actually using it from
carrier X and say to the management
their pen guys this is not only a
liability for the world because it
affects the way the net functions but
this is the liability for you personally
number one because your information may
be at risk if someone's routed a box
well now you don't own it anymore second
is there's always the potential that
someone will launch into civil liability
as a result of the use of that network
that's a messy messy issue I only want
to get really mirror if I can avoid it
but us notifying people usually us being
you know the nasty guys in the dark
suits usually has a positive effect on
management personnel and it doesn't
always but it usually has a positive
effect we're bringing a problem to your
attention do you want to fix it that's
up to you but we're telling you there's
there's a bad thing going on same way we
do it if there was a you know a bad guy
using the their warehouse to distribute
game they generally take a dim view of
that kind of activity because it's not
good for business I can't believe nobody
else has comments I do oh good I think
you I'm not sure where the last
questioner just went but I think you
might have misunderstood the question I
think he was talking about a public
place like math where the to list these
sites perhaps make it impossible for
people to use them is that what you're
thinking Paul yeah I understand the
background of maps in an ordinate cetera
and wanted to step away from that
because I can't for various policy
reasons get near embarrassing people in
public but I was also saying well if I
was sitting out there I would definitely
be embarrassed if my name popped up but
there are a lot of people unfortunately
who aren't and how do we get to them
this is something that interested me
because how do we get to the people who
don't care or you don't notice that
they're up on those kinds of sites I
know that the federal government can't
do that I can't put up a mirror of of
maps and say hey look at all these
goofballs we don't run their networks
well so I have to take a different
approach hi I'm fall vixy and I started
maps and we looked into doing a smurf
amplifier list some years ago the
problem being that the technology we use
right now Saul destination address based
and some buddies over at Cisco of and
talking to me about a way to to apply
bgp filters to source address which
would be very useful for this kind of
thing and you can bet that as soon as
that happens maps will sort of step
outside the mail abuse field and make a
an active list of Smurf amplifiers for
exactly this kind of purpose but to
answer a question you asked earlier in
your presentation as far as knocking on
the doors I've heard about your
jackbooted thugs and I would love it if
instead of knocking on the door you
would kick the door in and tell people
to
use close there they're smart amplifiers
I forgot my boots I'm sorry well
wingtips do for now okay depends that
they're steel toed I'm bill Manning and
I had the dubious distinction of having
one of my machines actually land in rbl
for the first time and I was incensed
for about 30 seconds when I thought this
is really cool because I now blocked
whatever the number is forty to sixty to
ninety eight percent of the internet
from getting to my machine for further
attack so i can if this is nice of the
industry that the community is willing
to shun me for a while so i can go play
in my sandbox and so if I leave that
relay open then I effectively air-gap
myself so in some sense you could sort
of turn this around and say this is a
good way to get some well-deserved
privacy the newest insecurity
implementation become part of our BL
okay we've got one on the on the go
visit them side there's got to be
somewhere somebody in this audience who
believes that anything that we do is is
not a good thing and I respect that
believe it or not because we need that
kind of balance in society and I'd like
to hear from the other side please if
people don't believe that's a good idea
and I'd like the other reasons why
because then we can tell management too
bad choice speaking not formal anyway I
think well what what we often hear think
and say is that the FBI response is so
slow is to be not helpful I don't know
what you want to say about that well if
you look at the letters that make up our
name unfortunately the look in the
middle one is bureau and
that is bureaucracy but believe it or
not we can do some things rapidly when
we choose to it's a matter of bringing
it to a high enough priority level
honestly is that's one of the most
wonderful things about the organization
is if necessary we can have 10,000
people doing something but the question
is is it necessary and is it useful so
that's one of the things I hope to get
out of today was is this something where
if we could make it a quick enough
response need something like a like a
list of amplifier sites doesn't have to
be a 30-second turn around it can be
something that's done over a period of
time because they've been there for a
long time unfortunately there and
continue to be there and as we get that
reduced somewhat I think we'll have a
smaller target set to look at the the
larger question is and one of the
reasons I'm here actually is if I
receive a list of new amplifier sites
new zombies I want to find a way to turn
that around within minutes you know okay
we have to go for legal hours to get
into the hands of people who can get
those things shuttle off and that's one
of the things i'd like to find out is is
there a way i can do that is there a
list of contacts that i can use for
instance the second to bottom point
there I've been in the other side of
this audience enough that I know that
abuse that particular network is not
useful in allocations is there another
way to do that for instance some of the
list that collected knock contacts how
many people would be interested in
getting a phone call it was followed up
with a fax those kinds of things you
know all the sounds really good the only
issue that I have is that I'm concerned
about the ability of the FBI to keep
that people who interact on the internet
and with with managers well trained and
in wealth staff if there's turnover you
know one of the problems that we've I've
had dealing with it was just that you
know we get people who who really are
spending their first hours in this field
you know
cases you know just trying to do the
best they can but they're not well well
trained for the job absolutely we have a
problem with training and retention just
like everybody else does and if cisco
would stop poaching our san francisco
squad we'd be even better off but in all
seriousness we do have a training and
retention problem just like everybody
else who's got anybody who's worth their
salt we have some people who are
fantastically talented and actually
believe it or not for some unknown
psychological reason wha stay in the FBI
as opposed to going and making money but
the way we approach that is try and get
in the training its best our aim in that
area and this is diverging from my
intent of topic is that they spend
twenty percent of their time in training
and what that training should consist of
is actually going where there is a good
relationship between a company and an
FBI field office and sitting with those
people and doing the job I don't hold a
degree in anything remotely related to
what i do now i have an economics degree
which means i came in count money
properly but by sitting down and doing
the job for several years it was the
best possible training i could get and I
think that's the kind of thing that we
need to get our agents involved in is
get them out there and say hey this is
what my network looks like this is the
way it works this is the way these
pieces fit together because then when
you talk about it later on this oh okay
that makes sense ma'am let's see if no
one's going to get up and make the
slippery slope argument I will about FBI
involvement and technical issues of the
side I used to think it was possible to
separate technical from policy political
etc then I found myself working for I
can i no want to believe that as soon as
there are mechanisms for dealing with
these things there's a problem defining
the scope and it may look easy from here
to define operational technical it gets
much more complicated very quickly as
soon as you guys are involved
so let's be really careful about that
and that's the kind of comment that I
need to hear is how can we draw the line
is the line so blurry that we can't that
it would be inappropriate for us to do
so my object in this is to get something
positive out of out of the exercise as
opposed to just you know waving badges
around the air which doesn't do any good
with this type of activity so that's the
kind of thing that I need to hear Cobra
will be okay p inquest I wouldn't mind
getting the phone call at two o'clock in
the night there's a smooth amplifier is
there they need to be killed like now
and are getting a male to abuse at
something it usually works in some
places even at the very big toe
operations and said second comment on
the international internet being
international and smooth amplifiers
whore sauce is not always being over
here or over there and what is little
international cooperation on smooth
attacking issues mode depends on the
country which is an obvious answer to
that question but I would say overall
anything involves system protection and
and infrastructure protection we've had
extraordinarily good results perfect
examples would be candid in the UK just
because of our traditionally good
working relationship with them we have
watch exchanges in real time regularly
with them you know we see this thing
that just popped up on a UK network in
an educational institution here it is
and they'll take action against it it
depends on the country and in a lot of
situations as a matter of getting the
people in that country to get in contact
with our watch office or the FBI legal
attache office in that country and we do
have legal access shades over the world
and saying Here I am I'd like to be
notified when you find something in my
country we do try and do a positive go
out meet people say hey we've got this
information available can we give it to
you when it comes up but
as is accurately pointed out there FBI
agents in general are generalists so it
may be difficult to to bring across the
idea of the perfect kind of information
that can be transferred overall it works
relatively well when we know who to talk
to me that's the key we have no problem
by the way if if a knock of a company
that's operated overseas is interested
in talking to us directly and talking to
them directly I will tell you we will
notify the legal access Jays office will
notify the host country's government
because we don't want to have a
government to private entity in another
country contact without the host country
knowing about it that's bad for
political reasons hi avi friedman from
Akamai which is my day job and net
access which is my weekend job and I do
run a network and so I have some
network-based comments first a little
point of nanog etiquette I believe
you're just say major router vendor and
not Cisco what actually makes again
personal day my good people okay no no
major router vendors the only approved
way to refer to them the other so I have
a quick question which is that one thing
we commonly do when one of our customers
is smurfed is line up all the smurfs
amplifiers in a row and get them to
Smurf each other because we've plenty
about them been what to do that with so
I was wondering whether you think that's
actually something that's legal or
whether the FBI would get involved in
and then the real main point that I have
I did our position it is of course
self-defense so but the bigger question
is it seems to me that the big problem
is not actually Smurfs now I can filter
Smurfs yeah people won't be able to
pings on my customers it'll make my tray
swaps better d UDP trace route but
that's not as big a deal is actually you
know non Ford source you know or in some
cases or the most cases forged source
directed attacks directed you know IP
attacks TCP you know sins acts things
like that and you know this is a very
controversial for nanog topic about
actually having the government or
someone get upset about the ability to
send forged source
and actually getting some shaming and
other things going on there I was
wondering don't do you see directed you
know broken into machines directed IP
for its source attacks is a bigger
problem and if so isn't that something
that would be even better to try to
address somehow although that is more of
a technical issue and political issue of
it absolutely the answer is yes the vast
majority the attacks that we see now are
not the traditional Smurf style Smurf is
just an easy one to point out and make
an example of when we say okay should we
do something about a particular thing my
first opinion is long as there's a
sequence of TTP flags that hasn't been
exercised to find out what it's going to
do nasty someone people to keep doing it
now we'll eventually the protocols
evolved to prevent some of that yet but
then we'll have new vulnerabilities pop
up because if the way the world works
can we take steps to do ingress
filtering it's physically possible yes
in most instances people don't like it
for one reason or another I'm not going
to get into that particular religious
argument because it is to some people
and major router vendors have a hard
time with it but
then doors vendors in seriousness yes
see the bigger problem now is not
traditional Smurf it is other types of
attacks and any situations where we get
notification of that and that's what I'm
talking about with networks of
amplifiers as opposed to the traditional
Smurf amplifier networks of zombies
drones whatever your particular word of
choice for that day is those are the
ones where I think we can affect the
most change when we find out about them
is get the information out so that
people can fix those boxes which have
been affected you know a speaker's done
its job when someone can hits their
chest and I think that time for caffeine
break almost go ahead oh I don't know
what even my answers are just us out a
few random thoughts and all sorts all
sides of the issue it's good to be
notified when you've got an inadvertent
vulnerability so hard to configure some
of these things correctly that it's
always good to have double check that
said it's not clear that the FBI is the
right organization to be doing it
there's a chilling effect of it a few
months ago I had to meet an FBI agent on
a street corner nothing serve dishes or
weirdest way and she have a picture of
me that she used how they picture of me
on the web this is a disquieting feeling
that the FBI is looking for a picture of
me but the alternatives are not
necessarily better you mentioned civil
liability I think it's an interesting
direction I think we will be going down
I've written on this but the insurance
industry doesn't have the same
legislative and judicial and matter
media oversight as the FBI does and
regulations coming out of there or at
least as effective and possibly more
draconian we don't want you know Lloyd's
of London London banning end-to-end
connectivity that's not laundered
through one of their firewalls and
that's another direction things don't
know I don't know the answer to your
question but they're all good arguments
oxide I would point out that a list of
for example Smurf amplifiers is a
wonderful resource for the Smurfs errs
they find a very useful place to go get
helpers
absolutely and all you have to do is
look at some of the newer versions of
stock will drop the others that include
as precompiled options some of those
lists the question there is the same
thing as the open source question is the
same thing as a lot of other questions
which is better more information that
can be nefariously use or less
information and hope to hide it I'm not
sure that in this case protection
through obscurity is necessarily the
better Avenue to take I think that we
may be better off by bringing the
information to those people and that's
what I'm actually trying to talk about
is what is the best way to get that
information to them to get them to
change their behavior and if us doing it
is the wrong thing because it is
outweighed by so many other options fine
if we don't have another option even
though the one that I'm suggesting is
suboptimal we can take that step and see
how it works we're probably going to end
up doing based on what I hear today a
pilot program where we take a piece of
the list that's in the US and a piece
that's overseas and with some of our
sister services and overseas places go
and visit the people and see how they
react and then come back and say well
that was a really great idea or we'll
just hope that never happens again
sorry Dwight darkness from rcn to that
point and to Steve's point over here a
minute ago regarding the appropriateness
of of your enforcement on this I think
that there is a let me let me bring in
here for me enforcement has a particular
meaning okay it would be sort of
outreach or liaison or something like
that enforcement means okay there are
any program is that your outreach let's
get it that way I think that there's a
direct relationship to the extent to
which you get brought into that outreach
related to the extent to which unnamed
large network service providers aren't
cleaning up their act and the arrogance
displayed by a lot of unnamed large
network service providers related to
cleaning up to cut their customers with
open amplifiers is astonishing and I
submit that if we self-regulated better
that is at the industry regulated itself
better and cleaned itself up better you
wouldn't have to get involved we
wouldn't have to be talking about
buttering our own slippery slope well
I'm going to say something that will
probably get me tossed out of the
association of government bureaucrats or
something to that effect but I would
always prefer the youth self-regulate
over getting us involved there are a lot
of things that we do very well there are
a lot of things that we do not do well
at all and muddling in the technical
operations of networks is not something
that we are interested in doing it is
not something we would be good at and I
agree that the best pressure is peer
pressure to stop certain types of
activities now of course there'll always
be the line drawn in the sand it says
don't cross this please or else we're
going to have to come and be mean to you
but that kind of approach is probably
the best possible outcome I can see is
where people get together and say hey
this kind of activities got to stop here
that or we're not going to appear with
you or something to that effect whether
it will come to that is a business
decision frankly it does this do enough
damage to my network that I can say not
peering with that network is worth the
cost benefit of John Brown I highway I
would concur with the other gentlemen a
moment ago one of the problems that we
face in via a smartphone or some sort of
a denial service distributed or
otherwise is when we go to our up
streams is sort of the void of clue that
you find at those up streams or maybe
not necessarily avoid a clue void of
desire to take action arm and to follow
it through and I think I think we as an
industry have to really figure out a way
to beat those unnamed backbone vendors
or however the appropriate two phrases
are they if you want to comment on what
that phrase should be we have to figure
out a way of convincing them that they
need to clean up their networks and they
need to educate their customers to get
those things cleaned up and they need to
take it in a proactive otherwise I think
we will find that there will be a dot
gov involvement to a greater extent than
what we would like to see I think we
have an ability to to police that we
have the technology we have the cpu
horsepower etc etc to do that what it
takes is us making a conscious effort to
go forth and to do that um but
publishing the list is wonderful as mr.
Bell oven says it helps the smokers arm
it helps some of us that look at those
lists but when you have people that
don't take any action on those lists so
what absolutely I would strongly
encourage and I'm speaking more to the
audience than I am to the gentleman on
the podium that if you run in that make
sure your network doesn't allow these
things to happen fix it and to say
otherwise is almost criminal in a sense
of association in a sense thank you
thank you you know we've spent a whole
lot of time talking about closing
amplifiers and doing all the all the
stuff that we should be doing in order
to stop these attacks from being able to
happen and I'm all for that but the one
thing we haven't really talked about is
what happens when the FBI in cooperation
the service provider actually catches
one of these people doing one of these
attacks and and hopefully other people's
experience has been different than mine
but about now three years ago actually
caught one and there was undeniable
proof that this particular person was
doing this particular attack and that
was three years ago and as far as I know
an FBI agent hasn't even been by to
visit the person let alone any kind of
prosecution or anything else happening
so we're really sending a message out to
this to the script kiddies that we'll go
ahead and do what you want because even
if we know who you are we catch you
nothing can ever happen to you and
that's a definite problem one of the
things that I need to point out about
that is changes in legislation since
then a lot of what we previously did as
enforcement action was predicated on
laws that made it very very difficult to
number one convince an assistant US
attorney who we have to convince to get
an indictment or prosecution that there
is a viable case the second is that
horrific issue of damages most of the
governmental prosecutor process hinges
on the idea that there is a monetary
damage you can assign to anything and
that's very very tough in a lot of
situations what I would invite you to do
is to email me anonymously if you wish
but otherwise if you can with
information about where the contact was
and that kind of thing because I would
like to follow up on them secondarily a
point goes back to an original comment
that somebody made about training a lot
of the problems we've had that are very
real that you've experienced have been
directly result of sort of the cross I
effect you try and explain something to
it somebody in an enforcement position
in their eyes girl hey because they're
not really sure about what you're
talking about we have been significantly
changing the the technical outlook on
life on a lot of FBI agents a lot means
a couple hundred in an agency it's got
30,000 people in it that's pretty hard
to get across the entire population I
would posit that if you're in certain
areas right now if you're in the
Washington DC area if you're in the San
Francisco area until some large router
vendor went on a party you would have
very good response
two people in the last couple of years
there have been problems absolutely
there has been coming from the other
side of the coin a lack of customer
service we are are certainly
endeavouring to change that and one
thing it's important is if a field
office does not give you the response
that you need you should always call FBI
headquarters in this case the national
infrastructure protection Center is the
party responsible for running field
office investigated programs i will say
that as a whole the field agents are
absolutely wonderful they have good
people skills they know enough about
technology that they will at least not
go catatonic on you are they the the
geniuses who can run their own networks
some of them are some of them definitely
are not in which case we need to get the
people who do have the technical skills
to sit with them when they're talking to
you and also you can do a lot to help
yourself by toning the information that
you provide into such a manner that is
comprehensible it's a lot easier for me
to talk about things with certain types
of people than it is for other agents on
the field you want to get something out
of these people so talk to them like you
want to get something out of these
people as opposed to either they're
they're the enemy or they're there to
waste your time I am truly sorry that
you had a negative experience that way
and I would like today opportunity to
try and fix it we can yeah the the issue
in this case was the the the the field
agent was was good he understood the
problem he was good to work with but he
couldn't get anywhere because he
couldn't justify the amount of damages
like you were saying it was like a
five-thousand-dollar number and while we
could easily say well you know we may
have lost a million customers because of
this attack and all costs way more than
five thousand dollars that kind of
reasoning doesn't count the the amount
of time it took and broken things is all
that they would count towards at five
thousand we can only come up with like
thirty five hundred dollars and even
stretching hard fast I can prove this
amount of monetary damage kind of issues
and that and that's that was the problem
let's talk to mark on this
we get my case yeah just to speak to
that the administration introduced
legislation earlier this year which
among other things would have amended
precisely that part of the statute to
provide jurisdiction is 1030 a fight a
is the particular sub sub sub section of
the statute I would have created at
least a misdemeanor offense for less
than five thousand dollars would have
been graduated levels of punishment that
bill I think it's fair to say has really
not gone anywhere it was introduced by
Senator Leahy by request but it is not
going to be passed this session it's a
problem we're aware of and we do feel
strongly there are a lot of offenses
where even though the the monetary
amount may not hit that threshold that
there is a substantial prosecute of
interest and sometimes we just have me
wait we have no way under current law to
pursue that I mean remember in this case
it wasn't just that data that it wasn't
that there's a monetary amount that we
couldn't need to measure that regulation
it wasn't a hard monetary amount it
wasn't a provable monetary amount right
because you go and attack my network and
maybe keep take it down for 12 hours you
know there's lost revenue there but the
lost revenue doesn't count because I
can't prove that I would have otherwise
made that revenue yeah I would just say
three words beyond reasonable doubt
that's the hurdle we have to get over
for every element of an offense so we
would have to prove that in a court of
law or at least persuade somebody's
defense counsel that we could in order
to make them fold and plead guilty so it
is in fact as it gets converted for us
thank you okay concrete question time up
here if I were to have information that
could be pushed out to customers of ISPs
NSPS name your number etc would that be
something someone would be interested in
you don't have to answer me now but my
email address was on the first screen if
you want to answer that if you could
email it to me I would really appreciate
it because we can try and construct such
a beast a notification at work etc we
already do that in certain circumstances
with our infragard program and that's
something that if people are interested
it's infr a ga rd gov org moving
information ISPs more easily I would
love to have a useful telephone number /
email / fax contact for any isp that is
interested useful that means that i'm
not going to send something that's going
to end a customer service department and
we looked at 16 hours later or 20 hours
later or whatever because we already
have those so if you are interested in
doing that providing that information to
us so that we can get information to you
in a timely fashion that would be
wonderful
um there is as far as i can tell susan
is holding up a piece of cheese as you
can see oh I've exceeded my time limit
on the microphone there is no it's over
with a long time ago there is no
requirement there is no expectation in
any of the internet documentation to
stand up information in a who is or who
is type service and so if this community
thought that an operational
recommendation would be that there was
an opt-in service where they agreed to
run either their own data I'm a firm
believer if people own their own data
that they tend to keep it up to date as
opposed to pushing it to some central
repository someplace where they will
forget about it and or somebody will
start charging them to keep the current
that if there was an opt-in service that
that might get you where you want to go
if people thought that that was
important otherwise if I'm going to have
to pay somebody to keep the data current
in whois database somewhere else the
likelihood of me doing that's going to
be diminishing Lee smaller so I agree
anything he gets pushed into a database
is usually out of data as soon as the
push is complete I mean all you have to
do is look at some of mine Nick handles
and a little stale I think I've hit the
end of the time I'd be happy to talk to
anybody who'd like to outside or in the
back and I do encourage people to email
me estimated FBI gov is the email
address and for those who who feel it's
so necessary I do have PGP keys up on
MIT ski server and we can exchange
fingerprints if you're interested that's
it and thank you very much for your time
I appreciate it
one last statement and I at least get
some smiles