stop this is about tools that we have
developed at the AT&T center for
internet research and it's called tea
but it's the TCP behavior identification
tube at the joint work between myself
and Sally Florence or other colleagues
at AT&T have also contributed to it the
outline of the talkers I'll begin by
describing the motivations why do we
need a tool to identify TTP behavior or
why do we need to do this out followed
by that I will briefly describe the tool
I will discuss some of the anomalies we
have found in current 200 TCP
implementations conclude by describing
your future work so TCP handles majority
of today's Internet traffic people
report all kinds of numbers ninety
percent ninety-five percent so
understanding TCP behavior is clearly
important it's obviously important for
voice vendors they need to improve their
performance of their TCB stacks it's
also important for isps because a lot of
their traffic is being controlled by
this protocol so understanding its
behavior is clearly important there are
many documents various RFC's
internet-drafts and so on and so forth
that specify how TCP should behave but
of course the implementations don't
always match specifications partly by
design partly because of implementation
coding bugs and all kinds of things so
it is essential that we understand what
is the difference between what the RSS
say that the TCP should do and what
various teeth will actually do here is a
quick example the initial window that is
used by a TCP connection is the amount
of data just giving a simple description
here amount of data it sends out in a
burst before it receives any
acknowledgement so for example when a
web server gets a request it is allowed
to send out a certain amount of data
before the receiver sends any acts ok
there is an RFC about this 24-foot 14
which gives you this formula that shows
how the initial windows should be
calculated for a given MSS so if you
assume a nemesis of 512 which is a
normal MSS a TCP implementation is
allowed to send a burst of about two
thousand five
but we have found using Tippett that
there are TCPS out there one for example
this stack that's running on www.qik.com
flus bites with emesis of birth and just
for fun we tried a nemesis of 100 and we
found that this web server will send a
burst of a tea packets without receiving
the single act okay and and this large
such last verse of clearly mean
buffering problems lost delays so it's
important to see what PCP is that are
out there they actually they do now how
do you detect misbehaving TCPS so there
are two ways of doing it one is passive
detection 196 197 basically carried out
thousands and thousands of TPP transfers
across notes there were spread all over
the internet and he looked at the TCP
dump races that resulted and found
several anomalies he wrote a couple
papers about that I think he also gave a
talk here at nanog but such passive
detection has its limitations for
example you want to figure out how a
particular TCP implementation behaves
when say for example syn ACK is lost ok
now you're going to have to do keep on
doing this until you actually get a TCP
dump race in which cynic is lost and
then you see what happens ok so that's
kind of time consuming so we keep it is
a tool that actively proves TCP stacks
at various web servers ok to test it
behave it here is an example now the
basic idea is like this you basically
send fabricated TCP packets over raw IP
sockets so you need root permission ok
so for example you send us in and then
you direct the first firewall that will
prevent the colonel from seeing the
cynic that comes back ok otherwise the
corner will say act for a packet it
never sent it will send a reset in your
test will be doomed right there at the
same time the BPF device will deliver
this blog started up to the user process
that sent the syn packet and now you can
respond to it in any way you want so
what the net effect what we have is a
user level user control level tcp
without any colonel changes ok so this
work is based on the sting project that
was done it in your city of washington
by stefan cel
so as an example for example I've
mentioned the initial winner on I'll
keep using this as a running example
okay how do you do the mind what initial
window of web server is using okay so
you send us in you receive the syn ACK
back okay now you have established a
connection you send an HTTP GET request
okay for the basic document and you
don't add any incoming packet okay you
wait since you're not acting in any of
the packets that are coming in after
some time the TCP stack at the web
server will pre transmit the first act
at this point you terminate the test and
then the initial window is the maximum
signals number eocene okay and you can
check this with several MSS value since
you have it's a completely user control
about TCP you can say whatever i misses
you want and you know this will let you
figure out whether it behaves
differently with different domestic
sides okay so this is an example of how
things are done we have implemented many
such tests so for example and of course
this is not all as simple as it sounds
and there are several difficulties and
I'll come back to them at the end of the
presentation we have implemented several
tests so far some of them are handshake
test whether the how many pcps that are
out there that for example use time
stand how many CPC peas are stacked
capable how do TCB respond to congestion
or packet drops with the reducer
congestion window which exact flavor of
congestion can you know algorithm they
use you RINO RINO doubt there have been
several proposed thanks selective
acknowledgments to the clients of the
web servers correct construction acts
directly when a client send sacks do
they respond to stacks directly I mean
most of the major oasis that are out
there linux for example and windows 2000
they provide selective acknowledgement
and we want to see whether this is being
used effectively there are other tests
for example what is the initial window
there we saw whether there are any TCP
implementing implementations that are
out there that handle ecn surrogate okay
so i'm going to present some results now
and the background for this results
is we had to list of web servers one we
just got from hundred hot calm and I
will call this list the hotlist it's we
are not claiming that these lists are
represented even anyways just something
we got off the web it has 200 unique IP
addresses we done got a trace from an
ISP proxy it was given to us by tax
calcine and it has about 27,000 unique
IP addresses of web servers we repeated
the test at least twice each test that
I'm going to report on and we are going
to report the results only if the
results are consistent across the runs
and I will describe later why this is
important our isp which is essentially
UC Berkeley it does not allow us to run
n map so we do not have any correlation
of what anomalies we saw in the TCP with
what OSS they run have whatever
information we have it has come simply
because people gave it to us voluntarily
if any one of you is willing to give me
an account and i can run n map then
please let me know the initial window
that i described we ran about 638 test
from the ISDN proxy list that we had and
as i said we found four hosts that will
pump out eight thousand bytes without
ever waiting for an acknowledgement so
that comes out to about 17 packets the
genesis of 512 about 85 catches emesis
100 and there were several and these are
the people who do it we found that there
are about of about twelve percent of the
horse use initial windows more than four
packets which is a violation of what's
required by the RSC okay time stands
timestamps enable TCP is to better
estimate the retransmission timeout
value and this is essential to improve
TCP performance we used about 136 test
from the hot list and we found that
twenty-five percent of the service do
not use timestamps and there are some
notables in this list for example
ebay.com HP com we also found that IBM
host under certain circumstances
I exos send garbage in the timestamp
options we reported this problem to IBM
and the fix is in the works they said
that they couldn't do it before the
Olympics was over so hopefully they are
going to do it now we are not safe said
of time stamps are used correctly that's
the whole different area and whether the
rap sequence numbers are done correctly
and things like that we haven't checked
out yet ok congestion window reduction
so TC peas are expected to cut their
sending rate in half ok when on each
packet drop and this is essential to the
stability of the internet that TCP is
reduced their sending rate when they
encounter congestion which they find out
by experiencing a packet drop ok we are
about 6,000 or test from the prop
stylist and the way we did this was we
let the sender window reach about eight
packets and then we dropped one packet
from that point onwards we counted all
the outstanding packets and that told us
whether the coast reduced its condition
window correctly ok i'm happy to say
that about 99% of the hosts are
nevertheless did reduce the congestion
window properly ok but there were some
about 72 hosts ok for example the one
said adobe.com and zdnet com they did
not reduce their congestion window they
went from eight to seven which is seems
to be kind of strange on the other hand
there is a caveat here I ran this test
with ms s100 because I wanted to make
sure that I have enough packets to do
this test ok and I'm not sure whether
that influences the behavior so we are
going to work with this more and see
what exactly happens here is a quick
plot to see how we did this test so on
the right hand side you have the USB
port or comp lot ok well the window was
correctly read it now look at the first
dark back at which we drop around point
six seconds ok from a window of about
eight packets they were coming back ok
so the x-axis time the y-axis is the
highest white carrot in the packet so we
drop the eight-pack ok and as you can
see it sent four packets without getting
any further
that were that were so this so basically
what that means is that it reduced his
congestion window at that point from
eight to four okay the other graph on
the other side you can see that after
the first packet was dropped it sent
about seven packets so that's incorrect
behavior okay so this is what we have
found and it would be interesting to see
what OS this is why they are doing this
whether this has got anything to do with
the MSS that we are using and things
like that selective acknowledgement
selective acknowledgments are now
available through most major operating
systems to linux I think all versions of
Lin moves of the versions of Linux that
are out there windows 2000 windows 98 I
don't know about Windows 95 so we ran
about 136 test from the Hot List and we
found that forty-two percent of major
posts that are out there they are not
stack hay river so for example Netscape
com cnn.com none of them ransacked and
of course sac is a bidirectional think
in the sense that both client and the
server have to be able to do it before
it takes effect okay what's worse is
that many of these fat capable host the
fifty-eight percent was that actually do
claim that they do SAT they don't seem
to do it correctly so we'll see how okay
so we're at about 2,000 test from the
proxy list to see whether the stack is
used correctly and the test goes like
this we let the window reach eight
packets and we dropped 6 and the 8
packet now if sac is implemented
correctly as it should as the RFC says
okay then they should be retransmitted
together but if it's doing the default
New Reno Reno behavior then you will see
only retransmission of sex which is sort
of a degrading in the performance okay
and this is this was a very surprising
is that we found that only about six
percent of the hosts on our test did the
sack correctly here is an example so
this is only X again on the x-axis here
at the time y axis here the sequence
number one of the graph shows that the
stack is correctly used so as you can
see the packet
sequence number 600 and 800 there drop
and they are immediately retransmitted
right there and they're both
retransmitted together so that's the
correct way the sack is used because the
sender is able to infer that those two
packets are lost on the other hand if
you go to the default New Reno behavior
then sack info is ignored package 6 is
of course retransmitted because of the
accumulators because of the cumulative
acknowledgement number but nothing after
that it's resent again ok so one of the
other tests were implemented was
explicit congestion notification ok ok
one of the other tests was explicit
congestion notification this is a new
standard it's as far as i know it's
available only in linux 2.4 ok and you
can it's i think the default is that is
disabled you can set it unable so easy n
is negotiated in some sense during this
cynic exchange ok so the tcp that is
running on an easy incapable horse sense
to flexi WR and ec in its end and it
holds the other end if it's willing to
do easy and it responds by setting ECE
flag ok we need which checked about
26,000 votes from the proxy list whether
they behave correctly and we vote for
what we found was surprising most of the
time if this is the flag that are set by
the client the server just ignore them
and everything is fine but eight percent
of the web servers that are out there ok
this simply dropped any syn packet that
contains gwr or ec flag which means if
you are a linux 2.4 user you are unable
dcn because you want to be a good
citizen and suddenly eight percent of
the you know web servers out there it
would be unreachable the problem it
turns out at least in some cases was
with some local cisco local director dag
scales and actually work more on this
and its effects has been posted on some
of the news groups of the cisco web site
we don't know if some of the hosts tags
themselves have problem dealing with the
facts but that's the story so far
okay TCB flavor what are the what exact
what exact congestion control algorithm
that is used by various deputies that
are out there whether they use Reno or
New Reno or tahoe this is when they do
not use that and we found that about 61
percent of them use New Reno 21 / 2
percent used Reno and the rest of the
test for this it's somewhat complicated
if you are interested i will show you RL
where we have a detailed set of results
and explanation and how everything works
okay interesting thing is we found that
some Microsoft servers and I literally
mean Microsoft service www.microsoft.com
we found that they took time out on
every packet loss for smaller transfers
so we talked to people at Microsoft and
they found a bug and apparently a fix is
in the works in the next version of
Windows 2000 or service pack something
like that so we're just going to skip
this graph here okay there are several
difficulties when doing this test okay
for example as we saw to test whether
the server and stack correctly you need
at least 14 pack okay now if you want to
run it against any arbitrary web server
the only page you can be sure of that
the web server will deliver is the root
page okay and this might not be large
enough to give enough packets to do the
test so maybe we can use smaller MSF but
does this create other problems do web
servers respond to different sized
segments different they shouldn't but
maybe some of the results we have seen
our could be artifacts of that so we are
working more on that if packets are lost
at random places while we are conducting
the test then our results might be
incorrect and the only protection we
have against it is we run the test
multiple times and hope for the best
look at the graphs also of course so you
can have multiple hosts answering the
same idea is sitting behind some kind of
a PCP sprayer or something this might
you non reputable results and I'm not
sure how to handle this actually and we
do not of course know any easy way to
test without a web server it would be
nice if everybody ran some kind of a tcp
data center and some kind of a TC beta
testing but of course
nobody will do that so future work we
intend to extend this tool as sort of a
full conformance checker for PCP it
would be nice to use this to generate
automatic simulator more models so
people can test their TTP's in the
simulation environment we plan to extend
this approach to investigate other
behaviors of Internet infrastructure I
would I would love to get more
suggestions from the audience what what
we can do for example some kind of DNS
testing and we would at some point of
time if we find a run and map so that we
can present this results in correlation
with what OS is there and finally all
the source code detailed results and
draft report are available people are
welcome to download the source code play
with it modified and please let us know
what you think thank you very much give
any questions well have you looked at
offered window sizes from chicopee
service from web service offered window
sizes um yes I mean the the maximum
window size the thought I know know that
we are not looked at that but that would
be definitely an interesting thing to
look at yes because I have noticed that
even like large high bandwidth streaming
content like Christie a galera video
clip at one megabit per second also get
offered on service with very low window
sizes so that the the theoretical reach
of those is pretty limited all right it
cannot be received correctly unless
you're 50 milliseconds from the server
also now that's definitely something we
would like to look at thanks
okay so we had work looks too close we
had one more question of this audience
which is that we we want to run and map
because we want to be able to identify
easily what OS has what gtp behavior and
when we identify it we talk to the
person who we know who what's the TCP
for that OS and they fix it how many
people here think that's socially
irresponsible and we shouldn't and map
for that purpose in time many people
here think it is okay and first the
hands of people who think it is okay to
run in mac n map is a scanning is a tool
used by hackers that that if that's what
it says it's mostly use force most eyes
peas won't let you run it in most web
servers treat it as a hostile act and
it's just on the web someone wrote it
and one thing it does it it looks at
peculiarities of TCP behavior what kind
of options are are exchanged to make a
guess about what the OS is it also does
some stuff which is port scanning which
we don't do when we run it which is the
most hostile part of what in that does
so that's why people wouldn't like it
that's why web servers wouldn't like and
that people running web servers wouldn't
like in that to be run they sometimes
send you mail saying you're running in
math against our site why are you doing
that and we send mail back saying well
you know because it's a research and
they usually say okay but one quick
suggestion about that there's a
gentleman and I'm sorry I forget his
name but he walks the DNS tree checking
for you know the same kind of you know
is DNS configured properly different
zones are there is in a ddr DARPA setup
and so forth and he post something to
major less like you know the nanog list
and I net access maybe you know some of
the ISP less that Sparky runs and just
lets people know ahead of time and he's
going to be doing that of course with
DNS the issue is you know he wants to do
zone transfers to check the data and if
you don't open up your zone for him to
transfer it he can't check your data
if you were to post something just to
let folks know you're doing it ahead of
time so they can be on the lookout for
it and know you know when they see if
they know who it is and was responsible
that would probably go a long way toward
you know eliminating some of those
problems I'm actually actually there's a
simpler solution nmap will generally
Jake lot you'll end up with a lot of
complaints if you're using every night
here you can you please we'll end up
with a lot of complaints if you use nmap
just it's probably a bad idea you
probably should use a search engine
situational testing primarily web
servers just get a little search engine
there's lots of different publicly
available ones use that to crawl to get
all kinds of links you'll end up with
all kinds of different web servers and
you can use those for testing and since
all you're making is HTTP requests to
things that are already publicly
available you avoid getting complaints
but if you use nmap that's it's a really
bad idea okay so we have both sides of
the opinion okay if you use and that
will end up with queries from people
like NASA and whatnot it's a little part
of a federal information system in there
you're saying that they have to look
into every potential security you know
incident yeah so into your right yeah so
yeah I mean we have recovered I'm Quran
and I've just do testing we did get
queries from the target of the nmap scan
and most I mean most of the times they
were nice after we told them that hey we
were just you know this is what we are
doing except that at some point of time
the people who run the Berkeley network
started saying well sorry you're not
going to run that anymore so that's the
idea I refer to these as goobers with
firewalls and there's a lot of personal
firewall technology out there and people
don't know how to interpret the results
so since I run a root name server i
often am told that i am attacking them
by sending them UDP port 53 packets
and since I host a box for Casey as part
of the skitter projects I also receive
all sorts of hate mail from people who
don't understand why I'm pinging them so
I'm already immune to reports from nasa
as to how bad on being and if you'd like
a guest account on ISC's shell server to
run and after you're quite welcome to oh
thank you very much