and I'm have no idea why and if you
aren't in the social engineering panel
because France
always extremely entertaining but your
yeah okay good
got rid of one person so at
this will be a somewhat visitors to the
someone said really entertaining things
to look at
in this topic but I'm the only person in
the room was going to get to see them
cell and skin like start my slideshow
and I thank you I'm my you know I asked
the wrong person if it was everything
was all set
the person you should always ask for a
TV people effing
have the commitment to stir some random
guy with the number two badge
I'm book
your now would be a little too much um
so the basic topic here is Ghosn zombies
in the machine which is just a
kinda completely random collection just
things that I find a little interesting
strange but the internet I'm
the this kind of two topics that the
now be focusing on to topic said are I
found kinda fascinating that have
definitely kinda flourished in last few
years
the first one is II
there's no real kind of official term
apart you can
column Wed Kooser zombie pages or
whatever
and it's just the I'm existence if
all the you know you've got what there's
hundreds and millions of blogs now and
there's like
92 exactly although all the pages
and web sites mean sure there's all the
kind of like you know there's the Canada
infinite crafted the
internet in the web where to in there
said banded web sites
mad make you know he's going to slowly
fade away your
just heard existing on the Internet
Archive and stuff but one more
interesting is all these
personal blogs and profiles have all
these people
and then the people died and the pages
don't
and its like this is something that I
came on
to originally when when my friends
and up in Boston gon who is
who 0 of course
this is like a cool down before it's not
I don't think it's the iBook one now
hmm the act but it's a few notes nice in
white
show you know has to have to
completely you know proprietary little
time
FM I'm sure it's somebody here could do
it well the only promises the wireless
doesn't work here soon
you have will mean you have to plug in
the computer to
were on standby power find the where
in money things and new
we could do that I'm
so either way and yeah okay we can I
come up in
we can You Can Am John the presentation
as well I'm
so I think we should give him a roundup
on throughout we see around prize and
then we'll find out if this actually
works
so
what's the actual the I would recommend
that strong you
okay so we're gonna make a little nice
little package and stick it on a fast
track
so that's one topic and then another one
is which is really completely unrelated
except that you could
call it's you know other than the zombie
concept is have
come from zombie army news and we will
be blue
which are just like I you know on the
botnets and
I'm sure there are people here who know
considerably more about it than me
who were here by now I don't think
enemies
really giving a talk about them so you
know I get to be the person doing
for
om and
the in
and those are again Mike Barnett said
you seen
X you know kind extraordinary growth in
last seen a few years and there's can
have
some really interesting stuff going on
with that in Trenton
you know complete multi task here
see you
mmm mississippi interesting
we can
kinda fake I guess so here
really we got that so arm
well and of will be able to show you
these pictures and you can catch up but
I'm so this is my friend Mike I the
Chris Malone to use the super cool check
she had like
you know 100 people 100 twenty-something
friends on Friendster in
Texas is back in I'm mike in
2000 to everybody within on myspace yet
in awesome
were called Sona you know we're not that
fourteen-year-old
I'm 223 said and I
she skin super cool boxing chicken
com was reading her bike without a
helmet not hit by a car and died
and you know and then kind like the
weird thing is is that her friend sir
pages like soon still sticking around
and now so now says that she's 31
you know but does no because two years
have passed by
we wanted big differences between and
Friendster and MySpace
other than the fact that their about
94 million people on MySpace now you
know some
be number approximating that we like in
he was at seventeen million so mean the
the growth rate there is a little
extreme I'm
is that also on profiles on MySpace
Mike its it the default settings that
people can just continue reading
comments in Iran might be posted soon
after you die year your page becomes
like this
you know happy tributes flash people
getting to write mean things about you
when you're dead
I'm and its is really interesting
because like you know the whole space
love how we deal with death and all
these things he's always been for you
know extremely well
om Union modulated by tradition and
culture in convention
you know it's you go to funeral singers
longer the deliberate ceremony and
in in you know in a bitch worries are
written by the same
you know old crusty guys in the
newspapers and they have a very specific
form about what
you know what is it that goes into an
obituary Mike
if you die an interesting way you get
the story about my
you know you get hit you were hit by a
car that fell off a truck
word you were eaten by an alligator for
you
you know hit by a car while you're
riding your bike for you
of you know where some guy few with
nineteen-years-old in
weaved in New Bedford and you hi after
you like assaulted and killed some
people in a gay bar you got it
hi killed in a a shootout in Kansas
on Mike you know with the cops
but the whole point is is that you know
that's kind of where the the story would
and then there might be no
a little bit chewy re that would you
know no dead
you know they door survived by their
their mother or whatever
your cat come but the difference is now
you get to go on their pages and you
see that these people you know were well
like the
the guy who me Jacob roba
was the one who now did a
became a nurse staffing in a New Bedford
about
scrimmages exactly a year ago and
he had you know really appropriate an
MySpace page for someone who do that
news big Insane Clown Posse fan
mom an unfortunate myspace took it down
but unlike some people have archived it
and then there's
been it's a factual if we take a step
back
from the stories and we think about is
kinda statistics
so there's like about you know
approximately 100 million people on
MySpace
and you know they're mostly in their
kinda 15:02
you know forty marine even less but
we've seen on the 15 24 25 to 44 each
group
down were talkin so for every hundred
thousand people
better you know between the ages 15-24
I'm about ninety at them die per year
common sense like 29 cars 18 you know
homicides
12 suicides and then for like the 25 to
44 you get more
you get more aids and cancer and heart
attacks om
this suicide rate actually is higher
when you're
border about over 25 which is
contrasting
but the homicide rate is lower maybe
because you're
dying of cancer instead or something I'm
but
the in with the truck so that kinda
liked when it translates in turn MySpace
users is that means that there's about a
hundred thousand people
we MySpace pages that are you know when
I'm sure not not all of those
94 million actually active by in and
then he's back a hundred thousand people
with
MySpace pages are dying like are dying
this year's a hundred
you know hundred thousand in the site
the pages the reason
on the site right now her for dead
people and scents like about the 1000
per month
more 27 per day about you know ten
people during this lecture
ten eleven people you know approximately
will guide
yes we're going something
few and I I don't know I just kinda fine
exam with fascinating that
you know there's this to see infinite
well dead people
I'm Nexus gonna popping up with all the
really bad backgrounds and
and their back then you know their
musical tastes and stuff
and NCED be used while however hopefully
when we get this out
if we do I can show you some of the the
more interesting pages
I am and there's actually right now
there's one guy who's
compiling these he started my death
space
about a year ago has a really sweet love
you Tom
and he has about like you know 400
posted now
mean you know and so we're talking Mike
this minuscule proportion
I love them and he has this huge backlog
like have people submitting
the pages and thank you you need
cock hook them up to acting in an
official bitch wary
and links to the profile and can and
does it without comment and then there's
like a form into
some people like haha this is for you
know this guy was such a fucking retard
I mean you know in like when you kill
yourself by climbing into a helium
balloon
Mike you know you shouldn't do things
like that
wake baby at least day the people who
did that
there was a and I this outgrown a guy
down enough or if they did it together
cell I mean you know I think you know if
you can make yourself known
dumb way you should do it with someone
else because you know
you know the number you like out you
know at least
someone outside with system
rain exactly I mean like you know be you
know in a it's with kinda fun things is
that it's
you you could think if this is I'm
making people talk more frankly about
suicide in about the dangers of like the
choking game
which is you know where I guess you I'm
hang yourself until you start choking
and then
if you you know we hope we don't die
time
but sometimes you do and then you get
and people get to look at your myspace
profile
I'm and the
well and then I can find info on what I
would do his own
kinda fast forward to the next topic
and we meaning yeah if you see stars
working
who that's looking like your screen
that sweet we can take a look at
summaries profile pages
0 and there's one that is really spooky
the girl got you by an alligator
Mike the day before nor actually like
the day that she died I'm
back and oh okay I mean I don't know she
was beaten by the owners whose attacked
and killed
by you know they use their mounts him
%um
the I
the that day before the she wrote a
little
into your blog how she'd woken up
you know in sheep in my conflicting with
her boyfriend
and she watching porno
I can after to ban them and freeing
I'm film
sweeping you can
going
our I'm
game makers you know I unika
now there's not really any excuse Penn
with from my computer
I'm fee no that's right that's what I
wanted to make a
II and the PowerPoint inward
because it's a macro PowerPoint file
your
the okay so well this is just a with
Cisco to the web and we can look at them
myspace zombie pages
be we're who track to do that
and may who was fifth woo
month I'm
soon
well it's probably different now like
you might have in order
version implication which case
I mean I could if I'd saved to thing
on but
the
I'm
if you actually from Nepal ko web page
we can
once a week in this time Brunswickers
do some stuff
summer
okay and the connection time to answer
networks
kind of hammered I think
arm so the other topic
that guys been looking at is
can have zombie networks the
whatever's on the Army's by nets and
thats you know him really all it is is
it's
and I can if hi illegal in on
hmm intentional distributed computing or
it's completely intentional on the part
of the people who are taking over the
computers
but the you know
the people who computers they are
generally don't know
that like their their cycles are being
used for
either you know illegal gain in profit
I'm
in its kinda been if you look at canada
buy the comparison
%ah like the biggest
widget in man distributed computing
project is study at home and
like it Scott about 5.2 million
participants
and so that's what work fast unit
performed
has performed on September 2000 26 2001
form a total 1,021 floating point
operations is acknowledged by the
Guinness World Records as large as
competition history
with over 900,000 to his 5.2 million
participants but
900,000 computers in the system an exit
or you can get over 250 teraflops
nance I can serve April 2006 where he
said blue jean
like the supercomputer nets at 200 PD
so that's you know senate like that's
pretty
pretty badass of course hi you know
the funny thing is is that the like them
the the botnet are on the same scale
as as these projects like and there's
what more well an author's want more by
what's
you know kind of work which assume that
they're there probably are
I there was one I'm
relatively recent case where
in the Netherlands where this I'm
guy who's like a nice these three people
I'm
when 1922 in 27 were arrested
for network that you know their prefer
said was like
a hundred thousand and and they said it
was like 1.5 million
but noted some kind of completely fuzzy
unknown very large number because
seminar thing is is that
the computers just keep on getting
infected infected arm
beyond the he was the the Houston the
TOC spot
Trojan which the install the Nissan
adware and spyware and the
on did ninety denial of service attack
on this US company
I'm T in extortion attempt because they
were like we're gonna
we're gonna take your website down if
you don't you know don't pass out in
in pairs happen and I you know to find
one time I am
but gonna get arrested so shipped
and they also like fish
Pay Pal account YouTube a.m. like you
know I'm
I'm not sure you I was able to see %uh
find out what what
cool stuff made by but you know it's
is when those things that about half the
time
the these are like there's a day
i mean you know if prongs like from you
know most criminals only
you know think really a flick you not be
big enough like
if you can do this if you know how to do
this like you
you know it so me a small flip to figure
I had him
make millions dollars like you know
legally
um you know and if it's kind of like the
West enough
you know governments in on the other
hand like
see mean you know working for the NSA is
what
high school so I mean like
what talks by did is that it's you know
it will all these things do is that they
just use kind of
known when does exploits on
Mike this one uses American a sequel
server
privilege s escalation deal well buffer
overflow and I i
just they just use known patched
Windows on Boehner
abilities %ah goin' Mike
he saw themselves and open on back door
on I and Jim basically
to start contacting
IRC various IRC channels
on Micon on different network said
and different you know ok servers that
have generally
can be I'm using names Micah
missing Mike you know on martian song
dot com and
my secure name dot com things like going
for Mars dot com
you know it's likely website and
the time
and and you know in in in the venue just
launch
I various attacks in there pretty much
mean is always
some profit motive some 100 on with what
I've
with a lot of stuff I am and
do you mean like I've kinda been in with
there's a growth in
the I'm hey say
McKenna for are organized crime doing
things
in mafia send it to you want to be a
pretty much
you know it's definitely majorities
overs overseas surgeon is found as
outside the United States om
and the Mikey you know another variation
ways is our like another group was MOOC
now like MW Tim 20 P
which is like a behind the lawn was a
63-year-old inning when a 28-year-old in
Scotland next year old in Finland
om and the wrote now recuse
Trojan which was actually based on the
Sony rootkit said
making a and in like in the Union
got like a fifty thousand computer
botnet
com and Suzi chin units on each
and I i think you have to give them
props for basically
creating the mean because
there's actually relatively widow and
investment in
at creating new
new malware new the the new software
most the time
it's just people taking the code in
tweaking a thing or two and Sue sony did
a really good job
you know paying cokie campaign companies
to do the real innovation
to find new attacks and of course no the
reality is that company
be you comp store Batcave stop their own
state
there are only two but the United a the
I really do think you should give Sony
credit
for advancing the botnet field
I'm and in getting away with it which is
pretty cool
10 agassi they had to give away some CDs
on which and I think they were like
Kelly Clarkson sound mean
you know who wins really ir
the and you know when they were just
doing it to your liking
d generate spam quick threes and minutes
is this whole thing this is like
if you've gone a hundred thousand
computers a control
your you can do the things that only you
know generate a few thousand bucks a
month
and you know it's it's pretty cool I'm
speaking you know you're a kid like cure
cancer with the
and he would do its in mint stuff arm
but it's you know it's
its not generally huge money except for
the time
but they can also do this is they do one
key walking
a huge fishing for like credit cards
and stuff i mean so he needs to am sure
Steve Graham BAM had been arrested he
would have been talking about how
like you know everybody has all view
credit cards
um were not necessarily the people in
this room before
because we're smart in WI we use
on proper security protocols om by
you know in a general sense Mike tears
you know I if it's being used to be
you know if you've if you've ever
interacted with anything with a Windows
machine
you know electronically you know you can
assume that
you know there's no real reason at that
date is
close down I'm the
group that I've gotten along so I one is
give some credit here something I wanted
this information has been coming from
shadow server which is in
volunteer organization that pretty much
II does all the things to try to you can
have track
and you have the tools to take down
views
on patents the Brian
on based set up and run honeypots
were day you know create
just aggressively open computers that
are just thinks he's in fact me
and then they you fat to track people
they also regular weekday also
investigate the software themselves
so the you know when they get good the
new I'm
when they get infected they go through
in like that
you know in our separate from what the
antivirus companies are doing
I am they also track
v these botnets which is 10 km most
interesting things and so
and they create a list I
running west various kinda pic
command-and-control centers
cell all these by Nazi have there's
some IP address that all these computers
are
Mike being controlled by and
doing and so it's the in like you so
wanted the kind of
v %um things that you can do you
and as their as a civilian if you are
don't want you know if you want to
protect in kind
fight the things is in the same way is
that they have in well actually these
are
not these are often a strong overlap
we age arm the with spanner
networks in other words these you know
you have your gonna black out miss
open relay servers I E they're also
these black
the source shadow server must create a
black out west
combat net control centers and you know
some users can if it's you're not going
to win
the game by blocking out the sites but
its
it's something that I'm you know he
gives you you something
of in age and
then they also worked with
the private companies and with law
enforcement to try
to you on track and then only and that's
it wanted in with that
kind there other mean group
use I'm tracking
the information that gets captured so
Mike whether or not some credit card
number has been compromised but what do
what these with the credit cards and
passwords and accounts
are that being compromised so they're a
definitely a very
kinda interesting grey hat group am your
white house
dead has farted no bad information
some whitehead's they're not bad people
home and actually the do they've works
baby the people
now have worked the best with them
everything's like the secret service
actually care a lot because the secret
service handles
Madonna Mike
federal monetary transfer stuff
banking fraud and v
in so they've kinda found that if we
look at the botnet statistics
about half of them on are just
onto now service-related kinda like so
the dumbest
I think he just a button a doozy 27 all
hammer
some sites simultaneously I'm about 30
percent in them
I do you do like adware spam
Mike so they'll step install adware no
send out spam
home in about 20 percent are just die
doing
Mike spreading Justin involved in Mike's
I'm growing themselves i doing
keylogging
and you and unless it goes Nana those
classifications are necessarily
exclusive
hot summer the things that they found
her the
how by netzer evolving you know so to
speak is this is that there's
you know and im someone to see the guy I
was talking to is
thing that you do not users is not
fundamentally interesting I mean it's
like its kinda the same PC software
being run by people
who want you know they're not doing it
to create are 24 Union
dude just infecting computers and then
Mike typing day the commands in their
little liar see
channel to have them you know going do
something
and so it's you know it's kinda code
monkey stuff but
v so the innovations are basically in
avoiding getting caught
Tom and doing things like running the
command control centers like from your
PDA
com more you know to accuse hang out at
a coffee shop in
and doing things like that arm and
there's also
more use it encryption I they're
starting to move away from
now I to susan RC their multi-server
I'm scene sees since the command in
control
and so that's one those are the types of
things that they're
on a their tracking and you know in
seeing
I'm and then so working you do
hands to kinda avoid
getting you know becoming a zombie so
II which is don't let people use your
brains
through number Mike if they don't have
the earrings is have to bite you
right second standards on beefing
rain rain you well so don't do that now
and stone
do anything said Mike was it like mister
scheck exercises
helps I think so but for your computer's
it's the it mean in some satellite it's
just the basic thing just keep up with
the patches
II you have your anti-virus software to
Phnom Penh strange email
consider a you know that they can have
the basic things that
like if everybody did it would be a lot
better
arm now secondly I
using and an Internet detection system
likes nor
time you know is is a very good idea and
those would also like there was some
those that software will often include
kinda like the botnet rule sets michael
is a botnet set some compiled by
group on Channel server and they also
have kind of like them
botnet signatures I've you know
the if the network com things
and so like it you when you get up to
your system and stuff
or even I mean your personal computer
like a on a
personal network runner corporate one
you wanna have
proper firewall configuration I'm in you
in egress filtering is I mean if you you
know it's like if you wanna
walk down I your network
is is that you just do it so like you
say even if I'm getting even if I get
infected
Mike computer I'm not gonna let my
computer contact
the the commands Center on
si se Mike you know you started to use
you know is if you block IRC connections
Mike fee your computer can be controlled
through IRC connections even if it or if
it has to suffer even if it's been
Trojans
com and so if you control and the
outgoing connections from a computer yet
from your computer's
you will that's when it kinda the
primary thanks
and then it's also the classic things I
are dead you know change your passwords
yousef don't use the same password for
everything because that's what won the
big things that these
on people do it so describe the
passwords and
you know on something that's relatively
in securing enough to start plugging it
into your day
in paper how and ever in whenever immune
been you like and life is creepy
on offense for right am cliche name
but I do I create the um and you should
do
things like do deep scanning I mean an
hour's like
on do more I mean do a kind about
48 like you know dueled do tried it
before review
iraq's and really pay attention to you
they can if unusual traffic I'm
so can't know what you expected network
traffic is
and when you see something that he use
strange its
you know probably something that's you
don't like
I love course there's also the whole
thing if you
om avoid windows you're gonna be
marketer of I but that's not to say that
bike you can have apartments that are
being run on my clinics in vaccines
because
um even if I'm the
their operating system doesn't have
basically
and he X you know exploitable
you know on our ability to serve on a
reset happen exported
if you're running say had you know
your PHP bulletin board system II
like you then if there's any in in this
is I'm not speaking entirely
hypothetically
and there was this I'm PHP now I've own
ability that was exploited and so there
was this network does
I'm using Mike the
Unix and and and no están
computers in running on them and so
that's
it is like
you know if you can basically be smug
about it like if you're
you know if you don't use Windows calm
but
you you know at some but that doesn't
mean that you won't actually ever
I'm get infected arm and so
kinda shadow servers here's a little
kind description unkind self description
from them so its shadow server .org
I am there they're kinda admiring
channel on IRC
and they're on freenode and it's on
shadow server not work is the channel
om and the couple
botnet in malware research with
gathering of intelligence sharing and
feed it won't be an open source
community
in building reports and data-driven
block with us we do work directly with
law enforcement in that gives us
another unique angle our team members
are from all over the world most are
us-based
but they have a good presence in Europe
and Australia so it's
United week I'm and their
internetworld I'll its this is where
I I think my my friendlier
am you know computer cover escaped
so now I if
at Chateau server they have 9 you it's a
it's easy it's a fun site to deceive and
kinda poke around on because
they have to wear civis the botnets
their tracking
om and I the
they have with the tickets and each one
has like
mike in need what've
them dispersed the there with the
specific now where was
that arm that originates a botnet
and so they picked it up either into
what they do is they clinton when they
first it
find botnets usually through another
botnet when one other hi honey pots
or if it orphan Makino arm
to skydive I tries to infect them hmmm
you know where they gonna get you know
as they get an email with it and so what
they do is they
md5 hash now where I'm classifier
according its function put that up on
the ticket they've so they put the hash
up this offer I am and the
take the in this is kinda fun things is
they
put up the the CNC dialogue that takes
place on their kinda IRC channel that's
using it
arm and it so like you know for example
like one ticket you think I R C barnett
looks like an ordinary nun
IRC chat session except that it's like
the they're not you know kind talking in
people with
it's more like looking at you know where
a file-sharing
IRC connection
and think they have something like their
topic for dinner 666 channel
like you know because that's kinda great
thing about these issues said
consider are in honour it's all edgy
arm and hatchery haxor
thank 666 is my computer is my channel
man so
like the command would be like scan
sixty 1.1 Gottex Gottex
om an I'm what it does is a big
it and in that sense that command out to
all the P on the computer in the botnet
to start scanning
on the United star port scanning I sixty
1.1
arm and then once enough machines are
found
the now where is downloaded to the
victim machine and
you know executors accused for execution
upon the Next Food
Combat Machine is now part a botnet
and the same channel commands will work
and so its kinda a he that is when the
fun things this is that you really do
get this
home you know the the Nets came into use
my software
knees the sanction they work well om
and you know and that's kinda what they
do but
see 26.0 we go
so that's in many ways live kinda for
the prepared text i half
there be more and foreign rice at it
they are pretty pictures
because you know it's especially of all
the
the MySpace pages because you know me
you know it's sad when the nice people
die and there are some people that you
can tell
why beaded home
well I mean you know Mike Keefe you
I mean there is the your like the
like you know I feared if you act like
you're
kinda meh psychotic racist
crazy dude who really likes guy and you
know it has like
use my picture my myspace profound he's
my guy in
and I'm Lake he you know Lake you know
and I hate gays and using the
you know you can you actually can you
can can predict that
I am so I
well material 10 who were you the 50
minutes before the hour so if anybody
has any questions or comments
I don't know if anybody in the eye.
audience has experience with that
but nets I'm under this is a a great
time
to come up and their and your
your two cents film beacon
you come up to my career to
chat I this on
yep I have a 9 experience this early
with them
but thats but I have a question and
combining the idea of
dead P that people's pages on MySpace
and botnets
sure they're about nets they were owned
by people are either in prison or
disbanded or
have gone underground so that would mean
presumably that's
there's a numerous man it's out there
that are not controlled by anyone at the
moment
right and I'm wondering aside from
source routing or something like that is
there a way to take those
over and here I'm will
its funnies it actually is this kind of
like com
through the big problem in the whole
like how do you deal with but that's
because
it's not it's relatively easy dish shut
down there
the command center but its
pretty much impossible to you bad
disinfect
the network Mike I mean the basically
you can kind the best thing that you can
do as you can
arm you can get kind of the general
like a min if you can get eyes peas in
such to you block
you know to ignore the track you know
those those traffic calls by
the computers themselves out there
zombies their gonna always do that
forever
om taking over I think basically the
thing is is that once
went once the network has been shut down
by somebody
I wouldn want to try to take over that
because the whole point is is that
people have already shut it down you
like 12 big dude who used to be running
is in jail
back now I can't really take it over
make
at a known it doesn't seem like the best
idea like by
I mean I don't actually specifically now
by mean there's no I mean basically
there's an knew anybody
likely anybody you could hat you know
who knows so they can at like the
password
arm for I'm you know running the network
you know being the kind you of being
authenticated as the
the owner the channel for example fits
our entire scene
by net then your day your
your the command om be at ninety
basically
it's that type thing months now on the
other hand like I you could certainly
for example I I have a feeling like if
you wanted to you could add go
and you know on your own
try to find other peoples but not for
having been like you know Kat yet and
try to take them over from the people
and you could brick it dates you know
it's relatively easy to start your own
but now it's basically
you denied
okay and
the yeah I know I i mean at some point
through
I mean that's why a if like people ever
start like really in planting stuff in
their heads as you know or think where
you taking over people RF
implanted RFID you know like you can do
them
you know some great stuff by people have
like implanted credit cards
and you know and you can start doing
these things
om a are we at one
you're out well since I'll give if you
want I can do some little
I'm you know dead tree
and no transfers arm so
my dead space dot com is is fun
and sky easy remember I one if
actually when the most interesting I
never really wish I could have called it
up because it's kinda grief
when the speakers at hi h2k
the 2000 hope ways I Chris McKinstry
who is this guy who on with running the
the mind pixel on mine pixel general
artificial consciousness project
in which he was like in people like type
in little things a little statements
that are either true or false
news compiling this like data and the
scene
this whole list what people
you can about the general knowledge of
humanity and it was all going to be
compiled into this kind of like you know
artificial intelligence that would have
this emergent intelligence
om in he had been Mike working down
in the radio telescopes down in
South America and helping to Mike
discover supernovas
things on unfortunately try
he was kind of like and you know how
many people have you seen a beautiful
mind
but he was kind of like what's his name
there the actor Russell Crowe Union down
ash
um and he a and in he was kinda like
that merits he was he was
was somebody who was genuinely very
smart but he was also completely crazy
om and so the
at the mine picture projects with very
much kind of like masses
little II conspiratorial jottings where
the the information coming in and you
know it's all real minutes you know any
really was compiling into a database but
there was no
Michael artificial intelligence Mike
what do it it
all we do is kind of like two-thirds the
time he would guess yes
and went through the time would say you
know Institute there's a time and say
this is a true statement
and one you know through time with this
is awesome was known
there was no intelligence no you know
parsing this
and II it in
2000 for
I believe he i wrote
non might suicide now he said this is
what an online suicide note looks like
me had various quotes about you know
killing yourself
from various I speakers com and
and Mike the next day he did om and
II its Syrian the
like you you know and it but now some
unfortunately so and I actually found
out about this because I was like
can if looking up some we're all day I
stuff in aid you know
bookmarked in camp on this and I quit
wait a second you
you know makes I read the blog wait a
second this is a little weird
and then now I you know internet he'd
kill himself unfortunately they like the
that like that page has been taken down
but it's been archived
com and
said there's so there's in a and in and
that is one of the things is like a lot
of the things fade away
and it's quite possible that my spaces
%ah been i win you know it its
a good bet that within the next five ten
years or less than that
myspace will have a whole division of
people that
you know when home institutional policy
for wise policy about how to deal
with the profiles people who've died
om you know like in Michael B
hi it'll be probably a standard thing
the prettier Mike wheeler
you know next attorney or something
really like you know in since
missus big thing because most people who
are 15 don't have wheels but they have
what MySpace pages
I am so at some point like when you
create your
you know your myspace profile you're
probably be asked to fill out like a
provisional will
tonight transfer electronic assets to
you you know I
you know what your electronic you know
World of Warcraft myspace et cetera
next two cannons com and
and then all you know and then like this
this agents on the school
sadly fade away
and would just be left with people more
nicely buried
I guess that might be a good place to
end the talking with but we have time
for like one or two more questions
but otherwise I will thank you all
fact okay get one
affect question as just wondering what
your take is
distributed computing way to
for cancer said would
might do any capabilities at those
companies
well I mean there's def wanna I mean
there's real
stuff is mean that's any project
is well it's also it's a good example
I mean you know like it's a kinda
probably quixotic pursuits happen
I'm but you know the but but like yeah i
right i mean but on
things that is kinda like on problems
that are no
nope we doable with like you know by
supercomputers like protein folding
arm and like you searching through
I am genetic materials I mean there's
absolutely no redeeming disturb you can
get if they have
essentially as long as it's the right
kind of task they have
essentially equivalent power arm you
know
traditional supercomputer om
there are like unfair
kinda cutting-edge research if I grid
computing
arm where in when it kinda ironies is
that
its the the Internet ARPANET
I coulda the carpet was originally
designed to as a distributed computing
network like the idea that people would
use the network to communicate with each
other
was not what it was about is about
sharing
use time sharing about sharing resources
on the on
having the computer share the resources
so you'd have effectively
I'm a more power for computing grid and
that you know viene academic research
an approach has has never stopped om and
but the now what that will end up being
you know 5 10 25 50 years from now mean
you can
you make your extrapolations and you
know read William Gibson and
and Eric Drexler and staff and you will
have immersion consciousness is and
Matthew
believe that the human mind is magic in
can't be paralleled
by computers because they're you know
binary or something
by in the yeah I mean like I think
you basically you should have your
computer be doing distributed computing
stuff it's a
it's a a good thing and
mean on the other hand Mike you burning
you know you
using a nerd you're using electricity so
you like eating a better
we're using its all these computers
wearing away
you know by yeah I know it's a good
thing
so abo I think the most interesting
thing there's just that
be Mike by net the
do widget in a distributed computing
world in the by net world
are basically the same size
I'm well thanks a lot and I come again
dishes
like that it's really easy on screen now
you can see it is I quickly sold
guy can you PT on the Mac and TPT male
and is I'm dismay lap on the Mac it just
got it and an extra menu
that
next time when you hear PCP for the
configuration
you can configure everything as well we
really have to stop now
but will take these two questions and I
will stop a question about the
browsing encryption abused or or
something want your ISP still have
records very thing hours at encrypt it
to them to
it you get to think ripped it's a great
you also doing
you starting creeps into the first node
in any goes with it or network
the ice cream social condition