you're about to hear about are fit and
privacy
before that a few programming
announcements later today
1700 we had scheduled exploring just
because the web unfortunately that talk
happen we've replaced it with a sci-fi
talk
have more information on that in a
little bit stay tuned
we've also had to change him become
clogged later today
track a with off the hook will be still
happening there just reversed so
kevin Mitnick tomorrow off the hook
indecent today
then up further ado
should introduce never 76 is a PhD
candidate
computer science he's about to talk to
you about all sorts of things you
probably didn't think goes
with orchid and privacy Arsenal
thanks for the introduction
welcome 2006 and welcome to my talk on
are for the proxy I'm impressed by the
time
thank you for coming I'm costing
PHD's to net University of Virginia and
my
research is in the area of topography
dealing mainly with RFID privacy and
security at the moment
I wanna FT's as intact if as possible so
interrupted anytime with questions saw
if you need clarification
okay and are briefly go over the basic
so far for the ICM that
all the few know what what freddy is
about
so are fitted tax I'll on me because
that was pacify her for the text are
very small silicon chips
attached antenna and is upper right
picture
this so the silicon chip is really only
to
come the tiny like dot
on their lower limit on that
used to be about square millimeter than
that went down to have a square
millimeter nobody really thought we
could
too small I talk to somebody of Phillips
last week day it down to quote the
square millimeter and
and shrinking so is a tiny tiny which
makes them very
sheep if you have a waiver silicon you
can tens of thousands hundreds of
thousands
system one waiver for that one price
we're talking
five cents at the moment a square
millimeter of silicon costs about four
cents
fit onto a quarter the silicon itself
cost you
a sensory itself 5 but that's the crazy
to another reason why these
tax extremely cheap as they don't have a
battery of any salsa
of power on them so that they must be
powered
by the reading device passively pouts
reduction
now which makes them not operates if
there is no reason
run are ready takes a everywhere
who have you use is that this PPS Exxon
Mobil
who have you has an American Express
credit card so
maybe you already have an hour for the
take maybe maybe you will get it within
ex-cop
but All American Express credit card
have it at the moment so
it's getting you pick it is who has a
car later then
2002 all
hockey stick that have protection have
for the texan
so it's it's really everywhere already
and on we'd be read many headlines on
our for the Walmart requires
all this applies to put our for the text
on the pallets
and the packages not on the item's
itself so far that's too expensive
same for the DOD it Department of
Defense
day on concerned with logistics
let's say rough environments Iraq
Afghanistan and a
they won this means that out too through
through more information
I'm deal at major plane ARF Eddie
all that hard to believe they haven't
received all have met but
day they not so much concerned with
logistics but with
theft protection if you can track
everything either
you know when you lost on right and
razor blades that their
the most commonly still good
in the world there are fifty market this
yes is worth close to three billion
already and we're just starting
it grew 39 percent from last year and
is an estimate by some consultant see
agency we
will hit that double-digit billions soon
I'm might focus can
be concerned with our for the privacy
and I already talked to limit on
on are for the back on I'll give you
some more basics as we go along to you
to help you understand I will next talk
about to threats that that iraq
arise from on are fed the use
and well then look into solutions on
the product a level this is not an
academic talk but I'll
try to relate it as much as possible 22
recent
research I'm mainly
and area of protocols well then look
into as the latest
I'm that the physical and the system
level where
more privacy on
issues arise I'm what is the
most commonly thought straighter in our
bodies that's that you carry text that
disclose information about you and if
you've seen any token
are for the product ever you probably
know mister Jones
IRA's through our state security
mister Jones slits in the future where
are for the has been deployed
large-scale
and he carries several are for the text
these are already takes Mikes disclose
information that that
he would consider private-sector on
they everybody who has a scanning device
can can learn
these things about him and a scanning
device Nokia for example already puts
puts reading devices in cell phones so
very soon
everybody will carry an hour for the
reader so
on you could learn that he was the
weekend has a replacement hip
on you could learn about his political
interests by happen
which books it checked out from the
library I'm
a proposal by the European federal bank
with T
on to make Bank Note smartphone fit
resistance through putting out for the
takes and them
safety if you could digitally sign
something put it on the banknote
that's much harder to counterfeit then
the bank note itself
and as are israel's points out this
allows for
extremely efficient marking you
he'd you don't have to guess anymore who
has most money is
probit so all all this information you
might want to keep private
and on what's
what what's the problem with was our up
for the text so far
if you read the number you know what
product it is and that's called the
the electronic product code so usually
are for the text have
96 bit ID thats all they can to take and
submit that
I D that's it super small tip I'm
that the information itself is then
stored in some computer network
and that the product code is broken into
and this is
kinda similar to the mac address these
and that to into a manufacturer id:
that that is assigned to different
manufactures by the PC global
organization I'm and then the main
effect its health can assign product
ID's
that there must a the same for group of
products they like the shirt that size
that color
now and then unique item id: so the
first to be manufactured in productivity
you would find in Baku
but that that last year on them but
that's the unique number so this is
this is what allows for for very
efficient logistics
I'm and having having in like your
rope reader who can you can get to
manufacture the product
at the allows 22 to look that up to
to know that is the bank note of that
that fell you this is the week
so on on this solution to this is easy
and straightforward just don't use
structured identifies
uses random numbers is those two point
into database and
and look up information so that that UPC
code is
is the reason why are for the text
disclose information
now and there's discussion which which
scenario we would you that I'm so the
problems
kinda soul only industry has to you
understand that
there's a second threat of far for the
privacy
people taking so this scenario being
that innocent Alice
roams and some environment and
she doesn't disclose any information
directly we have random
identify so her her for the takes
give numbers out that unless you only
pay
the you don't get information but
the numbers they sustain so different
reading events can be late and you can
you can build the trace of of Ellis
right so
that thats of less privacy concern for
most people
more its its up to it too to see how
this this from
penetrates anonymity but combining this
with other information that is collected
already I'll allows for very good
profiling
and data mining so this information
should be kept
private I'm what and that you
solutions to to that problem just as
many things implemented and proposed so
far
and the PC organization itself has
as to opportunity to kill tax
at checkout time so that the don't give
functional
are for the text to customers 1c what
you sell the take all the good that it's
attached to
you kill it I'm that request to pass
what that has to come from the many
factors for the wholesale to do
retail so that this some issues thereof
key management
other proposals where to just Rep
are for the texan and metal foil I so
physics class tells us Faraday cages
don't allow radio communication I
I'm or you could actively to stop the
protocol in other proposed by Aaron to
mister the block attack where you carry
another tech
that this thats deter to read a its
confuse the reader basically once that
the reader tries to procure ask for
for identifies it it generates
suit attacks and that the readers not
gonna find out anything about you
I'm and then to last up to obviously
it's its array technology so if you just
jam to rate the frequency
its not going away anymore which might
be illegal in most leagues
stations all these from
proposals from
effectively prohibit the use of
profanity
so on there's a trade-off between
comfort and privacy here and as we know
from
how many of you discredit cuts resident
cash
yeah well you decided for comfort right
and
I guess the same would happen without
for the so
people don't want to the text to be cool
people don't wanna wrap them in
aluminium foil or karen has a teapot
so let's look into
what solution three such cases
and here we come to trip up a few
feeling working at
am this scenario now is that we that we
want
detect to respond in a way that you
can't link
different reading events so each time he
credited take
it responds with a different number
that's the goal
I and now ellis's
the reader order that legitimate
database that owns
the tax and Alice
chassis one key with each text search
she has a list of
of keys meaning secrets fine restraints
and every tech has one key
down the techno on being probed
thinking of to to reveal its ID I'm
generates number use once a nonce a
random string
up its again yeah each time a different
strain
on and Jesus hash function the key hash
function that is a function
that you can easily compute in one way
so
given input you can easily compute
output but not the way around given the
output
its almost impossible to get input its
attractive functional one my function
she she generates using her secret P
and that that random number the hash out
and sensed a random number and hash
output over to Alice
who now the Casey outta protocol would
work how does
Ellis now see what
tech generated this response what she
does is she
she uses the hash function was every
possible key on that random number
and sees was a dark match is right so
the first key doesn't the second does so
Ellis knows which which text is talking
to
somebody who doesn't have two keys does
not no one is saying it's too random
booking numbers
one is really random in the hash output
is pseudorandom
I'm there's two problems with that one
being the
unsolved big problem of computer
security key management
how to get the keys on the reader howdy
howdy share control if they've different
authorities need to retake all these
things but
that left aside as the CEP second
problem
I'm in this case Ellis had to do to have
operations
but what if there is more tax
like really more case and we're talking
billions of tax
Ellis would have to do billions of have
has operations in order to
to to find the right XO that doesn't
scale is a problem now
scale ability to to real-world and
academia and research it it looks nice
lot small-scale
but then we talk the point is to Walmart
every item
being tech that's billions Sep that's
the good work I'm
there that the next step to to make
dis same product como scaleable is to
SoCal
30 secrets so the idea now being
we're under protocol several time and
each time remove down one level of dick
of two trees so with a trio of nine
texier
from and the protocol runs twice
so on on the first run we have again run
this public over three keys
we we find out that the public he has
been used
yeah and we run the protocol again find
out satyr
the and now we know that to take we are
probing must
be in the left so I 50 after tree we
don't know which take it is here
we we can run the protocol again and
from
week find it to take that we're looking
for
either this take obviously has to stop
boesky's that has two
to be able to generate both responses
for both around some the protocol
I'm that the scalability is extremely
true
week we don't have real cool in a number
of special operations anymore meaning if
we
billions of tax bill in South Africa
operations
with a look at Red number depending on
the tree structure
good question I'm using
a hash function as we know it like some
md5 facade 01
I'm that's not gonna work that at least
doubles the price
plus much more concerning quarters the
reading
distance because on you have to pass if
we powered it XO
I'm there the the more you compute the
more power you have to get it taken
since it's coming through induction you
have to get closer than
however we might not really needs hash
functions and
computer science sense what we do need
is one way
functions yeah and there's some
proposals how to construct
very cheap one-way functions and so
we do yes we do have a communication
overhead but
it might it might still be feasible yeah
a question thanks any more questions on
their
everybody was me okay an
so did
this product allows us to to scale to
large system
on there is one issue with this protocol
can receive issue
yeah on
we share secrets among several texts so
all
all the left X have to poke you I
that means if you can get the keys
on from the tax and that's not too
difficult for you
you can its silicon
I'm what would you do is you that that
the branching factor
is not 3 its you you can
with a was it real what's like 325
three levels you can scale to billions
of tax so you won't ever get over five
but still then even five is is extra
cost
is five times more memory for the keys
is five times more communication back
and forth
yes so yes there is costs associated
with it
it it's feasible
yet the question is is reading gonna
take longer
well yes it if
if you have three levels up the tree
it's going to take three times as long
yeah I'm said the issue with this
tree other than that Associated extra
cost is
you share secrets among several pics and
so you can extract the keys from some of
the text
and you can if you if you had already
broken attack on the left side and you
could if you see the
and protocol going on you could say
whether to take
is using the public key or not because
you know the purple you know so you know
was that the the keys in the left how so
on of I so so we did some master and
and from looked into
how many keys how many takes you would
need to break
in order to to to get a sufficient
information about
the tax and so how we define information
leakage
as given in this graph is if weekend the
fight that the group of tax
into two subgroups and put every play
if place every taken one of the group
that's one bit yeah
if you fall group that stupid three so
if you could say
male-female that's one bit okay you
could say
male and female and above or below
median salary that's two bits
I'm turns out that this is highly
simplified but
if if you break 20 takes on a certain
assumptions the contract
half of texan have to take San
reasonable I'm attack a scenario
so thats very feasible for somebody who
wants launcher
on large-scale attack
I'm so we're seeing
and what you can do is you can break to
the tree of Secrets into small group
yeah
not not necessarily group of one tech
but small group
and then if you have only one take in
this group in your environment
you can uniquely identified so it's not
really
seeing that take but distinguishing that
take
from every as a take that one think okay
which allows for linking to reading
events so we've seen that
on the product however wherever from
scale ability
a privacy trade-off that's that's not
really
sought through yet what the the best
trees had a
would be if there's another option then
the tree it doesn't look like it
that has been reset going on for several
years now and she's the best that we
have
but might be ho I'm
but still even if we had to protocol
that works not allow
for tracking at all we would still be
concerned with
other levels of an hour for the system
privacy can leave at different levels
and
what an hour for the 0 we first talk
about the physical ever
primacy so from the problem here is that
if you have two different exit don't
want them to be distinguishable because
if there were a you could Lincoln right
on a physical level that's difficult tax
can look very different this is some
text by
Elgin technologies to have extremely
beautiful looking
antenna but all of these texts must
not be distinguishable I'd
I don't see any way in which that would
be possible you just we did some
experiments you
from you send some high frequency on
radio waves basically to detect and he
measured a reflection and absorption and
beloved is textbook
very different and then ultimate
difference this is
a schematic of which and there for the
Welsh
its antenna is sequoias around to ferret
caugh said
think sick attack that is what is in
your car keys
it's more reliable and there's no way
which you can make this
indistinguishable from like a printed
tech
right so big issues was over the privacy
here
nobody really has a solution to that yet
I'm
another level at which we can attack
privacy is the system level and dinner
for the system
looks as this slideshow see
you've already seen the tax on the left
and and the reading devices but
to reading devices it's helpful only I'm
connecting into big a network said that
that the probe suffered began that way
on the reading device gets the number it
has to you to make these if it's so it's
it has two to find database it has to
look up a database
on and and then
get that information on that take from
the database so
the object namespace it it's not only
person my name to the
DNS domain name space service its it's
basically the same focus it
awareness is built on top of two DNS and
how do I want this works as
given is this some dis
3 part identify manufacture the product
that the and
the unique serial number the tech sense
that to the reader
the reader now wants to look up
information on the product
which is thought that the manufacturer
site the unique
information is stored locally so on the
product that put the
discards the that serial number
I'm sense that remaining
piece of information that the
manufacturer the end to protect that the
into the 1s and don't necessarily doing
DNS query
results name to IP address right so
we wanna get an IP address for database
that we can get information from
and it does that by just looking up
which server
its associated with that manufacture id:
and then crowing that server
and and purring what what database is
associated with that product
hierarchical system again for the reason
of scale ability
billions of tax millions of readers if
it is going to be
use so we need something para people
here I'm
the onus is going to point to some
database given the IP address and under
the reader sends over that that identify
and gets the product specific
information
at services what EPC Global envisions
large-scale
systems to look like on here's an attack
on
that the our nasa privacy in treating
attack again ellis's
I'm roaming and attacks are being for it
and now D and the reading devices have
to you going to do
when asked and find a server that
that has the point that then okay so
they get the point that that the mic is
different service different free does my
tooth
actually they they will that they have
to because
for reasons of capability that that's
why we have DNS
eyes capability not me millions of free
disk on Tuesday
the same server so what if now the
attacker
controls this I'm
this server that information to slip up
from
on people see incoming Paris from
different ENSO right so and based on
that
having linking between reading the
cation DNS server
27 knows where alice is its deliver
to Utah for free that information
clarissa coming in from different
locations
and you can contract just face from that
this from dysentery has two assumptions
that
might not be legitimate and real relax
this assumption cent see that the text
so worth
the first assumption being that the
taker dust control one of these
service now it's kind of like please
since
every small manufacturer who who somehow
is involved
without a pretty will need their own
servers so 10+2 thought everybody has
X is 280 can hack into one and
the sex is something is that we can we
can
give Alice attack that that
results to that server that might be
less liked it so we would really have to
22 taca right I'm
really likes those in advance to take on
the INS
in which again Ellis I'm
is carried by reading device
the reading device looks up to
information and CNNs
returns the pointer right for us to do
to decrying
DNS server and then back to the reader
and notice to take place is based on
something that I've seen by
Dan Kaminsky last year who has seen than
for Minsky's talk last year
now where he played around with the NS
on
so what what he did was he bit you the
bill the list of all the NSF
and I'm I mean Aldean so is he just sent
out first to all
IP addresses possible and
look whether there was in DNS server on
what you use this list for was when that
this only
on on the city's at the rootkit and Sony
claimed
this only so few computers infected the
query all these DNS service
all publicly accessible DNS service for
whether
the that domain name of that rootkit
was cashed and its cash flow like an
hour
something maybe 10 minutes that that's
different for different names
so what he found that there's more
servers that that catch that name
then Sony would admit computers were
infected
right so what what we can use this
attack for now
that own that did
once we did resolve another for the tech
was that system I'm the the information
is cash for some
time period I'm on all DNS service
on the way to to the DNS server that
information actually came from
so an attacker can now very different
DNS service for whether that piece of
information
is cash right it's a totally passive
attack be done from
true any computer we didn't help that we
didn't
touch anything to others which is ask
different DNS service whether they cash
that that record
and a scenario could be mmm
say who uses EZ Pass who knows EZ Pass
so they already use are for the
technology active text for
more reading range but let's say that
they would
for some reason start probing arafat the
text for
state governmentally induced
surveillance all
whatever I'm if we
now had their unique car
and the car being four wheels to have
our for the tax already
the car itself may be due model number
if we knew this discard alice is Carter
and easy has passing through each of
these gates would resolve
the name all these tax would just carry
the DNS service
at these locations for was a vacation
these
Fife records right so we could
we could by just sending of you can ask
for is every
5 for 10 minutes no where alice is
driving
okay well
to conclude on
the physical layer there's no hope
whatsoever that we could
ever not to leak any information
text will be distinguishable and if you
only get out
might say to bits breaking the takes
into four groups small ones in the big
ones too wet to send some other groups
you get to princeton
around at the tree protocol we've seen
that chart
you get another 45 its that's enough for
from the tech so
DT's bias Canada and then to system I
okay that's
just very naive to think we can used to
be an ass
for reasons of scale without much of a
change
and on use
are for the on that it will leak
information and
and if you if we only program up front
and
as an hour for the application and then
use infrastructure that exists
that's not gonna work privately
I'm only forces that I can see that
would
and foster for the privacy this three of
them first
would be like a slave ship California
for example
has law legislation this year belief
that
this allows the the use of our for the
and governmental ID's
including drivers license and all that
but it's only for the next two years
and they will reconsider so there there
is hope that lawmakers
understand that the problematic and and
we'll work on that
maybe not pick up on the second force
would be a customer demand
the people say we're not gonna buy
moment anymore unless he
the country is to kill the Texas do
something else to it
I don't think that's going to work with
people don't care
people use credit cards ID
spread this said those that focus would
be on
corporate intelligence something that
many companies haven't thought about it
yet that the threats would be
that say some target employees walk
through Walmart
twice a day scans all that all that ails
Isles for which products they have on
stock
said on they would see you how much they
sold from morning till the afternoon
today they could from get internal
business data
I if companies understand that this
thread Texas
the company's might requested an that
and legislation
I really don't we to two options that I
C that we will get
are for the privacy well sanctuary
so much for your attention and are we
having to take some questions now
what
so multilayer problems for with the
privacy
it seem like third
you know other than the protocol where
there is no privacy
ya at recess so well
on the product to lay out there is no
privacy use it he's a research results
things that
we academia wat one is see
nobody pace an extra sense percent for
that yet
I'm research has not really been done
the other few plus that there is no
office
straightforward solutions to be on Ando
some states are going to using our these
licenses he said consideration am
if this enforcing use things
being consequences for jamming
signals if you do now information
jamming
the same oranges blocking like me
wall blocking it from from you can block
it
what you can also do is from you're not
required
to to have working taken your ID's
European passports I'm from germany mike
has put hasn't
are for detecting it there is
on manufacturing time to put one in that
doesn't mean that once it has bought it
still has to work two seconds off my
wave do a good job there said passports
a valid for 10 years
I I don't believe many are for the text
will
work for ten years the the connection
between the tip and antennas kinda
Prattsville and that's gonna break at
some point so you could just be that
processor yeah those just curious about
that because you know
think if you have a long people
with our readies new pic Singh and
suddenly some ways
harassing look suspicious mmm
best bet that might that might be the
case and that yeah
that the your double check that the
border crossing
if you are for the tech isn't working
properly yeah but
jamming to come back to your first
question jamming is a legal separate
device that operates in these
frequencies
does need some FCC approval
yeah and they won't approve died
any further questions come up here
if you have a question what about the
possiblity
duplicate RFID since forgeries for
got news the on I'm company says
you let that that now use
come yourself if you take the track
everything I the more companies like
Prada
who who wants to put our for the Texans
hand and opposes
anti to it if you make them clone
resistant basically day so far rely on
that not understanding our friendly
technology nobody can make it take that
sends out the same number
sure that can so that's that the issue
of are for the security
you can use the same protocols to
tropical the privacy
I'm protocol 0 that I that I showed you
from not only
0 this allows
tracking it also guarantees security
because you prove that you have to keep
right so
its that there to respond realize
on the secrecy of the key for both
privacy but also for
authenticity yeah so it is it is
possible and privacy
so far seems like the biggest challenge
if you chief privacy
automatically get authenticity have two
part question
first off on the like passive jamming or
having a random number generator tag
are those of are the tax themselves FCC
there to the SEC certified or zone the
broadcaster boxes
the readers that had to be SEC usually
you get a verification whole system
there's there's no company that just
makes our for the text that they're all
always selling the whole package
but said that FCC approval
I'm basically sex was a you
you stay the lower certain thresholds of
rate radio ways and since that reading
device
last out lot of energy and to take on me
response very very silent
that there's no way in which you could
build and nor for the take that
doesn't get FCC approval yet so if
you're more concerned with
with reading ranges and making the
reader s hopeful
and the second question it was about the
encryption systems
I error checking that's going to be cut
throwing a lot of problems if you have
to if they're not getting
accurate back from attacks here
the readers are yeah all sorts of
problems Eric taking
I'm in most and that's that's that's a
level below to product a level
like that data link layer which then
again hit me
information that there's a problem there
sure yes so you would
you would but some rid read them and
Seanad
submit some of its to make sure its
understood well
questions about the power ring system
%uh I think they plastered with RF and
minutes rectified in a in the
transcripts
of that DC power from the rectified
right stuff
is is there any frequency range at the
youth
that's common 4424 the place I think the
EZ Pass issues use 900 megahertz
there is tax that use 900 megahertz more
common is certain point five six
megahertz
thats thats to I so
for the info for three standard that
Phillips entries
basically I'm the that the trade-off
was low and high frequencies is
to the higher you go in your frequencies
I'm that the more costly attackers
but that long after reading my interest
so the cheapest
takes the ones in the car key for
example they use
125 killer but they only
that they must only be extremely close
posted a review you stick the key into
T you're driving right so you're talking
few centimetres that
in the 900 megahertz range we had about
meters that we can achieve
we have seen the the 17
into it in there if the card then f8c
cheaper
is done by the
need infusion and the manufacturer and
the sarin number so
the verification is done via the DNS or
whatever
X there no sees them okie for polluting
the that's sort of the
X they're not check for to about the the
is it even possible to have larger
feel older in the cheap itself for so
further data aretha only
readable not write a book can be used
without
and the extensive that it that is
certainly possible
what we see for example rings isolate
what these in the larger baku taan 128
minute when they can store also
expiration date or whatever inside
without an external
that is certainly possible that do so
so-called contactless smart card
solutions so you have a big chip
usually the credit card something and he
you get really close to read %uh so
there's no
no problem is powering they have up to
64 killer
by of of beta stories so in applications
such as public transportation
invaders a actively sought Unitech if
you get
like it transportation cut from Tokyo on
became you can see a record of two lusty
away where you
got onto the metro and where you left
and that's not even encrypt it's
everybody can't
image so you got that but it's expensive
we're talking twenty dollars I 441
maybe 530 but not ascent never do you
ever see a point where
the computational power on the chip is
able to keep up with
Moore's Law just normal PC I'm
in cases like the Johns Hopkins work on
TI Houston Texans
pass yeah where there's so little
computing
are under the end-user crappy
proprietary algorithm forty
key modern PCs are now able to build the
table
possible lookups for tag noted good
question
I'm the most law is certainly ballot for
for all silicon including our footy
takes meaning that every 18-month
you get twice as many transistors for
the same size
what Waterford manufactures do now
different right they they take the same
number of transistors
for for a smaller package quote quote
holler yeah amputation power
is the country's was we might hit some
some
lower limit that where handling of the
of two tiny tiny takin if to if it had
to contend that you have to pack it all
that that's
that there's phillips's also that say
there floating techniques were with it
chip
loads and some liquid to contend in this
handbook
itself that that cool headed lower limit
once you hit that limit you come
bill smaller and most law kicks in again
then you get twice as many transistors
for the same price
yes at that point we can't put more
sophisticated security
and i'm just wondering if they're ever
going to reach a point where
are a pretty chips are able to give you
this
certain level security is required not
be
like Atik six years later after the
deployment system
yeah it seems UK
you can you get more longevity in any
case
and are afraid to take us to the complex
kitty
on on the order of 5,000 gates at the
moment
and there's an implementation by to
University of cops and
Austria that bills and a yes pfeiffer
with three South Gate C if I sell ready
and you at another 3,000 you a YES on
the tech
so that we're talking half
of more cost fifty percent more now that
is certainly possible yes
absolutely fascinated
number village idiot on this topic arm
but I'm wondering about connecting
improvised explosive devices to reading
RFID
is so I wanna blow up every Buick
LeSabre that passes or
every M-one tanks where are we on that
I'm
the American press but as far as I
understand it
I'm doesn't mean they I'm access control
so the reader doesn't have to prove its
legitimate
and no but I'm talking about automobiles
automobiles okay so
an improvised explosive device is
something that blows up the tank as it
goes past
so where are we in relation to be able
to read specific RFID
from the side of the road so that all
the american effort to put logistics
information to its vehicles is in fact
empowering the enemy I
reading range is typically I'm
to me this for foremost commonly used
texan
logistics four years same
that they that the radio
characteristics don't change we might
tweak it a little bit better antennas
all that may be 34 meters but
the the company's frequencies 13 points
%uh megahertz
they don't know so it's not a major
threat at this point well there's a
thread
as I said passports that this right
being that it deployed bomb somewhere
and
wat 2 a.m. an American War spy having
America 0
yeah and you
again arm now to an evil side of my
brain
I've always wondered the possibilities
in
you're talking about kill codes on tax
an thank the couple seconds on my quiz
kill anything like that the
possibilities just
overpowering tags: blown out the caster
on
with something a backpack mounted
battery transfers 0 click
and your territory systems dipped
easy yeah keep text very easy
with devices that don't get FCC approval
but
that you commit other crimes anyway and
it does well some like that
yeah know it's it's easy you can easily
overpowered him you need like a
maybe 15-20 what sender
and you kill X that they could become
for measures to that if that
that became the huge threat vandalism in
like wal-mart
than that day that they say anything in
the gap but close enough
that the only countermeasure really
would be to have a
resistor on the take that could burned
extra energy
projects with the cost for tag just its
resistance sex with hot to manufacture
in silicon see if you don't wanna
put and external transistor we have been
doubling the price
to and and even then wasting their
the rate if weakens the extra however if
you don't wanna destroy you take with
means
you create he tried so you overheat the
tag and then it breaks
after minute just not in a second that
there is really no good it kinda measure
that that would protect
tech
that was basically my questions are but
a moving onto
temporary I countermeasures to exposing
your privacy
you mention wrapping in for oil
as one type arm
are there any others that you can share
are how much
does it take to attack for example a
credit card from
sending its signal outcome you have to
what types in sales with your when
could you put are rapid Lori in the case
of the credit card
after that the Harvard you take this
just in addition I've never seen a
take-out
I'm not work I could actually pay as a
den at ExxonMobil
session so if you don't want to
functionality and it just comes with it
then microwave again
but if you if you really want to
functionality but only sometimes
you wrap it for that that's the only
solution I'm well
to Justin fireworks and any
any metal any metal yeah and buy/sell
on that they sell wallets that have a
metal
oil in it already yeah really
I was just gonna plug they're downstairs
to a boat over
loading a in their FA the time is 10 for
the thug
will eventually AP Israeli tweak the
the light air or whatever
cool the them as it without the
externalities can use in a
in the the israeli 3 the the light
because the is have it generates
know a lot of the the radio noise
all around can be the Angels over to see
use in that way so and
needed having you it's a little charges
near
the the cheap why can eventually
as he was asking for you without using a
for portable microwave on unlikely
unlikely that devices that are not
suppose to
to emit radio waves but that just do it
anyway like computers
they have much lower threshold on
on committee privacy on a meeting radio
so if if reading device can survive
an RFID if the Aphrodite I can't survive
are for the reader
it can certainly survive all external
noise yeah
any more questions
well thanks a lot for the discussion I
was