welcome everyone
is hope number six Saturday
officer 1400 that means it's time for
the keynote
number 92 apparently redesignated
michael Hart will be talking in a minute
have one quick announcement to make join
erection
author of harking hacking the order
exploitation will be at the Hampton
2 p.m. which is now signing books and
he'll be there for as long as their
books so don't be rushing to get there
we r about to hand over
arm so we ask without further ado
as long as you only think it's that good
after its over okay
everything I'm gonna say after this
is just bells and whistles this is the
important part I'll say it again at the
end
I'm here to try to help you save the
world
your hackers
and I'm gonna ask you to find
every ebook in the world that you can
get your hands on
and send it to us and if you have
trouble finding us
you not real hackers I'm heart at PGL EF
.org
and he's GV newbie yet PDF tower
.org in a bunch of other things and PG
lief in case you needed the monikers
Project Gutenberg Literary Archive
Foundation
for you okay
now what we want to do is giveaway
as many e-books to as many people as
possible that's that's the whole game
okay
and I'm asking you to help because we
have just grown
so far out of proportion will drive you
crazy I mean
use like him area and i cant talking
point at the same time
on this is the manger idea
I'm hopin
that you can think so far outside the
box in making this go
that everything we ever did before we
look really small
so far we've given away about one and a
third trillion he walks
and I want to make that mark tiny
really really time Sao
that's the goal almost did you know that
there wasn't much in the way literacy
before Johan Hedberg the printing press
effect
the average book before gutenberg cost
as much as the average family farm
and the literacy rate was probably
less than one percent what somebody
wanted information to get out they put a
poster up someplace
and the one person in the village you
could read
read it everybody there was a general
way that things went
in the next 50 years
after the invention of the gutenberg
printing press more books were printed
then in all the previous history in the
world I'm hopin
that in the next 50 years more evokes
will be created then they were ever
books in the whole previous history in
the world these are mission statements
the pretty simple pretty straightforward
and
most important part is you I'm hoping
you can help me find
all the books that have been hidden away
lost different sites that went down if
you come through alexei dot com and find
someone to the old backups or anything
like that anybody as backups
we don't mind we would rather get a
dozen
versions of the same book did not get
one some don't worry about sending this
stuff that you think we already have
we've
created so far about 20,000 e-books our
own
and we've had another 80,000 or so
donated to us
from over a hundred other people
collections around the world at this
very moment
we're celebrating the 35th anniversary
very first step in making electronic
books
which was this month in 1971
first time I ever heard there was such a
thing as the Internet
and I said let's put something on it
that won't go away
wanna put something on it that would
still be there ten years
hundred years later and I didn't know I
was dyslexic at the time
but I knew the program he was really
hard and
is really hard if you can't tell the
difference between a common a semi-colon
it and I had nightmares in Fortran
so I decided rather than try to write
some program that would stick around for
a while
that I should put something up there
that everybody a general interest idea
that everybody would want and as luck
would have it
that for the July on the way back to the
computer lab I stop for some munchies
and they threw in one of those folk
parchment Declaration of Independence
copies they handed out
back around the bicentennial and when I
dumped all my junk out on the floor that
popped out
and the light bulb went on over my head
literally showed just hardly lucky
anybody whoever says they did a project
like this
and wasn't really lucky I would be
suspicious if
I could never have done this without all
lot model lock in a lot a lot of people
helping me
including RPG lief CEO Greg Dulli
come on
me he does so much of the stuff that I
could never do
it I'm a I'm a see the pants kinda guy
yeah I just think up wild ideas and
pushing pushing pushing pushing trying
to get the snowfall over the edge
to wear start to pile that that's my
strength okay now
i'm suppose to mention that we're gonna
be given away
millions the books right now
such as people gonna be walking around
handing out DVD's and they're going to
be some back at the table
and if you collect both DVD easily have
you'll have about as many books as the
average public library
we also have some DVD images online
that we're hoping that people like you
well take a bonus round on
we have filled them up two-thirds away
to 20,000 books
and left a blank spot for 10,000 that
you choose
we want you to take these fill in stuff
given to your friends have them fill in
stuff
we want to go everywhere go we've place
we'd like to get in from two yards of
waco
in Australia and back from anywhere that
you can find books that may or may not
be the interest anybody
we want to get everything and so what
we're getting handing these out that are
on
if you put on a rerun will desk you can
just keep adding on to a woman when you
get it filled up to where you think you
going to be pretty much done
leases make me a copy and send it to me
or put it someplace where I can download
it
let me tell you about when they were
giving out so we have
I think enough for everyone is here we
don't have enough you go
good work dork slash CD project is a
form to fill out
and we'll send a free DVD
anywhere in the world poses paid we are
able to afford this because people
that got them sometimes goes back five
or 10 bucks to help us get out a few
more
the one that you're getting we just made
for this conference 17,500 books on it
is nearly full this one
on it's got a lot of HTML scotsman audio
stuff
it may not be sold this one
it has copyrighted I materials on it
donated to
to us so unlike some other ones he sees
resold on
UK because I've public domain and stuff
like that this one
I may not be sold we consider that to be
a good thing so up
what it says though is give me away so
make copies get the I so
II email me if you can find a good for
the I so up online
later on today ice about you know
four-point 3
gag and I enjoy it copy it pass it on
and share file share the whole thing
make your own sub collection
and get another now
don't worry about selling it I mean you
can sell for enough to pay for the
postage
the blank for whatever don't worry about
that stuff but it's just not supposed to
be retail
the whole idea behind all this as we
figure the world's gonna be a better
place
if we just jack up the literacy rate
education this whole idea is to build
things from the bottom up
not from the top down we don't have any
grants
we don't have any major people talking
for us
what you see here's what you get: your
worry about
and there have been
5 information ages 5
technological revolutions that basically
turned the whole idea publishing on its
head
now I got a lot I'm gonna run through
all these little slides here and come
back and talk the ones you want to hear
about the most
I'm not stuck with given a pre-prepared
speech
I I could talk what everyone is topics
for the whole time so
if you i'm talking to these boring kinda
like this
you know I'm talking about something you
like right but
would just fire to all these this is the
mic wildest dream here
this is as far as I dreamed if we do 10
million public domain books and then
get machine translation to put those
into a hundred different languages
that'll be up billion volume I'm
if we give them to one on a 601 to 700
naughty
people on the planet that's a
quintillion
books okay so what if I'm off by a
factor of a thousand then I only get to
give way quadrillion
books she that's the goal
we're not waiting
for somebody's approval we're not
waiting for bill gates or any those guys
to say hey you guys are doing great work
although this has been done with no
freakin
money project gutenberg: has never run
through a million dollars in its
entirety 35 your existence
all other period not count every
dollar I've had in every dollar that's
coming in on a project gutenberg: all
you all you have to do is do this stuff
anybody can make any anyone you can sit
down type it in skiing it in you can
snail mail it to us it will scan it for
you and you can proofread it or will
proofread
will do all the copyright research will
do everything we can possibly do
to help you out
this is what if we get a funny question
this is me way back in the back there
with the twenty thousand books
it now
some people say that e-books have never
made it there never gonna make it was
gonna pay attention to home
this is my counter example this is the
best selling book in the last four years
and in the knowledge with Paige
right there's a list I love over a dozen
of the most famous libraries in the
entire planet
and you'll notice number three that are
kinda stick sound
it okay we got to be the attack nasa now
we got 2 luv we got all the famous
libraries
the number three analysts project
gutenberg: because
we have a very wide variety of Bibles
and Apocrypha
all sorts of the stuff that you can't
get anyplace else
nobody wants some nobody has and you can
search a mall he did a lot of research
on this book
the only dollars on making a point is
this
kinda library makes really easy to
research shakespeare the Bible
the Greek plays stuff like that that's
what I'm hoping for
that's if we took all those boxes and
put them on top of each other
somebody wanna one-sided version I'm
this is a graph
for people who always said every year
that we couldn't do it for one more year
every single year there's not been a
year ago why did I haven't got messages
from people
says you can never do it for one more
year
he was a don't worry about Project
Gutenberg they want possibly stick
around for another year
this is how we got to 10,000 box
and this is as accurate as great could
make an
I have another graph of here that we can
get up and play with the computer at the
end
that is exactly accurate this one is
proportional spacing
it's very hard to make a graph with
reports of spacing graded as best
but it's not quite perfect I do have a
perfect one for you if you want
this is the same thing up to 20,000
and with your help will stack another
40,000 on top of that
okay what our people Jersey years we've
been doubling
every 18 months or so so more or less
and Moore's Law typeof
power curve doubling the number you
books every
18 months or so and that's achieved in a
number of ways most it is
technological advancement combined with
more volunteers
and waterways volunteered history Prof
readers
is the easiest place to get started PT
pp
dotnet history Prof readers
every year though we just barely make it
I do have to warn you about that
if you're on my mailing list you will
get notes from were just coming up to it
and people send me back stop jumping up
and down yelling and screaming I know
you're only one percent away from the
goal
the that's the kind of person I am it
don't really want to get it are you know
I wanted the book is right now but if
you guys are more interested in it will
come back to it
already mentioned about how anybody can
make in the book
is a couple things that great night and
talking about
that relate to some the conversations we
heard here already
we don't care who gets the credit for
the books you send us an ebook
will put your name on it your email
address your URL
whatever you like will give you two
lines to put anything you want
if you've got a dot com site and you
want to put the URL on their
that's just fine with me everybody
should get credit for what they do
I certainly don't need the credit you
guys to
should have the credit by the way for
some odd reason having project
gutenberg: on your resume
seems to help heaven only knows they
would never hire me
but these tend to hire the people that
work for me it
and a course that was by anonymous one
of our favorite sources
a lot of books by actually we did
we have a lot of books by this is
something that I love in serve said when
he came to the 10th anniversary a
browser's
Anna I should mention since I were
talking about credit stuff
that mark entries in with got no
credit he was never mentioned at the
10th anniversary browsers mosaic was
never mentioned
escape was never mentioned it was one of
those big political to do is
where all the guys in fancy suits that
were wearing my salary
they all got up there and talked about
browsers on ever giving credit to him
and that's the way it goes
it people are always telling me I can't
do this
and I just gotta say okays leave me
alone all succeed or fail
and you can watch good
is a much nicer way of saying the same
thing
it works very well if you put one book
in our collection tomorrow
there's a billion possible people who
could download
it will never get deleted not one of our
books is ever been deleted we did take
out Martin Luther King's I have a dream
speech without being asked
harami you kept up with the law but it
got changed in reverse then appealed in
all sorts of stuff
it was all over de klerk copyrighted and
we just took it up because without it
was okay with up to slot for it
we also have arthur C clarke's
permission we reserve slot 2001 for 2001
you but it's not in there
night this this gets a little heavy or
light on the same picture
we get a lot of conversations about like
darkness
and there are people who look at what's
going on right now I think this is the
greatest information age
it's ever been and there are people who
look at it and say it's a new Dark Ages
because a smaller percentage up the
information is available than ever
before
since the Gutenberg press copyright has
become virtually permanent
now copyright is not my favorite thing
to talk about but again
this is your guide to show what are you
guys ask God we don't have to wait to
the end for questions when we get to the
end
rollback feel free to interrupt me
anywhere in guide this anywhere you like
me I'm hoping that everybody will have
a buncha libraries that I brought a
little example
for five dollars at a garage sale
I have these in my room in paper
and my floor is one inch lower than it
was when I put him in there
okay if any if you have ever physically
seen
a century's worth a national Geographics
you know what I'm talking about
there massive and this book course if I
took them all output folder
there's only thirty season here not even
DVD's CDs
and they would fit in a little kids
carrying case that they carry along with
their walk
winner
alright
I do not I could just as other have
photographs of the pages so the ads that
had
if there was a page was only in and
which there were plenty of
I can't tell you whether all those were
in there or not I thought the ads were
kinda been lightning myself
and very cute tell a lot about our
culture and a lot about the pre-world
war one stuff
without the plan talking about it
afterwards now
we have slight to generation gap I'm
getting
get a little old but most if you could
go into your attic to your basement and
find a paperback
that said 25 cents on whether it was an
Agatha Christie rub preachings
ponder a or on Perry Mason or stuff like
that
y&i my parents were book a holics and
buy it was full and those things in rare
were the ones that were fifty cents or
35 cents they were almost all 25 cents
those same box at Borders and Barnes &
Noble stuff today
are closing in on ten dollars again I
don't wanna dwell too much on negative
stuff
but I've I can tell you all the changes
I've gone through with paper
publications and prices
and price-fixing and stuff like that but
if you imagine that a gallon a gas
today cost as much as a paperback today
that you think about the media frenzy it
would be going on
they're going nuts with three dollars a
gallon
what the heck with the be doing if we
were pushing ten dollars a gallon
but I've never in my life for one-story
about the price of books which is gonna
way faster the price a gas
will come back and talk about okay
here's the five information age is you
notice one of them was a
very very short the United States issued
a patent
in 1830 for the first high-speed
steam-powered printing press
and a copyright law came out to stifle
the thing in eighteen thirty-one
I this was no accident
United States copyright started in 1790
and basically got going pretty well by
the turn of the century
so those books and a maximum
copyrights be an awful lot 28 half years
okay
so they just started expiring so this
guy gets an idea hey
we could build all these reprint houses
and
fellow boxcars on the railroad in ship
of all these books
became and awfully lot easier
to print books pretty much to the same
order magnitude is how much easier got
when gutenberg came
now the original copyright was
created specifically to stifle the
Gutenberg press I don't want to go into
all the politics let you guys are
seriously interested in English history
but I have a whole list of all the
monarch serving when that they went
through trying to get the law passed
and nobody would go for it
and fire and agriculture in the wheel I
do have known of I'm not joking
not I have articles assert with those
you have to write
the first thing I said when they told me
we were on the Internet was I said
did they send a message like what have
got brought and they said no
and I said we have to send something and
I haven't got to that part yet but
that's right typed in the Declaration of
Independence
and tried to email it everybody in a
fight to succeed if you were never heard
the Morris worm but that's another part
of the story tell
I I actually tried the email the
Declaration of Independence
to all 100 people that were on the
internet which would have killed it
but luckily somebody stop me and said
let's put a note on what later became
calm Jim
and would just tell 'em is there and
they can download okay
yes there's a this is we got ninety
minutes here
and you're right I'm skipping over it
like a stone over the water and I
apologize
that any if you there are details and
everybody's interested in I'm more than
happy to go from
have get up to the microphone just
interrupt we have something to say
be happier I'll repeat the question as
to if you don't wanna
jumbo so went when I grew up
it was the 1909 copyright and everything
could be copied from maximum a fifty six
years
28 with the 28 year renewal stuff like
gone with the wind in the wizard of oz
paul sr Peter p.m. all the things I grew
up with
it with basic idea was if you saw it in
print and you live to be over 50 years
old
you are going to be able to republish
yourself however
while I was working on a particular
issue shakespeare
for the Gutenberg Project on they
extended the copyright law
back in 1976 because it is iraq
switching they also extended in 1909
due to the high speed electric presses
on there's
I've great story there I i feel like i
really should tell why all this stuff
happens
the sears catalog
was a 760
a page for lavishly illustrated
that was the first book owned by
millions and millions and millions of
people
because the combination
all a bunch of different kinds a
technology including the
Transcontinental Railroad
the high-speed printing presses rural
federal delivery which everybody forgets
about
but before then you could mail stuff to
people on the boonies
and everybody lived out in the boonies
so
Sears Scott really wise idea
mass-producing millions and millions
millions in these things and mailing
them to every single person they could
find
this upset the publishing industry
all to how because all the sudden
everybody was aware that you could
make a huge book and
send it to somebody at last cost
that could be recovered if they bought a
couple things on the catalog this drove
everybody absolutely nuts
and copyright was yet extended again
to stop the what they called reprint
houses
be going to use bookstores the look and
stuff it's a hundred years old you see a
lot of things by publishers that don't
exist anymore
but a few that do are cross and Dunlap
in Collier's and stuff like that
who specialized in reprinting stuff the
%uh to realize
that in nineteen hundred you could print
almost anything published
more than 25 years before them ninety
percent of all copyrights had never been
renewed
now if you wanna fight with these
statistics the fight with him
still because he is a PhD
of Library and Information Science knows
this stuff better than I did
and still the case ninety ninety percent
are not renewed
this means by the way that we have an
opportunity for about
a million books that you might think are
still under copyright
between 1923 in 1963 and you're actually
the public domain
we started that with our our rule 6 for
those is seen the website for copyright
clearance and
this is awesome opportunity for
harvesting the Senate these DVD's going
around
they are okay I like you got a library
you know maybe maybe I maybe have a
child maybe if you know someone younger
school library
17,000 the books is more than you find
in the after school library you know
someone that likes that much
you know someone that would like to get
one of these take take a couple we have
a whole box them back here
at the end talk will take a few boxes
with us to the
I to the pent-up course area I'm also
very funny
throwing them people just just one
o'clock by real quick
you did say that their to these the
others there there's one we're handing
out yesterday that has a different stamp
on it
because I'm see we're seeing a red one
and away we go round
we just want to clarify the odd the 2006
is one that should be going around I
they should be styled they're all
stamped it came from the same
volunteer the produce them its I should
say 2006
on it at you are you probably got when
you checked and
any on when you out I register for the
when you showed up a conference
is the Act 2003 edition those have a lot
of overlap
although numbers things from 2003 been
updated
since then so I we do have a whole bunch
%uh both these
if you take them both you'll have eyes
for an older version your version
and and the older one is primarily plain
text
this one has a a lot of plain taxers EPT
as well as lotteries gmail
summer in the multimedia stuff like that
on the ad the atom bomb
explosion we have by Janis Ian doing
society's child when your favorites
she did it live for us just for us and
some
totally project gutenberg: version yeah
very cool are
so I yes oh so few if you want both go
ahead take both we have we definitely
have enough to want to give away both
whether different colors just cuz we we
tend to buy these in bulk and I get the
cheapest deals they might not match
but should be stamped with 2006 for the
other 1i was mentioning the most recent
one
as I said the I so for that I is online
someplace but not really advertise if
you're desperate to get it right away
I drop me an email or ask we'll tell you
where to get it allowed elevate uploaded
to the Gutenberg org site
our next couple days and we have several
other one still
does the project for it for me for the
books that its
as far as renewed 3d yes but it's a
closed-form
the preferred format we're we're really
committed two formats which are editable
you can fix that you can use for
derivative works you can put your book
report stuff like that
basically that means we have a a bias
towards including plane tax but that
doesn't mean we are limited
the plane tax these days prolly AV
your 90 85 percent over our new books
are in HTML plus tax
arm usually the taxes derivative from
the HTML Seychelles a master
work we have just a few and we're going
to be doing this in the future with the
Servite proofreaders
is I XML so they'll be born as XML using
T I it's like the TV
as you care and %ah convert from XML to
just about any viable format we're going
to do
tax HTML maybe a couple others and store
those
on our servers and goes out to all our
viewers around the world
and then what we want to do in right we
don't have this fully activated yet and
you some skilled people for this is due
almost any other reasonable format on
the fly
so a PDF on the fly from an XML is cake
right on an easel CPU power to throw the
problem
and all of a sudden instead of having
one PDF file like you get from these
you know for a few sites with the books
you say hey I want this font
I want this size paper on it you left
and right margins verses
no se margins and get your ebook your
way was something we feel really I
strongly doubt
so we I have I think clearly about one
PDF on the book and now is is the book
that seventy two languages and
on editorials just impossible you can
even do with our TF
so otherwise we really are committed
edible formats
we also go back and fix you books to the
to at least a couple dozen
week and that's obviously important to
have an editable file I can't really fix
a PDF file to easily
if you clicked its
yeah will take will take all up Tech
Talks we would like to archive and I
think come
one thing that we've we have a delight
in the main gutenberg collection
good burger or collection which is this
close to 20,000 that that we're doing a
DVD
is we arm we've we've avoided doing a la
the technical books because they're
they can be transient and also there are
usually lot of other people are doing
those these days
what we're doing this gets back to the
slide you had earlier about
are the average person before gutenberg
having only one
you library right so we're doing
collections of collections
and what I'd really like to do is set up
a tactical
you book collections that all the people
that are doing like
your free documentation licenses create
a common sight slices
if they'd like to contribute their stuff
I would like to provide a place for
where that can not go in the archive we
are you we actually are up
arm are pretty close collaborators with
the Internet Archive and some these
other
projects and I just like them you know
we believe that
that if is spinning if it's online its
mirrored is on desk is downloadable
we feel like that's that's a a pretty
good place to be
on we are concerned about things that
are on paper someplace in our digital
and maybe I'll just be accessible in ten
years twenty years thirty years
we feel really saw strongly that this
get back to the previous question about
tax
that the work we do today had better
still be usable
valuable relevant you we don't know how
many people going user for what
wanna least make it sure is still usable
accessible in
certainly twenty years thirty years
fifty years not just five years ten
years and if we are going with the
format of the day
twenty years ago we have format that we
can read today in fact
we do have one we have supported the
shakespeare's in the folio for
.in dot the NFL from format out were
little barris about God people I emailed
say I can open this result neither can
we:
record a leader they saw a writer reader
the future
just the people ask is why we don't go
only with
PDF and stuff like that the reason is
that people own
it's a proprietary format and we want to
make sure that all this stuff is going
to be a he's dreamy shorter than I am
fifty years is nothing in my dreams I'm
Todd thinking about how this is all
gonna look up thousand years from now
now maybe a hundred thousand years I
just
like a set of I get to a quadrillion
book some I'm happy
yeah downloaded a lot your
on human great audio books and love them
just when I point of it all doing
audiobooks
human right audio books yeah we're
recruiting actors and people like that
we've hit up the Screen Actors Guild is
a lot of out-of-work actors out there
and we're we're hitting them up and
we're also working on more and more
different programs
where the words have actually been read
into the program's by humans
much like the old MIDI I remember the
MIDI synthesizers that actually some of
them use
synthetic tones and some home actually
had people play the notes in 20 minutes
re
produce the note for you we're working
on every one of those aspects
and it's a little slower than I would
like but is coming
we have 52 are really good partner sites
and that its liberal box
and literal system that's a little box
probably out ahead a little bit but
Tom of you to convert .org slash audio
that link to the sites and the human red
audiobooks I just put one on this cuz
250 megabytes I put on the
Sherlock Holmes our sure combs readings
wonderful
arm so-so mostly we're trying to work
with of projects that are more geared
towards
doing the things that are required for
human right audio books which involves
some different things and doing the the
plain text books and they were starting
to collect and we haven't like they were
continuing to collect them
in the good berkeley actually got 50 or
75 human red
got about 300 computer died
Texas beach I'm
I want to ask if there's any scope
within project gutenberg: for
not just expired copyright and all
things but people who wanna write
something today
and maybe contributor Creative Commons
are public domain
we have several different ways to do
that and if you the people email us we
try to figure out what their goals are
so which one would work out best forum
we have a preprint site we have
approximately two percent of our stuff
is still
done copyrighted by permission of
current authors
some people keep the contract give us
permission some people give us the
copyrights some people put in the public
domain
every there's a lot of different ways to
solve that problem
we're working on modern-day stuff as
well
the %uh the main and II impediment for
some folks
is we will match before about PDF and
stuff like that so many people have
formats that were are concerned about
their longevity
and so what we usually do with those you
mention we don't put into the main
Berkel action but we have this
preference I'll tell your web browser up
and you can see it said prefer in stock
reading ru .ms
which is reading rooms right and I we
love to get stuff
yeah back to the old sec
do does the copyright homie
the top deal with does apply only to be
work that's being read or the reading
itself if you want to copy write your
own reading on it
you can do that will become your audio
edition
and if you if you want to create your
own paper edition you can do that too
now United States law requires more
intellectual input to get a copy right
then other countries laws
some of them have what they call the
sweater the brow kinda stuff
and we don't have much in there so you
would have to do something rather unique
with reading is very unique
so that would be very easy for you to
copyright okay that was warning because
I have
like old tape or old
final recordings audio production that
I know some of we wanna check
with a good copyright lawyer cuz the law
on all that changed in nineteen
seventy-two
if you have any records in 1972 and
before
there's a very good chance that they
don't get a copyright in it
okay but you do want to check it I'm I
know thousand times more about copyright
than you ever wanted to know
and I can answer all the questions
anyway and
if if they're clear sure you did
like mp3 right well if you do your
research oh yeah
any the form its it if you do your
research on this often you come up with
the reasonable decision that its public
domain
you what the cost innocent infringer
they can sue you for a hundred boxer 200
bucks or something
you know but they can't take your house
or anything on because
you did some research in some you know
you did enough to say I think this is in
the public domain
but it helps to do some research and
will help you do it yeah that's that's
what you gotta understand we are
as mike said were unwilling experts in
now and copyright
and we have if you go to convert .org is
a how-to section we have a copyright how
to you
this is distillation love Bob 45
very big on lawyers
very expert lawyers and copyright
issues and we we keep Pattinson
trademark that says everything but for
copyright
we have a whole procedure to go through
and when we go through that procedure
when when you go to the gutenberg site
and you let us to your copyright will
you do that
you provide the information then we make
a determination of public domain status:
I'll we we haven't been wrong yet
basically we've we've got me a few
things that are gray area
there's some things that are there their
arm up in the air
awesome you might have heard about the
orphan works decisions are some stuff
it's
tell something section 108 apes they're
looking at so there are some things that
are great we're actually trying to push
those boundaries
where we think that basically you know
there's a reason
basically fall to the people rather than
falling to some long-dead
author's estate na na kar I'm also gonna
warn everybody I am gonna try to give in
some more
up but i wanna talk about I
%ah not on our I've I just don't want to
give told leon we were good so far in
the contract and we could stay there
forever and that's good
but I want to get to the end and bounce
back so you know what the options are
soon as we know what the options are
then I'm willing to go for any the
options that are available
yes let's go I'll get back as I was
asleep inside
go ahead while he's playing with it the
you have it stops it
still books from books for free
it's upset the the road you books
audio books for free dot org it's a
place that gave us some love are you
books there there I
non not a a in our car possibility that
is people we work with you get those
particular items
by you only have a substantive group
that's right
a subset of their books yet so audio
books for free is job to a site that
space in the UK
they do live pretty pretty professional
readings as opposed to
livevox with sound very good but they're
they're really amateurs
and they do have God not only for their
books they also have some higher
I like hysteria have some higher-quality
higher sound quality recordings not I
want to sleep like five or 10 minutes
right now
to just tryna cover all a joke at least
for one second appease
gonna wanna please throw out there then
you guys can pick which one here
each one of these inventions and I've
been talking about change
the whole idea of civilization
changed what it was to be a member of a
civilization
what a member of society change the idea
I'll how much you could no how much you
could look up
how much information you could have
without somebody else telling it to you
we were always so dependent on somebody
else telling us everything
and each one of these gay people
an opportunity to have a truly
encyclopedia incentive knowledge
in their own house now when I was a kid
these things cost 1500 bucks
for that great looks at a restaurant
world in the britannica
the Americana and all those are the
things that I grew up with
arm today you know I'm sure that
somebody here is gone on poverty in the
car for fifteen dollars on a DVD like I
did
brand new I could tell you how many
copies I have in the britannica
on DVD and CD but I can tell you that I
do have one for every 10 years for over
a century in paper
it um these things are fantastic
and it's just going to keep going on
that way unless they stop us
right now the concept the copyright has
been determined by the US Supreme Court
as to the possibly permanent
there was how media for Nov %ah Eldred
verses ashcroft
before was older versus ashcroft it was
hard
that's me versus reno
and I was suing on behalf a project
gutenberg:
but the lawyers were doing such a
terrible job by fire
I don't ready that's not a great story
but that the
a that came in they were going to lose
524 they lost 72
alright you but now the Supreme Court
even worse
so I don't think there's any chance up
getting the law changed
unless there's somebody out there who's
willing to be much more revolutionary
than I am
things are gonna happen quite a bit
differently a hundred years ago
over half of all copyrights had expired
it was a very nice kinda ratio new stuff
was coming in the publication about as
fast as your stuff is going out
kinda nice a hundred years from now
99.99 and I don't know how many more
nines
I'll everything that was ever
copyrighted well still
be under copyright
if I i wanna bring a budget dishes and
dual stack up dishes and Sonia
with pie charts on the dishes because if
I took a couple sex a dish is taller
than I am
I could make the mark of how big a
percentage in the year 2100
by taking a plane and drawing a little
triangle in it
about that wide on dinner
that will be I mean if you take your kid
to the new Lion King
take a five year old kid to the new
version Lion King this year
that kid will have to live to 2100
before that copyright would expire even
if it's never extended
again I don't want to go too far into
that may not be what you want guys wanna
hear about
but every one of these five information
age is was countered
by a copyright to stop the technology
that could have given
everybody basically all the information
in the war
this has happened before and it said
gonna have to have something more
revolutionary night
okay now why are they doing all
they're setting up precedents our legal
system is based on precedence
not know how many have you guys ever
seen a replicator product in real life
I brought some
ever heard at the MIT fam lab
I gave a speech over there last week and
they were kind enough to make me some
goodies to show you
this is a mounting bracket for a
solenoid in and of itself it's not
terribly cute
except for the fact it was made by a
forty thousand pounds per square
inch water trough
cutest little gizmos I've ever seen we
made a bunch of these
this is really cue and it's like I said
there's nothing special about another
factor how it was made
nobody ever touched used to this peace
and that when they're just near
you know got have goggles on
this is appalling goes on a
axle has little notch to put the rope on
you
right rope around and it was part of a
triple send a police in a big easy one
this was cut out by a laser and
a laser that was finely tuned enough I
didn't even have to wear delays approve
goggles I got to watch it make this
thing
and this is seriously hard
this is about sixty to eighty percent as
hard as anything you could make
polio its not rapid prototyping
anymore it's not just soft plastic
you can make real operational stuff
ready to go and yes of course
is a starship I
and this is ABS plastic and there are
half a dozen other materials you can
make
things out that I just I didn't find
this whole idea for years and years and
years
I started talking about faxing pizzas
and doing stuff like that back in the
early 90's
and that was nice to lose my audience
when I talked about that stuff they just
they just
Wallace comes up launch its pizza from a
fax machine
we gotta shoot him pppppp
was a
I'll this lets layer by layer for those
with a
run the layers and this particular 1i
didn't watch this particular one
me the 1i watched be made was made out
the old polymer stuff
this is if you can look as I can send
you the program for this
and I can send you hope homeless to the
composite it's me
email me I have effect I have right
around my neck
it's all right here when I was walking
to the family my stock
this and everything it was making
downloaded the instructions
I
and I have permission from the MIT guys
to put those three things
on project gutenberg: so you will see
them you can't download it will make
your own
you can find out exactly how it's me it
okay now again I I wanna be with much
time you guys as possible
on I designed it crayon jet printer
years and years ago that you probably
don't want to hear about this its easy
to think about
image in multiple pieces a wax and
firing them off and you could build up
a really great relief map have anything
you want
I thought this was just totally cosmic
until somebody printed be on a human
hand
and you could almost read the
fingerprints the resolution was so good
you could read that you could take it to
a palm reader you could read the poem
is unbelievable stuff that you can make
with these things
um I do still lose people when I talk
about driving away in a Ferrari that you
print on your computer
cuz you gotta give oil between the
cylinders and everything but I still say
that you will be able to do it someday
think about I'm sure some with you with
those guys were talking about the Cocos
and all that
remember when it was only one color it
was a bit
it was either on or off that was it that
was a number colors you got
and now you can get less than 16 million
colors
and you can get a lot more I say the
same thing for these materials
all you have to do is double the number
materials every so often
and eventually you have all the
materials you want so
don't get to tied up in that that if you
like that stuff
read diamond age
if you look at my pictures on the web
forum up in a tree
reading a book this is what I'm reading
this is the only hardback book ever
bought new
off-the-shelf when it was new in my own
life
and it was before I knew Neil I actually
went to a conference like this one and i
was standing in line with a couple of
weirdos we have a great conversation
and make a long story short we got to
the end we put our badges on
and one of them was seen June in the
other one was Neil
and the other ones me and I while what
cool threatens
is likely put the bags 0 your you 0
you know yep we have been the acting up
a storm in line for 45 minutes
and have more fun we had during the tire
conference
okay engines a creation by Eric Drexler
its it's not a novel but I read it like
one
I just ate the whole thing up so
interested in nanotech
and replicators stuff I'm telling you
know
you can buy a 3d printer now for less
than an IBM ATT cost in 1984
about a full body eighty not even
counting inflation
the same list price: not counting
inflation
you can build I want people printing out
donatella David and Michelangelo's David
in the Venus de Milo
and all that stuff not just Mona Lisa
okay gotta get this is details we can
get into later
i'm suppose to mention the world the
book fair um
I just got to go for it I'm I don't like
cum
and like on my own too much
but I asked a friend of mine
to help you summary the 35th anniversary
sit down Thomas in
tied dependents
so he gave you cripple your box
I could give you and they're all right
there
if you go to world he Book Fair dot com
for the next two weeks till August 4
there's
on the project gutenberg: books and
there's a quarter of a million more
not coming for duplication there's over
350,000
we're say we got a third and they're all
free
search him out download them give those
to your friends too
we just i just want to get the maximum
publicity for everybody
and this is a guy who sells these and
he's given away for free
for all month just cuz I asked really
nice
more junk here's here's the traffic
pattern
for some reason nobody comes in on the
weekend sold
if you get in there right now you should
be able to suck up what's a box it
and it looks like a lot of our traffic
coming from Europe and Asia
much more that we expected so that's the
traffic pattern
the world fair says the first couple
days
where we had to switch servers and wires
into all sorts of things because it was
just getting
overloaded to the max we've given away
over a million books today
every day since about July 7 South
32 days we're gonna have I'm gonna guess
we're gonna make it to thirty 30 million
books
but we also give Lee 30 million books
right here at this conference
okay
you know dat did this is how you can
volunteer
the easiest way to volunteers just send
me e-mail I love helping people
volunteer
50,000 volunteers and they all say I'm
so sorry to bother you
and I that's what I'm here for here to
help you guys figure out how to get
started
John alright
so now officially we got back to the end
and the beginning
so now we can go to any one of those
spots you want or
other spots I apologize but I just wanna
make sure got everything covered
okay question yes you have a question
since you open formats like since you
gotta push these open formats like
brought taxed
stuff arm have you had any blind
visually disabled people
call call you up and say hey thanks a
lot it
traditionally they would have to find
the book printed in braille and not
everything
me braille right there's a month goes by
and I don't get a note from some
visually impaired persons as please
don't ever stop making plain text the
works
not I gotta I got a string a couple
things out is not the time against all
these other formats:
people have misquoted me is a 125 for
some other form and said michael Hart
wrote the kill and all week you know
I wanna kill Adobe I just wanna plain
text
to I went to meet with a TI guys back in
that
ninety or something like that and they
wanted to destroy plain text
there was he Library of Congress
sana workshop on the text I in 1992
that never once mentioned plane tax
integrate revenge I got because they
published it in PDF format wanted to get
some feedback of the list servers and no
by the insert and week after week after
week I got 2 G's
home in front of 10,000 readers and say
you know why they're not answering
because they wanted in plain text they
don't wanna play with PDF
now this is 1992 it didn't come up
automatically okay had
fool around you never got one message
one person
until they put on a plain text saw
montezuma
I got my revenge do you have to have a
sense that they use for text to speech
for oh yes you're much easier plain text
works for everything now
what this team is XML kinda thing the
greg was talking about you should be
able to create plain text on that
so I got nothing against being able to
to go this way and that way
as long as you can get back to something
that the average person wants to use
interview coming up the IEEE magazine
today I think
on was really hard on me about that
and I said the reason I do that is
because I can stand here and say I
dare you I double dog dare you to find
one computer
the won't read our books yet
let's talk about free also the blind
bookworm
is all one site where they lots about
use
converting to April format with an FB
friends
is something that we're planning on
offering than that little spaces again
good opportunity and up but I really
wanna play garin
Aaron is the guy that manages our CD rom
giveaway project he was a guy that
burned 1500 these brand new
%ah I says a brand-new he's a writer to
give away
he's blind is a college student in
totally blind
caused in its Aaron can so thanks
group
not to help you books are fantastic for
educating people around the world but
for
for a reason the world the hardware to
read e-books
might not necessarily be is readily
available things like dollar
laptop project certainly help that sort
of thing
fifty dollar leapt up probably better
200 first
I'm just curious what your take is on
the hardware with
ePaper eating solutions: things like
that starting to come
I got two answers to that one is while I
was in a mighty I just happened to be
with a hundred dollar laptop guys and
we're gonna do some kind a joint project
with them
and my own
I I like to work for the bottom-up I'm a
simple guy when it comes to that stuff
all my suffers from garage sales
everything you see
I was everything I own is from process
and
my solution to that particular question
his cell phones in the next 12 months
they're going to be up billion new cell
phones
in the war and I'm pushing up for a
friend of mine named John beat see
from Malta who has a little sign up
mobile books and stuff like that email
me and
I'll tell you all about her go toward
latest newsletters that ira month ago
cuz I've been on the road a month
and Dom you can download 5,000
are books that have already been
converted into a WEP
compatible cell phone and we're gonna
put lots of other cell phone
the iPod was only out for a week before
somebody wrote a program to read her
stuff on the iPod
i'm waiting for somebody to read out
loud on the iPod
all sorts of things like that so yeah
cell phone I got a message
a text message from a guy from the cell
phone on the seven get the plane in
Africa
who's read one of our books and were due
and I thought yes
that's the definite wait for this to go
if guys gonna have to decide who's
online
person sorry that's me on I actually
I thought I was sort of a side note
almost the idea distributed proofreading
I heard also from the folks for this
media which I don't know if you guys
know
it's really a lot of under the folks who
revealed that distributed
journalism research they revealed that
there was a diet
been allowed into the White House press
corps who is not only republican plant
water but was also a male prostitute
so %uh you note so they're also working
that sorta
a side note that they thereof but that
they also have distributed proofreaders
issued its action occurs no wonder how
long do you think that miles from the
Bible
because it's one of those things that
just sorta you know takes a lot of time
it's a labor of love
helical I can imagine it stopping
for several reasons the first reason
which was valid twenty years ago does it
is today
is that you can take a diff program our
comp program
and compare any the files to different
people proofread see all the differences
in one second somebody changed one comma
you think it's gonna pop up so we always
had the issue
way way way back when %uh 1984 is on if
you'll notice the first book sided
there are like 20 or 30 persons a
balance in Wonderland literally is that
all the way up to Alice 30
not HTML stuff because every time I
change it like put a new file up so you
could see the whole evolution
from the first one and how we got really
the errors little by little now
distributed proofreaders for those who
don't know is a set up
where you can come in and proofread
one-page while you wait for some you
come pick you up
his log in and grab a page you can grab
another page you sit there and let me
just as official on
you could claim a whole book if you want
but a lot of people just pop in here in
there
there are single we had a big rush one
week and I think we're
there like 12 thousand people
proofreading in one weekend
it just gets absolutely berserk is how
many pages you can get done
and we have everyone I'm done twice by
the way yeah
we have done copyright research in all
sorts of other things for
in the body who was interested in the
box ever since I started I
I just want to promote e-books you
notice in our mission statement
it didn't say public domain e-books or
nonprofit the books or anything like
that
is my job is to promote
the creation and distribution the box
period very
everybody who started the book business
way back when
called me and I help them to the best of
my ability
so a cult this early proofreaders
is %ah an organization that's up you
extremely close its Leah
we buy their hardware we have you really
type
ties but they make their own decisions
also about what
give to process and they do focus a lot
on the public domain
and that's great I'll we I encourage
people and they'll help
to set up additional service providers
we have one say that's up and running
pretty successfully
IDPs Europe and would like to set up
other sites of people have particular
areas that are interested in
then then you can you can work with a DP
folks get the code
is so access to manuscripts and papers
as a big deal in scientific publishing
don't know if you guys at me connections
with people at the Public Library of
Science
the lowest or.org over okay
we've stopped emails with some on
sometimes people like that ask us to
make a backup forum
and sometimes they want to keep it
private cuz they want to get all hits
again we don't care who gets the hats we
we help in any way that we can form and
if you if you know somebody there and
you think you can make a connection for
sweet with my
no I do but I just mention it because it
did it takes the same issue opening up
copyrights and access to scientific
literature
on and so my question is about
on scientists and and just any reader in
general people build up their own
libraries have the course their lifetime
and yet you know I want my library to be
accessible by anybody
my personal library and I think you know
if somebody wants to share the library
me I said
access to that so to what extent if he
thought about developing models are
standards
for making real you know distributable
libraries or
making your library accessible to you
and everybody else from anywhere
okay I think I'm gonna answer your
question
I hope but its its is something that I
already thought of
not specifically in response to a
question so I may not hit the nail on
the head I
call the philosophy that I work with on
limited distribution
the idea is basically is that once
project gutenberg: puts in the book
online
every BBS every guy with a Coco anything
else out there
who wants to put that book on their
little system is
just D&D with me um you know like I love
linus falling sorry Mindstorm of
sent real men don't use back either
you know only when she's back ups real
men put their stuff on FTP and let the
whole world download
he had the exact same the same ID I did
I just was trying to do with more stuff
in fact I got a little story that may be
worth telling about that
where I pulled an all-nighter I mean a
literal when this is where you just
wasted you fall into the second unit
with the Woodside
asleep on and I did three books that
from Indian
and when I put a min two copies on the
East Coast 2 cups and went cosa tu
copies in the midwest and I went to
sleep and woke up the wrong one
and i was just totally freaked because I
knew would be a week
before I had nothing to do that again
and
then I got a wise idea after pounding my
head against the law for a while
of sending out an email to a hundred my
favorite friends
see anybody download these before they
disappeared
yes I I was saved because
all our stuff goes up immediately and
people have little clock set all day
long for people to back up our system
there are sinking every
minimum every day saw it now hard for us
to lose a book
and the whole idea is based on the fact
we put a book up
for example I did a icelandic book
called cormack this call
and there's only one copy a bit in
existence is known I did
I didn't know we gotta hold the only
copy I just saw you sent it to me and
said here
and I put it up there and I I woke up in
the morning I thought you know I didn't
do enough copyright research on this
book even though it's like from 1100 or
something like that
and
10 you are very high must change inside
your eyes is done I'm gonna wake up and
I'm gonna see if somebody claimed a
copywriter this that or the other
so I logged in and I did a search and I
got 1/2
that Craig find it was awesome we were
already listed in the OCLC catalog
so when attacked I fell asleep the time
I woke up to check
we're now the authority on this book I I
spun really is really strange
amount list outside I just we are in the
same time I found out we were listed as
having the best
Robert Louis Stevenson collection in the
world and and stuff like that
is everyone so I turned around and find
the weirdest dating reference the
project gutenberg: night
know me tomei their economy interview
before the right these articles have the
time
in his arms as did you know no just we
just did i do we get a lot of Robert
Louis Stevenson
I with apart the question was a about
for building personal book shelves and
stuff like that
that it can be distributed me we all
truly libraries and curation
your technical papers and all that is a
big deal and you should benefit
you think in p2p yeah nice easing your
personal book sale so so
so we we haven't done a lot that won the
main gutenberg server
is mostly what we say is look we're
really good at creating books getting
them out they're storing them
produce basic how long information what
other folks too
to provide all these these ways reaching
in that we didn't net
yet dream up show you one right here
invite you to make others
and mention that we also in a related
thing we we work with Wikipedia
so right now we're talking about a loss
to author BIOS do
bibliographies let's do about this book
there was a twenty minute
we're not really set up for that were
set up for for
like these big files that don't change
all that often and which are working
with the GPS that we link to them
and we let them do that arms s1 sorta
certified purchase or directions
the other up on the screen I i apologize
for Michael's try so far colors here is
a really weird colors
but us know we got our study last gotta
leave you slash PG I sell
that's where I made this image I had to
tweak it a whole lot after afterwards
people make their own collections of our
e-books and there's not time here we
haven't died
result of people out if I seen this yet
but Tom
they create their own collections right
so use like some some ourself in you
publish it
and then someone says hey I'd like to
get some of that stuff you click over
here he say make me I sell
and makes you and I so emails you want
some so a couple things that we're doing
but I think it
larger questions your answers we don't
want to do all that stuff going try to
focus on what we're good at
and we say yes you know we always
encourage people to do stuff course
people's car oh well
you know now I got work we also got a
15-minute warning
sold the if everybody asks a question
only takes three minutes we're on a time
campaign
I just like to say thanks this project
is but
also my questions about tax form
I know you mentioned the I mean I I
completely agree with that with the
plain text formatting
how it's essential and you said you were
doing
a little HTML to make it a little more
readable and I'm wondering if you
if you experiment was with things that
are more
for electing to pitch like attacked for
or something like that which is
plain text by on has a little more
facility for page formatting
and is is a lot easier to read in
read the actual mark-up than HTML is
because all the clothes
you talking to the wrong guy yeah hear
the answer is yes
we love it we have 20 attack books we
are not dive since a
plenty we have more voicemails I got but
I especially mathematical text tech is
the answer
I we're really interested by the way
this died Newton's Principia
we really want to get news Principe
online at some
bears a monster but you're not going to
do that anything about but
attack probably prolly these days so
what was the reason for the choices I've
HTML we don't use we we we encourage we
enable we accept
ecology as a yes vote the way they wanna
make yeah we answer yes now the HTML is
because it is like a great tools free
shemale
successful you know all the stuff on and
so and so that's what we get
when we change to XML will have more
options for spreading into further
formats
on but but tech as an option and then
we'll be some future stuff that's okay
as well
we got we got down 20 thirty something
different formats including NFL roster
anymore and I foes
okay no more thoughtfully of but almost
any other reasonable for me
have done a lighting got with the pawn
on all its again thank you's one of my
ex most exciting projects
always had someone ask question about
your his answer I quickly there's a
mirror how to
okay I it's about 160 gigabytes right
now we do a lot of rsync
and the reading root server which is
running this world the book fairs but
pushing 60 to 100 megabits
for two weeks as doing great job but by
and large I get your own copy the clicks
on your own server they
use your purpose is your friends or
whatever pretty easy nearing how to
question if you leave out the human
genome it gets easier
my questions about whether is interested
in
craft instructional materials there's
orphaned
books and magazines pamphlets from the
first half of the 20th century
religious thing laws speakers
publishers don't exist companies rich
never copyrights and then
community people who say 0 but
everything's
cancer on the project
yeah just will help will help on
thing when when people say that that I
you know we think this copyrighted
whatever operate as I said unfortunately
we're experts and
I am usually send email to copyright PDF
.org I get that and I
will try to help out arm again a little
relieved that the other question we got
sometimes format it can be a real issue
no we don't want
we don't really want to have a test and
just a test for something like that you
really want to actually turn into an
ebook
that you can %ah I use for all these
other purposes River
works cutting and pasting sharing with
want your friend
printing if you want to that by the way
what we invention is one thing that we
really think to say which is
gutenberg from some the work we are
coming out if I use Google's Yahoo's
and so forth they're mostly doing
picture pictures books throw CR
we feel like you need a little more push
unfortunately that little more push
is a lot of work to get it to where we
really want to be with being
usually book the longer answer than you
bargained for for answers your
with a picture of a book is not a book
if I have a Ferrari I wanna drive away
in it if I'm up my pie with there's a
famous painting a pipe that says this is
not a pipe
under it and when people ask me why
isn't that Google book a book
is because you can search it you can but
the most important thing is so you can
read it
and that's that is definitely the most
important part but it's not any block
it's a something it's a Google project
Google Burke
a arm I want to thank you guys for all
your good work
and over copyright question for you com
think we all agree that all earthlings
should have access to
every book but we have to overthrow US
copyright laws if we want to make that
happen
um but is there another country that we
could work in
iraq as very limited
ya represent they are they haven't yet
find the Berne Convention
I was turned on Afghanistan is the other
one that never signed the Berne
Convention I don't know
I don't know and Bhutan on the copyright
has been extended
in European Union's lie you know to
70-plus
Australia just that seventy-plus years
most address the world is life plus some
number
US's fixed amount on again short answer
is there's not a whole lot out there
and if you want to think in terms of
like God data repository
types of things you already know about
Haven co and then you've read
you'll see but the talks about that on
the problem is that
if I'm in the US I'm the infringer in
the US regardless whether they live
you know and I now you know see Sea
Islanders and I talked to the ham & Co
Chi
you want anything to do with it yeah
they're bad with his little too
expensive for us actually
yeah but job but I said so unfortunately
it's not that good a %ah
an opportunity are we we tend to be
really really cautious as I said
are we have collaborators the project
gutenberg: sources Center
is running this World Book Fair was
there any way is up
are slightly less are sort of paranoid
than we are and there are plenty of
other people it's a look public domain
spells below to main OS
complain that will put up for a for
download but
that doesn't get us the the contemporary
stuff that's kinda perpetually
under copyright it doesn't look that
good progress in the world but we are
doing
more and more contemporary stuff and
there's a lot of contemporary stuff at
the world the book fair right now
if you wanna see stuff that was just
printed my last couple years
get on there go some other sponsors
sites sadly to say Jim Payne
died while I was on my trip I want to
meet him in New York use he's one of the
sponsors other-worldly Book Fair
and he's given site keep a box that we
can all give away you guys
and Sun just no
we we're gonna have their stuff I can't
say
because people have made me promise not
to all I can say is we're going to malls
lot more box think just
as you amass huge amount
material what sort of solution do you
have for
indexing for finding things
funding any particular thing if you
don't know exactly what you're looking
for
well to go on to the to project
gutenberg: consortium Center site I'll
that site has been totally crawled word
by word and you can search any phrase
and find it in any one in the box anyway
like it takes for freakin
ever to run then search and we actually
bought new UPS is because the searches
were taking two or three weeks
and that thing would crash sometime
during the two weeks we didn't get it
done texting
take to make the index yesterday
endorsing a little faster that indexing
oh yeah
of our search takes longer than your
search yeah
to build the index that you guys get the
search like that takes
to three weeks and and finally what we
did was we farmed out to somebody
its it's got to be tried we think like
them actually thought coupe
Cliq p.m. dot org and they've been
running that
so redrew .ms has been pushing I said up
to 100 megabits for the last couple
weeks
they've been serving you know how many
queries millions the reason we crash
rebuild they grew rewrote the program
for us
they're they're actually pretty pretty I
Google of course index is the name Burke
likes we have a search
for them Yahoo has a in a special
program where you can you like author
title searches
so I will stuff cataloging for books we
try were not professional catalogers as
I said we
we try to be some this stuff to people I
know it better than we do
but we try to do a little bit everything
you know that we have as an RTF
I XML file the download build your own
catalog
using our data as and butanol this up if
you think they spent an hour on the
advance
offline catalog page I could got work
the hundred dollar laptop people made
big noises about
rebuilding our catalog for us to but
they haven't answered my email since I
left MIT's
they don't know one think people realize
how big this is so you know
a quarter million files yeah I got by
but a court you know
out 20,000 titles on
can be an awful lot their issues with
character sets languages
having author names that don't quite
match we fix these as we get errors
but we really I want to encourage people
to do
probably a better job with you basement
cataloging
still finding its things thank you very
much Michael you started the thought
that
I'm not sure you finished and I want to
see if I can get you finish anything
if you're talking about copyright
copyright stopping
the information waves you know and then
he said
why they doing this are setting
precedent and then you start talking
about the Neal Stephenson stuff and I
never
we what okay pressed into the settings
okay okay
have you read diamond age okay
I strongly suggests everybody here read
diamond age
anybody who doesn't like it swear to God
send it to me
give it to me whenever I will pay you at
least have what you paid for it
and I give it to somebody else that says
I mean this is hundreds of people but I
will do it
because I could never get enough copies
of it anyway same with daily online by
the way
it okay now the reason I recommend
talking about and now you may wanna play
New Years or something
II wanna mention a couple things and I
he maybe I should do this by email or
warning
yeah this is a step in a spoiler
warning: but I'm gonna ask this question
some do Socratic method here
rather than tell you the answers so the
real question is
why does it start with bod alva
creepy low-lifes in the world
why does it start with but when you can
answer that question
you understand a heap more about diamond
age in the heat more about my
what I was talking about in the sense
that
every time people the masses
can have stuff the haves versus the have
nots wanna step in and make sure they
can't have it
now I can go into the you want to look
up the history of fashion
a particularly tally in fashion there
were laws so far how long your freakin
toes on your shoes could be
so that if you had told that's right by
the way that's why Italian shoes have
pointy toes
because it was against the law if you
are one of us
to where the pointy toes it was actually
against
phone law to wear those kinds a close
now that we
Star Trek anybody watch Star Trek
my favorite favorite quote I got a real
tracker
or Traci but there are some seriously
good stuff in there now
on and my favorite quote is in one where
a
wharf and day to find these frozen
people one owns a folk singer
1 I'm sicilian there in 10 just somebody
and the folk singers I got a whole new
audience I can go out there and do all
this stuff i won
the lady wants to find relatives in this
billionaires
freakin per car Nicobar ship several
times over
and long story short gets to the end
and Picard finely tell some very gently
that there's no such thing as mani
guys about ready to freak out what do
you want
nasty and Picard sense
we invest in ourselves
we live in a society where we are def
finding ourselves by our possessions
long as we define ourselves by our
possessions
having the distinction between the haves
and the have-nots
will be the most important thing
and that philosophy has governed all of
our civilizations
all the way back to the amoeba the
amoeba says
it's better if I have it you don't
that's the way comes now up until
electronic books
there was only one thing in the whole
world at all if you could have as much
as you want to know
what was it very good here
today you can buy any computer off the
shelf
and download a million copies so that
declaration of independence I typed in
and you won't even notice to put a dent
in your hard drive
me you can have as many as those things
as you want
the first thing besides here which you
have as much as you want
I bought that terabyte half a terabyte
drive
couple weeks ago for 200 bucks a week
later it was ten dollars cheaper
you now you get to the point where you
can hold in one hand
and this is some what I said the day
that I started the book to death on a
project gutenberg: which technically by
the way was July 5th it was after
midnight
on ice I talked about laptops
and I talked about that you be able to
carry the entire library of congress and
one here
and I immediately appended to that and
they will make a law against it
nunno don't know I was in a smart as it
sounds I'm
was are you do read a lot of the stuff
that I wrote back then
and I'm a Kansas Kat it sounds like I
knew so much more
that I really knew I was just on the
right trail
I didn't understand what I was doing
I just knew it was the right thing to do
project gutenberg: is as much a
right-brain thing
is a left-brain thing for me you're on
the scene to the finance guy
I don't understand I can't be the
circuit diagram because I'm Dyslexic
don't make any sense to me I can read
code I can't even read a great
it's too crazy for me it it makes me
dizzy to look at a regular expression
but I do run command once I love I'm a
command-line guy rather than a point
click
don't again I don't understand why this
all works out the way it does
and run on a time when I said some
really good things here I would be a
great place
in but I we always got more one room for
one more question
the question is what is the website
or web-sites that we should be going to
gutenberg .org
gutenberg .cc
there's a good number dot CEO .au
or something like that I'll email you
all the sites
30 gutenberg I word that's a good place
to go on
thats with not the psyches of German way
with 2 T's
itself thank you good burger dork
email me anytime I'll send you a whole
list to the sites and even about how
much
is on the site as a contact page there
it was both our
are you males and there's a help address
also has me copyright dress also has me
and I would be happy to talk to you
there's of
50 languages Edinburgh .org there's over
100 guber .cc
saw those are the those are the biggies
you download everything from those two
you got a major weapon collection
but does not forget the Australians are
coming there was up to a thousand
and project gutenberg: Europe started a
couple years ago and they've got over
we've got project work in Portugal got
Senate Oracle question
on done in age when I walked into my
senior professors Department or
office in my department for the first
time I noticed there was a cop shelf the
book is for the major touchstone so
my question is when and where is the
first conference that centers on the
diamond age
well I'd know the guy who runs diamond
age .org
recent so if you email me ask them for
you
he's a replicator guide by the way just
case you didn't think that already
but %ah I am so far into this replicator
thing I just to me that replicators are
magic
there there is far out there is my
quintillion box
what about the the primer crime yeah
ladies young ladies per
well again is the writers are right
brained aspect there's a left brained
aspect
the young ladies primer is the right
brained aspect
and the whole programming thing you know
where she starred to start playing with
the chains and doing all that stuff
that's left brain aspect
and now that's nother of spoiler alright
the end to the book to go what happens
at the end I i want to say it
but if what did she become
what's the result of what she does
no she basically creates her own
civilization
Sao you start with bod the end up with
this stuff
new file I won't mean anything to people
haven't read it
I and that's kinda what I'm trying to do
here
is I wanna turn that the original logo
for project gutenberg: was the
big long lever hugely
with the moon as the fall from the earth
on the short in his little bitty guy
stacking books
on the long and with marks and
said underneath dragging the world
kicking and screaming into the third
millennium
it that's where we started anybody heard
a cow tipping
I mean the world to ping I wanna
sneak up on the world was not been
so we're gonna try to ramp up
yeah upward happy to talk to anybody
want to talk until I run outta gas
and BPD there will be a long time five
shuttle right to
pent-up North and there are bunch more
DVD's in get enough lol try to grab a
couple handfuls and
and asked me to address a conference
thanks everyone