yes for a five
okay
good
life
you're seeing all my secrets here
anyway enough the the sunglasses well so
it strobe lights and
jello by Aphra left a lesser known actor
at the time
was the voiceover for what has turned
out to be
the press %um look at Big Brother today
I'll
and I've always been very surprised to
find myself invited back every year
and on
Saturday I'll do spying improv and
since a lot of your new hopefully
that'll be fun so what I'm gonna do now
is give you a professional briefing and
then I'll answer any questions you have
I apologize for being late
I was in the room and suddenly real
estate and have cufflinks
but I had a plastic bag
cell several efforts later have
cufflinks anyway
its absolutely nuts this briefing is
online actually whack is
is um is the older version of the
briefing I've change this and I've
posted to the web
and there's a if you go in press
releases you'll see the the direct link
have updated it and i cant do it with
this lousy Verizon broadband
so I will do it when I get back on but
this will be posted with the new slights
arm shortly
these are other references that are
important there are 50 points that
matter to us
free open source software hi everyone
fine and I i read stahlman spoke I
really respect him as one of the
original hackers
surely purple did a great book on on
computers says my second self
astronauts to the edge of the envelope
and I think one of the reasons
in 10 let's we come back is because my
first in
instinctive sound-bite was hackers or
national resource they're not a threat
like astronauts pushing the edge of the
envelope this society is clueless
and by the way my son is in the audience
and if anyone can identify him by
Saturday I'll give you a price
arm I promise you he doesn't look like
this
but open source software open source
intelligence or collective intelligence
open spectrum it's not stupid on
frequency allocation these days
it's not stupid charging politicians for
airtime
on Airways owned by the people so we
gotta move forward there and then
finally open access copyright an open
societies
so these last things here particularly
basic
by things that will help you we are in a
six from
war of our own making and
I'm not going to go into all the details
we don't have a lot of time I am the
number one Amazon reviewer
for nonfiction there are plenty of books
documenting
what is either the idiocy love the Bush
administration
or its brilliance and doing everything
in its own interest in against the
people's interest
either way we lose we have lost the
moral high ground
and will and Ariel Durant said in the
lessons of history that morality is a
strategic factor of incalculable
proportions now
there are a number of books that are
vastly sufficient to indict if not
convict but certainly to indict
dick cheney for high crimes and
misdemeanors
he was given the mandate for terrorism
and intelligence on day one of the first
bush term and he blew them off the same
month
the wired magazine had a cover story an
alternative to weigh energy grid
Dick Cheney was meeting secretly with n
Ronan exxon
to discuss what turned out to be false
expectations love the Caspian area
reserves
and false expectations
love iraqis opportunities we spent a
half trillion dollars on this war
for a half trillion dollars I could have
given every one of the poor people on
the planet the five billion poor people
a fifty dollar cell phone and change the
planet for ever
so what are the things I do with the
slide in these threats by the way on the
side are threats that have been
identified by the high-level threat
panel at the United Nations
which had lieutenant general doctor
brent scowcroft as the American member
these are the threats impact on us today
and in the future
and your administration is spending all
of its time and money on threats number
8 and nine and it's not serious about
threats
8 and nine it simply wants them
as excuses as pretext for war
as Jim Bamford put it in his book and as
pretext for unlimited authority to make
the law and interpret the law
which is not part of the constitutional
private is so the executive
K I'm not sure bush is as much a pop
into some people think
but I will absolutely tell you hands
down dick cheney's the guy that needs to
be tarred and feathered
run outta town of
so this puts it in perspective
in grand strategy terms Arcadia
is zip we have lost it
on debt on water
on security on energy on education
we are not taking care with all these
other threats
unfortunately in this is a direct quote
you can't fix stupid
but I caution you dick cheney is not
stupid
dick cheney is an incredibly intelligent
war criminal
he is as good as it gets at pick in the
pocket to the public
and having you sleep through it not you
guys but all the pinheads the don't know
enough to elect benefits
okay which is how America's boating
these days I'm a little upset about that
so this is a brief in a nutshell
will focus on the sixty billion a year
and I just started picking a fight with
to press releases yesterday
after eighteen years I am this far from
getting a national open source
agency funded at three billion a year
always a tough for her it's a dogfight
between the CIA which wants the open
source center
have menopausal grandmothers and young
kids and button-down shirts
from fitness to become the open-source
agency
or me I wanted to be a sister agency the
Broadcasting Board of Governors
which manages the voice of american
other public diplomacy that is largely
uninformed by any grasp of reality
which is what the open-source agency
supposed to do so
there will be a bill coming up through
the house that puts the open-source
agency under the Director of National
Intelligence
and there will be a bill coming up from
the senate that says no way Jose
and I don't know if I will win if I win
it's good if I
lose I have to start making money
instead of campaigning for this
we're spending $600 billion a year for
heavy metal military this completely
unsuited to reality
Condi Rice is I am sorry
a blonde bimbo in the skies
okay
I just keep leave she's a placeholder
for nothing
okay the department to stay is building
fortresses that shocked the rest of the
world out
people no longer go to US information
centers because the draconian measures
have security
make them feel like the criminals they
obviously must be
I have good friends in Scotland Yard
elsewhere and the bottom line is when
you're doing this kinda stuff you don't
wear sunglasses you don't wear armor you
don't run around in massive convoys
you get out there with candy and water
and food and medicine and you become
part of the community
not for rumsfeld what
well hearts and minds but but with a
little bit brainpower I will tell you
why I don't have any comment on Donald
Rumsfeld
but I urge you to read my review of one
percent doctrine
in which rom spelled is quoted as saying
any when by CIA as a loss for DOD
and former vice president Nelson
Rockefeller is quoted as saying Rumsfeld
was beneath contempt
now the same book tells you that Dick
Cheney has experimented
ever since president ford with not
informing the president United States
when ordering an action in his name
there is a clear and documented record
of Dick Cheney are surfing the power of
the presidency across multiple
presidencies
now we're not getting him impeached
right now because we got a buncha but
kissing republicans and I'm a moderate
Republican
but these republicans are all trapped in
what's called the party line
read a book by congressman tom coburn
call breach of trust how Washington
turns inside outsiders and insiders
their two kinds a corruption in
Washington
one is money in the other is party-line
voting you wanna committee office you
want a nice office with the window you
vote the party line no matter what it
means to your constituents
okay then justice FBI is moronic and by
the way eighteen Steelers not me
that's the guy missing one leg that they
tried to arrest me for in Chicago
a while ago arm I was naked at the time
I just come in for must show they
quickly figured out I had both legs
smart guy sees young agents and a
cheerleader
arm national security writ large
this is about the nurture and use of all
sources of power
it's about educated and engaged
citizenry is about carpet intelligence
now see eyes done a couple things right
we actually had bin Laden
tracked for four dates rumsfeld
gave Pakistan air corder site first
reported this in the New York right
really likes I
on also gave them an airport or us
ostensibly to
remove a few other officers and they
flew up three thousand telephone
now if they ask me for someone I had
tell you what told The Wrap
white sheets around their heads will try
not to kill my way a
arm and that will bring back to you so
you have to ask yourself is Russell
still bitter was as part of the plan to
keep okay to live
as a threat that could be built on and
then bin Laden who is a man of enormous
character
chose not to fly out that way he chose
to walk out
and CIA tracked him for four days if you
reach our break on first and
these are books by credible officers I
believe them the pentagon refused to put
up a apatite arrangers
in his path again
are we still pick got lesser is this
part of the plan
morally sound diplomacy is not
ideological fantasyland
general Tony said he was called a
traitor by this white house
for bringing up all the things he has
learned had learned as
commander love Central Command moral
cell capitalism
as opposed to predatory capitalism
balanced offense go here
Homeland Security balance budget we are
importing poverty exporting jobs who
loses
us this is what we know about the world
I
if you don't believe me let me quote
george tenet in a meeting
with all the allied intelligence East
when he said we don't know shit
the law this is what we get
to gets better we don't put it all
together
anywhere there is no place in the US
government where everything we know
comes together
there's not even any place the US
government where we think that secret
comes together
now it's my judgment
as the open source intelligence pioneer
not free
you pay for but not nearly as much as
expensive secret satellites
it's my judgment that in the larger
scheme of things
global sustainable strategy prosperity
bringing up the five billion at the
bottom of the pyramid I absolutely agree
with CK Prahalad
if we only star entrepreneurial spirits
and give them comes devices
the world will never be the same
eighty-six percent
up what we need to know about the world
in order to be an effective nation
is not secret unfortunately a lot of it
is not an English not online and not own
any asshole Washington
so we have a disconnect here only they
don't think it's a disconnect because
the white house is fond of saying oh you
must be one of those reality-based
people
we make our own reality with ideological
fantasy is the foundation
okay and looting as the objective
this is my personal estimate where we
stand today
in relation to all of these threats
and policies and that's without
considering the negative implications
for america
of the big dogs on the other side
this is your politicians worst nightmare
yes
really really bad
will come back to it
now welcome back to that's what's called
an informed judgment
arm this is reality
your government is spending sixteen
billion dollars a year
ninety-five percent of the cost on what
is arguably at
best 20 percent the value
we are spending less than six hundred
million dollars Senate focused terms
with
with the for broadcast information
service the new $20 million
dollar-a-year this is Pissin stuff
twenty million dollars a year for the
large-scale internet
exploitation initiative we're talking
here $250 million of focus
open source intelligence dollars this
doesn't count research and all that
other generic stuff
what's wrong with this picture sixty
billion for the five percent we can
steal
less than $600 million for the
ninety-five percent we really need to
now
and changing the rules to the game but
it's hard going wearing your 18
over 25 your dog fight
have a small chance at winning
the intelligence community today to
monitor and predict the outcome of a
baseball game
will use clandestine human intelligence
to bribe one or two love the ball
players out of 22
to either dropped the ball a catch the
ball at any given moment
there agents of influence the signals
intelligence community will put a bug in
the dugout
in trying over here the coach giving
instructions
the imagery intelligence community will
take a picture the ball field every
three days
and try and call the game that way
the measurements and signatures
community will try and sniff the ball
and the direction it's going and when it
doesn't work we'll ask for
ten billion dollars more
the open source intelligence community
says go Deutz
catch the ball he's out we pay
it's about harnessing the distributed
intelligence the whole earth
I know you understand this people in
washington are very free to this idea
if they bother to think about it this by
the way is the assistant deputy director
of intelligence
for open source lipstick on the pic
k we have two different views 0 votes
send his view is he wants to be a good
boy and fit in with the bureaucracy and
has his office perks
unfortunately he has no program
authority
he has no money to spend other than $5
million per year
on miscellaneous and he is not permit
Steph
he's dogged me he is lip service
my view is that we need to create a
robust open source intelligence
community
outside the government my second book
the new crafted intelligence is
available at Amazon
and it basically focuses on the obvious
maybe it's obvious to you and me but
it's not obvious to the spice and I've
been a spy and I know all those problems
lessons of history Bush did not
understand
three months into the war in Iraq that
there were sudanese
Shiites and that the majority
like Deron
and in this book I just read the end the
Iraq
Ahmed Chalabi is role cannot be
understated
the man was a masterful manipulator I
believe he was an agent of influence for
Iran
I believe that Iran has run circles
around us and I believe actually that
Iran
should be much more respected by the
United States America
we tend to confuse nationalism and a
desire for alternative energy
with conspiracy theories and communism
and all this other stuff
I'm not at all convinced that Iran is a
major threat to the United States of
America but there are a number of
lunatics your new york city
who forget that the CIA
ran a cool in Iran against the will of
the people
and we're now paying for that as we're
paying for it many other places
global coverage there's no one agency no
one country that can see all information
in all languages all the time which is
my third book
and we have to do a burden-sharing think
there are 1400 Middle Eastern experts in
the United States America
washington talked about fourteen of them
1400 14 why
well these 14 yr white their in
washington
they have clearances they may be worked
in the intelligence community previously
okay believe it or not when a CIA
analyst tries to call people in the
country they're responsible for
they are investigated by the CIA
security officers
with high school educations I got
promoted after twenty years a check in
safes at night
okay this is seriously poor stuff
and then we still need spice in secrecy
for things like transnational criminal
gangs
and so forth you can actually eliminate
most fraud waste and abuse was
statistical analysis
okay we i've one fellow that they
discovered $74 million dollars in crop
fraud
for four million dollar package love
looking I have two other guys that not
but I don't know I just know them
to other guys found fifty billion
dollars a year in import-export
tax fraud avoidance tax avoidance fraud
this is like the twenty five dollar
rocket engines going to China
and three thousand dollar pencils coming
in from China
this is advance money laundering and oh
by the way upon the coffee from columbia
actually weighs between one and a
quarter in one and a half pounds
okay so we need to go toward a national
intelligence and ever
that has shared unclassified information
it has a help desk that shares best
practices best prices
it has primary research and experts
on-demand strategic forecasting
so this is it I'm gonna try put this on
my website as a model real soon
virtual library distance learning expert
form I had a bad experience with
Wikipedia the other day
it turns out that for every 10
intelligent people there are 100 morons
like to destroy shit a and so I've kinda
given up on them although I'm gonna go
to Boston and try and learn a little bit
more about it
it's my personal view the everybody
should be allowed to post
but only certified master should be
allowed to destroy on and I think that's
a good balance
everyone can be heard and then you clean
up the system and you don't have people
do on
collateral damage in there
this is the real military budget large
one
versus the false military budget you're
being completely disease
deceived and diseased by your government
doesn't want you to know the saddest
thing in my life and all the airports I
go through a single the amputees
this government is concealing the tens
of thousands amputees are coming out
iraq
and I will tell you that after Gulf War
one we had over 260,000
disabled veterans from the combination
of uranium
and chemical brew and so forth the costs
of this war to america
over the long term are estimated at
between two and three
trillion dollars and oh by the way we
have 40 trillion dollars a unfunded
future obligations we already know about
my wife causes my gloom and doom speech
arm
this is nuts we are spending vastly more
than the next 20 people
next 20 nations on military spending
next to nothing on diplomacy was
spending next to nothing on offering ths
the Department of Homeland Security is a
massive humongous
fucked up failure okay aunque
these guys give the combination of poor
Canadia see new meaning
okay it is all believable we have a
military heavy metal and we don't have
as Ralph Peters says in his new book
never give up the fight we don't have
enough truck drivers
we have enough infantry guys and Peter
says we've outsource so much of our
military that we've outsourced our honor
and I believe that iraq has been a war
profiteering
loot fest and paul Bremer cannot account
for eighteen of the twenty billion
dollars he was given to work with
this is seriously the crap it corruption
on a daily basis that no one's being
held accountable for
we don't have enough humans we don't
have enough state local intelligence we
don't have enough public health and
water tuberculosis
is back with a vengeance in the United
States of America
okay this is serious stuff
this is reality these are the ethnic
faultlines
people weep and moan over duh for what
about the other 17 genocides going on
right now today
I had the director-general the Red Cross
speak for me back in 94 he says we can't
rely on the media
they have the attention span of one
wartime unify see Christine up a poopoo
I'm gonna through my cookies again it
just to make this is
CNN is moronic
after 18 genocide campaigns going on
today including one in Russia to in
Russia
and one in China in russia it's the top
stars and check chance
the next wars gonna be over water this
was a stupid war
that should not have been flawed
ostensibly a war over energy it's
actually were overpowered wealth
it's a war between classes I recommend
to the book on the class war
it turns out the American elites have
bought all the elites in the countries
they care about
and the elites are essentially selling
out their publics
including the american public and
they're getting away with it because
outside a few
and a few others no one is paying
attention this still hasn't hit
Joan chain six pack in their beer budget
okay so we have a ways to go but this is
reality we're runnin outta water
the mall have decir and India are
dropping a meter every year
two thousand farmers a year committing
suicide in India
overdraw debt in the in the inability I
think that's a pretty high number
2000 year K Las Vegas is gonna burp one
day and be outta water and it is going
to be a colossal real estate disaster
meanwhile los Angeles is trying to buy
them all have desert aquifer
and the people who live above it helps
figure this out there fighting it
but the reality is there are no adults
in this country willing to say hey
time-out
we need water desalination plants a
whole bunch of other things
these are the global threats for local
survival
refugees in 32 countries I mean and
complex emergencies that's failed states
refugees in the millions across 66
countries starvation
in the millions across 20 33 countries
modern plagues
with india being a particularly passed a
law in place
modern plagues in 59 countries and
rising large carrot from the New York
Times wrote an excellent book call to
betrayal of trust the global collapse a
public health the soviets have been
doing level for antibiotics
throughout the Cold War that translates
in the hookers in eastern europe going
to East German businessman going to
Chicago going to american hookers coming
soon to a home near you
with penicillin resistant everything
okay your three degrees of separation
from being totally fucked
on
and then water and stuff now if you
cross walk the US budget particular the
Pentagon budget
against
the real world threat you figure out
that the pentagon budget $600 billion
dollars is relevant to 10 percent other
threats
now a friend of mine chilmark which and
some other really smart people wrote a
defense Science Board study called
transitions to and from hostilities and
we've recently had a decision signed by
the secretary which is called defense
says directive
3,000 .cc and it places
operations other than war including
humanitarian assistance on
equal plane with war operations now this
is a culture shift because as recently
as four years ago the Joint Chiefs of
Staff said real men don't do operations
other than war
generals any was not one of those who
believe that
generals any is a pioneer and I hope
that one day he is secretary defence
secretary state
he is a really smart person and he
understands that security in peace or
about relationships at the individual
level
and we have so thoroughly screw that up
over the years it's it's
incomprehensible state versus nation
inter-ethnic tribal
gang wars genocide decolonization these
are the threats so what does a president
to a president
exist to do trade-off decisions well
I don't think it's working out that way
there are a number of books including
are price of loyalty that essentially
say that dick cheney close down the
policy process in the US government when
he became vice president he and Don
Rumsfeld
cut out all of the bureaucratic people
good people
trapped in a bad system who had
knowledge that was useful
and cheney essentially made decisions on
behalf of the president
with no accountability with a complete
and reckless district fax
for reality and
here a manner that shortly agreed SLE
against the national interest but a
hundred million will buy you a small
navy platformer ground units thousand
diplomats 10,000 Peace Corps volunteers
or hundred thousand meters above cubic
meters a decelerating water or one day
war or
trade-off decisions I believe one
trillion a year is not being leveraged
between interest on the debt a necessary
military systems unnecessary secret
satellites in a wide variety of
subsidies and tax loopholes
I can find the next president five
hundred billion dollars a year
in additional revenue for social safety
network programs that as a no bullshit
statement now for lack of good economic
intelligence and counterintelligence and
ethics at the top
we are foregoing an additional $500
billion dollars a year
in tax revenue import pricing
insurance fraud lost revenues from band
with unfairly control properties and so
forth
were not a money were a rich country
with a very corrupt in impoverished
leadership
and I crucified the democrats who are
just as corrupt but more inept
or then the republicans both these
political parties are not serving your
best interests
we've had a policy intelligence
York but jello by after isn't the answer
either
he can however be Minister of Culture in
my government up
you're welcome I heard what you said
about me two years ago
um we've had a massive failure
this matters Thomas Jefferson said the
nation's best defense
is an educated citizenry so what we have
here we have an industrial school system
the pizza creativity at a kids for the
time in the fourth grade
K we got it we gotta fix that
and and one of the reasons I brought my
son here is because he figured out how
to get six hundred SAT's
and ease without homework while sleeping
or drawing in class
on in this disturbed me but
I'm sympathetic a you guys have helped
me understand that
arm now I'm enough go through these at
blinding speed
I have reviewed over 750 books 720 books
whatever the numbers at Amazon
and you can go look at my reviews you
can find my master review sheet
you can use my lists two hours in a good
bottle wine you can get a free graduate
education in global reality
okay so I'm just gonna go through this
really quick
for the PhD it has to be a bottle of
vodka okay
alright peace operations humanitarian
assistance we're creating
black markets anarchy genocide
resource wars water totally fucked
are oceans really bad we're using our
oceans as economic cesspools
thats knots because it turns out the
oceans are more important in the Amazon
up for our future industrialized poison
were based on Corning
up globalized easy excellent book modern
strategy technology is not a substitute
for strategy in time is the one thing
you can't buy
or replace we've just screw this country
over for eight years
in part because al gore didn't have the
balls to listen to grad pabst
go to the mat on the fact that Florida
was 35 to 50,000 disenfranchise blacks
and that took the election and then Karl
Rove repeated in Ohio
in 12 districts in 2004 retail at the
bottom line is the republicans know how
to steal close elections
if the next election isn't a multi-party
landslide
were toast and I'll finish with a few
minutes
brzezinski has some good ideas failure
vampire strategic cultures resistance
this is changing over
a complexity most policymakers are
clueless
until 9/11 we had congressman and
Senator saying
I don't need a passport because nothing
that happens outside the United States
matters to my constituents
K symbolic friction revolutions in a
technical there about the mind you know
that better than most
the best dollar return on investment is
on education and women overseas
yeah educate the women they stop putting
up with shit from the man the man
do less drinking there's more
productivity it is absolutely and
indisputable fact that women are the
secret weapon for the future
we need a police force when the united
nations puts together police force every
loser from Nigeria
too well Niger
shows up at these guys can't drive a car
they can read and write
okay so it's it's really quite
ridiculous we need Constabulary Force is
these are completely different
manhunts our intelligence community
cannot find fix and follow an individual
White House does not listen
early-warning army doesn't do mountains
Air Force needs 24-hour notice to change
a bomb on an airplane
Colo alright holistic strategy you have
to do in our agency holistic study I'll
tell you right now
iraq has a successful it is because our
troops are bleeding on the ground
and giving their blood in their guts to
try and make a success
out of a really shitty situation and I
will tell you that outsider the US
military there is another mother fucking
agency this government is doing your job
the rest to the US government is out to
lunch
state isn't doing its job commerce
Treasury aren't doing their job
these people are coming in at 9:30 in
the morning they're taking an hour and a
half lunch breaks are going home at five
o'clock
we are not in a state of war we are in a
state of comatose
arm apathetic ignorance
and you guys are letting it happen K
this is the military has been betrayed
by the rest to the government and this
is dick cheney's will
he's not really interested in winning in
Iraq
never underestimate the enemy I was in
vietnam they had tunnels
going for miles they had a little guy
squat on his heels
listening spoke English to the
g3 and then walk okay they have five
thousand sickened people we have loud
mouth generals that don't wanna walk to
a secure telephone
okay the north vietnamese with little
help from the russians waxed Rs
in terms of listening in including
digging tunnels right up under the
headquarters
and having a guy sitting there listening
now this is our home from weakness it's
not pretty
one other things bin Laden who by the
way I believe is a very reasoned enemy
9/11 was intended to be in a nuclear
vent
in the sensible playing going into
nuclear thing and they pulled back from
that
because they were afraid if it's getting
out of control
that is a measured thoughtful animee
but bin Laden knows he doesn't have to
attack the United States to grab us by
the dole nights and make it hurt
all he has to do is put em bombs in
Nigeria Saudi Arabian Venezuelan drive
the price up while the 200-mile
this is it hard this is the new strategy
we need a logo
very fast on this basically we need to
redirect funds in a massive way
toward peace and I had a couple speakers
on the Department apiece in
I've had a wonderful new york contingent
no
come to corrupt the minds my washington
people and it's been fun
but the reality is colin powell gave it
up
I've always admired colin powell but I
have to tell you i think
on call Tom himself to the bush
administration
and he really let us down he shoulda
stood up and said god damnit this is
bullshit I resign and he should have
crucified
Bush and Cheney in the first
administration and I'm very sad that he
didn't do that because I had a vision
of colin powell getting a hundred
billion dollars with which to do peace
and there was no finer man on the planet
qualified to do peace and colin powell
and maybe he will come back but I think
he has lost
an enormous mantle that he once held
now getting into strategy
the White House is right back where john
kennedy was in the cuban missile crisis:
the president licence the three or four
brothers who are trusted because they
are true blue proven republicans
in Iraq the primary criteria for getting
an appointment to go to Iraq and be part
of the Provisional Government
was to be a foolproof Republican not
actually know anything
and six young people and I mean you'll
ended up running the $13 billion dollar
rocky budget and they were comparing
notes
and they figured out the reason they got
a call in been hired sight unseen over
the phone
was because they all posted resumes at
the Heritage Foundation
so for all you looking for a job in the
next two years
go post a resume on the heritage
foundation and you'll be offered a
chance to go screw up some country
on we need a director general for
national policy this national security
council is stupid
okay it is so far removed from the
reality is a balancing economics and
security and so forth we need a director
general for national intelligence
who sits on top of a director for
classified intelligence
and a director for public intelligence
and I don't have a lot of power I'm just
one man with one paycheck
but I am going to try and make this
open-source agency a litmus test for
congress
fun public intelligence or be balanced
by the public
and I think there is a mood in america
to bounce the incumbents
both Democratic and Republican and I'm
really looking forward to seeing how
that goes
we need a director general for global
strategy
America has no strategy now Dick Cheney
has a strategy
Dick Cheney's a smart man dick cheney
really understands what he's doing
however what he may not understand is
that no gated community is going to keep
them safe ten years down the road
he may not quite get that I think you
will see
retrospective war criminal indictments
I think you will see retrospective
indictments for example love the
Senators
who knew that peak oil was coming in
1975 1979
and decided to cover it up because they
wanted to continue these elections on
low gas prices
and they wanted to keep the money from
exxon coming
I think we need to do retrospective
historical truth and reconciliation
commission is
and I think we need to massively scar
some people in the public eye
in the next five to 10 years in order to
keep the rest of them honest
from now on the public now has a digital
memory
this is really important
this is what I would do with the
director-general global strategy the
point I want to make you is that
Washington is is is that is is a a very
badly managed crisis
response organization doesn't do
forward-thinking
it doesn't really work on alliances a
relationship that doesn't look at the
trade-offs
between those 10 threats that the united
nations has so ably identified
you reduce poverty you reduce disease
reduce crime
you increase water availability you
reduce poverty disease crime
okay this is all connected you know this
as well as anyone it's a network system
washington doesn't work on the basis of
networks
it works on the basis of how much cash
has been made
been paid to do Mickey Mouse copyright
legislation
or whatever okay so Washington right now
is owned by corporations not by the
people
even if you are elected by the people
the day you get into office you are
bought by your party for the party line
you want that nice of issue nafta vote
the party line or
by special interests so we need
government reform in a land with my
proposals
I believe I wish I pray and I realize it
might be
idealistic and unrealistic
I would like to see someone like Mark
Warner a Democrat
offer susan Collins a Republican from
the northeast the vice presidency
I'd like to see them identify a
coalition cabinet in advance
that is ably represented by the Greens
the reforms the libertarians
arm the by afferents are and so forth
of and I want them to
put this out before 2006 I want them to
say
these five moderate Republicans are good
republicans who want to keep them
these five democrats are bad democrats
want to get rid of them
and we swear to you 2008 is about
electoral reform
none of these other issues matter the
democrats cannot beat the republicans in
a doggone dog issue an issue
contest they can't do it the only
dog catcher issue in in america today is
electoral reform if you go for left to
reforming you get a multi-party
landslide
did Rothe can't steal the election you
get the people back in power
everything else starts to make sense
cell
these are ralph nader ish reforms
legal women rotors was kicked out of the
presidential debate process the bar
third fourth and fifth parties
from that process okay so we need to get
our priorities straight
first be strong at home attacking iraq
was idiocy
what paul Bremer did with his first two
decisions was the site he knew more
about managing a rock than anybody else
and he basically took over the country
and then he disbanded
hundreds of thousands pissed off guys
with guns
okay against the best advice and don't
get me wrong I think the military is a
bright shining light in our country
against the best advice I've army
generals so strong America through
common sense now these for reforms are
all connected
electoral reform Intelligence Reform get
a grip on reality no longer lie to the
public
the national security reform start
spending our money in the right ways
and then governance reform and I don't
know where you start but somehow all
these things need to capitalise
I've created a small website
as a non rival citizens party it's not
going to go anywhere
I mean this country's need several more
Katrina's in
911 before its gonna wake up on
but the idea here is we need a non rival
party
with a my Republican weighing a
conservative Democrat weighing all these
other guys and we have to commit
ourselves to one thing
to electing individuals who will forego
campaign contributions
and who will four-goal party-line
directives
on how they vote and we need to keep a
close string on
and pulling back that website is www dot
citizen staff party .org
it's just a few basic documents it's the
juror move an idea
I will speak for sushi anytime anywhere
thank you
five minutes for questions
on all questions to the Mike please
by the way this is the other hackers
organization
Silicon Valley hackers think I'm elected
member out there and it's fun
select cone whatever those guys
hello to your pain on the recent
wholesale surrounds American citizens
conchita love well
a couple things about that number one I
think that they they have good
intentions there's there's a difference
between
the president's grotesque deliberate
decision to ignore the Faisal loss
and two into exceed his authority and
the professional intensive NSA to
actually trying to pattern analysis and
get useful stuff
but the other thing you have to remember
is that NSA is still in the 1970s
are eighty to ninety percent eighty
percent of their stuff is offline
you know the all magnetic tapes its not
really easy to do
good stuff here arm at last but not
least SAIC massively screwed up
Trailblazer so NSA has made any progress
in the last four years
arm yessir your comment was your comment
I was gates and Buffett fit in on this
that's a very interesting question I
think gates and Buffett are doing what
smart rich guys do their hunker down and
stand the hell outta
on now Google .org
with Larry brilliant that something else
are Larry brilliant had a really good
week
he got the TED Prize for the visionary
and then he got the job as director of
global that or
to spend $1 billion or not more than one
billion one percent
of Google's annual income on doing good
and Larry brilliance number one priority
is the global
public health intelligence are network
and I've got a letter out to him as any
of you know larry global please tell him
I am NOT a lunatic
I would like to help him are because
what we need is a public intelligence
network that no government can support
okay
and has to be in your face yessir you
show
let's set up so you don't have to stoop
you're in control here push the thing
down over there okay even better
alright you show very useful a nice
charts and figures about how fuck we r I
wes is a what is your belief about
using technology in distances social
change to correct some these problems
open technology works
technology is not a substitute for
thinking what we have right now is a
system
that is biased I mean I read I read stop
spoke this morning
arm and it's a good book are
and the bottom line here is proprietary
software like he says
is software that is biased against
sharing it is software that is biased
against improving in this offer that is
biased against
helping others so I believe in what
storminess talking about are I think
technology has a solution but only if
it's free
in the sense that's all means not free
bike price but free to be shared an
approved and so forth
this is one of the reasons I enjoy
coming here I i mean i get pumped up at
this place
gone yes sir next
hi
well good place to ask you crazy
questions and
on at the risk of being well let me tell
you that in 1992 when I publish t3i
ethics ecology evolution and intelligent
so the whole earth review
it was read on the 7th for CIA in Santa
Cruz when the senior woman at sea ice at
this confirms stills play some lunatic
fringe
so you're not lunatic you just a little
ahead of the others go ahead
okay thanks I
for water in your head okay go on well I
just wanted it
well first on the whole and blonde bimbo
thing you want to watch them a little
bit
I mean you want a following in fifty
percent of us the female if you don't
understand the humor with I specifically
don't want your vote
said
but I wasn't speaking to the humor of it
I was speaking to the sexism other its
house
sexist it's very intelligent humor and
I'm sorry if we don't agree on that
point
I'm so glad you explained it to me the
other comment I was gonna ask about was
the one about
and hookers spreading disease
businessman spread it
to you might want to speak to didn't
hear me talk about German businessman
love your five minutes are up here just
Axioo I have a question yeah
question instead of being a provocative
god damn sensor
did I say I was asked questions is it
wrong to ask a question you don't agree
there are
three people four people standing behind
you
you have a class together just
embarrassed yourself
did not yes time there's myself for you
would you get rid of her
okay fine we're done and those that want
sure she could speak
you guys that have questions I'll meet
you over here