that this is network monitoring in the
and the law with Alex months
things
switch
your I'm
gonna discuss US walter is depends on
mir's everest if you are
if you're you know if your head up for
something you know
state X always talk to an attorney in
that state
this isn't legal advice you have
questions
popular in your jurisdiction maybe some
weird little wrinkle
Glee also one wanna tell you today
may change tomorrow midnight last night
actually check I was reading an 9th
circuit now
about seismic work thanks everyone
thanks to all youth thanks people
organized hope I also want to thank
Third Circuit executive office for
funding this research
and of course my Moscow okay
or eyepiece
stalking wanna system internet working
your can look you're right you're right
depend on where you know how close you
are to be someone's
authorized look at traffic so yourself
accordingly
i wanna talk about what protected
traffic is and what is in
and how can you protect yourself and
your organization
and what does the future hold try to
make some
half assed gases what future okay
there a couple important statutes that
really determine what your rights are
busy network
on fourth amendment to the US
Constitution an important one
still we hope the
wire law it's all wiretap act which has
been amended by the Electronic
Communications Privacy Act
on the stored Communications Act
definitions
a pen register in trapping trees going
to what those are and then there's the
local statutes that affect your rights
as well Fourth Amendment we still have
one
what what's left right people to be
secure
now persons houses papers and effects
doesn't say packets electronic
communications papers and effects
I'm gonna go into how this is changed
years but against unreasonable searches
a recent searches doesn't save search
some things it doesn't apply to just not
applied
non-governmental actors if AT&T looks
your stuff completely different rules
Fourth Amendment longer applies
if AT&T quest to the federal government
looks at your stuff
then it does apply however even for
a private actors looking you were
communications
there are state laws that prevent what's
going on
intrusion into seclusion now
I'm gonna go into a little bit history
lesson because the
way the fourth amendment has been
interpreted has changed over the years
this is an all rule this is this is no
longer current law but i wanna show
state because the idea was of course you
have new
privacy rights in this new fangled
telephone
think your broadcasting your thoughts
your statements
on wires your house and go
and reasonable
to the police dept you offered you it's
like
broadcasting and that was because 1928
not you know the phone was not yet
completely endorsed by everybody not
everyone had a phone in their house
roll around and that was the law until
1967 when
same thing guys a bookie
guys making phone calls placing in
taking bets
police underarms I can't put a cap on
someone no warrant nothing in the go you
know
really I think framers the constitution
would imply
that you you have a privacy writing
blood doesn't change
same for them all of a sudden the court
says
now you have a privacy right so now
is unreasonable your lines without as a
fairly strong
it this this holding kind it's important
for future use because it's
is there you have an expectation of
privacy that
you expect and then do you have an
expectation of privacy that society
expects
and we can't establish this rule kinda
for the wrong
to the fed's sniff your email
can they sniff what pack what what you
know what web sites
looking so we have the wiretap
this is passed in nineteen sixty-eight
after the cats in
and effectively codifies
its updated twice updated in 1986 when
they make it
it's no longer just phones its
electronic communication
and its updated again in 2001 the USA
PATRIOT Act
I'm through this and last minute because
FIS is kinda
interest right now a little bit in
defines a
now this is kinda got the wiretapped
interception is
acquisition contents and I highway to
back its kinda important
any electronica world communication
through any device really really really
I don't know what this means
the courts don't know what it means does
this mean that the feds can even
sniff one me wraps contents
the there's a holding
in Steve Jackson games secret service
which is
probably landmark case interception
claims
not only because it said precedent
that's followed in almost every state
its also the founding this is the case
that founded the
people are pissed off about this case
and said I want to do something about it
under the wiretap I'm you're facing up
to five years
and victim five years in prison if you
violate the wiretap
act I even if your law enforcement if
you violate
and victims may sue for whatever damages
have
and legal fees in the suit I'm
also your protectors exclusionary rule
that says
evidence taken under this is
inadmissible in federal court
now what is interception look like gotta
now half assed
map here say sending email to be
if yeah whose it comes from his personal
pc
to mail server the Internet 2 B's mail
server
down to be she wants to read the mail
before be
would-be interceptions scrapping on the
wire this was sort of an important one
to seek
Steve Jackson if see sniffs it why
what's being transmitted
its intersection wiretap if he gets
their gets between on the lawn between
copies mail server and be might
if he somehow gets access to be his mail
server
polls how storage see for example be is
a popcorn
om store waiting for be to pop in
she gets in beats the mail not
interception
that was the case in Steve Jackson where
the feds came in without a warrant
took Steve Jackson's mail server read
the mail on it
some mail before never got to the the
actual owners
and the and court said past nine
interceptions
any storage is
anything from storage is not
interception rule
other couple interception exceptions
that allows you to intercept male
under are intercepts are any electronic
communication no matter what
if you the recipient you're allowed to
look at its it's one of those
things but I think they want to prevent
you know
if you're your lab to sniff your own
track I'm
service provider now this is this is
fluid terminal show you later
agents and employees service provider
to provide service to protect the rights
and the facilities so your allow to look
traffic if you were a
if you're in ISP employees you're
allowed to look at the contents
communication to protect your own system
are your
are your customers or other people
attached your network so if you're
afraid that some
wanna your users is sending out fires
span you're allowed to look for that
were because we're into protecting
other networks attached York's which
theoretically be
any work I'm there's this review to
determine the source
harmful electronic interference seems to
be talking about
radio but I've not seen any cases talk
about it so
who knows you may also
anyone may allow either
either better state agency to come in
and
sniff your own if you either lack the
capability are you want to set this up
were some kind of law enforcement action
you were allowed to
grant to law enforcement agency without
a warrant
you may sniff my its and then there's
the final one pursuant to a valid finds
a quirk were
within the fis special secret court
the proceedings are sealed you may
granted interception or
out input from the target anyone who's
given a valid
worry if you are an ISP fads come and
say this is about 5 order
you must keep your mouth shut
however interceptions without a valid
warrant are legal
even if under color of law I'm offended
I have 85 were I go to Verizon say I
wanna sniff some packets
it's still a violation rice is protected
because it's I thought it was good you
know how much was known about 5 order is
cuz
you work but it's five years
imprisonment
ten thousand dollar fine law enforcement
officers are
not immune from OPM
so it should be interesting considering
that the 9th circuit just said that
there is no state secrets
about the various wiretap
brouhaha going on so we may actually see
some NSA
getting arrested are not
okay there is an exception
the attorney general are the president
may were
why I warrantless interception if
known that it's between foreign powers
and agents there
there has to be some finding that you
are in agent
are you are foreign power I'm I
like the second line Mike I'm curious to
see how this please
now no substantial likelihood
intercepting communications
Americans are american companies so
foreign subsidiary of the US companies
also protected under five
even this special warrantless exception
the AG must
go to Congress within 30 days are
there's this emergency within 15 days a
declaration of war
clearly what's happening if it all plays
out with this AT&T case clearly there's
some violations here
I'm not sure who's going to actually
prosecuted because it's the same
attorney general but we'll see maybe you
know 2008 there's
change regime okay
back to what we have to deal with stored
Communications Act
on this is where the counterpart two
interceptions this is what happens if
you grab something
while it's in storage this is kinda
one half the federal hacking law
there's also the commute sorry Computer
Fraud and Abuse Act which I'm not gonna
go into
is there so many cases on that it's also
fairly settled
but its accessing stored Communications
service
on not really sure what that is
because it's kinda speak but it would
seem to be
ISP's mail server could be anything that
material our data is stored on even
temporarily
there's a incidental so theoretically
even plowing and memory buffer router
would be stored Communications
before its forward there's a
interesting split here there's a done
for profit
there's a greater effect it's a greater
penalty done for
the reasons and the exceptions much
broader
owner the service so it's not just
provider for protection system its I
the router I can but i won no I'm doing
to protect it
I can I could claim to be I'm being
nosey
I'm fries I wanna see what your story on
the mail server
perfectly acceptable I can sniff it
but I can't look at Walt stored in my
mail server and then there's the
if you're accessing your own stop so
theoretically
rise in for example holding your data
holding your email on you cancel your
account
you could then go back and get what your
mail
I providers may also what the their
limited in what they can't divulge to a
third party
they can divulge content to recipient
are provide
are for communication which is kind of
an obvious ru like
we hold the state were allowed to give
it to you your the intended recipient
that's your job hired you
I'm providers may not nationally
default content are art
the fact that transmission occurred
unless there's unintelligent
weaver by the person who the risks a by
the recipient
also with a valid court were not it
doesn't have to be Faiza can be just a
regular
search warrant can be even a subpoena
civil subpoena
I'm now there's a the
there's this in a river discovery rule
that says that
if I negligently if I'm an ISP
get somehow not intentionally not
looking for
but mail from a to be talking about a
criminal act like
we're gonna go kills I'm the sysadmin
miss route and I'm reading the post
master account bounces to me
I'm allowed to tell see by its
sp Criminal Evidence are reasonably
death grievances
harm so it's not just hey bobby one help
me wasn't
tax fraud got be something serious
now there's a lesser protection given
to pen register and trapping trees this
is
not content 50 this is
should this is where's where's the
communication
going who is from their isn't anything
specifically talking about
packet routing argue this
when I when I help break the white paper
3rd circuit to say
packet header information is like is
like a phone number it's like an email
address that you have
less interest privacy interest in it
because
you have to give it to someone else for
you to get the information to where it's
going
for example you email letter you have no
right of privacy now cover up the letter
because someone has to read
to get it to where it's going
much the wiretap law says that
there's some protection on who you're
dialing
who's calling you
the own terms are trapped and register
trap and trace the haven't changed
even though I don't think there actually
already physical pen registers in
traffic trace devices anymore
by records names dates times
payment method headdresses main are also
protected
you can get those with the less with the
warrant that requires less probable
cause
but the unless there's a waiver
to the ISPR the provider
they can't divulge to a third party
so providers may use this information
either with informed consent
so in somewhere in that 18-page contract
you signed with
your provider the mail this information
third parties on for billing purposes of
course they're allowed to see you know
while you mean 25 minute phone call East
yet
well their lead to bill you for I'm
they're also want to do it for casting
armenians operations service for obvious
reasons
and then there's this terrific how to
protect the service user
are connected networks from a legal or
abusive X
not really sure what that means has in
many cases on it so it's
out there
now when the law enforcement do a pen
registers slash track and trace
if it's part of a legitimate
investigation with recipients permission
so you're allowed to say I think
someone's using my telco
my I'm a provider their using my systems
for fraud
I'm allowed to book
medicaid I'm allowed to say packets are
coming from
a to be not allowed to look at the
content without a warrant
but I'm allowed to look at syrup
information about the information
any law enforcement can also get an ex
parte a were
basically it's that its male and judge
or magistrate finds its relevant to an
ongoing criminal investigation
very low standard you know it's no
affidavits really have to come out there
anything serious just
hey we're investigating for fraud
want gooseneck can go see where the pact
going
not contact now
the remote having requirements under
kaliya I'm not gonna going to call you
can squeeze
by this eliminates the requirement
actually physically install registers
track entries
every communications device has to be
easily argued that that means it has to
be
remotely Apple with how permission
control
even notification a provider
spend it's being rebuffed by
because their such interest in this
right now
every manufacturer at least that I know
is making stuff
that you can remotely with no operator
control because God knows your Cisco you
don't want to sell stuff that
you know your thinking total cost you
wanna make sense it's like
I'm siskel comply like you know
you know this is this is also not the
y2k problem it's gonna be the new
version
okay this fits all your regulatory needs
by
should be should be interesting to see
how that plays out I haven't seen cases
argument a provider can can can install
on kal remote wiretap compliance stuff
it's not limited to voice in wire it
seems to also include
any any kinda electronic communication
so that could be radio
that could be microwave its be
open it's just like any communication
I think it could be used to describe
sniffing headers
time the date stamp stuff like that I
don't know yet
okay now their civil remedies what do
you do if
you were packets gets there's this
common law
true toward intrusion into seclusion you
can get
damages for about twenty-two states
allow
such action where it's and unreasonable
unwarranted intrusion into someone's
privacy
there's kinda mixed holdings on whether
or not you have
perfect privacy email because there's
this whole
well it's going to someone else use the
sender have no protection
because the idea is that you're sending
to a third party
third party could send now I'm
I sent an email to be it four to ten
thousand people
I therefore new protection be hasn't
interest in protecting
incoming communications so
he has no standing I have no standing
I'm sending to be
be standings for
on the stored Communications Act allows
a fine
civil fine for thousand dollars per
violation
I haven't seen cases on yet where how
they're going to find that if thats
per packet if that's going to be per
email message
that's going to be well you read 1800 my
email messages
you thousand dollars don't know yet
um electronic wiretap act
allow civil suit against private parties
for damages but
and state agencies are in you to civil
suit on
that's why I the case against 18 he's
going
AT&T because they can say
we finally did your rights have a nice
day where
I'm gonna go in a couple interesting
cases now
about in how interceptions kinda falling
what privacy rights you have
in your electronic communications in the
workplace
home at schools
recent one guarantee John Handcock
you have no expectation of privacy works
9 even did this is this is kinda scary
is I red parts the John Hancock
manual it said you do right of privacy
we will not divulge any emails unless
they're necessary a John hancock
violates this
in this case in the court says that's
fine
so even if there's like a we're going to
give you privacy
your privacy
however cover you which is kind of
equipment
um even the makes kinda felt that
wealthy do staters privacy
you have a privacy right however I'm
sure every employer
is saying you privacy right just to
protect themselves
hmm to kinda weird splints
there's a to come not cases that
any user can grant permission to view
website
so on have I register to use
a password-protected website I sign
Terms of Service
say Irish I will not divulge my pastor
anybody
I handed off to be who does not sign the
contract doesn't click
you know I agree and
website website operators as women you
die
you improperly came in its
to bed any user can grant access kinda
creepy
because then you could have you
you can have a disclaim its new law
enforcement come in they can come in
however this there's a split in this
thinking
this kinda creepy case out Chicago
Citrin where they said its unauthorized
access
to use your own work laptop it was
deletion beta keys where even though you
haven't quit yet
your going to quit you've decided that
I'm not going to work for you anymore
using my work laptop
to start kinda feeling for other jobs
and
the owner are the sorry the authorized
user
the laptop lost their authorization to
use it for the quick for the employees
you and the
civil charges kinda scary because it's I
don't know what this means is completely
in flocks
will probably take ten years from just
wash so
right now kinda scary
the PK's going on right now changes that
whole
intersection problem I talked about
councilman
is a for circuit thats basically New
England
minus Fermont pa Sport Rico
kinda true the circuit strangely
by whose scum
he offers free web access I'm sorry 3
web email packages to
people that do business with he sells
rare books
what he does that was he says well I'm a
provider under
stored Communications Act and why hacked
wanna do is minutes any rights has code
written
thats out any stuff going to I'm
in a row so he can hold back email
and then make a better offer for
whatever book thereby
on school dot-com era but you think it's
kinda creepy when
yeah I want to buy this rare book gonna
get a better price like
you know or less from the guise of from
email
how do you know what I want book so they
go and complain
to it's the feds come in and say
overcharging you
interception he's thinking I'm safe
because
I grad Mike on system
and the effectively the fed's get a
conviction anyway
kinda through everyone watching this cuz
its no
store communications wiretap bounced
around the courts
a the the appellate
the Appellate Division the appellate
court said no
its we're gonna hold Steve Jackson
and have where all were all the judges
answer
Consett me here the hear the case he
said no
you got the email before intended
recipient it's now interception
changed everything has not yet been
followed
so Steve Jackson case is still good law
everywhere but New England no other
circuits followed
but it kinda makes this interesting
split so
you know if your gonna do this stuff
do it somewhere else
and the per makes a provider protections
so much more limited we don't know where
it is
read that I read that and you may be
five or six times I don't know how
providers
see so
what is was all boil down to if your
provider
you can intercept some communications
your generally safe your
doing it for legitimate reason to
protect your own systems
your networks your users
store stuff that's in storage less
protection
and stuff that is being transmitted
there's
greater interest on the wire
communications I'm
it just seems to have a wall please out
on councilman still first good
still good law only in the First Circuit
has involved anywhere else now how do
you protect yourselves
get the consent users getting writing
either in terms of service or separate
den
if you are employees and you you happy
reason get permission from your employer
in writing because you won't be able to
wave at around someone complains
better yet have written your job
description if you have one
guests its it's a nice piece evidence
say no I'm allowed to be here
really because there could be
convictions someone who say works on
helpdesk
says wall you know you know I decided to
just
I bought this I got you packet sniffer
wanna test
now in fact that was a line I got from
the prosecuting attorney and Councilman
which said
you have a legitimate reason we're not
gonna prosecute but if you just wanna
play with
the real will come after you
that point I was like yeah guess I won't
be doing
I'm and if you are
the provider if your employer have a
sniffer policy
says you may when you may use this who
may use it
when may you use so that way
everything's really nice and clear so
that way
if God forbid get prosecuted are you get
sued for it
you can point to that and say we found
her own rules
therefore were on the clean side
I kinda rush through that cuz we're
running a lil bit later many questions
yeah
and I'm sir and I'll what's the other
computer if
you're not if you're not capturing
anyone else is packets
you should be okay the problem is you
think I'm gonna
like hot network not a switched network
you may grant packets
are yours so
your than up for yeah
okay
it's still an electronic communication
they've modified its in the
modification of the Patriot Act I
believe what they say expressly
mentioned
these they talk about I VOIP
and capital I you may not use this you
know it's a violation
to a new way horned blah blah blah blah
that seems to be a hold over to say if
you're convicted for
phone harassment but you can say well
it's not phone its VoIP
so it seems to be that any electronic
communications covered by I'll
stuff okay yeah
question is your security vendor you get
measured from the company
companies liable US sacred OKC your
third-party your each and the company
a hard you to come in and say please
never packets okay
but they are not allowed to do I'm not
sure
I think you you've got some defenses by
even having defense is coming into this
is means you might be up for some
litigation
in a civil sense I think the Fed to be
less interested because you're
it's harder to prove the criminal case
and would be civil case I think you'd
wanna have some
as much documentation says we're doing
this for a legitimate reason
anyone else
yeah
you mentioned allowing party which
signed your terms services to allows
third-party access your website
or network let's say that you had a
Terms of Service
degree to everytime they logged on with
that sorry
I didn't hear that if you had a terms
services
that party agree to had to re
agree to every time they log on and they
allowed party see into the website
like you know the password with that
also by party see to
those terms services yes it could by
if a terrific
that the click track you know are and
click rapper
are are Opera House browser app license
it seems to be
binding however it would still not
if if be CP's an authorized user
be gives see these password and logon
see still bound by the contract
but they're not violating the stored
Communications Act
even though you a as that provider like
I don't see here you know so its kinda
it's kind it seems to be in flux right
now I think you had a really aggressive
prosecutor
you might be able to get something but
you realizing your terms service you're
also protecting yourself your
by saying if you come you may not get
your passwords you have action against
B&C see for coming in on authorized be
for
hanging up password thank you you
encrypt the contents of your packets
does that have any influence on the
expectation of privacy good question
there is a key out have
have I think the Southern District
Florida
on the case seen on this one's couple
drug dealers
using they're using friction over radio
they want said he wasn't guys is just
like voice scrambler
the court said well you listened
in and because you encrypt it said
you your subjective expectation of
privacy was dues
so then they allow that in wasn't
the wasn't wire it was just Street 4th
Amendment case
so I think you're right I think it does
reduce your
expectation of privacy ironic has been
held up
that memory contents are stored if it's
incidental
if because it seems to know X systems
per se it seems protect
communications I don't know
help for that goes have in many cases
where it's like purely machine
Commission communication
not human initiated if it's
if it's if it seems to be electronic
communication that's in storage however
incidental
then it would be protected under stored
Communications Act said
crypt clear
still prosecute 10
I'm gonna see your whose who's doing the
said use in
communication Sep crack
prosecutor because but it
what's the evidence you don't having if
it's not cracked it can't be presented
we have you know and you can you know
skill defense
yeah that's that's you know 18 por not
legal
thank you still continue mystic yes yes
yes they could well they couldn't
prosecute they would arrest you and I
you and then wait until the cracked if
your network with and
bpm connection that is
servicers with your network are you
allowed
packets their traffic your who are your
provider
you you own the land but you offer
employees or something
but someone employees should have access
gains access and you try packets their
traffic over the
I think your project under whole
defensive your network rule
that says that while you're on
authorized user therefore I'm doing this
to make sure that my systems are not
being used to
fractional you know for fraud abuse and
to defend
other systems because you're you know
your land theoretically is connected to
the rest
internet so you could then say no
I'm allowed I'm allowed to look at the
content of these packets because
I'm protecting my self so
University sir
the students for Sensible Drug campuses
decides
traffic to look for crimes resist the
mall
yep you
just connection months at a time
just campus this comes down from
higher-ups
if it is a private network actually just
State University then mines Fourth
Amendment
due process and for I'm sorry mines
Fourteenth Amendment Due Process also
implies
fourth amendment that you had
unreasonable search however given
its University somewhere in the terms
service there may be a
we allow we're allowed to sniff whatever
we want whenever we won
if there wasn't I think you have a key
space wifi its it's still
electronic communications so sniffing
Wireless
70 miles connection with the same
sniffing a wired connection
you some part in the wiretap says stuff
that is
broadcast with the intent of being
generally received
and it seems to be more imply radio like
than a.m. shortwave that there's no you
know
on ninety 1.7 college radio broadcasting
you listen
well that's kinda hinge by if it's
if it's a if its electronic
communication that your not
arguing is were widespread consumption
you would then have some protection
yeah
this is this is wireless there is that
seems exception says your allow to sniff
content to you find out sources
interference for your network I think
the
still women because it's you can sniff
18 packets to figure out somethings
interfering with I think
there some you know some reasonable yes
I don't know yet but
that's how I that's how I would
yet
yeah use my if you're
organization acceptable use
is extort
if you
what you want to do is in your UP our
Terms of Service you wanna have
the can look track you won't have that
protection
clearly its looking for violations the
terms
service different what we're looking I'm
not sure if I'm I'm being clear on that
you wanna have we are allowed to look at
your
if your use of our network presumes
we're allowed to look at yourself
you won't have that wine there more than
just were looking for
violations abuse because the you seem to
be
it seems to be more narrowly defined it
seems to be:
fraudulent abusive
like if someone's when your network by
by you know doing packets for that would
be
that would be acceptable if it's you
don't like that
for the call the conservative college
its it might be a violation
service you advocate for
for it three-drug society but it might
not be still
finally your privacy rights here
is see
see monitor
for I think you could argue that it's
you're preventing abuse or fraud and
shrug your shoulders and say look
think it might be you might be doing
fraudulent use said
think
I think so I you get it in writings that
we've got a far better defense to say
told you we could do with their for your
use a wave versus then
this sort of like we're looking for
abuse good someone to
argue well is use things
you are sir
weren't which here it seems
there's a key recent case it seems you
too because it's a violation
due process you however only talk to
that boy
you can you can't call up user that's
being
has you know if you're if you're nice P
we want to look at your user you can't
call say
a you should hire you can hire a word if
you're you comply with the order but I
don't think you can
inform anyone else but I don't know if I
this kind of weird I don't you know what
I don't know about Canadian
I think approaches everything so
I believe it seems to be the other
nations laws
seem to be other than europe seem to be
mirroring
US their or European EC directives came
down
much much stronger on privacy I'm
starting to think
you to host any servers posted somewhere
anything else
cool thank you very much
just a quick announcement there's been a
schedule change today
at ten o'clock
now 8 o'clock military time the kevin
Mitnick unplugged and the of the
off the hook happened swapped so
on the kevin Mitnick unplugged is going
to be on Saturday
an off the hook is going to be today