up
after a bit of
or server logs word
yeah could you be more disruptive no way
one running okay we're back MapQuest for
example
will take your phone's GPS and will
remotely access MapQuest system
to tell you where you are what's near
you at any point I'm not
that's very convenient for you but
there's a big trade off and everything
privacy convenes MapQuest will be able
to tell
the person with such and such a phone
number which they could force
rather rapidly trace is at such-and-such
a location
trust me I'll be able to access that at
some point
he's a real world example which what we
do this for law enforcement and
and governmental agencies I'm very big
on real-world examples
Riverside County California if you are a
DWI
if you're convicted of DWI they make you
wear an ankle bracelet
when you're not in jail they make you
work for your tire service
you have to agree to that if you don't
agree they said no problem
for 10 where we were yards on early
prime we'll put you in jail druthers the
tracking bracelet would rather chill
I'll take the trucking breast know they
have a program set up
using official office of that tells if
your GPS location
is a ball or is a car rental agency
is a strip for is anything on a list
that i think is 14 or 16
for hepatic plays this is the real world
forms
it's that easy and by the way the GPS
trackers this
that they put on the on the guys ankle
is the same one that's in
almost all cell phones more personal
information that you give up for
convenience
TV TiVo cable everything you watch
when you watch it you know
there's nothing but you do with your
cheever machine that is not set back to
the mothership
what your whites or do you watch
sporting shows do you watch who were no
do you watch you know i tivo'd she'll
they connect
sure they going to do something from
that either offer cop failed
drug deal you know one or the other
Arnold but all of these
all these services supposedly for
marketing purposes
index in record everything you do and
I'm gonna tell you
what you watching TV especially watch p4
to watch on TV pay-per-view is a
terrific window into your personnel
now mind you there's
a great deal now
over of people mixing and matching
businesses
cable companies not only know what you
watchin cable
but maybe you get your phone service
from maybe you get all the services from
for rising is now gonna be sowing
broadband TV
it's not going to just be the in the
past if I wanted to find something out
about someone
I have to go to multiple sources from
multiple times have information it's
one-stop shopping
you know who you talk to on the phone
when you're in the house what you
watchin TV
and so on and so forth money
anything that you do have any interest
involves money
your restaurant
you buy a book you travel somewhere
you payee a parking meter
every time you do anything with money
plus cash it struck
everything everywhere every time now by
the way
it's not only attracts but it is now
capped for far far far greater lengths
of time
and it's kept in one location another
there is a good reason for that they
want to track terrorist activity
they want to track wire transfers if a
guy gets three transfers from a
terrorist facing Yemen
they want to be able to find him I don't
know
why Department of Homeland Security
thinks that
terrorist on use ATM's but they
record everything and because the
Patriot Act
it's kept forever and it's immediately
available to the US government
and by the way that includes Pay Pal Pay
Pal
just have to search all the records for
people who use Pay Pal
in the United States but have bank
accounts
that are connected to that paper lookout
outside the United States
how many terraces been court 0
how many people with foreign bank
accounts that didn't declare a mother
taxes
have already been arrested 140
everything that you do its record
everything that you do
other information can be extrapolated
from
in for USA is a perfect example
of the stealth amalgamated this is a
company
to study I'm you forgive you for your
search.
a okay I want to say less than five
percent of the rumors that means
this company has more information on you
than almost anybody on the planet
they buy it every motor vehicle records
every driver's license
every real property records every
telephone record every business record
um they have marketing list so you can
imagine
doctors lawyers engineers everything
that you do
they suck it into their system and they
prepare targeted marketing farms
its astounding bankruptcies
court judgments criminal records
everything
they are estimated to have Los to
a hundred individual records on every
American
here's examples have some other stuff
that they have
just in their basic service that they
make available national change address
records
David Hanson services with a turgid not
just
demographic records but psychographic
records which were gonna
going to a second email appending they
attach
your email from one source your name
address telephone number date of birth
Social Security number
it's such a researcher from other
sources I am
penetration reports penetration reports
or
what can be sold to you easily
another word what she likes and dislikes
or
let's talk about target marketing
this is the most insidious gather
information
every time that you do something
commercially
it's reported one way or the other
through credit for purchase
or through warranty for or through
rebate
or what have you people know water
computer you use what type of wine you
drink
or if you drink wine what type of books
you read it
up have you contributed to a charity
have you contributed to a political
campaign so on and so on and so on
things that can allow a third party
to accurately and immediately deduce
exactly who you are what your
personality is which'll likes dislikes
religion
sexual orientation politics that
separate search or about you
these guys by this up by the church
Greenlawn
every magazine subscription think about
if I stood by your mailbox so
every magazine you receive would tell me
a lot about your personal character
sure look every magazine subscription
is sold no such thing as
a private subscription to newsweek
or a private subscription pic at famous
your journal
every time you call an 800 number or 888
number
it logs to your who your call are you
calling
tech support for your new ultraviolet
grow light
it's what every product service every
product registration
and this is wat every target Barker
wants to know about you does know about
you
let me give you two real-world examples
these are two cases of dog
first guy he subscribes to soldier of
fortune magazine this is real case
soldier of fortune magazine American
rifleman
Washington Times he recently purchased a
force of reason
he's a registered Republican and is
listed in focus USA which is being
marketed
focus USA's christians did Christian
donors loves
anybody here not know what this guy is
all about
is a right way Christian going on
republican which is basically me except
for the Christian
or Mexico
subscribes Village Voice High Times
cat fanciers he purchased
Chomsky's obnoxious in the american
recent book
he's a register Green Party voter he
contributed to the United Jewish appeal
the gay men's health crisis an American
Friends of peace now
this guy's a left-wing jewish homosexual
yes now I know it's over sexual not
because a
gay men's health crisis because all
captain
no no these are these are real these are
you know he's a real
actual real profiles here's an example
of what's
available out there this is just one
outfit corny marketing they have
something called
court in a pickle lets people who are
clearly having trouble paying their
bills quit
amigos which is their condescending
thing for Hispanic people were looking
for loans
desperately seeking products domain
registration all
people working from home I know about
this because I bought up that list
before I was able to put water
together myself we do a lot of work comp
investigations
for insurance companies of your own a
business from your house
in maybe you shouldn't because i'm
concerned.
outdoorsman product buyers verbal
advantage so on and so forth
these are databases that tell you a lot
about the people on the list
by the way this I put up your cousin
just cracked me up
this use the basically
the loser marketing list his fault
astrology success
I don't love astrology success customers
have responded to a correct mail
solicitation
or fring n show like intervention
okay 60,000 people
not this we'll tell me if you're on this
list your clinical notes
to I want to find out if you're gay I
could find a home insurance
through your purchases through what
books you read through
a whole variety of indicators that you
can extrapolate out to
but if I get really lazy I'll check to
see
you access gay web sites or do you
read magazines or respond to
solicitations
specifically targeted for
gay or lesbian persons know this
got a packed away show you later if
you're interested there's even a
magazine
called palms Proc which is for the
people who are HIV-positive
I can't imagine working more on this
from subscribe to that little body no
his HIV positive noises the most on
distrusting I'm a planner
but even that isn't a database
three major companies which by the way
are
routinely accessed by private
investigators
have hundreds of billions of records on
these people take every bit of data that
they can beg borrow and steal
and the amalgamated and they offer
personal profiles
or everybody in america that are
accessible
by one piece of data entry I can put in
your social security number
the whole file comes up I could put in
your telephone number
and the whole file comes up I can put it
your
specific address number by that I mean
Street an apartment number
everybody at that address comes up with
their farms
this is routine now here's what's
in cities not there are good reasons for
this
fun to lend you a hundred thousand
dollars I need to know if you're that be
weasel if you're going to be a nanny in
my house
I should be able to find out if your job
loss
but here's where it gets obnoxious
the US government is the largest
customer of these companies
he's with the US government does US
government says
your choice point you've got so many
records in there so useful tools
here's all of our stuff to
criminal records contact lists
everything
merging with your stuff create a
separate file that's only accessible
for law enforcement which these
companies have done
and let us access it on a per search
cases
ChoicePoint accurate margins incisive
also
cool what they do for free I did you pay
us to access your own player
so choice points I said wanna head
did this now I so want to file a Freedom
of Information Act
request and find out what sort of
information can the government access on
I'll no freedom of information is a
private business records
there there the government provides a
lot of the info
the government accesses the in for
whatever they want
but it's not a government worker very
very sleepy
here's all listed companies purchased by
choice for the past five years
and by the way I could give you 10 pages
the easiest thing in the world for you
to do is go on the SEC side look at the
10 caseworker
go on their own site probably find this
hymie everything from
insurance screening to DNA screening
public records provider drug testing
company drug screening company
insurance rating company medical review
company
DNA identification company
pre-employment
email database before the purpose if
this is
they take any matching point the merger
to go
here's subsidiaries have chose
no here's what's coming facial
recognition
cameras everywhere and cameras
everywhere
that have a brain behind them that looks
at your face insist
thats Paul and reports it into a
database
these or actual
a I'm a
locations of cameras in a spot in
Manhattan
I believe that this is that this is
where where Broadway and Seventh Avenue
intercept
98 2003 2008
no england is a good example of where
we're going
it is estimated that in England the
average person just walking around doing
their thing traveling around
have a normal day is on camera was 400
times
facial recognition software will allow
somebody to determine
where I am at any given moment of the
day
that can fix
you on campus Colorado
University Colorado some guys had a
slogan
you know smokin par
University Colorado first ride
putting up the photos of all the people
say film everything no
at you see they put up the photos of
everybody on a Web site
so slipshod if you know who this person
is let us know we'll give you 100 books
nobody responded so the winner they got
a program which cost them all up eleven
hundred dollars
the cross-reference these photos with
student ID's
every single person identified was a
stew when there are people who
came in of Canada safely from bone
all the students Cup yeah got
identified I got more identified on the
UC web site
I would imagine hat a very ugly time for
people love video people love still
photos because
for his number one he cover photo room
the the famous has while shooting I love
this
nope although if you look if you look
behind the the Texas Ranger
you see the guy who did this we did this
thing to his face
but you know photos overall just thought
I'd throw that out there
no Hughes on no other fairly
insidious technology that's gonna be
cataloging everyone had identified
current location over
this is actually in use in England
your ports its Katie recognition
technology
and the theory behind it is you know you
can put on a mustache in a big rush
remarks nose in a way to get a
and and do whatever you want but you
walk down the street to say we're even
if you try to disguise it
you know your your behind as a certain
number of centimeters this where the
I'll I don't know how it works I'm not
an expert on this
but apparently it works really really
well
you know we go into this but I will tell
you that there
used today a product available to law
enforcement
up put up by a company called Empire
North that allows the police
to shoot a radio frequency ID tag
into you and track your that you can
beat a reply to lose
and it's being used by the Copenhagen
Police Department
so I don't know figure out where this is
going to go this is just so
let you know what's in the future and
freaking out a little bit
we're almost done with the with the
generic examples
gonna go to rid the region but we're
talking about psychic graphics
cited psychographic is predictive
profile
and it is just remarkably accurate I use
it all the time
the government uses it a hundred times
more than I do
and certain private companies that want
to develop marketing lists
use a thousand more times than mean the
government put together
the first really good use of this was by
Volkswagen you know you gotta figure
Germans were
come up with something like this but
they found out
if you own cat
you bite chunky peanut butter not the
Brent just the chunky kind of peanut
butter
you are much more likely to be
interested in buying a VW bug
so they boil the catalyst and they
bought the chunky peanut butter list
and they put it together and they have
you know coverage at
day marketed to these people and they
sold it on a VW Bus
the real real marketing campaign
this is used like may edit in political
campaigns these days
the first go to do this was of course
what they call Bush's brain call rolf
call roll Michael targets voters
where you live what you're purchasing
habits or
so on and so forth can allow him to
determine within your certainty
who you gonna vote for and how likely
you are to go out to the polls
now if you're inclined to vote for
george bush but the profile shows your
lazy fat ass
he's gonna said a Republican van by to
pick you up to take you to the polls
if you are a real enthusiasts and you
are technologically adept you may try to
have you come down to work the phone
banks
and that sort of thing it's incredibly
accurate only just ridiculous things he
discovered like
bourbon drinkers are republicans June
drinkers and Democrats
don't know why but it's true
world should you should use my database
quiet no heckling or interrupting on
what was going on
I don't mean that there are things like
the average American is no I'm friends
drink smoke from the serial ball
each 25 pounds you can deal year
has lost 12 teeth by age fifty to the
candy probably and for for smooth peanut
butter over shortly
everything there is to know the No and
they know it connected to individuals
they an
back to the back to the Volkswagen guys
they're doing again with Jeter
they have put out hundreds of thousands
up these four farthings it's on the web
is there we go to have you don't you're
is once more important than breakfast or
did you sleep last because the time
spent on the Internet
sneaky way of saying you stop him from
your computer all day
is the first place you go for
information is the inner you prefer to
shop with your friends you like to spend
a quiet evening at home
what the rest do folks were gonna
continue the
examples of quick and dirty
interpretation of data
that is available on everybody
an air force employee move stock
holdings from Boeing and Airbus
you check flights to iraq before Obama
you buy a book
on fighting cancer normally buys a book
and fighting cancer Eliza they were
somebody
they care about his kids you run a gay
porno movie
como you put in address into MapQuest if
you put in address into my quest
you have some temporary or permanent
connection to the address you have an
interest in their trust
you fill a prescription for Xanax you
fill a prescription for violating
necessarily in that order here's my
favorite one
push this is from a real case you're on
a plane four times a year
sitting next to the same warm was not
you
come on now adults
let's talk about wreck Dakine rick is
not here
right Britain luck assays are checking
cuz he's really not a chicken
records in Florida probably gleefully
dancing naked in the young manatee
Democratic Club which user and
a leader of arm know he couldn't make it
here he had an early Thanksgiving thing
with his family
he said he would try to make it very
probably wouldn't
we put out a call on be off the hook
radio program for a victim a volunteer
the soccer Kendrick said my name is Rick
taken
I'm willing to be your guinea pig
an that's the actual email at all that
we had was a
domain address and phone first thing I
did was I i win
I read his phone number three so-called
tell a tour or you put in the phone
number gives you name
Druce gives you address history data for
social security number
everything from the phone number a
cross-reference businesses and
everything
this is the actual told a role in its
report
then I'd put him through skip trace
America which easily
database pose a lot more information or
so on and so forth we pretty well
determined that he was a real gun
so I can recall I said hi Rick how are
you on
Stephen Obama and for this is what we'd
like to do it
he said okay now let me tell you for the
2004 hope convention
I had a volunteer also and the guy Inc
came to me before the day before though
convention
I think he even come to be called me on
the phone with his lawyer
and he said listen I reviewed everything
you found them he said as a courtesy we
should be everything you from
so I can your situation I sent it to
we called me the next day with his
lawyer which was the day before though
convention said
you know what I know that I gave you
permission but
if you put it up there I'm just to see
in
this time went to my lawyers and I said
I want
you most all-inclusive obnoxious receive
release you've ever seen she drew it up
affects the tour ok
got worse his little shaved
he agreed to soften we just reach one
paragraph
paragraph through polo remade
disseminate any information about
Lauren's my first given to see
any information about me which obtains
and/or compiles to any person
in any venue as it sees fit even if the
dissemination of the information
could cause me harm emotional distress
pain
injury humiliation or ridicule or other
personal or for financial damage
and even if the information disseminated
is partially or completely false
why okay you'll notice is notarized
signature
I told him I want your last any did
so then with your investigation riddick
notice to just have
put this in context let me tell you what
we did what we did
we did not go out into the field now as
an investigator
we do database investigations on
everybody who becomes
of interest to us a client a witness a
subject to suspect would have
but we always take that information as a
starting point to go out into the field
because you can find out twenty times as
much actually
knocking on doors and talking to people
then you are just from databases data
bases give you a phenomenal sore
important
but that's it we wanted to show
just strictly on a privacy issue basis
what we could phone we can go onto the
field we didn't talk to anybody not even
on the telephone
we didn't do any dumpster diving by the
way great source of information on
persons there
garbage we didn't do anything illegal
anything gray area
or anything even though we have you're a
believer will release from me said
King a credit card does my phone does we
didn't do
not other we also didn't check a single
non public access governmental the arabs
started with her thing called a row
jurors you put in a guy's name address
telephone number
and it gives you back every reference on
the net even
on the deep work every reference to the
we then went and ran it through our own
it you know how service called I
opportunities
and then we use that this factually
something that's being put up it's kind
of a closed system
for investigative associations called
or Inc on more investigators network
when we used to as a beta test subject
to the
gauntlet we are medium we almost
immediately goes in
we got his address we got his telephone
number we got isn'ta
social security number date of birth we
got isn't our
residences stood missus walrus insist
we found no
who is who and what is a central system
with him and I mean less than five
minutes we found that is true name
his social security number his date of
birth everywhere he overlooked
was okay no to pose for a report would
use
a pretty overall good gusta
report we found that is a property owner
I where is a property owner we pulled up
the property details loses all public
worker
we did this through private database
because it's pointless in-house
this is all public record your father
you know it was
there's a million online databases you
can do it without even looking county
courthouse
want either County property appraiser we
found that was worth
and by the way it said condo in Sarasota
and it said it was only worth eighty
nine thousand dollars intriguing
balloons
so we want to Adele
online so schools will which is four
units available
to everybody most amazing real estate
site ever told you what the properties
worth
even gives you so I'm sure to love
we found 0 was how does work to the
bosnian
then we decided without leaving the
office to take a quick look at the
problem
so we use Google Earth no reason then
was a looonnngg I've overlooked was
looking
up the solar yeah it's actually a photo
that we that we found love you to adjust
further than the this among other things
with the funds for
we found out more details about as a
poor blue
being good investigators we noticed
going back to the
so I photo there's a huge s parking lot
and he lives in Florida with his no
public transportation
so check for coral reef studies you must
the protrusions
paid all and the license plate
you know what will skip by this
we were in the condo address this is an
example of what you can do today
that you couldn't do five years ago were
10 years ago
you can run address you notice the
person we found out his company
we found 0 I would say was
was 43 pages
I love internet and online references
yep 43 purges we found a consumer info
which showed bunch of places where he
works
if you wanna suffer he recovers to
you we also found out you can now run
through private databases
people's domain names by their name we
can forget the domain name we of
he he personals we found out he had
a domain name pointer feely up yeah
which is now down it's no wonder or we
felt that up by
going into Wayback Machine please no
jokes about getting back up with you
okay by following
individual latex we found I mean
he is a perfect example we found his
author's bio
online licence or sooner worry what the
college were you tempted to get and a
that he's a game designer the large
Dungeons and Dragons
the help from critics who you know 0 ke
mafioso %uh he's working on a sequel to
give mafia
where he likes of coffee every day the
is active in local democratic politics
but when I saw the investigations again
thousand-dollar report
we won what time zone we focus every
book the wrong
we want to use work his MySpace page
know this is he took on MySpace page
we have his interests that actually
sounds ridiculous interests
we have his friends we have his school's
American University
Pineview school for the gifted so it's
kinda scared
yeah we find that we find out he's
involved in publishing writing is a
novelist
%uh that he works at Blue King studios
even was
kind enough to right next to the iPhone
the dim sum
you he's single
a he's intimidating he 6-foot-1 a
bodybuilder whiting
he's a ates he's an Aquarius need
a he's a boy who were you went to school
was
interests or what type of music he likes
movies Yonex
television bossy
hooks group
that because I knew Dakine dot com
I wanted to the directories on his
website which were in close pursuit we
love you
and iPhones entire resume everything he
ever wrote
I want the research team of you
found out he's a %ah not just a democrat
forever
ever-growing thought at one time it was
an eyewitness
that when he was in an unstated
medicines for this week the book because
it wouldn't
he probably got a ride on the world
didn't even have to pay for
that he downloads podcast because he was
kind enough to do it
to move already taken dot com from a
buncha left wing radio silence
he listens off the hook by the way I'm
por que es also
I also simultaneously
he downloads a rumor
some wahoo this blog posts
what now you consume can't sleep so I
will lead me
and the world we know exactly what would
say no one was ever found yourself a
this one was a typical blog usually
what the guys thinking what he's doing
who is doing it worth
so wats the photos are up lets him by
the way
a lot kicking convention you
and we were able to determine by
combining public had so many public
databases
whose funds or will they or I don't grow
up makeover making a killing 34 New York
left-wing as a que
shown 27 is a comment from the airport
in New Jersey
now love you so sony's a blocked 0
reviews is screening rained August 25
have
know she's in Tomball Texas so on and so
and soul
were able to find out his dad is get
mother and their Stephen Karen
is that is George Clooney condo near
Route
he's got no felonies a serious lawsuits
we found a cell phone that it's not just
the June weaving things I don't forget a
lot like this but I B you for always
we found that for example when he was in
San Jose he like the whole release
but working critics who you know if you
look at is
bond profile back then he likes tired
Mexican food
here hume we have actually this was an
interesting moment I thought we found
something really cool
thought we found a winston
during our investigation we found out
he's affiliate
without food it's also took digital
through he hosts there of course
that's rich picture right there from the
newspaper
the smiling guy with the initiative to
but when I want to Cryptic Studios
website
iPhones saudi and Kyle Clauss
who looks just pointing I mean
identically working
so %uh the same done I V
for reader she identical
it civil no we have to stop and do an
investigation
we find these are not know the real
history with the real social security
number when Rick was in
said it was a living his life in getting
into the database is an
being tracked to have described to you
the stockpile cross was a source of
Florida
leading his own life so unless
rick is incredibly deranged frequent
traveling
so both two different guns and he was
worried worked out but
me just recap on what we were able to
find four and a half hours
rocks address and every worries over luv
they'll as an adult and when we lived
with his parents
phone number cell phone number his
entire employment history including wage
working now
his politics his past politics
his religion his sexual orientation
what he reads what he watches on TV
so on and so on and so following a half
hours
not leaving the office stopping drinking
a cup of coffee
that by the way is my mourners leaving
you can see Figures
since I haven't picked up by now you can
go for
there really is no that's not what
series
was also know is a point so buddy monash
into your room so
now is to mars is a communal find that
stuff for us
you
most people or you go wall who opposed
to being in databases
or they have the feeling you know
they've been gathering info on me for
years
there's nothing I can do about it
privacy is dead
I might as well just get used to it
basically
lay down and enjoy it and there really
is a need for a lot of his name
have something simple and you thousands
or millions of dollars they have a right
to know what your financial history
the creditworthiness is for example
mortgages
pre-employment I wanna know if you're a
blood draw insight about
before I use my perceptions for example
if I meet somebody on wall I am or or in
person for that matter
I came back to the whole what drinking
segment
I'd like to be able to find out who they
are Morgan
if you can marketing problem
you could bring things to consumers
sheeple I feel less annoying one
if you are not interested he didn't play
carriers because you're allergic to
peanuts
I don't want to be sending you 50 pet
carrier solicitation of course
and I want to be able to effectively
chiefly so my pet carriers
so I can lower the price a lil
another problem is today
I don't know only talking about
terrorism people from overseas whatever
unknown identity even if the person who
knows
idea to social security number but a
popular
when all other a noted that these
bullshit excuse my French
any college kid can go out I get a stack
of stuff that so see someone else
know by 11 again real-world examples
use my California driver's license as
David Moore
name Salvatore Romano and david hale
old I have permission to do that
so there is an FBI guy here saying you
see
yeah you to going
what I used to use this example and by
the way when we're not quite the prior
2600 speeches national passport so it
got me and
banking on saddam the company's the
night so
on occasions when I'm going to cover
everybody also say the look you know
call you do something for a living your
next month
you know it really does applaud
who knows she learns
oh and somebody's gotta know raise yet
she should
is no not you who's looking for some
store unity
by the way when we go to Q&A 3 these
were
no these or famous designer investigate
native tissues
so three request thank C that here's
barbara Bush our president store
when the two daughters barber and
generous to go out
Bouza they have think I do
I i don't know what they thought I mean
the secret service was following him
everywhere else
people don't know that I belong both
they are fake ID in the 100 make
got caught drinking by the Texas DPS you
know what the hell to do in the
president's a
charger heard the secret service called
in
using the earth's code names button but
long
yeah I love the job home
anyway that yes the president's
daughters
fake I V not how she got it is just
amazing to me I mean
media three guys with your pieces
following you around go
we don't think I've been you know but
she got it she got arrested within
I know I've got because I'm licensed in
Texas and a lot of friends down there
I had somebody get me a copy of the
evidence in the case and that he is
her actual honest-to-goodness think I do
and you can go for example to the
International Herald Tribune
everyone's that's what they call you in
the market then
there are people who saw you post more
storms licenses love you on
some countries a lot of a new church
here's a your business for
and here is hey special agent in charge
at US State Department say yell
our passport so really tamper-proof for
unfortunately anybody was a good you can
go you
bellowing real-world examples here's a
very enjoyable
who had had his license suspended
eighteen times
his license was suspended at the time
that he was driving
that killed tell people this is in New
York on
homes in ninety days ago burgers
their doctors get my slow I've
investigated doctors
who have been arrested and convicted for
outrageous felons
undersold of its your right to know if
your doctor is gonna
give you some laughing gas impose he
looked gross
okay not to shoot for this book who
knows your photos
on recent history people living in caves
still more who jokingly are but
UK so it's a no I V
job in Abyan current this is the guy who
claimed he killed JonBenet Ramsey and
was arrested for
do you know what he didn't at the time
that he supposedly
killed JonBenet Ramsey year was a
schoolteacher
and he was a school teacher even after
he got arrested for
being shown which open arms
no so you're going to charity so he's a
perfect example is an example
let me give you the both sides of the
coin
here is why the US government wants to
get information on
he is an absolute fact that fourteen
home the eighteen
9/11 terrorists could have been
identified was propagated a success
to people the two people would stop know
of in Cali
were all on CIA watching so it's all
well the discussion
how they .bz came to the US will will on
the watch list
but there were no and in all the
terrorists most of the other
tom was willing to want some assurance
russ was no of colleague well Mohammed
on another terrorists
lived with them another one used his
frequent flyer
flyer number I'm 50 overs
a common telephone numbers will its
phones
if the government have been doing their
job but if the government had been
maintaining a cross reference into this
is
he's 14 guys wouldn't show
it's a good morning it's a really good
one I'm a New Yorker
I've lived in Israel so pretty much
every word every move
I agree with the idea you need to be
able to put in identifying
who's a bad guy before though so server
don't fly a plane into a building
kill 3,000 what machines
well here's the other side
since 9/11 US government agencies
have swooped up hold on what's
wells close to 2,000 people
that they believed was somehow
related connected to terrorism much
this is not a thousand people though
they arrested at the very beginning
put them in jail held in forever the
didn't prosecute a single or
the zone new cases out of these cases
which if your former law enforcement
agency wherever they are and then you go
to the prosecutor's office
and so we think you are prosecutors go
writing of the past
the majority of the eighty percent of
the cases the prosecutor's office is a
you know months people who said anything
eighty percent of the cases
the federal law enforcement Fort Worth
investigating bring the prosecution you
us
the government prosecutors so they work
well
another 10 soon are just sitting on the
sidelines
then you have move
good comes out like seven percent that
were actually prosecution
I don't that for those were actually
convicted
again on the intended uses data
DNA databases if you're closing blog
is all rested and they take DNA from
them which is routinely don't know
they not only have boss database
boss DNA in the database they have an
indicator every time
Waterloo Bob rose come to attention
either using about me
another thing you need to be aware of
who's wall the US government
is gathering game either directly or
through private company
they are closing aggressively even
rapidly closing
all the data that you have access to
they are running back out there
reclassifying data
even if it's been open for decades we
give you really ridiculous example
1971 richard nixon gave a speech
and in that speech vulnerable hope paper
on the stats on my website
go put down as about 30 examples this is
the most ridiculously
richard nixon 1971 gives a speech
but he talks about the small way to
russian missiles
that how many missiles they have in
other words how many bombs to land on
our head
that the US government is a Welsh 1971
posts page richard nixon press
conference
reported ever US Government classified
that the real issue
I truly don't know why whatsoever
brought donuts or two
question is assisting minutes but it's a
truly representative example
I love not just 10 minutes now
question-and-answer period thank you
very much
you
great moderator somebody who can do the
jury spring along ru
microphones or why I think trying talk
about
I'm I'm sure you can yeah
own I have yours first this
Walmart all how's my that will deal on
who is this it would take the when you
place like that
and second word he's really worked well
with here as well
who soon and so course you're
Rd online you home safely yes
well there's a would really suck if if
this was you
I that's a good question to give you to
ship
just home let me repeat the question
phenomenal two part question first
questions
how people get by private medical
history doesn't have a protected
and the second question is how do I
protect my IP address
ok give you a second part first
really simple spend a few extra bucks a
month
you have a No I do not own this is Russ
or get for example horizon DSL line
the research the the connection either
every three days whether you like it or
not for every time you turn a more
modern of
you've got a actually go to the trouble
of doing that not elisa's
shock perfect example those Church of
Scientology subpoenaing anonymizer all
the way in Finland
getting the entire elements who's this
were
you if you want to be the other funds up
well if you if you have if you have
I mean you need to choose between
between static and dynamic IP address
if you choose correctly and turn your
motor on of every time you log on
ninety-nine point nine percent in the
trucking
will disappear you know there are some
services that actually track you might
use
diffusion waffling nothing you can do
about them
no matter what you doing if you log in
as you check your email using wifi cuff
whatever nothing to do but because they
have a right to know if you're the guy
was really painful
serves so that's that's the easy really
easy question
I think what you can do to be a
non-issue pretty much in Reno
medical records medical records or pro
there or the proper to medical reference
not third party rights not
if you pay for your xanax with a credit
card not the issue
by a book on kidney disease not use you
dario
and a number for information on retired
dysfunction
you said 14 insurance
we names 10 that is very his prognosis
justification
but when your partner so that I was not
even need
because you're gonna pay for your change
with your group or
when you consider that former moon hide
frankly I'm you have a look at your
profile
and look at what you've been rated yet
and see how much to show you look to see
if yeltsin sonar
he spoke look at the games you for
specific there's nothing in it might be
like you
well all that's all almost nothing in
the medical databases
that I can compile on my own but
creative uses for reporting from
notes records or day well
that's the theory you know
no mother won't let me just tell you
there was no official or the whole
medical workers mostly electronica
the most important rule which means they
must be on database that successful
there are 20 gazans move with better
suited to tell you how easily that again
it was electronically maintained by more
work
so his forested have a store
miss Lawrence a good you the city walk
to a medical records in the city
corruption there needs to be a rule that
the doc is keeping a stand-alone system
and so-and-so few
the homies you today yet
I'll for small little as
you okay for small
I probably shouldn't is your questions
as you interrupted
but I like the first part of the
question they can
there's a Social Security Death Index
every state nor cross-references it's
done farms
and if your social security number is
linked to that person
your day even if you up to that's how it
works or
there are thousands of people every year
who have to go down and cry at your
local Social Security office
this is the same way so they would have
so yes I can tell from the database
issue that
don't do that you know our own I'll let
you get in which case
good Mike I can do nothing to you next
history yes whose license plate scanners
things right going axle question
today yes in about a year
no in about a year
it's not it's not a question technology
license plate
data is there especially if you go to a
chocolate
the slowing down of had put you in
exactly the spa
where they want the camera and it'll get
you but spell your to live for
you know being to the point we're tom
cruise would be jumping out or
window on the New York State through a
I'm working my way West I just wanted a
mention it no yes
liar 70 I was involved in an
investigation
yeah I two summers ago and
days one rises who was using that IP
number at that time
I am NOT talking about to let
access to those records i'm talking
about third parties
be able to till by the IP number that
you forward to them
you will never be safe from your IP
your own he knows who logged in
to that IP number at that time you'll
never be free from your ISP
knowing who's on that one because the
billing
but i'm talking about. oooh
our own you go to a pen a few your
website
not looking for pedophilia the journal
but because you're a victim
I don't generate your IP number so
instantly somebody somewhere is going to
know
that the IP number belongs to someone
who is researching
victims of molestation as an example
now yes the FBI if you use over rising
cheap Dr Solon terminal or more than
often let you know that throughout
cycle work so
I I'm real same
go and brown you
have guys like you say
I want to buy this property I went down
to the registry office
I got the persons name on that the the
address is no longer any good
%uh that he was worse the thirty years
ago global of
hole about this property before the
government grabs a you know
maybe they'll give me a cheap price what
can I do hire a private investigator to
find the person for you
here's hire somebody who could do
everything which is described
her son that's not well I
I'm if I'm higher different privacy yeah
part 12 actually knows how to do the job
it's not a sales pitch for me
I'll talk to you later be great if I
actually money also went to the store
yeah friendly person
about the mars Super Mario Bros u
for you you are you most my
or corlew yeah it was good
yes israel also over the summer
they are others who'll be used by
someone else yep that's right
and both for their I am only using
social security number
wreck a 6-foot-1 a black belt in karate
and weighs about 295 pounds
assume this goes on his ass kicked by no
yeah
that's all religion he's a huge guy
whose wife no
I i kno nice is going to give me but
still
think it team change
no K go ahead rover