Paris arts are the techno the
difficulties
um so as you can see that's a name like
presentation um
apologize for the you know slideshow
stuff but I found it actually
works pretty well in these situations so
our
I did talk about there'll be three
sections to this one's going to become
the anecdotal thing
and eternal art history and i wanna talk
about the free culture movement
term pardo arm first thing is a
all you guys know this is because the
caption but this is a %uh Steve
Wozniak's
blue box he made blue boxes back in the
day
in early nineteen seventies 1973 and 74
even Steve Jobs hang out in california
on
got kinda on the Boxwave and in case you
don't know that's what 2600 named after
the town that a blue box generates arm
a spare the technical details but
essentially generates a tone that well
back in the day
they make free long distance call years
of us anyway it's on display at the
computer museum
I think the computer museum must be in
Germany I'm not sure which one
this is on the computer on to call for
up there's a photo
steve wozniak using a boombox there's
him and Steve Jobs
Steve Jobs up was there
so here steve jobs now doesn't look
similar
um got a huge corporate logo behind them
and up getting to be on the wealthiest
man or
so arm here's
apple computer I'll just before they
start apple computer Steve Jobs
and Steve Wozniak went to business
selling blue boxes to people in the Bay
Area
and that didn't work out so well so they
decide to start
selling a home where computers that's
what led to Apple one
noble to but now this is the new face a
valuable
are the harbor school and fashionable
and stuff but
everyone knows them for the iPod's at
this point and
consequently everyone knows and because
their DRM on
Apple's the largest the RAM retailer in
the world
now how does Apple in 1970
with Steve Jobs and Steve Wozniak taking
apart
phones and using blue boxes come to be
either largest
your am retail world that's our question
and answer
no I'm not so much interested in steve
Jobs was
a personal history and what led him to
this decision but
I am interested in the fact that the RAM
and kind of copyright control our
culture
so arm as level we know but
or a lot of people don't know that
Apple's first logo is this are
pretty ugly well look good I back on
ipod now
or computer or anything for that matter
doesn't look good but the interesting
part
is that the guy under the tree is Isaac
Newton and I'll
most people work with computers are
physics or something are
any anybody besides world of course
knows who he is but respect them
because it is kinda progressive thought
on how
he did his work and how other people
that is work and means famous for saying
effacing further it by saying I feel
that the Giants
interesting part about this that he
actually say this isn't it this is in
his first
this isn't his he was this is an
original if you took it from
burn our from John assaults for Salsberg
rodent 159 for four years before noon
was around on
a statement pretty much the same um
we like the same so much that we put on
the back burner T-shirts the one where
now are on the left next to that such a
thorn in my pants
standing in Newnan are is the quote from
before
a that if I'd seen farther is by
standing on the shoulders of giants so
what does this mean this means that
noon accepted the fact that he didn't
have that my i mean
ironically he did he was one the most
kind of um
prolific scientist at this time but but
few realize that you could have gone
anywhere if that people before him
and contributed something and let it out
into the field so
you wrote this this is a letter to
Robert Koch who happen to be short so
was when does come in and saw but I
now people like the bat around that
people like me like about around that
quote as
indication that Culture and Science in
noonan's case doesn't progress unless
you have access to the past and so is
the
this is the theme kinda my talking what
I'm interested in
is that copyright is always gonna be in
that
this tension with letting people have
access to things that so
those kinda by anecdotal
story on figure introduce but
at the heart of it copying is inherent
to creation brothers
whether a hacker artist you're using
something that somebody did before
and copyright as it stands now and as a
will be
on in you know hundred years ago or so
stand against that they don't want you
to copy
it US government in and most other
civilized societies but
limited naw monopolies in hand the
people who have created things before
them
a four-year so and then those people can
dictate whether or not you can use
their creations runs for covered
but is interesting that you is a Greek
or Roman
the statue itself i think is roaming but
it's from a great met
this is in the classical buried in Roman
civilization when they start
realizing that these groups know what
they're doing point as
the Romans that have work elements that
I'll before room but
but after the XO yeah I I'd rather as I
can remember helmet stickers
before/after comment anyway appointed as
the Romans the side that the Greeks know
what they're doing and decide me a copy
of it for themselves
and most Roman art that you see now is
based on some Greek art so this idea of
copying what be
what came before you in order kinda make
something significant
and culturally valid has been around
since
human creation has been around I mean
obviously there's a lot more human
creation before this
but I'll this in the Vatican on a great
school
op so another great thing
that combines kinda artists and hackers
I think is that
we both have I mean I'm consider myself
an artist but
actors and artists both have a distinct
desire to subvert the status quo
in in that artists what makes them
contemporary invalid in
and kinda interesting to people is that
they've done something that nobody else
before
stuff and that's the central Africa
Pakistan
at the heart of it you're just wanting
to one-up the guy
before you and so art works like that to
you
and and there's no real reason to see
such a distinct line between how hackers
work
artists work I think are
the painting by Ivan law I can't
pronounce on French because im
you your life but I've its OVA
kinda party industry but here's a quote
from art me know dot com
about what the impressionists what
people thought of them presence at the
time
this is to give me an idea that they
were China's you know they cause
great offense but I'm are in the
beginning the Impressionist painters
were nothing but
ridiculed by the public our critic's all
the paintings unfinished in the clear
the artist as Mad Men
newspaper cartoons pregnant women were
or not to enter impressionist
art exhibition because of the danger a
miscarriage the caricatures that was
proposed to fend off the Prussian army
was marching towards Paris in 1870 by
showing them freshness innings
so thought they had you know like this
looks like a
kinda stuffy old painting to us but at
the time this blue people's minds
the that you bother to be non figured
and kind of
impressionists was used as an insult at
the time um
was was too much for people to handle
but you now these
sell for millions dollars these are part
of our culture part over history
so I find a lot of
I'll a lot of the motivations
artists in the past if we just look back
have examine what
what angle they're coming from are
similar the way hackers operate in terms
of creating something new
from what's been before and and and can
have
putting a new light on the world for
people so
part of this whole talk is for me to
appeal the hacker community
and show you that copyright the thing
that mandating controls these things
is an important part love your world and
my world too and that we have to
have we have to have moreover
dialogue going and arm
10 biggest point i think is that hackers
are just like artists an artist just
like hackers reuse
beautiful technology to create something
new I mean how often have you just
rejected
you know wire or program and just alter
input or argument and its totally change
the Athens and the program essentially
or
you know some small subverting this is
what this is actually the
kinda largest the move by my argument
about
are impacting um is what modern art been
doing in this is one
most significant this is considered I
think the most significant piece modern
art but
you know people or are you about that
cool November on the books but
arm is more solstice Marcel Duchamp's
Fountain
on essentially took a public urinal and
put on display
and gallery in Paris in this blue
everyone's mind I'm sorry from boring is
sorry for the story but are decided
under a different name because he was
crazy like that and %ah this cause
another up
out or a bridge so
um that's just one example on the people
just can't handle that you put a
Toyota museum or not even a fun thing
well using so um I fine
marceau Marcel Duchamp's gonna
motivation behind this very similar to
how hackers operating
creating are nuclear programs are
Apple tour the same deal I mean you know
this is lying around
shelves I've everywhere convenience
store in america
and one artist Andy Warhol decide to
take it into
and taken into something larger and he
by putting it under a canvas display
that
you know it these consumer are objects
can actually function as r2
so its it's really just a memory
contextualization
for Andy are for Andy Warhol but it's
also a matter
love reusing something from the past F
campus when after and if they did
if they contacted and I thought this is
a great way to promote the product
but they went after him this this whole
theme of Pop or
may not happen now in now
copyright is becoming more hurtful to
prevent people like
Andy from creating so I'm gonna go to
one last example for
and support you probably haven't heard
of and us by artist and Cory Arcangel
and I he basically remixes Mario
and are remixes video games and and
among other things this is someone who
is all there are in 2003
but as you can see the right to talk
Mario
out of Mario just left the clouds and
our
I was gonna try to set up emulator and
play for you is a
runs a bill was passed down but are at
the clauses go buy music place
kinda cool but this is to me a great
example perfect synthesis and the idea
of hacking art together
where an artist is reusing something
from the past summit copyrighted
something that
some to pay for there's a copy made up
and
turning into something that really
challenges our perspective on how r
and you know I mean people talk about
how your thoughts about her childhood
and how
these icons have pop imager similar what
we're all used in i mean there's you can
talk lot about
how arm
reuse of cultural icons are important in
our
arm but that's all I'll say that these
are
now possible with the to increasing
copyright a regime in this country it's
not clear that people continue to be
able
make art and program like yourselves so
that leads me to
the story about free calls for a 40 talk
about this I'll tell you how I got
involved
I'll I was reading the 2600 are
summer issue like 1990 eight or
something it was
my first issues were a they got
frightened by the MPAA for publishing a
DCS
and after that I read that it kinda
Upton said interested in covering
Slashdot involve the case
actually want to appeal when they lost
the case in suit again
or peeled on in New York in hours
uniform if point for me
when I realized that this law called the
DMCA was really strong stuff up
online for people I'll way realizes how
significant there is a world power was
are a couple
couple years later Lawrence Lessig was
working a book on Fri culture
when awesome memos from the deep ball
corporation got leaked onto the internet
yes familiar with that mean you heard
about that are
basically a bunch of internal memos got
leaked that were
displayed people their particular bad
light if I remember correctly they
admitted that the borders reselling it
state of California
broken voting machines among other
things but the members are millions of
pages
and arm in order parts them properly
people just decided near them on the
website so that the public after
so arm is kinda like a cat out the bag
thing like once it happened
members were but are doesn't have lost
me
on the right on the left and SAR arm
was part of a anti-war or
group on campus at swarthmore and figure
that this was an interesting case
against the bush administration
so Nelson and his friend posted the
people memos and theres of more
accounts which is like 10 megabytes you
address and
arm sure nothing I cease and desist
letter from the mall
claiming copyright infringement is going
crazy because deval the left the memos
ok
in a open public FTP and just they like
forgot password
something is fully ridiculous and the
claim that
the only reason people weren't allowed
to distribute them was copyright was a
was a pretty bogus claim so before
they actually soon yeltsin and they did
Nelson got together and with Lawrence
Lessig and a side issue Diebel
first for bees copyright they won that
case in its star
at Star this huge national kind of
commotion around swarthmore campus and
it became kind of figures for arm
blessings
the kind of extension of us a good idea
the book that is published Fri culture
you haven't read for culture is it just
you are check it out you can download it
for free its licensed under Creative
Commons license online
get a free dash culture .cc you can
download the whole book
are you buy and stores I think it's in
its fourth printing now
are so nelson et start something called
the swap or coalition for the
Digital Commons and on as cover already
title and
once again I realize there's so much
national attention about this
one topic that had to do with this you
know Republican corporation abusing
copyright
he job decide to make it larger so with
a couple friends a surfer cultured or
which was gonna be a national student
movement about this because
I'll not only was the bold interesting
case for college students but
on divorced on OBC about our and that
was
getting attention so that summer
I got in contact with God Nelson gonna
sit on the analysts and
and arm previously I as a perforce prank
for summer 2000 are the spring of 2004
at the posters on my on NYU's campus
saying I
that are a was coming to campus and you
can meet Hilary Rosen and Metallica
and if you brought a CD with your mp3's
on it you could trade it in for immunity
in future are a lawsuit's
I was at the post now but it's on this
laptop but I looked really official and
what we put all these are
but like the date and name we did like
people 31st in like
you know 1 p.m. to noon always like
times it didn't make any sense that you
can actually
go anywhere do it we splattered all over
campus in
we just thought were being funny we did
at like 5am you know morning before
april fools
and we go to forget about it this is my
roommate and I and then like a week or
two later we hear these people getting
argument in the stairwell in our dorm
dislike sure it is argued about whether
out RA was justified in throwing people
and goes all over the city today for
full sprint but it was like
you know that we kept on hearing about
it and we're like wallace actually you
know people talking about this on campus
I thought that they're just afraid it's
a
they feel like the IRA is a is in a
morally unjustifiable position
and doing college students and I was
like I thought this way all along I mean
I fall the DCSS case
you know whatever's happening at the
time and especially the deep okay so I
was like
now's the time like I I should start a
club or something I start a club in high
school
like this thank you some college campus
but I can make a political
so I got in contact and the saw your my
senior year
on 2005 arms are 2004-2005 assert for
culture W
arm graduated and then I kinda stuck
around the city and became outside
agitator
hand we started out when my ideas was to
have a DRM protest
so this is the first year and protest
ever as far as I
I'll and we made poster boards and
sandwich boards
and on funny things into showed up a
virgin images of fires which of the 10
later that arm
explain what the ram was essentially how
and how to damage your computer and
house
problematic for arm
you know your rights as a as a copy
realities
are your rights as a consumer arm
essentially you guys on your stand the
problem here and it's only there to
prevent you from taking
copying bring iPod itself you wanna
remix
and actually create something new with
that CD it will prevent you from doing
that
and to break that duran is it the NCAA
violations so
if you're somebody who wants a remix
jay-z for example
right in that city has dear mr.
ten years ago or five years ago even 4dr
I'm really existed
you could copy the whole city under
computer maker remix
and then disperse it onto the web hoping
that its
fair use and and that that's its own is
to mean for uses its own problem but you
would actually be
violating any laws by getting
getting the songs on your computer
remixing now do your own
presents a problem in that in the way
that
it it is a violation a plea brakeman a
break the RAM
the DMZ but I'll so is covering up with
a lot of attention for this week on
Boing Boing
are and random people to show up was
phenomenal actually people set up their
own posters answered
any analysis is kinda you know internet
meets
real-world feeling you get every so
often but
it was especially kinda exciting to see
people who
knew about the issues and just want to
do something in New York about so
arm we on the opening of fires inside
the store in a virgin people were like
what's the Euro
somewhere you know we 5 and because
everyone just goes in Virginia in square
in the stanza
your put flyers and it's just like a %um
my will be a public space to the P the
clerk for just like whatever but
are a lot of people mister like this is
really interesting we actually got no
negative
like feedback but nobody was actually
you know you kids you're downloading we
got one person that after explaining the
whole thing he was like water
her I think the record companies need to
you to keep the revenues but
it wasn't that somebody there was no
protest in that there is somebody
sitting in virgin who actively disagreed
with us so we call that moreover
demonstration that we're really just
informing consumers not to buy these
essentially broken product that was the
theme of our flyer are you buying damage
CD
so there's some photos from that are
wrong way
up so here's this parts in the second 1i
a pulse photos
people larger um and the original
sandwich board reared had
throwing up iPod I really sec iPod in
that you can get a
you know your sister iPods here I was
upset
on he River throwing up computer because
this is
we got really lucky and between a first
for tests are second protest is the Sony
BMG scandal
where there are essentially release the
virus and the public
hand it was a rootkit but a you know
most people understand that has a virus
and
a there it was just this hot moment this
hot flashes
Deron gonna interest um by the public so
we made her sandwich portable computer
throwing up you can see them
upper left and a we're actually
fortunate Richard Stallman was in the
city and had heard about this and I
didn't
emailing back and forth that you want to
come housing sir
why not so he just grabbed a sandwich
board heart the entire night
and on the front of it we had their old
compact disc logo which is that
which actually means the sea is redbook
certified
on Andy RAM cities not that so they're
like imposter sees
it's actually really interesting so they
have this other logo which is that kinda
see with the triangle and I'll another
see which means content protection or
something
and I'll so if you ever see that log
don't quite see obviously but we made a
sandwich board the kind of demonstrate
the difference to consumers
um interesting part is that one of my
friends had
went in and bought this Sony BMG the van
Zante CD
at the Tower protesting just in case
we got a question about it and arm
turn let later that evening the manager
the store comes out and he knows we're
talking about obviously he's like we're
not selling
cities and he certainly has trouble is
required to go to Virginia like
did them last month man I mean we're
just which is making the rounds it's not
like we're
no finding you in particular and
hassling you in
knees you know he's hemming and hawing
is that I don't like this either because
again we turn in this whole thing but
for the record companies are doing what
you know the hardcore
headquarters and I was like role
honestly we don't care about converting
a buncha
monkeys in suits I mean their jobs are
absolutely in
10 years anyway you know like people
like us to go
used to go and buy CDs are the ones
you're care about this and
obviously our target in this action arm
so then finally he's like we're not
selling that CD or like yes you are my
friend takes that CD in the receipt if I
you know hour before and that such a
goober the store manager on upper right
holding the CD looking are are now
for Mike's arm so
there's a group shot at Cecils for is a
a great guy
I'll that was a really fun night and
that was the second year in protest over
weekend like
haven't heard anybody doing anything
else in we made all the Flyers available
online
some people showed up arm if you're free
to protest
Union Square is really good for it and a
corner of West 4th Street and Broadway
isn't so good for it's like really windy
and if you doing at like 7pm or
something
its it's just kinda Cole and
and November are scupper
Armada we're good plan to do some during
the day
at the Sony headquarters on and I think
we may do that next year
I'm so this is really exciting thing in
and eventually I'll
enough people can contact here's a
here's the fire this is the original
fire
on so it's really simple we had a lot of
criticism from people in the tech world
that you're like
you're not explaining the at you know
the the CD install software her
it's like you can't really part the
people just walk around the street can't
parse that kind of information
quickly like like I mean its kinda
second nature for people like us but
but when your hands me a flyer first
they think you're selling something
and second i wanna talk to you so so
trying to explain that there's these
like
obtuse technical details about the
format CD is just gonna go over your
head you need to explain in terms that
they really understand
and that's can't play it on your home
computer mercies have this problem last
year
cities have this problem you can't for
the songs on your mp3 player
1 I've Apple's big advertising campaigns
was that they were
letting you can for your collection from
CDs
to your iTunes collection and they can I
stop talking about that once they start
selling the iran because
Apple fall people doesn't like the idea
for Mac shipping they don't want you to
be able to shift from
iTunes to your iPod to your city and
then tear
you know home mp3 server they want to be
stuck with
iTunes approve John so
those one thing we can explain very
easily and then making a backup copy the
CD
some love the Europe's offer would kind
of
tangentially let you do this but it
would be like a 120 kill a bit version
the whole CD which is far below senior
Quality Inn
on they're wrong let you make three or
four copies
or maybe even one copy are so we can add
a checklist and then we set up a web
page that was kind of like a resource
for people to understand more about the
RAM
so this is just like a really simple and
flyering
we headed out like a thousand these the
first night and they want like
littering so wheat we took we made on
assumption that people working at home
um the second one we made like a
full-page fire
because we had so much to talk about the
Sony BMG stuff I'll
and we put the logo on there which is
really important are
and and just like some quote from the
new york times and so people who were
be serious um all these are online
available for download so if you want
your own
your protests are licensed under
Creative Commons are you care
you just do whatever you want with the
stuff I mean the probably
typos and stuff unfortunately the their
original files are in PSD
they do it again on public put him in a
more open format
arm but our yeah he's really useful
people got it people loved
I stalk let the stalking us on the
street is random consumers a
you get the idea that most people have
no idea about these
things but once you actually stop months
ago actually there
they want to talk to you about and and
they're interested so people pretty
smart
and we found that to be the case so
here's a article the village voice heard
about it
on that was really this is a really
interesting story on my friend inga
who funded for culture don't want you
with me on the
left there arm is quoted in this article
are the tickets on
here okay here she says
if there are laws i believe are wrong I
will break them
at the time she was working in our
trademark I'll law firm
I was really pretty just one in Midtown
and it took a couple weeks before
summoning office found this article
and on your column in the HR and
they told her you basically can't work
here because you're opposed to what we
do
and in your anything as a sophomore in
college and
his interest in copyright and how these
things are affecting
you know computers and technology in
and culture and economists economics in
general
arm this year job as a paralegal shoes
she want to go to law school in fact
she's applying the law school right now
arm so getting a job as a paralegal what
you do but it doesn't come to prohibit
you from being
a political paralegal if you're not at
work so
the firm care that like at this
wishy-washy
thing that we're not firing you for your
views but we are firing you because what
you believe in and then it's like that
same thing assholes
a home tho so ago I wrote
arm so I was looking at this is a big
deal she's like no it's not and she was
really upset in CA
you know a person X that you get the job
but that was the problem she was just
like
I you know I I don't like having like a
black mark on my resume I was like no
you care thinking this is a black mark
this is awesome this is drawing a line
in the sand
for people out there to understand what
dear is what you know what the problems
are copyright or so
as like we gotta go public with this so
fortunately we had the advice from a pro
bono lawyer
and she can have step sister as I can
probably don't want to name the name law
firm
arm so don't ask on but you're welcome
to share your story
are so in your right up this long letter
about it it's on our web page if you
wanna go free culture and why you dont
or
just explain what happened pretty much
what I just told you and that
years she finds it unfortunate that a
law firm so short-sighted and
like this very kind of like formal
apology and we surpassing around him
every lawyer we talk to was Kevin raged
about this and they're like this is
you're doing exactly the right thing
on and so on america's on Slashdot and
it's like
by what for culture and where you got
like twenty thousand hits in one day
and there's this huge threat on Slashdot
about people are going over whether or
not
Angus quote there was something to be
fired over but the important point was
that it
establish some precedent that if you're
gonna be
involved to help our law firm you can
worry about
what your political views on BRM are
enhance that's a really funny thing I
mean how you feel about some technology
is is is the interesting thing to be
call to qualify your ability to work at
a law firm
so I was interesting article arm
washings were news we were a with a
friend we
we collaborate a road op-ed and it's got
out a lot of people
this is on my way couple times and just
on campus
if you're thinking about doing campus
organizing or Paul
poll politicizing that kind of thing
your op-ed column in your
and your papers a really good way to get
things started I mean really doesn't
require much to
read a couple hundred words about
something you care about and
trusting college papers are star for
interesting things
talk about especially technology 0
USA today we're going contact with us
into the whole article this is
in the man section of USA today and
that's my friend Diana rosenthal
well with the iPod from NYU bus they
said she said it took like all night to
get that one photo
500 shops and USA today it was
their discover you know they're good but
didn't wanna the
been care about like the actual politics
ovett they just want to hear
about how you can turn CDs and iPod
files and it was kinda frustrating as
we are trying to tell them that there is
a significant
political party how these files work
what was happening with the CDs and
they're just
concerned about poor college students
getting ripped off on
which is a part of our message but it's
our our message
okay so um move other vans we did
was a Creative Commons archer yes from
lawyers Creative Commons
are basically it's that time too do open
source for
I'm do licensing for culture on the GP
only
are did you kill me if I saw for there's
FTL that applies for
are suffer males are that was designed
for saw for man of
but really there's no good way to
license your work said
in order let other people know that you
want them to share henry's
so part of our goal the call was to
kinda advocate Creative Commons
on campus in on in any way we could so
we decide to host a critic comment
archer and we basically just bought a
bunch of our friends for
files for for photos or other art that
they would like to licensed under
Creative Commons
that we would then put online the same
time
as doing physical archer we told them
that their as long as they brought their
own friends and friend
themselves there for sale at whatever
price they wanted to
can have and Kurds the fact that there
can be real world analogues
to you kinda digital world stop even if
you're giving out something for free
online it doesn't mean that
original proprietary version in the
physical world costs anything
are can cost with its ok this weather
works
are if there's more I hear some more
there are just you know good work that
ever you know from the friends and
people who are
licensing under Creative Commons are we
just kind of set our
feelers and got enough feedback and were
able to slide maybe 10 or 11
great pieces are two years I in our show
pairs of this is diana's case up
she was the girl yes it's there
because she's also a photographer arm
this is my friend will chairman
he runs the site untitled name dot com I
its he does mostly graffiti stuff but
this I P sed
in Red Hook are the licenses his work
under Creative Commons already so we can
have to explain it to him was really
interesting experience talking college
students because
most them understand the copyright isn't
working on
on internet & digital media and there's
no way
to really on keep control for work want
to put it out there so
a lot of them really amenable Creative
Commons in a row like the idea that
they could kind of get some publicity
through their name
and not have to worry about like
you know all the problems entailed with
putting things on line in new features
like a
you know attribution-noncommercial
license they could have some legal
recourse if that's all their photo
and up and some Ford commercial or
something like that
are are some more photos is was the one
that got kinda picked up by the media
this is our blogs is being kinda like
there's a free art opening are you go to
it
their kids with guns on is actually 10
this the photographers brothers and are
Minnesota think this is what they do
this thing out issue
rounds I guess um but our yeah it was
calls were released
we had a party at NYU and then released
all stuff online at the same time on
Flickr
under Creative Commons license and kinda
made sure everyone knew that
so her systems photos a we decide to do
it at a student lounge
we like the idea of having our meeting
still out as opposed to cause of room
just kinda
church people show up and drop in that
kind of thing on
and it was a firm on and we got a lot or
great responses
um was even better was that arm
Creek Commons and Second Life decide to
do up
art show in Second Life so they can have
gave us free space and Second Life which
actually cost something
leader not and are yes from lawyers
Second Life its
it's a online world not a game on
where where people can have created
everything themselves
the only real things created by Second
Life the company
are the tools to create other objects so
everything you see here is user-created
aside from maybe the ocean
and shading on sky arm my shirt
is actually the virtual version my shirt
on
so we can go online art show and I also
gave a talk
and Second Life about it posing callers
that we then encourage everyone in
Second Life
to go on remix art that could mean it's
the stuff that wasn't under
and no difference license so is just one
example
I'll what so many did with it his clean
bill the scene
from a taxicab thing made it seem like
he was hailing a cab
and then turn this into a piece of work
that he did relicensed under
Creative Commons so on I'm forgetting
his name out but
is gonna need application and on this
stuff
the graffiti seeing the kinda middle
left people then used to put up on
buildings
and Second Life has to make it like
virtual graffiti for
wifi which is kind of interesting
arm before
more so are the spawn of I'll
the Harvard free culture archer so they
decide to do something to
and this is the heart from their ship
and on since its
kinda on you know it's just more art but
in a huge reception in our gallery um
I was really fun her some photos from
that night %uh they had live
performances from
people doing cell phone ringtone stuff
from on
just live remixing in general are
so here are this brings me to our last
project that this is your
which is a remix contest is anyone here
about this yes from earlier this
cool years and 11 months of are reside
the sponsor
or people remixing DVD's in this is like
a
cause that was really near and dear to
my heart because
the whole reason I got involved in this
whole movement my whole interest us from
that one DCSS case
baffin 29-year whenever was and
I just I've still been thinking how
insane it is that people don't really
have
access to movies that they want to
create a
and remix so after love talking
are actually I just presented this idea
the fickle trigger
and they're like this is okay this is
you know good idea
what are we remix worrying when we
encourage people to remix
movies into those kinda trailers that
your see online
Alec the book back to our future: wine
and Sponge Bob
mazlin or whatever was was the other one
a
the shining one was really good serious
in that arm so we wanna go
we want to kind of capitalize on that or
capitalize but
I'm jump on that bandwagon and I
encourage people to do remixes
movies and we didn't know what movies
were gonna do are
because we kind of got up got caught up
in talking about the legality of it
arm because a lot of those projects are
just things that people did
did themselves like it's just like I
found the tools
on the movie myself nobody told them to
do that
telling some you remix a DVD take apart
a DVD in
and essentially the cryptic is
is in itself illegal on the if you
instruct somebody
powder turn a DVD from its encrypted
form to
decrypted form if you give them specific
instruction we've been told them where
to get the specific instructions
trafficking DMCA violation arm
so as a club on campus we didn't quite
want to get
to angry we want to get the
administration to angry with us
so we can talk extensively and we're
also interested in this
about the legality of up hosting a
contest where we would be telling people
essentially break the law and whatever
older members are
told us that the one thing we had to do
was I'll to thought the lawyer so we go
back to our
provide a lawyer friend we're told that
we wanted to film remix contest and he
understands all implications
the DMCA and are we we have these long
meetings to decide that
we can give a link to a guy that gives a
link to a guide
I've had it secret to the if you're a
mean we can say here here guides on how
to
d crypt DVD's and then they themselves
have links to other pages that give you
the specific instructions
arm that can have degree of separation
from the offending
illegal code was was enough for our
lawyer to be happy but what he also
wants to do
was to create a legal waiver you get to
it arm
so we trade issues legal waiver that was
just like I mean if you look at this
page for culture and where you done or
such film remix there's this guy never
initial explanation about the project
and kinda how do I participate in
formats and and then there's a legal
waiver which
which stands we we've had this I'm hurt
people that sign in
and entered out on me submitted their
work
are and it's this kind have long
not so it's not as legally is as it
could be but um
basically indemnifies the club from any
team CA lawsuits
you happy if your work happens to get
picked out by the MPAA
and so on arm we did this
not so much to play by the letter of the
law but to
indicate how absurd the letter of the
law was love the project was just too
demonstrate that the DMCA makes media
creation for
like many artists using DVD's very
difficult
we want to show that you have to jump
through all these legal loopholes if you
want to just take a DVD
in excess or if you wanna take like a
photo the soup can and turn that into a
painting
its there's no dnt have poison their
right
are so we had people read through this
whole legal
disclaimer and kinda sign it and we have
a PDF to calm down lorenzo like
form only goal and that kind of thing
are and we have an FAQ
have explaining wiry did all this
on so it's got future ongoing mowing we
had a a
examples because I was assigning on
if this works
the line or
per not them
yet to bring up I'm I mean I look at my
side
yeah I'll and while we wait are
world we're fortunate to have to be able
to show the the
contest submissions a conference that we
were invited talk at
the conference and fair use at NYU
church I
no maybe my submissive or
notes I'm working I'm here so well you
get the idea
the play um well I guess you have to
have a party a
up you sorry about that
a know it's it's it's always something
up with my mission it's over you
are so we show these a
for use conference and if you're
actually interested you can
good archive or up
yeah it's on on demand
it would be playing for my laptop
usually flash stuff works
a
well way for a
so we're part of this fair use
conference a at NYU
they were able to show the videos were
but was really cause that they had an
explorer from the MPAA
sitting on the same panel like I
actually gotta sit next to this guy and
and then they had similar from music
organization
I on the same panel and
are that basically shot one of them
the guy from them PA was like this is
garbage how could you consider because I
showed some the shining sup to you as
well as a
other entries the contest and the guys
like this is an art
what are you talking about and I E how
could you consider
you know kind these satires and parodies
and satires impairs the XOR
silliness and um so
there was really interesting experience
um
I have summer films with the movie if
the the time
isn't if the sounds at work in the
church worth it arm
go back to ok think that's it here's
some
future reading arm a
some again a very told you guys about
these
a there's some good sites %uh if you
want to get involved have locally
in your interest income which has been
in protest in that kind of thing are
doesn't join our email list get for
culture and where you died or you can
to sign up arm and get our email list
for culture .org is a national
organization on
we have chapters in over thirteen
colleges right now they're like up and
running
and like forty different universities
interest in starting the chapters if you
go to university please talk to me
very excited about meeting people from
other universities and getting started
arm you can check out let's a go toward
for updates from Lawrence Lessig
he wrote the book for culture is a very
smart lawyer
arm Boing Boing dot net is always good
for doctors can have
on this the constantly and a Slashdot
your rights you online up social are or
such why are
0 a world detail or other stuff going on
with
laws and that kind of thing um try to
think there's
anything else are if you'd like just
sorta if you like the
you can find the comedies a fair use
is the name of the conference that I set
up
are that not that I was a part of that I
use ran on
I was able to get all the audio from
this conference online and I'll put our
I dot org licensed under Creative
Commons saying down 100 alt 1 gigabyte
192 kilobits and P-three's but they also
important Aug for you which I feel is a
lot smaller
incidentally been mp3 arm
but there's some great people talking
here are Lawrence Lessig get to talk to
our
are there's they're two great artist
writer nancy is my soul's
I'll talk about operator thing i guess
im just bored in this now but
um feel free to download it and send it
around
um I guess you know now
open up to questions every interest in
like the student movement
a router next projects are I'll and tell
you next year
and where you are going to be a grad
student ass and to start agitating about
are how much and where you case for
journals arm
if you've ever worked in a library or no
people working libraries all know how
much
academic journals cost in car a single
journal that comes out maybe two times
are
even quarterly causative thirty thousand
dollars a year
are I think thats after physics be I've
heard quoted
are right now there are alternatives but
they need to make more
and there needs to be education from the
university level
so that those people doing research at
universities
no to publish their stuff under open
access rather than
with the publishing machine that's when
my big projects and where to start
to fighting with and why you to have
been this close
how much they're paying for their
journals make that available to the
students so they know how much their
tuition goes to paying for copyright on
I'm journals that could be free
scientist hey these journals themselves
to publish their own work
and i get charged to get access to it so
arm I want the students to know about
that I want in I want them to know that
you know
X percent is going to have silly
copyright fees arm that's one thing I
think we're probably do another
during protest here there on by all
means sign up in your
know about it before everyone else does
arm
I think a are always the most of the
works
one thing works in doing is are setting
up a freedom toaster
them you know that is on this moral
limits project but it's interesting
because its earning corporator Commons
license music and art
offering toasters a project set up by
I'll the Shuttleworth foundation
Mark Shuttleworth is a guy that runs
conical that runs been to
um so they designed a kiosk
are that would burn 1x project
gutenberg: all these kind of
freely copier popiel media things on the
TV is for you
they made thirty these kiosks and
distribute them around South Africa
which is pretty cool and nature and I
found that over your people
these this kiosk became incredibly
interests like incredibly important in
these communities
up shots would set up next next to them
and just sell
blank media for people to use on these
kiosks are created this on
kinda like small local economy but II
just I was just at the
I common summit in brazil I got to meet
a bunch of them so
I'm gonna work on trying to build one of
those emperor and what you do or
arm and see what happens to kind of get
1x farther into the
community and now they're gonna start
supporting are
Creative Commons content stuff from CC
next yr .org which is the kind of
a iron ore YouTube Creative Commons
music us to forever hopefully will be on
their rivers a
um a YouTube alternative that
incorporates occurred Commons licenses
but also allows you to charge
advertising fees before and after your
um video so those are things we have in
the future so
coming over for more questions because
if
yes
all academic journal thing is really a
good thing
to talk about yeah I'm an astrophysicist
know exactly what to talk
but you know most most of us who are
past the 10-year heard
who RM academic institutions or national
laboratories
most of us a publishing on xxx-large
other go rich
which is free right and that's physics I
mean there's there's a whole biology 0
that yes I I think I think there is a
movement rare
people just creating the sort of
databases and people submit papers your
and its it's interesting its its often
more useful than this sort of
traditional journals because
you get a lot more feedback on your work
your people email you and say hey I read
that paper
that was posted on the site for you
explain what you meant by this area I
thought that was really good idea I
thought that sucks that's
totally wrong you know so
gone now II I keep to go on yeah I did
get a hundred
I mean more people we have from kind of
tenured academic year
agreeing with us the better sorry up
guys are gonna cut it short if you want
to ask questions afterwards
free for a while please do coming up an
instructor in San I'm from for cult
about or
you can email me at Fred free for
cultured or
if you like