here where
rate is 1700 in the open slot has been
filled by state-of-the-art electronic
conduction
this missus hope 6 we have
ev-one announcement
a dusty corners on the web has been
cancelled permanently
it is not coming back to my knowledge
there will be a presentation at 12:30
tonight
by members the CAS computer club called
biometrics in sci-fi in this room
so if you're interested in that
presentation it will be at 12:30 there
was a flight delay
testing done is graciously agreed to
inform and entertain during this time
so I leave that for we're gonna try our
best
okay
so welcome to hope number six everyone
have a good time so far alright assets
rainy here we go
the small crowd here so everybody's
gonna pitch and you know how about this
actually this is a presentation I'll
tell you up front it's gonna be very
fine I am gonna be calling on people
from the audience to help out
it's very it's something that everybody
in here can do and it's nothing
deeply technical but it's a very fun
presentation I put some things together
that you maybe never thought about
before never looked at
and this way before so can keep that in
mind it's gonna be very fun and
lighthearted hopefully
funny in some parts and I guess the
start of the first thing would be to
define what is
electronic deduction and I made a nothin
important arm but it's basically looking
at
it can be anything from screenshots arm
content I guess would be the better word
focusing on content
and what kinda patterns or interesting
things can you find from something like
a screenshot
are something like meta-data inside the
files
I we could do a whole talk several hours
of talks on meta data were gonna touch
on a little bit that
second half but the first half hour
we're going to focus on looking at
screenshots
shoulder surfing things along those
lines what you can actually find out
probably a lot more than people may be
realize so
arm it is a former footprinting
if you look at it like that if your
shoulder surfing you're looking at
somebody's I'll
desk in their office you can find out
very quickly a look at someone's laptop
in here watch over your shoulder
everybody right you
I see looking over some a shoulder arm
see what kind of stuff they got
installed it tells a lot about who they
are as a user
on finding different patterns and
discovering software
that the use or or different web sites
so yes sounds pretty simple yet
it's common sense hacking us pop star
when the guys from our forums have been
a red dot com pam pam
%ah has referred to it in a very much as
is common sense hacking in your gonna
find out that it is something everybody
can do
but put a process to it up sitting down
and thinking
or what exactly does this mean sure I
see they've got
this application installed but was that
really me
so what if they've got something install
the level of depth is where comes into
play the depth of how much
experience you have how many software
packages you've seen
arm I've got some screenshots coming up
I've given this in a couple different
meetings
and every time I get someone points out
something new that I didn't even see
so it's all about the experience that
you have and what you recognize what you
put together the kinda come up with and
obviously VF physical access in time
available to sit there in
really pound away at you can find a
whole lot more that's when you can start
looking at meta data and things like
that
so yes this is very simple and I'll what
is the goal
love doing this well besides just being
funny kinda owning dropping the docs or
whatever you want to refer to it as
arm try to build a case think a bit you
know going to Batman won't pretend you
got utility belt
start putting all the stuff together
build a case like
I'm gonna prove that this laptop belongs
to this person
or arm if you want actual
truthful application when this might
come in handy if you do
get busted which hopefully nobody will
do that on
you can use these kinda things I say
look i cant use Microsoft Office because
I run Linux
or I can't use XYZ because I run that
you know you can use these things to say
listen
I can prove that's not a speech on my
computer because I don't have that
you know you can have that mister arm
but not have these individually will
stand on their own
they're all circumstantial evidence
you one thing I so don't think that this
is gonna stand up in court is some kinda
defense for anything
but you can build a case I love a
sequence of events and a lot of
different things that will prove that
something is or is not our or probably
as a probably is not you can never
also never come to 100 percent
conclusion but you can get pretty close
so coincidental evidence by itself is
useless so what if your
this person uses Microsoft Office sold
over one million other people
that doesn't really narrow it down or
prove anything
which there ago I guess again around her
okay
but building a collection of coins and
all evidence can help build
a case and and this is kinda overkill
but i wanna illustrated the kinda make
sure that the point gets across
is if you want actually chart this and
make this a process and security
field they like to make processes and
steps in stages and measure everything
which is
you know not exactly the hacker way to
do things but to visualize it
think are different types of users I
just made up of you here you know you
see
I hope you have a can see okay student
game or a home user
business user hacker just again made up
examples
and I just used a one to 10 scale
positive and negative starting in the
center
and based on what you might find on
someone's computer getting kinda build a
case for
one or the other user so for example
if you find a computer that has
accounting software
installed on it Microsoft Office outlook
as their client
are things like that that's going to
raise the percentage of the likelihood
of it being a business user
home users use some of those things too
so the students but a gamer
having an accounting software hacker
having accounting software
kinda lowers their probability so kinda
keep that
process in mind as you see some these
and think what kinda person this is what
kinda category my fall into
I said at the very beginning for those
who just came in this will be
interactive so I'm gonna be
and its it easy trust me it in in this
is a very simple nice example to start
with
first of all I mean what operating
system is this person using
commodity start the whole room windows
xp obviously we know that
well actually not necessarily course
people can scan things and it's
different when doing systems you can
trick people but that's pretty obviously
Windows XP we all can tell that
arm and you can tell kinda hardware
anybody really think about telling the
hardware from what you might see in
as simple as a task more when i'm
looking at a whole screen shower let me
just a taskbar
you know it's a laptop because you go so
you can put these things together
arm what else can you tell about in the
laptop is plugged in obviously
you see the AC power so it's plugged and
what about the speaker icon
you know such muted so
somebody muted their speakers that
doesn't happen accidentally
with isn't this a little things think
why would somebody
mute their speakers has got to be a
reason for that a game is not commute
their speakers
we kinda silly defeats the point right
there
this and this this man right here was
that no price
arm this screenshot I'll tell you was
from
other was this laptop on my other
laptops in an airport
and I didn't wanna disturb the people
around me and I didn't want to play my
vulgar language from minor revolution
radio tonight at eleven o'clock in this
room
be there me arm so yes this absence or
put this evening see how you can to
start with one thing kinda build up to
what it actually means
arm the software that's being using C
the icon in the center
everybody recognize that probably
Microsoft Outlook
what about the one next to it now this
is one of my favorite examples the one
right to the left of that
trillion what trillion not only is that
trillion
there's actually something else you can
pull out that little icon is more
information on that little icon believe
it or not
well I don't I honestly don't know that
that's I never heard that before that
that's a good one arm does anybody
isn't a very familiar with trillion
right here
trillion according to actually let me
back up yes if I back up
for those of you who don't know trillion
I'm assuming it but it does but let me
back up trillion is
a chat client that will communicate with
AOL messenger whatever their
things called MSN Messenger Yahoo
Messenger
its center is an all in one place
but the IKE right so there's to circles
there whatever that icon
if you're connected to all of the
available networks let's say you have an
AOL and MSN
Andy of if you're connected to all of
them both of those mobil's
light up yellow and this when you can
see that
only the top one is late which means
they're not connected to all a possible
networks they're available
what does that mean maybe nothing but
this is what we call building their case
building a preponderance
other evidence so many people actually
knew that the each little
icon is not just this is the software
using is actually a lot more information
and a lot of them so on anna & also
go outside on the icon says she and
other you can see the network icon is
showing
connected to a network somewhere
obviously you know it tells you a little
bit more
arm I'm sorry
were a actually very good point
absolutely and
again this is gonna fall under the might
be important might not be
but the time stamp the time stamp on
this was $3.37
or or what about think what about this
what if that time stamped in say 30
whether said
1537 somebody's doing military why
wouldn't you know
what kinda person would use military
time no just
just things like that some people might
some people I have reasons to do
arm so actually that's the least reagan
anybody in nosing come up to me
afterwards 337 has some significance to
us
not 1337 but 337
if you look on your phone keypad to
figure that out maybe
alright so first I can walk through this
one gonna come after a lot let everybody
play along with this
again for small operating system
Windows XP a go I'll can are ready sick
wireless network that's not connected
right rack
it's running on battery power is not
plugged in good point yeah
well actually I'm gonna go with that is
not
what's wrong you're on the right track
or something else here that
that is actually and if anybody who is
very familiar with Dale
that's the application of ship with all
the bills for their built-in internal
car
and I purposely did this this is very
very
probably i'm looking see well on the
overhead out here but
you might notice that the wallpaper I
purposely clipped off from the wallpaper
that yeah guys can see but from the
wallpaper you can learn a lot as well
this is actually the default lol pic
this is a brand new I laptop I was
setting up for work
and if you know again if you're from
Iredell and lot of people roll them out
at their jobs or whatever you can
recognize
a lot of the Dell things come on with it
own apt say oh well just want to upgrade
the software that's a great one
the icon on the far left does that
now now building with our case that
we're building up your does that fall in
line with what I just said a new
laptop it's been pre-installed without
lock but they haven't activated it yet
so see were billing okay this is a new
laptop you know so you're getting a case
of exactly what kind user who the person
using this is pull out my
watchin I'm what other software you see
on-air
very obscure when that's gone anybody
else pick that one up
you know to download manager with the
goal of a download manager is
Download Manager and most cases and in
this case which helps build a profile of
this user
is if farm you're downloading something
on unstable network
and it crashes halfway through you don't
have to start all over again want to
automatically pick up where I left off
or you want to open up multiple channels
and try to pull it faster et cetera et
cetera
so what kinda person would need such a
thing
you know might be might be aware spa
piano could be arm
right there you got it I'll sit in my
this again is from my laptop or the
entire an hour putting that case
together the show's
this was from a laptop that are setting
up for work out sitting at home watching
TV
in my living room on my wireless and I
was downloading all the updates and
everything and i don't wanna lose that
when the first things I install on your
one other icon right there second one
from the left
again del they recognize the Dell that
comes with that's that damn annoying
del alert that you or I won't even
go into a rant on that thing arm sound
obviously the speakers
microsoft money came pre-installed as
well but if
we are you know this is a free install
system but money's kinda more indication
more the homies are wouldn't be
business as early as Microsoft Money
they're going to use a more professional
accounting package of some kind
microsoft money
could be a student may be something like
that but I mean out I've
I did this rumor Packers how many of you
have Microsoft Money in Salt
yeah so you can eliminate certain group
of people and that's again the point
up the whole presentation so the
conclusion already kinda told
again the timestamp in this case not a
whole lot of significance but it tells
you that what time I took
the screenshot obviously but yeah it's
pretty the cation
everybody sees all the evidence is there
what I describe this is me sitting there
installing a brand new computer
I for you out that's a temporary yes
that's absolutely
as absolutely good point in this case
was just temporary because I was playing
around with it in
but yeah I think says that can be easily
turned off and on
yet but it but it's absolutely 10 sings
you left
when I go back to the that slider sure
the beginning of making that case
that could be maybe a plus one or -1
kinda field all those go in that
direction to you get
get a good profile of where you're going
now this isn't just for
for them on taskbar obviously this can
be used for
anything you see on the screen and this
one again Windows XP
obviously but what programs the
sickening I know if you got to see that
especially maybe in the back
so maybe somebody up front can help us
out here but some programs on there that
maybe stand out as different like
microsoft office isn't exactly
different but for example you probably
see on here
power toys okay what kinda person has
power toys installed
no a power user up sometime that's not
something that
you know the the receptionist was gonna
have installed on your computer or
something like that
arm UCI I'll okay how about
nero 7 why would you have an assault if
you don't have a CD burner you just got
a clue about hardware from the software
once again
what does it mean again maybe nothing
but keepin' contact
arm iTunes UCI to user
possibly have an iPod
maybe
that's what I thats exact that was right
that was my trick question I've got it
in the notes here
that's a total red herring that's why
you wanna enumerate all of them don't
depend on any one thing
when you install that stupid dumb
QuickTime
it automatically puts that iTunes and
there now saucy that's a tricky one
night there
I love how about to let see what else I
don't spend too much time on it but
Tom palm thing in the bottom right
now as far as I know that doesn't
installed by default anything but it may
probably mean somebody has
some sort of palm device that they
use with their laptop
and and they obviously we know that that
comes with
arm Windows XP you can use the built-in
command line or
Internet Explorer or you know any
browser will support FTP but this person
went above and beyond
to get a doubt an FTP program for some
reason were
actually I'd never heard that that's a
good point yeah absolutely
absolutely because they're completely by
default order
course you can go in and alphabetize
them storm whatever began this case I
did not do that
s a very good point I didn't catch that
they've got
this person might be paranoid they've
got a couple anti-virus on their
I am
man got on all kinds of stuff
all me and you guys are so you don't you
guys can get the presentation you doing
great you name it
every one of these little things like
bowl on the desktop that's me move it
later put on the desktop for now
but not only that if and again I know
people can't read some the file names
but if you can look
you can see like the the at the very top
there's an mp3 file
at is even know that icon with its
associated with when I am
everybody recognizes that problem
gotta
maybe a that's actually
random in a randomly assigned to
something when you yeah so
on that could be anything arm look at
the
and again I know so we can see the
bombings but the file names on a couple
as mp3's
you may not recognize it DJ Snyder space
something there
some F bill F bill radio buddy
no may not know what that is from
looking at the screen shot but you can
go and search for later
on your search engine of choice we won't
mention the word whatever your search
engine of choice is
and find out and now you're building not
only profile the computer but even more
the person they're into this type of
music they listen to these particular
shows
what if now well
yeah that gives it later but I mean
I could make up a screen name with your
handle on it just as easily that's not
you know
well yeah i absolutely that so many
think summer more obvious than others
like that of course
I put another little man any stragglers
who knows the bottom right
I have a window open my taskbar the G
miss
in an art of deduction which is named
the presentation so
GG I that's not something that's
normally map by default allotted rise if
you're up to G
so this is probably on maybe in external
card or map to a drive on a network
somewhere
you know just little things now you've
built up someone who has network access
is a power user who has all these things
install
right absolutely
well like and I don't know this it may
be a little obscure but when those
explore
if you notice is on my anything above
that line
are you see those four things Mozilla
Firefox Thunderbird
Media Player and Windows Explorer 1064
doesn't go in there by the fall
so I went out of their way to put that
there so in my case
Michael browse my files directly a lot
so I put that there but what if you
would have seen that accounting software
someone is using this almost exclusively
for they want a visa so much they're
gonna put it right up at the top or
doesn't mu
the ones below the line rotate based on
use so
a
and what kinda user might use notepad
well
and actually here's another thing I
didn't really think about what you guys
are given the idea is to is if you look
through a lot of these
applications you're saying quite a few
pieces of different shareware or
open-source offers of this person
obviously gets around knows how to
to get what they want so yeah I mean we
could we can sit here there's a ton you
see how this can build up and how fun in
putting all these things together so
we're gonna move on to a couple
others here about your browser window
we're gonna go we're gonna start going
through these lil bit more quickly cuz
you get everybody's obviously gotten the
point you guys would beat me again the
stuff I didn't find a 4-cell
so you guys probably got this down but
there's also some fun things in here
offer small the browser and operating
system that is being used we know some
browsers don't work on certain operating
system so that
helps isolate it but arm up
on on less on less
up unless they were purposely setting up
a screenshot for this presentation
com branded by
Comcast so we know what cable network
this person uses a cable modem
up man doesn't everybody have been Rev
on the toolbar
no not yet the Rev dot com check it out
you could download this presentation
from my sites thank all dot com
all the stuff that all the articles I've
had 2600 psi side note advertising
doctor opposite center center as I go
ahead yeah
Thomas squished
squished this all down
on here's a couple other little things
besides the AC the links in the plugins
are take a look at for example have yeah
you know wow that's a that's really good
yeah that's absolutely right
I notice how many okay so let's look at
the individual toolbars and this is
where at the very beginning I said the
more experience you have more things to
recognize
on the Google Toolbar if you have to
experience with it she's got the pop-up
blocker
and it's blocked a lot stuff sick of
myself
lotta stuff so they've had it all for a
while
you know this isn't a new computer for
somebody can say all know I just
installed
Ono you've had it for a while you know
that you're going to Lotte prawn site
with pop
I that's not me though that or
their paranoid up %uh spire and i were
absolutely on
look over on the far right-hand side of
the Google toolbar use the snag it
does anybody know what Snagit software
screen capturing software
so this person has a reason to do that
maybe make screen captures a videos
recordings for something like I don't
know act TV .org
him why I'm gonna for up published
leaving
I am arm product place at that sort of
stuff struggling for the word there
product placement the awful toolbar
actually gives you a little bit more
arm focus target this is actually some
useful stuff here
if you and again this experience you
know what comes with the fault with the
Yahoo Toolbar
by the fall with Yahoo it doesn't put
these things over here are like fantasy
sports
this user isn't a fantasy sports for
some reason and that kinda narrows it
down to a lot of people specially
hackers
my the only fantasy sports here in
hacking community
okay one more so that narrows it down a
lot as well so
again a lot of arm a lot of stuff as a
couple more obscure ones just for the
heck up at the very top
arm there's you see the the
passionately to point that very top
they're the ones on the far right
I looks like the AOL my icon guy there
and as a couple other between as anybody
recognize those
yeah they probably up they've got MSN on
their the low dollar sign
right there Party Poker now
so this is somebody who's online playing
poker
which in that narrows it down yeah and
well you know an input now that we've
got this big footprint now let's step
back again let's do the analysis part
we can cut it so what type of user is
but we've got enough in just this one
to really pinpoint we know this person
is has a yahoo account
because I got ya into what they probably
got a Google account maybe not not
are required for the pool to I don't
think anybody correct me on that
okay but you'd for the Yahoo account for
you to have your
those custom links and stuff in there
you have to have a yahoo account for
that
so you put all that together you know
they've got a party poker account they
play party polka dot net
XIV all of these things you really
pinpoint it down if you're a
are detective trying to find this for
real trying to pinpoint
get the information from Party Poker
fine from ya who put it all together
you're not going to get your free
pretty good handful of people
yeah that's so you gotta give me all
kinds every time I get that this
so much that no you know it's great I
keep coming keep uncommon
thank you I
alright so again
this is another one Tom very quickly
through this because I see how much time
here
nor worker arm very quickly for this one
different browser but still looks like
Windows XP
using Firefox Eva says most Firefox on
arm
again Lotus the links you see the been
traveling on their
arm there's a couple other interesting
things and these links
now we're getting very precise a very
detailed I want every back up and think
of the overview that you're looking
for specific things that you can build
their case on and they were
using examples to illustrate them arm
IMDB
that's an interesting link to have on
they have three different search engines
that someone
who doesn't have any allegiance to one
particular search engine
the big G somebody who actually wants to
mix up their searches for whatever
reason
arm tiny or else an interesting thing to
have arm
how about list this to on here that are
really
the very next witnesses post to
mainstream does anybody here
for me with mean streams good friend of
mine de CS
and I rattle run a site name streams
which is a arm
social bookmarking site kinda like
Slashdot
things on those lines are based on the
medics engine
arm but that's a post to
I can go to a web page that I find
interesting and click that button that's
a little JavaScript ap lit that will
post
that injury to my particular blog on the
site so
this person must have on the extremes
account we've narrowed it down quite a
bit once again
and a/c way back machine than
the very last one assist press it does
anybody recognize
that I'm hoping somebody will get this
one press it
who said that
WordPress there we go Word Press
that is same thing if you it's a little
job thing that will post
and it read your blog and you're not
voting interest
other people's blogs are you well I
guess in some cases you can but mostly
your posting your own blog
so it says right there digital doll cut
off or whatever so
that's my site a pretty but this one
pretty much nails it down to who it is
again
right and if you know the stumble upon
toolbar
when you do go to our site you can post
comments and things like that
if it's a site you've been to an add a
comment the entries on that will change
the colors will change in your you know
that this person has been to this
particular site before
right right and this case yet this was
just put on again for the screenshot so
arm
yeah
yeah absolutely Sangha Gogoi Gmail com
anybody care arm are
again to briefly go through this one IRC
ever is getting the point some really
nice speed up to a couple more these
arm you know they're using what client
using work obviously
but you can see in that screenshot you
can tell what username I was using
I was logged in as so this is more like
shoulder surfing you want to find out
with our login as he so-and-so is that's
also what I do
they see the username you can see what
downed server they're connected to this
is our
in red saree see what channel they ran I
just chop this office is pretty
self-explanatory
what user names anything else like that
you get a time stamp on this
as well depending on what the topic as
you see the topic the channel is
been Rev radio 134 this Tuesday so
134 with Mark Spencer white what time
frame was that that was
you know what we're gonna be doing 157
tonight at eleven o'clock so
you know twenty some episodes ago sing
at a time frame exactly when the
screenshot was taken as well
up
90more is the messenger clients
I this is these are just reply from the
first um
first Google Image Search all these and
look at all the plane user names people
take screenshots
when I can harass anyone these people if
I want to be a jerk I mean
they're posting their usernames all
their list of all their bodies you know
let's
think oh well you know the bad things
can happen when are you going person a
Denny's people can pretend to be on a
friend of so-and-so yeah
you know Center could be dangerous to to
have someone that kinda stuff
out there but you can learn a lot of
from it I do that
Ste just
just saw
check check check costs Ste
physical access to some other files
any better when I have to eat the thing
hello
check check you better get
I am so what's actually got physical
access to some the files even if
for temporarily getting access crabs
them off
well you look at the Med and again
people
probably know about meta-data skim
through this quickly but meta data is
actually
data about data that's the Wikipedia
definition I think it's a great
definition very simple and to the point
data about data so what kinda files use
meta data
image files document files music could
be anything really
arm it's all in the file specifications
and what the file
contains arm and what kinda data to the
attached for example id3 i think is a
great example this because
you to put the author the title on the
genre all these other there's a lot of
stuff and
id3 tag that's a former meditate its
data about
the rest of the day about that mp3 file
so
meta data can be really really cool XML
is the rocks or is awesome it's a great
way to
export and import data arm
and here's a really good example this is
a fun story this is my
to the trends manassas and Virgil who
mom did a presentation at inches onto
a couple years back the blackboard case
where they present a simple abilities in
Blackboard software
and you can go do the research on an
hour it probably would be to end up
going to hear but
basically they gotta cease and desist
because black or didn't want this
information released
well the cease and desist was sent in
Microsoft Word format
so I took the file this was several
years ago so they I took the file
I open it up when I see this comment in
there nothing they can read a bliss says
on this section gets us nowhere airing
our dirty laundry and this supports the
notion that we picked onto kids they
don't have spelchek they can stop it
right
we claim things and they denied way to
embed
embarrassing stuff in there and I have
the exit or not we will call an XML as
Microsoft bastardized
XML we won't go there on to show that
that's actually embedded
in that data and I can't go in there and
look at the properties of that document
file I can tell the author
this was the second revision so probably
secretary type that handed
lawyer he and his all comments and then
made a fool themselves until the company
name
hope they don't come after me now
because that arm fight is public
information is out there on Google you
find it anywhere
tells the date that is created they
can't deny that they didn't say this
they can't deny that this is a file from
them it's
it's right there in plain text in its
not really much they can say to deny it
true
sure you can artificially change meta
data but
you can get into deeper levels a
forensics to prove
real actual dates and things like that
that's totally
could be a whole presentation in other
itself
but its pretty damning evidence will put
it like that
great
even if you don't turn trains tracking
you everything is on
every time you pass something back and
forth Microsoft logging all that stuff
Microsoft Office
doc format or whatever well terminology
just explain
but it logs all that stuff here's a neat
little trick if you ever find
I found this is someone at work on time
before the had this follows about three
or four pages long but I was 10 megs
minor asking my sis pile so big it's
only couple pages long
so copy and paste that text output and
new files in a backyard is to clean up
and then I
you know look to see what's really in
the file is taking up the stand next
business day it's not
you know its all these undue is an all
these iterations of stuff them
past self a lotta stuff that's kept
captain
in the document and there are tools out
there if you're worried or concerned
about that he's always go through this
tools you can download I think even
Microsoft KB
made one they will strip a lot at midday
out for you for privacy reasons
but see X if properties
in Windows XP the screenshot we have
here meta-data
in photos again building a case on gonna
spend too much time on this but you can
see
the equipment make arm stamped in there
by default the camera model:
that's the type of camera the person you
so if you someone can claim they didn't
take this picture
that picture you got some nasty prawn in
the compound in on your doors and
you're not going to say you can take it
if you got the camera model is stated
its timestamp
notice at the bottom there's author and
keywords those optional
but if somebody actually put those in
and seated with their camera it's gonna
stamp that in there as well
really damn yourself but the other funny
thing out a throw this out I'm not gonna
given examples of this but another funny
thing I did find some
you go to someone site and find
they've got pictures of their vacation
and the kids sledding in the winter and
smiles
and then somewhere else they've got
those private pictures with their wife
that they put on some site that in think
anybody ever find but
coming from the same time frame same
camera type same author tagged in there
you get yourself in some embarrassing
situations so
again daytime pinpoint some the general
say again circumstantial evidence
but never give them any more information
and this is something that I
talk about the usual at never
voluntarily get more information than
you have to
those things are blank by default don't
put in your offer name what would you
really have a reason to unless you're a
professional photography
copyrighted or something like that by
you should be
making Creative Commons I here's one
example that I made up on one other
thing that's kept in phnom
in meta data is thumbnails sometime so
on this a good example my very good
friend along who
come bump into here in a week or two our
good friend along for this is a picture
of her from Freaknik
conference on the southeast thumbnail
love the image now you see the image
name up there's
I am g0 10 2001 details
all of the properties of that image well
noticed that thumbnail in the bottom
right corner that's embedded
in the meta data that is part love the
image okay
now we're gonna go to the next screen I
open this up and I edited
and I my graphic skills are the socks or
so all I could to
was tight the big white box over this as
we love a la ca
arm but I did say that that is an added
that to change the picture
the thumbnail does not get updated
specially older applications it does not
update them
and updates new versions of Photoshop
added that feature in there
when they realize what was happening and
everyone
in the room above 18 is a famous example
Aug 02 actually I do
how to find the data native support in
the OS
so you saw some screenshots I was doing
we're just right click on Properties
or application specific like id3 tags
and there are several tools out there
there's these Java libraries yes I want
to do from the program inside things are
some other
tools you can download arm or you can
actually go in and fix
and it the data itself and you'll see
earlier you saw the
sickening back you saw the camera name
their eastman-kodak et cetera
CX 7430 you have to use the properties
are the limits the operating system over
nothing up in hex editor
hex editor of choice and you can
actually see the data they see the
bottom says Eastman Kodak Company
it's in love a different format you got
the end of line markers in
control characters and things like that
in there but you can see that data
so yes catch Schwartz famous example of
this
cast I didn't know this was to be honest
because I didn't have cable
but apparently this was a host of tech
TV show some tech TV show
and she put these two pictures up on her
page
and you know looking also tree in
seductive
all that good stuff and you know should
you be worried about something like this
well
these are private pictures and as I said
earlier there's a thumbnail that's kept
in those images so even with you edit it
like for example you only want to show
off the eyes or something like that
and forget to update that I had to edit
I had to edit the naughty bits because I
didn't know United wanna get in each
other or
but you know she's a little grainy
because these were
for me it worse X expressed expanded on
with the proper term would be that
they were pulled out of some now so
they're not as high quality other
pictures
but yeah you trim those pictures and
don't do the update and yet you can
get yourself in an embarrassing
situation question is nothing to be
embarrassed about
yes me but will go on from there
um or what else Luciana speed-up
wanna miss anything arm Microsoft this
is another great example of my favorite
examples
arm Microsoft busted in piracy
they had an excuse but will we'll get to
that in a second and you can open it up
right while I talk a few emails using XP
can open up right now there's a path at
the bottom
you can browse so that and look at these
files and you will see it on
your laptops right now you can have
evidence that this on
this is one of the wave files when their
sound files in the help
and you go into the way file to hex edit
on you see the salt agar very and
and some love you might not recognize it
is kinda obscure but deep zone
I S ft Sound Forge 4.5 we know any
program that used to create these way
files it was
Sound Forge version 4.5 but the
key here is the word deep zone
deep zone is the name of a cracker this
is a cracked version if
a sound forge 4.5 minutes in every copy
a Windows XP so Microsoft excuse was we
outsource the sound production to
another company we didn't do that
but they can't tonight they can say no
we did you gated
so when he did the crack it would at
that to the files
so here's the last example so the first
two were kinda funny that
more serious all the more scary and all
that maybe more close to home for some
people
in this is great because it's a fairly
recent example on
keep in mind the legalities especially
for defense it was an interview in the
washington post as you see dated there
you can
certainly reference this in and verify
that it's all true
on and it had well they did in an
interview with this guy
I don't know how you pronounce his name
0 as 0x 80 of 80 of city
whatever and Dom didn't interview with
him
and it had IPTC information IPTC is
another former meditate it's an optional
former meta-data
shoes by The Associated Press
because they have these giant databases
all these photos the stock photos at the
use for their stories
and the mix them all up well
they all this optional extra data into
their photos
so they're doing and story on this
0 by eighty guy who was running by
nets bragging about how many millions of
dollars he made from scamming people out
of money
all the straw that he's committed in an
interview and kept him truly all this
anonymous tough
all but they have accidentally put the
city and the state
in the IPTC information saw okay we'll
okay fine narrowed it down to a CD
Universe New York City
you know from this is Roland Oklahoma
self little bit more extra research
again
utility bills go Batman on national on
this was
detective work from people on Slashdot
on the article itself gives you a lot of
clues
you know that this person was 21 years
old that he had blonde hair covering his
eyebrow City skinny et cetera et cetera
nearly down physically quite a bit you
know the smokes and even for for is
morally
you know get details on the story in a
hard-hitting journalism
lives with his parents in a brick
rambler mother mothers a
religion Christian dog southern accent
Center
is a high school dropout well you know
in the town like that how many high
schools that they have and how many
people dropped out you know
you know in a lil customer seven years
ago sorry about that
and the even says that you lose your
used car lot a gas station convenience
store in a strip club
well you take that a step further mix
all that together
well fact role in oklahoma has a total
population of around 3,000 people
3,000 already narrowed it down to member
preponderance of evidence to build down
a narrow down to find the person you're
looking for
probably twenty the role in our mold row
high school the only two high schools in
the area
you know pretty pretty straight for that
that's going to be
pretty accurate city data dot com
reports there were only about 40 people
in that town
that were that age in the year two
thousand little math and Mac
to got wage was in 2000 only about 40
people
down to forty possible people now and
the fact that he told where he lives
Google Maps will give you the court
instead he somewhere between that strip
club
their convenience store and that used
car lot somewhere those coordinates
and you can actually go and google map
the whole thing
cell kinda scary that here you are
giving an anonymous interview
in this presentation is that haven't
done it hope in the passage definitely
check out about
how to talk to media be careful you
don't give them stuff like this and
don't
specially for running up on ripping
people off will be a retard anyway
they'll be stupid
what a moron but I will anyway so before
we wrap it up
what high-profile did you make about me
you be watching this whole thing
Stanback what for small
she did you look at Brown laptop my
using Adele
arm what software did I used to make
this presentation
stempel it's pretty common
PowerPoint PowerPoint every summer arm
obvious if I use PowerPoint
running operating system put all the
stuff together about me
did I admit that I you some other things
earlier during a presentation that I had
a Google account for example
accounts fantasy sports I gave you a lot
of stuff on the way was
keeping all that animate or as we went
along but I gave you a lot of
information about me just from
presenting
just from showing a lot of the stuff
what web sites I frequent what was I
supposed to have an account mean streams
Up Party Poker things like that so you
can get a pretty accurate profile from
me just from this
presentation today cell that's about it
I get shouts out to the digital art thou
several other over here
I am going to digital art and/or which
is the blog like having already
the sites enough saying I dot com you
can download this presentation
all the presentations are given it hope
Def Con all over you can download from
there all the articles I've had
all from sang dot com and been red dot
com we mention
great form slots a cool people there
lotsa stuff to learn
in red dot com the addiction into my
local been read meetings this
presentation in this is this is to
everybody
this presentation that very first
image that use of the little taskbar was
me
flying for work and I look to my task
wow that's kinda cool little trillion
think downey like I wanna fight guys at
my meeting with recognize that
that's how the space station start this
whole thing started off as just dial
screenshot
like on its Kenny don't know what else
we can come up with so I went to the
meeting thinking all this just be a
silly little side note in we all started
looking around why what else cool if I
will sacrifice actually put together
several other screenshots
put it together into a fifteen minute
thing now we've got a full presentation
looking meta-data
all the information that you can find
out again I made up the term electronic
deduction but it seems fitting
have all the stuff any %uh view even
these little things that you find
interesting
other people can find interesting if I
know this is kinda finally did make
learn anything from this is a lot of new
stuff in your right I mean is nothing
that was above anyone's head
you know it's all stuff that you know
before becoming putting it together in
such a way
that it's like wow thats that's kinda
cool that I can isolate site
stuff like that so your gifts give
presentations at your local been
meetings at your local 2600 meetings
whatever you make whatever you call it
doesn't matter
meeting with people making all
presentations you never know what you
might
get out a bit so I've got a couple
minutes of you can
stairway from the spinning monkey the
mesmerizing
enough if you have any questions we got
maybe five minutes left three or four
minutes left so I'd be happy to
answer anything at a camp I may have a
question for summer youth she's out
there you guys give me not to get stuff
so
I'm sorry arm that was actually of love
your blog was
no such
shop thank you and I bring in bring that
checkered
look if you open up the chip pecan added
plus
which i think you're using to look at
the source
a Photoshop also put in some doubt about
I'm pretty sure there's a time in there
when it was edited and then that
original exist at it was still there
when the photo was taken
so you can also check for photo
manipulations way
if new some saved in
things get deep yeah you will also put a
you know metadata
said what's after with
another way of checking so to speak
you said I was there was ways of telling
if somebody was messing with the
meta-data
if somebody is like except writer or
something like that
uuuu minutes his ways that you could
kinda prove that how would you do that
you can change that's really while
talk afterwards because you get into a
lot it's not my expertise
but there are forensics things that can
go through their mostly what he's
describing
what I was thinking up was just going
back in there in a racist like describe
the Microsoft document
keeps a lot of stuff in there but their
applications custom
custom design that will do that they
sell law enforcement security and stuff
like that
rip it out or like he said plus is what
I use
good is a presentation on those tools
Sunday is presentation on those tools
and a
great comebacks what
also tonight for some people came and
your toys
tonight eleven o'clock find a revolution
radio season 4 episode number one
come back have some more fun probably be
a lot more colorful language is that
when this was love it more low-key
at some point across for that and
black racks doing freaking 101 tomorrow
at twelve o'clock
in this very room make check that out
I was gonna expand upon that point about
the forensics basically
what you do is you back in new track
with the computer dippers and use you
look at file access times file free
eight times
use access to our network you get that
data on
the servers and that as far as the
frenzy tracking
annex this
I don't like the way microsoft does that
turn tracking on
its tracking anyway you know this is
kinda like this way to say oh yeah
to make it easier for you to follow
other people's but is keeping a lot
all data on its own anyway and
yak of yourself anyway
thank you very much short notice yes
original one is cancelled that was
supposed to be
yes has been cancelled but there is
still a police station
12:30 tonight after shows come back and
check it out thanks again for your