am number 113 for those of you who are
unaware
the theme for the weekend for hope
number six is based on
also program called the prisoner with
Patrick McGoohan as number six
the senior my talk this morning is
flash Sox for advertisers actually
flash sucks for consumers who cannot
download flash
advertisers haven't figured that out yet
and so they're still buying your
website's
and then say ok download flash or go
away
I hate that what see
the reasons I hate flash want to waste
my time
it really has content but i wanna see it
doesn't know I have graphics turned
of it takes for ever to download Flash
content if you haven't got the resources
and its public box always asks always
trust mega media content
maybe don't want to okay
it wastes my time
you only have download flash once but
they keep coming up with
new bloated versions and then
the flashing able Content takes forever
to load some people are still on dial-up
Sunday because people have figured out
yet he keeps moving the pictures above
my eye is naturally following it and
find it difficult to break away from it
a technique first used by MTV music
videos
I have never forgiven in TV for this not
a dial-up connection
it simply takes forever for a website to
start up
I'll let's you know
it really has content I want to see
I'm not looking for the number 31
Cingular Wireless Nextel Cup
chasing mighty Chevrolet Monte Carlo to
zoom around my screen
I want to reach Jeff Burton's by I want
to join his fan club
why are they wasting my time now you're
end is annoying enough
as an animated Jeff now you're fucking
with flash
as well I use yahoo mail online why
can't you know me I have a preference
for
no flash yes nor no animated yes we just
take
longer to download speeds when a dial-up
preferences should ask
what is my connection speed and have
dial up is check its limit the size
enemy to Jeffs presented to the user
just also haven't
all component with and height if you
include those with an Heights components
than a table can load while the rest of
the document fills in
otherwise it has to wait until it loads
the graphic so it knows with a width and
height are
and then can display %uh the table again
a great waste of time
it doesn't know if I have graphics
turned off
women who would turn graphics of well
people whose families can't display
graphics I have a
picture of another 32 teletype your
which on Fort Lee is not coming up
if you visit my website Cheshire
catalyst dot com
slash flash talk dot HTML
it will have these graphics and I'll
Desai people can't display graphics
college students
during exam week turn off graphics but
but colleges have also been with
yeah lots a band with foreign tired or
you ever been in a dorm during exam week
everybody's hitting the web that band
with gets down to a little sliver
and you know what the graphics you want
the information content for your study
to try of the graphics also
people with links the text-based web
browser
are still used by blind users with me so
the sizes
web browsers with limited plans
on their cell phones %uh there's a whole
nother subject
where I get invited to 0 visit
somebody's website
I try to pick it up on my cell phones
I'm right there in the store
and ok so you can see is what they will
flash or the RAM in your store trying to
your website to get some more stuff
and i cant get there because you decide
to have Flash
there's also PDA uses our pilots
with web browsers on and
summer web browsers 0 they can't handle
flash
I'm sorry you're not reaching us it
takes forever to download Flash content
a who wants flash
well the advertising agencies okay
flashes expensive to develop
so that neither the Billings increase
and that's where we're headed season 2
is increasing their billings also you
the fastest processors and video screens
to develop it
more Billings was gonna buy that faster
hardware
thing you have to put a copy that
hardware on decision-makers desk
so that you can see it and so who how
flashy
how eye-catching
you wanna waste this guy's time and want
to approve the project
you can deploy the other Flash graphics
and get out there before the public so
arm ever housing agencies love flash
80 clients are sold on the value of the
MTV affect and love the fact that
they're getting product will keep the
test for the audience
but for how long as you want 'em back to
your website in the future
gonna sit through that thing again and
again and
again they don't like it
it irritates them one rule that housing
don't irritate the customer the pop-up
box always asked
always trust my committee content there
is no box I can check it says
never trust met the media content or
never asked me this question
again you could say it never happens but
again for this version of Flash
or below and that's fine when the next
version comes out
ask me again but wait until then leaves
know who can't use flash people laugh
about an ass carnation
but muscular chasing a mature miles per
hour literally
sure what to wear TVs out there Web TV
users can't use Facebook maybe
they purchase your product pepsi's a
good example of this
turkey sending me emails all the time
composer flashy website
I get there and yes is flashy Alexis got
flash but i cant download flash
when I'm at work my firewall on the job
when I'm home in a dialogue
it takes for ever for content I don't
even what
because it wastes my time I what
information contact
not lips up blind uses I got bigger
market who cares a very lenient
right R-twelve the Americans with
Disabilities Act may
rear its ugly head at some point are you
may want to keep that mine
people behind corporate firewalls were
downloaded any kind are forbidden
paranoid people who are too afraid to
what malware might be in a flash
attachment
we had actors here at this conference we
would never go
love such a thing I'm sure up so
the question is Watson ever Kaiser to do
art don't just say get flash or get gone
building a non flash page is billable to
you can hire on an extra programmer for
that that's billable
a if you can find the Rules page %uh
contest
usually it will jump you to a non flash
page reconnect just
fill in the form and enter the contest
that's what you need to do
is have a way of getting the consumer to
the contest page you can
get there email address get into options
you can sell them
more stop isn't that what it's all about
so basically
flash sucks for advertisers and sucked
is a technical term meaning
customer dissatisfaction you don't wanna
piss off your customer
so find a way around using Flash and get
it out there
any questions yes
other steven is the flashes easier to
deploy for advertising agency
this is true up flair Macromedia
which creates and distributes flash is
now owned by Adobe
and the whole Adobe Acrobat model is to
give away viewer software
and then sell development software and
this works very well for
for flash from that standpoint
the fact that flash is eye candy
contract the I love the decision-makers
another good reason from agency
standpoint but
when it comes to consumer you're telling
consumers with
and you don't want your to consumers
because they make just walk away from
you at that point
and that's not what you want
yes 0 good
but mic wasn't working czech chick other
so why not just have go for
instead of the web isn't HTML to
whiz-bang like should we just have text
for everything then
work takes just pointed out that your ok
that's fine arm
text for being is fine and in fact when
you have
a graphic do have an alt tag on saying
what the graphic is for those people
who do turn off graphics arm go for is
good but I love
know anybody's really program for go for
any more
what happens when people don't program
originally more
and everyone uses flash assuming that
happens a flash still comes in under a
TTP
Hypertext Transfer Protocol so it will
still be
Nishino readable page
should be at any rate okay i was just
curious
okay thank you at this point I'd like to
choose my friend very
green who will bring up the next
part over representation here
okay you now
you
which button
first
weird
see me mouses
yes
right because
this
good morning
I'm sure a green light introduce myself
island in the Orlando area
for 25 26 years I'm a transplant
she said from Green Bay Wisconsin over
the last 10 years
retired 25
twenty-some years before that I was in
computer sales
in 20 years before that I was in the
educational field worked at the college
level
district office level regional service
agencies across 37 school districts
in urban us city districts
and in high school middle school and
elementary levels
my presentation today is on the
the digital divide
its some things
which
that's what the objectives
for the for this digital divide
presentation first objective is
can we shrink the digital divide faster
has been sinking
very faster than last year in fact it's
quite fast acceleration
but there is a large residual group of
people
that are still left behind in this
process
can people with limited reading skills
use the internet most of us
have long held a bias about limited
readers
which will exploring this presentation
can text to speech
help teach reading we look at this
interesting possibility and what
text to speech has to offer who among us
are capable and willing to help this is
my primary present
purpose for this presentation today to
the whole organization
and beyond hopefully from a contact with
other folks that in this particular area
lets the fine
the common understanding the digital
divide
it's basically individuals without
access to computer
internet the capabilities
on to use
equipment many people are are
just unaware other unlike many people
lot more people are fearful
using the internet because they've
really are
have fear failure hardware however
and software and connectivity an honor
primary concerns their other areas
that are you in have greater concern in
this area
a brief aside 4e a quick
Packers trivia question what city in the
United States
was the first city to have free internet
access
broadband throughout its business
district we'll
look for answers that the question your
presentation let's look at trends in the
digital divide
how many a bus are using
e-books blogs the week Ian this
organization
and the like on cell phones and
blackberries
iPad's and PDA's during your commute
back and forth to work
while exercising and why we're just
relaxing is
remote communication between people
increasing or decreasing we can safely
say
that there's been a
large increase in the
spread
of between people who are
like yourself who are high end users and
people who are non-users we can also
safely say
shrinking because we have far greater
far less number individuals who are not
using the Internet
today is a publication industry moving
into e-books we'll pursue that slightly
and take a look at
book pub book usage
and the options have the
is reading required to use the web
any books basically
most of us have a bias on we believe
that
we must be able to read in order to use
the Internet and although there are lots
of people who have relatively limited
reading
their potentials for us to circumvent
that process
let's have a reality check for a moment
about the book I was on the internet
just last week
stumbled across this particular
group data one-third of all high school
graduates
never read another book arrested their
life
spring forty-two percent of college
graduates
never re another fifty-eight percent
have
I love adults United States never read
another book after high school
by the way this is a way to sneak in
some information that wasn't presented
first 1/3 because this comes all
drop population as well
eighty percent United States families
did not buy
or read a book last year
seventy percent of US adults have not
been in the bookstore
can past last five years fifty percent
new books I'm not read to come
to completion
let's not focus on the people who have
who have not have chosen not to read
books
but instead let's look at the internet
and those people who are unable to use
it
because they cannot read the content on
the front page
we have federal law section five away
the deals with the blind
learning disabilities we have the Daisy
consortium is a group for publishers
that are focused on publication material
he in in print form and and also
five away has to do with the internet
computers as well as print
why is it that we are overlooking
other groups who are limited readers
which hinder their learning and
employment potential
what groups either should toddlers
access the web without being able to re
should school-age limited readers should
be allowed to learn in school
until they become proficient readers
should limited reading adults be allowed
to use the web to acquire information
and learning
to become more productive members of our
society
how easy can it become for these groups
to access the web
reading on the internet people with
limited reading skills
can easily learn to access information
online
but he takes summer components to do
this
first of all it takes an introduction we
need to have an orientation
one-on-one or hope fully
on the net and interactive type format
could be created takes an interest
what's interesting is if if individuals
have an interesting topic that they
choose themselves that they
really want information about their
interest will propel them into that
information
and successfully will be able to see
them
information speech them open
this closed-door print this copy
interest learners
and be a major benefit to them
what process can we use to make a smooth
transition
to text to speech
text to speech to read
text to speech enables a new in freeway
to learn to read
there are gaps in the complete solution
needs to be software written that ties
text to speech
to the learning process based on
findings
this will if properly done with
learner interest be self-motivated
self propelling and hopefully program in
a way that it can be
self-directed
online content interest to the
individual
provides incentives to continue
to the learning process
we will work not only on reading alone
but we will break into its components
hopefully
beginning with fun X which is the basic
structure
getting into comprehension or reading
and other components skills necessary
it's no small task but one of the source
needs
it's like declaring a national priority
on the light side just as an aside in
contrast to the earlier stance
on the use of the book there exist
today on the Internet a website
that has 300,000 e-books which are all
free they were put up there on July 4th
and very symbolic date in our history of
our country
and after August 4th
100,000 these books will be left up out
there permanently
for people to have access hopefully be
able to use
text to speech to listen to
like to think I've text to speech as the
technologies
sleeping giant not only text to speech
but I'm concerned about voice in hand
voice our
both both
methods process let's look at
the talking page becoming self
talk reading text to speech
is one of the elements need to add to
that
function facility with the Internet
Explorer Google
throw in some other skills on the
Internet like being able to diagram a
sentencing using
talking dictionary and then
we would move into voice recognition
later
which will allow us to deal with we're
all reading
and writing skills we mix all this up
and throw this into hopper
have a free-form database free-form
relational database
that has components text Voice and video
and now we can begin to roll up our
sleeves
thing off my jacket and you want to get
into the details
this program as we look up in the first
component
1 o'clock diagram here its
disliking reedy if you
have struggled in school with 3d or know
anybody that has
me know that they become disenchanted
with the printed page
and the reading process one ever take my
techniques that I
strongly recommend is his stupid the
percent
try to use text to speech
in order to do this we really have to
manipulate the person by starting to say
well
what are the interest areas that you're
most interested
to 345 tell me what those areas are
hi I have a technique for use with
Internet Explorer go up into the
favorites I put persons name down
up there let's grab a couple names Adam
Zoe and and war
Lori excuse me those three names
just happened to be the name of my 30
grandson
and his two-year-old sister and
Lauren who shins
in her second day on the rest of her
life today
she was born yesterday so third
pro grandfather I we take the topics
the three-year-old for example was
capable of
love listening and understanding a lot
text to speech
and we ask him what what are your main
interests and when we do that
he comes up with I like bob the Builder
and or
like Thomas the Train and if you list
five
if 43 whatever number of topic areas
that that particular
individual whether their child or an
adult under
their name under Favorites and then go
out and find five web sites and each of
those topics
and then copy those web sites over under
Favorites
then you take the person out there in
and we're going to use
text to speech now there's a many
TTS is out there document readers page
readers tax treaties whatever you want
to call them
and they're appearing quality levels of
annunciation the one that
I use is one of the largest insulation
bases in the world
it's on Canada's call replys dot com and
the need to Sparta
replys is that it's free they have two
other versions that you can pay money
for
but this free version is copied onto
your computer
and then you go into the favorites pick
anyone these web sites
take Lanham out there or any adult out
there
hit that particular website see the
print material in front of you
and say all I can't read block it cut it
pasted into this program hit the play
button the plane but will allow you to
talk
any speed use you select it will allow
you also to magnify the print bigger
smaller
it allows you to pick for voices it's
free
what happens then is after you do this
over a bunch of periods of time a beat
10 15 25
maybe fifty times the individual gets
the sea
hey if I'm an adult I can read
and all this print material that's been
totally unavailable to me all the Sun
I can get access to ALL that's just
awesome opportunity that's been
in the field since I first bought my
hobby is computer
in 1978 with ways recognition
the text to speech programs came in to
have
decent operation about ten years ago and
in the last five years
they've been very acceptable but they do
in my mind represent an absolute
sleeping giant as the use this program
we begin to like text to speech
people become happy listeners
and then after that we kinda shift gears
a little
we offer them a concept that says
how would you like to be able to as a
sideline be able to
learn how to read just kinda like a
hobby
make it easy and painless and
most people will kinda go along with
that
particularly if they can be doing things
and learning things day 10
not somebody else use them as an
assignment
learning that most of us have
participated in
so basically what we do is we grab that
information
and love we say well
let's let's see a little demonstration
here we're gonna do a demonstration of a
word capture
I want you to visualize with me now that
we're going out into this this
free-form database we put on before okay
its like this big holding tank and
we're going to have it structured as you
would look at a spreadsheet
so we have a spreadsheet down the side
with all the words
men across the top we have all these
topics
and the topics are going to be the first
columns going to be
new word and all the words are the
second column would be the Talking
Dictionary now out there on the internet
is a free dictionaries if you go into it
there's a fanatic pronunciation if you
touch that
with your mouse it breaks the word in
its phonetic parts for
very nicely done the next column
I would have hidden in the background
explain that later
there are forty 6 180 characters that we
use when we talk
and I would have the versions of the
I or you in their multiple painful
ramifications of how we
pronounce each one of those listed first
and then I'd have all the individual
vials sounds
like be see the K
all the way through the alphabet and
then at the end that I have
but %eh in whns agency each and all the
other some through
forty-six okay now that person doesn't
see that that's in the background
so we're gonna try and capture a word so
we have them going through a page and
they listen to the page
and then we we say to the person well
hope
let's see what we can get out of this
page from learning perspective
now when we teach reading we know that
the first thing you do
is to take advantage above the words
that a child has learned
from memory visually that's cool site
for Caterpillar's so we Grampus Eight
for gamblers
in a preschooler a child in kindergarten
so far that's 150 words
at the usually acquire in people that
are older and into adulthood you may
have
3 500 1500 or even a thousand or so
because we learn a lot about traffic
traffic words and
restaurant names and all that kinda
stuff so we take this page that
since Lerner has listened to the first
time and we say let's go back over
we're gonna do something different this
time I want to look at the beginning at
this page
and i watch look at the page and pick
out the first word you already know
and so they look at the first word and
guess what it could be the word
so they know the word okay musher
you know virtually almost all
us people who who are illiterate have
some degree
love love basic reading
that are limited so the word does pit
well what we do is we need programming
here
to take what's going on on this text to
speech page now
on that's pretty much wine here days to
seek
that kinda horsepower his we need to
take the mouse
move it up touch the word though
double-click on the left-hand bottom and
that will be highlighted
and we need a program that says take
that word now
and bowls that word the
and then next program search for that
page
and find all the other those in
Baltimore on the page at the bottom make
a total dominance is under 12 14 those
on this page
and then US the individual well
let's look up at the top of the page and
see what the next word is you know
is at hand is it or whatever but you
know
and repeat the process over and over
again so you have all these words being
being bold and highlighted tabulated out
the bottom
when you get done with the page even
those with very limited reading
capabilities
got 50 percent seventy percent of the
page that they already know how to read
and that in itself has a motivating
factor
let's go on to the second page now will
turn the page over
and we see on the next page that every
word from the first pages been carried
over and saw all those an answer but
some
there are highlighted and the REIT
Adelaide on the second page
so we have those numbers also
accumulated okay
now we keep doing this until week after
all no words
which are this 150 your thousand-word
vocabulary
you know some point in time we also need
to worry about
building beyond the site for Camry we
take an hour into this forty four
phonetic area
that we're talking about making the
spreadsheet alright
then the person excuse me
then the person is basically
going to take on new words now there's
another segment to the process that
that we call comprehension really and
will be doing theirs we go back over the
page again
and listen to it and this time we say
we'll is there anything on this page
because you're interested in this page
and it's a topic that you like
is there anything on this page if you
want to remember for future reference
and so we can create
and external segment have a database
that allows them to capture certain
elements on the page putting out
inundated
any organize data is given some kinda
label where they can find them again
and help them to comprehend reading is a
significant element
reading okay so
basically as we do this then and we keep
doing this
some time in 10 or 15 pages later
and you come to a new page and the
person has a total and they're going on
all the sudden they're gonna say
who I know that word I know that we're I
know that word at that particular point
you have taken the person who only went
there because I've content
motivation and was something that they
were interested in reading
you now hook them into this processor
reading
the air been swept up into it and their
acquiring
their site for cambiar hand they say
will I don't know that word but that
word is about the topic that I'm
interested in
so that's a new word so I wanna know
that
well basically
there are many who want to to and need
online access but are limited to reading
many over my right here in New York City
in your city and in mine
in our nation in in the english-speaking
world
or by the way one of the reasons why
I'm interested in circumventing read and
helping limited readers
is because although I was
as a child passed on I basically flown
the second grade
third-grade fourth-grade fifth-grade
6p and seventh grade
at that time they tested me in my
reading level was that have a
second-grader
those years were very
painful but fortunately
I was given another opportunity I was
put into a special class and allowed to
repeat the seventh grade
I was able to graduate high school with
no more than a fourth grade reading
level in the upper half my class
and devoted my life to the things I talk
to you about in the first session
being a special educator for twenty
years
now that I'm retired can look back in
life and I say what are the things that
I haven't done
during my career when I was working and
I have time to do now
and this particular message mission is
very near and dear
to my her
to create this process underwear
I believe would help many individuals
and give them renewed cage or
p he whole thank you for your time
your questions are you preach equally
appreciated
for the purposes recording those if you
have time
talent can care enough to help
please contact me and jerry green
my email was GGG green 37 me back
my phone numbers 407 862 6665
he cell cell excuse me to
Shin my cell number is 407 701
thank you very much
do any of you have any relatives for
families or friends
that have difficulty reading
yes aging population yeah I'm was a five
min
trouble yes season asking me about to
text to speech in
internet as and have more options for
that given a wonderful views you just
grab this free program movies icon
if she can't see it you have to copy and
paste for all the website's
are there is a version it is these
programs that you can pay money for
he has two other versions and there are
lots of them read aloud is common one
and many others
and they have charges this particular
program if you buy the two components is
up two hundred thirty dollars or so
and basically thats were were
basically looking at because she can
then go to website
touch and then read right on the
internet for
what and want anything for people with
division problem thank you for that its
macular degeneration so she's
you have to get high contrast keeper for
her first year with
but this program magnifies Prince
and it's free so thank you mean thats
need to
one thank you for the early day to you
and which is a very disturbing
your legs sure you have a sense
have ideas for your sense how the trains
are the last few years ago an educator
summit decades a
wells getting nice if if we listen to
what's going on
in the field of education the if the
process has been slowly crumbling
from within and without okay
it processes hood crumbles from the
parents I defense because parents are
are indulging their children too early
with too much
television computer games was whatever
the technology that we've kinda brought
into the world
and not really you know going into
reading and spending time in reading
working even towards that parents don't
do reading readiness at home in the
child gets a school
they will fall behind and those that
fall behind fall off
the the treadmill love learning because
it sent the bill
generally lockstep thing and when you
fall off your in trouble
and you stay in trouble and by the time
you get to middle school
truss you heat
and there's a lot kids the bottom 20
percent
education basic
its its it's really you know it's
getting worse
and to help this the federal government
states are making these national tests
in Florida we have an Afghan test
and we're testing academic function
okay were testing content and all
content is really important
and the kinds of schools that we grew up
in were content-based schools
okay there was some process in our
schools and quite frankly
with the internet and the access the
information with WiFi
him even more so in the next couple
years content is not something we have
to store here
we have been have access to that
digitally I mean I can grab in my pocket
and ground and advice and say go on the
internet and what do I need to find
I will get it I need to know how to find
it I need
know how to evaluate it and I need
know how to put to use in my life those
are processed
and so are the the need to read actually
is is 21 hear something scary
I consider it change it or I don't
consider it a long-term
need because although hoover
made the printing press and we're
celebrating
these Gutenberg Project which is 35
years aged
which is pretty awesome itself I
envision
the future will be more p graphic gooey
world
he information will be transmitted and I
know we don't like to look at the MTV
any a marriage is pretty much but the
content stinks
but the process the process is the way
your mind works
the printed page works way to use law
for the capabilities of our human mind
and all and very few of us and the world
that we live in has not focused on
developing
what's called photographic mine when I
studied to be a special educator
I learned about two standard deviations
on both ends of the scale
and on the gift inside okay there are
many
things we need to worry about it percent
upside down or not
its 10 minutes okay harm
we need to you get different time
schedules
between to good home
we really we really need to to
be aware that this information we now
transmit to to ourselves can be
condensed
into still images can be put into
minuscule clips not the sizeof
commercial
one 23 seconds or so you can mean
the Chinese explain to us
thousand years ago a picture is worth
how many words so
so we need to learn that message and
and the only reason why we don't have it
had it recently is because we've only
had
com megabytes gigabytes
you know but we have terabytes now
and a thousand times more into petabytes
and we have that all out there now in
it's like having this huge closet
in our in our intellectual house that's
empty right now
we will fill that closet okay
hand we've been concerned
with dot matrix images
okay we we don't need to have week we
can
we can transmit through raster and their
conversions from
from dot matrix interested masters
enormously more efficient in controlling
data
and so there's a lot of things out there
that are yet to be harvested
but the saddest thing is we are falling
further and be
further and further behind in
application software development and
hardware utilization
I'm worried that your date is pointing
to some science fiction
stories becoming reality whether it's a
science fiction story a
comics without words and
my wife's retired teacher and she talked
to some the sewers students in reading
as the UI
with the talking brings member from yeah
you this book
well brings you for talking in there is
nothing other than
that's where food is an ass for what
about Library Thing is
yeah well you know can't now with cat
scanning going on in this
looking into our brains and seeing
what's going on in our brains
live were thinking on
we probably will be seeing even though
I'm almost 70 years old I potentially
can see in my lifetime
the ability to find a way to transmit
information
90 not through our eyes
not through our years a Sony sony has a
patent on that that was
about the Times's Service Pack the idea
the idea is not information
the idea of life is a process
and learning the process of living
how we spend hardly any time in our
school systems
really developing what we are who we are
and more importantly why we are and so
I'm into other things beyond
text to speech been developing
curriculum
and a new concept of the learning
environment in the future
and also home we'd
to look at life and discover
you as a person who and what your
those bits a communication for sessions
may I ask any
as you're gonna see website has the the
books were posted July 4th e-books
whole it just put down the the Gutenberg
Project
for farm gutenberg our work
or put down 300,000 e-books and
ill be there thank you again even any
other questions
here's my
yes this might be a bit off topic but I
was wondering what your opinion is the
No Child Left Behind Act
is you know the ideal Elzinga school its
well my concept is real simple I have
come from a world that's been built
educationally generally from the top
down No Child Left Behind and way before
that
way back in this in the sixties when I
got my message
exception education we were concerned
a bow going to the bottom in building at
the bottom
and in are bottomless
is exception alleys people that are
physically mentally and emotionally
very limited in all kinds of ways I've
learned in my life
there those of us that we've given a
significant
challenge in life have an advantage
over people generally given all the
positive guess
because if we r cable to over comments
that have succumbed
we've become very very strong people
okay
and very driven people and so
the No Child Left Behind thing I support
I'm concerned primarily in this
presentation
about working with people that are right
above that group
okay this twenty percent at the bottom
that's growing
and festering in causing our society
enormous
problems and expense okay the answer
session at this time
during I will be out though think order
efforts of those who want to
with us thanks for coming enjoy your
convention here
were village be seeing you