good evening everyone
it is Saturday 2200 area a
hope number six that means it's time to
learn about building a hackerspace
brought to you by
numbers 107 54 39
in ninety-eight usually I just enjoy
these panels but
today I'm on it I'm porch up
I'm from the a new your computer
Community Connection project a place up
in Poughkeepsie New York
next to me Harry from the illegal
factory next in line binary from the AC
pastry
and last up is drago and also from your
computer
community computer Community Connection
project on you might be wondering why we
picked that name
NY CCCP seems funny we want to talk to
you about a whole bunch of things and
we're just going to start by asking
se binary why
a build a hackerspace much a reason
still
hackerspace there's many people tried is
pretty long history United States
but all main reason is cooperation he
can do so much more with many people
then just by yourself
and by pooling resources down with costs
putting everything
you can accomplished so much more and
another reason just getting everything
out your house your mom's basement
whatever it means
not having you know power tools and
computers and crap all over the place
it's pretty good have a separation that
and I think another important thing is
people work on projects and sometimes it
takes them quite a bit I'm
to finish something it's nice to be able
to work on something a couple hours a
day and have it stay put anybody messing
with it
for you know weeks or months at a time
and then it's just good to have a
meeting spacer place to hang out
you know will always be there how did
you find all the people that
were interest in creating its kinda
plays a mean of course you know there's
a lotta each room
money from the people in your CD how big
is your CF to be I'm
cover I'm we able to do in Philly that
will
me on loan so is a fairly large city
and there was a small group of people
that kinda banded together
on and that some of us work for local
universities
so is fairly easy to put feelers out on
there were twenty six hundred meetings
that some of us would go to
an attempt to recruit new people on a
lot it was word-of-mouth minutes
it's really quite difficult to do that
by word of mouth on
summit things that we've toured around
with doing are having like
demonstrations are talks
or you know like some sort of community
involvement actually give
new people a reason to come and take a
look at the space
and you know see the sort of things that
we have to offer
I guess I double the all the groups
appear poughkeepsie is probably a small
city
arm we found people just because they
were our friends are there centered
around college
we primarily found people in the Cape CV
the college's
are the colors that work for and your
friends at IBM in places like that
gives is very different than new york
city or Boston or philadelphia were sort
of
small is everything ok people should be
looking for in
potential space members his
his people with big money bags important
days people with the
I mean I would think I I think it kinda
goes along two separate lines so
you definitely need people were stable
people who can contribute money
on a regular basis on but a lot of those
people are also very tied up in their
jobs you know they're working twelve
fifteen hours a day
they might have families so they can
really always contribute in terms of
time
so if you can get younger people who
have more time than they do money
and make you know I a good balance
between the two
you wind up with a pretty nice space
yeah I mean people are there definitely
the most important thing and I think
again the purposive why we don't talk
right now is just to share our
experiences
failures and successes and on hopefully
getting other people to create
you know working tax bases around the
country but most people think that
economics is in a driving factor in all
it's important miss it the second most
important factor
spaced the people in selecting the right
people stable people people a dedicated
to it
are the most important thing you can do
so
to find those people usually they find
you on
in Boston were pretty lucky enough where
it's happening on history and I
you know kinda walking on that and I
found them
they didn't find me pretty much so was
going out in the different spaces in
I was involved in some different spaces
in New Haven Connecticut
on and you to know people
bring your honor rent the space station
just find someone has money in C
here Suki's here's access or stuff you
know
three password all the machines and
everything it's really important to find
stable people
it's important to find people you can
trust because a they're going to have
the keys to get in next year's servers
and
all your tools and anything like that
see need to make sure you don't bring in
people that you're not comfortable with
either
people that a like 'cause other issues
or drama
anything like that or have other reasons
to be there just wanna space so they can
get
moms house or something like that
shouldn't
but left economics people with money
can't stress enough that if you do to
temper stars space
we found that on shouldn't really a
single person should not be paying more
than two hundred fifty dollars that
seems to be the magic number
this year at least for space anymore
than that if you were to lose that
number
nearly put the whole thing financial
would you say that the people involved
is the major contributing factor to
downfall i've seen I've seen many spaces
on I've only been involved in this wind
however
it seems to me that if there was one
thing I was gonna cause the downfall
a certain place in the people so I can
speak to this because we just have one
%uh var mi MOU
members move away on and he was probably
the most social out of the whole crew
and often brought everyone together be
it at the spacer barbecues or what not
and we've suffered quite a bit from that
there's you know not everyone not being
a socialist him
kind of meetings fizzle out a little bit
and so now trying to really
ramp up again you find a lot more just
called I mean definitely having someone
is very social and and can go out you
know has
many different frenzy in pole for many
different resources
makes it a bit easier to deal with
heard being described as being social
before it's pretty cool
but yeah it's definitely on important to
have stable people the usual several
plant if you know
people move on people moved to different
cities get jobs life changes
you know they can Ford page definitely
have a plan in place
so if one person were to leave be able
to still maintain this pace
that something is to be don't planning
into we've been fortunate to have enough
2g contingency plan if the kids see that
a we've had a few people that had to
drop out
because they got married and bought a
house or
various things like that were said sorry
guys can't do it anymore
they paid off for the last month and
moved on but a
if you plan well enough they have a bit
of a slush fund it doesn't hurt that
badly too if I did remember
we actually kept I think it was three
months worth of slush
in slush go well that's a good theory
it doesn't always work out that way I
was going to originally pulled all sorts
of graphs and charts in a way
nifty financial stuff which I never
actually choose to do
by Tom you do need to keep some here
funds
squared away so that you can at least
operate the space assuming
worst-case scenario for three months
you can you truck jump user some
speaking of things like leases which
provide flying
actual it's only once when she found the
people you have the drive in the means
to do that
next thing is to find placed stuff
so that what size like to determine what
kind of
a bigger place was I think for
poughkeepsie at least what we did was
we measure our apartment we decided that
well okay my
like crap roomies about 1/4 this
apartment
about half so I'm 18 so having
we ended up with a number like a
thousand square feet or 800 square feet
some like
yes something in the 800 to 1500 square
foot Rangers are original target
the the way commercial space generally
works is you pay
per square foot per year so
in an ever a number that we were looking
for seem to remember was about seven
bucks 750
or so and that's some dollars fifty says
was a price that you know people
advertises a its
seven dollars and fifty cents per square
foot per year
per mile no for you
if you do the math okay its you know
works out about
if it's in the square feet were
trust me it works out it didn't sound
right to you to me
in addition to that you have any sort of
shared space you have with other tenants
in the building
our case we bathrooms and others
sort facilities which shares week
beans for that there's more costs like
utilities get to that second
home book we're talking about size the
space will support about special final
sick that the next important thing the
suicide rate
at that stage things distance should
expect people to go that far
well as living in New Haven his writings
ArchiCAD
and I was a flick 45 minute drive for me
Cycle Show build
this to go there once a week if that
so should find a place that central
everybody
no one has to travel too far to get
there that's pretty
and then think that young
physical location obscurity gonna have a
place for the class
storefront or something like that wanna
have place that's pretty obscure no
one's gonna really know what's going on
advertising watching hearing here you
know
this couple that both some also checking
out the building and integrity
place it's falling down has water damage
a leaking roof stuff like that
and especially then take the electoral
system you have a lot of computers
running
you want something with fairly he said
little service
one thing I remember to keep see was so
when we moved in the
there is a a certain for the ceiling
which had been replaced so there is you
know
mushi rock up there which just look
different from resin we didn't think
anything of it
on on to the peaks no
and then that rose in the is a flat roof
so
drain dreams basically out
normal drainage system and so water in
their froze
pushed out the service can and then once
the water melted
including all the water on the roof it
came out the service
and about half a foot away from our
primary iraq we had one rack at that
time
so about half away from Iraq one was
johnnie
and now so you want to be careful about
even though you can't see you know these
are some tell-tale sign
might indicate a problem the other thing
to consider is
what former heating the building has and
what former cool in the building has
the first place we looked at tipsy was a
really really me
%uh old IBM buildings on Austral girders
use power buses and everything until we
discovered that
its stonewalls small windows and
no central heating system at all the
only way to heat it would've been
electric
baseboard heaters running of our power
bill
I think account without as like three
thousand dollars per month
just electricity to operate enough
heaters to keep that place
he did I don't remember how I keep
no we we have radiator for ours im we
have the same sort of thing like it's
all breaks
radiators works really well but trying
to call it down
yes we have fifteen foot ceilings
and wall units sometimes just don't cut
it we have one
12,000 BTU air conditioner
and while there really kinda cools it
down a little bit
it doesn't come close to really
providing the cornice the from
two racks of servers running on
thankfully for us our electricity bill
doesn't seem to go out no matter how
much more
the add-ons yours we've gotten all
factory
where there are a lot of seamstresses so
they're
heavy duty equipment running all the
time there's like
syriza 200 amp breakers down
in the basement so we had to it all the
time and it seems worked out well
but if you're not lucky enough to have
that then
electricity costs for calling can really
cripple your
yeah we know we know all about that
Cambridge Massachusetts that so
are tough she's electric bills
sometimes definitely they left us
marquee sorta realize it's going in but
much to electric heaters
machines interested calling in the
summer
its very difficult for a while using
little portable a/c units
I would recommend stay away from us is
there really not designed to have the
exhaust or the out-take whatever
extended also after going through about
three of those contacted a professional
HVAC guy it's pretty cool
if you find the right kind of person
they can so used here you achieve so
ended up getting a 30,000 BTU
to care much for the call summer cost
about as much as
for just the right person
definitely if you're looking at try to
talk it out
here utility bills for water
down with will be before you you know
jump into it sign
his for big data centers I think the
largest cost item is actually which is
not being
yeah that's true and it's getting worse
because Obama all these rack-mount
servers
realize the density get smaller Heathrow
this is amazing
in Poughkeepsie now we have gas heat in
the winter which
we rarely turn on at this point because
we just beat the system there the room
with all the computers
and than during the summer we have a
18,000 BTU wall unit
and then to 12,000 BTU stand-alone units
just for the server room
and it barely keeps up it should be said
to you that it seems like from talking
with a lot of people
this there's mobile units actually
seem to provide a lot less generated for
on they suck yes so so if you if you're
buying at 12,000 BTU
mobile unit expected to put out a lot
less than 12,000
is there also twice as expensive yeah
they are i mean they just
don't really seem worthwhile if you can
get a place with Windows
large enough to accommodate some larger
African wall unit air conditioning
on there's there are far better in terms
of efficiency
we had to go with the stand-alone units
because our server room has no
Windows so we've had them directly into
the attic
the attic fortunately is is pretty much
opened a ritz
its orbital where house you'd
home so we're talking about
cooling & Electric our
the space pieces that we are so getting
electricity from
the guys we ran from so we pay a static
two hundred dollars a month no matter
how much we use pretty much
so lucky yeah how does that compare to
you
that seems to be the case for us a case
for you yeah
like I said there's there's a lot power
coming
and we plug in things all the time
and nobody ever seems to notice an HP so
is the power bill in your name urs it in
the
least the place releasing from I believe
it's in the owner's name i'd have to
double check on that but I'm fairly
certain that that's the case
know and Cambridge again actually fairly
sore SF
our ability few months but if you find a
pic metropolitan area
I would look at your factory space it
that's included a lease but
are 42 much on this but look at the
different options that your electric
company provides and frites you figure
out a way to swing
the lowest one certain means
commercially zoned space there's over
there too with major ways
metering power as I understand it
there's the how much power using
demand for the entire month and then
there's so much power using any given
moment
for the entire in there's a slight
difference there
you guys are you guys on this little one
hour
we have in store on Boston and they
have two different plans residential
demand planner demand plan set up for
more
like people that use so much and stuff
like that
as a huge rush AC motor exxon
yeah are building that were in
Poughkeepsie is leader of
that it's an old bowling alley and it's
currently full day Cement Company
so they get metered by peak usage which
means
they basically don't notice that were
there using their power
%uh if you go to try to figure out where
your pal power bill is going to be
should probably come up with a number
and then at least double it
we look at all of our equipment and not
counting the air conditioner
on the 244 line that we can't measure
we yes to me were running something in
the city 5,000 kilowatt hours per month
which with the it's a lot of power we
should be a significant
bill I don't even calculate that there
we've got this little
handy dandy me to call the Q law K
bash a dash to view ATT I think
ThinkGeek sells on the amp started
sewing
here you can also use a multimeter with
an improved
yes but only if you separate out the way
3 on it so you have a space
yes some people on what you do with that
a couple things the first thing you want
to do do that with stuff that we found
that that works to trial
is aside a function teach person one
person will be in charge
you know with the landlord be a liaison
for that on personal be a treasure
back-up personnel personally take care
network operations a personal take care
you know fiscal of least in our place we
do a routine cleaning schedule at most
people don't think about that but it's
really important
is place we'll get really nasty really
fast
you don't have someone clean the Florida
batter whatever so
we find on just havin monthly schedule
usually works
yes stick with that were slightly less
well-defined keep see about that
but a we look at where some of the
cleaning is done by the cleaning service
that
the company that leased space from hires
veterans are insured area
but for the rest of it when it's time to
clean weekend just call everyone say
show up and we're going to for a buncha
crap out if you don't show up
your crap like it from now yet we're
pretty much the same way
we have a shared facilities as well so
luckily we don't have to clean up after
everyone else which is pretty nice but
when it comes down the cleaning the
inside
space it becomes rather difficult to get
everybody around
so unit meeting times
we have concrete floors obviously worked
ok Rico no
even before that we have that concrete
floors and I'm constantly amazed how
much
actual dirt gets on those floors if you
look on any
anyone at your desk for those of us were
roads under desks it is it's actually
like a note that you can
you can scrape with your finger new in
there's actual
depth to it it's kinda
unless you actually market every week or
something
unit do so think
it's just really really attend remember
actually
the room that we we inhabit used to be a
show for concrete
so we had to do was basically take we
took book it's
water threw it on the ground we pushed
it out before we moved anything yet so
we were
by any means clean it when you first get
in there to
as much as you possibly can if you can
afford it to air filtration systems like
have the filters
on even know when you're in your case
you probably have to change them fairly
frequently
very far are very nice do about once
every two weeks for a place where the
furnace filters
we we have a special exhaust fan exhaust
into the server
and goes through a filter in this field
is clogged
about two weeks yeah one thing that's
funny about concrete which
I didn't realize at least here other
people probably knew when I just
still concrete plus
water equals caustic to metal which is a
problem in computer
so filtering out
stuff became very very important for us
very quickly after we started to see
still although I don't think we've
actually seen things we we fail
I blew a power supply here the the other
thing that can be very funny concrete
dust will do is collect
on all the services that are supposed to
be
heat sinks and so on and so forth just
inhibit
is not just concrete dust though our
chances are you're probably getting a
building that is brand new
so chances are there's going to be a lot
of dust falling from everywhere
so you need to plan to take care of that
and you'll probably want a plan about
air filters wanna concrete justice
particularly pervasive and fine
but any old building any industrial
space is going to be full of dirt
gonna get into servers and what not if
you don't put in air filters
a in our case we maintain positive
pressure in the server room
so that we exhaust and so that a minimal
amount of dust comes in since there's no
direct connection from the server the
concrete factory people
we haven't done it yet but um one thing
you can do to cut down on does
done this at work is to it a concrete
sealer get
people whatever put it on a bare
concrete floors that just basically
keeps the
any dust from rising from the floor ft
shoes covered you drop a heavy surf
some answer free
it so one thing to keep people there
sounds
it's good to schedule a weekly meeting
really stick to it say
okay we're gonna meet every Wednesday
night 8 o'clock make sure we should
and that that's come the 18 where it's
other other things you should think
about are like their policies and
policies on someone leaves whatever
usually ask for like personalized
but so if you have a visitor policy it's
good to have phone
you know one night a week where we get
together to work on a project clean the
place
work on infrastructure something like
that and just not have rendered people
come over to drink
where on really can't stress enough that
it's really important to just
say okay certain things need to get done
to get done once a week
that's pretty much the in that that work
pretty well
if you include food people seem to come
yes really
you get together dinner then to work on
a project afterwards
yeah along those lines on
having some there is a space in every
look at their own work area for stuff
but then
having clear to find separation in the
common area every just things out
have a video projector couch couple
video games ever
its complete separated from people's
work space is pretty important
for quite a few reasons having a server
in completely separated of
is also kinda nice on when you're jammin
in a bunch
sheets together as many as you know it
gets pretty friggin Wow
on and so being able to have a public
area where you can
and get away from all that noise is
really nice
when we move into our space there is a
serviceable cage area these teasers
to shit home eventually what we ended up
doing was what we try to put up this
stupid thankful in order to to dampen
the sound that actually worked pretty
well
we thought and we had a more machines
she's we got more sensitive to issued
much noise so we certainly she rocking
well
that was great on and then we put more
insulation in their league actually or
15 insulation with fiberglass insulation
fiberglass insulation
any other where she rockin then that's
what we got elements
rei it's too loud some places
because government vento so
rate so one thing bud can talk about
what she touches down with a minute
that's been important
on the workspaces those involved in
Boston rented a place
that we can get the assault or anything
to it
so we had a space about three months we
had to leave the least because
can get it down spree week couldn't
really use it for
is intended purposes so on two different
options to pay or you live for looking
up in Boston to
departed a cough cough realized who
pretty much runner church guys
to help offset the cost I think all the
work spaces do this is offer
like web hosting a co services preachy
have people you trust me I'm in 10
machines
a netbook for them that that's good
income to help us at the ballot
was a time you gonna want to go with the
commercial this all service specially if
you know you have people
thank you to see you get a good sooo
don't try to do something with
cable chief DSL or something like that
yeah arm we look at getting an official
t want
tipsy and thanks to the lack of
any tech companies for the most part
except IBM
in the Cape see arm at1 would have cost
up about nine hundred dollars a month
it's a big expense that's more than yeah
so what we ended up getting was a
commercial DSL line as well
and we lucked out because there's a
non Verizon on phone company DSL
company in Poughkeepsie so we're one of
their largest commercial customers so
they tend to like us
which is really beneficial you have any
problems with your with airlines
there was a guy we suppose that you
present at this conference you could
make it
on who did a lot of skinny a lot of
things
most eyes peas wages but the collage
home
they called us up first and say well
what's happening with this guy seems to
be doing this you
and I can actually talk to them and
explain to them what exactly was
happening
is a girl okay well you know we're
getting complaints this that and the
other thing
and he could finish is researching
he ended up finishing his research so
having a friendly company
a person you means that you can call
this exists at
larger companies to but unless you're be
commercial customer
you generally don't get that level of
attention the guys don't know you too
well
finding the smallest he talking to them
at a time showing the house include huge
work more probably yet demonstrating
cool for missus really good if you can
talk to their text directly up
we were lucky enough we even got reverse
DNS delegation %uh when we first asked
about it they went no because
people we screwed up in the other server
dns is broken and were actually able to
persuade them that we're not
stupid and we lucked out in there
as well that would never happen if we
done yourself Verizon or something like
that
it also helps if you on wanted okay sure
something like that justified
we gotta after class see for ourselves I
guess you you have
you own your own see sure you can sort
of
we we take have a classy from your ISP
on I remember when when the they come to
install it for commercial customers
there's really nothing you can do
to prevent them from coming to install
so they sent along this guy who just
happen to be living
in the direction we were on his way home
and
he was a dork he was a UNIX admin for
the company
they were small enough that the UNIX
admin also that installs every once in a
while so he came
he sold redoing he was really
how often would you ever imagine rag-tag
group for people in this
concrete factory nerding it up with all
sorts computers
so he was amazed and and turns out that
he's the actual does the Riverstone
nations so gave him a call-up and and he
hoped that sounds ok result couple
problems since
wanna the when the coup for people
israel's was a building with how much
being with you actually keep which doing
how much do you need how much determine
running two teams
for you well
again that's situation get preachy
return it ourselves farewell
touch other families here two years ago
Cambridge now its REM
it's a group of people Boston this
said okay work pretty fed up with all
the sites teasers costar so
but to the whole company today we have
10 people but he wants you know by 10 I
want
fast where we get a lot like 5-10
dollars over cost
their termination fees you looks like
the space to look at the physical plant
around the space
the coppers horrible you know schools
are showing up whatever you call you
have a lot our time DSL
their frequent your office building as
fiber to
going to like this or something like
that it's free a definite plus
so if you're looking to purchase basis
of if we look at the first one to see
look at 56 basis crisis is a good place
to look just running around your city or
whatever
performance on this just keep table
what's good
what features space everyone leave
its kinda nice if you're in a and major
city
to the near public transportation as
well
were kinda rate of the subway and so you
know it's a quick trip down there
people who don't have cars can get there
easily without having to pay
you know taxi fares one and its it's
pretty nice
general I think we went we when we were
looking we went
just tool was not the whole group users
like his or
6 I think originally there about 10
people its first tentative interest
and you know we end up now with 1234
for about six people were and
so just the two of us got in the car and
drove around until we found stuff
near us that was pretty big about the
right copied on the phone numbers to
Publix your pictures
picture weir's actually when contacted
them two pictures inside
shouldn't everybody and a we all went
out the biggest
the best with where we were
if you're in a more rural area it might
be worth your time to investigate
how or rather where the telco
switching stations are City make sure
you get close enough to DSL
the first place we looked at we could
literally open a window for a rockin
AT&T
it was the bigger ok no we didn't that's
a place that we couldn't afford the
yeah North single
will probably take questions for the end
if you wanna keep standing the whole
time
you well we weren't 33 minutes past the
hour
from can we spend but say three minutes
talking
require stuff and then and they will
head to
so pictures and stuff and then to
questions
hope 10-15 is a question years so
home how did you decide what you needed
and how did you acquire all the crap I
think the key word is
grift yes I
there's an amazing quantity of free
stuff out there check out the local
colleges especially in without days
I'm working for local universities
discrete to
they seem to have a lot of turnover in
things on
at least in pennsylvania it costs a lot
to recycle your computer's
so if you work for a local university
talk to your manager more often than not
you know they'll have to sign a paper
that says you're not responsible for
office
here and you can walk home with older
son servers
what's a Dell gear on occasional network
switcher too
and I mean all that just absolutely for
free
with a lot of furniture from our local
university
home when they were throwing out to all
the all guests from a computer lab
just piled up in a warehouse or I'm so
anywhere
so we for the whole bunch desks is
space worked out really well is actually
amazing when we started to space and we
talked to everybody we knew even people
who were actually involved
how many people just came forward with
hey you wanna couch %ah
here's a rack things like that which is
well I Q the first coat you had already
yet but then there is
to catch is that came after that me with
a partial
knows those those his account said no
it you have to get up from the couch
um so furniture
everything we have any other tips on the
university's
on well you know there's always
Craigslist there's local garage sales
for things like furniture
it's helpful if someone you know has
pickup truck
because it's easy to take a ride around
on you know Saturday or Sunday to
local thrift shop for what I you buy it
so
for like 50 bucks so that's pretty known
this coz there's the MIT Swami
yeah I found a while UPS's and some
computer we'll keep a lot of computer
equipment that's communal
aside the stuff that's been there so
long which uses
so we found like for your UPS's
and those actually last was replaced the
batteries
which is expense we were out we were
lucky enough we got are to me
UPS's which are right now UPS's
2200 for free on there was a mistake in
order and they can return
so it's helpful if you're known as the
guy who will take
any bit of hardware that comes your way
whether you're gonna keep it or whether
or not you're gonna throw it out
if everyone knows that you'll take it
damn when they have something to get rid
of their gonna come to you for it
on and so thats really really been
helpful
it's gone so missed everything I don't
we haven't bought much that's actually
brand new
aside from maybe some access points
our core router double-edge sword though
sometimes you end up with a walk
yeah you'll see that the pictures yeah
speaking of which your way
move along to their careers one quick
tips on acquiring network hardware
if you can give the techno house if you
look on ebay there's
so much network equipment that's forty
LTC
you can get yourself DC regulator
rectifier preachy find network routers
or switches you get them
maybe a third at their cost if you're
willing to user
especially left over from people
cookie that stuff tokars its it's really
cheap
yourself 24 switch 50 bucks
is also if you look for some the off
brand stuff
Nick pointed us when we started our
space towards Cajun equipment
which has been made for a while but
we're using it and its
pretty much as good as Cisco's far as
we're concerned because everything we
need to and
parts to replace anything embraces free
pretty easily
stop with the management face you says
making your face in those things
it's with some pitchers kinda the kinda
touch on some stuff we talked about talk
about
answers picture keeps the space from
just before we moved in
are just before we got there they're
using it as a storage area
for you its you also notice the
interesting water damage that we didn't
pay attention to and
that's when it got turned into as binary
pointed out leader
try to create a bit of a division
between where you hang out and where you
work so
from that perspective all the tests in
the servers in one hour behind us
her behind the the camera so we keep
where people are just hanging around
chatting
probably good 20 feet away from where
people are trying to work which cuts
down on some
no reason overflow like that and
that's just an example love cheap ways
to mount racks %ah
go get it for by foreign cut in half at
Home Depot to cut in half for you I
think we paid about
30 bucks for the rack mounts and
nothing for the racks so as great if you
can sit on the floor you on Israel for
post you really do have to secure those
the floor we're using user
you know be a service these are two post
0 X the actual handle it iraq's or
strong enough to do that
but you do need to get them onto the
floor really well and even in this case
you can you can sort of pushing
walls it so if you're an earthquake
think but ago
yet defeat there are four feet long to
give an idea of how much
balance actually also just a a general
though
you probably should ground iraq's a lot
of people
do that by when before we had grounded
racks
and when I was a certain grounding into
the racks
I did notice that there was a difference
for some reason that just made me think
OVA
now I for think about 5
I'm I'm really tired he CC right just
since those diagramming a sec ago
you see there's two lines coming in from
the from the right there
and they're going down to a black thing
and that's that's actually or ground
we've got that big giant loop
like a laptop gone all the way back to
to ground stake that so real hard ground
we paid make sure
200 bucks for yeah should make sure from
the
people you least from what their
policies are earning more power in our
case then you know it
they do an electrician at work on the
side so we were able to
save a little money there and they're
pretty flexible about
running heavy condo cable for their
feelings and what not drilling holes in
the walls
but if you don't have a place that
flexible you need to make sure you have
enough power there already
you may not be able to add more we've
got 3 30 amp circuits
3 20 amp circuits 1234 28 Nov 3 2010
circuits
and to 30 answer yet or in just for the
servers not counting people's desks
and the air conditioner for the name
this picture here
is the other two well news almost
because the two air conditioners the
12,000 BTU or one time for those which
used
so that's two tones air conditioning
theoretically home
one thing we should know from there or
will clear plastic tubes that are
heading down those the condensate oops
on the emptied into a bucket the book
was on a scale
skills attached to an email address
which page does whatever the street with
brisket think
if we also had MRTG grass and everything
set up so that you could see
for the skew hopeful the book it was
insane you when you had to go
into you if that lasted about three
weeks before we realize were empty the
bucket every
hours yeah I was nothing better than
getting woken up for the morning to go
into the air positive get a long look at
this isn't like a small little this is
the big honkin
anyway home humid times sometime
might i remember humid plus concrete
equals
me um I think it's all
say about picture with little services
though wanna
factory in Philly on and some other
things that we tried to do
were build utilitarian desks that could
be used for
electronics work for you know said
laptops or desktops
and being able to you have a fairly open
area where people could just fly again
and you know there were some spaces that
want to claim as their own but the rest
space is pretty much open
first come first serve on you see the
two racks
of to the center into the race and
there's
were just moved in they were donated to
us on and we're trying to keep them as
far apart so that we can keep
the sound out at that as much as
possible
isn't that the tabletop a whiteboard
yeah oh yeah I'm sorry actually
from Home Depot I you can get tabletop
that acts as a way forward
on so if you don't really have wall
space to hang a way forward
it's nice to just be able to jot down
notes on the table and know that you can
actually a race from later
so I this picture was thrown and simply
because if you look at the door
on you may see something that looks
familiar to you and it's probably
something that every good
hackerspace should have on that's a
picture of Captain Crunch that states
cities watching you
who %ah we had shared bathroom so we
could really keep it in there because it
tended to flee a lot of people out but
is kinda fun to have nonetheless
but also you could use a store space
metal racks
lot of companies those
%ah so this is an example of how easily
John can actually acquire on we don't
tend to throw out a whole lot without
all bunch of pushing on so we recently
went through a major clean and sweet and
everything in this picture pretty much
wind up being thrown out
on in in pennsylvania you can either
drive to the ghetto and drop it off in
some street corner you actually have to
pay to have a recycled
so it's something to think about as
you're gathering here
because it's like twenty dollars per
computer to have a recycle
make sure you ever get a nearby or they
already
in the ghetto shark as this is a just a
quick picture showing on
is the pastry in Boston our division
culinary in workspace re-election a
separate or
still there on city level security
seeking
people can hang out for without
disturbing anything
it's going on and other world I appear
gonna ask freak out sometimes and
culture this is well
we are final solution our air
conditioning our server area was
said we are called around we found hace
goes to a willing to work on the side
any soul this this commercial a/c unit
that was pulled out of an office
building
was working large condenser unit outside
came from Leichhardt university or
something like that he sold it was very
very cheap if you ever seen the movie
Brazil
on your mind me a lot of very title
especially with this
whatever the hell those things called
over here on our works pretty well in a
bikini
it's actually because it's so large it's
much more efficient does the compressors
and you to run nearly as much as
no reason for the units Texas Health our
electric bill and this is a rare picture
of minus
enjoying the view this is a for space
those involved
hitting pictures
I think so go to questions I think we
minutes line up at the Mikes and
ask your question perspective apparently
very short person that was also a
you use that Mike hit that my go
okay I'll
first off track are good friend over
wants to send free to you from
Albuquerque
com but my main question is about Tom
are you guys
a nonprofit 501 c3
perforated you guys do anything like
that for for the organization's
we'll we looked into it in Poughkeepsie
and we may still do it at some point are
there some benefits in there some losses
to it a
it's a lot of people work you have to
have regular board meetings
have tested mission plans and there's
some restrictions about what happens
to the equipment you acquire as a
corporate entity when you then dissolve
namely if I recall you have to hand it
off to other non-profit entities
so if you we're trying to use 501 us
once I won't see three-state if you try
to use non-profit status be able to get
equipment
tax-free and other things like that then
can't take it with you if you break up
arm
possibles five hundred dollars for the
application to become
501 c3 yeah but when we're starting out
that was
five dollars for defrauded have on the
upside
a your nonprofit so donations you can be
written off
so theoretically you could try to get a
of
someone to donate space to you as a tax
write off I don't know that that's ever
work
certainly try are you might be able to
get network ran with donated or things
like that
liability works differently in get
insurance a lot easier their benefits
there as well
yeah it's a something you should you
could look into which if we do a lot of
reading on it because there's
a lot of subtleties to it Boston we
formed a partnership which gives us a
federal tax ID this file
LC probably be the optimal go
for this many reasons sort have any
shirts on in Philly were kinda mixer
so as a group word kinda loosely knit
and we don't any any governments
concert sponsored status
that all other networking and everything
else is currently under an LLC
and we do that primarily because it
gives us better rates
were able to get things wholesale that
way if we need to
we just have our offices there as well
trigger for through your questions yes
gotta
the line and not much time go ahead and
you it's not the
band with situation 381
19 of course we have newer systems
I have files somehow save 10% down to up
30 month
I wanna kill me here I'm ninety dollars
a month 31
has anything Valley because what
commercial areas that
it features you read your service
agreement that's a question
I'm unlocked I can do any part doesn't
matter I've been up yet the weather
as obvious service-oriented yes alerts
yeah says
basically on your whether or not for
profit or whatever is that was
dictating this situation you all if it's
also a complex question answer but it is
different tiers and different service
levels and different places you care
onto the internet and fire this is a
completely different animal its
residential
for things but what and has anything
come along
that prices have dropped because newer
technologies available to the consumer
well a lot of it has to do with her
first gets fixed
race yeah that that's makes you very
much but I don't think he
well especially if they're all sitting
your BAM with by
are charging other people services you
can't really do it with a residential
plan
you need something you gonna be able to
get on the phone and speak to someone
about when your links gonna be back know
that there's trouble shooting in place
with fires were cable or regular DSL
you simply not gonna get and you're
always going to have a flutter
on it's just not worth basically that up
to
yes its York Times the availability if
something happens to our line this phone
will ring within five minutes 90
if it doesn't then there's significant
fiscal penalties to the eyes peas
so we've actually been called by ISP
worry organizing our server room
we on for the DSL modem to move things
around and they called us and said
did something happen how's that for
certain we have only limited time
as much people set up their own unique
lady talking to known also Jeff
thank you a up too quickly that also
implies that you be using your link at
the space to host servers
if you just using it as a work area and
you're going to do your sir if you look
at your the coal facility you doing all
your hosting of
site then it might be much easier for
you to get a cable but
if you're looking to host servers
yourself or submit your band without the
need to
get something that lets you do that for
me it's expression
also on the ice you know if you're in a
buildings more than one or two stories
look around for a local wireless ISP is
there for mom and pops my friend cool
sysadmin
I don't know about the uptime on those I
wanna ask really what do you do when
when somebody in your space to something
really stupid it's the whole place rated
it's sitting in a warehouse next the FBI
building in Virginia
what do you do how do you Inslee
yourself legally when one-member the
space does something really
a peaceful that yes I
Gaurav pillowcase those oranges works
very well too
doesn't leapers I guess that's why we
really gotta be careful about
you accept and what sort of levels and
access you give them
on are our group is trust the key group
where we've known each other for a
really long time
and any guest access is is fairly close
that goes for any
any kind of working organization to I'm
in the office who work in what happens
that person that sits next to you this
is something like that how are you
liable
mean it would have to be something that
would put everybody risk
I think in the office situation they
going to take that
persons machine you know it from there
caster an organization
the exact same thing in the space is
that a citizen of a situation that's
basically what you're free
it doesn't look very professional
because you know you're a shoestring
its deletion of the situation is still
we should be taking and if they take
if you know they're all in the same
crackin AR warrants as any
it's a situation we haven't had to
address personally but hopefully
never will here like no other
with the deal number of people you
should get to share one space
all that really depends on the number
people involved in how large a space
you can get we find release
the space evidence of that we find six
or seven people
is a good number seems to be the magic
number I think we have we both have the
so 6 a I probably wouldn't go much
higher
one i guess i you know way like core
people versus people who come into work
on various projects %ah
but definitely contributing members we
have six as well
yeah we had the original division uva
full-time people and students
center right near the college we didn't
feel that we could charge them for price
when they don't have
a real job yet are but so we had a
number of students that would come in
and out and then we had a a
about five or six core people that would
pay most the bills we charged issues
very we charge a $50 bucks a month for
basically all the same things except for
they all shared one joint desk on 2
minutes left
next question please
could tip the mic down your sorry short
first sure
in this situation hits from
one just how to maintain security
between our office this
its
I I guess it depends on what level
security I mean
if you can put up drywall like there's
obviously visible security but that's
not really gonna keep people out
on I don't know that I would necessarily
want to share
a space with a law office but I mean if
you get a donated thats
pretty hard to turn down of into tipsy
were fairly lucky that were
really friendly with the people that
share the building with us where their
ISP
among other things that we do tech
support for them when they need it so
they leave their office door unlocked
all the time don't think about it
we've forgotten our inner door unlocked
and we'll think about it
that they accept packages for us
I mean you should definitely build up
their relationship with the people
around you is what it comes down to
if you could do drywall and put up like
a cheap a
actual wall there that's the best I can
think of something
we can talk to you more afterwards last
question
just get one more question and then we
gotta it out
no no question okay very well one last
question
actresses more comment I made a
reference that
scanning project in everything your got
it how to feel that
thank you no problem anytime but I
really wanted this comment thank you
guys publicly for
was forgive you I was doing that thanks
your relationships and
for easy process me I cuz your pain I
probably felt
but it really goes to show that this
really works benefit a lot of people
really build re support structure
anytime research
wants to do so thank you very much out
one is things that we should mention
before we go is that all of us are
always looking for new people
so if you're in sort of your boss inner
bucket see
I maybe look at sup send us an email or
something
yeah thanks guys hopefully this is
useful to you
as ken starr his face you