being will be around until about 2 on
down the second floor
and the about 1:30 I think they stop
giving tests for the
for the him license for the tech license
arm with that
I introduce number one thirty in number
does not work alright
missed at the podium cuz I wanna be like
Hitler I guess this is a good work
either
in yesterday I was laughing at Kitana
cuz he was so hungover
and now that's happening to me it's not
funny alright certain
this presentation on abilities in a
connected future night paula jones for
the confusing title
its actually a lot of our smarthome
hacking
and down and some other stuff too we
actually modify the presentation today
it's way too long so we're gonna fly
through some the stuff to try to get
as much as possible and down both mean
quite on our
veterans and we have a little bit about
the whole veterans
now identity theft thing that's been
going on
change
I 89 pass that document versioning
back in stock comforts such stocks that
each team now alright
a smart home the color socks
I guess you just gonna have to listen to
me talking
trust what I have to say it's much more
entertaining that way anyway that we get
to see me stumble over my words
I'm smart homes are a new breed of homes
they haven't a very connected nature and
they also do really cool things like
identifying information about you trend
that data and make decisions about you
so explaining a system like that could
be very fruitful
nom there's a description that you can
read
arm there's a cut on a couple a smart
home projects
Anna in the world academia right now
arm to the most well-known are MIT's
house and and Georgia Tech's aware home
and
there they both have web sites on the
last I checked the where home site was
down for some reason
an idea alright
info on this presentation compliment the
now motivating factors for doing his
presentation was a sitting on my couch
one night watching the Science Channel
and they were exploring you know home to
the future and they were showing
different things you could do
and this guy got like a text on his
phone and said when the alarm sensors in
his house when of
so he wanted see what was going on so
you log into
the admin interface and connected to his
home
start looking at a bunch of video games
is house and I started screaming oh my
god this http
you know I was like what are these
people doing in an you know those
countless other things they were showing
and I just kept jumping off the couch
going oh my god I can't believe they're
gonna sell it to people
and I can't even imagine what's gonna
happen once manufactures actually start
you know mass-producing this technology
its gonna get a lot worse which is
ash kinda fun okay our team impasse that
Tom basically that's last slide said I
was honored
arm smartphones are to have typically in
the past they've been focused on luxury
you know I mean not everybody can afford
the clapper right so
what ended up happening is they started
seen a tremendous use for this
in assisted living you know with the
elderly or medically disabled
which brings in some more really
interesting aspects when you're talking
about attacking smart home technology
you know you can actually be affecting
some is life home
and E okay in the future smart homes
and their components will be a part of
everyone's life and why is that
is because we all love getting owned our
now this is really interesting I wanna
do like in Philly local pictures in here
and I found this picture I want a guy in
a wheelchair to show the disabled in
israel is really funny cuz actually very
first thing that came up in Google
Images was this picture says my son's
hit me
says wheelchair-bound man and this is
the 80-year-old man claims that his son
slapped him and tried to push him down a
slope
and it's come to Austin okay anyway
nevermind
free it s like the contents of a smart
home
Tom you gonna have some components like
%uh servers
not connected appliances cameras
furniture
jewelry Exeter Exeter tera now many
newer devices
some come with some sort of connected
capabilities even if it's just for
getting updates I mean if your toaster
want a firmware upgrade its gonna have
to connect somehow
mean you know the the I'm sure you you
know he's not gonna be like flashing the
BIOS you gonna hafta
to you lose control of all your points
is so some third party's gonna have to
manage that
not interfacing with the smart home
there's many different ways
that smart homes will be interface with
am the phone the web
my wireless in all its you know
capabilities RFID power outlets cap 55
yr
and countless interfaces that have even
been developed yet
so that that's a lot of different
interfaces
arm smart homes on the flip side
interface with us
mom you know technology can not actually
affect the way we feel
and we'll get into that later with the
psychological aspects in actually
hacking a person
which is actually kinda cool to you and
I'm across a NorCal my son
home mood pendants photo albums our
prediction activities
antenna prediction content in actually
making decisions
you know what I can see the slide better
over on this side of the screen and you
can out there that's really funny
om well if you're yale is rotated around
so everybody can see the back
right haha am prediction technologies
Tom you know what do you want for
breakfast oMG what do you watch on TV
now this could be cool what you watchin
TV you get your TV and we've already
seen as with like TiVo to start to
make decisions for you right based on
what you watch now what if your friends
get older that you know i mean
my friends come to my house they sit
down and there's like 100 episodes a
Will and Grace on my DVR slide what are
you doing it
you know so our favorite television
shows on
you know whatever food you like the
system's hold a vast amount of data
they're gonna have a vast amount to date
on us think a bus like an advertiser's
dream
you know marketing companies dream is to
have all this information exactly what
you like to do exactly how you like to
do it
and how many times a day you do it which
now and wants me knowing exactly how
many times a day I do certain activities
but my house would know and that was
scary
and it's done to context-aware computing
in we'll get into that man
arm yeah I'm kinda comp so
so what does all this stored predictable
information about us me
not that we're gonna have to read our
usage agreements very close with third
parties
when we start buying this technology we
have to make sure we read the fine print
not say you allow us to take all this
information is sent
rate back to us so we can use it against
you later
home we're gonna have to be mindful on
the exploitation of the systems in the
different ways the system's be
vulnerable
and that information can be extracted
now
in our personal pronto archives can
actually be ripped off and mass when I'm
scared
okay context-aware computing on
context-aware computing
involves you know sensors in logic in
order to analyze movement activities are
viewing this is done through sensors
placed
all through your house mean on you know
on sugar containers on drawers
on the walls on light outlets on this
and a simple this is an extremely
oversimplified example
but just to give you an idea when I mean
say there's two people that live in a
house
you know Allison bomb when bob walks
into a room
rate before you know walking into that
room the lights
come on with a red t because the house
knows that bob is about to walk in the
room
and Amitabh green light so they're gonna
turn on lights red but when Alice watch
in the room
she hates red lights her lodging action
overrides the other logic and when she
walks into the room let's turn angry
really simple example and so I have a
bunch pictures that you probably won't
know you pricey those fairly well
in in this is this is from MIT's house
and they call those little
the little chips the column mites which
is actually kinda cool
MIT ES see get a joke and all the
sensors
are on be no sugar flour there on India
the the light outlets there on the
drawers with the silverware is
and that information is being back to a
central computer
and it has a tendency to learn things
about you and you can actually there's
actually a picture on not
MIT's house and where they have a PDA
and appointing at different things in
the PDA knows
that's a fork you know that's a spoon
that a knife it actually learns
about your activities in about the
physical items in your environment
okay now we can get to some other fun
stuff impacts upon abilities right
think about the impact on your computer
being compromised that's pretty bad
you know you you may have password so
Security numbers bank accounts credit
cards
tax turned prime browsing activities
and how stupid your screen name is I
mean people actually can learn that
about you by
you know exploiting your computer system
nothing about the
on the impacts upon abilities in your
home
so you could actually have internal
video cameras which to me is just
utterly scary I don't know why anybody
would be ok im inside her home
I'm pair Nadine a I'm paranoid enough to
put money outside my house
but yeah it i cant used to select
wireless cameras why would anybody for
wireless cameras on the inside her home
yes porn driving
okay nom internal video cameras arm and
disarm alarm such change prescription
use
what you like and you DVR temperature
your house which can actually really
funny world we live in Florida Minister
P
sometime mom temperature you liking
house mischief
with not connected appliances are you to
have its location technologies
and dont know if your kids are home
which is always fun to scare people with
their kids
mean advertising companies do not I'm
the president won election with that you
know all that stuff
okay attack vectors for a smart home
very cool multiple attacks actors
you have %um people in the home
connected appliances
outlets picture frames which is very
cool
and you know and the actual medium you
have no wireless
telephone lines not count 55 yr
down so so we know that these homes are
gonna have to have some sort of
administration interface
have to have some kind administration
interface so most likely
they're gonna be have issues with
regular admin interface is that we
already have whether it be programming
logic
passwords tokens but plain text plain
text authentication which probably won't
I mean some some manufacturers are
actually smarting up a little bit so
this may not be as much of an issue when
they start rolling to sell
but they may have some weird backward
compatibility that actually has HTTP
built into it
in eighty people accidentally just use
that interface versus an HTTPS interface
our man in the middle attacks telephone
you know you can bring war dialing back
am Wireless were driving and basically
and interfaces will be known to an
attacker had a time
so is if the manufacture tries to you
know avi skate the
admin interface say by switching the
port you know
like nobody would ever figure out that
they switched the report from
82 you know 1337 or something like that
they would never figure that out
even though they publish it information
how you have to connect to it
cells everybody's going to know ahead of
time if you're specifically targeting an
attack in a smart home
you already have an information so you
won't even bother going looking
anywhere else have you know exactly
where the information is to begin with
now third party issues these
future smart homes on most likely will
have
third-party interfaces because people
are too stupid to you
run their own stuff so you can have this
wonderful third-party
that to next year your smart home for
the monitoring operation
administration om and it all depends on
the technologies marketed maintain
am you know mostly most likely people
will meet it
be connected to a third party even if
it's just for updates have some kind
and we all know that that our computers
never send information that we don't
know about back 2 a.m.
you know a big company starts with an M
right K
and that be really funny have Windows
Genuine Advantage on your home
so then they disable your updates you
get on like all over the place because
you had like
pirated copies XP running your own be
really funny
there's a big potential for misuse and
exploitation by third parties just like
any third party
you know I'm always scared like that the
alarm on my house doesn't have a two-way
communicator which i think is really
funny because I know some of the people
that work it like ATT and safe touch in
all these other companies
and you know in the middle the night its
you know there's nothing else to do
you know I can just see some may go in
useless in this one
was this is one oh man oh man was he
listened to your own business when you
need
into people's grumpy everything else so
you know the in this technology
can definitely be outsourced so now you
have you know people in another country
listening to you have sex or watching
your video cameras are doing
you know anything you know the prior
relatively unskilled
envies they have a vast amount of
information about people at their
fingertips
that could be very easy to sell
nom week protections in place for admin
user lockout
on you know it it just seems that all
the technology changes stupidity is
timeless
people are gonna forget things I mean
I'm sure the first the first caveman
that invented the stone will was like
I am you he saw the vision this will
change the world there's like four
hundred other came a stand around on
I don't get it home you know
no lockouts could mean you know
automated attacks
and I can just see people getting pissed
off after like it i three lockout
in a time period and if you're talking
about like nom you know medical
issues or something involving health you
wouldn't be able to lock people out
he'd kill somebody on third-party
not manufacture backdoor counts
manufactures again and
have ways to get any update their gonna
have accounts on the system
he also has a third party in support
accounts soon
you know now you have all these other
people that can connect your home and
get into your account and also you know
if the if an attacker exploits when he's
back door counter
third-party account they have the same
access to the system is a UN
on people you know still choose you know
we pins and passwords
phishing attacks on your house good
start to happen
depending on I'm when people start
realizing
you know how valuable this information
really is and how much is worth
Tom home loggins could be you know the
keys to the castle
allowing an attacker to view thing went
on to someone steal personal information
and voyeurism which is the only one we
agree with antenna
access to technology is gonna be done
through mobile devices so you have PDA's
laptops cellphones
and it if you lose one of those we all
know that everybody
it can be recovered right because
everybody walks their PDA the phone
whatever so nobody would ever be able to
you
analyze that PDA your smartphone in get
anything of an
and most likely people will store the
passwords are he's comin comin
device itself she won't even have to
attack you already have the information
these smart homes are also gonna have
servers and operating systems
so the same vulnerabilities that affect
you know
the Windows box at work you know is also
in effect
you know the Windows box in a smart home
on
so what OS are they gonna be using i
think im using Microsoft 1x
Cisco on in all these illnesses have
never had security problems right
okay on from from an OS level
on I'm repeating myself you're not
looking slide sorry
on in a course you have now where worms
spyware getting on year your home nasty
snarky
so exploiting the medium in in llegas
and apologizes
there's so many slides were trying to go
through a mall in were we're trying to
put some the most interesting stuff
appear so exploiting the medium the
physical medium you know
there's definitely multiple mediums
communicating over
your multiple protocols over multiple
medium so you have wireless fiber
collect power lines cafe mixer center
center
on all these mediums can beat after just
connected to you
I'm from protocol perspective it looks
like one network me TCPIP doesn't
really care what it communicates over so
you're in a mean you're
your toaster campaign your computer your
toaster can be plugged into a power
outlet near computer plugged into your
cat five lines in your house
to home this means that the lowest
hanging fruit can be explained from
medium standpoint
there are there are couple mediums
actually extend beyond your house
so would it wouldn't even require you to
be in the home to exploit them
and that's our wireless in the OP mom
just we're not gonna go on wireless I
mean that
while a securities obviously been beaten
into the ground so we show mountains
you know Wireless security get arm
GOP on the other hand allows Ethernet
communication is basically over your
household power lines
and this is very cool technology you
know
just thinking about it you're like okay
you know Ethernet over power
Tom you know how far does that girl
in I actually have some these devices
and I had him you know plugged into my
house and
I was like running around my house
inside in of course I was
getting a great paying on everything and
then I went outside and started hitting
up the outlets on the outside my house
and had a great paying and then I was
going to my neighbor's house
and come to find out we're still doing
research into finding out just how far
that signal goes
and down think about you connected
technologies like this
in like a skyscraper I mean we're gonna
our skyscraper in a
I can't even imagine how far that that
would travel through the electoral
system so you can actually get
office next to you you know and company
that you're trying to
you know perform espionage on in
actually possibly get into their local
network if they had some this technology
I was nasty get
when as far as transform
for the transformer
plug at the bottom is really
yes so
fingerprinting a home that's very cool
home the this takes on a whole new on
approach when you're talking about ipv6
so if you have
every you know if your toaster your
fridge
everything as a globally routable ipv6
address it would be possible to
fingerprint home
so now you're talking about you could be
giving you know I a thief
and pretty good idea of you know your
your Plasma TV
I hear you what kinda fried you have
farm
all this information I can foreseeing
the future if his
technology starts rolling out becoming
widely accepted you actually have
databases fingerprint databases that
will you know tell you all this
you know probably toaster you may even
be built in and map
you know toaster version 2 nom you nor
our fridge version 1
outdated you know explain and now be
really fun easier to manage my project
was like and you know actually built in
for fridge
shell yes
arm vulnerabilities don't just have to
be buffer overflows companies are really
good at creating their own
vulnerabilities due process so you have
process vulnerabilities which
are can be exploited by taking advantage
in the way they do things whether
you know it's a om a vulnerability in an
authorization and more vulnerability and
authentication arm see here because
on yeah okay process when I really think
adventure steps in the process that are
not properly checked on
because they're not fun ahead a time
because the manufactures didn't care at
the time
not only do you want to do sell you
stuff on because they don't know how to
stop it
and wanted to make money anyway and
usually an authorization issue and
stupid picture frame example
I was will say that out loud the at my
example that would be say you have
a picture frame technology we can send
pictures to
not gramm and did the technology works
on
he creates an email address for itself
and all you have to do to send a picture
to
did picture frame is just email the
picture to it well
you know without any authorization
authentication you could send whatever
picture you want to do to the picture
for me
it's going to take manufactures a while
to get it right arm
Google hacking the home is possible on
in be really interesting to see once
again once this technology
gets widely accepted if you know
Google's gonna spider your homie
find different interfaces on on search
technologies
some admin your faces user interfaces
arm can use for fingerprints
be in the system an course you robots
not textile save you every time I
own video services down these video
services are usually marketed as safety
and I got this of a cent no vision
in what's really funny is is the it
doesn't it's really hard to see but
I circled in red because our he says
know if kids are home
it doesn't say no if your kids are home
it is is no if kids are home and I
wonder if their marketing this depend if
I'll see
make and in I didn't realize it at the
time but there's is it there's a guy
laying on the floor and it says feel
secure with panic services
and what what the hell is that but thats
Sentinel vision dot com
and there that's their marketing
internal video cameras
for your home and I'm sure they're
secure an almost thinking about buying
the services to find out
you know what's going on with it and how
its access but I know it's remotely
accessible now electronic portrait
this is going to be very very very fine
in steven is actually marketing this
already antenna you know the comp an
additional family quarters
they're connected Porter technologies
are you can remotely send pictures
on wouldn't it be funny for grammy wake
up one morning with goats in tub girl
on oliver picture frames in our house
that's what i foresee happening Tom in
the logical move is to make these things
Wireless
because people don't want wires running
all over the walls right so
eventually they can make the sink
Wireless most likely not to be protected
in a grandma gets go see in tub girl all
over her walls
UK in she doesn't change in case she
doesn't know how
and that be funny she had a church
meeting that morning it's like
when you bring medical systems into the
picture do some life-threatening
consequences
because medical systems can be remotely
monitored remotely exploitable
and what about a DOS to be in a dialysis
machine
I mean it's really not funny cuz it
would kill somebody
but thats the technology that they're
pushing
978 what is it accidentally happens what
a fun you know what a phone a warm is
just scan in the crap and everything in
it scans a dialysis machine or something
many good actually kill somebody not
even do it so then guarantee they trying
to crucify whoever wrote the virus
not medicine cabinets to be really funny
to replace grandpa's heart medication
with the agra
he's wonder why you know each as a
possible pressure something
om in in it not even just the attacks
but what about a malfunction a
on the medical system because a malware
you know viruses things like that
your toaster just blue screened
and gesture pendants these are really
cool these are
are wearable jewelry that you can
actually do different things with
so you point added devices and adjust
your PIN is a good morning and he turns
on the TV
so you can actually you know break dance
in point and do different things
well what about false positives are
false negatives
I mean are you can it might turn off
your free agent like any
you know false negatives in the
assumption about this technology
is that people are going to use it the
way it's intended I can foresee with I
would use agent jester penny for
gesture pendant for and Tom you know we
all know this worked real well in the
past like you know you're only supposed
to do things for their intended use
and %ah someone is gonna have sex with
one of these on it is to be flying all
over the place
and you know who knows what's gonna turn
on turn off the shades open up
be very funny somebody has to video tape
and put it on you
on this is one from Georgia Tech's where
home got a bunch a little cameras and
Andy you you didn't want to see anyway
there it is yes you can so you can see
he's a
pointing at something in his getaway
Lannisters a dolphin assured
I'm memory aids
memory aids are devices that you know
help grandma remember she took her
medication and/or help you remember your
shopping Lannister
things like that so nom
it enhances your long-term memory I'm
attacking these could lead to some
interesting results although most it
would be for mischief I mean
you know unless you're trying to track
you know what people were trying to
remember
which I guess could have some some
marginal value but
you know making some think they did
something they didn't take medication
now missing messing up a recipe would be
really funny
I can remember the men in their N in
creating confusing memories
antenna also replacing icons have
tylenol tub girl
you know be funny on but the larger
picture is
memories and used its lost so
in essence you could kind to say that
these the memory technologies are
actually replacing
you know your ability to remember
yourself is part of remembering in using
your brain is with
you know they did actually in research
that said you know the more you use it
you know the more you you you keep it so
that's why doctors researchers and
everybody
typically don't have the memory issues
later on in life that some other people
do
I'm hacking your mood on there's a lot
of technology going into place that
actually
finds out your mood sounds like ok am
upset okay and you know
I didn't realize I was upset you know
sorry but your house will tell you
you're upset and maybe put
my changes let me know the walls or
something to suit your mood
well you can actually attack that
technology make people think they were
saddened like him I don't remember be
I don't think I'm sad I just laugh in a
minute ago you know so that that could
be
interesting and also if people know that
that d when you're angry things turn red
and the come over to your house is like
a home billy ol shit I'm out here you
know
so you can actually get other people to
think you're in a certain mood as well
and this is %uh that's what I call on
the pending attack
I'm RFID implants there isn't a good
presentation on that
on and I'm music Friday antenna
it was pretty good I i'm still would
never get one I think for one the
technologies to New and then all the
the virus jumping in everything else
that they're doing she now for me
and now the baja club in Barcelona uses
microchip technology
so that the so that they know when your
VIP members walk in and they just put
drinks honor
tabby on that date they cloned in 20
implants
on Friday said be really fun to walk in
the club yes skinny
you know I'm gonna in a runoff with
drinks
GPS GPS implants %ah this is also
for for small this is marketed at your
kids to fear tactics
on this scare tactics employees will and
you can't blame me scare tactics worked
for president and it worked for Hitler
cell
me wanna use in the marketing so
specifically aimed at your kids and the
bigger picture is
is what what is the real issue that
you're looking at what you trying to
protect against it dude is actually
a greater chance risk by doing GPS
implants
in there are something actually
happening to your kids people to analyze
the risks well enough
when when me and taking these things
into account arm
in whatever happened it is raising your
kids
on but the in like I said the larger
picture the bigger risk is the fact that
you know most likely it's gonna be kids
that get these so now you just let
everybody know
on you know whether it's through third
party or whatever where kids are
be at work yeah re and
gun to pass it others basically was
misusing exploitation that technology
arm I R in forensics also gets really
interesting with
connected technologies I mean the worm
were making assumptions that
you know the technology's going long
properly you know when also most likely
she's going on
you know critical system errors or
something like that because they don't
want to use up
valuable memory in these technologies
be really funny too like do friends
exxon toaster now
or so many owns a toaster and then ends
up startin' to own different companies
with it not be really funny to trace it
back in its like oh my god you're
toasters attacking the world
your toaster attack China
om there's some psychological issues
with technology
his anytime a technological device comes
on the market yet you kids
people try to use that instead of
raising their kids you know whether it's
tracking them a final where they are or
or are you know just basically putting
them on lockdown I have a true story
about this
which is not very long but I what I grew
up with this girl who was a strict
Bethel Baptist she couldn't even wear
pants for crisis
had to wear you know the school lots kar
take things she hated him whenever
she grew up to be the biggest slut on
the planet I think she had sex with
everybody's cool tough for me
just my luck and you know its ok so if
you push
people too hard one way it always comes
back way worse
home she's getting I and
arm possible rejection so with
technology
maybe this technology is you know too
intrusive
and people don't want it the most likely
that's not the case people were eating
up I mean look at what happened with
Paris Hilton psychic there's this whole
thing or her psychic not only in
in that was the the way everybody
thought it happened so I was like oh
shit
the mall as a psychic money self we love
to get owned
um we will focus forego our privacy
because she's cool
and guess what vendors lie you know on
that
a I laugh at all these new commercials
are coming up like city identity theft
solutions
like they have this disease blonde if
you'd like to get his password online I
mean
that doesn't happen or the or the two
mom the to redneck guys who bought like
motorcycles with some dudes account I
mean come on that's not realistic
and another one is AT&T's new security
solutions they have to have this
person walking around in Nike you know
on-scene password in Germany and doing
missing
I can see a six-year in Chinese you know
secure I'd tell you what
if you believe that you better learn to
say douche bag in a couple those
languages because that's what you're
gonna be
I'm okay smart cars not just a little
bit about markers because we're
replace it I I have no idea how many
slides we went through already
on but smart cars on
connect back to the home so you can do
you know seeking
check your house have your garage door
mom mark Compton open garage door
we we have the technology now and it
hasn't been you know to admit
you know the turning of your long arms
amino starting out on me all that senior
on the scene
all that um and its tracked by a
you know you have GPS cue track to law
enforcement third parties
com and largely because the the force
the technology down your throat by
holding you kids have you had any non
star is best at that
you don't care about my feelings you
ok it wasn't funny sinatra please arm
there there's a
Tom there's a company an Australian its
marketing this technology
mom so let's look at it you know what
happens to me steal your car
you know now now near you know connected
back to your home in
in the company said it going the company
said that
you know if someone steals your car is
not it is no problem with that because
they can get in your home technologies
that's because people always look out
like they should
now and there's always there's no way
anybody would ever program their home
address into the GPS that they have no
car right
on people would want to customize any
other features to suit their needs
and on also people always use devices
for their intended purpose
so most likely have to do is open the
glove box month for the pain
arm in a green biometrics into cars is
stupid I mean is your car more valuable
than a body part
I mean every can see is coming the car
more valuable than a by Park
no to a crackhead yes so if you
integrate yourself into a car
you increase the the chances are having
to include yourself in a carjacking
either you or a body part is gonna have
to be included as carjacking
car theft is not gonna stop because on
the
was a yeah I know that that's why I said
above the warning everybody can see it
coming
um so that's very bad I mean a to me
a key works just fine I'm get into the
car and if somebody hold me up a mic
take a shit ton of a ban on
okay so I now we're gonna get into a or
more about vehicle tracking here
arm thats let's discuss ons are a little
bit here
our question disaster know where I am
all the time
no i answer does not continuously or
routinely monitor
update or otherwise tracker location
Exeter Exeter Exeter
we're trying to keep the children say if
whatever
plus I don't want them knowing where
where I go from a good hookers
now there's word that they're using
TaqMan a
thats exigent medical workup
sorry no college education so are
require
requiring immediate action or remedy and
other words
anytime OnStar feels it necessary know
when three-letter organization hams know
where the hell you are
to
26 pretty pleased
the value tent staked is its total
0 biometrics and you know so
if they're being counted as the RI
thank you now I can lower my voice
being used on me biometrics are being
touted as the be all end all security
device
and there the really not
mica said they're not it's not see her
in in we're gonna go in team
to more of a rant on this and give you
some examples but on
a Gaga names and bony did a presentation
at last year's de con
and if you go out there you can download
the presentation for free and it's a
very good overview love
you know the technology different attack
points
you know and he explains a lot better
than I could other protected resource
has to be mom you know can be more
valuable than a limb
it it actually ties back into the whole
rant about the cars
now if if it's a fingerprint that's
required to get into a building
you know some the tops of your finger
you kinda screwed if
okay I did put in their Zamboni's def
country stations going to it silent you
step there a lot you can give us
afterwards
okay identity theft which it's basically
fraud according to Bruce Schneier
arm ask Mrs Catherine phone exploits it
via
bank account fraud Pay Pal Amazon are
I'm sure you'll have seen several
fishing letters
and I the pretty much all social
engineering attacks
arm or stolen data more if you I
the getting better at it reason better
English scams
scam sites look much more official
sometimes even have valid SSL certs
and I the obscure obfuscate the URL's
any veterans in the house
you have to raise your hand just think
about it did you get one of these
letters
are about you but I'm pissed
okay so we went through and did a little
om experiment to figure out how much how
much space
26 half-a-million record database would
take up
and I'm thank the gods for bastards
honest
if arm
ended up in about 40 gigabytes because i
was thinkin that
maybe their mainframe got hacked in
their issues in this laptop thing as an
excuse
well not necessarily mom came out to be
about 40 gigs
pretty easily fits on external drive but
they recovered the sup
yeah after two fucking months who knows
really what happened to arm
it's damn easy man hard drive read-only
on
this is a policy issue the contractor
had written permission to take that data
at the building yes since 2002
yes
we think they put a GPS device on the
laptop to track
yes arm
president ass munch also has been very
nice
to deny 160 million dollars to protect
our veterans
despite the fact that the store so
useless war and causes war veterans
on
you can't control your personal data in
pieces at record stones MasterCard said
record stone
State Oregon eccentric said Rep
on even places you've never done
business with Hills ChoicePoint
and why did they sell a hundred and
sixty thousand records to identity
thieves
because they want to make money its near
the only ones paying
on so what happens when that
database contains the informers for your
smart house you're smart car get stolen
will on now again they have full access
your vehicle
and your home okay and we made it just
in time for questions to know
hopefully we have some interesting
questions that we can answer
is the best kind okay thank you
no no just getting for I'll for
its yeah knob its hacker pimps dot com
force last doc study shemale
this is real easy it's not up yet so
yeah he has to go back to it he's
hungover and he's not listening
not go back to what the all the slide to
good yes found while looking at I guess
Spiers devices
interfaces cetera you know much like I
guess like wifi routers
that they have security features but
that they're not enabled by default
that's correct
even even a little the HomePlug devices
it says I
its it's got a 56 p as encryption and
there's like a little key on the back in
the day
guess but nobody ever using plugin ran
into the wall and him communicate with
your printer or
or anything else nice
we are damn good we only had one
question
and I hope you all enjoyed it thank you
thanks