are ever gonna get started just a couple
a quick announcements
all of these panels are being recorded
and burned to DVD
you can buy them for ten dollars shortly
after
the %ah panel right back with a t-shirt
the twenty six hundred years been so on
I highly recommend you pick one up so we
break even
am on that note these conferences
are a very positive 5
om but they're always one or two people
that try to make it on positive
if you see in the body doing something
that they shouldn't be
please find our security or I
number two type person I because they're
are folks that seem to enjoy coming to
these events just so they can steal
laptops & ham radios and things like
that and that's definitely not what this
community is about
so to the other 99 percent you thank you
and the one percent you suck
and this is a citizen
engineer consumer electronics attacking
an open source software
with Philip terone who is number 106
very proud of his number
calm and Lady A to who is number eighty
right
yep system engineer we're gonna see how
to get A's are so you see people doing
bad things
you can shock them how the
five dollars yeah made
I so awful to a senior editor magazine
you guys see make time
resize image down vendor area later
hopefully we can read
youngest I guess in a way to kidding and
passing work with 2600 on free Kevin
stuff
acted site collection have a lot of
things
people bill their basements homes in and
I'm levy I'm a currently R&D fell on IBM
which is a
new media gallery actually York now
and I basically feed Google by making
on-time
project something online you know that
on the open source
kit so people build them so anything
that I present you that you like you can
get full documentation
on lady did not match or you can buy
some kids if
dot com so I can also already in its
so citizen engineered benefits are
gets tossed around a little bit think
open source hardware might be
a new term for a lot of I mean everyone
saw
Open Source offers and the benefits and
how it's start
and people started building things on
top of things
sharing citizen is there's a little bit
different and what I like to do
carry around a slide present conferences
and
like lately representing like getting
hard I care on the sides kinda look back
history when everyone had build stuff
wasn't distribution there wasn't the
type things you can just like or
something
you had a TV or radio or car kinda had
so I clicked diesel covers this is up
from Popular Mechanics 1961
how to build the safe side work hard for
your kids that's really insane actually
it's a
yeah so that's %uh lead acid batteries
little teeny like that big problem
yeah %uh scientists on the brink hell
that's still true and
makes reference circuit board but not
this is
type things least other the plans were
shared these magazines
public act Science Monitor the most
popular magazines for a really long time
millions million copies everyone red
like things
change a lot now at people magazine
think that this is a good
stitches think other airline def talk
doing it and if you look really
generally I have like guys like like
everyone's happy holiday
this is this might be a good way to
fight
like future tears subject I
sick a size our site of complete plans
I just a job rewire house on
make we have a lot of projects like
where like I don't have school last
forever
we show people on a wire stuff like
everyone's are you worried about getting
sued
on know hopefully like one day maybe
something up
you can refer back to sale while
actually do things like
criminals be
the lie detector the good
this is my favorite line that I love
Sarah
the motor less clutter copper you can
build yourself and tell what your car
in
like that's a you know it to me the
other way that is that like
this is such a bad idea a
people actually used to build these like
this is we had
different type maginnis we're going to
the moon ever just space race going on
this is what we wanted to build a from
Seattle
we still have got a monorail said it's
kind of a letdown the things like how to
revive
picture what to do when your furnace
quite like this is what people
thought technology met what can you do
over millions of copies
this issue proud other
drug drugs are open for thirty-five
dollars the fun are you prolly her to
the case that the garage door opener
company stopping people from making
their own garage door openers is that
the code for copyright its
what 1963
life this is the the world's safest cars
just because nobody I think in israel
now
safe there and talk about another
Tripoli project later
here to free blueprints for traveling
traveling like their
losses ready to happen any nation
but up least things free parking ticket
for ten dollars
emits light projectors backer plan an
awesome
about stumbling in six basic steps a
you can build this Rhomobile I could
take it down this
crazy this invention ever mechanics shop
kinks the Scott thing stinks radio
thanks
a major one man sup maybe
and I this is that this is a good when
you can make a lil radio
see can listen to I radio y fly
airplanes
now you really can't and a geiger
on its the elementary you some other
books like like the point can act 700
things for boys do
there's like a really popular thing i'd
the this is a really good luck
there was a time where all the chemical
formulas for like coca-cola
anything that defying a curfew the have
just this documentation
actually make it yourself itself I like
copies of this book in our
bit torrent is a wonderful place to find
he's really a box right now
foxfire but users there's a lotta Center
to do copywriter not really a log cabin
building
a snake floor faith healing shine like a
lot of people just below the surface the
foxfire book series
had it or got arts and crafts things to
me
we have the dark times much exactly sure
thing
after world war two there is a lot of
mass production
us certainly electronics from other
countries but
in the eighties and nineties like
everyone stop buying stuff for a while
really hurt think everything that we
started the nation as the Packers
like benjamin Franklin was thinker
money so this arson
dark times and but things started to
change now specially
you look at criminal sessions here it
looks like things that are in the
physical world
are starting to come the code
you can use this stuff Megan and by that
I mean if you look at like the AM radio
skydiving example you built this but the
the actual pieces inside if it were that
code that ran on
there's other examples out there and I
think one of the things that happen
30 television player
but the AM radio really need example
everyone don't want everyone happy
everyone did something with his big
cabinets around everyone shared
some way and we have something happening
right now there's little pieces of
evidence
that things are are changing and the mp3
players a good example
how many people have like an mp3 player
like absolutely so it's kinda like
in although you didn't build it is kind
of like a transistor radio
is just something up certainly see all
sorts of weird project this is %ah
the peasant every player this guy
actually worked with
has and decided to build his own mp3
player
and it's a as mp3 player license without
dying selling get it online
the document at the whole process he
tried to open source parts of the body
you could %uh this is the mp3 card this
is a nine dollar
players actually lesson like five
dollars now and you can
put it into other projects so it's
almost cheap others my i pod collection
I was doing some iPod firmware
Seth all while ago these are some weird
accessories and these are you know
people putting Linux on
iPods in each generation gets better the
type of things you can do
so that the actual hardware itself is
interesting buddy type things that
people are doing
on top of it are even more interesting
one example as I wanted to audio
recordings
and so I put iPod when exxon my ipod and
I was able to run around
high quality audio recording the
hardware was disabled
shipping by Publix on their and your
higher-quality recording and they can
also record of
up people started to play around the
graphics so this is
the born do not connect looking thing
and I use projects like this to get kind
of the younger kids
into electronics different pieces
technology as
the really don't know how did build
stuff that's not something that's
taught maybe there's a there's a few
examples
get better doing something with
electronics but
everyone wants to something custom they
want to customize it
my something it's more and so we
released but how to use
I A how to how to come I am
and on mississippi Stud every single
slide you see here has a how-to behind
and we're giving wealthy such as at the
end of the presentation I'll give you
that way to download all the stuff you
watching your firmware
these things on the such as letter thats
a
no other things that inventors TV Guide
is here
there's a presentation tomorrow about
subversive technologies and that there's
a ton of fun project that too I reported
this
I R sound that came from the TV Guide
and then I put my i-pod
and I have a sound I R converter that
lives possibly so that I'd walk from
Best Buy
or
or our site or maybe some I and
like CES is a good place to get it is I
TV's just loops and turns off all
a even the boxes so lot wanna status
there are others
there's eight million iPods like the
first year now there's a million iPods a
quarter
and like no one talks about these boxes
are even
like what are people doing this sign in
an iPod boxer about so with all that
distorted iPods
you can make your own little robot up
another fun thing that happened was I as
technologies retire
reuses theme and this this is a I the
Walkman iPod case
up funny story behind us Sony said this
guy
I think they sent a cease-and-desist
because they said you know your you're
really a
confusing everyone a we don't want
people to think we make crappy
players that are really big that no one
buys sony makes crappy players
buys up so the way around this is week
there's a how-to
so you can post out is just can't sell
these as price anymore
just a fun one you know the its good
project is up
old mice like everyone has liked or
falls my eyes
what do you do it is well this is a a
and I'd be a mouse
FM transmitter cell shuffle fuckin
other creative things that are happening
charging solutions this is what does
handprint flashlights you can charge
and that was round once okay let's get
to it
but let's show how to modify the
existing PC technology with the crowd
and then charge iPod but wait there's
more I'll will put on a bike
so now the guy petals are out recharges
as I fight again
every everything's documented and
there's a lot to me improvements on this
on this 1i had it takes forever though
like for it takes like 40 days
but if if if our world
political problems continue I'll have
liked the last week
up and
even things that are quite meant it to
be tinkered with
right away so the iTrip is FM
transmitter and
won the 1st battalion Irish the Rangers
better so we
how to how to crack it open just require
lawn $10 you get more range a fun things
you can do if you go to a gym where they
broadcast TV's
over FM so people can list their I went
to one there's like Fox News I decided
to display my own stuff
or you can go the other way
and this is a megaphone helmet at and
you can plug in your iPod just I walk
around
for a music player %uh
so what's going on here with all the
stuff why is actually happening
this is an unfortunate slide this is all
these are all these crazy web 2.0
companies there
XML and RSS and like all these like
everything ends with are
or it's like some weird name in we all
these companies agreed on next year
but the good news is a a lot of the
things that they're doing are helping
sharing information without
wiki got Flickr up workers actually one
of the most interesting places
to share how to use right now and it's
only because it's like
the way it's bill we have new devices
there
are super easy access to documentation
the way that
things get sent out there like right
away there's wanna recipe
is interesting and people know about it
we all probably saw the mentors and Diet
Coke
things like every so here's a fun house
you guys take diet coke
but I think I meant isn't it and
explodes day easy
are medicide to do a contest about coke
diet coke
decided it was freakin they're scared
meant just look the other way and the
like no sinister videos
so you know that instantly went up on
YouTube is only one around the web so
it's getting into there's things that
are happening I
and yes I have to ship so much stuff
like we have so many cell phones this
is this is an artist who takes photos
have cell phones people tossing
recycling everything but what can you do
with assault are really
thats crazy up and we're getting mad one
of the things that happens
us consumers customers everyone column
are starting to fight back
what's been going on there the web
recently you know a while phone calls so
trying to cancel their accounts
there's a site devoted to custer people
not happy with
whereby things we started this thing of
you can open something
you don't know it now
his alright started like sending this to
companies like I just sent this randomly
like so like they don't really respond
but
like hear something so special tools
like why do I need to buy special told
Open Mic thing like
okay like maybe once in a while it'll
make sense but don't don't just make a
special tool that have to buy
I want to open up something turks okay
but like don't ever do tamper-proof
up some things like if something can be
replaced make everyplace like
you know the power doubt our things are
going always go on laptops on
laptop power supplies would be great if
they all work the same how many times
have you keep by
by said different ones for different
laptops power from USB
why isn't everything anything is
rechargeable USB
standard connectors on the first snap
site itself open
screws are better than cialis up docks
and drivers like every company please
pick stuff on archived or
like if its drivers company all things
out we just can't find drivers
useless documentation their stores
surges free now
get it out there a met a person or not
of like schematics like
right now what we're doing make it any
type kidding
bill where clinton's the stuff same
thing
abolished and that finally see the
return ticket
things things that are happening right
now because access to all sorts of
different stuff because
there's online stores because
international shipping there's some
kids that we're starting to see that
mourner available before
so this one it's that paper itself sorry
a plastic cup reporter
so you can record your own voice until
possibly up just like record player
is an of us are you tubes
RFID there's tons of our there's an RFID
session earlier
many things about that sheep easy to get
so we start releasing
projects okay so are fighting you know
everyone else as other
what can we do well here's a simple
project how to make door opener so you
can just wait RFID bad
again but of course what did people the
right way they decide
pinar ID attack in their hands said just
like you'd expect
so here's a project that you put the
reader inside a keyboard
and as you go up to the keyboard you
know i unlock your password
so you don't even need to login anyways
and for believing
you of and you've got other
house yeah yesterday all servers and
you've got other problems
up and then of course what do you do
once you have an RFID implant we make a
trampoline
that can only be activated with your
hand and when you jump on it she flames
so this is the an RFID enabled flames
shooting traveling
course like 10 seconds and this is
everything there's that would probably
be on what it is all magazines Asian
like
white I would you feel the thing I fun
stuff %uh
it you know what are the themes and
images fours like when she started
great stuff and and mod it like I have a
digital camera that's really all that's
really crappy
but I soldered in a new chip that makes
take photos
like a second charge teaching first I
like digital camera better digital
camera
because I made it something next each is
another example like these are really
this all russian hardware and they were
used for all sorts the scientific
all sorts like hardcore/style and now
they're just all over the place
and you can't buy them go on eBay he has
RSS feed
just like puttin 8255 eventually but
people making Fox
wristwatches all sorts things %uh
what are the other things that happen is
a candy
and also its of a sudden kept seeing all
these projects
two people he's met like wow this is
nice cases you do something so people
take their own house and they decide to
make an outside
10 house the project this as a
camera thats mounted on top oven outside
and its crude and there's a big strong
magnets you can put your video cam on
top of your car
and drive around like passengers worry
about that
this is a really good one will only be
sweaty flip the switch and
good race LED's in general
used to be one a dollar at least
be like for boxing now
you there's a session gonna make them
and throw them on things free like
literally throwing them away so
so recommend so you know what can you do
to take part as well
the reason that I think that we have an
opportunity here
is that electrons a lot cheaper
intruders more service not heart hard
cider but on the other hand
you can get arm courtship which is like
100 megahertz computer
like this small for a hike box 60 cheap
another thing that's really nice is
because Open Source offers already
really established you can get open free
tools GCC is important to a lot of
microcontrollers and microprocessors so
pretty much anyone you to suffer back on
I have a softer background like I was
of a person you can start like
programming stuff and
you know like I public for example
people we program I Potter
also some more examples later things you
can do with free tools but
basically you know internet you don't
have to Thomas mister anymore you can
get circuit boards me
30 box there's open source circuit
layout tools and this just
tonics you know point only other tools
available
up to tonight unicef always been around
since accessible again
because there's week eases you too this
lichter you know this
so many ways for people to connect
Instructables also to
showing projects so I mean I think it's
great that
almost anyone just get into this even if
all you know right now is PHP reached
him out
it's really not hard their stools gets
out there
such a nice it's no longer like wire
wrapping
its you can like started
so like I did that night so what I do
is I make kids and educational
you know you you get a bag apart
and you know L usership service the type
a project like this this is the
so you can get
bags and a full electronic parts we saw
it together and then you can
this one's a USB charger the 1i should
for have the power cord on
and you literally plugin your pearl for
knocked just happened is she ok
now and then you can just download free
tools AVR GCC
and reprogram it merely these blankets
etc any
yet so and if you can see it but it does
make seen
and sell some people
some people look put on their bikes
Kenny my grasp well
this guy got to politically class
a San Francisco version no hun
Washington DC
and he said that you look at me to John
your bike you can see it's kinda cool to
I'm now
that's weird I you know
you can program the message just in the
the poly people in the audience is
actually office gets a 20 and like it
cost like five dollars
heart you can actually have it's the
skin ass online the codes online you can
you can get the parts for free in Milan
some people do if you look on Flickr
they look so cheap they don't even send
me to 1750 get a circuit board and they
sought to the parts together
I'm sick himself that's fine see and
made a bigger version for bike wheel
also to take the same thing that really
big I have it
there's a Mac you like it just odometer
backwards
so the next did you
supply yes we can wield
so I'm I'm burning man with pac man in a
ghost in like you
okay back is this some people
that
side not only did what's interesting is
because these tools are so inexpensive
notta lotta education like this project
actually
she skopje schematic do anything at all
I don't lie on USB charger for iPod and
people really like you too could begin a
project
and such but this is more efficient and
better engineered almost anything else
on the market
the case is handled if you want to give
the job to get me wrong
because I'm not constrained by old to
make
chief apostle margins are so low you
know I can I can
the do is get a job want to see here's
the part little more expensive but
you because no marketing ties that you
have to give overhead posso
in so we have one two batteries
places iPod
come up after the talk or defender by
building you can look
will have a couple kids with a few one
get one Hassan said sit down there just
like building it a six-point
a so you really interesting because it's
a sort of like an extreme version
open source hardware if any money using
musician you've probably heard
ruling TB 303 if not its to really
famous
besides those manufactured 84 and
unfortunately
it was meant to be an accompaniment for
guitarists and like nobody uses
in the really noises but then summer I
think any
Louise early nineties don't
who was that so much people start using
it to me acid techno
and it just exploded it was huge
everyone
needed TV 3 usually like couple hundred
bucks and
now you going TV taken to get three
thousand dollars but was really nice is
that
you can copyright hardware this is
really great because it means you can
reverse engineer hardline Islamist
patents in this case the word any
patents well there was one was actually
the public domain thanks you can
you know I we made the exact schematic
circuit diagram made
shit free open-source like I have a
couple hundred people
on these and it's really neat because I
sequencers all
open source also and people actually
went modified
this is amazing you might you buy
synthesizer at it
you've got it doesn't it doesn't doesn't
another one wanna my customers really
want swing timing
which is when you have sort on the
sixteenth note sometimes for
after jazzy feel and this one
the original see if we didn't have it
misled he said on dad and I said sure
there's interrupt do try this this and
this issue happens in
he just needed and then share for more
than the people may uploaded
so there's a couple people out there who
have upgraded to the site is not
if you don't repeat your TV like every
time you like
it's broken I don't fix it you can you
can do that with patchy
you can do that Zilla you can do that
with you know any open source software
you can't do that was harder right now
so close so
like we really need you guys past doing
we get together
wanted it
so we've been trying to do the same
thing so yeah make controller
decide systematics and it's basically
anytime you want to control any type
devices here good example
like but say if you want to have fun
like your instant message client
change the color up hi
you want to have to change the color
lamp so
a in a lot of people than me now says
gently to the article like I would do it
a different way
and is awesome cuz I said yeah please do
you know like okay
you know your download the SmackDown
from updated anywhere you want and
we'll see how it goes I mean it's a its
first experiment and
like a full-blown get that to be used
just about for anything
I and again this is all information
about this is available for
doctor this a camera talking about so
us a 1.3 megapixel cameras like the old
lunch box size
ones I we all have we've all bought like
five dollars it I'm
and took apart my you know a be really
need if I could do something else with
it
and then get other people to start doing
other things with these there so many of
them
I i look the part there's a market share
a report on
like which kid cameras are out there the
first research
others like so on bridges I take this
little time which
5552 most common on out there
and circling around it so I found that I
can rewire the switch
to are likely take photos as soon as you
turn it on
uses all smart yet like this big like
flash you know
Mike there's no other use for this thing
I don't care if it breaks
sure what happens to it so much okay I
don't do I could put on a kite
so iight I took I
and a it went up and up and up and a
and and it crash in survived in this
thing just won't die
so I start like I could do other things
so I'm I was a
looking at Amazon's a9 search engine
and you can type in an address and what
they did is they drove around
just like really expensive car with this
GPS is camera
they put all those dots are voters a the
the to
but you know what it's like to be my own
person this so I took a GPS little
hand-held I took my camera
that are likely to differ is in the GPS
logs
as a pretty standard file and has a
timestamp and the camera
takes photos timestamp so all ages I
masters together and then I made my own
version have a nine in this is just me
drive
the Apple Store like sawyer
are other examples I earlier today there
was the
that's visible digital video camera and
we're finding people are
using these products are light
here
talk of
scale right away
here some other ones the best one is
like kids
Thursday happens people take the store
is in the pudding Flickr
learns about really
other things so
yeah rotary phones I it's kinda sad
story so I
bring this this my self a that they
bring with me everywhere
play it's awesome in restaurants
think about rotary phones
sad yeah this is kinda sad story when I
bring this
places there's a little kid put his hand
in it like his old and he's like I don't
is what a game controllers as I'm like
oh man
bad news I so
yet history cellphone I what you do is
you got a
regular self-serve regular on rotary
phone which you can get theirs
drive sales are actually the best place
for them and
sparks on electronique so I'm gonna have
their link in the back
they sell all the components that you
need basically rewire
and the signals from the the dialer
store
and I'm gonna try to do right now give
away something call
approach giveaway that room but so what
I want you guys to your phone's out the
first person to get
to the phone where it's a 2006
1323 F signal
rain all
got a winner
who
who is it take about half of the Atlanta
ha contest
ok
wanna hack rumor
also the hacker in a minute nunc 1 now
it's gonna happen is this is on DVD
and people watch it I'm gonna get phone
calls for
haha
also you have lots of fun
send a kickoff to the cell phone numbers
on
and you can anyone else nice
so here's a an inside view but
that not have the interesting thing
about this particular phone is
the it last forever like if it doesn't
rain but want to start
really drains battery like that in mind
have it turned out a movie theater
someplace ticket
to those are the components VCR's how
many
people have VCRs what the fuck are you
doing all these VCRs
there's no they did you can even get VHS
tape same or so we thought about this
for like we're gonna figure out
something to do
with a VCR and we figured out you can
make cat feeder
added um unfortunately looks like a cat
grinder
but
defense I feel like cats so for twenty
everyday detected
and this is what I look like again it
doesn't like a I
tech writer cell it just email me like
that schematic sir
it's easy to build then there's the
motors in like its it's getting cats
like I
iRobot makes these a robotic vacuums and
does anyone have one of these fkk if you
look there's a little tiny port on the
side
spry of like little Mack connector and
what are the things that up week talk to
I Robot
about a while ago was know would be
great if people to start getting in the
robotics without having to do all the
awful things about robotics
if you tried ur ever builder robot you
do a locomotion yeah I got it to move
now I'm tired
I don't feel like doing anything else
ever again you don't get to like ever
focused
on the actual robotics parts so are they
decide to
release Open Interface and you can make
your own
USB to serial director
the other way to do it and I think you
have the this is from a
a bubble gum container yeah and other
y'all
Apple serial connector and its subtlety
up with you part you can use your phone
or you can use any
bluetooth-enabled computer to control
its control
remember and is like it on a project
already we're starting to see
on it's our community built around it
there's a book coming out it's like
backs or something and how to get sorry
out there
its its it's being used p kids are using
these robots
as something to learn about electronics
and programming
it's super easy cuz it's Dom serial
interfaces like going to go so you can
like do logo
like the logo up couple shots ovett
someone made a a MIDI interface so you
can use it as a mini instrument its
kinda fun
II taking this to a lot
yeah so I take it some said farr's and
I'll bring to
and it'll be our yurman verse a
regular room versus other River their
necks the red ball
on his is in cleanup mode it's using its
normal after them to move
the balls around and it thinks is
vacuuming and then the human
tries to beat it and like the the robot
wants most the time
so human doesn't land but we also
started an underground river cock
fighting
time so
I that tiny and you can only stuff
available in like you know of the office
settings
and that's kinda funny get in like
there's money involved
that in and then up there is it one-time
I'll
cited them do real life Frogger
that's a very bad
so you've ever been Austin
it's pretty laid back I they didn't
really care too much
asking by just like thinking like cue
yeah
like a strap pretty bad when the cops
like when you're going oh cool in real
Frogger
now cell jobs so we made it
pass I
half have thinks he should be arrested
yeah so is that a an email so the cops
and said I can't believe that in real I
like Austin like
yes than ever been also its cool down
there like a so we made out like a
touristy certain some
cops and everything and we place better
some that betting Spurs
was the only times you can get it back
and forth across the street and everyone
said Wyoming
actually was like 10 and then eventually
a white SUV ran over
up but survived these there they're
pretty tough so
the TV be gone %uh
fun little device you know it's fun the
turn of TV's
and we thought it would be more fun if
we added more LED's
like 12 and added more power
so this how to turn off the TV up to
like ninety feet away
and the battery lasts like
really long time yeah and how to do is
on makin
is available on Instructables and a its
it's really fun and then there's another
one
outlets if you don't wanna like name
your thing around in like a crazy
are you can build inside had cell
yeah it's hard to see but you can over
yet so that's the hat
on the outside had underneath cell
its kinda fun to walk around your
favorite electronic store and turn off
things and
this is part of a bigger project a you
know if you've gone the computer shows
like CSI used to have like fun stuff
now they just have big LCD screens
that's all they're selling so I thought
to be kinda fun
I don't know if someone do it maybe I I
would laugh about it but like to put in
a helium balloon
and have this kind appointed down all
day just like with the brain is like 90
fwy
turn it off a
legos another knee company that their
latest round robots I the firmware you
can
do anything you want for they do that
now so this isn't
next give us the doing weird things like
as any Western
USB Drive like a vending machine say it
like you can get the start
a and the the leggett communities did a
really good job sharing all
the program you can play connect for
versa
like us valid line following robot
and things are starting to to advance
even more critical than about the future
and what's changing well there's
commoditization
a the hardware there's the software
that's that's free Lego and
there's over projects that you build
everything virtually
and then you know which pics sore
starting to see that that might be
something that happens
your future with some electronics summer
the other project
people so again about
mark billing stuff you you can get
involved everything is meeting like
Chinese
sweatshops now like this one and it
kinda bad because it means that began at
it cannot like you open stuff it's a
complicated weird
but there's also some side effects one
other I side-effect again discussed that
now so much talk earlier is that stuff
is so cheap that
if you if you break if you can break it
doesn't matter it was ten dollars a ten
dollar camcorder
camcorder who cares if you can former
hockey
like you know if you mess up wicked
anyone least
lost firmware upgrades and messed up
understand this
tragic device good you know
Constitution hardware you can go in
there and
mess with stuff like mess with this
digital camera into
care of a really popular cause I think
it's great
is a lot your Havanese wrt54g
sis so for example again you know she
LA Times the turnout research chief you
can get encore for nothing
inside this chip is actually next
computer
and that is all the routing is actually
is tolley do this
and it isn't negative sources open
source information
because the way information people
started building communities where you
can like shares which
your router skinny again you don't need
to actually no
ellen Johnson Jane degree to get start
messing with hardware
like rounder that's just a nice it's
it's a it's nice that firmwares
is it's possible from so cheap she with
open source tools
you know iPod clinics again its you know
you can do stuff like this
you know in five years difficult and you
know nothing that's that's an
interesting
to see in the next five to 10 years just
as ten years ago
pentium computer 100 megahertz pentium
possible thousand dollars in a CD burner
once the
400 bucks and it was leaked out bro
and now to you can get a list enough to
get tickets so come on height so cheap
well you this machine like one on the
left is it PCB router
it's actually about the states not to
and one on the right is an email
and CV theoretically just as laser
printers
over 5,000 10,000 other but it could be
that you know one day
stab revolution that people talk about
these could be in your home you could
buy
Sears so you could download open source
information
how to build a USB charger Press print
and I'll print that the case
on the many male picked up the circuit
board and the order some parts
Amazon Amazon currently selling like
tonic
s trying to get to that market and they
do the stuff at home what can I say
do it yourself fabrication incredibly
cheap
on the fly you know you can compile
stuff at home
CD-rom burners never there are like five
thousand dollars they're cheaper
laser printers others like
too expensive for anyone have I use a
laser cutter laser-etched
RCA from you accident notch on the back
nine hour but
so used to be applied to 30,000 lbs 11
others like 10
10k a lot many for ten thousand dollars
its 18 by 12 word acrylic vinyl anything
you wanna get so meet you can do a lot
of really cool stuff
you have to say to see people I know
people are find them
basements expensive to live now
not and other examples are google has
Google Earth
and like it's not really clear with
Google's doing but I cannot be doing for
the keep like releasing some interesting
things
so our those that have ruled the world
yeah are they doing well
but there's some interesting tools that
they have like Google Earth
you can start to pick your own buildings
in there okay that's interesting they
product company cults catch up and you
can it's like a relief
need rapid prototyping environment and
it's free on PCs that people are
building what they're gonna put in their
homes and they take before and after
pictures
and we're going if our oh well you can
actually build entire house
and once the the glue that the software
that will tie the
electronic drawings to what the physical
hardware is
you'll pull a lever and you can get the
stuff delivered to you up all of our
projects
and make we're gonna try to do is get
suffers and so if you want to learn how
to build
we have like a potato cannon which is
really fussy dictators are in a bit
peace
PVC pipe and we're gonna show how to do
it
like step-by-step be a 3d so you can
like modified different pieces
and where it's going this is the milling
machine
not massive multiplayer online games
like World of Warcraft uneven
the user-created communities of Second
Life there's an open source tool called
dollars at all other yeah I'll and you
can get the
the geometric shapes outta using OpenGL
and you can get the shakes out like this
guy made a sheep so you like bill to see
in the virtual world that's it looks
like and then emailed it
at a farm support there's some early
indications
someone built an entire city and then
this is printed out on a 3d printer so
we're getting close to being able to
get the parts to you that what causes
as much as it does now like cost more
sometimes the ship something from Amazon
the actual or wherever up and that
have leads to the the future
up what else is out there needs to be
open source and like one example that I
like two years
is there's a really big problem with
their
mortality rate of infants in like the
rest of the world and equipment
there call baby wonders the equipment
out there is expensive it's hard to get
shipped out there so a doctor came up
with inexpensive way to do it using
regular light bulb so she actually
sketched out
this design use regular light bulbs with
damn and mortality rate cut happened so
these plans are getting shares are
getting distributive
using local materials there's there's
likes this really good reasons to do a
lot of this and like
the trick is like how do we get people
involved like my trip like do something
with an iPod like everyone's like
doesn't well eventually this is
something that people might start to
think about other things I like
voting machines likewise it is open
source why the papers is
up water purification medical public
transportation like
you think I've open source hardware
projects out there that we just benefit
everyone there's a new project that
there to playing out in South Africa
that it's a merry-go-round
and his kids %uh it's been around
america rockets water pump
and it pops all the water upset
justifying it's fun they also sell
advertising
sites so there's there's yeah so there's
things like that so I'm some resources
for an open up for questions and also
after
up of course make up you know to send
any mail facility
if I all 26 dot com and I'll give
everyone a copy a digital copy the first
issue make so popular sizes h2o section
how to find out which is good course
make website pack today I Instructables
this is one of the few places right now
that's kinda wrapping a lot of this
putting in one place you can put your
projects like any particular software
project
just right on struggles dot com and
resume crips you can see the type of
projects that people are putting in
their
like right now are the projects are
kinda weird like there's teaser gloves
that speaking
here its Kenny on
Flickr a few certain if you look for tax
for how-to & DIY
we have a mic Flickr photo Paul and it's
kind of like a lite version
Instructables
people's put up they're built photos and
you can see like step-by-step
about things are building and %uh spark
fun electronics is where I said
a check to regular basis like all the
things you see here like
sparked fun cells have a lot of
electronics and %uh fidgets that's where
the RFID
readers are from and so the little RFID
parts and they also have a deal with the
guy
Road RFID hacks projects and that's a
really good book to check out different
RFID
projects that this is a information
mine and I think we've got a few minutes
for questions and if there's no
and afterwards yeah everyone does it the
big question
difficult him a questions get a copy at
least
you make yeah a question cell
yeah but they're right there
really it's like extra
left side alright so
questions got a few minutes get ideas
officers projects yeah neither are I'm
I'm actually in the process doing a
couple and somebody donate some space to
me
like to call the gym computers and stuff
got some kids I'm actually and I was
getting discouraged by
militarization is there so much hardware
so this is great because
extra information I didn't have about
how to hack things that are almost
surface mount loath me is that yes this
is getting sluts getting many tries to
technology allows for it
on the other hand I think even stock
fund has a kid for
temperature controlling a Black and
Decker reflow
Black & Decker if lovin the 7 they have
a little chip
temperature control and do reflux you
can get like a5
Delores Lovett in your kitchen to dougie
lead so don't you can use that to like
decider chips again johnnie something
similar I miss technologies out there
and again internet is fine so maximize
my question's going to be
what's the best way to find people in my
area because I'm I'm hooking up with
course the internets great and making
all that you deserve n you for like
finding
out is close to you yes i mean the
Research Triangle Park area
North Carolina and might be I know a lot
of people that are
hundreds of miles away from I don't know
a lot of people that are within 30 miles
yeah but I tended suggest is go to
flicker of course it disposable project
the budget ax as you can for your
location
good Instructables bigger location these
groups are self warming up to make forms
there's always a call for makers like
people say like a i mean I mean
Indiana whatever I I'm looking to do a
project with someone like it's like
it's like matchmaker but not really like
that don't you can search on the dress
yeah okay yeah Radiohead group to and
what up coming out or
there's like there's a fence in like a
lot of areas and we also have an event
listing
on make that we try to but out there in
everyone can send in everything submit
your event in there too or whatever even
if it's just a meeting
that's I
um you talk a lot about open source
hardware
how does that relate to hands and
how would you protect your open source
hardware from being patented by somebody
else
on you can't hand something that's been
released into the public domain that's
just
if you look at the way the patent system
works once you've really something
%um you they could and you have to fight
it court which is unfortunate but
same thing happened same thing happens
with open source software
illnesses have to be at convinced police
said
but you can't pass up it's an open
source I mean that's fine
yes that's the best trade-off publish it
because it
right for 50 bucks the Patent Office has
a Gazette that you can publish things in
check that would that would
you post any word from my you
high art but that you might have to
defend it in court is
when I love okay that's good are you
fully with the rep rep at project
yeah yeah school stuff and is that
already covered by patents existing
patents
don't know offhand you'll have to look
into I have no clue either
Askim she I'm a real curious
if you guys have made any attempt to
connect with free energy
device creators different dinners I'm
going to the
test at a convention which is coming up
in a
in a week or so and was wondering if
there's a
resource that I could use to try and
convincingly
remote I'll open source
their their hardware and their devices
for the website crashes the mighty
the visit and all the sudden the
technologies
years I think they should open source
because there's a lot of skeptics of
course about free energies
ever free up the so they should really
yeah I mean absolutely like this you
post up a destructive all early
you know howto & play her something but
as far as
a convincing them there's a ton of
benefits
I i think is like we get a lot of emails
we might do an issue
that kinda looks at somebody's free
energy ideas and concepts
and like you know how it works out as
are currently all that in everything in
between
so I'm emailing I mean like more we're
gonna be covering this on make
early next year so I would have them you
know you at the same address you gave
yes Washington that's fine but yeah they
definitely should open source their
ideas
thanks has gone
you know that really a question just
comment I've been playing with a lot of
this stuff for
pic chips things like that all these
projects
a real good source for all these old
electronics /url the
ham radio fast totally ARRL .org they
have a list
times dates places all is
here knee-deep in all
video recorders and camcorders styles
day hand fast doesn't ham radio liked it
if done all the stuff already
we just expanding I mean a this is all
if you tell him it is all to you like
bill yet did
I mean on straight but was
tragic create a large community so yeah
refs
meet people there get parts right to
keep
model train guys to make them print they
have like there like the best furniture
for guys like thought
let's all thanks
I FeO D-day state a receives additions
like if I am
project currently working on back in
just a minute
because I'm actually building something
I've been building a lot at that guitar
effects
and and ends at the salon stuff just
communities for people to do that
yesterday
positions I like new ham radio hackers
decade yeah i think is a new we pay
higher 10 trying to get information from
manufactures regarding hardware and how
to access it
one of the common excuses or reasons
they give especially in anything art
related
is that the implement regulatory
compliance and software
if they open that everybody would be
regulatory violation it would be a mess
yeah comment on that kinda thing you're
wealth been dealt with
I can only give examples we have stuff
right now getting up
though example that I can get real quick
is room for like think once you
mark this and everything could push a
grandma down the stairs
and so it's like it's really no like who
knows like and like you violate the free
Laws of Robotics want you
haida like tell them your student you
need I mean like
make mean you're hot such a gr8 right
get
thank you