I'm like the slaw dried before
so I will try to I will get us out of
here in like 20 minutes
but I don't expect that
and let me just I have an official
scroller who's going to scroll through
my presentation because it's in PDF nod
PowerPoint alright next slide please so
this is coordinating cyber incidents
initially this was a presentation
utilizing Star Trek Captain jean-luc
Picard unfortunately as it turns out
Capital One doesn't own the rights to
the bald captain of the enterprise so
I've made it more generic any Star Trek
fans though cool let's catch up
afterwards
definitely TNG is my favorite followed
by deep space 9 I'm not really a big fan
of voyage or anything kind of new of
course I'm a Capital One I manage our
cyber incident management team I'm
working on me and my MBA at Virginia
Tech any Hokies there we go one two two
three there we go thank you and I love
sci-fi of course black mirror has been
kind of my favorite show and carbon
altered carbon anybody seen altered
carbon excellent
I love altered carbon I love that
they're doing kind of a sci-fi noir
blade runner-esque show so hopefully
there's a second season next slide
please
so basically we're talking about
coordinating and communicating cyber
incidents I'll start off with why this
matters and then we'll go to the kind of
before the hits the fan or stuff
hits the fan and after stuff hits the
fan next slide please
so at Capital One we've set up a cyber
incident management team basically this
is the team that works really closely
with our incident responders we thought
it was you know like well like many
companies we're kind of finding that you
need people who can actually respond to
the hackers and take samples and delete
malware and conduct forensics and then
you need people who can kind of talk
about what they're doing and give them
air cover so I'm one of those air cover
people so I like talked up what we're
doing and I say everything's alright
it's not terrible here's our plan in
Capital One we found one two three works
and other companies I've worked at phone
one two three works and really we're
looking at cybersecurity generalists
right that's people who kind of know
a lot about cybersecurity but don't want
to get too in the weeds with anything
next slide please
so basically why it's important to
communicate in your cyber incidents of
the enterprise at Capital One we really
feel that cyber should lead cyber for
the enterprise right so that means we're
in charge right
that means when things go down we step
up we communicate confidently we know
what's going on and we have this
360-degree view right the business is
paying for a service the business is
paying to feel safe and to be safe and
so it's our job to make sure that we can
articulate power protecting the business
and what we're doing to respond right
also simplicity any kind of complex
story when a you know when bad cyber
incidents occur it gets really complex
right I mean look at Equifax it was
really confusing what was going on with
the company especially as somebody
looking from the outside and I'm sure
was confusing inside the company as well
so if you tell one story and if you have
somebody who's kind of a clearinghouse
right you're able to bring much more
people to the table
and that means your business leaders
that means the people running your
applications that means the CEO feels
like he or she understands what's going
on and makes us as cyber a lot more
important to the company next slide
please oh yeah I always like to pause if
yeah this if this is boring for anyone
so I used to do this thing it in
conferences where I would pretend to use
the restroom in the middle of the
presentation and not come back of course
because it was boring but if it's boring
for anyone now is your opportunity and I
will not be offended if you get up and
pretend to use the restroom any takers
all right so I will assume all of you
are semi interested or you are
comfortable next slide please
oh sorry good call so a lot of a lot of
what we're doing before cyber incidents
occur is socializing our enterprise
response plan of course everyone in the
company has weighed in on this or
at least everybody who needs to weigh in
it has weighed in on it training people
telling them okay one a cyber incident
occurs this is your role right this is
what cyber is going to do this is what
the commercial line of business is going
to do this is what our card line of
business is going to do and this is what
you know our application support teams
are going to do I spend a lot of my time
and hopefully many of you are spending a
lot of your time meeting your IT and
business leadership right because you
don't want the first time they see you
is they're panicked and you're panicked
and it's probably not going to be a
really fun time right so I try to build
we try to build a relationships with all
of our IT leaders people in charge of
our desktops people in charge of our
servers our AWS make sure they know you
before stuff happens as well as your
business teams right because these are
the people actually making money for the
company money paying your salary so you
want to make sure they know who you are
and they know what you're going to do we
try to take our network not our like IT
network but our personal network really
seriously by mapping out okay these are
our key stakeholders these are the
people that are important to our success
and then really tracking how many times
have we talked with them right
have we met them in the last couple
quarters if we haven't then
relationships start to fall apart right
and you don't want to be forming
relationships in the middle of a cyber
incident tabletop exercises are actually
kind of boring at this point anybody do
tabletop exercises and they you know
they kind of get boring so we're trying
to move to more drills right so I won't
tell like much analysts when we're going
to do it but in the next week we're just
going to run an emergency call and wake
people up and get people on the phone
and that's actually one of the ways we
train Capital One cyber if you want to
move up like a level to like a higher
level senior cyber incident manager or
something we tell you okay in the next
week you're gonna get a random phone
call and we have like four people
sitting in a room pretending to be angry
business leaders and you have to just
respond and start taking questions and
start kind of coordinating the cyber
incident so that is a lot of fun to do
if you'd like kind of throwing people in
a fire which I do
next slide please so at the beginning
Capital One we're really we really
stress pause it and really getting a
good understanding of what's going on
with the cyber incident okay I know like
a lot of people just start reacting
right oh I know I've seen this malware I
know what to do or I've seen this
ransomware I know what to do I know how
to respond but what I found is if you
wait like 20 minutes and just figure out
what's going on and start writing down
the story right it'll make things a lot
smoother so we think you know pausing
and figuring out the story is a lot more
important than just starting to respond
like a robot okay a lot of our cyber
incident management would kind of have
this relationship with our IRT and I'm
sure many of you do too where we like to
challenge each other if something's not
making sense you know speaking of course
that's kind of table stakes in cyber and
then this is kind of what we do for our
summaries so you know always the bottom
line up front we always try to connect
it to the line of business so what line
of business is impacted what's the
impact what are our next steps short
active sentences you know like some
people like to write these long flowery
sentences and really get technical and
the c2 server did this and this was a
communication but you know we want to
keep it as high level as possible
because like I said that brings more
people to the table and of course let me
take a little jargon and then we try to
speak really you know at this time right
if you make those definitive statements
of course everybody knows are those good
or bad yeah precisely so they might come
and bite you in the ass so if you're
making a definitive statement make sure
it's really true or speak tentatively
this is what we know at this time next
slide please
so a capital one we have our own ticket
management system that we built in-house
Kevin one loves building things so we
use Jarvis like the butler
Jarvis incident management system
because it's kind of just I mean this is
really basic stuff right that everybody
is recording and most likely in your own
incident management systems so I'm not
going to go through that too much next
slide please
I love this I love
scrolling you know a really good
scrolling yes question so it we've
actually switched our terms we define an
incident as a compromise or unauthorized
intrusion into our network that requires
containment and remediation at Kaplan
won an event is actually a higher level
than an incident an event is like a
multi multiple incidents or incident or
one incident that impacts multiple lines
of business so we have alert incident
event alert many people use alerts for
events you know you can adopt deadlines
to that help and then we also have our
kind of our own severity scale that we
use impact data so the analysts when
they're first starting a case are going
to figure out what's the lob impact
what's the functional impact is an
application down
is there no functional impact how it
done to the network is the actor an apt
or like a hacktivists or like a script
kitty and then Jarvis will crunch these
categories of course this is from the
NIST
incident management standard will crunch
these categories and determine a
severity level that it suggests to the
analyst severity five being of course
the Loess Saturday zero being we are
like I'm probably out of a job or have a
job for a really long time because it
got really terrible next slide please
so a lot of our work how many a lot of
our work happen occurs on bridges right
you know like this is usually at like 11
p.m. at night we get a call and
someone's been sitting on something all
day and then they're like oh maybe I
should escalate this does that ever
happen to anybody here or is that it's
like I always scroll to the first email
and I see you are talking about this
since 9:00 in the morning but you're
calling me at 11:00 p.m. at night so a
lot of our work gets done on Bridgette
bridge calls where we'll pull all the
resources we need like the network team
work station team database team privacy
legal etc
and we try to have a very strict way of
running these calls which I'm going to
share like anything we always do kind of
a pre call which means before we do
anything right we pause and we figure
out what's the story we're gonna tell
how are we gonna tell it and then we
kind of brief ourselves to make sure we
can brief it it's really important for
cyber to show up and take command right
like I said the business is paying for
your information security Department the
business is paying for all of us to be
in charge right they want someone that
says hey hold on
stop you know stop freaking out we're in
charge we have a plan here's what we're
gonna do so by setting the tone and
taking command of the call at the very
beginning right that really gets us off
to a good start
and personally I like to stand up you
know that these are big calls you might
have 4050 people all trying to talk at
once right has anybody been on one of
those chaotic calls all these network
teams everybody's talking randomly I
actually found that standing up and
projecting into the call makes you sound
a lot more confident and so - smiling
because you don't sound as panicked you
know like the firewalls going down but
that's okay
it really works like people can hear the
calm in your voice if you're calm
everyone else will remain calm your VPS
will remain calm your directors worry
income if you freak out it's you know
it's really not going to be fun and
people will not be happy the next
morning establishing the cop operating
picture if you control the story
you control the incident right in terms
of managing it now I can't tell you you
know you can control the story but if
the apt is still in your network like
you know you haven't really done a lot
but at least you control the story so
that's a really good start you can start
figuring out what's going on to fill a
lot of work stream management so we set
3 work streams work stream a contain
we're extreme be eradicate we're extreme
see talk to our legal department about
what happened right and then you can
treat you know then then you get started
and go through these work streams I love
sharing my screen I have all my analyst
share their screens because has anybody
been on those calls when somebody joins
like in the middle of the call and they
say hey this is Bob from the Wintel team
what's going on it's like dude we just
went over this for like 20 minutes you
know thinking then you have to restart
and re-explained everything so if you're
sharing your screen you just tell them
hey read the screen and eventually they
get used to doing that next slide please
so on the bridge we like to use a lot of
approval based action so cyber or at
least that our company shouldn't be like
taking down a web application right we
should ask the business hey or we
recommend to the business due to X Y or
Z we recommend you take this application
down for the next two hours while we
apply an emergency patch providing
updates every 15 minutes even if you
don't have an update a lot of times
people will try to control the call
right and so there'll be this dead
silence edit awkward silence and like
somebody will speak up and start like
controlling things who's not cyber what
I found so make sure you stay in control
of the call even if there's nothing if
there's that awkward silence always
asking like okay team what are we not
considering like you're not supposed to
have all the answers if you're leading
that incident response right you're not
meant to have all the answers but you
are meant to kind of facilitate and okay
this application security team what are
they thinking during this incident they
might have a really good idea oh who has
everything really ever done this you're
on a call and somebody's like speaking
out IP addresses and it's like the most
confusing thing right and like
everyone's trying to type down what IP
address is he's saying or like sharing
sometimes it's just what did you say
what did you say so just put that in
chat and I like if anybody starts doing
that on a call that I'm running or my
analysts are running we immediately tell
them hey can you please stick that in
check because it gets really funny when
everyone's saying was that 1.3 or 4.7 a
lot of people say I think on these
bridges right well I think the hacker is
gone okay but we're not really here to
think we're here to know so you can
think that but then we try to fact-check
each other well how will you know that's
true and then of course I like to remind
people always escalate if things aren't
getting done if it's a severe incident
you should be telling your VP you should
have their number
you should keep going up the chain all
the way to the CEO if things aren't
getting done of course you know
hopefully that would not be the case
next slide please
then when we get to leadership so
usually these calls are like 11:00 p.m.
so leadership doesn't really want to be
waking up at 2:00 a.m. but you know the
next morning we might kind of will
provide that perspective the context
we're paid in cyber I'm sure your
companies as well they're not paying for
robots right they're paying for people
to give perspective how bad is this
really how long were they in the network
what do we need to do to get them out of
the network right we always like to do
one recommendation with three options so
our recommendation is to you know take
these servers down for a week and you
know let us do more forensics there's
another option though which is that we
don't do that and we just wipe it and
move on and then really up to the
business and we'll present well this is
what happens if you do it this is what
happens if you don't but let the
business leaders make decisions and
always prevent your presenting the
recommendation first if it's a B and C
you know a should be the one you
secretly want not C or not B right and
all we always like to tell the
leadership the next update is going to
be in two hours so they don't keep
bugging you that's even more probably
the most annoying thing that that you
might experience is when people keep
asking for updates right say well the
next update is in an hour and we'll get
you an update then of course if it's
your CEO or something go ahead ten
minutes left
question
whatever experiences the seaso and the
leadership should be making a oh yeah
okay question is who should be making
the decisions should it be the cyber
analyst should it be the CCO should it
be the business leadership what I've
experienced is your seaso and the
business leadership should come to an
agreement but at the end the business
are the ones making the money right they
are in charge of how the company is run
so we try to you know we do that right
we'll lead cyber for the company but in
the end it's the company's decision to
either drink water or you know gallop
off leading the horse to water reference
next time please I was like the one mess
up scroll so that's okay at the end so
what we found really useful is having a
cyber problem management team question
yeah so when we have a zero the question
is if there's a zero day or something of
significance is there an established
protocol we have it we have a team that
runs with those it's not an incident
management we call it event management
but it's almost the exact same thing get
a bridge go and get all the people
together talk about the work streams
divvy up work streams and the call
check-in the next morning or the next
you know so we have a cyber problem
management team this is a newer function
at Capital One but it's awesome because
like I don't want to be waiting for
things for like three day right beyond
to the next thing but this is the team
we pushed stuff off to they'll track
stuff for weeks or months or however
long it takes to do you know some kind
of patching like a thousands I mean that
would only be a day or something but
something that takes a really long time
this team are the ones who will who will
kind of track that down at the end of
the at the end of the incident we right
run report every week let everybody have
their feedback and then we finalize the
report I think that's the best way
that's the one story there's no more
stories right that's the report that's
what happened there's no more opinions
and then of course people love timelines
the next slide please
lastly this is what we're working on now
so we've kind of established this this
framework and how
run things we're working on really
maturing our metrics so you know what
are the quality of our incentive
notifications is it like is the right
really or is it good is it
understandable can you read it and
figure out what's going on how long it
takes us to write things is another
thing like it could some people spend
hours trying to make this flowery
language and make it perfect but really
what's important is to get information
out to the company what's going on and
one of our key risk indicators is how
many incidents are we managing at one
time so if weird vanishing like ten
incidents at once it might start getting
a little risky for the company because
we can't we may not be able to keep up
with that level of churn properly what
we're working on in the future is
automate automating and augmenting our
notifications so Capital One of course
loves AI and machine learning so if one
day I'm replaced by AI cool I don't
think it's possible they don't have the
charm that I do with one chuckle that's
fine but we are working on augmenting
our notification so I don't have to
write everything by hand machine can
like start writing information and then
I can just fill in the gaps and that is
scroll please it Capital One we have a
booth of course you haven't seen us if
you want to talk to me about anything
hopefully work related here's my email
address if you're interested in hearing
more about how Capital One manages cyber
incidents are there any questions yes
yeah cus so the question is about
customer-facing and yes it's it's more
of everything and faster and we bring in
more people PR or legal compliance etc
to the table but we run the same
framework and the same calls and the
same people yes
yeah yeah we do so question is arbitrary
timelines and like the legal team is
like hey we need an update in 20 minutes
about everything that happened that's
actually not it this is really hard to
do right
we're not that quick so but the way we
combat that is is upfront so I've got
all these relationships I know that all
the legal people and I've explained to
them how long they should expect things
and so they know to ask that would be
kind of silly so they don't so that's
what's really helped us anything else
then please you know enjoy lunch and
stop by Capital One booth thank you
I'm story that does jeffrey club