sedation will begin momentarily
you guys ready I can introduce myself
that's fine so good morning I'm Megan
Ferguson and this is commas kill writing
better for analysts I want to thank be
science for taking a chance on having a
tech writer present something I think
it's not something you guys normally get
and I really appreciate it
I am a technical writer at the National
cybersecurity and communications
integration Center and I have years of
experience working with analysts and
cybersecurity reports I do not have
years of experience speaking in public
so I appreciate you bearing with me
because I'm terrified right now this is
a very big room so I'm very lucky I like
I like cybersecurity I like working with
analysts and I like writing so I'm
pretty much in the perfect job I
developed this presentation because
writing well is no longer optional not
only our analysts expected to analyze
malware performance and response
but they're also in spite of expected to
write stellar reports the cost of
submitting a bad report or a bad product
to a customer as they may choose not to
work with you again which can affect
your livelihood you may lose credibility
with your customer and your peers for
something that you know it could have
been fixed this presentation
presentation gives you some tools to
improve your products maybe even make it
easier for you to write them and I'd
like to start by addressing the title of
my presentation commas kill with a
really stupid joke
a panda walks into a bar he eats a
sandwich he shoots the waiter
the bartender shouts hey where you going
you just shot my waiter and you didn't
even pay for your sandwich the Panda
yells at the bartender I'm a panda look
it up bartender opens his dictionary and
sees the definition of a panda bear eats
shoots and leaves
in this case the comma really did kill
next slide so this presentation will
cover the following information how to
organize your data how to support your
analysis how to avoid common mistakes
and if you're lucky enough to have them
how to work with technical writers next
so before you begin writing I like to
have you start with three simple steps
we need to define sorry consider your
audience who is your intended audience
the audience of the product is it fellow
analysts is it c-suite executives or the
general public which is actually worst
of all second define the documents
purpose what are you trying to
accomplish what is the document supposed
to do are you providing information to
help leadership make decisions informing
analysts on something you've observed
reporting findings from an engagement or
assessment the the purpose of your
product will really help you figure out
how to write it especially for unique
products I like to put the purpose
statement at the top of my report while
I'm working on it
so if I get off on a tangent I can
revisit it when I open the document and
think all right I really didn't need
that information in there then the last
is choose the vehicle by which I mean
the type of products does your
organization have templates if so you
should probably use them your technical
writers will thank you you'll be a hero
templates can often narrow down the perp
the purpose of your product and your
audience because specific products go to
specific audiences the type of product
needs to work with your intended
audience so a report going to leadership
should have an executive summary so that
should be something that your template
has fellow analysts want technical and
analytical details and the general
public does not want technical details
at all they just want intro attribution
but that's a different presentation to
help you remember these three things I
worked very hard to come up with some
acronyms the first one is a PV audience
purpose vehicle when you're thinking of
it you remember the alligator on the ATV
you wonder what it stood for you
probably revisit this talk because you
just remember the alligator and there
you go the second one I made up for you
is like the old Batman episodes
that vehicle audience purpose I've been
thinking of this stuff for about a month
and this is the best I could come up
with so I appreciate your kindness about
these all right now we're gonna go into
the next slide the camel with three
humps so when I started writing my PhD
my advisor told me that basically any
document is a camel with three humps the
first hump is the introduction you tell
the audience what you are going to tell
them the second hump is the main body
you tell them what you are telling them
and the third hump is the conclusion you
tell the audience what you've told them
as analysts you should be spending most
of your time on the main body your
findings your observations and analysis
are the meat of the report so next slide
your first draft is the first pancake
why is it the first pancake it's not
ready for primetime do not give this
pancake to Gordon Ramsay he will fire
you
so first thing I ask you to do is start
early edit often but I'd honestly be
happy as a technical writer if you did
more than one draft that would do it for
me as a student I would write papers the
night before they were due I'm sure that
a lot of you did that as a teacher I
told my students I could tell if they
wrote papers the night they were before
they were due because I could if you
send your first and only draft straight
the customer they're gonna be able to
tell that this is your first pancake you
guys are lucky in one way analysts write
reports once they complete the work so
you do the fun stuff you generally know
your conclusions before you even touch
the product you just have to write it
which is the part that kills the purpose
of the first draft is to exist
don't sweat it too much just get started
on it it doesn't matter I mean with
computers you can change anything not
like the word processor that I used when
I was in college but the biggest point I
want to make to you if
you don't listen to any of the other
stuff I've said is always right the
introduction last cannot emphasize it
enough introduction last first of all
you're gonna get hung up on it because
you don't know what you're saying before
you've written it second of all you
can't tell the audience what you're
going to tell them unless you've already
told them the thing so introduction
lasts sometimes a first draft just
doesn't work it sucks if your product is
just not gelling there's something's
wrong it's not going very well and you
know it's not just that you hate writing
you need to remember the alligator and
go back to a PV you may need to reassess
the audience the purpose or the vehicle
and that may help you with the next
draft a couple other things to consider
in your first draft what does the
audience really care about this is
different for different audiences you
know the c-suite executives are not
going to care about the same thing as a
general public and the analysts are
definitely not kind of going to be
interested in either of those two things
will you need to provide narration
through a step-by-step process for
example maybe you're on an incident
response engagement first you arrive
on-site then you meet with a customer
eventually you deploy host base agents
if you're going to have to step-by-step
a narrative process what level of detail
are you going to provide the audience
decide roughly how detailed you want to
be it'll save you some time later next
slide
so organizing your data over here you'll
see this is just a rough outline of a
paper report any report so after
thinking about the audience purpose and
vehicle you need to start thinking about
how to organize your data and I'm going
to tell you about two different ways
very basic ways to organize your data
the first is organizing by chronology
and that will include your step by step
processes the second is grouping similar
data together
if you're organizing things
chronologically maybe you're writing an
incident response report that requires a
narrative of the threat actor activity
that was observed it makes sense to
present this information and the order
it happened rather than in the order in
which you discovered it so you might not
know exactly what threat actor was doing
in order you're gonna find it in
different ways you want to present it in
your report in the order in which they
did it it'll be easier for your audience
to follow first you would provide
details on the threat actor using
compromised cadet credentials for
example and then how the actor used
those credentials to complete certain
actions all in chronological order
second example you're writing about a
tool like Jack's boss the report would
likely start with an executive summary
and introductory materials so people
know what they're getting into
maybe they then take a break then it
would take the reader through how the
tool works step by step if you're
interested in Jack's boss the us-cert
website has an a now sport on how Jack's
boss works the other thing is grouping
similar data together grouping like data
together helps the reader process it
again in an incident response report it
makes sense to put information about the
tools you used together second example
information on deploying sensors put
them in the same section even if you're
working across a couple different sites
different networks the deployed sensors
need to be grouped together so the
information on the sensor deployment
makes sense to the person reading the
report if you show them in the
chronological order when you deployed
the sensors it's not going to make much
sense and they're gonna forget reports
can definitely use both of these
techniques finally even if you don't
know which organizational technique you
want to use developing an outline is
important an outline is just a rough
guide gives you the idea of how you want
to organize your report you can start by
sketching out section headings and it
doesn't need to be perfect it's probably
definitely going to change I always say
you need to make a plan so you can
change a plan you can't change something
that doesn't
you need to have an outline to change an
outline I have even used outlines in my
report put them in the first draft and
then written my report by filling in the
information for the different headings
and then if it doesn't work rearrange it
all right
so next slide is very important to me
and this is plagiarism is the enemy I
can't emphasize it enough what being
accused of plagiarism could you could do
to your career and your credibility
you must give credit for ideas and
information that are not yours if you
take credit for someone else's work
either by ignorance you didn't know that
you took credit for their work laziness
it's too much work to provide your
sources or just willfully people will
find out it's especially embarrassing if
the author of the product finds out that
you plagiarized them because they will
take the Twitter about it so I was going
to bore you to death until a friend
helped me with this slide I was going to
explain how and when to cite sources and
you all would have had a really good nap
before lunch believe me what's most
important is to credit the sources you
use it can be very simple simplest thing
provide a link to the source up in the
tool bar if you use Windows which you
probably hate click references footnotes
or endnotes
put the link in there that's it if you
have a technical writer they will figure
out the rest I've done that before don't
get hung up on how your footnotes or
endnotes are formatted even just
providing the simple link is is better
than nothing and there are even free
programs that format citations for you
they're called bibliography generators
you put in the link and it fills in the
rest of the information an example is
easy bib but I looked it up there's more
well these do you guys know what I'm
talking about
some people worry that listing a lot of
sources makes your report look weak it
doesn't
this gibberish is one of the pages of my
thesis where I cited a whole ton of
sources there's some that are longer
like long division showing your sources
is showing how you came to your
conclusions you just want to show people
that you've done the work so they can
see how you got there you will not be
graded on this next will be avoiding
common mistakes and like the
bibliography slide this was going to
bore you to death but I changed it so if
you're bored now that's your own fault
when I started writing my thesis advisor
complained that I was writing small I
knew what I was talking about I knew
what my analysis was I could see my
conclusions coming a mile away but the
way I wrote it my readers could not
necessarily make the same connections
and that's what I call writing small you
need to write big writing big is
explaining everything and being super
detailed think of it again as showing
your work you need to explain the ideas
that your audience may not immediately
understands even if they're intelligent
people you can always edit it later
second thing and you will hear this if
you have a technical writer is using
active voice first of all what is active
voice active voice clearly explains who
is doing the action for example the team
analyzed the malware not the malware was
analyzed the team reviewed the logs to
identify an omlette activity not the
logs were reviewed for anomalous
activity and no matter what you get out
of this talk
this will make it worthwhile this one
thing to identify passive voice if you
can say the phrase in question followed
by the phrase by zombies its passive
voice so the malware was analyzed by
zombies yep
the logs were reviewed for anomalous
activity by zombies both passive and
it's worth your money basically by
zombies
so analysts do not always have to use
active voice so that grammar squiggle
that you see on word turn it off well I
mean don't turn the spelling one off
just the grammar one sometimes passive
voice is just gonna work better for you
guys you use it when you're drawing
focus to the thing affected by the
action it can be used when you're not
sure what is causing the action so
example the signatures were used until
it was determined they were a false
positive or they were creating a false
positive this focuses on the intruder
most sorry this focus is on the
signatures not the intrusion detection
system or the team the malware was
submitted for analysis in June 2018
maybe you don't know who submitted it
you don't know where it came from
last of all be specific being specific
is different than explaining everything
if your report uses a word or a phrase
that could mean different things to
different people provide a specific
definition for that word example malware
variants and malware families I cannot
tell you how many of my friends and
co-workers I have asked well what's the
difference to you between a malware
variant and a malware family I've gotten
a different answer every time so if you
know what you're talking about put
something in there that explains it to
the reader because they may have a very
different idea if you find that adding
the explanation into the text or a
citation is awkward consider using a
glossary so the reader can just go to
the bottom see what you're saying
go back up there good always provide
specific dates and specific numbers and
then double check them for example let's
say you are on an incident response
engagement and you have sensors in the
introduction you explain that you have
two sensors on a network but later on
you say that you have five sensors total
why is there a difference people are
going to notice so be sure to
double-check
all right next slide yes
you know we're not allowed cameras at
work so if you're working with technical
writers if you're lucky enough to have a
technical writer there's a couple of
things I want to tell you from the
technical writer perspective it is
absolutely not personal you will feel
like it is but it's not the changes and
suggestions that a technical writer
makes to your report they're just trying
to make your report stronger and make
you look better it will feel personal
and it's absolutely not and a good
technical writer will rip your report
apart there are two types of technical
writers in cybersecurity there are ones
that like cybersecurity and technology
and are interested in it and they will
research it on their own time and there
are ones that don't both types can help
you with your report
they are there to help you you just get
different stuff from different people
their review is going to help you make
your analysis clearer and more concise
they just want you to look good if
possible especially when you're working
on something for the first time meet
with your technical writer it's gonna
have helped establish the tone of voice
and the working relationship you have
with them especially if you're going to
read their horrible comments to you
later if you can tell them about the
type of product and the audience and the
purpose when you meet with them they're
gonna be able to help you more when
they're reviewing your work they may
have useful suggestions for you anything
you tell them will help them and if you
can't meet try to provide this kind of
information when you're submitting your
email to the technical writer just give
them a heads up here's where I was
thinking here's where I was going it'll
help them help you for the love of God
spell out your acronyms
I am a wizard with Google I can find
anything but I might find the wrong
thing and I'm gonna put it in there
if the technical Raider is not sure what
you're talking about it may impact their
edits making them less clear or even
wrong just you know spell it out if
you're lucky your technical writer will
do the acronym list for you but they
have to be very well paid in sodas
answer questions that your technical
rater asks you if they ask you questions
it means they're engaged and they're
reading for content not just where they
want to put the comma the answers are
gonna help them look for that sorry the
answers are gonna help them learn more
for next time hopefully they won't have
to ask you the same thing twice your
readers may have similar questions to
the one your technical writer is asking
so by answering their questions and
having them at your work you are heading
your reader off at the pass
review the edits your technical writer
gives you don't blindly accept them I
know it is very easy just one click and
all that is gone you may catch
grammatical changes the beat that
introduce errors in your work so the
technical writer may be focused on
making things sound right but they may
make your content wrong you need to
catch that or you're gonna look silly if
you review the changes in the comments
from your technical writer you may learn
some things that make it easier for you
to write your next report you may also
not repeat your mistakes so you're both
learning from each other it's a
symbiotic relationship they're getting
more on the cyber security knowledge
side you're getting a little bit more on
the writing side next site
work smart I cannot tell you enough how
reading makes your writing better read
anything whatever interests you I don't
care just read and read a lot it will
make you a better technical or better
writer you'll just know what sounds
right it'll just make sense to you when
you're reading it take notes as you work
on a project use whatever format works
for you for the notes paper notebook
word document spreadsheet just take
notes the purpose of good notes is to
make it easier for you to write your
report you won't have to scramble
through old emails you won't have to
search for that article you read six
months ago that you kind of remember but
don't really you don't have time for
that your notes are going to help you
remember sources and information and
it's very important so for me I create a
document dedicated document each time I
work on a product and I serve I look
who's killing me I create a dedicated
document and I save direct quotes from
the source with no paraphrasing I know
that these are direct quotes and so I
don't have to worry about miss quoting
something or being accused of plagiarism
because I've done my work I know exactly
what the quote says the other thing
about notes is they can help you
remember your thoughts while you're
working on a project you know a lot of
times I can't remember what I was doing
and I make a list the same thing for
notes you are gonna have some brilliant
analytical insights and if you don't
note them down you may forget them
you're gonna make connections you just
need to keep it all in one place yes
reduce reuse and recycle this is
something people are not going to tell
you you can reuse your standard language
you define something once you can use
that definition until it changes or
until you feel like changing it I
developed a document with the best
versions of standard language from
reports and then when someone had a less
good version I just popped that
standard version in there I was ready to
go you can do the same thing you find
something you like you can reuse that
language not plagiarizing you know your
own work
alright always provide these so what's
so I was working on my thesis and my
advisor would return the chapters that I
wrote with blood sweat and tears and he
would write so what in the margins of
nearly every page
it was his shorthand away way of saying
why are you providing this information
what is the significance what does it
mean for your analysis
you're always providing stuff because it
supports your analysis you need to give
your reader this so what why are you
including it why is it important you may
think your your analysis is basic that
anyone can see it coming but your
audience might not see the connections
so you're gonna have to state it for
them editing your work or having a peer
review of your work is also very
important it is awful it is
gut-wrenching it feels like you are
handing off your baby to someone and you
are not sure if they are a serial killer
you do it anyway colleagues can help you
identify gaps in your analysis they can
bring things to you that you haven't
thought of I mean think about how boring
this talk would be if I had not listened
to my friends it's better to receive
criticism and feedback before your
product is released than after it is
because people on the Internet are not
kind and finally good enough is good
enough theoretically as you identify new
information you could keep working on a
report forever sometimes it's hard to
have closure report and say it's done do
it anyway you can release an update or
an updated version whenever sometimes
you just have to say I'm done with this
I'm going to go ahead so slide please
remember these things audience purpose
and vehicle write your introduction last
right big be detailed be specific and
please do not plagiarize reference your
sources so the next slide is questions I
am actually developing blog to go with
this talk and you can find it at commas
kill blog spot.com I just put up the
first post yesterday you're going to
have more information and I'm on Twitter
which I'll tell you about the the blogs
as I posted if you're interested in that
kind of thing so that was it
[Applause]
you