thanks for the introduction and I'll be
speaking about a new public key
cryptosystem via merci numbers this is
joint work with Ando and you and upon
Prakash and me close Santa okay so so we
started trading public key crypto back
in 1976 starting with the breakthrough
result of defeating Hellman and there
were several candidates over over these
four decades let's say about but more
recently the focus has shifted a little
bit to more advanced primitives and
although maybe public key crypto was a
very important object of study maybe
maybe in seventies or eighties so I mean
this is evident from the fact that for a
lack of company this this dog was put in
a section titled various topics in this
work we'll be proposing a new public key
cryptosystem that we believe is probably
simpler than what was already known and
we also believe that it is secure
against quantum quantum attacks and ok
so so this crypto system can be
classified in this family what we called
the ring and noise family so there you
have a certain ring I mean the key
generation algorithm starts with a
certain ring does some operation then
adds probably some small noise so a lot
of crypto systems can be classified in
in this class for example the NT reo
crypto system code base crypto systems
of learning where there are space
creeper systems so many of them but we
are talking about a different ring here
so the ring that we'll be talking about
is the ring of integers modulo a
Mersenne prime and the noise is also
different so the noise function would be
Hamming weight modulo this prime so what
I'm all seen Prime's so these are
Prime's of the form 2 to the N minus 1
where n is also a prime so these prime
numbers were first studied by marine
mersin
who was a French mathematician and this
this is where the name comes from and he
studied them back in the 17th century
and as I mentioned the main advantage of
a cryptosystem is going to be its
simplicity so I hope I'll be able to
convince you during this stuff that it's
really simple so again so the ring would
be the ring of integers modulo the
mersin prime so the prime of the form 2
to the N minus 1 and I buy R P of X I'll
denote the representation of X in this
in this ring so it's an integer between
0 to P minus 1 and the Hamming weight of
X is the number of ones in the binary
representation of X modulo this prime so
modulo is prime this the binary
representation has n bits and Hamming
weight of X is the number of ones in
this representation so some important
properties before I get to the crypto
system there here some important
properties of arithmetic modulo Mersenne
Prime's the so would kind of justify why
we are using Mersin primes so first of
all the Hamming weight of the sum of two
in two integers X X and Y is upper
bounded by the Hamming weight of X plus
the Hamming weight of Y notice that I am
talking about integer addition and not
bitwise XOR so we cannot really conclude
this from the triangle inequality but it
is still fairly simple to to argue this
we can think of it like basically adding
strings of Hamming weight one
sequentially so inductors you can prove
this by induction and you can see as a
simple example when you add at this one
string of Hamming weight one to this
string do what you will be doing is
basically looking at the at the first
zero and so first of all you look at the
corresponding one in this position and
then you look at the first zero before
this and then you replace the 0 1 1 1 by
1 0 0 0 so the Hamming weight would
typically go down but it can it can
go up by at most one when you do this
operation because you are replacing some
t minus 1 0 t minus 1 months and 1 0 by
t minus 1 0 and 1 1 so Hamming weight is
going to not going to increase by more
than 1 so by an induction we can see
that the Hamming weight of X plus y is
Hamming is upper bounded by Hamming
weight of X plus Hamming weight of y the
second property is that when you
multiply X by a power of 2 so x times 2
to the I this is basically just a cyclic
shift of X because we are doing it
modulo 2 to the n minus 1 so so 2 to the
N is is congruent to 1 mod 2 to the n
minus 1 and so 2 to the n plus I is
congruent to 2 to the I mod 2 to the N
minus 1 so which means when you do X
times 2 to the I it's just a cyclic
shift of X so Hamming weight of X times
2 to the ice is just the Hamming weight
of X and combining these properties 1
and 2 we get the third one which is that
the Hamming weight of the product of two
strings X and Y is upper bounded by the
product of the Hamming weight of X and
the Hamming weight of Y and this is
because just product can be so product
of Hamming weight of x times y so x
times y can be just seen as X I mean
basically adding let's say the Hamming
weight of Y is some H so we are adding H
cyclic shifts of Y so sorry 8 cyclic
shifts of X and so it is so using the
producing the first property we get that
the Hamming weight of x times y is upper
bounded by Hamming weight of X times
Hamming weight of Y and the fourth
property is that when you take the
negative of X the Hamming weight just
becomes n minus Hamming weight of X to
see this notice that when you look at
the binary representation of X and the
binary representation of minus X if you
if you add them so you will get an all
one string because all one string is
just two to the n minus 1 in binary
representation so it is just 0 but 2 to
the N minus 1
so so basically minus X is just going to
be the complement of X when you look at
it as in binary representation okay so
to start with I'll give a simple
encryption scheme which is just
encrypting the string bit by bit in so
so we are going to just encrypt one bit
so so P is the prime two to the N minus
1 H is a parameter which is going to be
a bound on the Hamming weight so f and G
are two numbers mod P with few I mean
ones in the binary representation so
they have small Hamming weight and then
we take the reciprocal to take their
ratio so H is F divided by G modulo P so
the public key is going to be H and the
private key is going to be F comma G and
the hard problem that we are going to
basically base our crypto system on is
that given H it is hard to obtain F and
G notice that even though F and G have
small Hamming weight when you take the
ratio this number would typically look
very pseudo a pseudo random and you will
not be able to it would be difficult to
guess every F and F and G from it and
this is the assumption that we are going
to make that this is a hard problem okay
so here's the encryption scheme as I
said the public key is age the secret
key is G and F and G both they both
contain h at most h once in the binary
representation so - we want to encrypt a
single bit so you encrypt the bit zero
what we do is we take H we and we take
two small Hamming weight strings a and B
and we compute a times H plus B to
compute to encrypt one we do the
negation and then the decryption is
simply basically what we are going to do
is we're going to multiply G to the
ciphertext and then it's either going to
be plus a times F plus B times G or it's
going to be minus of a times F plus B
times D
and then do you what we do is we just
check the Hamming weight of this G times
C if it is small then we decrypt to 0 if
it is large then we decrypt to 1 so
here's an explanation for the sorry so -
yeah so here's the here is a tie example
so notice that when we have so if the
numbers are here written in hexadecimal
form so F and D have small Hamming
weight and when we take the ratio this
this number looks fairly random and then
the encryption again we are taking a and
B to be small Hamming weight and then
the ciphertext is this when you multiply
G so this is quite random I mean this
then you multiply G times C then you get
a low Hamming weight string so you get
that Hamming weight is small it's less
than less than half of the maximum
having weight so we conclude that the
bit that we encrypted was zero so what
is the rationale for this
what is the correctness argument when
you do T times a 8 a h plus B which is a
times F plus B times G the Hamming
weight of this by our properties that we
that we stated earlier is h times h plus
h time there it is upper bounded by two
times H square so as long as two times H
square is smaller than half of n which
means n is bigger than four times H
square we have that the Hamming weight
of this is less than n over 2 and the
Hamming weight of the negation is larger
than n over two so so this implies that
we can decrypt correctly now since since
this version basically just encrypts one
bit at a time and so it's quite low so
we want to do something a bit faster so
we now give another version which is
encrypting multiple bits at the same
time ok so I'm going to change the
public key and private key slightly so
we had H was F divided by G with which
we can rewrite as F times minus 1 over h
plus G
equal to 0 mod p so this was a
pseudorandom string we can think of it
like f times R plus G is 0 where R is
some pseudo random string that was the
public key and now we are going to have
instead of this big 0 we'll have two
random strings R and T two pseudonyms
rings R and T so which would satisfy
that T is f times R plus G mod P and R
will in fact be uniformly random all
right so so then the encryption
procedure is so we now have the public
key is R and T and the private key is F
and G so the encryption procedure we
just compute two numbers C 1 and C 2
which are a times R plus B 1 and a times
T plus B 2 where a B 1 and B 2 are again
small Hamming weight numbers and then
for encrypting a message M we use an
error correction code e so we encode the
message as G of M and then we XOR it
with C 2 so then so finally the
encryption of M is C 1 concatenated with
Z and then the decryption algorithm what
it does is it computes F times C 1 and
if we ignore this ignore this small
additional additional string then F
times C 1 basically looks like F times R
so sorry a times F times R and which is
basically a times T if we ignore the
small Hamming weight additional noise so
so what what we hope is that this error
correction code the decoding procedure
and you exhort the C 2 Prime with Z then
you should get back em I just justify
this correctness in a moment ok so here
is the analysis of decryption so C 2 was
a times T plus B 2 which is a times F
times R plus AG plus B 2 if you do the
calculation and C 2 prime is f times C 1
which is a times F times R plus B
F so when you do the Hamming weight of C
to exert C 2 prime which was basically
the error that we added to the message
in the end this is just Hamming weight
Hamming distance so this is just using
triangle inequality it's the Hamming
distance from C 2 to a times F R plus
the Hamming distance of C 2 prime with a
times F R and so just because these were
small these were strings of small
Hamming weight so we conclude that this
Hamming weight as so these two Hamming
distances are small actually you need to
do a little bit of work to show this but
it works out and then we can decode
using the decoding procedure since this
error is small so we can decode using
the decoding procedure we flip we
flipped a few bits you can decode to
recover back the message we can use
different error correction codes for
this but I mean we can since this since
these strings were chosen randomly so we
can assume this if we assume this
heuristic which we tested actually that
the error is well distributed then this
allows us to use a much simpler
repetition code so we can just repeat
every bit of the message several times
and then I mean you that that would be a
resurrection code and then just do the
majority decoding okay so now how do you
how do we get chosen side ciphertext
attack security so we want to get this
key encapsulation mechanism Bob so Bob
bond bob has Alice's public key he wants
to use this encapsulation procedure to
get a shared secret key and to send a
ciphertext to to Alice who using her
secret key D capsulated to get the
shared secret key so you want to you
want to modify this such that if there
is any active attack then so if there is
an adversary who let's say put sends its
invalid ciphertext then the D cops
decapsulation algorithm should output
bottom so this is what we want and what
we do is we start with the random seed s
and we initialize a pseudo-random
generator using s so this we can do
using a random Oracle so assuming the
random Oracle model and then we produce
pseudo-random shared secret from this
seed s and we run the basic encryption
procedure of s where we vary the the
randomness that we need for the
encryption which is a b1 b2 is also
generated from s so the procedure is
completely deterministic given the seed
s and then we output C 1 comma Z and the
decapsulation procedure it basically
runs the same decryption algorithm that
we earlier had with c1 z and then we
obtain the seed s from the decapsulation
and then then we re encapsulate from the
seed and we compare with the within
capsule with c1 z if we if we get the
same answer then we output the shared
secret that we obtained from the seed
otherwise output bottom so it I mean in
the random Oracle model we can show that
this actually achieves CCA security and
the parameters that we recommend for
this crypto system we choose n as 7 5 6
89 so this is a merge scene Prime and
the Hamming weight low Hamming weight
parameter 8 is 256 and we encode 256
bits so this is something that we
implemented actually so with 2048
repetition encoding which means that
each bit is repeated these many times ok
so to prove the security we need we need
a hardness assumption so the hardness
assumption that we are making is that
this particular problem if you look at
two uniformly random strings r1 and r2
and then you look at two low three low
Hamming weight strings a b1 and b2 then
then you look at these four strings r1
r2 a r1 plus b1 and a r2 plus b2 so
these four strings look like a uniformly
random couple so this is the assumption
that we are making what are the best
known attacks for this
well the trivial
one is we can just try to guess one of
f/4g so that takes time n choose age and
using some recent results the so this
basically appeared after our first after
the first version of our paper came went
online so this the best classical attack
runs runs in time I mean it takes time
to to the to H times something so it's
at least it's larger than 2 to the 2 H
and then so you can just use Grover's
algorithm to improve a quantum algorithm
which runs in time to to the edge under
some assumption so that's that's the
best attacks that we have so far and and
since it's it's a pretty simple scheme I
mean it's easy to understand so the hope
is that it would be easier to kind of
look at cryptanalytic attacks for this
one and maybe since it since in
particular this assumption has a little
bit of a similar flavor to lwe so maybe
attacks if you get a tax for this one
maybe that gives us some ideas for for
learning with errors and another
direction for future work is of course
again because it's it's simple maybe we
can come up with ideas to improve the
efficiency without really compromising
on the security so that's all thank you
very much
[Applause]