okay so as it was said this is a male
shark but as to talk so we are going to
present you two attacks against
obfuscated House
grunting forum of mosquitoes and as the
two talks are very similar
sorry articles share to attack the same
structure we decided with minke so I'm
to chair the Turks I'm going to do the
introduction and then we're going to do
more into the details so there is only
one torque so let's start with what is
this talk about so what you are going to
present you two attacks against some
candidate branching program when they
are built upon the G th certain
multi-layer map and so there are partial
attack in the sense that the first
attack works only for a specific set of
parameters and the second attack works
on in the quantum city so as such the
two attacks have as I stated similar
structure where we both use weaknesses
of the underlining gg8 certain media map
to construct concrete attacks against
the candidate of mosquitoes so let me
start by defining what is an obfuscation
scheme so from a functionality point of
view and a biscuit ax is simply an
efficient and efficiently computable
function transforming a circuit into an
equivalent circuit that means the
circuits that compute the same function
as a first circuit and in this circuit
will be interested in a physical for the
class of all polynomial size circuits
are all parameters branching program but
I'm going to define what it is later and
so that's for functionality of a
branching program and what are the
security requirements so the more
natural definition we would like it's
called virtual black box BBB and it
basically require that your pisghetti
program should reveal nothing about the
initial circuit except its input-output
behavior so we want the obfuscated
program to act as a black box the
program that
it has been shown to be impossible to
achieve so that's a result of barakato
in 2001 and so in the same article they
also proposed a new security definition
which is called indistinguishability
application and so this definition just
require that for any two equivalent
circuits so circuits that compute the
same function we want that the
obfuscated version of the two circuits
are computationally indistinguishable so
all the obfuscator are going to describe
in this circuit in this candidate
indistinguishability of mosquitoes so
this second definition may seem a bit a
bit strange because what we really want
is that the obfuscated program hides the
circuits but it still has a lot of
application to cryptographic
constructions so functional encryption
for instance but also a lot of other
applications okay so the fact is that
almost all candidate obfuscators we
currently have relied on cryptographic
limit in our maps and we have a mystery
main candidate cryptographic in our maps
which are DG 8 13 13 and GD age 15 the
problem is that all this reckoned with
as much in a map i've been shown to
suffer from weaknesses basically because
of the encoding of zeros and so these
witnesses of the melting amethyst does
not directly implies attack
interpreters using it but still so all
the attacks we have uncounted eight of
the skaters realize and the weaknesses
of the media maps and so in this talk we
are going to use weaknesses of the G th
certain map to attack the obfuscated
also we will consider only a biscuit are
built upon to DJ certain map
okay so let me give you a bit of history
of obfuscators candidate branching
program officiator and some attacks so
in this history we focus on branching
program appreciators so there are other
candidate of mosquitoes which are not
venturing program ones but we will focus
in this torque interpreting program of
mosquitoes so the first candidate of
this Gator was proposed in 2013 and it
was a branching program of mosquito but
so it also candidates we have no
security proof and this one so didn't
have any any security proof so after
this candidate was proposed other
candidates have been proposed also lot
this is not exhaustive I don't think so
but they try to prove security of this
Gator in some idealized model so where
the underlying multi Namib is supposed
to be somehow either so in 2013 there
was a first attack against so old you're
please get off previously mansion except
the first one so by mile science in 1916
in 2016 sorry
so which relied on the fact that the G
th map was not ideal so they were able
to attack home to visitors except the
processor so after all this attack was
proposed a new candidate had been
proposed in a weaker model so this model
captures the attack and so we cannot
extend the attack to attack this new
applicator and so more recently there
was a new attack by change and healthy
and the first candidate obfuscator which
works only for specific type of inputs
and there was concern with your proposed
a bit later to try to prevent this
attack okay so let me sum this up in a
big table so the first two lines of the
tables are the two attacks I already man
so in this table we also mentioned some
circuits obfuscator but we are not going
to speak of them later in the talk and
so what we are going to describe you are
the two last lines of the table the two
attacks in the last lines so the first
attack works against all branching
program of mosquitoes in particular it
works for GM m plus of guitar which was
not attacked previously but it works
only in a specific regime of parameters
and several attack works only for the
more recent branching program of his
guitars and for surface guitars but
again it's an e in the quantum city okay
so that's what we are going to describe
in this talk so in order to describe the
to attack let me first describe so give
you a simplified explanation of how is
the obfuscated artwork so we are going
to focus on the branching program of
mosquitoes and they are very similar in
structure so I'm going to define a very
simple of mosquitoes which captures so
not all of the branching program
officials but a more recent one and then
he is going to describe you how the
attack works and this simple fiscal talk
ok so because we are going to speak of
branching programming theater let me
first define what is a branching program
so it's simply a way of representing and
computing a function and so how does it
work
we we have a collection of matrices so
let me show you in the example so a
branching program consists of a
collection of 2l mattresses so in my
example L is 6 we have also two vectors
a0 and a7 and we have an input selection
function which
which goes so the invitation function
goes from one six so six is the number
of pairs of matrices in the branching
program in two one three or three bits
length of the input and so how do we
evaluate so let me show you a we
evaluate sorry the branching program and
this input X so we're going to multiply
the matrices and pick only one matrix
Baccarin so do we choose it we first
pick a zero because there is no choice
then for the first column we will look
at the input selection function of 1
which is 1 so we are going to look at
the first bit effects it's zero so we
are going to pick the matrix with a zero
yeah so this is one we look at the first
bit and we do the same for the second
current so in of two is one again so we
look at the first bit effects it's still
zero so we pick the matrix with a zero
for the third one it's a one so we pick
the matrix with the one exit rights at
all and so we multiply all these
matrices and we obtain something which
is either 0 in which case we says it's
your put of the branching program is 0
or 1
no sorry none zero and in which case we
say that I put of the branching program
is 1 so this is it for branching program
so let me give you a brief definition of
what is a cryptographic module in our
map so cryptographic mutant our map is
indexed but is so there is some
parameter Kappa which will denote the
maximum level of them reading and so we
will have encoding with levels from 0 to
Kappa and we want three public
procedures to be available and these
ingredients we want to be able to add to
encode things at the same level and get
an encoding of the Sun at the same level
we want to be able to multiply through
on cuttings
get an inkling of the product but whose
level is the sum of the two level so
when we multiply we add the levels and
when we add we keep the same level and
finally we want a public zero test
procedure so we want to be able to
determine without including at the
maximum level isn't including of zero
element so that's what it's a
functionality we would like ferment in
our map and mean he's going to describe
better how does the gdh map achieve this
functionality but we just need that so
now I can define I can present you the
simple obfuscator so how does it work it
takes as input a branching program then
the first type the first step sorry will
be to randomize the branching program so
there is three main procedures to do
that the first one is adding diagonal
block to the matrices but we put a block
of zeros here so when we multiply
everything is a big blocks gets canceled
out and so it's just the a block that
remains the second randomization
technique is multiplying by random
matrices but in such a way that when we
multiply something so one will become
self by r1 minus 1 R 2 by R minus 1 etc
and so at the end we still get a product
of the a matrices and finally the last
possibilities is to multiply everything
by random scales because at the end we
only need to check whether something is
zero or nonzero so if we multiply by
random nonzero scoffs there is no
problem so you have these three
randomization techniques you can pick
any subset of them and you will get
different of the scales but basically
all GOP skaters the branching program of
the skaters use some subset of this
randomization techniques and then we
just anchored all so sorry so we get
18-day which has a randomized matrices
and we just anchored them using multi
namib and so because it's emily a map we
can multiply the encoding we get an
encoding at maximum libel and we can
test whether it's zero on it so that's
this encoding is out the output of the
launching photo of the obfuscated
obfuscator so is that the obfuscated
planting program so that's all for the
definition of the simple skater so I
hope it's clear and so now Mickey is
going to give you more details about the
attacks
Thank You Alyssa now
we received on gg starting working
immediately and then talk about the
contributions details and limits GG
certain mode remap usually defined on
the Linga text over X to the n plus 1
for a pulp to ensure N and it takes the
plain text paste P which is the quote
out over the ideology for all small and
elements G in her here small means that
she is every every coefficient of G
sufficiently small and it's it's it's
it's that work our work its including
spaces IQ which is equal to R / qi for a
large integer kill and usually like
express acute to denote the leper the
representative of x in r q2 initial CJ
certain martini ahmet vicious
temperature tenets which have a happy
disguise of q and on encoding of a at
level is defined by a plus RG over said
to the I here R is also small element
inner in the Ling are then is that it it
is easy to verify that that it is
satisfies the addition and
multiplication condition of the Virginia
map and to check the sir testing issue
define a thorough testing parameter
which is equal to some failure and the
despite the following property for some
level including yield to product of you
enter testing parameter
modulus q is small 10 the time level
including is indeed including of zero
now we are ready to see the
contributions let's begin with only
present the praising the main idea
postal bar what explains the don't make
missus no Gigi's dirty martini
into the concrete or text for the
opposition cases more concretely the
first attacks of the spy tongue Kim Lee
and me used our intro tech previously
for the suggested parameter of CJ 13 the
underlying entry problem is solvable in
polynomial time using Excel filter text
but this enter uptick is nothing to a
concrete or type of GG 13 in this work
we show that using intracerebral
printing program of post occasions over
GG 13 can be broken in polynomial time
and the second attack so this pi
alehsalaam re-used are short which the
provider program purple which known to
learn in contemporary time in other word
she showed that many obfuscation and
circuit of post occasions can be broken
in contemporary time now we will see in
detail let's consider tool everyone
including a 1 over G and 800 G then by
dividing them we can obtain a 1 over a 2
which is done entering instance then
thanks to this table field optic we can
obtain a GI even and she too in dalinar
murabba for the other including a 3 over
G we can compute she a tree in the Ling
are in some are stick back our estimate
respectively then combining this we can
obtain some kind of simultaneous entry
server that is forgiving many including
a re obereg' you can obtain Shi AI in
the Ling are simultaneously and in other
words for keeping including of matrix a
we can obtain or another form of
including obey yes
the thing is every element we obtain
these are in the lingaiah
rather than on cue in other word we help
the modular skill now we will see the
attack we take a novice cated program
Opie and a prime plane program Q as on
input and the purpose of the attack is
distinguish whether PS q or not note
that it is not least to prep the
indistinguishability of the Opposition
then for each given pension program
mattress test host Katie reading program
as matrices mr. blanton problem
simultaneously then we obtain we obtain
our new matrices which are all in the
Ling R and it is also of the form of
branching program and let's consider the
evaluation of the pension program for
the plane broke when playing program
output 0 then opposite Katie's program
Alice tomliboo encoding op 0 of the from
our geo budget to the kappa and in I
program it is correspond to multi probe
G by some computations in other in other
word we can come many multi probe G
using the evaluation of printing
programs then by collecting this using
homie number form we can recover the
ideology and then compute the she ate
here the modulus G notice a till the
modulus G to not contain randomness our
and the by parameter Z and the modulus
kill broker we can remove the effect of
skull Evangeline seen it is the team but
we omit this in detail because it is
case by case study and is not complex
then we can learn the mix team to detect
next team to the tag is the distinct
issue not take on printing programs or
obfuscated brainsick program using
invalid inputs
let's see the example consider on in
function with output 1 1
- and to functionally equivalent
printing program for a pellet in put
these two printing program should output
the same value however consider it is
invalid input indices 0 1 1 it is
invalid because first two indices are
not equal which is which violate
constraint from the input function so
for this invalid input disturbance even
program may have different value say a
output 0 whereas B ops nonzero so we can
distinguish a MP by evaluating these
invalid inputs in fact this is not
permitted in the post gated mode because
many randomizing values such as color
bond links but we have removed many
randoms so we can learn this and another
in fact we in the paper we have done the
matrix theorizing or take later than
fixed input optic which is the
generalization of mixed in protect this
used the sum of many valuations letter
the name but one invalid inputs what we
skip it here now let's see the second
object for every evaluation of output
evaluation with output 0 it is
correspond we always complete the tamna
encoding of 0 product through testing
parameter mode rescue and it is a value
correspond to probate in the Ling are
then by collecting this many values many
multi probates we can compute a step in
condom polina with quantum polynomial
time using short Princip write your
problem server and then using this we
can manipulate some kind of double 0
testing at level 2 kappa using this
period in other word we have reckon long
- couple of alpha skated program the
second step is the mixed team project
however for the hopper a very mixed
Infotech
for disability input it is not permitted
because we do nothing about the lambda
misers though it is fluid down instead
we construct the two couple I've ever
post gated program by the application
door or is in every one and then for
statistical to be choosen invalid input
which output some kind of w0 we can
learn the mixed in with object and then
attack is done now let's see the table
showing the lizards in the first attack
we show that in the interest of a
parameter let him or eventing program of
post Gators are vulnerable to enter
attack and in the second attack many of
us occasions over GG 13 is not secure in
the Kanto Mart this table lays two
natural questions at first how about the
first occasion JYJ's RSW
in the quantum world and how about the
circuit obfuscation for entropy and
through a circular metal is it actually
we have made many progress tests in this
regard why we are preparing the
presentation for the first obfuscation
GTRs w it is broken in Kanto mode by
combining our work in other word at
first manipulating double zero testing
and then lambda matrix terrorizing
attack and for the circuit of
ossification in enter observable
parameterizing
many has the thermal circuit of post
occasion is broken using into attack now
we leave open problems and Damac our
take heavily rely on the time level
including of zero store however a basic
function to not output values so we do
not know how to take special occasion
for evasive functions
and we are really curious about the
contem assist for the critical tech it
is easy to prevent by increasing the
dimension n to prevent antibiotic
however for the quantum otech we do not
know how to prevent it and we guess that
it is very hard to modify the CG certain
to prevent a condom or take a test we
give all important implication of the
work many schemes especially listen to
post occasions that are proven in their
security in the idealized model or
somewhat weaker border what the earlier
construction heavily rely on the
concrete concrete other schemes or mere
candidates however these candidates may
not fit in the idealized model or
accommodate in fact this work we show
that this cap can cause a significant
weakness of the concrete games in other
word we should focus we should pay
attention on this gap if the concrete
schemes concrete schemes are proven
interior security in only in the
idealized model thank you for your
attention
[Applause]