so thank you very much introduction so I
mean you're scared Toto from NTT such a
platform laboratories so I'd like to
talk about first correlation that they
visited so this is a joint work with
Takanori soba within a year kata
Milwaukee and Pynchon okay so first of
all this is our bubble you my talk so my
talk is about fast correlation attack
which is around the most traditional
crypt analysis techniques against the
symmetric key cipher so the ancient idea
was proposed that in 1985 and more
advanced attack strategy was proposed at
1989 so I think first correlation
attacker is among the most oldest crypt
analysis techniques against the schmidt
wiki server so now so we limited the
first correlation attack and the way
proposed a new property long key
hypothesis and a new attack framework so
our new idea exploits our new idea is
very powerful and there are many linear
approach made representations so in
other words our attack is a so-called
much probably near first collision
attack and finally we applied this
technique to modern stream cipher family
grain family and especially to the grain
boy one at grain one to eight a
successful in stand station grain family
and grain boy one was one of the ìiî in
portfolio and one to eight a was
standardized by iso/iec and our new
attack framework can break them or
faster than the exhaustive search okay
so let's start talk so first of all I
need to explain error FS are based
stream ciphers because potential target
of the first correlation attack is lfsr
based stream cipher so first so this is
internal state of the lfsr and the
secret key and in your initialization
vectors they loaded to the internal
state at lfsr and
this state is a secret then so this
state is updated by linearly by using
the linear feedback polynomial F and
also it outputs a T so if we use a T as
key stream directory it unfortunately
such sci-fi as insecure because the key
stream is highly T stream is perfectly
linear it computed from the internal
states so if we can if we use for
example BarCamp massey algorithm so we
can easily recover the internal states
from the key stream seekers
so error sequence et is very important
so by exerting ET with a T and so DT is
also set u becomes a security stream
seekers but of course now we need to
discuss a symmetric key cipher so we
can't choose ET from purely London so in
modern stream cipher so we additionally
prepares us another state and this state
is updated by non linearly involving the
array vessel state and IRA sequences so
outputs from the non another so now we
want to attack this cipher by using
correlation attack
so but the assumption so we assumes that
the probability of e T is equal to 0
minus probability of ET equal 1 is C so
if this cipher is purely secure against
lfsr so sorry it's secure against first
correlation attack so this C must be 0
but now so we assume C is further from 0
then so we first get initial state s T 0
and compute a T if we guess correct s T
0 then a T plus DT coincides with ET so
next we complete this part so if we get
correct key so this body follows this
normal distribution but otherwise
so it follows this normal distribution
of course the the means that difference
so that we can distinguish the correct
key and incorrect key but of course the
conventional attack is very famous
attack so family design so modern stream
cipher so ET is not biased usually but
sometimes we can observe a high bias
relationship for example so we we use
the sum of DT plus i from optimally
choosing the set T see the ends of the
we can observe the highly biased
relationship with the internal stage for
example the case of grain Brazil so the
FSC 2006 so bar being broke the grain
Boozer off which was initial version
great problem by using the correlation
attack so in this attack so they use is
that T Z is equal to 0 and AD so from
now so that I want to explain the
procedural phosphorylation back so this
attack consists of three parts the first
part is a generating party tape
equations and second part is the reduce
the size of secret bits and finally D
covers a involve the secret bits okay so
this is a high-level view of area
through cell based stream cipher so at
St and BT internal state at time T who
lfsr linear state and nonlinear States
respectively then st plus 1 is generated
by multiplying with G and the BT plus 1
is generated from st and bt by applying
with nonlinear function G and this
function also generates the keystream G
cos K T so now we first find the high
bias linear trade so this idea is almost
the same as linear cryptanalysis against
block ciphers so the first up rise at 0
mask for a bt and zero mask for BT plus
81 and we find high bias linear mask
lambda so and the display
the correlation with destroyer is highly
biased so in that case we have this
linear approximately presentations so
the most important part is to find high
bias to linear must grab the I so once
we can find this really this
approximation so first st plus I is
generated from SP by linearly so we can
compute the gamma satisfying these
equations mobile SP is also generated
from zero linearly so we can change this
part to like this so as the inner
product this body is a chance to this
inner product so finally we get these
linear approximations so now so that we
updated T and we can correct many dis
linear approximations and by using this
many these many approximations we
recover the secret key Estero
so original linear approximations is
like this so if we want to recover for s
0 by using this approximations we need
to get a bit SL so if the n is greater
than or equal to secret key level a
secret secret key sites so this attack
is always was always so larger than
exhaust such so first we deduce sides of
secret involved bits by solving partial
busted product problem so for example we
focus these two vectors and XO as a
result this last Elvises are always 0
and their so by from this n big n and
chapter and n bit vectors we generate
this new matrix so then so we so instead
of 2 instead of evaluating these
approximations we use these
approximations so
in that case so that we don't need to
guess the last bits of the s0 so that so
only two to the N minus L time
complexity is enough to about it dis
approximations so finally we evaluate
these values and liquor by s 0 such that
this body is farthest from this body so
if we use the tabular precision the time
complexity is like this but by using
fastball chatham are transformed so the
time complexity is reduced to this
dis complexity so after the Khobar you
pasteurize 0 so we can recover so for SL
and and then b0 step by step and finally
the secret key is recovered but this
procedure has drawback so because the
correlation drops because of the pasta
products problem so let's see these
original correlations so but by exerting
two vectors the correlations drops to
the city square so until in other
results the love estimation required
data complexity is order 1 over C 2 to
the phone
so in that case even if we can find
linear approximations with correlation
to 2 to the minus 50 that required data
is about 2 to the 200 so if the security
level is a 128-bit
so it is a even if we can find such
linear approximations
it is a mini-dress ok so from now I
propose a new insight of phosphorylation
tuck so in the first polarization attack
sort of we compute this this approach
missions and this matrix multiplications
and s is a secret and n bit low vector
and the G to the T is n times and binary
matrix and gamma is the optimally chosen
the linear mask okay so first we focus
on these multiplications and there we
propose so special we propose there a
special structure
this much in multiplications so first of
all let's go set a finite field GF 2 to
the N where the primitive polynomial is
the feedback polynomial of lfsr and
alpha is the primitive root and gamma
over GF 2 to the n is natural combustion
from the N bit vector come then we know
G 2 to the T times gamma over the binary
matrix its natural conversion of alpha
to the T gamma over GF 2 to the n so in
such case of course does a
multiplication over GF 2 to the N is
commutative so that we can extend the
order so the G to the T times gamma goes
to alpha to the T gamma is equivalent
with gamma alpha to the T and then so we
combat this matrix this multiplication
over GF 2 the end to the matrix
multiplication corresponding matrix
multiplication so this is the summary of
transformation so originally we compute
G to the T times gamma but instead of
this evaluation we about it we evaluate
this multiplication where alpha T to the
T is the same alpha to the T is the same
as the first column of G to the T and
this first column is the same as the
gamma and gamma is generated like this
so the first column is the gamma and the
second column is gamma alpha and gamma
alpha to the t bra bra bra so that we
can generate sell this binary matrix so
in if we use this technique so we know G
to the T times gamma is a commutative so
we can change this linear approximations
in to this linear approximations so now
we notice one fact
so if parity check equations that
generate it from alpha to the T instead
of G to the T times gamma then if
attackers gets s times M gamma
instead of s the approximations above
halls with high probability and now
assuming they are may there are many
high bias linear
like this so all of them are highly
biased so in this procedure we have
multiple biased solutions so now we want
to exploit this fact okay so the
originally s prime is s high bias but a
new fast correlation tag so s prime is
SM Gamma high biased so now this is a
procedure of our new algorithm so first
we generate parity checker equations by
using alpha to the T by correcting the
enemy chapter and which key stream key
stream so the time complexity is n so
next we pick top NP s prime whose
empirical bias it's high but of course
to Abadi at it so we need so we need to
get n bit s prime so the time complexity
is the energy to the end even for
yourself a small Chatham our transform
but now we exploit we use we exploit
many high bias solutions high biased
origins so country we have M high bias
solutions so in that case even if we
only about it s prime whose LSB is
always 0 so we should find a mobotu high
bias as primal average so in general so
if beta bits are bypassed so we can
reduce the time complexity for fhw t
from energy to the end to n minus beta
times 2 to the N minus better so now we
bypass beta bits so this time complexity
is registered to write this and finally
so we apply M mu gamma I inverse for NP
liquid solutions the time complexity is
the NP times n so the second step so to
estimate the success probability so we
use normal distribution for the second
step and Poisson distributions for the
subject so this is the example problem
so the area the size of area vessel is
24 and assuming we have the correlation
with two to the minus ten point four
five four one five and assuming we have
two to the ten linear high bias to
linear masks and now we bypass fiber bit
in the first world shadow mode transform
then we first correct to the twenty
three point two five bits and a body to
this value so if s prime is s times M
gamma I so this value for all these
normal distributions otherwise so this
value for this London case so this
random normal distributions so now we
introduce a threshold here so this is
the two to the twelve point six eight so
and the we pick s prime whose empirical
correlations is greater than this side
greater than two thirds and pick the
solution at the number pickle solutions
is the 2 2013 2 8 and after that we
applied to to the 10 high bias linear
masks and so we recover the secret key
so finally so removing the M gamma so as
a quick key for all the distal at the
number of appearance in the appearance
of the correct key for all the poor
disposal distributions but in correct
key so it follows this Poisson
distribution so now I implemented this
attack to the toy grain cipher and it's
a plots of the experimental result so as
a result our experiments almost four
hours early and in this case if we use
the threshold 9 so the correct key is
always distinguished with imports keys
ok so finally so we apply this technique
to grain family so
our new idea is powerful and there are
many high biased linear approximations
so if so the importance is so grain like
ciphers has many high bias to linear
masks so this is a structure of grain
and that this bit is the keystream
sequence and the keystream is generated
from the boolean function H and this is
example of grain bibim so H is a boolean
function from five bit inputs to one
bitch output and H is a boolean function
like this so if we use linear mask 0 0 0
1 1 dense of the correlations of minus 2
to the minus 2 and if we use 0 0 1 1
well for example the hype the
corresponding correlation the 2 to the
minus 2 so in this example so we know 2
to the full so 2 to the full potential
there to do the full potential linear
masks with highly high with high
correlations and each input linear mask
derives different linear approximations
so in the case of grain b1 moreover the
some herbs that teacheth keystream bits
is used and in the case of grain b1
which is e is reckless
so the potential number ba polish
missions it's a 2 to the 4 times 10 and
the treats of 40 different linear
approximations but of course so that
this is rough estimation so the India we
need more complicated evaluations so
actually it is a very difficult to
explain it in this short time so the
police be that wallpaper in detail ok so
that this is the conclusion and the open
question so this is a summary of our
attack
so for examples the green one to eight a
we can find to that twenty six point
five eight linear approximations with
correlation is write this so in this
parameter we can attack
this team with time complexity to the
150 point four so features are faster
than to the 128 so bets we have big open
questions so yeah actually we can break
the grain 128 a but target is only grain
128 a wizards authentication mode so if
authentication mode is enabled so all
the even croc outputs are used at key 3
and the other clock output is used to
generate a tag in that case of the
attacker cannot observe the odd clock
output in the heuristic assumption so it
is a very difficult to generate high
biased linear approximations so average
entry so that we cannot break a grain
112 is with also education more
authentication so it is so so it is an
open question to break grain 1/2 edge a
with authentication mode thank you very
much
[Applause]