thank you I'll talk about
non-interactive zero-knowledge proves
for composite statements this is joint
work with Shashank arrival and payment
mahadji zero knowledge proof spre vide a
powerful tool that allows approver to
convince a verifier that a statement is
true without revealing any further
information zero knowledge proof
satisfies the following two properties
soundness which means that a cheating
prover cannot convince a verifier of a
statement that is false and the property
of zero knowledge which means that a
cheating verifier cannot learn anything
more than the validity of the statement
itself it is known that all languages in
NP have a zero knowledge proof system
but it remains challenging to design
proof systems that are efficient enough
to be implemented in practice so if we
look at the state-of-the-art and zero
knowledge today we have Sigma protocols
that are efficient in terms of proof
size and publicly operations for both
the prover and the verifier and they do
not rely on any setup assumptions but
they apply only to a restricted set of
languages like proving knowledge of
discrete logarithm of a public value or
roots or polynomial relationships among
committed values and so on then there
are approaches that are based on garbled
circuits and MPC in the head this line
of work is very efficient for the prover
requiring only a few symmetric key
operations per gate in the circuit but
unfortunately they lead to large proofs
and the system based on garbled circuit
also leads to a proved system that is
interactive and then we have succinct
non interactive arguments of knowledge
also called snarks or they allow for
very short proofs and efficient
verification but they rely on a trusted
setup and they also require approval
public key operations per gate in the
circuit so now we have very different
techniques to prove different kinds of
statements if we want to prove an
algebraic statement like knowledge of a
discrete logarithm of a public value Y
Sigma protocols are really efficient on
the other hand if we want to prove a non
algebraic statement that's represented
as a circuit for instance knowledge of
preimage of a hash function like sha
then the garbled circuit approach or the
snark approach is more efficient than
Sigma protocols so the question is how
do we prove a statement
that is a combination of an algebraic
component and a non algebraic component
we call such statements composite
statements and ask how to efficiently
prove such composite statements such
statements frequently arise in practice
and for the purposes of this talk we
look at privacy-preserving audits and
cryptocurrencies as a motivating
application so we have the Bitcoin
network here and most Bitcoin users
prefer to store their assets on an
exchange like coinbase which provides
services like online banking with
account management and so on while this
is very convenient this also leaves the
users vulnerable to loss of their assets
in case the exchange loses bitcoins due
to fault or fraud a famously mount GOx
which was one of the largest exchanges a
few years ago and handled about 70% of
all Bitcoin transactions filed for
bankruptcy but only after losing for
fifty million dollars in client money so
the goal here is it is desirable to have
exchanges prove that they are solvent
and what does it mean to be solvent it
means that the exchange controls enough
assets to clear each of its customers
balances and this is easy to do if it is
public what bitcoin addresses and
exchange controls and a list of its
customers along with their corresponding
balances one can publicly compute the
total assets of the exchange and the
total liabilities and check that the
total assets is at least as much of as
the total liabilities and therefore the
exchanges indeed solvent but this is of
course not private it reveals both the
total holdings of the exchange itself
and the holdings of each of its
customers so the question is can we have
an exchange prove that it is solvent
while preserving privacy of the exchange
and its customers the state of the art
in our privacy preserving proof of
solvency is a system called prohibitions
that was proposed a couple of years ago
which is based on Sigma protocol proofs
but unfortunately it doesn't work for
Bitcoin because of the following reason
if we look at Bitcoin addresses they are
of the form H which is hash of Y where Y
is G to the
for a secret P X and H is a
cryptographic hash function so if we
look at the statement that we want to
prove for a proof of solvency it
involves proving knowledge of X and Y
such that Y is G to the X and hash of Y
is H for a public edge now notice that
this involves a non algebraic component
which is the hash function here and an
algebraic component which is the
exponentiation here so we have a
composite statement and because
provisions is based on Sigma protocol
proofs it does not really work with
Bitcoin hash addresses of this form so
how do we prove such a composite
statement in principle one could use
Sigma protocols to even prove a non
algebraic statement represented as a
circuit by writing out each gate as an
algebraic relation between the input and
the output wires and using Sigma
protocols to prove such a relation but
that don't mean the prover
exponentiation and the proof size grows
with the size of the circuit and it
becomes prohibitively expensive for
large circuits like a hash function on
the other hand we could also prove
algebraic statements by writing it out
as a circuit and using circuit based
proofs like snarks but this would mean
that we have to represent group
operations as a circuit and this would
blow up the size of the circuit for
instance exponentiation requires cubic
size for n where n is the bit size of
the modulus so what we ideally want to
do is to use Sigma protocols for the
algebraic part of the statement and
snark for the non algebraic part of the
statement can we simply combine two
different protocols one for the
algebraic part and one for the non
algebraic part if we do that a cheating
prove our could simply use two different
witnesses in the two different protocols
without having a single valid witness
for the entire combination statement so
such a live combination does not work
and one of the challenges we face when
dealing with composite statements is to
be able to bind the values that the
prover uses in the Sigma protocol with
the input that he uses in the snark
proof and we want to be able to do this
without having to prove large circuit
statements using Sigma protocols
without having to represent group
operations as circuits so we study how
to prove composite statements
efficiently and show the following we
give constructions for snark on
algebraically committed input and output
and then we give constructions of Sigma
protocols on committed output then we
show how to use these two building
blocks to prove composite statements
that arbitrarily compose algebraic and
arithmetic representations of functions
for instance a composite function like
this where each if I could have an
arithmetic or an algebraic
representation and have shared secret
inputs I'll begin by talking about snark
construction on algebraically committed
input and output our starting point is
the snark construction based on a
quadratic arithmetic program
representation of an arithmetic circuit
I will give a very high-level overview
of a quadratic arithmetic program so we
have a circuit with addition and
multiplication gates over a field and a
quadratic arithmetic program encodes
this computation in the following way
we pick a distinct root RG for each
multiplicative gate in the circuit and
define a polynomial that is called the
target polynomial to have roots at each
of these chosen RG and now to encode the
values on the wires we define sets of
polynomials V W and Y where the
high-level idea is that the we set
handles the left input of a gate so we
define V I of RG to be 1 if the iith
wire is the left input of the gate and
the W set of polynomials handles the
right input to forget so WI at RG is 1
if the eyuth wire is the right input of
a gate and 0 otherwise and the Y
polynomials handle the output of the
gate so why I of RG is 1 if the eyuth
wire is the output wire and 0 otherwise
so to illustrate this if I label the
input and output wires of the gain G
here as 1 2 & 3 we see that V 1 of RJ is
1 because 1 is the left input of the
gain G and we do and V 3 of RG will be 0
W 2 of RG is 1 because 2 is the right
input wire of the gain G + y 3 of our
is one so now the quadratic arithmetic
program itself consists of these sets of
polynomials and the target polynomial
and it is said to compute the circuit F
if the following condition holds a 1 to
a n and a k2 am is a valid assignment of
the input and output variables of F if
and only if there exists intermediate
values of a that is a n plus 1 to a k
minus 1 such that the target polynomial
divides this polynomial expression P
this polynomial P is is a linear
combination of the V polynomials and the
W polynomials minus the linear
combination of the Y polynomials so at a
very high level why does this
divisibility condition encode this
computation if we look at the
divisibility it means that at every root
our G of the target polynomial T the
polynomial P is 0 and that gives us this
equality and at a particular gate G at
root RG this equality basically gives us
the gate equation because of the way we
have defined the V and W polynomials so
the divisibility check handles all the
gate equations in parallel now to
construct a snark from a quadratic
arithmetic program representation of a
circuit the high-level idea is to encode
the polynomials of the qap in the CRS
and this is done by evaluating each of
these polynomials at a secret point in
the field and encoding it by
exponentiating within a bilinear group
so I show it here only for the V
polynomials but this is done for W and Y
polynomials as well and now the prover
uses the witness to compute the values
on the wires the AIS and now are using
VC RS and the AI values he can compute
the encoding of the four polynomials
here so the V polynomial is a linear
combination of the VI polynomials where
the coefficients are the wire values
that he obtained W&Y polynomials are
defined in a similar way with the same
coefficients AI H is the quotient
polynomial with respect to T
well tea is the target polynomial of the
quadratic arithmetic program and now the
divisibility check of the qap can
proceed using the bilinear map so this
verification equation here tests for the
divisibility now to construct a snark on
committed input we begin with the QA P
based snark and then separate the
circuit wires into committed input and
intermediate values so we have a
distinct CRS and proof elements
corresponding to them recall that in a
QA p based not the prover computes the
encoding of these four polynomials like
we just saw
and now the prover computes the encoding
of two different polynomials we come and
we met where we define we come to be a
linear combination of the VI polynomials
but only for those via values that
correspond to the committed input and
the V mid polynomial is a linear
combination of the VI polynomial but
only for those indices of wires that
correspond to the intermediate values so
this separation of wires does not
interfere with the divisibility check
which can still proceed using the
bilinear map and after adding additional
checks to ensure that the same
coefficient is used in all the linear
combinations and certain additional
elements in the crs we can show that
this is still a good snark so why did
the separation of circuit wires help us
we now notice that the new proof element
which is the encoding of the weakened
polynomial looks like an algebraic
commitment if we rewrite this proof
element it has a I the values on the
circuit wires in the exponent where the
base is the encoding of the VI
polynomial and is already a part of the
crs so now the prover uses a standard
Sigma protocol proof to prove knowledge
of AIS and show equality between the
exponent here and a value inside an
algebraic commitment so this proof binds
the value out inside a commitment and
the input that the prover uses inside
the snark we use similar techniques to
achieve snark on committed output as
well where we now separate the output
wires and have distinct proof element
corresponding to the output
menus and an additional Sigma protocol
proof like this to prove equality of a
committed value and the exponent in the
snart proof here I'll now talk about our
Sigma protocol constructions uncommitted
output I'll begin with a simple
situation where our algebraic function
has a 1 bit output so the function is f
of X y equal to B where X is a secret
value and B is a bit and Y is public and
now the statement we want to prove looks
like the following we want to prove f of
X y equal to B where C is a public
commitment to X and D is a public
commitment to be our construction is
simple using the Sigma protocol for the
algebraic function f we prove that f of
X Y is 1 and the commitment inside D is
1 or the commitment inside D is 0 and to
prove this statement we use the standard
Sigma protocol or transform that allows
one to prove that either X naught is in
L or X 1 is in L but without revealing
which X I now in general when our
algebraic function has a group element
as the output the statement we want to
prove looks like this where we want to
prove knowledge of many x i's and Y such
that Y is a product of G I to be some
polynomial in the x i's in the simplest
case we only have one input and this
statement reduces to proving knowledge
of x and y where y is G to the X given
commitment to X and commitment to y so
this is the discrete logarithm proof and
there are techniques known in literature
that work for integer groups so we show
how to do the double discrete logarithm
proof in an elliptic curve group and our
starting point is the proof of point
addition for elliptic curve points the
point addition relation is specified by
an equation that is specific to a curve
for instance for the Bitcoin curve given
points P and Q the point addition
relation is specified by the following
equations for distinct P and Q and when
P equal to Q to specified by a double
formula in general we can think of
polynomials and
are in the coordinates of the point that
specify the point addition relation so
can we use Sigma protocols uncommitted
coordinates to prove these polynomial
relationships so that is the general
idea but one issue is the following the
point addition computation is over ft
where the coordinates of the points live
and therefore the commitments have to be
in a group of order T which is not
necessarily the same as the order of the
elliptic curve group so we get around
this issue by working in two different
groups G 1 and G 2 where G 1 is the
elliptical group of order P and G 2 has
order that is large enough to prevent
wraparound in the point addition
computation so now we come in to
coordinates and the intermediate values
in the computation in the second group G
2 and prove the polynomial relationship
among committed coordinates now to
translate this equality 2 modulo T we
use division with remainder along with
range proofs and this proves the
polynomial relationship of the point
addition relation over FD finally to put
things together we again use the Sigma
protocol or transform and prove the
following statement that either P and Q
are distinct and the ad formula holds or
P is equal to Q and the double formula
holds our P is minus Q and T is zero and
this proves the point addition relation
now we use the point addition proof or
to give a double discrete logarithm
proof in elliptical groups so recall the
goal is to prove or T is P to the lambda
where we are given commitments to T and
commitment to lambda the prover begins
by choosing a random alpha from the
field computes QSB to the Alpha and
sends commitments to both alpha and the
point Q and now the verifier chooses a
challenge bit
if the challenge bit is 0 the prover
reveals alpha if it is 1 he reveals the
difference between alpha and lambda
along with the proof that P to the Z is
QT inverse the verifier checks that the
commitments are well-formed and that the
proof is correct here notice that the
commitment to the elliptical points T
and K
is really commitment to the to
coordinates and the proof by here to
prove this relationship is where we use
our point addition proof that I just
talked about finally we also give
arbitrary composition of algebraic and
arithmetic representation of functions
in the paper but I don't have time to
talk about it now but what I want to do
is to give an outline of how our
techniques applied to composite
statements in two applications so
revisiting the proof of solvency
application that I started with recall
the statement to prove is knowledge of X
and Y such that Y is d to the X and hash
of Y is H so now using the tools I just
showed you we use the double discrete
logarithm proof to prove that Y is G to
the X uncommitted Y and X and then use a
snark on committed input for hash of y
equal to H where H is represented as a
circuit to prove the statement the
second application where composite
statements arise is in privacy
preserving credentials where the setting
is the following we have a certificate
authority or a credential issuer who
issue certain credentials to a user and
the user later wants to be able to prove
to a verifier or a service provider that
has been given appropriate credentials
so the credential itself consists of a
set of attributes and the signature from
the organization and one solution if if
a prove it wants to prove certain
properties about the attributes is to
simply reveal the signature but this
would reveal additional information
which is not always desirable so what we
want is for the user to be able to use
the credentials he obtained and prove to
the verifier that has been given
appropriate credentials and attributes
satisfy a certain policy there have been
several proposals for anonymous
credentials in literature and they rely
on specially designed signatures so what
if we want to base privacy-preserving
credentials on a standard signature for
instance like an RSA signature now
notice that RSA verification given a
message
and a purported signature Sigma involves
checking of H of M is Sigma to the emod
L this again involves a non algebraic
component which is the hash function and
an exponentiation and results in a
composite statement so we can use our
techniques here or to prove this
composite statement using a snark on
committed input and output to prove the
circuit statement of the statement H of
m equal to H and then use a standard
Sigma protocol to prove knowledge of
each root of committed value and this
proves the RSA signature or to conclude
in the paper we show how to use our
techniques to prove general composite
statements that involve function
composition or and and we also give a
protocol to prove equality of committed
values over different groups and then we
show how to apply our techniques to
applications in proof of solvency and
anonymous credentials thank you
[Applause]