Thanks I also do bar mitzvahs thanks for
valve so let me start by talking about
classical fully homomorphic encryption
so in this case we have a week one a
week a client that wants to use the
computational power of a strong server
to compute some function so the client
has input X and it wants to get f of X
and the restriction is that we don't
want the server to learn anything about
the input X in a way this is done fully
homomorphic encryption is that the
client generates a pair of keys a secret
key and a public key is just encrypts
its input using the using the public key
and our security requirement is just
standard semantic security just like any
other encryption scheme but with the
fully homomorphic encryption the server
can perform homomorphic evaluation on on
ciphertext and get from encryption of x
to an encryption of f of X now this
doesn't have to look like a fresh
encryption of f of X but it needs to
decrypt to the right value and of course
we require this notion of compactness
which means that the length of this
encryption of f of X and the time that
it takes to decrypt it should be
independent of the complexity of the
function f itself another property that
is not always required but it's actually
going to be important for this talk it's
called circuit privacy and for our
purposes circuit privacy just means that
this encryption of f of X really does
need to look like a fresh encryption of
f of X and this should hold even for
computationally unbounded distinguisher
so this is circuit privacy and homework
encryption schemes classical have been
constructed based on the hardness of the
learning with errors problem and this
problem is considered to be intractable
even from quantum computers this gives
you a plausible post quantum candidate
for fully homomorphic encryption so post
quantum means that the the actual users
of the scheme are classical but the
adversary might be quantum so quantum
fully homomorphic encryption was
presented by broadband and Jeffery and
there you want to outsource a quantum
computation so the server has quantum
powers and you wanted to quantumly
evaluate a function on encrypted
unencrypted ciphertext now we want to
allow the client to be either classical
or quantum whatever it wants so for that
purpose we need the key generation and
the keys to be classical so that the
classical line can use them as well and
we also need the property that when we
encrypt the classical message we
actually get a classical ciphertex so
this can be done by classical by
classical client but if the client is
quantum and it wants to encrypt a
quantum message then they should be able
to do that as well so we want to be able
to encrypt one two messages in such a
way that it can degenerate to classical
and
straightforwardly so this is what we
want and broadband Jeffrey don't didn't
only only present the the concept but
also presented an approach on how to
achieve it it essentially uses hybrid
encryption so they propose to combine
classical fully homomorphic encryption
with the quantum one-time pad to get a
quantum fully homomorphic encryption and
this approach was used by all previous
works and also by the work that I'm
going to talk about today whoever it
seems pretty hard to actually apply this
approach to actually get the
full-fledged definition and in fact the
only prior works that achieves the
definition that I described is the very
recent work of Mahadev and she
constructed the scheme based on the
hardness of the learning with errors
problem so similarly to their classical
schemes but with a super polynomial
modulus Q so the modulus is a parameter
of the learning with errors problem and
the smaller the modules get the harder
problem becomes so the assumption
becomes more favorable or weaker and so
originally reg a proposed the hardness
of lwe with polynomial modulus but as
far as we know super polynomial should
also be hard so this is an assumption
that we're okay to rely on the reason
why certain polynomial modulus was
needed was because this quantum who
morphic evaluation actually had
correctness error and the correctness
error scaled more or less with the size
of the quantum function that you wanted
to evaluate divided by the modulus so if
you want the scheme that works for every
for every polynomial size function then
you want the super polynomial modulus so
that the correctness errors remain small
so additionally if you want the
strongest notion of a fully homomorphic
encryption you need an additional
assumption and this holds even in the
classical setting so even in the
classical setting for the strongest
possible
notion of homomorphism you actually need
what's called a circular security
assumption and this is needed even in
mahadeva's quantum scheme but actually
she needed a new circle of security
assumption which seems stronger to the
assumptions that were used in it for
classical schemes however this is like
pretty amazing that this can be done
that this definition can be achieved but
let's be greedy and ask you know now
that we know that it's possible why why
can't it be as good as classical fully
homomorphic encryption schemes so let's
let's do the comparison here so in terms
of of the modulus for classical schemes
we know how to get it from Tomomi
available you the polynomial modulus
in terms of circular security you need a
weaker flavor of circular security
assumption or seemingly weaker at least
and for correctness error actually in
the classical setting you can get
schemes with perfect correctness so
there's no correctness error at all what
we do here is get close to achieving the
the to getting to the classical setting
so it all sort of boils down or most of
it boils down to the to the correctness
error so instead of getting correctness
error that is sizeof function divided by
modulus we get sizeof function divided
by 2 to the modulus which allows us to
use the polynomial modulus to get an
exponentially small correctness error
and this allows us to use lwe with just
polynomial modulus which is slightly
larger than the modulus that you need
for for the classical setting but it's
still polynomial in terms of the
circular security assumption we don't
get the same assumption is in the
classical setting we're actually getting
an assumption that appeared in
literature before and perhaps
surprisingly it appeared in the context
of multi carefully homomorphic
encryption so this is the same
assumption that you need in order to get
the strongest flavor of multi key
classical fully homomorphic encryption
so this is an assumption that already
appeared in the literature but perhaps
as important as the specific
contributions here we have sort of a
conceptual approach to the problem that
connects a quantum homomorphism with
this circle this circuit privacy notion
that I was mentioning before and this
red light even on previous works so let
me tell you a little bit of let me tell
you a little bit about it but first
let's do a little primer about qubits
and quantum registers so a quantum
registers the register can be in
superposition between a few classical
states and if these two states are just
0 & 1 then we call it the qubit in terms
of notation we use this Dirac notation
which presents a quantum state as a
linear combination a linear combination
of classical states where these
coefficients w0 and w1 are related to
the probability of measuring the value 0
or 1 when you measure this quantum
register in particular if you measure
the register then the probability of
getting zero is the amplitude square of
w0 and this means that the sum of
squares of all the amplitudes should
should be 1 so when you measure a
quantum register you actually collapse
it States to a classical state so if a
measured measured 0 then the register is
going now going to be in classical state
0 but in fact you can collapse a
register without measuring it
if it's entangled with another register
so for example let's consider a two
qubit state so to say 0 0 plus 1 1 this
is 8 over 2 qubits and these two qubits
are related or entangled or even less
formally you can say that if you see
qubit number 2 then it clicks
information qubit number 1 in such a
case measuring qubit number 2 will
collapse the state of qubit number 1 as
well so even though I didn't measure a
qubit number 1 explicitly I can collapse
its state just by measuring a related
qubit two properties that we're going to
need about quantum registers so if I
have a superposition over States a then
I can create a superposition with the
same weight but on States a comma F of a
for every function for any function f
with the same weights as before and the
last thing is that you can efficiently
do Fourier transform on a quantum
register if the states come from like a
nice abelian groups which they will all
right so let's try to see how to use a
fully homomorphic encryption together
with quantum one-time pad to get quantum
fully homomorphic encryption so I should
tell you what is quantum one-time pad so
this was presented by a - at all and the
cool thing is that allows to encrypt a
quantum state using a classical key so
using a using a sequence of classical
beats and get perfect security so in
particular to perfectly encrypt a single
qubit all you need is two random
classical bits and and you can do this
and in terms of notation we're going to
denote alpha sub Y Z the quantum
one-time pad encryption of the state
alpha using using pad keys using pad
bits y&z so if you're wondering how this
is done so in the quantum one-time pad
you use one of the bits to do exactly
the same thing as classical one-time pad
so you use the bit Y to do a bit flip of
the quantum register that you have and
then you use the bit Z to do the dual
operation so you're doing a phase flip
if you don't know what a face flip is
don't worry about we're not really going
to mention need it today but importantly
note that the classical one-time pad is
just a special case of the can be
derived as a special case of quantum
one-time pad when you take the bit Z to
be 0 so a classically one-time pad at
value classical value can be seen as a
quantumly one-time pad at value so the
probe and Jeffrey approach is the
following so if I want to quantumly
encrypt a Quantum's
date what I'm going to do is I'm going
to generate a quantum one-time pass I'm
going to generate two classical bits Y &
Z I'm going to use them to quantum
one-time pad the the my register alpha
and then I'm going to use a classical
encryption scheme to encrypt y&z and for
the sake of my own sanity instead of
writing you know classical fully
homomorphic encryption classical fully
homomorphic encryption of y&z I'm just
going to use brackets so things in
brackets are encrypted with a classical
scheme so this is a pretty cool idea
even regardless of whom morphism it
shows that you can get a quantum public
key encryption from any classical public
key encryption scheme and security is
pretty immediate just by just by a
hybrid argument as usual with home or
'fuck encryption the problem is how did
how to get correctness how to get home
morphic evaluation to work and as I said
this is sort of always the problem
so we're going to forget about security
once we got to this point security is
guaranteed there's no nothing that I can
do from this point and on can harm
security all need to worry about now is
to get the functionalities to get the
correctness how do you get the
correctness well it turns out that the
following building block is required in
order to get home morphic evaluation for
this type of schemes so you can think
about this in analogue for home morphism
for linear functions in the classical
setting so I haven't encrypted bit x + 2
+ 2 bits a and b and what i want is to
get an encryption of ax + B this is sort
of a pretty basic primitive but it's
quantum analog is slightly more
complicated so now again we have an
encrypted classical bit in a
superposition over two qubits and what I
want is to get an encryption of ax + B
but now using our sort of new using our
encryption method so this superposition
needs to be encrypted with a quantum
one-time pad and the quantum one-time
pad needs to be encrypted with a
classical scheme so if I'm able to
perform this type of transformation
given a classically encrypted bit X and
a superposition over a and B then I I'm
going to be able to get the entire
quantum quantum evaluation that I want
and actually another way to think about
it is that this operation in fact takes
this bit X which is sort of inside the
cipher
and teleports it into the into the
quantum superposition so this is
actually an approach that was was useful
in the past so let's see how to actually
do it so this is kind of complicated so
I'm just going to simplify it a little
bit I'm going to do something that's I
think it's as hard and I'm just going to
take I'm just going to take a classical
bit X and now a superposition just over
a single qubit and what they want is to
get serve the quantum analog of an
encryption of a times X so this is what
I'm going to work on from now on and
naively so if I'm saying that this is
the quantum analog of getting an
encryption of a times X well I know my
original X bit was encrypted using a
classical fully homomorphic encryption
so I can start from a superposition over
the A's and get to a superposition over
a comma encryption of a times X this
just follows for the from the home from
the classical homomorphic evaluation so
what I get now is a superposition over
classical over classical home Orphic
ciphertext and this is not what I want I
mean I'd want to now pull out this
classical ciphertext from outside of my
superposition because what I want in the
end is that all classical encryptions
are outside of the superposition and I'm
only getting a superposition that is one
time padded and not like encrypted using
classical homomorphic encryption so
maybe the right thing to do is to just
sort of measure the register that
contains a times X but this is not going
this is not good because it's going to
collapse the superposition so the first
thing that we could notice is that the
value 8 times X actually depends on a so
once I measure an encryption of a times
X I'm going to collapse the
superposition of a and this is going to
destroy the correctness of my the
correctness of my evaluation however
this is not so hard to fix I'm just
going to introduce a mediator between a
times X and the classical encrypted
value and we're going to see that this
is going to solve our problem so I'm
going to introduce a new register Y
Prime and this Y prime is just in
superposition between 0 and 1 and now
instead of computing ax plus ax I'm
computing ax plus y Prime and I'm going
to call this value Y now why do I claim
that this solve the problem and what I'm
going to try to do is pull Y out this is
going to be my new goal but first let's
see why this is like why this is
progress
so just by definition y equals ax plus y
prime which means that equivalently Y
prime equals ax plus y so Y prime is
just the value a times X one time padded
by Y so if we measured the the
encryption of Y then really what we
would get is a times X one time padded
with this value Y for which we we get
the cipher text for so this is this
seems like a step in the right direction
so this is really what we're going to do
however we observed it even though now
if we just measure the value Y this is
not going to collapse our superposition
from for the reasons that that I just
explained we're not measuring Y itself
but actually we were measuring an
encryption of Y we're measuring a whole
cipher text and the cipher text might
click about about the history about it's
about the way that it was the way that
was created so and this actually has to
be the case so long as you're home
morphic evaluation is a deterministic
process so if we were if we were to
measure Y then we would be okay but we
need to measure this ciphertext of Y and
this this could create this could create
a problem because the cipher text itself
contains some information about the
value a that was used to create it and
this will still collapse our
superposition so this is like sort of
the hard problem any suggestions on how
this can be fixed okay never mind
so circuit privacy seems like a tool
that could be useful here because
circuit privacy essentially says that
the information in the ciphertext should
not be much more than just the
information that exists in the plaintext
so let's sort of talk a little bit more
in depth about circuit private classical
fully homomorphic encryption so what we
have is instead of having a
deterministic evaluation process so
remember now we're talking about the
classical setting our home morphic
evaluation is going to be randomized so
in addition to taking the encrypted the
encrypted value encrypted input X and
the function f there's also going to be
a random tape and this is going to be a
randomized functionality and the
guarantee is that the OP the
distribution of the outputs the outputs
Y is going to only depend on the
plaintext
the encryption of wires only depend only
depends on why and this is true even if
you know X and even if you know F even
if you know everything except the random
tape so in a sense the circuit private
home Orphic evaluation actually pushes
all of this ugly information that we
don't want into the randomness register
so so long as you don't see the rendered
randomness register you don't get any
bad information so property for
randomized the evaluation that is going
to matter for us is the conditional
distribution of the randomness
conditioned on like all this other
information to import the output and the
function that was evaluated so I'm going
to explain why this is important in in
in the next slide but for now mmm
this let's just think about the
definition so if you know the encryption
of X descriptions of Y and F what can
you tell me about the randomness are and
the way we interpret some aha revs
construction is that she requires a
circuit private classical home morphic
encryption scheme where the runways are
is uniquely determined by these values
XY and XY and F sorry whereas here we
want to work with sort of more efficient
or more elaborate ways to get to get
circuit privacy and especially we rely
on a scheme by bourse at all from from
crypto 2016 and there the this
conditional distribution of randomness
is much uglier so it's a Gaussian
distribution over a lattice coset that
is determined by these XY NF so if you
don't know what these lattice cosets are
don't worry about it we won't need them
much but it's like an much uglier
distribution okay good so let's see how
to use how to use this circuit privacy
in order to teleport X into our state so
before we said that we are going to
evaluate a X plus y prime now we're just
going to do it using a circuit private
scheme so we need additionally a
randomness a randomness register so in
addition our quantum state we're going
to have a randomness value and we're
going to do and we're going to do
circuit private homomorphic evaluation
of this value ax plus y prime and this
actually works now if I do this the
I can actually measure this part of the
register and get this classical
encryption of Y but now the quantum part
while it contains a and Y prime which is
good this is what I want but in addition
it contains this randomness value which
as I said before now it contains all
this like sort of bad information that I
didn't want the ciphertext Y to contain
before so now I need to find a way to
sort of get rid or uncomputable
terminology this register this register
R in order to avoid the stage from
collapsing so if I just measure this R
to try to get rid of it then I would
collapse the sate just as I would just
as I did before
so what mahadev showed was that in the
in the case where R as unique then you
can actually remove it by performing
binary Fourier transform on the register
R so it doesn't actually remove it it
just sort of pushes it into the face in
a way that is manageable but let's not
get into that
so for unique or you can actually find a
solution which is sort of I would say
it's computer toriel a nation in nature
whereas what we try to do here is get
some sort of an algebraic approach to
removing this to remove this randomness
register so really at a super high level
what we try to do is replace the binary
Fourier transform with QRF we transform
where Q is this lwe modulo so all of our
elements sort of natively live in Z mod
Q so it's natural to try by the qre
fourier transform it doesn't work
immediately so you need to sort of work
hard to make it work and then use this
algebraic properties of these lattice
cosets instead of the uniqueness
property that that was used before in
order to show that when you do this
Fourier transform it allows you to sort
of push the bad information again into
the face in a manageable way and this
involves sort of coming up with with
some additional tools and some analogs
quantum analogues of classical tools
that were known before but I'm not going
to get into the details let me not
summarize but give you some remaining
some ringing questions from this work
and then maybe tell you something else
so I think so the way that I view things
is that what we did here was to sort of
show that this approach of
to evaluation actually requires this
requires circuit privacy and the
question is whether this is inherent it
seems like you know in the quantum
setting things are so delicate that you
have to somehow prevent prevent them
from collapsing by something like
circuit privacy but I don't even know
how to formally so define it so that I
can try to prove it so this is sort of
one one interesting question so the
second one is I said that we get a
slightly larger modulus Q than the
classical setting in fact we match the
classical modulus of the circuit private
scheme of bore Sadao I wouldn't be
surprised if you can take it further
down and get very close to the classical
setting the issue of correctness error
is kind of annoying so we get like great
tiny correctness error but why can't we
get perfect correctness like we do in
the classical setting it's not clear how
to do it but I haven't actually a purely
classical question that you can think of
and if you can solve it then I think it
would be a good big first first step
toward solving the quantum issue so the
question is to come up with a semi
honest oblivious transfer scheme that
has both perfect correctness and perfect
privacy for the sender so we actually
know how to do it based on DDH and other
number theoretic assumptions but I want
to get a post quantum solution so I want
to come up with a post quantum scheme
oblivious transfer scheme that has both
perfect correctness and perfect sender
privacy completely classical question
and I think if you solve it it would be
a good step towards perfect correctness
here lastly there's some ugliness in the
construction so we apply like every
quantum gate we apply requires
afterwards a lot of post-processing in
order to restore the state and again we
have the slightly non-standard circular
security assumption and you know we
don't want to have these we actually
want to get the same the same efficiency
guarantees that we have in the classical
setting so I want to tell you I want to
buy eight into my questions time and
tell you a little bit about things that
are slightly different so there's been
pretty interesting developments in this
whole area of quantum outsourcing so
this setting where you have a quantum at
quantum server that wants to perform
some operation for a weaker possibly
classical possibly classical client so
we talked about the privacy issue but
some other interesting things that are
happening so
you might want this quantum server to
actually convince you that it's really
doing a quantum operation so you only
have a classical communication and you
at classical dude but you want the
server to compute to convince you that
it's actually performing a quantum
quantum operation this is related to the
so-called quantum supremacy problem
that's that practitioners also care
about I don't think that you can they
can want a quantum party to do is to
provide you with fewer and Ernest this
is sort of the only way in the universe
that we know to get pure randomness is
to use quantum is to use quantum
processes and me as a classical person
want a proof that indeed my server
produces produced randomness in proper
quantum way last thing that you may want
is the delegation problem so you want
the server to solve a quantum problem
for you and you want to be able to sort
of verify the solution it's correct even
though you're just a classical users a
classical person so the first two issues
were addressed in work by Christy with
the Christiano Mahadev fuzzy Ronnie and
Vivek and this last point was addressed
by a recent work of Mahadev so both of
these are going to appear in Fox in the
upcoming Fox and all these like these
two works and mahadeva's original
quantum fhe or actually related and let
me sort of try to give you a super high
level intuition that connects these
three problems to the quantum whole
morphism problem that we that we saw so
the verifier can use a quantum sort of a
quantum a fully homomorphic encryption
he generates classical keys and encrypts
the classical message to zero and he
sends those to the and he sends those to
the server now the server does quantum
amorphic evaluation of a designated
quantum function according to this
specific task that we want the server to
perform so there's some basically the
quantum function of the server needs to
apply and then he sends back the
classical part of the result and what
you want to argue is that the verifier
who has the secret key now knows why and
also the randomness that was used to
encrypt why in this you need to work
hard to argue that this sort of
straddles the prover in some meaningful
way that allows you to get soundness for
these
for these sort of tasks so this is super
high level connection also not
chronological connection between these
between these two things
and I think there's some pretty cool
progress and some some interesting
problems that lie ahead thank you
[Applause]