thanks brother thanks for the
introduction
where's my slide oh okay
so for this talk I'm going to present a
new definitional framework called
indistinguishability up to crack knees
I am DC for short so just in one
sentence it is a new technique for you
to write security definitions or to
design security games in such a way that
you don't need to attend to tribal wins
or more specifically but specifically
excluding tribal ways from the adversary
hence the title simply find game based
definitions so let's first start with a
review about indistinguishability are in
deep or short as we are not we're all
familiar with indistinct ability is
about an adversary's advantage notion
that measures how good he is in
distinguishing a real game G from an
ideal game age in this setting an
adversary a would ask questions to one
of the two games and receive responses
from the games his job is to
differentiate which games he is
interacting with so the
indistinguishability advantage of an
adversary a against games g and g and h
are defined to be this probability
difference that he outputs one in both
worlds so this concludes somehow okay so
based on such an atmosphere advantage a
game G is it's called indistinguishable
from an ideal game age for all adversary
with reasonable amount of resource he's
distinguishing advantage is small this
is all very familiar but I want to
emphasize is that
indistinguishability won't be so useful
and so important to our field
if this slide is all what is about if
you go through the literature most of
the definitional work uses
indistinguishability in the following
way the games G and H
are really constructed in such a way
that it depends on some crypto scheme
spy and then people would define all
kinds of security advantage against such
a scheme high as the IND advantage of
the games G and H that are instantiated
with this pile there are this talk I'm
going to call this way of defining
security as the conventional way
so let's first go through some examples
of what commercial games look like in
the literature so here is a game that
defines key in distinguishability
or bi-directional ratcheted key exchange
the relevant talk was even right here by
Porter
two days ago here is another one that's
about that models integrity property of
a primitive called data stream channels
it is a joint work done by official in
at all in crypto 15 yet another one that
model circuit hiding property of any
encryption by the way onion encryption
is the encryption algorithms used in
Onion Routing network like tor and mixed
nuts this is a recent work done by Tycho
Brahe understand
I believe you your crab dated all these
games are really complex so maybe let's
switch some switch or a mine and start
with some games that look not that
complex here is a game called all sub I
it borrows the authenticity property of
State for authenticated encryption the
same topic as a as mine hmm
so if you look at their secret it is a
joint work done by Boyd Hale poisonous
the media in CT RSA 2060
if you look at their code it doesn't
look that bad at least it's
comprehendible however just waiting one
year after their first publication to CD
RSA the same others publish a revision
in which they revise the pseudocode of
their security gates to ePrint
in which they added this special
processing to warm their sub cases and
even this revision is still not correct
because there really should be a return
or statement between line 5 and line 6 I
believe it's just a typo so all these
stories and and complex games are
motivated us to think about what are the
essential problems about indistinct
ability paradigm so as you can see from
the previous life the definitions or the
security games related to those are
really complex and subtle in such a way
toward degree that they're just hard to
debug and believe worse a prior work of
Valerie Hoffman's and kills showed that
even with the most basic security
definitions like ing CCA security for
public encryption schemes people still
would mess up and they are way in terms
that they are wave of how to evoke
queries from adversary's artists allowed
the orders showed that just by tweaking
the way that Tremmel queries are this
allowed you can define multiple ie
equivalent security notions for ind CCA
security for public key encryption
schemes and key wrapping algorithms as
well in summary it's just hard to
justify for a cryptographer once he
writes down some pseudocode of security
games for some security properties it's
just it's hard to justify for him does
this game really capture what I want
part of the reason for that is there's
no good theory for cryptographers to use
as how to create security definitions in
the literature we have many good tools
and theorists to upper bound adversary's
advantage given existing security
definitions security notions like
coefficient H methods expectation
arguments for example
but as for how to create that security
definitions typically we're on our own
so our IDC framework is supposed to fill
in this gap you know high level it works
like a definitional compiler where you
feed into this compiler to security
games that capture what you want but
really do not work because there will be
trivial winning strategy for the
adversary so the definition on the left
hand side is bogus however you live with
that you pass these security games to
the compiler and it will automatically
generate two edited games for you whose
ind advantage results in relevant
reasonable security notion in which
there is no triple win so what is this
definitional compiler then it's a
process we call Oracle editing it works
like this we start with two utopian
games G and H the games are called
utopian because there are trivial ways
to win this there are trivial winning
strategy for the adversary's win these
games we again prabha we in addition
provide a kragnes class C that is
mathematically just a set of crypto
schemes of which satisfies certain
kragnes conditions the kragnes condition
is just a familiar functional property
that a class of schemes need to satisfy
in order to work for example for public
key encryption this will just be the
decryption needs to be the reverse
process of encryption you pass these
three building blocks to the process of
Oracle auditing and this will output the
edited games GTO de and H tilde we then
define a new adversary advantage called
IMTC advantage in the middle at the
bottom against G H and C simply it will
be the plane indistinguishability
advantage against G tilde and H tilde
the same advantage
there used to be what happens security
advantage against the underlying scheme
pie okay so what is this article editing
process in particular mmm
in order to illustrate this I would
first go deep into our game playing
model as shown here security games in
our model consists of initialization
procedure or encode procedure and
finalization procedures these are
written in pseudocode and they are
stateful they have stays so that the
game states are maintained across
invocation an adversary a will simply
ask questions to the oracle procedure
receiving responses and then he would
under Edward Alice at his will output
his own Abruzzi which surely echoes
through the game outcome Omega this will
be what the utopian games behave like
like I said there needs to be added done
so what is this editing
well we added the utopian games by
adding this yellow demultiplexer this
demultiplexer will before each time the
response is given to the adversary
confused a silencing function so on the
current game transcript the game
transcript includes all previous
adversary queries and responses and if
this silencing function returns true the
response of the oracle why i will be
replaced by a special diamond symbol we
call this oracle silencing okay
so now comes the real crux of our whole
framework how should we define this
silencing function because this really
captures what we mean by tribal queries
so we think that a query is trivial if
the adversary based only on the current
game transcript and based solely on the
fact that the underlying scheme is in
the kragnes class C knows the answer
beforehand so let me repeat this this is
very important we think a query is
trivial so it should be silenced when an
adversary based solely on the card
transcript that includes all his courage
and responses at this point and based
solely on the fact that the scheme is in
a chronic lass knows the owner before
know the anger before had formalizing
this idea we define a silencing function
in this way that given T the answer is
fixed across all schemes Pi in the Class
C for the real if the animals are
interacted with the real game
we formed eyes
we give definition formulas for their
stylists functions I don't want to go
team into this but only you want to
point that the silencing function here
is a logical or of a thickness predicate
that means whenever there were
priorities that needs to be silenced it
reminiscent so it's like a silence then
shut down approach this concludes the
description of NDC but before I leave
this topic I need to mention one
important caveat that is the silence
function needs to be efficiently
computable or at least on the domain
that matters transcripts that arise in G
sub pi / H sub pi if this does not hold
the intuition that because the adversary
knows the response so he should not ask
it simply would not hold that summarize
how we use I and easy to create
definitions we first formalized
intensive cry of schemes PI then the
correctness condition this will give us
a kragnes class at the same step as the
conventional way we next design utopian
games G and H and in doing so we don't
need to attend to logic for excluding
treble-winning queries for example along
with C this determines the IND CC curry
notion we want finally we need to verify
the silence function silence of CG is
efficiently computable on the relevant
sets of transcripts
ok so that is the conclusion of Ind C
framework let me go through two examples
for that the first example is
let's use it to define IND CCA security
for public key encryption schemes a very
familiar notion I'm going to perform
this definitional process first in the
commercial way and then by our IND C way
as we're all familiar with a public key
encryption scheme consists of two
probabilistic key algorithms key
generation and encryption than a
deterministic decryption algorithm the
correctness property is just that for
all messages if you encrypt by a public
key generated by the key generation
algorithm and you decrypt that you would
get back the original message all these
are very simple so let's try to design
security games for IND CCA security this
is the first attempt both the real size
g1 are the ideal size each one share
initialize key decryption finalize
procedures that have natural semantics
except for the encryption Oracle we're
in the real side you encrypt the real
message but in the ideal side you
include an all zero bit messages if we
are working in a setting of conventional
way I'm sorry if we are going to give
conventional indistinguishability based
definitions we know that this is not
enough there are ways to trebly win this
game adversary simply asks encryption
and gasbag see the hit equals C so that
by practice in the real world you will
see the regional message and but in the
idea that he will say D or zero bit
messages are traditionally there are
multiple ways to exclude such remove
wins you can either exclude from
consideration exclude from consideration
all adversary's that make such trivial
queries or you can first allow such
trivial queries but finalize in the
finalized procedure you penalize that
behavior by returning zero bellario
opens and Q's called the first one
exclusion style the second one panel
histone okay this is the conventional
way what about our int C way
we need to have first syntax Crimea's
condition which we already did we need
to have new token games G 1 and H 1 this
looks the same as the first attempt and
the difference with the previous slide
is there is no logic for excluding
there's no code that attends to the
exclusion of the trivial queries all the
security code here looks very natural
and that's it C 1 G 1 H 1 define and IND
C is equally notion and we shown that
we've shown that the resulting identity
security definition is equivalent to the
conventional one ok you might say this
doesn't look very promising you only
managed to remove two lines of code so
let's go to our main example of state
authenticated encryption there have been
many prior work on this at least three
of them as you might imagine they tend
to have different syntax different
security goes and they have relatively
complex security games that's most
important so let's try to use int Siong
Stateville often you can equip ssin
first the syntax we simply augment the
traditional authenticated encryption
syntax by a state space both in the
input and in the output and the next we
need to define Krakus somehow
surprisingly this question to the best
of our knowledge was not answered
explicitly in the literature we choose
it if you think about the question what
is a correct state of authenticated
encryption so if you apply that over a
reliable channel things really matter
here
if you apply that over a reliable
channel then you might only receive the
required a receiver to decrypt correctly
only just for the cipher text that's
receiving order but if you are using
stateful authenticated encryption over
unreliable channel then you might need a
stronger correctness requirement you
might require the receiver to decrypt
correctly for any out of order cipher
text except for replay for example
between these two
can be many variants about this level of
fidelity for the receivers we choose to
model that by a level set L this is just
a set of natural number sequences so
that a number sequence is in this level
set if and only if it is considered a
permissible orderings of the ciphertext
generated by the sender at the bottom is
our formalization for this Cronus class
that's parameterize by this level set L
the next let the next step is to give
real and ideal utopian games as you can
see compared to prior work our security
games are much more simple thanks to the
IND C because we never we no longer need
to write how the explicit logic to
exclude those treble-winning queries
from the adversary we have an safe o AE
construction that satisfies the
resulting in DCC CC a security notion as
well so finally then we conclude with
some of the possible variants for int C
framework Oh
so everything I just talked about
actually it's about one central question
how do we formalize the silencing
function to reflect the idea of
excluding drivel wins
there are many definitional traces apart
from our silencing function which is a
silence near shutdown style we can
instead silence once but allow
additional queries there can be ideal
side editing we don't silence the real
rows but instead we added the ideal
world responses by the railroad ones
there can be penalties to editing where
you simply modify the finalization
procedure to penalize whenever in the
transcript there is a fixed miss query
there can even be symmetric silencing
let me skip this but I want to mention
that out of these four three of them we
show that they are expressively they're
equivalently expensive as our initial
version
however convenience does come with some
price first definition is coming out of
Ind see our abstract in terms of the
edited games do not have conquered a
security code however most of the time
it can be concretely recapitalized so
that you can do the conventional
security analysis against it it is still
a speculative proposal we've only used
it on an encryption public key
encryption and state fault indicated
encryption but we expect the idea can be
broadly applicable and there definitely
needs to be more work done on this topic
to understand how general this idea
works and that's all for the talk any
questions
[Applause]