okay and so here's a reminder of the
efficiency parameters that we want to
optimize in searchable symmetric
encryption there's the space usage of
this scheme which is the size of the
encrypted database and ideally we would
like it to be of n where n is the size
of the original database
there's the read efficiency of the
scheme which is the ratio between the
number of bits that the server is with
each query and the actual size of the
result and ideally we would like this
ratio to be constant and there's the
locality of the scheme which is the
number of non contiguous memory
locations that the server accesses with
each wearing and ideally we would like
you to be a constant number of locations
so let's go over existing schemes and
our bounds in and we work we focus on
schemes that do not modify the encrypted
database while searching and while this
captures most of the schemes or a base
techniques such as in the works there
heard about are not captured in our work
and schemes that have what is called the
minimum leakage which means that they
leak only the size of the database the
size of the result of each query that is
performed and the query repetition
pattern what Eric called the quality
pattern that is what queries are
repeated and first there are various
schemes that did not a cloak ality into
account so they have optimal space and
read efficiency however the locality is
as bad as o of n then caching Tesoro
suggested a scheme with space n log n
locality log N and constant read
efficiency it was later improved by a
shallow Battelle to have a constant
locality and was later a generalized by
the metrics and path amento to have an
arbitrary locality and for locality L
the space overhead is
and log n over log in and actually the
their scheme also supports non-constant
read efficiency however in those cases
the the leakage is not minimal and in
terms of lower bounds there's the lower
bound of caching to zero
that applies to schemes that have non
overlapping reads which roughly means
that the locations that are accessed
when querying different keywords do not
have a significant overlap so they show
that such schemes cannot have both
optimal space and locality and other
above schemes fall into indeed have non
overlapping reads so this explains why
they can't be optimal in all parameters
but still there's a substantial gap
between the lower bound and upper bound
so in this work we ask can we close this
gap now not all schemes have
non-overlapping grids and the two such
instances are as follows and the first
one is another scheme by asha orbital
we've optimized space and locality so
they circumvent the the lower bound of
caching to zero
but still the read efficiency is not
optimal it's Oh till dove login and they
also improve the read efficiency to out
it off lock logon and however this
scheme only works under the assumption
that no key word appears in more than n
to the 1 minus 1 over log log n
documents now in terms of lower bound
they show a lower bound that applies to
schemes that fall into a framework that
we call the statistical independence
framework which roughly means that the
locations that are accessed when
querying different keywords are
essentially independent and they show
that such a scheme with space off n or
even larger and locality o of 1 when
querying a keyword w associated with n w
documents the read efficiency
be a super constant function times one
over epsilon and W where n W where W the
number of documents associated with W
and epsilon and W is the unique epsilon
such that began to demand minus epsilon
equals end Avenue and they're both two
schemes indeed fall into this framework
so the lower bound explains why the
assumption on the log log n scheme is
necessary but still there's a gap
between the lower bound and upper bound
so we again ask can we close this gap
and our contributions are as follows we
observe that all current sse techniques
in this context and our fall into two
frameworks the first one is the already
mentioned statistical independence
framework and the second one is the new
framework that we introduced and called
the apparent split framework so this
framework refines the non-overlapping
grid property but still captures the
same existing schemes and within this
framework we show a tight lower bound
that matches the scheme of the Matteson
path amento and within the statistical
independence framework and where main
result is an improved upper bound that
is we construct a new ssa ssi scheme and
it actually matches the lower bound of
Asherah Vittal for a range of parameters
as we will see and so more formally in
the patterns fleet where framework our
lower bound states that for a scheme
with locality l the read efficiency must
be omega of n log n over log n and
within the statistical independence
framework we construct a new SSE scheme
with an optimal space and locality and
the read efficiency depends on the size
of the result and W and matches the
lower bound up to an additive term of
all log log log n and the Omega one
term can be any super constant function
and still our scheme works in the
resumption that no keyword appears in
more than n over log n cube documents
which is the fair less restrictive
assumption than the previous one so what
it means is that as long as n W is not
too large a worried efficiency is as
small as a log log n and for larger
values of n W a worried efficiency
matches the lower bound and so in this
work and in this talk I will focus on
our skin so for the pendants with a
framework and lower bound please check
our paper so to understand our scheme we
need to understand the log log n scheme
of a shallow Vittal so what they do is
to introduce a process called the
two-dimensional to choice allocation
which on a high level is a way to
allocate lists into bins with the
following two desired properties the
first one is that the elements of each
list are placed in consecutive bins
which helps us in terms of locality and
the second one is that the location of
the first element of each list is in one
out of two random bins which allows
proving security via the statistical
independence framework and to prevent
overflowing bins what they do is to
limit the length of the each list and
set the size of each bin to out healed
of log log n and this results in their
scheme that has space often locality of
one and the read efficiency is altered
of log log n because instead of reading
a single elements they read entire bins
and actually it's two bins per element
and so our idea is to actually allow
overflow and so we show that assuming
all lists are of length at most n over
log n cubed if we set the number of
the size of each bin 200 local or
cloggin and the number of Bin's
accordingly then there are at most n
over log n overflowing elements so the
remaining question is what should we do
with those overflowing lists so here's a
knave attempt to solve this maybe we
should use the first scheme of a show
orbital for those overflowing the list
and the reason to do that is because it
has optimal locality and read efficiency
and even though the space overhead is
not optimal it's n log n but it in our
case it's actually n over log n so this
only costs in an additional of instance
and but the problem with the solution is
in its security because it reveals which
lists are overflowing and it's in turn
leaks information about the database
itself so our solution to that is to
modify the scheme of a sure orbital such
that it will not reveal whether a list
is stored in it or not and I won't go
into the technical details of this but a
key I did in there is to avoid rehashing
the hash tables in their skin by using
cocoa hashing with a stash and since the
stash size depends on the length of the
list our read efficiency depends on the
size of the result so this results in an
SSE scheme with space often locality of
one and the read efficiency consists of
two terms the first one is caused by the
size of each bin and the second one is
cost is caused by the stash size so to
conclude and here's the summary of our
result and thank you for this
[Applause]