[Music]
[Applause]
this
is our next talk coming up it's sofia
daily
with the state of digital rights in
latin america
sophia up to you thank you so much
um thank you everyone for tuning in
today
and as it was said my name is sophia
celi
and i'm a cryptographic researcher
mainly uh clutter but i also led the
development
of the opera of the record messaging
protocol in session four
and on my start time i also researched
about the state of the digital rights in
latin america
and specifically i research around the
usage of digital tools to enhance
gender-based violence
in latin america specifically but today
i was wanting to talk to you about
the stage of digital rights in latin
america and this is a really big topic
uh so i will try to just cover the
basics of all of it
um so don't expect that much in in depth
of
uh of the topics that i'm going to talk
about is more of an
outline so people are more aware of the
state of it
so let's start with one of the most uh
interesting questions we're talking
about the state of the digital rights in
latin america
to actually talk about what is latin
america and for some people maybe on the
audience this would be really simple to
just
um because people already have a
preconceived notion of what latin
american is
but actually to latin americans so for
people living in south america or
central america or the caribbean or the
south or north america
this is not an easy question because
there's a lot of um
questions around when actually latin
america was created as a concept
and what actually means of the concept
to be a latin america
does it actually mean to have uh some
certain
uh cultural background that is shared
between each other
what else actually does this mean and
actually in certain parts what
some people will actually uh think is
like in america
some people need actually don't think
they belong to latin america
because sometimes they're associated to
be part of latin america to have to have
a background
of uh being colonized by european powers
and i also have an indigenous background
and that space
racism in latin america as everywhere in
the world certain people in latin
america that think themselves as white
don't want to belong of life to latin
america because of the reasons
so speaking of nothing america from
sanosia is a controversial topic
in itself in latin america itself but on
this talk i'm going to speak about and
be referring to the latin american
region
specifically to countries belonging to
the to south america
to central america and the caribbean and
to the south of north america mainly
to mexico and when i talk about latin
american as a region i'm not including
french guiana because that's part of the
la jazz de otreme is part of the
schengen area
so that's the first question that now
have been answered at least
for this talk and so actually give a
little bit of background why i think
it's
actually important to talk about the
state of digital rights and latin
america
it's uh mainly one of the reasons why i
wanted to give this talk at
ccc was mainly because sometimes in this
kind of conferences
we hear a lot about the state of digital
rights mainly in the global north
but sometimes we oblivious to actually
what is happening in the global south
and it's the same kind of a state or the
same kind of ideas and notions that we
have for digital rights
apply the same to the global south and
in this case i'm just going to be
focusing specifically on one region of
the global south
mainly latin america but uh they will be
needed
actually more research and more actually
people talking about other regions of
the global south
and to give a little bit of historical
context why it's actually important to
talk about digital rights in latin
america i was wanting to actually uh
start with this specific historic
instance of something that happened in
latin america
and the reason why i'm going to
highlight this specific instance
is because sometimes we think that um
this kind of surveillance or this kind
of
um censorship of the kind of um of the
kind of going against
uh human rights only happens sometimes
in the global notes because we
sort of associated that the
transgression between
um that the transgression between um
between uh towards digital rights only
happens between
spies and like big countries but that's
not actually the case i mean this
historical context i'm going to
show you why it also happens uh sort of
in latin america
uh so what is the theme the scene right
now is um
the cold world uh the cold war and this
is basically this historical
instance in which there were two
superpowers basically fighting for
economic political
and even culture i would say um around
the world and there are two super wells
with soviet union and the united states
of america
during that time during the 70s and the
80s latin america
uh sort of elected certain socialists
and i put socialist
and codes socialist governments to be
the representatives of the people
and i say socialists because sometimes
we have an aesthetic notion of what
socialism is
but it was in a specific notion of
socialism in the latin american context
so these governments were actually
elected uh but certain other powers that
exist also in the americas didn't
actually liked
that uh these governments were elected
or even they didn't like what happened
in cuba mainly the
cuban revolution so in order to prevent
uh for all the latin american countries
turning completely
socialists what happened is that the
united states factor campaign of
political repression and state of terror
involving intelligence operation and
assassination of opponents
mainly in latin america and in fact the
deposition of many of the socialist
governments
um that were elected in latin america
and this uh backed campaign of political
risk
repression happened in several countries
in latin america mainly in argentina
chile uruguay paraguay bolivia brazil
ecuador and peru
and the involvement of the united states
was not only about backing them
economically but they actually provided
a planning military cooperation uh
training on torture technical support
and supply military aid and this
happened uh during various
administrations of the
of the united states mainly during the
administration of johnson nixon paul
carter and megan
this not only happened between
cooperation between these latin american
countries and the united states but it's
also happened between
the same latin american countries so the
same countries that i just mentioned
also cooperated between each other to
provide themselves with actual good
planning on how to efficiently torture
and efficiently kill
political opponents uh to the regimes
that were installed by the
united states against the socialist
governments
uh during the 70s and the 80s not much
was known actually and how actually
these operations would actually carry
out
of course it was known that a lot of
people were here and a lot of people
were disappeared and a lot of people
were tortured
but it was only until december of 1992
that martinez
jose agustin fernandez drove to an
obscure
dropped to an obscure police station in
the suburb of la madre
in associal in paraguay and what
why they drove him to this station was
because with the blower actually
schedule
um the plan or where this uh police
station was
so they drove to it and what they found
is that they found a cache of seven
seven hundred thousand documents
pioneered to the ceiling
or something that later was going to be
called the terror archive
los angeles delta which was a complete
paper database
of the interrogation of records of
integration torture and surveillance
that was conducted under the military
dictatorship of alfredo strossner which
was the paragon
a paraguayan dictatorship during the
military intervention of latin america
what they found out is that mainly it
was used uh informants telephoto cameras
watch apps to build this paper database
of everyone that was viewed as a threat
and i highlight here that was everyone
that was viewed as address
was not actually only people who were
actually deemed to be
actual political opponents to the
military regimes during those times
but it was mainly everyone that they
thought was actually
uh some kind of threat it could have
been an artist
uh creating art that was against the
regime it could have been
students that for some reason decided to
read karl marx so all of these people
that somehow were associated with
socialism or somehow were
deemed to be opponents of the regime in
that time were
um targeted as threats and it was not
only them but also the friends and their
associated so
they created a database on not only the
people that they think
they were a threat to the military
regime but also of any kind of friend or
any kind of family that they have
the archive was a total of 60 000
documents and where the photos and comp
and it compromised uh 593 000 microphone
pages
the restored level of this and of all of
the database
and all of all of this torturing a lot
of these killings was that up to 50 000
people were killed
30 000 disappeared and 400 000 were
arrested and in prison
and until this day if you go to any of
the countries that i have just mentioned
you will see several instances and
several families of action
of people um or relatives of people who
actually disappear and until these days
there's a lot of
countries in which a lot of people still
ask for the bodies of the people who
disappear or at least to know what
happened to the people
to disappear
so why i'm speaking about this the
reason why i'm speaking about this is
because we sometimes think that these
things
don't happen at this level that people
don't get disappeared because there is a
paper database
of you that uh that showcase yourself as
a threat
for some reason for whatever reason just
because you
somehow read some book that uh someone
deemed that it should be unacceptable to
be read during that
time which was what happened in latin
america about that time
and the other reason why i'm showcasing
this is because sometimes we think that
countries only surveil their own
citizens well this is not true it was
even true in the 70s and the 80s
that several different countries that
had military governments at that time
were surveilling the citizens of other
countries and these countries were
sharing these databases between each
other
and the other reason why i'm
highlighting this is because this was
not like a
stall or solitary operation that was
happening because these latin american
countries decided to do it
this was backed out and actually planned
by the united states
this well known and the victims of the
torture have actually stated several
times
that for example that they when they
were being tortured uh there was always
the presence of a
united states person in the room
actually training people on how to
efficiently turtle
training people onto how to efficiently
track people training people on how to
efficiently
create this database what will happen
today today will be that this
kind of paper databases that existed on
that time will be much more efficient
because people are using the digital
dose
every day and it will be the same that
they will be backed by
some um power some more powerful country
that will have an
interest in the economic and political
um
scenario of several different countries
so today
this much they will be much worse but
the reason why i wanted to highlight
this is to actually show you a
historical instance
when indeed this happened and that it
could indeed happen
in the future as well so what's the
theme when talking about the digital
rights of latin in latin american
countries in this talk i decided to talk
about
four main topics that i think are really
important with talking about digital
rights in a region
the first one is to talk about what kind
of privacy laws exist
on those countries the second one is
talking about the types of cohesion that
exist
in these countries by the using or by
the usage of digital tools
the third one is to talk about the state
of civilians of those countries and the
fourth one is to actually talk what kind
of secure communication are actually
provided in those countries
so let's start with the first one which
is actually the privacy laws
and on this um since the arrival of gdpr
has been like a hot topic for
now some years but indeed this is not
something that just
was just created by the arrival of gdpr
but indeed for example in the human
rights
it's actually defined privacy is
actually defined as a human right
and because of this most of latin
american constitutions
actually provide some certain kind of
protection
towards previously because it's part of
the human strides
mostly in the past the constitution have
was only focusing on
privacy as part of the non-digital world
but as with the arrival of the digital
world privacy is also applied to the
digital world
since 2010 worldwide 62 new countries
have enacted data protection laws and
every countries as
i have said in latin america has some
form of private uh data protection
in latin america the first country to
actually have a privacy law
um was chile in 1999
followed by uruguay mexico peru colombia
brazil
although in brazil would put an asterisk
asterisk
because even though it was created in
some parts of the law still needs to be
debated on august 2021
and some parts of the law were actually
video by the current president
and there has been some pushback around
that law for a while now
other countries that have actually a
privacy law at barbados and panama
one of the questions that you can ask
yourself when actually talking about
privacy laws in that in america
if this is actually a phenomenon in
itself or it's just like something that
has been inspired because of the arrival
of gdpr
in most of the cases uh that we have
actually seen it's actually mostly
inspired by gdpr
because it's mostly what is right now in
fashion so to say
um but it actually needs to actually
happen still a lot of research to
actually say that this is a phenomenal
of their own or that these privacy laws
are actually thinking of the reality of
latin america
on their own and not just taking some
other privacy laws from other countries
so the first question that actually
needs to be addressed when talking about
privacy laws
in the latin american concept context
itself
is to talk about what is privacy in
itself and this is something that now
scholars and researchers are actually
talking much more
around in the sense that even though for
one region privacy
uh will mean something because of the
cultural background of this region
for another reason maybe privacy will
not be deserved
the same because of the different
culture meaning of privacy depending on
the region of the world that you're
talking about
so for example something that still
needs to be researched is what actually
means
uh what me what privacy actually means
for a latin american context what does
latin americans actually think of
privacy itself
the other thing that actually um gets a
lot of talking when you're talking about
privacy laws
is what actually applies to privacy
privacy it's only the contents of
communication
that gets the status of the status of
being private
or if anything for example the network
transmissions are actually also part
of privacy and this is something that
still um
been talked around the same winter when
talking about privacy laws in latin
america
actually thinking about what what data
is defined as private as i have said
and what about metadata or subscriber
data and what about
linked data metadata is usually what
they say is
uh they usually define it as like
auxiliary data that gets created during
for example
having a conversation subscriber data
sometimes they define it as the
auxiliary data that the
initiator actually created and linked
data is more about this data that can
actually be linked to an individual and
use for example for advertisement
several of the different laws in several
latin american countries have different
uh approach to all of this these
definitions
but most of them are mainly inspired by
the same gdpr definitions
what about anonymous data certain of the
privacy laws indeed have
in latin america indeed have some kind
of mention of anonymous data i think in
the brazilian one for example
they say that anonymous data should be
prior should be private
if by some reason for example you are
able to d
and the anonymize the data by using the
same mechanism that the service that
anonymize the data
are used you manage to de-anonymize it
and then the data is also considered
private
but if like for example you took the
data um
created by some service and you later by
using
a completely different mechanism that
the one provided by the
service you manage to de-anonymize it
then that that data is not private
anymore
and this is sort of mentioned a little
bit like in a big terms but
at least it's there um so i just wanted
to highlight these questions in the
sense to actually say
the most of the time when you read the
privacy uh laws of different latin
american countries
the sort of notions are sort of vaguely
defined or sort of vaguely
mentioned but not that much going in
depth of the different notions
one important thing to actually think
about when talking about latin american
privacy laws is what about the data that
that gets sent or transmitted to other
countries because one of the
realities of latin america is that there
are some services that provide
us that provide certain kind of services
in latin america that
are latin american itself meaning that
they are like
uh companies that were created in latin
american countries
and where the data is stored in the same
country but most of the time in latin
america
the consumers of applications mainly use
social media that is created in other
countries
and where the data goes to another
country or
communication systems that go to another
country most of the privacy laws in
latin america
latin america actually says that
actually says
that if the data gets transmitted to
another country
that these other country should have the
same level of protection
as the one that is uh given in the in
the
owner's country but even though this is
set in most of the privacy laws in
practice this actually does not happen
until this day i have not actually seen
anyone actually asking any of the
companies that we use for social media
or for communication
to actually surrender the data to say
that they are not applying the same
level of protection that latin american
laws
provide for their own data so that is
still
it gets on the law but in practice not
much happening
and another question that you should ask
yourself when talking about privacy laws
is what about the data that is already
stored
so one of the things is that even though
this that
these privacy laws exist even though
they existed for some long time
um still certain uh countries and
certain companies in other countries
have been installing this data for a
really long time
and we don't know if there will be at
any point any kind of request to
actually say
yes to render the data of all our
citizens that you have
a store for this amount of time that
doesn't have happened
so far now let's talk about the second
topic that i was uh
outlining in the other introduction the
second talking topic is the times of
cohesion what kind of cohesion actually
exists in south america
in latin america in regards to digital
rest and in regards specifically to
freedom of expression
of the current state of what happened in
kovite 19 and about gender-based
violence
by using uh digital tools so the thing
first thing about the health system and
kobe 19
so in this um this is a really complex
topic but i will just try to highlight
certain points
uh about instances in which uh digital
tools are being used to actually
diminish the rights that people have to
other things
specifically something digital tours
have been used to diminish the right
people to help to the health system and
to the education system
so in one instance of this happening for
example is by the usage of biometrics
which is the
on arise in latin america specifically
in chile and in brazil
one of the proposals for example for
chile was
to use biometrics uh during health
checks meaning that you will have access
to certain public systems
and some and to certain um to certain to
certain health checks only by
surrounding the surrendering
the the biometrics of yourself
and this actually doesn't apply to the
latin american
um region in the sense that for example
in the rural areas
most of the people that were asked to
surrender the fingerprints
because the work they feel or because
they sometimes have some kind of
disabilities
the fingerprints could not be read
because there was no fingerprint or
because the fingerprint was really
difficult to be read
what this mean is that the health system
became unfair in itself
because the people who were not able to
access a health system anymore because
they could not really surrender the
biometrics because the idea of biometric
didn't match their current reality and
this is
something that we will talk during this
talk quite a lot but sometimes in latin
american governments they take one
technology because they think it's cool
or is what other countries right now are
using
but they don't thinking of what it means
to actually apply this technology
in a latin american reality another
instance in which
biometrics are actually abused in latin
america and this is an abuse that is
happening not because of latin american
governments or maybe it is
in a way but mainly because when latin
americans have to
travel to another country for tourism or
for working or for whatever
reasons they usually have to apply for a
visas for the schengen area or for the
united states
and most of the times they are asked to
surrender the biometrics at the time of
applying for the visa
or sometimes at the time of of uh of
crossing the border
it's not really known what happens uh
with the biometrics of the people who
are are being asked to surrender them
for the visas or the legality of
actually of all of these um it's not
known where
is this distort and in some instances
even uh when you are surrendering your
application for your visas and
surrendering
your biometrics you're also asked to
sort of surrender your social media um
in the sense that most of the times uh
in order to be guaranteed to be given a
visa you have to sort of know
that your social media is going to be
examined uh
and it's going to be checked that you
don't have anything that that country
that you're willing to travel to
deems um bad but coming back to this
health system
uh sometimes in the health system for
example uh
the reason why for example latin
american uses social media quite a lot
is because sometimes the social media is
the only option do they have
and this you will see in a few slides uh
that i will talk about this in the
future
but sometimes because uh latin america
has an
unfairness between what kind of
discourse gets pushed
in the in the mass media what happens is
that minorities usually go to social
media
to actually try to put themselves in the
discourse or to actually
have support from other people or to
showcase what kind of
fairness is happening to them which is
um
which is bad in itself because this is
the only way that they can publish what
is happening to themselves
and at the same time they are
surrendering surrendering their
information to social media companies
that exist in other countries
so in the case of the health system for
example this happens quite a lot
uh with people who are who are hiv
positives
in the sense that because they don't
have a support from the local
governments from the local latin
american governments
they use social media to actually find
psychological support or to find any
kind of support
or or even to actually find any way to
buy the medicine that they need because
the woman
government is not providing the
medicines that they need what they do is
that they have created their own market
in which they can uh buy the medicines
that they need because the wellbeing
government is not providing this what in
reality this
makes is that there's some there is
an unregulated market for medicines and
there's
extortion and of course there's data
that is being stored in the social media
of these companies that exist
outside of latin america about the
health status of the people
are suffering from from this the thing
happened during coveted nightside
in which mainly all of the health system
of all latin american countries
collapsed
and what happened is that there was a
lack of medicines and
people started selling uh medicine again
through social media
um or oxygen tanks or other kind of ways
that's the only way that people could
actually sometimes get medicines through
the use of
usage of social media and this again
poses the question that this was the
only way
that people could actually access the
health system and at the same time they
were giving away the private information
and the health information
to companies that exist outside of the
latin american countries
because it was the only way in which
they could access some kind of
health checks just to give you an
example
in uh on a specific example and a study
in 2019
showcase that in ecuador uh 10.7 percent
of people between the ages of 15 and 49
as defined as digital illiterates and
only
41.4 has access to a smartphone
and there's more access to smartphones
and in general to the internet in urban
areas
and there's more access to smartphones
from men than from women
and other genders this is really
important to highlight especially when
talking about kovite 19 because one of
the proposals that the latin american
governments have had
is that in order to know how much people
have
been infected with kobe uh you should
install an application
on your phone that actually tracks uh
your movements and this of course has
privacy implications for your
um the data around your location but it
also doesn't really make sense in a
latin american
scenario because most of the people
don't actually have a smartphone
so actually asking people to install an
application for kovind 19 when they
don't have a smartphone
or asking people to start an application
uh to for example
schedule health checks um doesn't make
sense in that in america and just
makes it why the the the unfairness of
the health system itself
and this is again an example of the
onset of the ideas that sometimes local
latin american governments have that
they just see that other countries are
actually
um creating an application for tracking
the kovid 19
but it doesn't really make sense into a
latin american reality and
so yeah and another topic sort of
related to creation and unfairness
is gender-based violence so when a study
of the world health organization in 2002
showcased that gender-based violence is
the main cause of death of women in the
world
and the 23 of women or women worldwide
have reported some kind of digital
gender balance
for an example in the latin america
conflicts itself in ecuador
every 71 hours some woman is killed and
if
this women don't get killed in a quarter
it's not because someone for example was
trying to steal something from them
but they were killed because they were
women so this is often
a times called a femicide latin american
countries are
pretty much sexist um so
as i said most of the minorities in
latin america don't have a way to
express their struggles or to gather
support
through mass media or through the or
through the discourse or to the
main discourse that happens in the
countries so what they do is that they
switch to social media
or any other kind of digital to sort of
empower
the struggle that they are living but
what happens is that
um because they have been using social
media or they have been using digital
tools
some other groups have actually targeted
them uh
through the internet and actually
surveilled their usage of social media
they have
they have created um strategies for hate
speech
unauthorized discrimination of intimate
images cyber sexual harassment
trafficking inspiration of their
identity and censorship
so if you talk to any person or activist
who's actually working on gender-based
um activism or in lgbtai
plus activism you will see that they are
always targeted
uh by the usage of social media and
there's actually uh
on some instance that i talked to some
activists there was actually a showcase
that
um right-wing uh parties and right-wing
people
actually create trainings on how to uh
how to actually harass
activists uh by using social media one
important case to highlight here
and it's again from ecuador is the case
of juliana campo verde which is a woman
that was killed
by an uh christian pastor
and what this christian pastor did was
that he hacked
into the social media of this woman to
actually try to convince
the family that she was not disappeared
um
and this was actually at the beginning
not even taking into account by the
court but
later by um but actually
by pressuring it it was actually taken
into account
as i stated mainly uh the people the
minorities who actually try to uh
be actively um actively
fight for the rights of women or lgbta
plus
a i latin america get a lot of hate
speech they always get the fresh sharing
of their photography
monetary commenting reporting every post
they send them masturbation videos of
men
uh and what also happens and in one
instance that i was
um helping one woman for example all of
their photographies were taken from the
social media
and it's a specific men created art
based on them
and that was a sexual uh of sexual
nature of these uh photographies that uh
this person took uh from her
account and that happens all the time
and most of the time when
women or other groups actually try to
publicly say that this is what is
happening to them or they go into the
judicial system to say that this is
happening to them and that is unfair and
illegal
most of the time they are diminished
because they say that this
is just hysteria of women in the cases
of grooming
um this specifically happens in latin
america for teenagers and for children
and what this research has shown is that
this happens through the usage of social
media for teenagers
and the usage of games are for children
one important thing to note here is that
in most
global north countries uh it has been
said that one of the reasons why we
should break end-to-end
encryption of certain secure messaging
application is because they're trying to
find
child predators they have uh or child
sexual harassments
uh that operate at a level that
sometimes is international
and while it's true that sometimes they
find the sexual predators
um what happens is that this person gets
locked
or something similar but not really a
reparation for the
people who were harassed in global south
countries
so yeah and as i said um there's massive
attacks against uh people uh fighting
for
rights specific to gender uh in one
instance for example we know that they
were even giving like training sessions
for how to censor
uh people activists that were working in
gender
based uh rights for example there was
one instance in which they were
given seminars on how to efficiently
target and how to efficiently
um send like memes and create sexual
imagery of this person so they will
silence themselves in their activist
plans so the goal is always the silence
and intimidation
in the specific context of domestic
gender-based violence
it doesn't happen as it is often
highlighted in a global note that it
happens often by installing for example
more way in the cell phones or in the
devices of the victims
that doesn't happen a lot what happens
most of the times is that the past would
get the stolens by either by cohesion or
either because
the person sort of guessed um
or what also happens is that most of the
time in domestic abuse cases what
happens is that the perpetrator
perpetrator will take away the devices
of the victim
they will take up away their computer or
their smartphones or whatever they have
um instead of to isolate the big thing
so it's not
much more about installing malware as it
is in global north countries
but in this case there's a lot that is
actually missing and there's a lot of
research that is
needed around the topic there's a lot of
research to actually call
these acidities this is actually
targeted surveillance uh
even though some people have actually
not called it that way
because they say that this is just uh
this is just activists being targeted
or this is just activists that are
complaining too much or this is you know
the state of the world in which
um obviously if you're a feminist you
will get all of this targeted
targeted harassment but that's not true
this is actually
what the research has actually shown in
latin america is that this is
actually targeted harassment around
groups so there are seminars who
actually train to how to efficiently do
this
there are facebook groups and private
what what's a group
with in which the social media of uh
of activists they share and people are
encouraged to sexually harass or harass
in any way these people
um it's something that is missing that
is an interesting research to actually
do is to actually find out how the
campaign
of the the homosexualization clinics
happening in latin america
they are usually happening in over
social media what uh what is the
homosexualization clinics is basically
some clinics that exist in latin america
that they say there are clinics for
uh drug uh drug related issues so you do
recover your drug addiction but in
reality what they are is that there are
clinics in which
lgbtia plus uh people are actually
kidnapped
and tortured until they become straight
what actually
means we commenstrate i don't know but
they are actually torture in many cases
they are raped and this happens all over
latin america
and the way that uh these uh clinics are
showcased or advertised is to the usage
of social media so it will be really
interesting to show
to have a research around how what
actually are the strategies that these
people
are uh making by the usage of digital
tools
and the same for abortion clinics and i
put abortion clinics in quotes because
abortion is mostly legal illegal in
latin america with deception
uruguay and since yesterday in argentina
but what they do is that sometimes in
university forums uh in social media
they advertise this abortion clinics
which are not really abortion clinics
but i like just
um places where women go to think to
have a safe abortion
but it's actually places where they
either convince women to not abort or
like try to kidnap them so they don't
report
um this will be an interesting research
to actually do
and if you want to know more details
about gender-based violence and how it's
actually executed in latin
america have an upcoming upcoming
talking enigma around
specifically this but let's move on uh
to another topic and the topic is for
billions as i said
uh when talking about activist women's
activist an lgbt ai
an lgbt i a class activist and
um uncertain over difficult different
activists i have already said that this
kind of minorities
get all the time targeted civilians even
if people don't want to call it
uh surveillance itself it is in itself
surveillance of these groups
and targeted harassment of them but uh
to the most classical civilians that
people have in their mind
the surveillance that is either mass
civilians who target the civilians or
political opponents
and uh human rights activists let's talk
it now in this point
so already surveillance is also a
question that has been asked when
talking about privacy laws in latin
america
and one of the interesting debates that
happened around the time was
what is civilians if it's only like um
if you have the data of someone and
you're reading it as a human
is the surveillance or that also
includes like for example if there's
machine reading meaning that if it's
gathering your information and later
creating
advertisement based on it is that
surveillance or not and there's still
some ongoing debate around that
i really like the definition made by eff
in this report which is really
good so you should read it if you are
interested in which there is not
surveillance not only about private
communication reading private
communication for another human being
but also collecting monitoring
intercepting analysing it
using preserving it and retaining it
so and what i like about this definition
is also that it says past essential
future
because surveillance is not only about
what is right now happening but also how
much it has happened in the past
in latin american legality itself latin
american governments oftentimes allow
some form of white harpinos civilians in
the face of
uh crime in many of the definitions that
i have
found um they allow in the face of crime
if this is a serious crime
if it's terrorism or is it to aid an
investigation
what exactly is a serious crime is not
actually defined
or when does a crime become serious what
actually
defines terrorism itself sometimes it's
not actually properly defined
or when to add an invade in aid an
investigation is actually a good case
for actually having white happiness
actually also not really defined
measure for the means of civilians is
not really there
so for example there's not really an
instance in when they say
that more when installation is allowed
but in practice as you will see in a few
slides that actually
occurs and most of the times when there
is more weather than it's been installed
to target
political opponents or human rights
activists it's oftentimes more on
software that is solved by global north
companies which
opens up many questions that i will
cover in a few minutes in the case of
location tracking also some kind of
access is provided depending on the
latin american country
in colombia for example just to give an
example it is required that
telecommunications services
um the two main ones in colombia claro
and movistad and that will provide us
hangover location data authorities in
ecuador it's actually really
easy to get location data about someone
it was an incident for example if you go
to the police and you say that someone
is disappeared
they will actually turn location
tracking for that person in order to
find it
pretty easily but something that is
oftentimes found in most of the
laws of latin america is that well it
says that authorities are
can get access to location tracking
there's no clear distinction around
which authorities actually have access
to this location tracking
or even more is the authorities share
between other authorities how is the
sharing actually happening
that's not really defined
in the case of brazil colombia
honduras they all have data retention
obligation
which uh requires that they lock vast
amounts of data about the users and
provide low informants access to it if
they need it in the case for example of
uh to aid an investigation of
of or of a serious crime
um in practice um this is really
oblivious and opaque to the user
sometimes there's sometimes
some kind of notification that says that
we're using a service this data is not
but most of the time the user don't
really know that this is indeed
happening
and if you ask an everyday person in
latin america if they know that
their data could be potentially used
later for
to aid an investigation or that it could
be given the authorities most of the
people will
not really actually know that that's
indeed what is happening
and again there's no clearing
distinction around which authorities
have actually access to it
so let's talk about in general about the
question of civilians if there's
actually master billions in latin
america
what it has been shown that in contrast
to the global no there's not this
traditional
instance of mass civilians in the sense
that they have not been really that much
leaked documents that showcase that
there's a plan from the government to
actually surveil all the citizens
at this scale um but there has been very
much instances of
uh targeted civilians um
it could be and it's it's mainly
reasonable to say that they could be
massive billions but at least some
so far we have not have that much of the
examples of it
so notable examples will actually target
the civilian cell the software uh
installed by colombia that's called
esperanza
and the other one that was sold by
bering system that is called puma
and this was on spy software um for
telecom
community telephone communication uh and
it was targeted towards journalists
political observation parties human
rights activists
and this was all done during the alvaro
us government
um in colombia most of the times they
took way
or the reason why they tried to justify
that they bought this more when they
bought this always because they tried to
help anti-kidnapping operation and the
extortion operation anti-terrorism
anti-drug trade
and this is a common thing all over the
world that the reason why they say that
the break-in to end encryption or that
they need to buy
more it's because they're trying to a
criminal investigation of some kind
citizen lab from the canada center for
global security studies monkey school of
global affairs
actually rebuild existence of command
and control servers from fiend spy
the gama international team features
remote nutrition civilian software
in mexico panama and venezuela and
paraguay and of course the spyware was
developed by a german
based company and the same happened in
with the hacking team in other countries
mainly in brazil colombia chile ecuador
honduras
panama and it was the same it was mainly
targeted to political opponents it was
targeted to human rights activities they
were targeted
for journalists um how it was bought
that raises a lot of questions so why
the global north countries and these
companies were actually selling this
market to governments in the legality of
it these companies
couldn't actually solid uh as it is um
so they tried to find a
legal way to actually sell it the way
that they found it by using uh
intermediate entire intermediaries
um mainly for example in the case of
ecuador there was
a company a colombian-based company that
was the one that was
uh buying the software from the from the
global north companies
and then reselling it to colombia and
ecuador
another question is if it was safe to
use in the sense to assist this more
we're really doing
only spying on the political opposition
or whatever they wanted to spy and it
was not backfiring and also logging
data of the latin american government or
the of the people that were inspired
as we know now it was also doing that so
there was not even a notion of the
government's
abortions of what actually they were
buying and what about superiority what
about
actually buying another software uh from
another country to actually fire you on
your citizens
um that raises a lot of questions
in the case of secure messaging um what
we have found
is that there's not a lot of usage of
actual security messaging in the sense
of traditional secure messaging
application that exists today
in the case of signal in the case of why
um
many people in latin america use social
media if they're activists they mostly
use social media because that's the only
way
as they don't have access to mass media
the social media gives them a way to
access
um to have a way to publish what they
are doing
in some kind of way and the the way that
for example they operate
how they are going to create meetings of
what kind of a strategy they are
developing is through the usage of
whatsapp groups
there's not much useful such signal that
i have no no no no because
it's not so known because it's too slow
um
specifically when i have spoken with
journalists in latin america that
sometimes has told me that they don't
use it because it's too slow because
people cannot really send documents
through signal because they will take
forever
because it's too difficult to use some
people say it and mostly because
contacts do not use it so most of the
people don't really use signal and
so therefore they don't really use it if
your family or your friends don't use it
then you
will not use it often something that is
really used is telegram um because they
have sort of a marketing campaign
for um latin american activists so most
of latin american groups actually use
telegram
all of the key messaging communication
systems are highly used you hardly see
people actually using otr
or pgp because they are much more
difficult to install
so not really that much use um and what
often happens is specifically we are
talking activities about
that uh fight for indigenous right is
that they often don't have
uh enough economic uh advantage to
actually buy lots of
smartphones and put signal into it or
buy a lot of computers what they do is
that oftentimes they have one desktop
computer and they share it between each
other because that's
what they can um so in this case
there's another really good solution for
secure messaging for them
there's one instance in which you can
actually say that um
there's a country who has actually asked
um whatsapp to actually surrender
uh encrypted data of someone to aid an
investigation in this case it was brazil
between 2015 and 2016 and because
whata refused to provide this data it
was blocked
during that time which to this day
there's still
some debate about the legality of
actually blocking it or not
so as i'm running a lot of time let's go
uh directly to some
conclusions so in conclusion does it
still need a lot to actually think of a
lot in america in terms of the digital
tools and the privacy of them and the
civilians that you can actually make of
them
and that needs to actually be thinking
of a latino american context and what
means privacy to the region itself
instead of just
just thinking that we need a law so
we're just going to just you know copy
some of the same concepts and put the
same into the latin american concept and
all will
work the same the same in the context of
kovit that even though it's nice idea
maybe to have tracking applications for
kovid19
if there are privacies preserving of
course um
but maybe in the latin american concept
it will not make sense because not a lot
of people have actually access to one
smartphone that they carry around
all day it's still a need to think about
the data that's consumed by other
countries
um so mainly because the most of the
people in latin america are using social
media that is developed by other
countries and
mainly they're using facebook and what's
up what actually means that
the data gets a story in another country
we need to think about the more we
market and why certain
companies from global north countries
that actually sell in this malware and
what does it mean and like what legality
has that actually
um what we know is that malwa is mainly
used for targeted civilians
specifically uh for journalists but it's
highly used for digital gender-based
violence
i know that there's a lot of studies
from the global notes for how malware is
actually installed for sparse ware and
other kind of
things but it's not that much used for
gender-based violence in latin america
in latin america it's mostly about
hacking
social media accounts or like
restricting the access
to the device we need to do more
research to actually know how digital
tools in
uh how harassment our digital tools
actually impact the minorities
what actually means for example for um
women's rights activists or lgbt ai plus
activists to actually be ha uh be
harassed all the time and monitor all
the time
uh their activities uh through digital
tools
and we also need to think if there is a
secure messaging solution that actually
works in latin america
for activists that sometimes don't have
the same level of access to technology
as they do have in the global north or
the same access to the to the internet
in general the connection of the
internet
as in the global north uh more details
around all of this will be discussed
actually at the panel that i will be
inviting you now all
um to happen maybe in january and
february and to actually talk to people
who have been doing all of this research
um around what actually of the findings
are and what we can actually do to
actually think about
and a specific way to create secure
messaging solution or to think about
privacy in a latin american context
and just some time of reference if you
want to read about privacy laws and
putting some links here the same for
surveillance
um the same for cohesion when a stake
occasion is covet
domestic abuse um hater speech
gender-based violence
and all this um with that thank you very
much
and i don't know how the questions were
but yeah thank you very much
thanks a lot for that really interesting
presentation
um there is still time for uh for
some questions here use our rc chat
it's linked in the chat tab below
in your video browser here and you can
also
go to twitter and master on rc3
iphone csh would be
the hashtag
so far let me quickly see
yes no questions but i have a couple of
questions so in the meanwhile folks if
you're interested send us your questions
they will be collected and forwarded by
me in the meanwhile i
have a couple of questions let's say
to you until the others
come up with their questions you said
um that police treats
females which have been harassed when
they go actually
to to indicate that there's something
really going wrong
as historical beings so the question is
for me
um that's a typical say male reaction so
what's the
the distribution between males and
females in police in jurisdiction like
for example
um judges lawyers and so on and so forth
so
i suppose there is a certain in
this equilibrium disequilibrium
yes there is not a balance between
the number of women in the police and in
general
in the judicial system in latin american
countries
even as far as going like for example
women presidents in latin america
are hardly a thing i can't think of an
instance in argentina and chile and
brazil
in my country have not been an
encouragement president although
it should have happened because there
was actually an ecuadorian woman who
could have been the president but they
didn't allow her
any help but yeah there's always a
disadvantage about it which actually
asked the question if there will be
women more women in the police or in
legal authorities to actually believe
women
that could certainly be the case but it
could also be certainly the case that
even though there were women sometimes
for women
join mostly male dominated fields what
happens is that they
um integrate into the same uh
pattern of thinking so they get more
so they get more easily uh
more easily so they feel more is it is
that comfort
uh on the work that they are doing so
that could also be that
even there are women that will be still
treating other women reporting vats
because
um they have integrated into the same
male thinking
just to preserve the job okay
well that's that's a sad story obviously
i mean that's exactly the way it
shouldn't work okay we have some uh
questions flowing in so the first one is
what is the reason for people not
thinking
about their own privacy what do you
think about so in general i think that
in latin america there's still in
digital tools there's still not this
notion that you are actually being
surveilled and that the data that you
are given to companies actually have
some kind of
um cost or that it has some kind of
uh yeah that it has some kind of cost so
what people think is that they
only use social media as they will be
using casual conversation
they think they corporate uh social
media with that like
for example social media is the same
with having a cultural conversation with
someone
meaning that after i finish this casual
conversation it will go to the air and
there's no record of it
so there's this notion of that there's
still some need
to actually say no this actually is
almost us writing something into a paper
because it has the same level of
storage it's it's not like only talking
it's it's the same so that
still needs to be actually pushed into
the agenda maybe in the same education
system to actually say
the usage of social media or the usage
of digital tools has
indeed these actual implications and
this this needs to happen i don't know
if it's
specific to latin america certainly in
latin america happens but i think it's
also in the world that people treat
the usage of specifically social media
and what's up as if it was like
you know casual conversations but it's
not actually the case
great thanks for that elaborate answer
um
oh wow no it's good it's going on that's
good we are
having the questions now um can
activists operate
properly uh under the circumstances
that they actually know that they're
being spied on
there has been some instances in which
um activists have been actually targeted
and
sort of been aware of this there's a lot
of journalists who actually been
aware of this and in ecuador for example
what they started doing is that they
were started collecting the malware that
they were sent
um so there's like a little collection
of the moment that was
sent to them and they sort of realized
this
but there was no way for example they
they sort of
figure out this later um at the time
they were already targeted
because most of the time people don't
have access in latin america to
anti-virus software
vs it's really expensive and your
company will not pay for it
or sometimes you install your antivirus
software from up
buying it in an illegal way the license
in a legal way that happens a lot in
latin america
um so there's no way
[Laughter]
in the case it's also sometimes when
governments actually targets
um political opposition or activists
they sometimes they don't know exactly
how to target so there was one instance
in one there was
one judge in argentina who got killed
and when people analyzed his phone
they found out that he had more weight
installed but the more we was not
functioning because um
because the mower was only to be used
for a computer for a desktop computer
but not for the phone
so even the government sent this more to
try to target him but it was not
efficient because it was not for the
purpose that they were wanted so
sometimes even when governments buy this
malware
they don't know exactly how it works so
they just only send it
is there a way that they can keep
working there's some ways that they can
still work but
most of the time what activists in latin
america use is mostly they use social
media and what's up
and they get infiltrated quite heavily
in the school groups um
so they can try most of the times what
they do is that they have uh
have now created like a strategies on
how to efficiently use social media and
how to efficiently use what's up
and if they actually need to come up
with certain important
decisions or certain important meetings
what they do is that they
gather themselves in person rather than
using any kind of digital tools so
that's like a common thing that they
prefer to meet in person rather than
using any digital tool okay
yeah okay um there's a question actually
about this panel you've mentioned um
folks out there are not quite sure where
how to find it so basically if you
can comment on that that would be cool
yeah so i'm still thinking of
exactly what is going to happen uh
there's yes to having people from
the uh from article 19 from charisma
from eff
i did something similar uh on an event
about secure messaging but that was with
activists from hong kong and she did and
this one is going to only be focusing
like in america
um i will put on my twitter because
that's the way i bought it
um i usually send it also to mailing
lists last time i also send it at all
mailing lists
um but people have an idea for what are
the mailing lists i can advertise this
too
i can also send it along it's very it's
very in a hacky way in the sense that
it's very self-created
nothing like advertised by these
companies so yeah
you want to know about it
just tell us your twitter my twitter is
uh claus
says wait uh yeah okay
just tell us yeah there it is
perfect that's the one we need
very good um
okay let me see we still have a little
bit of time left now
um maybe another question
you were talking about data retention in
several countries of south america
are they usually then requested by
judges or do you have
some some information that this actually
flows
by some other weird let's say channels
it flows by a lot of weird channels
specifically sometimes police itself has
access to this
data that gets stored if it's important
for a crime
um i don't know how much resampling
companies
and that's a question to us in itself in
for example in the companies who have
access to the data that's been stored by
the same companies
if there's like some kind of internal um
internal guidelines of how actually who
has access probably not
uh but usually the police is the one who
has access or the
or if it's in a serious crime and a
crime when i say serious crime i mean
something that it has
it gets more like public attention or
mass media attention
um usually it's the prosecution usually
is the judge
those are the ones who have access okay
okay
um yeah we also got some some tech
comments here basically so
one person is saying what would it be
what a cheap disposable live
usb os uh be of help
for for activists over there for people
like tails ninja
os or something like that it will
definitely be your help um there has
been some instances in for example
the tool project actually um trying to
reach out
certain southern latin american uh
activists and actually helping them and
i know they have been doing lots of
good work around that area we taste it's
a little bit less because
installing tails for people it's still a
little bit scary
um and sometimes they don't really know
why they need to install tails
and most of this operative systems that
i have seen been used by activists
specifically indigenous activists in
latin america's windows
um so yeah
yeah yeah that's not the way but the
other operating systems they're a little
bit tougher to
use and plus you said people are very
very
um let's call it illiterate when it
comes to digital uh
communication i mean they are using uh
their phones and just think it vanishes
in the air
so i think it's really hard to
communicate yeah
use of those operating systems i mean
there is
also one i mean digital rights yes
that's also
part of the of the topic somebody's uh
wondering if there are
uh hints that manipulations were done on
the level of
elections do you know anything about
that
yes specifically in brazil there's a
really interesting cryptography
by the name of diego rana who actually
made
a huge research about brazilian
elections
um in terms of copies actually this is
an interesting really interesting
question because some governments have
actually been proposing to do
digital um ways to actually elect
uh presidents to uh day they haven't
come with a good proposal
in terms of fiscal elections there's
always manipulation
in latin america in my country in
ecuador there has been lots of
scandals of actually fiscal manipulation
of elections
when they create uh for forge uh values
when they
toss out from like big containers of
balance that they don't want
so even in the physical sense there's
still lots of effects around that
okay sophia again lots of things for
this
interesting hour with you uh in the name
of the audience in
my name which is gracias
they can actually reach you through your
contacts
now back to the studio okay thank you
very much
ah
you