okay so today i'm going to show you guys
the log bit ransomware as a service uh
cnc server from inside out okay so i'm
going to reveal
a water team at the product which is i'm
also a a
in advisory board of the of of the
fractionality's company
so uh it's really really interesting
because it's really
uh
powerful to see how much effort money
they put in this kind of in this kind of
back-end
cnc backhands about the doing and
delivering their bad things
so first a little bit about my agenda
today so i'm going to introduce myself
uh then i'm going to speak about the uh
the
uh
yeah my actually my my title is here uh
slightly different but it's not silver
fresh but never mind so is i
yeah
so and then uh i'm going to show you
guys the executive summary because i by
the way this is my previous uh research
so i i was also presenting them in other
conferences so i'm going to
show you guys an executive summary then
i will go on the on the technical
analysis of the puppet itself and then
we're going to romp up with some kind of
statistics
uh and then i'm going to guys show you a
little peek about the usta platform
which is a threat intelligence platform
built by our guys at
that product and then we're going to
conclude with something
uh with uh with some best practices
and yeah i have some news at the end but
let's keep it for them okay now about
myself i'm from macedonia originally i'm
born and grew up in the small city
called dostoeva
currently living in working in amsterdam
uh i'm holding a lead architectural for
advanced at cisco covering uh
europe middle east and africa and same
time i'm also in a board of advisor at
product which is a very old
pure
let's say targeted right intelligence
company which is uh uh which is uh out
there and doing a really really great
stuff
yeah uh i started with the commodore 64.
yeah 2007
my first iphone hack using sim clone
that that conveyor that gone while that
time and that's how i end up actually
today speaking to you guys about this
kind of stuff so that's that's actually
the spark that takes to the cyber
security
uh yeah let's start so let's go for a
log bit transformer ransomware as a
service first of all
we all know run somewhere right i mean
we know uh that how they do it we know
why they do it we know the the benefit
behind a bit and stuff like that but
honestly when i'm thinking about the
ransomware a lot of time i'm always
thinking about how easy is to deliver
around something okay in the past when i
used to live and work in milan italy uh
i was working also for another threat
intelligence company
part of the service master of
intelligence where we were also chasing
and and trying to figure out and taking
down
our bad guys who were stealing our
credit card information and doing the
middle browser attack to store credit
card information and to transfer the
money right
and we know how complex is to build that
kind of attack right where you need to
steal the credit card information to
bypass second factor doing man in the
middle brusher attack to still steal a
couple of a couple of uh a couple of
dollars or a couple of euros right and
then ransomware came in uh and you
didn't need to do nothing of this right
any of these so you don't need to do any
any stuff right you just need to land
the encrypter or run some ransomware
application and then you just start
to encrypt the files and you are asking
up my money right so
one of the reasons why ransomware is
also very very popular it's really easy
easy doable i mean you don't need to
have multiple people to do something
like that if if you are a skillful bad
guy of course
so log bit is relatively a new
ransomware uh it became popular in
couple of months it was formerly known
by about like abcd rounds
and it was growing you know uh in some
couple of in last couple of months like
it's really so because right now we also
have a top list of the ransomware so we
are living on an age where we are
actually ranking which bad guys are
better than other bad guys right
so how we came up to this since the
server how we managed to break inside it
was that our team uh got contacted by
one of the customers they asked for uh
help and then yeah our team step in they
done the forensic they reveal the uh the
the compromises uh the indication of the
compromises the artifacts and stuff like
that and then how do we end up actually
on the cnc server so
so yeah
getting inside encrypting the private
case we also save the customer files
without paying any run somewhere and
with a lot of other customers not all of
them we we didn't have the you know the
ultimate luck to save everybody but we
saved a lot of customers which were
under that affiliate on the time of the
attack
uh yeah now i'm going to present the
report by the way this report is also
more longer and more widely explained
but i just made a shorter version for
the powerpoint and to be able to keep it
the time within uh within our
presentation today
now
speaking about executive summary
uh so lockpit is also is a malicious
program that prevents users from
accessing their files okay so when he's
penetrating himself he's scanning your
network he's checking for useful targets
he's spreading the infection he's
stealing and encrypting the files
okay so that's the main risk so he's
doing two things right he's stealing the
files
and he's encrypting them right
that's the main purpose of the lock bit
but what's this
what's the very interesting thing here
is that according to the cover
which is some kind of
ransomware or analytic platform i
actually i'm not very familiar with this
with this specific statistics but it was
one of our guys put it on the report
which was really cool it shows the log
bit is number three right now in a top
list
in worldwide about the ransomware attack
so they own a market share of 7.5
okay so again we are living on the age
where covert is everywhere and
ransomware is everywhere and we have a
top list about around somewhere and
markets
i hope that this will not going to end
up in the nasdaq so where the people can
buy you know stocks from these bad guys
okay that's that's the worst case
scenario that can happen with this with
this nightmare okay
now coming about the
ransomware as a service so this is
actually the same software as a service
that we use every day in our day by day
life okay so everything that we use from
the cloud based on some subscription we
call software as a service right so we
use uh youtube uh services of youtube
it's free right if we pay the five
dollar per month to avoid the
advertisement then we actually take some
kind of software as a service from the
from the youtube right
this system is similar or exactly the
same so what they done is actually they
built a sas platform with multi-tenancy
multi-tenancy auto provisioning and
payment system in one system in one
platform where they can
resell
or rent the platform for the affiliates
where they can take carry on where they
can carry on uh run somewhere attacks
so it's interesting right so they built
many mssp portal actually let's call
this way
for a ransomware attacks
uh here the affiliates the users right
the guys who wants to use this platform
to deliver around some attacks so they
can create a new run
run somewhere samples so they they have
a click create they're going to have a
unique piece of uh malware or piece of
ransomware whatever you call it we've uh
never seen shadow synthesis before right
so it's unknown chapter 56 and then they
can drop this uh unique shuttle fit this
is and then they can start
uh let's say
encrypt or in fact the victim machines
let's see how it's inside
so the structure itself is that uh the
the ransomware owners employ more people
affiliates to to bridge into the victims
so you okay let's put this way you don't
know nothing about hacking
but you came to this platform you
managed to rent them
the consumer as a service and then you
going in the underground and you rent
hackers to hack the companies in behalf
of you or you buy a hacked
compromise
endpoints to deliver you around
somewhere
so basically again you don't need to do
you don't need to have any hacking or or
or
penetration test or whatever we call
that you know you know knowledge to be
able to deliver this kind of attack so
basically you run this run somewhere as
a service you hire a hackers or you buy
a compromise machines and then you
deploy your your let's say you're on
somewhere
uh another thing here is that uh yeah
it's also they share the commission the
from 10 to 30 from each round some
payments so basically you know
these uh ransomware as a service owners
they also can give access to you for
free
okay so they say okay here is the
platform for free use it wherever you're
going to have a victim we're going to
speak with between 10 and 30
uh margins between the for the for the
service that we that we deliver for you
and also they provide a virtual machine
exploits and tools and everything so
they prepare the
the guys to deliver run server attacks
which are not you know educated or uh
which don't have any knowledge about how
to do this kind of stuff
here on the on the right side you can
see a example of a threat actor using
extortion method right so they extor
people to to pay them ransom otherwise
they're going to release their files
how is the structure of this of this
business okay
so there is a the the affiliate panel is
it has a
capacities like creating building around
trading and building around somewhere
executables okay so this is really
really important
why is this important because uh
again you don't need to build the
payload itself to be able to encrypt the
files they're going to provide for you
so you don't need to be a smaller author
uh they're going to preview provide you
the decrypter program okay so you don't
need to deal with all these kind of
encryptions and and keys and stuff like
that they're going to provide you a
payment gateway for cryptocurrencies so
you don't need to
think about how you're going to get paid
uh
the system it's not going to calculate
the commission rates between yourself
and them
uh you can monitor your your lovely
victims and the statistically you can
see which which one is better to uh to
to extort or not
and of course they're going to give you
a chat functionality okay
uh where you can speak and where you can
interact with your with your victims
uh here as you can see uh on the right
side this is a text taken from the from
the actual victim right so they give
them for 10 to 15 minutes
uh for the to accept the to accept the
agreement between them then that you're
going to pay the ransom and then they're
going to decrypt your files
another thing here is that the affiliate
itself
uh because they give you the platform
for free so they expect from you
to
bring victims to bring money okay so
they put a lot of effort on you they
they say okay if you don't bring a new
victims you're going to close your
account you will never ever have another
another chance with us etc etc so
they're pushing they're making a target
on target earnings kind of things to
this to these guys okay so it's
interesting
now
jump into a technical analysis uh so
this section going to going to contain
uh going to contain the management
portal of the of the ransomware service
uh we're going to also also
contain a ransomware samples you can you
can find them you know in our portal and
you can find them also in virustop
everywhere he also at the encryption
software and step-by-step analysis of
the lock bit attack kill chain because
the wall attack kill chain is
interesting it's really how they start
and how the wall situation is evolving
to that point where you are forced to
pay the ransom let's start with the kill
chain okay so here the first thing
is the target selection
so lock bit affiliates they use mass
vulnerability scanners phishing and
traditional stuffing right to find the
new victims okay they also
as you can see here as you can see in
our reports they also buy a compromise
remote desktop removes desktop mdp
servers they buy a compromise servers
from the underground et cetera et cetera
most important thing that we've found
here is that they also use affordable
vpn exploitation uh it was one of the
methods used uh that we detected within
this cnc server inside right so they use
this kind of vulnerabilities from the
vendors in this case fortinet can be
anybody else right
nothing is perfect nobody is perfect
right we all know that so uh for that
reason uh yeah they use this kind of
this kind of things here here you can
see how the user attack vector starts
okay
still in the preparation phase when
they're gaining access to the target so
it doesn't matter did they if they
purchase the compromised server or they
use hackers to compromise it or they
compromise by their self and now lately
i was also reading on the news that they
also try to uh to bribe a company users
to deliver a ransomware that's really
interesting right they pick a company a
big one they reach out to some people
hey you know
do you want to deploy around smarter
company so we're going to split the
money i we have seen this kind of things
happening lately right now
so they own the machine they start the
enumeration process they check if there
is any controllers that they check for
domain controller they check for backup
servers bus servers so everything that
can store data everything that can be
encrypted right
uh after that they start the data
exploitation so before the encryption
they extract the data
they store data in the safe place
they evaluate the inside of the data to
determinate if they are going to do
extortion for for the for the right for
the for the for the victim itself or
they only just going to end it and
they're going to ask money for them they
push everything on the mega upload
server and then they are ready to go
then the next thing is
after the data is exploitation
they
can go back to the run server as a
service web page as you can see here and
they can generate a
unique ransomware sample for that victim
okay so now they have the data
the data is cool
it's valuable
they proceed here so you log into your
control panel you download your unique
malware sample only for this victim okay
and then you deploy
the ransomware in your victim to start
encryption process
transformer is certainly executed
manually when i say manually this is
what we have seen like a delivery method
but if there is some idea in place some
i don't know ransomware protection in
place some next av in place of course
they can leverage also the exploitation
they can leverage some zero day it's
it's up to them right it's deep it's up
to the protection of the end point how
hard on it is the endpoint itself and
what kind of methods they're going to
use to bypass these hardening techniques
so
ransomware is executed right
uh
when
everything is uh so so again so
execution is happening recognizing
spaces is trying to animate all
accessible directories and network
shares so this is where the run server
itself is deleting the shadow copies
using vss admin and then he is searching
everything that can be encryptable and
he's starting to encrypt each file with
random isc okay
so i sk this is very important
uh and then
with the static public key inside the
log bit sample is again so they encrypt
also the k inside of it and they use a
specific offset inside of the file here
and this shows and this is making them
like a unique k for every single file
that is encrypted on the endpoint so
this is again
you know that this is very is
interesting to to
you know to avoid uh
somebody to reverse engineer around
somewhere and to find some flow in the
encryption itself and to start
decrypting the files using the sims
using the master key so to prevent this
they encrypt everything individually
and now what is happening the demand and
negotiation right so now all important
households are cryptics
backups are deleted the shadow copies
and stuff like that and the wallpaper is
changed now they are asking for a
ransomware this is when you are
realizing that something is happening
and that you need to prepare your wallet
to pay the ransom if you are stupid of
course
here on the c on the on the left side
you see uh is is the the place basically
where all your files is encrypted
they're asking how much money you're
going to pay
how much
time you have
uh
also restore my file takes file is
created
and help file is also there right on the
desktop so you can read your help file
if you need a help how to restore your
files so they're pretty much you know
they're very helpful right they help you
to
register your files
here as you can see
the lock bit decrypt at the top and the
on your web at this it contains a fusion
instruction for purchasing the software
and to decrypting your files using a
sample sample
encrypted sample file okay
to be able to access this you must use a
top okay so that's one of one of the one
of the interesting thing and then in
this manual here they're also teaching
you how to install the tor and how to
reach out reach out to this to these two
domains that you see in the top here on
the laptop
and then also they have a sample uh
update here basically you can check
uh about
sorry you can check if if your files is
encrypted correctly and if can be
decrypted correctly and also a chat
support here where you can chat with
them where you can negotiate how much
you need to pay etc etc
next one management panel so here
you manage
how you call uh you manage the
affiliates here okay so he this is uh
this is also accessible by the torn
network it was hidden service right
again and it was a managing victims
affiliate accounts generating neurons
somewhere bills and servants like
services
and serving the decrypted software if
the demand runs on with paid so here you
are putting
what the the service
what your victim is going to receive
after they're going to pay the rounds
okay so you here you define the
unlocking keys etc thanks not right or
maybe invoicing right if you want to if
you want to invoice them you know for
some kind of i don't know tax return and
stuff like that this became a business
you know it's really really scary
again trail
mechanism here uh this is mandatory okay
so
this is very important i mean like
affiliate you cannot decrypt
any victim if you don't have a sample
actual sample from the victim itself and
they do these checks to avoid somebody
else to you know to steal the victims to
be able to
to be able to to avoid uh you know fight
between the bad guys for uh for a week
team so they made this kind of you know
uh mechanism to to make sure that your
victims are yours and somebody else's
victims are are owned by himself you
know so this is really interesting here
also on the chat here you can under
victim button you can see the mastering
session case right et cetera so uh first
and last video days total views builders
so basically they comments so they keep
all kind of statistics about the about
their victims and what what they're
going to do with their victims
yeah some statistics here as you can see
uh view chart present
visited victims recent upload test files
right so basically here you go here you
are actually seeing your business
because victim means business right and
here you can see
all of your victims et cetera et cetera
and also inside of the affiliate
management dashboard here where you're
going to
send the creator for that again remember
the decrypt application works only for
that victim okay because when the victim
pays the money
and when the money is divided by the
ransomware as a service owners then you
then for the affiliate is is
is enabled the option to
have a decryption
application okay so it's interesting so
they control everything right
so you got the victim you managed to
you managed to extract money from him
the money has been paid and now finally
you can send your victim a decrypter
that you can drop from the from the
management portal itself
now from the admin side right so this is
the owners so we also managed to get
inside of the owner's portal of the of
the ransomware as a service right so
what we've seen at the beginning it was
up the victims the affiliate and now the
owners okay so here as you can see there
right i mean they use uh my my php admin
so basically uh
they can uh they can manage the the
mysql right php and mysql actually what
we saw what what we saw in this in this
cnc server but what was the most
important thing here is that with
phpmyadmin
they can extract
the encryption case for every single
user without having access to the
affiliate portal
right so this is stabbing back
the affiliates if they don't comply
with their game okay so that means that
if you have some i don't know conflict
with a
uh with a with a run sooner as a service
provider
then you can lose all of your encrypted
victims because they can still access
using this onion address and they can
extract all the
uh decryption case of your victims okay
so they take over the victims by
themselves if there is some you know
conflict of of interest or whatever it
is so this was also very interesting to
see here right that they always have
some kind of vector to the bad guys who
are actually working for them
and the decryptor right
so here uh from the victim side right
on the victim side you when you pay the
money when they got their split when the
system itself allows you to
send the the victim the decrypter the
victim finally can
click and can download the the decrypter
itself okay so this is from the victim
side to to see the to see what's going
on so basically you click and you
decrypt the files
some dynamization about the data that we
found okay so our team uh yeah we reveal
the identity of the log beta affiliates
relay retailers and developers itself so
they use
uh they use a jabber so this is their
jabber contact account so maybe
maybe you're going to take some
screenshots here you can do a few
further research no problem you can do
that
uh next one is uh yeah username number
of big things registered and lost access
that's for every lobby affiliate so
these are the affiliates and look how
many victims they have okay so every
single of these guys they made a good
money right but in total if you see here
the ransomware as a service owners they
made a huge money right because you know
they managed to have some good sales
team here right they built a very good
sales team and this sales team performed
very well you know bringing all these
weak teams
into this into this trap you know
yeah uh again here uh
the aliases of of of of the at the
jobber addresses of couple of uh uh
affiliates uh revealed to be uh also
working for babuk and the rebel
ransomware groups okay so we also
detected this so this affiliates these
bad guys they are also
uh
we also have seen them or their
nicknames or their you know aliases
well well we were also you know
researching a bubble can reveal around
somewhere groups
again
uh the connection between two threat
actors and this of that because we have
still have ongoing investigation and
everything
and by the way you know when we start
the investigation we always
inform the law enforcements always
especially in switzerland because the
company is based in switzerland and then
when we inform them
the wall you know pink and punk
in connection with the law enforcement
is so slow that we are in hurry to
publish what we are finding but we
cannot publish because we from the lao
informants love love informants
enforcements and we are starting we are
waiting the green will let for them for
the reason sometimes you know it end up
that after three months after five
months after two years to reveal a
report right but we started we
intercepted and we informed the law
enforcement two years ago but because
the investigation was ongoing so we
couldn't reveal the report okay so also
here we cannot reveal too much of the
correlation between these two groups but
we know a lot of a lot of things about
what's going on in the back end
uh again hitting them back right yeah we
capture ip address right or one of one
of these affiliates
uh yeah he's a logbit developers one of
the lobby developers right
based on our observation here is a tor
network right using vpn uh yeah uh again
linux we managed to fingerprint the
operating system itself right uh it has
a the
cost name of fibonacci
i mean i don't know maybe it's italian
name or i don't know i don't want to
i don't want to make assumption but yeah
this is what we
until where we came with this with this
with this cnc server of course there is
a lot of things that has been shared
also with the law enforcement but this
is what we can share right now so again
yeah
you know sometimes
we are luck we have a luck to hit them
back and to reveal who they are and to
share with the police and stuff like
that
again some statistics here sector sector
distribution of the victims for
transportation manufacturing customer
services energy food everything right so
basically they were targeting everything
so we didn't detect some kind of you
know gail
gale offense right where they target
only specific country like we had on the
silverfish
uh research before right which was uh
excluding the ex-russian countries here
they don't have that kind of stuff so
they go for everybody
which uh going to fail
to their uh run somewhere or or to their
attacks right
uh
yeah
also that we managed to calculate the
average ransom which was around eighty
five thousand dollars per per week
uh of course uh some wallet id and how
the money flow
was they use a wasabi network right
because they join and mix
in a small chunks right when they
distribute the money to be able to
to to avoid tracking and stuff like that
yeah but you can see all the btc bitcoin
values and and the amount that they
transfer to each other
uh
yep so now i'm going to do uh some very
peak uh introduction into the usta
platform
and please contact me if you want to
play with usta okay which is very very
interesting threat intelligence platform
bit by our team
so now let me share my
my
my chrome
google chrome okay i hope that you can
see my screen right this is ustop right
the the threat intelligence platform
that is developed by our team
this is the main main dashboard of the
list here you can see our rav data
occurs by our rooster sensor so we
deploy sensor all around the world and
we fetch intelligence from them
uh also here on the left side left side
you can see a tactical intelligence
tactical intelligence meaning that or
team of more than 60 plus people are
heavily in underground monitoring and
and and
extracting data from the underground
forums highly private forums and then
trying to build up reports
uh about the campaigns about what's
going on in this report in these forums
and stuff like that
we have also throughout the intelligence
here so basically the full blonde uh
working solution with the rest api
support and stuff like that especially
for the fraud transaction and stuff like
that uh corporate credit card
information compromise uh you know login
login login credentials and stuff like
that
also brand protection is one of the one
of the features that the platform has
security intelligence vulnerabilities i
don't want to bother you guys i know
that you know all of this but
my aim here is just to show you guys and
to give you
uh the the the
feeling a little bit how is everything
built together it's very very nice built
and that you can play with it okay just
email me on my email which i'm going to
share later and then you can play with
it so again yeah so this was a little
bit about our platform itself
now i'm going to come back and i'm going
to show you guys something interesting
uh can you see my
slice now
[Music]
you share
powerpoint yep
so
last
we were
here yeah one more thing
for today and then i can take some
questions
we already managed to
monitor the vet2 version 2 of the log
bit transformer as a service
so again
we are not stopping we are chasing them
24 7.
we are in the monitoring phase right now
we monitor them law enforcements are
involved involved and but
we cannot publish anything yet because
the ongoing investigation is going on
and the cnc servers are still up and
running
but yeah
wait for the
version two of the log bit runs
somewhere as a service
last thing
uh as i told you before
those are my research articles