all right so welcome everybody
today i'm going to
present
uh
why sorry
um
the motivation regarding this uh
talk is actually based on the quote from
one of the black black hot dog
and there's a very nice quote uh from
marco slaviero
and
basically there are more and more
resources in the cloud but the number of
known attacks
against aws and other providers too is
pretty low
so it is
rare it is uh
fair sure that this number will increase
in future
and i hope that after this presentation
uh you will start to discuss in your
teams in your companies
how are you going to mitigate those
modern threats
but before that let me introduce myself
so my name is pablo jaba and i work as a
senior ethical hacker in soft surf i
also recently started
the
my career as aws authorized instructor
so i'm giving the aws courses
and after work i'm still passionate
about the cloud security so some of my
researches can be found
on my medium block
if you are
interested in
some cloud security news then i
encourage you to follow me on my twitter
and linkedin accounts
all right so most of the attacks start
from initial access
what we already know
so before we will jump to the less
obvious attacks
let's talk little about commonly known
methods
one of them
is
i
i am key slick
and it was the real plug in github so
what i did i did recently uh the
research uh so i committed the real aws
keys in my one of my github repository
and in around 50 seconds i got a
notification email from aws
and
after around six minutes i got first um
attempts to use those keys by malicious
actors
now
if you
if you uh
think that a six minute is a good time
then
well i think it's pretty slow for bots
right so
there's an explanation why it took six
minutes why it took so long
first of all this situation has
changed a little uh recently so
once i got the email notification from
aws
um i automatically to my
compromised keys there was added the
aws compromised key quarantine and this
policy
actually denies some dangerous actions
of course not all of them but definitely
that's a good step by aws
furthermore a few days later i got a
notification um well
i got a notification about the created
support ticket for this incident
and i got any
quite interesting information from aws
support that hey i'm running three
instances
launched in my uh in one of the region
which actually that was true
when i searched the event history of the
cloud trail i seen nothing
but in cloud trail logs if you want to
read cloud trail logs in
um in cli then this is
this this is not trivial
uh but once i
uh filter the uh the actions taken by
aws support team you can see that they
can you know that
they can
investigate the issue and help you
now
why those bots were so slow
this is because github implemented the
um
the mechanism of finding those law those
leaks so for example aws keys of course
not only aws keys but
um
including them
before they will publish um the latest
comment in public repository it
they are
delaying it
by five minutes
what it means you have five minutes for
your reaction
um
to
block those keys and to take some
actions
after the after those five minutes this
is accessible for
publicly
and
of course malicious bots then will start
harvesting your keys
this is a well-known method
another well-known method is the
is
compromising the web application
uh and because of which is hosted in the
cloud and then exploiting the
vulnerability like server side request
forgery uh remote code execution or
unintended proxy because then you can go
and
um grab the instance profile that is
attached to this particular instance to
your web server
and then you can escalate your attacks
uh if that is something new to you you
don't know much about it then i
encourage you to
go and
watch my previous presentation about it
if you want to read more about the real
case scenario then i think the capital
one
breach is a great example here
what is new regarding um compromising
the the hosts
in the cloud is that the
the new group well they are not new but
they started their campaigning to 2020
the team tnt group
they are they are targeting uh many
applications mostly kubernetes clusters
so they are searching for
um kubernetes clusters which have
publicly as accessible control panel
uh and then they are start start
harvesting aws credentials
and probably in future they will
do more about
lateral movements and privilege
escalations and to you know to do
um
to make even better results
if you are curious about the the team
tnt operations there's a good research
about it so encourage you to
go and read
[Music]
reads all of it
but now we are going to the main part of
this presentation what if
i don't have any publicly exposed
resources i don't use any iam users
which is pretty common nowadays people
stopped using iam users and instead they
are using the iam roles
and
it is not a rare thing that people
started scanning their
cloud infrastructure against enemies
configurations
well obviously this still can be hacked
first rule
do not trust people in the cyber world i
think we all fail
and
let me prove it
in
in the
previous year
i made a little research and
i needed a
lambda function that was responsible for
renaming the
names of the
files uploaded to
the s3 bucket
so once the file is uploaded to the
bucket then the event is triggered that
if the event triggers lambda function
and this lambda function should rename
the name of the file from test new png
to
scan me test new png
i haven't found ready to use
library so i created my own package in
npa npm js repository and i called it s3
object rename i put some
usage instructions and that's pretty
pretty easy
to follow uh package
what you can see after a few days after
several days there was uh 53 weekly
downloads
but
after
a month there was almost 500 downloads
of this package what is so special about
it
well
i created so here just to give you the
idea the concept of this package so here
if you use
it in the lambda function you have to
attach it
to your lambda function
and then you can you have to just run uh
you you have to give the name of the
bucket the name of the file that you
want to uh rename and the new name of
the file
pretty easy right
so when you run it
then you will you will see in your logs
that everything
went smoothly everything
is good so that's all
but under the hood if you invest
investigate this as free rename package
you will see a line of obfuscated
javascript code
after
this code is is basically doing this
thing so it verifies if among the
environment variables if there is the
aws access key id so it doesn't have to
be run in lambda function but if it is
run on your local workstation and you
have a configured aws access key id uh
in your environment variables then this
obfuscated code will uh will be launched
and what it what it does well it
basically
sent
as the get parameter to my uh server
[Music]
and i got those uh
those aws key on my uh on my server
what is
pretty scary about it is the fact that i
got not only my test aws access keys but
i also get keys from
random users
who were blindly running my package
this is not new technic
attack technique actually
there is even
better uh attack technique which is
called the type of squatting
in 2016 one researcher made
a pretty good research uh so what what
he did he
uploaded a lot of
a lot of
renamed packages which are
which names are very very similar to the
original packages like coffee but with
just one letter e
and
uh
he uploaded it to
the python package the ruby package and
the
javascript packages
the results uh were
again very scary because there were more
than 17 thousands of unique hosts where
these
packages were launched
basically he was testing uh the
launching similarly to me that
he was grabbing a notification
request
taken from the
victim
now
the new the new thing uh that appeared
uh
recently was that one of the
developer he
published a package which is named as a
dash
and
the this package that didn't contain
well
i'm not sure if it's
now it is accessible but
there was no malicious code inside
however
he was testing if
he can uh name package like that like
dash or double dash
and there was
almost
there was over 70
hundreds thousands of downloads
why
well
probably because if you put such name uh
such comment in your cli like npm i dash
space bar
some flag some package name
then it will install this uh this
package named
as a dash
going even a step further uh also a
research from this year regarding the
supply chain
supply chain attack i'm sorry
um
what was about the the researcher
found in the internet in the publicly
accessible resources a lot of packages a
lot of internal packages
packages which were used by apple
microsoft and other big big companies
now those internal packages were only
accessible in their
internal
repositories
okay but
he found a way that there are those
package managers used commonly in those
companies by developers um
they can
for example if this package is not
accessible anymore in the internal
repository then this package will be
downloaded from that publicly
from the public repository or
if
if there is a newer version of the same
package name as
as it is in uh the public repository it
will be downloaded
so in this way the the researcher was
able to
run to run remote code execution in
in
big companies
now going into the cloud
is the package um the the supply chain
attacks only accessible
only a threat against packages well not
only so here's an example of community
ami
when you are running the ec2 instance
you may have may choose the brand new
amazon amis
or you can
take some
amazon uh machine images from the aws
marketplace so for example i was
searching for apache guacamole
this uh so in the aws marketplace you
can find the aws
ec2 instance with pre-installed and
pre-configured apache guacamole which is
super
nice feature because without all those
configuration steps i can
just in a few clicks i can spin up the
ec2 instance
with working apache guacamole
server
but there is also a community ami
there and
everyone can also uh
publish the community ami with the same
thing so for example i can create my own
ami and publish it
as a with the working
guacamole apache guacamole
[Music]
the difference is that those from aws
marketplace costs additional money and
community ami
are for free
those in aws marketplace they are scout
this price
always you know you have always
something for this additional price
because it goes from the
um
from the
authorized sources as well as
those
amis are scanned by amazon
but those in community amis are not
and this is not a
rare um observation that some of them
are already uh infected um here is the
example
that the one company they discovered
after five years of running this ami
they found that this easy to instance is
quite uh slow comparing to others
so they started investigating it and
they found that this ami is actually
infected so they reported it to to
amazon of course it was removed
but the thing is how many of you
is going is using those from uh
community those community amis and they
are really investigating if there is any
malware inside of them
because there can be any kind of code
that is running on your
cloud resource
another thing the serverless application
repository another great feature great
service in aws that you can
publish your serverless application and
it can be run by
others and i was searching for
serverless gold if you don't know
this this project definitely go in the
github page and find the more about this
server let's go
one important thing is that this
repository is no longer maintained
what it means that it was created that
this is the original
um
original deployment in serverless
application repository
however the
node runtime version is the
deprecated in this version what means it
doesn't work
so
there are other alternative version
like with the same uh description with
different
names with different
number of deployments
and even in the
github issues of serverless go you can
find that the the advice just go to
serverless application repository and
search for upsec serverless gold because
it there is a fix and it is the working
version
so
but
what are those
well
nobody knows they are
deployed and they are released by
other aws accounts so there's no
problem if i'm going to release another
serverless gold version with even cooler
name like the this is the latest
serverless gold and people are blindly
running it
i hope that all of you are
reading the code before running it but
the practice shows that well not all of
us
[Music]
another uh another interesting fact is
um
that we are giving this access to our
cloud resources
and it is pretty pretty um often
and
it is only visible in the trust policy
so you have a role that and this is your
uh
aws account id
and this is
the aws account of
other um of this third-party service
okay so for example this third party
service is doing the
log monitoring
for you so they need access to your
to your cloud
account and
most often it is done by uh adding um
access via the iam role
now there was another research
that 82
of companies
unknowingly give third parties access to
the to all their cloud data now
why unknowingly why so many and why
access to
all cloud data
because
because that is the easier way
okay so here is the
instruction
uh from one third-party service pretty
common uh that i've seen a lot in the in
the wild
and they are giving the instruction that
hey give us uh give us a read-only
access role
so we will be able to
to do our job
now read only access and it is very
common that those third-party services
are asking for
such uh such role why because as you
remember as free bucket name has to be
unique okay so every aws account uh
which has the buckets for logs have to
be named
differently
and
the and
it should be the access for example this
third party service require access only
to one bucket and only permissions to
read objects inside of these buckets
with logs but it is much easier to ask
for read only access but it also gives
an access to all the uh you know the
read access to all
other services
now when i went through this research my
first
thought was
hey is the
cloud version of solar winds is just a
matter of time
uh please let me know in comments what
do you think about it because i think
that sooner or later one of those uh
third party service will be compromised
and that gives access to
hundreds or thousands of aws accounts
which are using this uh third-party
service
so as you see initial access
is possible even if you are not exposing
any vulnerable resources in the public
internet now let's go through their
privilege escalation methods
pretty known i hope that it is commonly
known error among you
methods of escalating privileges um
those those this method is based on the
research of spencer bitsen
and basically it searches through the
dangerous permissions
for example if compromised principle it
can be the iam role it can be the iem
user uh if this principle has the
permission to pass role and to easy to
run instance
then this user
can simply spin up a new ec2 instance
and
we've attached instance profile
with the
admin role and in this way
then accessing this instance will give
the access to the admin role
which gives you access to all resources
in your
um
in your uh account
but this is about the lesser known
techniques so here is my research
it's it is based uh on some uh
misconceptions in trust policy because
basically in general
iam role every identity and acts
management role can be assumed when
those two
requirements are satisfied so first of
all there has to be a trust relationship
with the principal so for example my
compromise aws
identity and access management user has
to have the trust relationship with this
particular role
and
it should have also this sts assume role
permission
i've seen
several times
when there was approach that for example
operators in aws account they
didn't have the assume role permission
and only administrators have this
permission
and
in this approach every administrator can
assume any role in this
in this
account
which which is good because
operator cannot assume this role right
so there's no way about the privilege
escalation
well
this is not always true because i found
some
um some ways that this
requirement doesn't have to be satisfied
and here's the example
when you have the trust policy which is
uh
which has this
um
organization id okay so
nowadays i think that everybody well
surely not everybody but
most of uh
working companies in aws they use a aws
organization
and it is much easier to configure
such role
for all
principles in the organization
so there's a wildcard but there's also
the conditions so
so the accounts which are external to
this organization cannot assume this
role
but what i discovered
the
it it was that if there is the
wildcard here and no matter what
condition is there
any
principle
will be granted with the sds assume role
permission
in other words
the trust policy behave like a
resource policy base resource based
policy
so it can grant permission to the
principal
[Music]
and
you don't then
require the assume role permission
in them when you search for trust trust
policies some
references
on in the
official resources like for example
aws uh security blog which is awesome by
the way
you can find that
such policy is even in this block as a
reference now as you can see uh i'm
referring referring to this article
using the web archive because after
publishing my article this section was
removed which is awesome because
now i have approved that aws folks they
are listening they are
they they see
that the researchers work
and they are trying to do uh to do
better
[Music]
this is not the only way how can we
bypass this requirement of having the
assumed role another very interesting
which is
still
quite
old for me
uh thing about trust policy is that if
you put in the principle
role uh
on r a r n sorry
um of the role
then this role again doesn't require the
fsu role permission
which is weird
in
in this case just imagine that there's a
compromised unprivileged iam user which
then is allowed without uh assume role
permission is allowed to access the
maintenance role and then if the admins
role trust policy have this principle
have this role in principle then
from the maintenance role it is possible
to access admin role that may be quite
um
confusing and hard to understand so let
me show it on a demo
so here i have compromised user okay
as you can see there's no uh permissions
so this user has no permissions okay so
nobody cares about compromised user
which has no permissions
we have this maintenance role
um
with read only access so again nothing
very scary uh just read only access and
if we go to the
trust relationship we can see that yeah
there is wildcard in the principle but
there is also condition that only a
principle from this aws account can this
aws organization can assume it so
assuming i have this compromised account
uh long term keys
so here uh using the aws sds get caller
identity here i can prove that yes i'm
using this compromised user profile
so now let's try to assume the
maintenance role you can do it by the
command sts assume role then you have to
specify the ir and
the name of the
of the role uh and
then voila you are getting the aws
access key secret access key as well as
the session token because
roles
do not use the long term credentials so
let me now configure
um this maintenance
role profile on my local workstation
here i'm specifying the aws access key
id secret access key
as well as the region and i have to also
specify the session token and from the
cli you can do it by aws configure set
aws session token
command and then you are specifying this
session token
[Music]
uh so let me just quickly copy paste it
and then of course in the name of the
maintenance role uh
profile
okay so
that gives me so let's now check if this
role uh was configured properly so again
sds get color identity but this time
using the profile maintenance role
and
it is a confirmation that yeah i'm using
the
assumed role maintenance role now
there is another role under the same
account but this time there's no wild
card in trust policy
um so let me check the trust policy of
the admin role okay there's a
administrator access
attached to this role
but this time instead of wildcard there
is the maintenance role which is allowed
to
assume the admin role so now because i
have this my maintenance role i can
assume
admin role too
okay
and
as you can see now i am the admin role
so always if you are uh doing some
pentest stuff uh remember to verify
those trust policy configurations
good
now regarding data exfiltration
um it is well known that you can
once you are inside you can exfiltrate
data using numerous ways
now like for example you can do
a shadow copy of the ec2 or rds
snapshots
and you can then share it with the
attackers
aws account you can if you have
permissions to the simple email service
or simple notification service then you
can simply use them to extract those
data there is even the vpc endpoint
way that you can set up the
connection from the
restricted vpc uh to particular services
like uh
s3 for example so imagine that you have
restricted vpc
um and so there's no connection uh
outbound connection to the internet so
you cannot use as free service but if
you set up the vpc endpoint and then
from this restricted vpc you can access
the s3 service
not going out
from the amazon
infrastructure
but the thing is that all of them can be
monitored you will see logs
in when you investigate the issue you
will see all those logs uh
when the attacker use those services
so lesser known
okay just the luck sorry um so in a
lesser known technique is the dns
exfiltration which is so cool for me uh
that there is um
default configuration when you are
spinning up the new vpc or you are using
the default vpc
there is always by default
enabled dns resolution
what means that once you set up spin up
your ec2 installs in the
vpc then you don't have to worry about
the dns because when you type for
example curl google com then you will
get the name google com will be resolved
by the amazon provided dns
easy right
but the devil is in the details and if
you go through in detail uh through the
amazon
documentation you will see that this dns
traffic actually
cannot be controlled
in other words you cannot block it
control it using the network access
control lists or security groups
furthermore
um
there is the
vpc flow logs if you are familiar with
this this is the service which is
responsible for
logging all the network
traffic okay like
what was the query um
from which source ip to each destination
ip what protocol and so on however even
in the documentation there is the clear
statement
that this dns traffic this the traffic
to amazon dns server is not logged at
all
so what it means from the attacker's
perspective
well it is a great way to exfiltrate
data which is silent uh they exfiltrate
data because it is not logged anywhere
so imagine the following situation i
have the private subnet and i have the
public subnet from the private subnet
every
traffic which is going outside of my
subnet should go through the public
subnet
to the internet gateway and then to the
internet
but
knowing that the amazon aws provided dns
infrastructure uh is using the different
infrastructure
when you do the following
comment like ping and here is the secret
message encoded in base64
then
i'm the owner of the name server
zepsky.com now this query will be then
sent to my dns
name server
uh which is the jetski
and then i can see this secret
message
of course i can go a step further and
instead of just sending the secret
message
using the dns i can set up a reverse
show right so imagine you have the um
restricted vpc
and you can spin up the reverse shell
over the dns okay so
um this this instance shouldn't have
access with the internet
but i can run the dns
cut to binary on it
okay and then it will connect
to my name server so using the dns
traffic it will come it will give me the
reverse shell to this victim instance
one important thing to note is that this
is very loud okay so there's a lot of
dns queries when you are setting up the
reverse shell
and if you are so loud then there's a
good news for you because it will be
detected by the aws guard duty so then
you will get the incident that
there's a dm
possible dns data exfiltration
so what about defense
um
let's start from the ending so regarding
the dns exfiltration
there is a new service which is called
the route 53 resolver dns firewall
and this service was released
at the end of march of this year so
that's pretty new
and
from my experience it seems that it is
it is not commonly used so
in other words i don't know any customer
which is which uses the root 53 resolver
dns firewall but it is definitely
something that you should use
[Music]
why because then you can
see
any logs you have the ability to allow
block or alert
any dns queries
and for example here i specified all the
domains uh and i want to be alerted
about all dns queries and then in the
logs i can see that and then
and then
once you test it you can then
specify the law or
block
rules
[Music]
regarding the
privilege escalation
start from limiting permissions to third
parties seriously this is
very common and practice
what is what i've seen among my
customers
so
it was even uh
that i asked hey why they have so so
much uh so uh wide permissions
um and
all of them are replied that hey this is
how it works the the third party service
is asking directly for this uh read-only
permissions
um there was also situation when i uh
when i found some aws account which has
even even higher than just read-only
permissions and it took several days for
the customer to investigate who the hell
is this aws account and after several
days of investigation they found that
well the this is the third party service
which we were using
a couple years ago and we no longer use
it but well
they they forget they forgot about
removing it from the trust policies
and another great service that you may
like is the iem access analyzer and
based on the history of usage
iam permissions uh well all aws
permissions
it will give you an information which
permissions are used by every principal
and uh which are not and can be removed
so this is a great approach to
set up the list privilege
policy
and one more thing if you are doing
security assessment it is not just
running a scanner
finding just misconfigurations of the
service is one thing but do not be so
focused on just finding the missed
configurations because if you run a
scanner it will not detect those issues
well vast majority of scanners will not
detect the
um the issues in trust policy because
from the perspective of scanner it looks
like
legitimate traffic
okay
and regarding the supply chain attacks
well
uh that may sound quite sarcastic but
but use only trusted resources
now i need to say why i uh
i need to explain myself why why i
didn't use you know more
um
more instructions what should be done
because it depends on how you use um aws
how you use any cloud
and
how your infrastructure look like
so for example one good rule is to use
the golden ami image okay so you have
the um authorized the brand new ami from
amazon which is free from any malware
and then you are baking it in uh
with the all the dependencies
your application require with all
software additional and so on and
your users are allowed only to use this
golden image and this is in general a
great rule
but if you don't maintain this golden
image then it can be it can
very quickly became um
you know
unpatched and
vulnerable to newly discovered uh
vulnerabilities
um
so yeah
so forgive me but
in this in this um
regarding this class of attack i have to
just say that use only trusted resources
raise awareness among your teammates
that such attacks are possible and those
attacks i'm pretty sure they will be
more and more often visible in
in the wild
all right that's all from my side um
so
we are a little
um after the time
uh so
if you want to uh connect i would really
love your feedback regarding the
presentation this is the first time i
was giving this presentation so
uh i would really appreciate any
feedback from you
again if you want to follow me on
twitter or linkedin feel free
there i'm sharing my uh latest findings
okay
that's all from my side are there any
questions