thank you so much for
hi everyone um thank you so much for
being here today thank you so much for
having me again at confidence i'm so
grateful to be
counted among such legends um at this
edition of confidence my name is
i am a senior threat intelligence
analyst at pwc and in my day-to-day my
main focus is on tracking advanced
persistent threats based in the
asia-pacific region including
china-based and north korea-based threat
actors
um we have quite a fact agenda today in
fact so let me just walk you through it
real quick
so we're going to have a bird's-eye view
at the start of um north korea-based
retractors particularly lazarus group
which pwc tracks internally as black
artemis and their pursuit of
cryptocurrency companies for the past
around four years
we're gonna look specifically at true
intrusion sets that we also assess
to be likely based in north korea that
target cryptocurrency and we call these
black alicanto and black death 2. so in
the talk what i'm going to do is i'm
going to give you an overview of their
intrusion chains and what you can expect
in the initial access and initial phases
of compromise by these threat actors so
you can recognize their campaigns you
can hunt for them and defend from them
should you ever encounter them and then
we're gonna look at how and whether at
all black alicanto and black death 2
have any links to black artemis that is
lazarus group
so without further ado since we have a
lot to be covering let's get started
let's get started with the timeline of
you know threat actors targeting
cryptocurrency
we all know that lazarus is famous for
uh cyber heists against financial
institutions whether that be bank of
bangladesh or red bank but then since
about 2017 north korea-based apts start
targeting cryptocurrency companies
now lazarus group for example starts by
making off with five million dollars
from a yapizon a south korean
cryptocurrency exchange
and not happy with that after yapison
rebrands to ubit
well in late 2017 lazarus compromises
ubit again and makes off with 17 of the
company's total funds which means that
actually uh ubit has to file for
bankruptcy
in the meantime lazarus has also
compromised other cryptocurrency
exchanges such as coinies as slovenian
cryptocurrency company and then this
fund spills over in 2018 when the threat
actually compromises cryptocurrency
exchanges across uh south korea japan
um indonesia
at the same time the three doctor starts
developing trojanized cryptocurrency
trading applications that you know get
installed by unknowing victims and then
they get their crypto stolen
but then in 2018 also there starts being
reports of an unknown intrusion set
that fishes cryptocurrency companies
with you know your documents
um and link files and specifically a
link file called
password.txt link
so much so that the chemistry
intelligence company that reported first
on this called this intrusion set
dangerous password
in 2019 f-secure releases a report about
lazarus group
and about a campaign targeting the
cryptocurrency vertical and in this
report there is an explicit connection
that is drawn between the two techniques
and procedures being used by lazarus and
the dangerous password intrusion set
if we skip ahead in 2020 um you know
lazarus continues compromising uh
financial entities and cryptocurrency
entities including one in new york and
then a report comes out about
another little known intrusion set
operation gold hunting
which also targets cryptocurrency
companies and investment and venture
capital firms
so i want you to remember these two
names dangerous password which we
internally call black alicante and
operation gold hunting which we
internally call a pwc black dev2 as you
can see the trend of stealing
cryptocurrency is significant for north
korea based reductors and later we're
going to touch um on why but let's with
further without further ado jump into
the you know the thick of it and let's
start with black alicante
so this right actor has actually
been known for quite a while
it's it's active since at least april
2018 and it is only open sourced by a
lot of different names and i'm gonna be
really sorry this presentation is going
to be full of names
so the aliases that black alicante goes
by are dangerous password library turtle
crypto mimic crypto core
and operations not scripted
there are several reports in open source
detailing this protector and you will be
able to find all of the ones that they
gathered in the references that are at
the bottom of the slide deck just in
case you want to consult them in your
own time later black alicante is
financially motivated and it's targeting
despite being focused on cryptocurrency
actually is very international it
doesn't necessarily matter what a
company space more so what it does
in terms of the intrusion chain that you
can expect to encounter when you are
targeted by black alicante or when
you're tracking this reductor well the
victim would receive a phishing email
with a compressed archive and this
compressed archive would contain two
files
one lear document that is password
protected
and one file called passwordlettext.link
so the victim would reasonably think oh
well you know i need a password to open
this file there's a file called password
here i should reasonably open it right
wrong because the double extension means
that this is a link file and what this
link file will do is connect through a
bitly shortened url to a first stage
command and control server and from
there will come the password used to
unlock the document that will be
displayed to the user and also cabadrat
kabadrat is a first stage vbscript kind
of backdoor that is dropped by a
javascript file what cabadra does is it
connects back to the first stage quantum
control server it places a link file in
startup to ensure that the backdoor is
persistent across system reboots
and will in some cases download a
further bb script backdoor known as
cabbage rack b which acts very much as a
profiler you know giving a more in-depth
view to the threat actor of who the
victim is that it compromised
and now the threat actor can choose
whether the victim that has been
infected is of interest or not
if it is not
well then the intrusion chain roughly
stops here but if the victim is of
interest then the threat actor will
start you know the kind of hands-on
keyboard manual exploitation and
manually deploy a further payload
another vbscript backdoor but much fully
featured than the other one before it
called cabadra c which even has a
different command and control server
kabaddra c then might execute commands
might you know fingerprint the system
and might also be used again to manually
deploy an even more sophisticated
payload that is known as mso rat please
remember that name because it's going to
come up again and again in this
presentation
so you're looking at the initial access
phase of baccalicante we've already
mentioned the use of compressed archives
and the combo of the password protected
your document and the password exceed
the link file
alternative types of initial infection
come when the throat actor might send a
malicious document with macros to a
target and ask them to enable the macros
and then the macros would reach out to
the bitly url shorten link and connect
to the first stage command control
server
or this protector might use double
extension files for example you know the
dot dot x dot link or dot pdf.link file
in terms of the themes that the viewer
documents have there's of course an
amphibian cryptocurrency the third
doctor might also use job descriptions
uh for specific you know roles like
cryptocurrency companies and the three
doctor might even use more business
themes such as you know here's your
salary plan for the year or you know
this is your personal development plan
and an employee at a company
might reasonably expect to receive
emails like that so it might be more
prone to opening the malicious
attachment
on the topic of job descriptions while i
was preparing for this presentation last
week my colleagues and i stumbled across
some very interesting black alicando
files you know made in september 2021
and
these
files use the job description theme and
double extension combo it is a technique
that the productor was using in 2018
so you can see them here on screen and
they reference blockchain intelligence
group which is an on-chain analysis
platform you can see salt landing which
is a provider of crypto backed
loans and then you can see jpmorgan
chase which is a prominent financial
institution that also
has some initiatives around
cryptocurrency um a few nuggets that i
wanted to point out here are that
first of all all three documents have
the same picture which says if you check
you know
the image it says chase like jpmorgan
chase but you know that doesn't really
fit in well with the fact that there are
several companies being impersonated
then you will notice that uh the
blockchain intelligence group document
actually referenced in the description
and comments real ag which is um an
investment and real estate uh kind of
firm
and then
also the description or you know when
you work for companies with that by
engineering the future well-being of
humanity blah blah blah
that is literally lifted straight out of
the lockheed martian careers website so
there's a lot of really weird things
going on here
and
black alicante is generally coherent in
its lure documents so it almost feels
like the thread actor had an intern and
told the intern oh you know we need some
lyric documents so that's going to be
your project and then this is the result
but you know jokes aside um
one
hint about finding more black alicante
earlier documents is to examine the
machine um id of the link files this is
because unless the threat actor
decides to rip off the metadata the
machine link the machine id will
be the same across link files that have
been generated on the same system and
that can be very useful to identify
further samples indicators to block or
also to people on to find more of the
campaign
let's talk about infrastructure because
of course no malicious campaign is
complete without its infrastructure and
the third actor has very specific ways
of setting that up it registers domains
mostly through portfolio and these
domains
mostly mimic you know google drive
google cloud and microsoft cloud
products with this whole theme of like
oh i'm sharing a document with you or
i'm hosting a document for you or this
is the cloud service for xyz
and then the transactor might also
decide to impersonate specific
cryptocurrency companies for example
here on screen like towards the left
side you see um
several um cryptocurrency companies such
as fidelity digital assets being spoofed
but anyways after the introductory sets
up all these domains and registers them
it will point them likely to a same ip
address and so if you run passive dns on
a first domain that you've identified
find the ip and then run passive vienna
you can quite easily pivot around and
find much more of the campaign
infrastructure being used by the threat
actor
and sometimes the productor might
register an ssl certificate and then
deploy that on multiple servers that he
uses which again helps us we like when
introductors make these mistakes or
dismiss those miscalculations
speaking about servers and there are
several technology components that are
found on
servers that black alicante has set up
we should mention that whenever the
threat actor is using a specific ip
address
all the domains um on there will be
black alicante for specific for that
specific period of time
and you will also be able to notice when
black alicante was using that specific
server because there will be a set of
specific uh technology components being
installed
for example specific versions of apache
open ssl and php
that you can see here on screen the
productor will also leave open only a
few quarts uh four four three three
three eight nine eighty eighty
um and sometimes
rarely uh the protector might also use
temporarily uh 2150p four four five for
smb and 1433 for ms people which you
know are the kind of technologies that a
product uses to manage the server
you know i could talk about
infrastructure fingerprinting all day
but taki coder has actually given a
brilliant brilliant talk about
uh you know black alicanto's
infrastructure and so i would really
recommend that if you're interested in
this you go and watch that talk and or
at least read the presentation i have
linked it you know at the bottom of my
presentation like in the slides for the
references so you can find me there
so
so far at a glance we've given a decent
overview of what to expect about you
know the initial access spaces of black
alicanto's intrusions
we've talked about how to give it across
link files across your documents
um across domains and ip addresses as
well as how to use ssl certificates to
find further infrastructure but there is
one item that we have not touched on and
which i promised we would mention again
in this presentation
and that is mso rat
now msrat was so called by entity
security that gave a very good
presentation on crypto mimic that is
like alicante
and the characteristic of msoraj is that
not just pwc but several other companies
in the public domain have mentioned how
similar it is to backdoors employed by
lazarus group and more specifically by
the lazarus group subgroup known as blue
norov a financially motivated subgroup
so
i have included here some hashes of mso
rat that you can you know start pivoting
on to find more samples and do your own
analysis but just as an overview all of
these samples contain matching rc4
encryption routines same section
structure of the peas and same execution
flow
despite being packed so you know you
would have to unpack them to see with
that uh their facts would be unprotected
or they might have uh and
for example there is a definite
correspondence between msorad that
entity security talks about and the back
door mentioned by f-secure in their
report about lazarus targeting
cryptocurrency it's you know highly
likely the same backdoor just slightly
modified
and likewise f-secure in attributing
this to lazarus group pointed to an
almost identical bacteria having already
been deployed in operation kill disc
while clear sky in their analysis of
msora pointed out that this backdoor and
had the same codebase as a 2016 blooner
of samples and
wheel that's a long pedigree for a
backdoor you know
even through all these changes to find
connections back to 2016 codebase is
a definitely interesting link
so you know malware is never enough for
attribution i would caution anyone
against thinking that malware alone is
sufficient to attribute activity so i
decided to look at the infrastructure
and what i noticed is that starting from
a cluster of faster latex little link
files um
that are dated around 2020
if we run passive dns on the initial
situ
servers we could basically get back
really quickly to domains that were
being used as initial access domains by
f secures uh you know by lazers in the
report published by f-secure and other
lasers infrastructure so you know it all
comes full circle it's not just amazon
it's also infrastructure that you can
give it across and at the same time
f-secure in publishing this buzzer's
report was also calling back the
activity mentioning dangerous password
which is an alias for black alicante so
you know we've come full circle if we
take a step back and we examine this at
a higher level perspective using the
diamond model of intrusion analysis
which is a great framework
for um performing structured clustering
of intrusion sets we can actually see
several similarities between the kind of
lazer subgroup lunarof at least in the
ways described in several reports by
like a secure for example and black
alicante
we see the use of bidly links of uh
several domains having the xyz top-level
domain which is not really common we
also see domain-speaking microsoft and
google and like the theme of hosting or
cloud
and cryptocurrency themes as well
um although black alicanto maybe focuses
more on the pork ban registrar while it
has not been seen as much in um lunarof
we also see the corresponding you know
initial access intrusion chain with the
password.txt
file and several stage of bb script
files the use of msoraj and of course
the targeting the targeting matches
which is the cryptocurrency and
financial sector for financially
motivated purposes although
the targeting itself is international
and geographically distributed
so we have overlaps across capabilities
infrastructure and victims so i would
say that that's enough to have at least
you know a fairly confident assessment
that what might be the case from our
internal visibility and collection and
open source evidence presented that
black alicante dangerous password
intrusion set
is highly likely a subset
or a spin-off subgroup
of blunderoff that is in itself a
subgroup of what is known as the lazarus
umbrella
i know i know it's a lot to take in so
we can take a bit of a breath and it's a
lot of information and that's why i'm
glad that it should be recorded so
hopefully you can watch it and make
sense of what i'm saying
but i also promised that we were going
to talk about black touch too so if
that's the right i'm going to move on
and talk to you a bit about that
so plactive 2 is another reactor that
targets cryptocurrency and this is the
kind of intrusion chain that you can
expect to see if you're ever targeted by
or if you're ever tracking black theft
ii now in some cases the protector might
send a phishing email with a compressed
um archive in some cases the third actor
just delivers in some way a malicious
document lure to the victim of interest
this malicious document actually is um
built to weaponize remote template
injection
what that means is that once the victim
opens the malicious document
and this will fetch a remote template
from a remote server that is the first
stage command and control and payload
staging server
and this remote template will have
malicious macros in it
what the macros will do is that they
will look for a picture inside the
original malicious document
decode it into an executable payload
load the dll into memory by process
injection
and then this yellow will connect back
to the command and control server
and then it's only at this point if the
victim is of interest because the cll
payload is a profiler a victim profiler
if the victim is of interest the
transactor might decide to then deploy
manually further capabilities including
yes i know you've guessed it already
amazon
now if we look at how black death two
fishes um targets this reductor that is
active since at least august 2020 and
that is known as operation gold counting
and operations last crypto as first
actually clusters these two threat
actors contemplative two together
the third actor um
has made a few mistakes over time that
allows us to connect its campaigns
one of them is using very similar word
templates across all the newer documents
minted by its operators
and one of these is insert your first
table of contents tutorial.x
so if you pivot on that you will
actually be able to find um malicious
viewer documents that perform remote
template injection that are the black
theft two ones
in terms of themes that the productor
uses the titles are generally
referencing and the contents
non-disclosure agreements
um iso
27001 which is really ironic because as
information security professionals you
will know that this is the standard for
information securities it's quite funny
that the product mentions that
a lot of documents will purport to be
protected protected by microsoft azure
protected by kaspersky as you can see on
the first lure from the top
and a lot of actual um lure documents
will be seen around presentations or
pitches as if the transactor was trying
to get funding um or venture capital
from some investors
there are also overlaps not just on the
themes but on the
monikers or authors that the trade
actors operators have left in so if we
look at this that's actually a very good
way of pivoting around your documents
if you peel it around an author metadata
of nord you will find several malicious
documents doing remote template
injection that are black black death
tools
if you peel around the author never you
will also find several malicious
documents doing remote temporary
injection that are black tools and
several of these actually overlapping
the themes that they use so there are
several items that you can use to pivot
around and find more black tattoo
documents and from there you can find
more infrastructure
if we talk a tiny bit about the macros
and the dll payload what the malicious
macros in the remote template exactly do
is roughly you know they locate a
resource in the original file then they
decode this image they basically turn it
into a you know pe format
and then they inject this payload which
is a dll into either a system process or
another process that is maybe hard coded
such as a notified plus plus
the dll payload itself is 32-bit it's
packed with the mida at least the one we
have observed but it might also be
packed with vm protect for example um
its name is generally the fault the rdp
although the protector can easily change
that and it is
roughly a victim profiler and a back
door and i've included um a hash for you
below so you can start pivoting around
and see naturally and find more samples
if you're interested
in terms of you know
the back door
that
the full rdp deploys there is actually
more it's always uh you know an
intrusion chain with several steps
we have seen at least two cases where um
mso rat was deployed um through um
before the rdp manually and we have
identified at least two samples of
masonry that we assess were used for
black f2
and
essentially msrat is
packed
like in the other cases we observed this
variant has the same exported functions
and as we have seen for example in black
alicantes and lazarus payloads it has
the same structure and sections same
visible strings not only it even hits on
our yara rules that we made for some
lazarus malicious dlls back in 2017 so
again quite a long pedigree here for
this code base and this backdoor so at
this point we're left with three
different productors
different maybe not so much uh using
msoraj and those are lunarof the subset
of lazarus group which we call black
artemis
black alicante which we assess to be a
subset or spinoff of lunarof
and lactep2
but we have to hold our horses because
we have said that we will not attribute
based on our alone because that would be
a tragic mistake so let's look at
something else before
let's look at the infrastructure the
black district uses so you can recognize
it fingerprint it hunt for it protect
from it so the product will register
domains that imitate a specific
investment or cryptocurrency entities
for example
abcbc.japan.net uh avsbc is an actual uh
japanese venture capital company um this
attractor might also register domains
that imitate microsoft or google or
cloud or file storage systems you know
you see here uh protect azure.com
or domains that might be a mix of the
two naming schemas above so you see here
protect.uncapital.us
again this threat actor as well
blackdiff 2 as well just like black
alicante register is a bunch of domains
although this sort actor prefers
namecheap and name silo instead of port
one and will point um several of these
domains to the same ip address
so again passive dns is your friend if
you want to find
further infrastructure and malware being
used in a blacked out view campaign just
rely on passing dns and that's a really
good start
in terms of the server and the
technology components that are deployed
in these servers we see again that
blackdev2 also likes to use apache
openssl and php on windows 64 machines
with specific versions
now you know you can tell me about you
know literally like everyone under the
sun uses apache pssl and php that's not
groundbreaking and i'm gonna absolutely
agree with you
um i'm just saying that it's interesting
to see two threat actors like black
alicante and black dev2
building infrastructure in a very
similar way registering their own
domains with very similar themes and
keywords
in presenting cryptocurrency companies
and deploying the same technologies
just slightly different versions on
their servers but i'm saying and this is
also useful
because if you identify some
infrastructure that might be black f2
and you're not quite sure looking at the
technology components deployed on the
server might actually help you give that
confidence that you're actually looking
at black vector infrastructure
and black dev 2 as well makes some
operational security mistakes when it
comes to certificates so for example in
at least one case we observe the threat
actor registering an ssl certificate for
one domain and then deploying it on a
whole bunch of others so that definitely
helps finding you know the broader scope
of the campaign so whenever you find
mistakes like this it's very useful to
exploit them for your own um
intelligence purposes
so at a glance if we wrap this up a bit
we've actually
also built a decent picture of what you
might see if black death 2 targets your
company or if you're attracting black
death 2 this is kind of roughly what you
can expect to see in the initial stages
of an intrusion
and something i forgot to mention is
that the ip addresses that black dev 2
uses to set up its command control
servers are mostly on host wins so
that's another item that you can use for
tracking and fingerprinting
in terms of the entities that blackdev2
has impersonated so far well there are
several batches of documents and each of
them in personally different entities
right but what's interesting is that all
of these companies operate either
directly in the cryptocurrency vertical
or in the venture capital investment or
financial services sectors
but companies that have a specific
interest or investment in blockchain and
cryptocurrency as well as other more
like cutting-edge technologies so that's
an element to keep in mind in terms of
understanding how the product operates
the distribution of these companies is
quite international the companies
impersonated are mainly in japan and
partly because japan is a heavy user and
adopter of cryptocurrency and the
industry is just starting now to be
regulated freely
but there is also a lot of companies
impersonated in the united states
particularly in the venture capital
space as well as you know all around the
globe really on an international scale
you can see a map on screen of that
so i have a little easter egg for you
you know they say that time is money so
i decided to spend uh my time and my
company's money plotting all the
creation and last modified times of the
year documents used by blackdev2
and
you know you can ask me why does that
really matter is it really useful
i would say yes that overall timeline in
campaigns and timelining artifacts like
the creation and last modified times of
your documents
or stuff like the compile-time sample
binaries can give a good picture of a
campaign does it operate in matches is
it active um every day a little bit
but of course it also depends on the uh
on the maturity of your organization if
you work on an organization maybe has a
very small security team and is really
setting up its security program and
focusing on the basics like patching a
securing systems that's completely fine
and then this might not be as relevant
to you
on the other hand if you're a more
mature consumer of threat intelligence
maybe you have your spare intelligence
program this will be more useful because
it can be an element towards attribution
now let's look at these compile
timestamps or well creation and modify
timestamps you can see um on the bottom
left on the screen
when i was plotting them in utc there
was a peak between um you know midnight
and 4 a.m then between five four and
five and then uh you know until 5 p.m
uh and then between 5 p.m and 11 p.m
absolutely nothing zero
which you know is very interesting you
know there can be night owls that um
work all night and then some part of the
day and then sleep in the afternoon we
don't judge anyone everyone has their
own working patterns
but also this kind of look like maybe if
i adjust the time zone it might
feel a little bit of a more
working pattern if you get what i mean
so that's what i did
i plotted um this time these timings in
very different time zones and
um what i landed on ultimately was gmt
plus nine and that is korean standard
time
the reason for that is because no near
neighbors of this time zone actually
come close to having such a neat pattern
what you can see on screen is that the
creation and last modified times of the
44 viewer documents by black test 2 that
we found
actually have a very similar graph
there is
you know close to no activity between um
roughly 11 p.m midnight and then 8 9 a.m
almost zero
and then there is a peak between like 9
and 12 or 9 and like 1 p.m and then in
both graphs between
12 to 2 p.m or like maybe 1 to 2 p.m
nothing
nothing i mean i wouldn't want anyone to
spoil my lunch break either if you know
what i mean
and then the activity resumes there is
in both graphs no uh activity recorded
between 8 and 9 pm in korean standard
time and then maybe a tiny bit of
activity before nothingness against the
next morning
so you know
of course uh timelining is not a silver
bullet you can't really use it for
attribution just by itself
but you can make two hypotheses and one
is that there is a threat actor black
tattoo somewhere in the world that has
operated for at least a year an entire
campaign in korean standard time maybe
purposefully as a red herring or maybe
its operator is just really like
sleeping in the afternoon
or the threat actor is based in korea
and dare i say based on the other
characteristics that we've seen of black
death 2 likely based in north korea
so
we have given an overview of black
alicante we've given an overview of
black dev2 and we highlighted several
connections that these products might
have to last group which we call black
artemis and specifically its subgroup
lunarof so let's connect the dots a bit
on one hand we have black alicanto the
subset of black artemis lunarof uh and
black dev two all using msrat as you
know an advanced payload deployed all
new victims of interest
then we have uh in terms of
infrastructure
black alicante and lunarof overlapping
in terms of their initial access command
and control infrastructure as we
mentioned there are several cases where
you can pivot back from blackley county
initial access domains to
lazarus initial access domains as
attributed by a secure
in terms of black dev2 we can actually
have an interesting connection in the
sense that the domain abc dot info
resolved roughly at the same time to the
same ip address that
pokersonic.publicvm.com
resolved to and this domain the
pokersonic was actually used as a
command control server for a sample of
the mso rat variant that we said you
know that actually looks like lazarus
but then msrat is also deployed by
lactif2
and then between black alicante and
black dev2 we have tooth reductors that
use a very similar domain naming schema
uh down to the top level domains that
they use they make similar mistakes with
ssl certificates deploy similar even
though not identical server components
both really like to just um have
neat chains of passive dns connections i
really hope they're not listening
because and if you do you know if you're
listening please do not actually you
don't change that we love that um and
also
you know blooner off black alicante and
black f2 would also all have an interest
in cryptocurrency
so if we plot that again using the
diamond model
and and i realized this is a lot of
information so you can absolutely go and
reread this in your own time if you're
interested we have overlaps across not
just capabilities but also
infrastructure
and victims and it almost seems
sometimes like plactive 2 might be a bit
of an evolution in the trade craft that
black alicante uses
so our assessment at pwc you know and
this is entirely dependent on our
internal visibility collection and the
evidence that is publicly available
other companies might have different
visibility
we assess that black death two
is actually likely to be the same threat
actor as black alicante and we have
already assessed that black alicanto is
highly likely
um
a subset or a spin-off group of
lunarov which is in itself a subgroup of
the lazarus umbrella
yeah i know right it's uh it's a lot to
take in there's there's
a lot of analytical work going on here
and let's repeat that for a moment black
dev two operation gold hunting
is likely the same third actor as black
alicante dangerous password
which we assess to be in fact
a subset or a spin-off of bloomer off
yep that's a lot
so i'd like to
touch on a couple things on this topic
and one of them is that black artemis
lazarus group is a productor that is
capable of building highly sophisticated
payloads
and you know it's possible to trace a
whole
uh pedigree in its code base and that is
also the threat actor is achilles heel
the code based reuse is what continues
to allow analysts to build connections
across newer and older black artemis
operations so whenever you encounter
payloads signature them build arrows
build detections and you know leave them
there for some time because you might
never know they might surprise you the
2017 rule hitting on 2021 payloads was
really interesting for us from an
analytic perspective
and in terms of the focus on
cryptocurrency by several north korea
based transactors well
you know
that's not gonna wait that's not gonna
go anytime soon illegal financing is an
existential imperative for north korea
and for north korea based right actors
so
so long as the price of cryptocurrency
continues to rise so long as the
industry is not well
regulated yet so long as it's not
sufficiently protected and so long as
it's hard to recover the funds we can
definitely expect north korea based
protectors to continue on this line
now at the end of my presentation i have
included the mitra attack mapping of you
know the techniques that we've discussed
so far in this presentation and i've
added the copy-pastable hashes of the
newer documents by black theft ii
impersonating several uh vc and
cryptocurrency firms just you know so
you want to do more analysis and then
i've also included
two pages of references to topics um you
know that are of relevance to what we've
discussed in this presentation
and you know all of these being said i'm
just really glad that you listened to me
for a whole 45 minutes i am really glad
you came to my presentation and i'd love
to hear from you whether you have
questions now or after a presentation
please do get in touch and thank you
again for having me at confidence i'll
give the line back to the studio