um so good morning again
uh i have prepared a completely new
presentation
about the ip about the current state of
i.t security in slovakia the name of the
presentation or title of the
presentation is for the third time
everything's wrong
and i'm going to i'm going to tell you
about like a three big fails of national
health institute
uh in slovakia
how uh in our company uh we were able to
reveal trivial critical vulnerabilities
and thanks to these critical
vulnerabilities we were able to uh to
download uh
all sensitive almost all sensitive copy
data on all citizens
of slovakia so let's start
firstly very short background uh i'm id
security guy i do like security for the
last 20 years i created multiple uh
ethical hacking security hacking
companies uh
netanyahu also have some other companies
and in the past i participated
and i was looking for vulnerabilities in
many
many different public services uh or or
massively's products
maybe i should mention that i really
like freak out vulnerabilities in athens
tickets like a public sms which which
are used for public transport in most
european cities also with my colleague
uh we brought the first open source the
first open source cracker
uh thanks to this corrector we were able
to create almost one billion of mile for
classic cards and these were like really
huge so interviews for example isaac or
euro 26 or
any of these uh massively used car uh
you were very vulnerable and it was
possible to find like keys to crack this
car and find the keys make the clone of
these cards
also i revo another vulnerability in
parking tickets in slovakia
two years ago we also did a big hack
uh we revealed
um very very serious vulnerability in
the system which is used by all slovak
entrepreneurs i mean more 100 000 people
to register cash operations so for
example in slovakia when you want to
when you go to supermarket or you go you
go to the restaurant you buy anything
uh paid by cash or you pay by card this
information is immediately sent to uh
slovak tax office
and they use like a specific hardware
where they store the sensitive
information we found a way how to how to
compromise uh how to how to
uh
completely emulate uh systems which is
used for recording this sensitive
information
one important thing uh we always follow
responsible vulnerability disclosure so
what does mean we always notify the
vendor like the given institution
responsible for the given service or
product we wait
a few days a few weeks a few months
uh for fix or patch for from the from
the given institution and after that we
release the information about the given
vulnerability uh we did it in the past
we still are we still doing uh doing
that just now
but it's
but unfortunately in these days that we
are facing like a
uh
they're they're trying to sue us so so
we are facing like a legal process in
slovakia unfortunately
so now i'm going to uh tell you about uh
like something that is related to covet
and in slovakia we have one important
institution which is called nh ic which
means national health information center
what does it mean
um in slovakia
like everything related to khabib or
copy data management it's highly
centralized so for example when you make
any covet test in slovakia or you are
vaccinated in slovakia you're vaccinated
in slovakia this information is
immediately uh
sent to one place so so basically the
national health information center is
responsible for gathering
analyzing and storing of all cover tests
of our people who are who were tested in
slovakia as well
for our coveted vaccination of all
citizens and this is like a really big
thing because it means that national
health information center is a single
point of failure which which means when
anyone compromises your application of
servers
all kobe data
about all in all citizens will can leak
and can be misused for example in czech
republic uh it's decentralized so in the
czech republic there is no one
centralized
place where all these information of all
patients are are centralized but
unfortunately uh in slovakia we have
everything centralized so just one
vulnerability can lead to uh can lead to
a leak of all covey data sensitive
information and this is exactly what
happened and i'm going to describe how
so
first fail
uh
in um 30 30 of march 2020
the map of covet positive people leaked
from this national healthcare institute
and
because in that time we consider covet
positive people infected people twist so
dangerous so national healthcare uh
institute
they decide to publish the the map where
all these people live
of course there was no specific names
but there was uh some crucial
information for each person and this
information was the age of the given
person
uh gender
if it is male or if it is female
and the street and the city so basically
like a approximate
uh address of the given person
and what is the goal of this probably
the goal was to reveal location where
there are mass infection or where is the
highest concentration of the infected
people hard to say
of course uh national health uh
institute
uh
argued that this information cannot be
misused of course it can be
uh so so what what was possible to do uh
it is probably it was possible to make
something what is called the
anonymization attack because uh it's
quite likely there are probably not many
people with a given age and generally on
the one street in one city
yeah so when you just think about how
many people
who are like
males or females
with
with a specific age live on one street
probably one maybe two maybe three but
not more
so let's de-anonymize that
so uh you can find a lot of sensitive
information about property owners from
the public slovakster
that uh
that has all information about owners
including their name including birthday
uh including birth numbers
so it is possible to download all this
information from the public institution
which is called slovakataster about the
owners
uh so it's possible to find out exactly
who are all owners of the given
properties on the given street
so then what we can do we can just
filter all people from this list with a
given h then we can filter all people
with a given gender like males or
females
and voila we have the name of all covet
19 positive uh positive person it's
quite likely it will be just one person
or maybe two person or just very few of
them
uh it is necessary to say that this is
the anonymization attack uh works uh
just for the owner's
of property so it's not possible to
reveal identity of renters because uh
information
renters uh it's not in these uh
in this public cadastr
[Music]
display that we described that this
ethic is definitely possible it seemed
that
this attack has never been publicly
executed
uh so national health crisis um uh
institute central they stop propagating
uh these saw anonymous data about
patients that can be easily
de-anonymized
and of course everything in slovakia is
connected with the politics so slavic
politicians they started to spread
rumors that these other is definitely
not possible and of course it was
okay
uh let's
let's let's switch to the second fail
uh
exactly one year ago
in our company
we were able to enumerate and download
all copy tests almost all copy tests of
all people
now you can see like a very simple very
funny script
that we used to download 100
000 um
[Music]
tests
for about 90 1900 um 1900 100 000 people
and as you can see it is
very simple very stupid so so using this
uh
this script is it was possible to
enumerate and download all copy tests of
all people who were tested in slovakia
no kidding so very simple script so
basically it means that using this
script uh we were able to to download
the name and true name of each tested
person first name date of birth
gender mobile number place of residence
half
information like for example about
clinical symptoms
also the name of laboratory where
the given person was tested uh his
medical doctor and protocol number and
of course
uh the result of his covered 19 19 test
so so really a lot of sensitive
information
so if i can summarize what was the fail
so so just this simple vulnerability uh
lead to the leakage of more than a
quarter of million personal data
uh of
all coitus of all slovak citizens it is
possible because of the following
following issues and following problems
uh
first there uh there was like a leak of
apf format to the public search engine
so we basically find out how
exactly this api looks like and thanks
to this we were able to reconstruct it
and and uh may make this download link
then uh there was possible to to uh make
like a direct call with no authorization
to this api api code
any authentication
so we just run this script and it
downloaded all this sensitive
information
and we were able to do that by just
simple enumerating like this number it
was very very easy
and another critical thing is that there
were no mechanism that stopped us so so
we could do that for 130
uh 30 000 recourse for ninety thousand
ninety thousand people
and all downloading information uh were
unencrypted so they basically it means
they were in plain text no encryption
was used at all
so um just more information uh when we
when we downloaded all this information
um it
uh of course this information can be
massively misused for example they can
be they can they can be misused to carry
out carry out sophisticated schematics
for example because we know like all
sensitive information about these people
uh
there they can be misused for some kind
of impersonification attacks so so for
example
someone can call you to pretend you to
be your medical doctor or your insurance
company asking you for some money or
something like that
so so
we can imagine a lot of scenarios that
can that can be used to for the
potential misuse of all these
of all this information
to be uh it is necessary to say that we
have never ever published this
information and we deleted all the all
this information
uh after the agreement with the national
healthcare uh health uh
health institute
so so the question is
there are many questions we should ask
the first the first question is uh why
such sensitive information about
covet patients
uh
were placed on the public internet
why all this information uh
wasn't anonymized or encrypted in any
way why
it wasn't protected in any way by
authentication
why they store really a lot of
information several months old right
away the information about several
months old patient records were wasn't
destroyed
so so we should ask so many questions
and until now we have never received any
answer to this question
and
in slovakia
we have a new law a new regulation
according to this new law which was
approved it was it was like a pandemic
law which was approved last year
uh slavic camera for government can
receive location of all like a physical
location
[Music]
uh gps like coordinates location from
the mobile operator
for each
uh slovak citizen from mobile for mobile
operators and without court order what
basically means
the slovak government
now
knows exactly location of all people
thanks to their mobile phones
so the question is if the state cannot
protect the personal information of all
people tested on kavit and apparently
it cannot
the thing is why do we think it can
protect the sensitive location data it
can obtain from mobile operators about
the location
so i'm very skeptical about this
uh
because this was like a really
uh this was league of a lot of sensitive
data of for a large part of slack
population
of course we uh followed the responsible
disclosure
of the vulnerability and we contacted
tiered
last year 13th of september and the
vulnerability was fixed immediately in
three days
no it wasn't immediately but it was
fixed in three days
and after this vulnerability was fixed
we published this information
we decided we decided to publish the
vulnerability report
and now
what happened last month
so we were able to download the eu
vaccination certification certificate
for any citizen of slovakia
based on their name and date of birth
and this was really critical
so another third phase
in slovakia we used a special
application which is mandatory which is
called iraniza which means like
something like e-border
and this application is mandatory and it
has to be used by all people who are
traveling to slovakia it doesn't matter
these people are citizens of slovakia
are not if you're traveling to slovakia
or you are coming back to slovakia you
have to
to to to use this application and you
have to feel
a lot of personal data for example you
have to fill us your name your birth
number
uh unit or some id number assigned by
another country your email address your
mobile number uh the information whether
you were vaccinated or and and therefore
you are not going to the current team or
not
so uh
so when you're traveling to slovakia by
car by plane
by train
officially you should
use this application and you should
provide this information to the slovak
government
and we revealed one month ago revealed
critical vulnerability in this
application
we revealed that this application
allows really anyone to change the
contact details of any registered
citizen
so so so for example uh
when
you in slovakia everybody
everybody has some kind of unique
identification which is uh
birth number birth number is basically
uh
um is basically
uh constructed for the birth date but
it's not only birthday there's just some
another numbers
so for example in slovakia uh when you
when you went uh
and you you were vaccinated
uh during the vaccination during your
vaccination you filled your you provide
you provided to the government some
personal information so for example your
email
uh your mobile mobile mobile phone
number and what we reveal that if later
you use the application iranita whether
you be the same birth number
you were able to update
to set up the new contact details for
the given birth number
without any other question so basically
it means
if you know the birth number of any
politician of any person in slovakia
you can register him or her
um to
to the system and you can easily
you could easily change
contact details of the given person and
this was and this was critical
so
i tried to
summarize it again just to
to make it more clear
so firstly you could fill everyone in
its application which is mandatory for
anyone whose broad number you know
uh so when you're when you're feeling
this information you just set up the new
contact details for the given person
you know the first number
and then
during this uh you could trivially gain
full control over all communication
channel because this information is
updated so these new contact details you
could send
uh for example
uh his or her you
could certificate
or you could do you could you could do
any other operation on behalf of victims
for example you could do register for
vaccination
change vaccination vaccination
registration edit any personal
information and so on
so so basically this was like a really
simple stupid uh vulnerability just the
possibility to change
like a contact details for any person
you know like a birth number
so the question is how to reveal the
birth number because probably we know
the the birthday of any person
you can you can find like a birth date
of famous people for example celebrities
or
politician and wikipedia and we can if
you can find like a birth date of all
other person at facebook so it's quite
easy but uh the question is how it is
possible to reveal to find out the birth
number
uh
according to the information according
to his birth date number
or birth date and his name
so
um so i can check both numbers can be
expressed in the following form as we
can see it's basically a 10 digit number
so so there is like a year month day
and some on four random numbers but the
thing is that the whole
10 digit number
has to be divisible by 11.
so so uh you we
we can we can estimate there are for for
the each um burst date there are like a
ten thousand percent number but it's not
true
because if if it if it is divisible by
11 for the it means that for the each
uh birth date
uh we can generate a or we can find out
just 900 909 birth numbers and that's
exactly what we did so we use like a
trivial script to generate all male and
female numbers so uh it's like 15
millions uh birth numbers uh
male 1 birth numbers and about another
50 million female birth numbers so
together 30 millions
but the thing is
these birth numbers were completely
generated so the question is
how
uh how how it is possible to find out
which of these birth numbers are real
so uh the reveal we find out another
government service like a publicly
available government service uh which is
called verification of insured person
insurance relationship so this is the
link
and this is like a really
really uh simple form when you just get
you can put birth
number of any person
with a optional information like a name
and sure name
and uh this form immediately shows you
if the given person
uh
if the given personal birth number is
wallet valid or not so very easy so what
we did
for for example for any celebrity
uh we know the first birthday to be
generated exactly 909 uh potential
possible birth
birth numbers and we use these following
quartiles just to find out which of
these 909
birth uh
numbers are valid or not
and it works in one person cases so
super reliable
this portal had also some security
issues for example the captcha
verification was totally broken so we
could reuse captcha multiple times
and also uh there was another optional
uh fields like a name and true name and
thanks to these optional fields we were
able to uh specify the name and and sure
name of any person we are looking for
the first number
so so um
after um after contacting
um after conducted syrt
uh they fixed this portal so they
basically fixed this capture
verification and they also removed
these optional fields like a name and
shown
okay
so
thanks to these
we were able to find out birth numbers
of several
or almost all prominent slavic
politician with immediate minutes
and also we were able to download their
covet certificates or if they were not
vaccinated they usually did like an
antibodies test we were able to
download antibodies tests
and
we did it for prominent slavic
politicians but of course
this is possible to
to do for uh to identify the birth
number of any citizen of slavic republic
and download his covet
certificate or
result of his coveted antibody stress so
basically we find out that this possible
to do for basically anyone in slovakia
and then we analyze like multiple
possible scenarios because this was
possible to this is possible to do just
for the person we know
we know his or her birth number or birth
date but what about like a massively
download the vaccination certificate of
all citizens
uh this is
likely possible
because uh it is possible to use a land
registry
or cadastr in slovakia callister
where
the each owner has sensitive information
of any property
has information like name sure name his
date of birth
so basically uh in the past there were
multiple multiple tries uh to
completely leak this line register or
the caster
and also there is like a private
database which is called state
population register
only specific institution in slovakia
uh has um have access to uh to these uh
state population which is like mobile
operators for example
and all these institutions they know
exactly like a birth name
birth name of all their customers for
example of all people so when they uh
when they use the vulnerability i
described before
using they were definitely able to
download
to download the eu covet vaccination
certificate for
most people maybe even the whole
population
and now uh let's describe some uh nasty
consequences of of this attack so the
first thing is uh
what is quite nice about this adder is
that
you can download the
value eu vaccination certificate of your
name namesake
so if there is another person with a
for example my my name pavel looked like
it's quite common in slovakia in
slovakia there are at least like 20
different people with the same name like
like like my name
so the thing is uh it's quite likely
from this that this maybe one third or
maybe half of all these people are
vaccinated so what i can do i can just
can i can i can just download uh the
covet certificate
of my namesake and i can i can use this
uh certificate basically everywhere as
an unvaccinated person so i can uh i can
use it to interest around all places
where all these vaccination certificates
are required
and what is quite interesting and funny
is that
nobody assume
assumes that anyone can update their
names namesake eu vaccination
certificate so it means uh when you have
the same name like uh
like your namesake
nobody nobody
will will check your date of birth uh
when checking the eu vaccination
certificate so it's very likely that
this impersonation attack
will be feasible
another big problem is that uh
thanks to these uh mandatory application
iraniza e-border
it is possible to contaminate completely
this national health care health
institute uh database
and basically you can you you you can
put to granting virtually anyone and
this is really dangerous so for example
when you know like a birth number of any
your favorite or non-favorite politician
or any person
uh like a birthday then you can
then you can like generate a birth
number
you can register this given person to
the iraniza
and it's really uh and for example if
this person is not vaccinated and when
you just
register him that he is or she is coming
back from some dangerous country some
africa or brazil or you know some covet
dangerous country
according to our legislation in slovakia
this person is automatically at risk of
mandatory quarantine
and he or she
needs to go to quarantine and basically
there is like a denial of free movement
so uh
we didn't demonstrate
the the the iranis application
can be
very in a very easy way completely
contaminated and makes no sense and we
recommend it not to use this application
unfortunately this application
is it's it's still yields in slovakia
uh and because this is also a big thing
uh
we did like responsible disclosure of
the vulnerability so we contacted uh
syria
uh 30 of july 2021
and
they confirmed it three days after and
basically in one week
like 10 days they fixed uh
they fixed all these vulnerabilities
but
despite responsible disclosure policy
nation health uh institute has failed a
criminal complaint against unknown
perpetrate perpetrator and unfortunately
we are the only ones uh who can be
prosecuted
so uh
what just happened is that instead of
saying thank you a lot for telling us
about this critical vulnerable
vulnerability
national health institute they accused
us
that we
that we stole the birth number of
citizens and this is like this like a
lie because we have never done it
because we generated them from scratch
and they always
accused us that we publicly misused
[Music]
this national health institute to change
the context details of citizens and
steal their data which also we have
never done it because we followed
the black day for its security in
slovakia
because it's very dangerous president
uh
and it means that no idea security firm
or
no id security people will have any any
incentive to report any vulnerabilities
in the state in state system of slovakia
because
they will face the risk of prosecution
so i consider that this is really
dangerous what is just happening and i
strongly hope it will survive this legal
process
that's all oh thank you a lot for your
attention
you