all right guys so welcome everybody one
more time and our today's talk regarding
marvel development my name is pavel
gordos and today with my friend patrick
cheshko would like to introduce you into
a world of warm album development for
advanced adversary emulation patrick one
word from you
sure so hi everybody uh
some some words about me
so i currently work uh in the purple
team in standard chartered so
in a global bank and we are forming a
property capability there previously i
worked with pablo at deloitte and we did
a lot of red teaming for i think four or
five years
yeah we we we've been working uh
together for a couple of years it's been
a great journey uh we've been we've
gained a lot of knowledge and one of the
main tasks that we have to do was the
rethink so uh when it comes to the
directing one of the essential things
actually contact the custom tools and
custom malware because when you use like
well-known solution of course it will be
obviously
also well known flagged in a multiple
antivirus solutions so we started
developing our own tools and today we
want to share the knowledge with you
so the presentation will consist of four
main steps first first we'd like to talk
with you about how the malware is being
prevented from spreading and running and
how it is detected because obviously you
need to know that once you want to
actually
evade that
second a few words about malware
delivery then some covert loader
architecture overview and we will
develop some malicious loader
and shallow share certain techniques
regarding uh evasions of both antivirus
solutions and malware analytics
yeah so maybe let's start uh start with
that
so when it comes to facing your actually
opponent uh what it will be
first of course those will be antivirus
solutions and edr tools but also you
have to remember that you will be facing
some kind of malware analytics so let's
start from the from the beginning let's
talk briefly about how the antivirus
works so there are like the four main
stages of of each antivirus solution
first one and oldest the simplest one is
the signature based detection so what
the solution do is basically compare
like the checksum or known strings or
node byte sequences with its own word
list so it can it knows that this kind
of file of this file will be malicious
obviously this is like a very basic one
the oldest way the way detection because
you can actually easily bypass that
the second step is the heuristic
detection so we got the static analysis
of application behavior and you also
tried the tools also try to identify
potentially malicious characteristics
and use the of the malicious functions
because some functions are well known to
be used by malware so uh antivirus want
to know if the function is being used we
probably would like to hide them hide
this from them
the third step
the most common one is the sandboxing
sandboxing is basically a running
software or
unknown executable within a controllable
environment and see what actually the uh
software is doing so you can actually
know uh the actions and by doing that
then judge if the file is malicious or
no and there are also some edr specific
uh
functions like function hooking and
memory scanning we'll talk about this uh
in a in a few seconds so those were
those were the tools uh also you have to
remember that you probably want to be
want to somehow address malware
analytics and
the malware analysis which they do so
what they do the first step like like
previously is the static analysis static
analysis is very simple uh just look at
the information in the in a pe ap file
you also can do some source code
recovery analysis so they do that and
they try to judge whether the file is
safe or not then there's some dynamic
analysis
and here you got this analyzing
analyzing of execution flow monitoring
of file system register changes also
file system changes you will you also
want to know what is the network traffic
so we can probably spot some uh
adversary actions
and the first the the last step is that
debugging so um uh those analytics will
do step by step instruction instruction
execution so
uh they know what actually the program
is is doing when when run
and
they want to pro modify the program and
the runtime and
try to extract the hidden data
so this is basically what we will be
facing let's try to do some counter
measures but before doing that we need
to actually deliver the marvel to our
target and i am delivering the talk to
the patrick right now
thanks so a few words about delivering
our is called to the victims for example
via fishing or or
just just doing some some or let's say
writing activities so we often used uh
office documents so
or text of files with macros with
symbolic links and we with some other
stuff like dynamic data exchange or we
can also uh
use some hda files jscripts there are
some some native uh features of windows
or office or other applications that
allow code execution and we just try to
abuse them so for example these visual
basic macros which are
normally used for for some let's say
cell manipulation excel or whatever but
all those
macros or
hda scripts another
allow to
execute some more specific code and
we usually try to to deliver some and
execute some some native code like shell
code using using the macros
or
or other uh
native features so uh let's say we we
have this
excel file with macro and
it
ultimately tries to to
execute some shortcut in memory and what
is this circle so so it's a piece of
code usually used doing for example
binary exploitation so buffer of results
and other stuff so basically it's some
kind of position independent code that
can be executed from wherever place in
memory so it's it must be formed like
that so so
the processor can just jump to the first
pipe or shell code and then execute
everything
and
it uses some some clever techniques to
to find its way around the process
for example locating process manual
block and then
libraries functions
as i said this is a
good material for in normal injections
so we can
execute this in our own process or
inject to some other process using a
variety of techniques
and
well shortcuts are like this a perfect
example of called reflection because
this shortcut can modify itself however
it wants uh by design so these are some
features of shellcode and we often
for example deliver
any
comment and control payloads implants
in the form of shell cult which is
executed from for example vba or jscript
or whatever uh
we're delivering delivering to a victim
and some words about this specific
windows shell code for example we can
generate the simplest one from
metasploit so so
the basic metasploit shortcut is this
reverse shell and it works like that's
also the code is trying to locate
processing by not blocking memory it's
easily accessible then it locates
the kernel 32 library memory because
it's it's loaded in specific place in
memory indicated by
loader data located in process manual
block and then it can
find the specific functions like get
proc address library get module handles
so these functions are used to
dynamically load another deal load and
resolve another function so having those
functions and be being able to call them
we can for example load windows socket
library or
any other library and call some some
other functions and
this reverse shortcut is just
creating a socket
using this windows socket library and
then creating process a new process
command line so cmd or something else
and attaching the standard thing to
output and narrow to this socket so then
there we
we have this this rudimentary reverse
shell
working on just on pure tcp
and this piece of code will obviously uh
will be detected by most likely any
antivirus and our job starts right now
we need to hide it
yes so so the first step is uh
some technique for injection so this
simplest technique to inject circles in
our own process but we will usually
target some other processes but let's
start with with the basics of injecting
in our own process
uh is based on creating some memory
which should be readable and executable
we can
change memory protections however we
like but in this simplest case we just
need to this memory patch to be readable
so we can write the shortcut there and
executable so we can
execute the shell code run the
instructions
and then we can use create thread or
just cast the pointer to a function and
call this so that this is how it works
from from c or stickers plus so
and
those macros and and other
high-level languages usually use those
native apis
like virtual or log create threads etc
to run the shortcut
and uh now let's say a few words about
uh
some some advanced covered loader that
we would be uh
developing in this uh theoretical
exercise so
as we said
we will slaughter will start with basic
memory allocation shell called uh
writing to this memory
in our own process and then triggering
the execution for example with create
thread function
and then we can add some some
runtime routines to decrypt the shell
code so the show called uh doing static
analysis would be encrypted and
not not visible
for defensive solutions so
for example antivirus would be able to
detect what it actually is and then this
would be decrypted during the runtime
and uh
executed so this is some some basic uh
bypass for starter detections then we
can implement some sandbox check to see
if we are being analyzed by some virtual
environment
also some anti-debugging checks for
example to hinder the the job of
manual analyst
then we can add some obfuscation to
to any data that it's sensitive like for
example you know ip addresses or ports
or some user edges that would say our
shell code or our implant is using and
then this data would be obfuscated
during current time so it's hidden from
the static analysis
uh
what we can also do later is
purge the shadow code from so remove
this from memory and for example load it
again after some time
also we can implement
some
anti-debugging features there and to
just regularly remove the
this
shell code or other
important sensitive data from the memory
by writing memory with zeros and
repeating that's for example activating
the shell code when when it's needed
well these are some some advanced uh
features that that
just to give you some idea how we can
develop
such a loader for shortcut or some
implant used for for custom
returning engagements and stuff like
that
and one cool idea i had is to also
crack the decryption keys so
let's say we are encrypting and
decrypting the the shell code or some
other stuff in memory during
our malware runtime so we can either
hard code the key or just try to crack
the key during quantum so
this is some additional
feature and also we can dynamically
resolve functions to hide them from
this
behavioral analysis so for example hide
the importance table and the result
functions uh during contact so the
analyst or antivirus
won't see that we are using some
functions like create
remote thread or other windows apis that
are associated with some malicious
activities like shortcut injection and
also we can
implement some compile time obfuscation
for example with
sql templates or
llvm so
that's a variable topic and more on that
you can find on my blog which will link
at the end of the presentation so
let's go
to some actual implementation
yeah so uh let's try to bypass some
static iocs and these static properties
they include like strings or header
details hashes the data and embedded
resources
this type of data
well actually can be acquired very
quickly because there's simply no need
to run the program in order to see them
so uh we probably would like to address
those and we've
chosen six one is the the hash so each
file has its own hash well you can
calculate the different hashes and this
uh this hash will be unique for this
particular uh
compiled uh version of the software then
you got the strings inside of this
this executable then some static
signatures debug informations important
libraries like dlls and also imported
functions and what will be the com
counter measures for that so you know
for each file when you make a new
compilation you you simply build the uh
the the solution one more time and the
hash is being changed so
uh in order to avoid being
found or
traced by hash just simply you can
recompile the solution for strings and
static signatures you can
use xor encryption this is actually
patrick's favorite
favorite way of doing that uh
for the debug information you need to
jump into the
linker settings probably you have never
done that before but this is actually
kind of useful we'll talk about it in a
second and for the important dlls and
functions you got this api hashing so
let's start from this file hash so if
you
if you know this is actually a
screenshot from a various tools so you
can all upload a file there or you can
also upload just only the uh the hash in
case you don't want to upload the whole
file so by simply making a new
compilation you just
change the
the hash and your program will probably
uh will not be traced that way obviously
it will not uh actually improve the
detection level but we'll talk about it
in um in a second
uh the uh the second step is uh
those are the strings and
pdbs so let's start from the
the pdb so what what this pdb file is
pdb file is a program database file uh
this file is generated when uh pro
program is being compiled to store some
debugging information about this
particular individual build of a program
it may actually store some symbols name
of functions and other information to
assist you with the debugging but we are
interested in that because of the
actually the the file path which will be
embedded in the final executable and
this path will may contain some
sensitive information so in just imagine
some banana developer with well
organized directory of structured names
so this directory can look like the
following so maybe c username then
desktop company name project name and so
on you probably would like to hide it
from uh being analyzed uh also you you
can actually fool the
malware analytics so so you can embed
something uh some something different
something some kind of message for for
them or or whatever
uh those api hashing patrick
so so that's some tricky stuff so uh
here we would uh
try to
resolve the the functions
just like shellcode so by locating them
in memory instead of uh importing using
input others table because when we
compile some executable
uh
then the windows loader needs this
import address able to know which
functions to and which libraries to load
for for this
application to use so for example when
we are writing some some tool that
injects shell code using create thread
virtual lock and some other
suspicious functions these are reflected
in the importance table so
to
bypass that we would
try to implement
this technique used by shortcut so
locating process environment block and
then browsing the the loader data for
specific
libraries and calling the specific
functions to for example load functions
on other function libraries during
runtime so
and about the api hashing we can
calculate
a hash
instead of
storing the name function we can
calculate the hash of function then
browse all the functions for example
from kernel 22 library and find the
specific function by its hash
so
during analysis an analyst want to know
what the first site what functions are
we importing dynamically
and this would be resolved during the
malware execution time
and
again some some
information about about this
shellcode's
bootstrapping technique
so uh how it works with galaxy exactly a
the process manual block address is
located
somewhere relative to the gs register so
it's
very easy to
uh
acquire this address then we browse the
peb
at specific offset it's based on the
architecture so the offsets are
different for 64-bit and 32-bit
architecture
and process and
in this loader data we have some double
linked lists of all loaded modules so
the libraries so for example for every
process
the loaded modules would be the process
itself of the executable itself kernel
32 and dll kernel base and maybe some
some other libraries that are loaded by
by the system loader
by windows loader when the process is
created
and
we can then browse this
this double linked list and there are
some some specific data structures which
describe all the dlls also there is the
name of the dll and address and we can
for example calculate the hash of the
name
find the specific function we need let's
say a create remote thread in current 32
library and then find its address
because it's also stored in this in this
data structure
and
we can also
find the get proc address of library
functions to to load to any other dealer
so
and
those names of the lessons and function
can be also hashed to to find it
dynamically so so that's how the circuit
works
that's how circles work and that's how
we can also hide this stuff from from
our executable using this technique so
here we have some screenshots from from
the windows debugger in the left and
you can see that there are some some
libraries loaded and
it's the information stored in the
processing management block for a
specific process and
for example on the right we see
the dump from kernel 32 library and
those specific functions that that are
stored in the library so we can just
browse them in memory to find them so
when we have address of the library
loaded in memory we can go there and
find the specific functions in the
current 32
in memory and then call those functions
just just like any other function like
in native code
so this is some simple implementation of
this technique we have a simple function
to calculate the hash and then uh some
loop to go through
all the names of uh
functions which are stored in the
library so so it's just a matter of
interpreting the dll
according to the pe format portables
capable and then finding finding the
functions and creating two slashes of
the names and then getting addresses of
functions and calling them so
it's a some code example and all all
those examples and that information you
will be able to find this on my blog so
uh let's go
let's go next
yeah so we have faced the very basic the
very first
method of
detection of the antivirus now uh we'll
try to fool them because uh before
actually allowing the the file to run
antivirus will run the software within a
sandbox and check what are the actually
what the program is doing and we what
we're going to do we probably would like
to
stop the execution when our malware will
detect that it is being launched within
this sandbox
environment just in case to avoid being
being detected
and the very first thing you would like
to do is to check whether this is
actually a virtualized environment where
there are some characteristic things
about the sandboxes obviously those are
simplified environments so you don't
have that much uh information in them so
also there are some limitations both for
hardware and software so
first we can check how many cores of
this
machine
has so and compared to like the certain
amount of or of course probably in 2021
or you once bought a machine with with
two cars on board so this is the the
first thing and actually the second
thing is you can check how many how much
ram memory do you have on this
environment and also if the ram is less
than a desired value you can stop the
execution flow so that
actually the antivirus will probably
won't
flag our file as malicious
also uh
sandboxes cannot allocate so much memory
because they have to work uh very fast
and they cannot slow down the computer
that much so you can
try to allocate a very very big amount
of memory and see what actually happens
maybe then the sandbox will stop
analyzing because
it won't have enough resources and one
funny fact about
also checking some other things as you
can try to load some fake library which
obviously doesn't exist but some boxes
may try to emulate
libraries and in case it somehow exists
you can actually stop the execution flow
because you will know that this is not
the
real real machine
uh
one thing
that also improves the uh our uh chances
of success is to implement
multi-threading because uh
multi-threading environments is
relatively harder to do so when using
multi-threading you probably will have a
less detection detection score
and if you have some extra knowledge
about your targets you can also check
for some uh characteristic information
about the
machine so for example you can check for
the computer name because usually in a
domain environment the computers are
named within a certain
convention like starting with desktop or
l or whatever it is if you have such a
knowledge you can implement it in the
code so the malware will compare the
computer name to uh to what you actually
placed in there and then
it will actually run only on the uh on
the our target also this is uh this is
also useful when it comes to skipping
the the malware analytics because
analytics will also have uh what won't
have that that that the same computer
name same story for uh for user name if
you are facing a certain username you
can also do that one fun fact you can
also
check if the computer is the main joint
because probably we will be facing
domain joined computers and
you can also check
for the connected usb devices because
probably you won't spot a computer with
this
device's
number of zero so if if this is like a
very fresh machine or maybe the sandbox
you probably will have zero in
in there
uh for those of you who have uh
installed some guest additions in any
virtual machine you know that this
guest additions they also add something
some artifacts to both registry and to
the
system files so you can browse through
disk all the registry to check for the
certain strings which may be
characteristic for both uh virtual
environment and some some boxes and in
case they are spotted just stop the
execution flow and also you can do the
same for the network devices because the
mac address of this virtual uh
network adapters they're
quite quite common and you can also
check for
for those
and the timer is counting but
but also there's one funny thing about
sleep
you love yeah we don't have much to how
much time left but let's quickly
talk about the time you're conceiving so
we have
some functions like sleep or individual
execution to
delay the execution of our exam
application and we could use this to
just to time out the analysis because
let's say
sandbox
usually have a few minutes allocated for
for sample analysis and
it would be a good idea to just see the
application for like let's say half an
hour and then skip the analysis so what
the sandbox can do is
just
hook the function
and return some some false uh
information about about the time past so
let's say we are uh
sleeping for for
one hour
and the sleep was fast forwarded by by
the sandbox
due to function hugging we think we
could then check
uh
what
amount of time actually passed so if
it's uh less than the one hour we can
assume that it's sandbox
or some some other
fake environment
but the thing is the the function that
is returning
the system up time or
wherever we use to calculate the actual
time all can also be hooked uh to return
the false time
with the
aligned to this fast forward that sleeps
but there's there is another thing we
can do there is some
kernel data structure it's called k user
data and as its
name says it's some kernel data shared
with user and there are
some on this data structure
the actual system up time is located and
this requires some some
gimmicks and
points or mathematics and calculation
but
ultimately we can get the i think it's
most
reliable uh source of the system time
and we can compare this before and after
sleeping to see if the sleep function
was hooked and our
execution delay was fast forwarded
and uh about
some some a few words about function
hooking why it's it's done for example
by some boxes or evrs so to to monitor
my relationship behavior for example to
fast forward i
execution delay attempts or to monitor
some some
suspicious functions that are used for
example
create thread or the lowest level
antiquater idx function this can be
monitored to see
what is
what kind of
threads threads are created in in which
processes for example to decide if it's
something measures or not
or
the anti-radical memory it's used by all
those dumping functions that
for example
this pro program tool it's using that or
some some other custom tools can use
that for example to
dump lsa sets memory so some edr for
example can we can monitor those
functions and just block
the anti-reduction memory call if it's
targeting the lsat process
so
it's some kind of
defensive measure and we can also try to
bypass this so to find hooks we can
find our
functions in the ls loaded memory and
check if they are modified for example
by
checking first instructions or just
comparing them with original development
disk
and also uh
in the same way we can unhook the
function so let's say we have some some
hooked function
and we know it's hooked so the
instructions are modified and the
execution flow is transferred to some
library of some edr tool or wherever
it's loaded in memory
uh we can just
replace the first bytes to restore the
the original
function flow and then call this
function which will be unhooked and this
should help us to bypass those
detections based on function hooking by
sandboxes for edrs
and others
another kind of bypass of function
hooking we can just execute the ciscos
directly so here we have example of
create thread call stack and ultimately
the lowest level
in user space the
and
on the right you see the actual
implementation of this function and it's
just a cisco so it's called specific
processor instruction to transfer the
execution flow to kernel and then the
kernel is is
handling the the thread creation
prosecution and lots of other stuff so
we can just try to
directly call the kernel and bypass
all those hooks if they are implemented
so
to do this
it's it's some
quick tutorial how to do this in c in
assembly so we define the cisco in
assembly then we define the function
in c as an external function which would
be
like imported from disassembly compiled
and the function has to
get all the needed parameters so so
this would be placed on registers in
stock and then after issuing the cisco
calling
this function would actually
invoke the cisco and specific parameters
will be present in the right places and
kernel would
know what to do with this and for
example create this this new thread in
our process
so this would bypass some user land
hooks
put there by edrs or sandboxes
and some anti-debugging
we can implement some
either very trivial or more advanced
checks we will just go through
some of them
and
there is this function is debugger
present
and
obviously it returns the status
unless it's it's modified by analyst
or for example
debuggers also can can
tamper with this data so
to bypass just the simplest debugging we
can we can check this uh
this status of his debugger present or
some other flux because his debugger
present is just checking a big box
flagging process from around the block
and this anti-global flag this the
second flag is also located in process
garment block and it indicates if the
process is debugged or not so to
that just simplest and debugging measure
it's
easy to bypass this but
when we are dealing with some automated
debugging core or i don't know
non-advanced analyst we can just
try to to check those flags and then
if the process is debugged just
terminate it
and some some example of of more
advanced anti-debugging measure
we can implement implement some function
let's say we have this crucial function
and
right after the function implements some
some other function and then
during the runtime try to calculate the
function bytes hash so if we have this
function unmodified in memory the hash
would
have the specific value but for example
if there's a breakpoint placed in this
crucial function of ours
the
hash of the assembly in memory would be
different so we could for example have
another thread running uh regularly
checking the
uh
op codes so assembly and calculating
hash of the assembly of specific
function we are interested in and to see
if it's being modified by for example
some some breakpoint or some other uh
manual tampering by by analyst using
debugger and then for example terminate
the process when we detect such an
activity
so
one of many examples of
some cool and debugging stuff
and also to
make
money well analysis a little bit
difficult
we can implement some
uh
callbacks so there are some asynchronous
functions like
read file
this extend version so
normally read file just work
synchronously and returns the handle to
file when it's
loaded from
red from
specific place and this with fire ex
function it can
be can work asynchronously and then just
monitor us when when the file is
when the file read is finished so in
this piece of code
the
callback my callback function will be
called after the file has been read and
we can implement some some malicious
activity in this callback so when uh
analyst just jumps over the
call to read file
uh the the shell caller wherever we are
executing in this call but would be
executed
somehow in in background so it would be
harder to spot this so an analyst would
need to click
step by step through this uh read file
call to locate this this callback so so
it's it's could have some kind of cool
trick to
hinder with manual analysis
so uh yeah that's that's it and uh we
don't have much time left so maybe let's
go quickly through the other clever
techniques uh so the first one is there
is the parenthetic proofing so
uh this is like the simple uh simple
method to uh
hide the
apparent process in the relation like
the parent child and
you can you can actually uh prove that
in order to hide for example uh block
motors activity like uh
word or excel application starting
powershell you probably uh want to want
to hide that some uh some antivirus and
some monitoring tools have alerts for
that so that's that's kinda useful
uh also uh we've
previously we've talked briefly about
dixor encryption or so you can take it
to the whole level and you can use some
advanced uh encryption techniques uh to
to hide
data and
the
from being
being decoded and you can also
encrypt any data before putting it in it
into the application and then
just try to brute force that instead of
hard coding
a key in the
[Music]
in the source code it will make the
analysis even more difficult uh you can
also for example build a pipeline if
which uses the random key for each each
compilation and this will be a pretty
pretty much a funny thing
and the last one is somehow uh
connected to the sandbox evasion we've
talked before you can use environmental
keying so you can target the specific
organization or even the person uh just
by just checking and placing some
conditional statements like uh username
or computer name
before the
first the software is
executed
yeah we made we made it in time i guess
uh so uh so that's that's it what we
have for you today when
we encourage you to visit patrick's blog
there are a couple of more clever
techniques
to go through
so thank you let's let's go back to the
studio