thank you
okay hello everyone
welcome to the meeting of the six law
working group please make sure that you
are in the right room
my name is Carlos Gomez we are the
cherish shweta bandari she is online
today
we have our responsible ad Eric client
here
and we have at least one minute taker
Dominique volunteered once again as
minute taker for six laws so thank you
so much for your continued support
and we encourage actually everyone to
join the collaborative process of taking
minutes which will be done as usual by
means of hedge doc you can find the
pointer at the end of the slide
also we might need some jabber or zulip
scribe is there anyone who would like to
volunteer
if not then we'll see if we can handle
that by ourselves
and finally on the screen you can also
find the link to the online agenda which
anyway you have probably seen many times
already
so there are a few tips for this meeting
similar to the last couple of meetings
which had an in-person component
for in-person participants please make
sure that you sign into the session into
the meet Echo session for example by
using the on-site tool which you can
find from the data tracker agenda it's
also available from QR codes here
recall that we are going to use meteco
to manage the queue
so there's a single unified queue which
is the one in meteco
also for remote participants well you
just need to keep your audio and video
off unless you are presenting something
then this is the node well this is a
reminder of ITF policies on several
important topics such as patents code of
conduct few others so please make sure
that you have read it
and this is the agenda proposed for
today
so the first presentation is the usual
chairs introduction which is currently
in progress
this will be followed by an update of
the IPv6 over NFC draft given by Young
Wang Choi
next there will be an update of the six
low use cases draft by Jung Yoon Hong
and that will be followed by a couple of
presentations related with neighbor
Discovery the first one is multicast
address listener registration and the
second one is a new draft although the
idea had been presented in a previous
ITF which is on prefix registration both
will be given by pascala
then there will be another set of two
presentations you may recall that in
August we had a call for working group
adoption on the document that was known
as native short address NSA so there was
a lot of discussion then and the authors
have updated the documents and now they
have been renamed as path aware semantic
addressing pasa
so there will be a presentation on the
base draft and also the companion
reliability considerations draft both
presentations given by Luigi
then I will present uh the update of the
draft on transmission of chicompress
package of the 15.4 networks and as you
can see these leads already to the total
allocated time for this session which is
90 minutes so you can see that this is a
pretty packed agenda so we need to
kindly request the presenters to try to
stick to the allocated times which in
addition should allow for some time for
discussion and questions and so on
nevertheless if time permits we have
another presentation which is entitled
IP payload compression excluding
transport layer by hangxi
so is there any common any question on
the agenda
okay
if there is none
let's proceed to the status report on
the working group documents we have
currently four working group documents
in six law
the first one is IPv6 over PLC which is
currently in the RFC editor queue
the second document is IPv6 over NFC you
may recall that this draft was evaluated
some time ago by the isg then it was
modified and now after some time the
draft has been updated and also we have
interesting news that the draft is back
in isg evaluation State and it is
actually scheduled for the telechat
agenda in December
so it will be interesting to see the the
feedback from the isg and there will be
a presentation on the last update later
today
the third document is the six low use
cases draft
which had been evaluated by a couple of
directorates then the draft has been
updated trying to address the remaining
commands and the document has also
entered the isg evaluation State and
it's actually on the same telechat
agenda on the same day in December
this will also be presented later today
and the last working group document is
the multicast address listener
registration draft which has been
updated several times since the last ITF
and it is perhaps getting close to being
ready for working group last call
so
um is there any comment or question
if not then let's proceed to the first
or the next presentation which is on
IPv6 over NFC
oh
the Commerce that this is your one
choice from entry career
um I'm going to present that
the object or the status of date of the
IPP system NFC this version is number
18.
next slide please
the first page is the kick introduction
about the LFC actually
every time I shoot that the
and this is the the history of the draft
the draft has such a long history
actually
uh I think the the longest history ever
or ever in ITF I think
uh last the first Stella chat two years
ago just we got the updated two for two
draft budget the number 17 after that
the uh there is something common from
the Eric day he wanted to know the
changes the because the the there's
newly list of the the data link of the
NFC is for the number waterfall from the
Wonder three so he want to know the
changes between the two specifications
so
and then after that the finally I got
the good news from the Eric with the
draft update with the new schedule of
the telechat and the we are going to
second round the child chat on December
next slide please
this is current status
let's try it please
so since the previous meeting results
actually to Eric gave us the comment uh
gave me the comment actually
uh he got the finally reviewed about the
the
of two specification of the data link of
NFC version
1.3 and on the four
but I think he did doesn't know do not
have any any more
concerned about that changes what about
the two between the two uh
specifications and then he gave us gave
me that one comment from about the
secret concentration
revision about that the
incompressibility the other uh six or
four document
and then a couple of days ago he also
gave me
um
they mentioned about the RFC sorry
756 about that the survive the layer
sequence condition five position six uh
he gave me that the I think we need to
put the new references of the RFC
770s
37 56. so because I will produce the new
draft version maybe 19 as soon as I I
finished we finished that the sixth row
session this time next slide please
so this is the details of the the
changes from the version 17 to 80 80.
uh actually I got I gave some example
explanation about that the first crop
about that the llcp this is still a data
link of the NFC version number 1.4 is
the it's about that security data
transfer
lsdpa
and the second paragraph is actually
this kind of the the short address
the cluster of a fixed consideration
about the salt should address of the NFC
next slide please
so next step actually
uh I'm going to produce television the
19th I put that I mentioned that the RFC
sorry 7 56 will be there you'll be that
will be
put and then we will have the second
round the TeleCheck on December 15th
so I can see that the final step
finally and then I can see it at the end
of the a little bit more that before I
think thank you
any comment down
comment
any questions or comments
in the room or remotely
okay so if there are none
thank you for the presentation it will
be interesting to see the feedback from
the ASG hopefully in just a few weeks so
the next presentation is the six low use
cases draft
okay uh good afternoon everyone my name
is
present the sixth row use k-thrift next
page please
uh this is the history and status or
this is the 14 revision so in this year
so February this document will to ISC
evaluation so we are awaiting some of
the feedback next page
yes so this is the opaque after last
meeting or we call
a couple of command so we believe that
we are we reserved or comment but among
document from the robot
or spark or there are some the command
was not remaining as on the result that
is the handling appendix a and the
security control section so appendix a
is neither introduced or differs from
the body of this document so we ask why
it is here yes he's right so in the
revision we try to resolve his command
and the second thing is the security
control section uh Robert Sparks says
that he didn't satisfy our update so in
this revision we also try to resolve his
command next page
the first thing is to appendix a the
appendix a is a design space dimension
for sixth row deployment so in all the
position of this draft or this content
in Authentics a is located in main body
but or during the progress in this left
and resolving some document it was moved
to appendix a also the other comment to
keep the appendix a because it provides
useful information for sixth row
deployment so our resolution is to add a
related sentence in the introducing
section so it is a simple modification
next phase
yeah the second thing is to security
control section it was come from the
robot spark so import the text is like
this it is a little short but He
suggests to add some sentence which is
related to L2 layer of security so we uh
analyze the other six row RFC document
so we cut some ideas from the existing
sixth row rfps document so we modify the
security control section as like it is
so in the last week I replied to robot
spark for how about or changing this
update but until now we don't have any
feedback
yeah we hope so it resolved his command
okay next page please
just stay true okay thank you any
question Workman
any comments questions
so it seems we have none this is also
another document that is on the telechat
agenda for December so it will be
interesting to see also the feedback
from the ASG on this document
thank you thank you very much
so the next couple of presentations will
be given by Pascal on the two drafts
related with IPv6 and D
ude hello um
so this is Pascal from Cisco
um this document here is an extension of
RFC 8505 that aims at uh
registering not only unicast addresses
we do in 8505 but also multicast and
anycast addresses
it comes from a requirement that was
made by the white sun Alliance so for
those who are not aware of the wise and
Alliance wise and
develops a standard for smart grid
devices which operates on the 802.15
forcepgig ASM band
so that's that allows several kilometers
between devices
and the devices are deployed in mesh
networks which can range from Androids
to thousands of nodes
those nodes join the network using six
slope nnd and then repo is used to Route
inside the the subnet so each mesh is a
single 64 where you can find those
thousands of nodes and the links are
about 100 kbps speed
so it's all route over using repo
now the reason why we developed six
slope and indeed the way we did was to
avoid multicast because the 6lopan
devices are usually sleeping so they
cannot respond to lookups and we cannot
afford basically the the energy of of
broadcasting all the time
so devices Alliance recognize that but
at the same time they said a we also
have uh multicast traffic
and the benefits we see for six slope
and ND for unicast we want those same
benefits for multicast and so when they
looked at MLD they said well well that
won't float the boat we need something
where the device can sleep exactly the
same way as it would
for a unicast and so we turned the MLD
model where the router pulls the devices
and the devices have to be awake into
just 48505 same thing as a model where
the device wakes up makes a request to
the router and can go back to sleep
um for those who are aware of RFC 9010
RFC 9010 allows to redistribute the
host's addresses which are learned from
8505 into repo
so these are called external routes but
triple allows for Unique for address and
prefix external rods
it Ripple also allows for multicast
addresses and anycast addresses so what
we do in this draft is not only enable
the registration of anycast and
multicast addresses in 8505 we also
couple that with work on the Ripple side
to redistribute this knowledge into repo
same message 505 the advertisement is uh
unaware and Abstract agnostic to the
rotting that happens on the other side
of the router so today we want to use
this for any other multicast rotting
protocol like PM we can we can always do
that
um so this this makes it so that the
six-dependent family is growing
um we so we have this multicast
registration which as you said is is
close to finish we are done with this
document pretty much we have the unicast
lookup which has not progressed for a
long time we've not been working on it
we'll have to decide what we do with it
but basically the idea is since the
rotting fabric knows where the addresses
are why do we still broadcast work as
lookups so can we generalize what we do
uh in so we don't even have broadcast
value caps and then there is the new uh
member of the family which I will
discuss after which is the prefix
registration
so
this gives us kind of an interesting
family now
next slide please
so what changes do we see so as you said
callous we've moved uh quite a bit since
last day ATF so um we have improved the
terminology we have beefed up the
section that says how we improve uh
Ripple we extend repo the six slope and
piece itself has been uh rather stable
but on the Ripple side we have improved
in particular the way we look at
freshness
for those who are aware of the way
Reaper works there is a sequence counter
that comes from the host when the host
moves which is password 505 and then
redistributing in redistributed into
repo as a sequence counter the path
sequence that allows to find which is
the most fresh the freshest path and key
on the older path
well when you inject a multicaster
drives for multiple members those
numbers may not compare
because each each host will or each
router will maintain its own sequence
number so as long as it's Unique as it's
okay there is a single one but if it's
multicast then there can be multiple
sources and the numbers cannot compare
so we we explain how we use the rubber
field which is taken from six weapon ND
and inject into repo as a proof of
ownership of what's being distributed
um we basically say hey if it's coming
from the same guy so same Rover then you
can compare the sequence number and
eliminate eliminate the stale routes if
it's coming from different Rovers so
it's different listeners for the same
multicast address then effectively all
the routes have to be injected in the
multicast rotting table
another thing that happens is the
introduction of the P flat pfl but I
will go back
um to that on the next slide and with
clarifying the language when it's any
cast or multicast we are using the term
subscribe as opposed to register
just to say hey it's a subscription
because you intend to get a multicast
packet delivered basically
we had we discussed last time an issue
about the consistent uptime option so
the consistent uptime function is option
is the way the host can figure if the
router
has lost a registration State basically
did the router uh reboot for instance
since last time this device registered
in which case the device need to
re-register because the router may have
lost the state
um this is this impact six-man and so
the question was sandestier and I guess
they're equal well tell us
um
basically what we do with this this uh
consistent option obtain option
and then again there is the next slide
so you'll be free to next slide please
so yes there is the option it does
change a little bit because we want to
to exchange uh the uh State uh sequence
information in both directions so the
host can know what is the most recent
State for the router and reciprocally
it's completely abstract to the fact
that we use it for six slip and ND or
any other state from which the host and
the router must have you know some some
kind of agreement
uh right now it is still in this pack
because we didn't get a clear message
that we need to write a different spec
for it
I'm perfectly happy with that uh
and as far as I know we can go for one
group let's go in that state
and Rick you jump in when you want
even if during the work group let's go
we decide to take it off I don't see why
that should hold our group last call
because taking off that section
is still good reviews I mean if anything
get reviews yes during World group
Prescott for this and we take it off the
reviews are still good to take
yeah do you have a problem with the mic
there we go does that work yes
um yeah this fell off through the cracks
a little bit from the last Philadelphia
meeting I did send email to six man
chairs and there was a
uh but I failed to follow up because I
think there was no the general
discussion on on that email the thread
that I said
um so I think a perfectly fine thing to
do is to
uh do it you know if you want to do an
adoption call do an adoption call on all
cc6 man yeah sorry uh and I'll cc6 man
um
and we'll talk about it then I mean like
like we said any review is good to take
even if we take that section off later
sure
so I don't see that as blocking local
classical next slide please yes
so the the other change doesn't affect
the binary of the packets uh that would
be thrown it's just that since we are
doing the work and the prefix
registration for a number of reasons we
needed yet another flag to indicate
prefix but if you look at its unique as
multicast any cast and prefix are
mutually exclusive
so why take yet another bit
saying it's mutually exclusive with the
others so the idea was let's keep the
two bits with the same value zero
unicast one multicast zero well second
bit on any cast but call that a single
field so the value of three would be
available to us for the prefix
registration
so it doesn't change the implementation
for this draft but it allows to free and
to to give a sense to what this means
when both multicast and anycast bits are
set basically it means it will mean
prefix
um by the way so the prefix is the
second draft I will be talking about
right after but remember for those who
have a pending draft there is this early
INR discussion that has happened for for
those drafts and Amanda came to me and
said uh what do I do with this thing and
well that's a question to the group
if we agree to do the prefix with the
value 3 then we could avoid having to
declare a registry for this draft for
which the last variable values 3 would
be assigned by the draft which is right
coming up
on the other hand if we delay the work
and the prefix and we don't go for
adoption Etc then we probably want to
have this registry so the value 3
remains
um unassigned so at the moment the
assumption is you know we don't know
what we do with the other draft so this
draft has a INR section which requires a
registry for this with the value 3 on
the side that's that's the state of the
art
if anybody jumps to the mic
um next slide please
so yes I mean no news from six men and
uh certainly it would be nice at least
to circulate this at six months during
the war group let's go
and ready to start the worker plus call
as far as I'm concerned
yes so the idea will be to uh to start
the working group last call perhaps we
might need to keep six months maybe in
the loop somehow
Eric
yeah yes
it kind of fits with what Bob said at
six men the other day which is like when
the group is you know he's happy that
this thing is needed then he can
circulate by them but not too early but
that's not too early anymore okay
so then uh well I don't know if there
are other comments or questions about
this first presentation
uh just a gentle reminder that why sun
is effectively waiting for the RFC for
their home specs so I mean if we can be
Swift on that one that would be nice
sure
okay so then let's proceed
to the second presentation
okay so this is the the newest and
bestest member of the family so
next slide please
so this one we already saw next slide
yeah
we we are already redistributing what we
learned from 8505 into routing this is
not a surprise the way it works is today
when the host or even the router has a
unicast address and he wants to ensure
there is reachability back independently
of what the rotting is above the first
operator it will set the r flag
in 8505 telling the router a whatever
you're doing in the proxy Rift evpn you
name it repo obviously do whatever is
necessary for me because I won't be
doing it myself on the other hand if
it's a ripple router doing it then it
will not set the r flag because it will
inject its own dial messages
so it doesn't need the other router to
do it with a 9010 if the bit is set then
the Ripple router that accepts the
registration sends a dial message with
the external bit set meaning this is a
route to the outside next slide
so this is
um
what we have here
and well that's effectively the way
Reaper works so you can see this uh
prefix a which is the whole ysn network
if you like the the single subnet and
you can see that uh Mr C and Mr D
um tell the root that their parent is B
and the root will know that it has this
last Hub to to make to Rich basically
you see on the right routing table
that's built out of that next slide
okay so this is nine zero one zero the
difference is now the Hub between uh C
and this node L that you can see this
lfn as we call it in my sun
um is this this device uh is effectively
injected into Ripple by c as opposed to
l
okay as an external Rod the result is
pretty much the same it's just that the
router is aware that this host does not
belong to repost so it cannot be
expected to terminate the Ripple
artifacts that we place in the packet so
typically a tunnel from the route
uh that is supposed to reach L will
terminate at C that's pretty much the
the main um difference with the usual in
usually determine the tunnel will
terminate the node because it's Ripple
aware but here we don't even expect that
the node L is capable of terminating the
rod the tunnel so we terminate it at C
now we have this for hosts but next
slide please
um we don't have it for prefix so what
are we waiting for there are a number of
reasons why we would do it for prefix
not any type of prefix we never want it
and still don't want Ripple to become a
Transit Network because we expect tlds
to be a very edge network but for this
Edge node that we saw there could still
be a an external stat Network connected
or it could be that this Edge node is
not only owner of a one address but it
could be owner of a prefix for instance
there is the story of doing 64 per host
which is perfectly good and legal why
would not Ripple a low for it so if we
if we go for something like that we have
the need to expose to the Ripple router
that we have ownership of not just one
address but the full prefix
and that's what we are doing here next
slide please
uh so this is a reminder as before the
triple is not only for uh host addresses
and no threats its Ripple is a generic
distance Vector protocol which is uh
optimized for a number of reasons for
power but still it can route prefixes
just like it can route or struts and
basically these are the kind of routing
table that you build next slide
and what we're missing is dependent of
the other drawing where effectively The
Host
as a routing protocol independent
agnostic way of telling the router hey I
have this stub
attached to me or this step that I hope
and so this is the gap that this draft
is attempting to solve so basically in
this case it will be a ripple again but
it could be any rotting protocol or any
action and I will be presenting this
draft at slack tomorrow because it's it
solves the slack Prime just like it's it
helps in the Ripple case
snack snack snacks it's like well much
is like these days
so I will skip that but just just as an
example of uh how that's that addresses
the snack use cases basically as soon as
a router advertised like a step writer
advertises to a main writer that it has
a prefix the the main router can forward
the packets to that uh first router you
don't need a full-fledged rotting
protocol with distances and stuff
because the stub is attached to a 6lr2
so why go and participate to a bgp or no
SPF of this world when all you're trying
to say is hey I have this prefix it's
attached to me you can give me the
packet it's going to be loopless
okay so that's that's effectively what
you are doing next slide and and a
symmetrical case is when the steps are
separated from the the main link
um that that's that can be typical of
some some households I guess when you
have levels and stuff same thing the the
routers which under the steps can
declare to the main router hey I have
this tab and then you get reach a bit
Rich ability back next slide
so the interesting piece is uh okay now
we are doing uh 8505
for prefixes uh What Becomes of that do
you want to do put a configuration
and that's an interesting one because we
could
and we have to work on it we have to
decide what we do but we could say say
that we've got this slash 48 for your
home
could you say oh routers are free to
autoconf
64th instead inside that slash 48.
because we have still this 6 lbr which
could manage no you can do it it's a
duplicate or you can't do it I mean we
have all the the tools that would
basically say Hey you have this prefix
or you can't have this prefix
so it's pretty cool by reusing what we
have but instead of looking at exact
match
of okay that this address already owned
exact match with this adult dress now we
could look at is this prefix part of
that other prefix is this other prefix
available for auto config subnets of it
okay so so there's a whole uh
possibility there that we we could uh
develop just because we we have that
anyway and it would be an extension of
what we do for that but by looking at
which prefix is inside which are the
prefix
so so the draft doesn't do auto
allocation or prefix a location right
right now but that's a possibility that
is offered to us with this draft next
slide
so well how that would that work but
pretty much the same way as nine zero
one zero works I mean the the step
router uh advertises through ND the the
one half reachability of the prefix
and then the routers above will do
whatever is necessary maybe the
aggregate maybe they redistribute
whatever they have to do in their own
routing protocol and here I have the
case of pvpn but it could be anything
basically they will inject if they are
flag is
if it's set then instead of injecting a
horse route they will inject a prefix
rod now there is a question I presented
that slide to ietfs ago because when we
started this I presented it before I
wrote the draft to see if there was
interest the group kind of told me hey
yes we're interested in working on that
so I produced the draft and in my slides
I indicated it could have been an RS and
the other option could have become a
stub router or option or something
the names are not that important it
could be cool to figure out if we want
to use errors RNs at the moment
to keep it very similar to 8505 it's a
narrow option in an NS and there is just
a prefix length that set it to the error
option
but if you know you guys think it's more
relevant to call it an errors then it
could become an errors
whatever works for me
next slide
and big surprise as I introduced this
these two bits which can say unicast
multicast anycast now the proposal is to
assign value 1 1 to say hey we are
registering for a prefix and if we are
registering for a prefix yes you have a
prefix lag somewhere in this packet
next slide so in the RO effectively and
this is not change much this is this
this just shows that same asset 505 with
uh eight nine two eight eight nine two
eight is the way we do sound in that
world
that basically says hey when you
register an address if this route
ownership verification verifier is a
crypto ID then you can be challenged for
running it so so if the same address
shows up somewhere else the routers will
challenge the somewhere else to see if
this token is can be validated if the
host can validate the token it means he
has the private address that goes with
it so it can only address that's
basically the way we avoid stealing
addresses well we can do the exact same
thing for prefixes if the prefixes are
owned by a single node
or if the different owners share the
same key
then it's possible to ensure that a
route can only be injected in the
routing fabric by the real owners
okay so the same zero conf zero trust
I'm sorry the same zero trust
capabilities we have for host now
becomes available for prefixes as well
next slide
and this is just a trick on how this
could be used effectively for ipv4
prefixes
um by uh putting them inside slash 96.
same thing you would you would provision
a certain prefix and and then uh okay
the slash 96 and encapsulate the the 10
dot or whatever uh for certain tenants
so this is more of a data center type of
use case like list by VPN
next slide
okay now so it's just a beginning there
are tons of things we could do
um
would we want to to
add a
to to make it an arrest uh make it an NS
would we like to to
extend the proof of ownership per ifc9
8928 which is not done yet in this draft
um more interesting since we are
advertising prefixes and we may
advertise them through different places
do we want to influence load balancing
again that's more of a data center type
of use case
and then again it's not a distance we're
talking about right it's it's we're
talking about weights
we are not doing a routing protocol we
are still in NS space
but in NS you have a pre-filled router
for you have this router preference
thing right same thing when we inject
the prefix we could say hey if I have
several parents to whom I want to
advertise this prefix I could say
I want more traffic through this parent
and through that one for instance
because I don't know I mean that's the
way balance Mannix
and well that's pretty much it I just
want to to to
be very explicit that this is a
beginning and there is a lot of power
that we could develop with decider it's
so so don't take for granted the fact
that it's an NS uh or that the
capabilities that are disclosed in zero
zero are very limited there are tons of
things we could be doing
but then again it's not a rotting
protocol it's just advertise the one how
preachability it will stop
and that's pretty much it
so yes I would like to to see
discussions on where we want to go with
this I mean if we go for adoption uh
would we would we care for doing an SRS
um do we want to call the ero with you
know P equals three uh stab registration
option
um
do you want support ipv4 prefixes using
search 96 do we want to extend the zero
trust that we have with uh 8928 in all
these questions
and that's pretty much it okay thank you
Pascal so are there any comments or
questions
I mean
I was on Courage last time I mean 12
years ago to do this work are you still
kind of supportive of this thing this
happened
yeah okay
yeah so now since there is a written
draft now it's a good moment to actually
read it and provide feedback so we
encourage the working group to
to read the document and provide
comments
thank you so then the next
set of presentations will be the ones
related with past aware semantic
addressing
I'm requesting for sure
I'm granting you
should be there yeah okay
foreign
Luigi I'm gonna give you an update on
what was named before
NSA the native short addressing
which is now called password semantic
addressing
smaller meaningful as a name a model
focused on the real content of the real
aim of this work
this is rapidly the the
the history how the the draft day is
advancing we are back again to zero zero
because we changed the name okay uh we
have beside the name we have to welcome
two more quarters one is Pascal that is
a great job in helping us we'll go over
the his contribution Kieran as well all
this contribution actually came up from
the nice discussion that we had during
the the working group called for our
adoption that I mean the document didn't
make through but actually all in all we
did good progress to be honest so that's
wonderful uh from my perspective
uh
the outcome of the call for adoption was
the the fact that we need some clarity
clarification sorry the chance did a a
good summary of all this discussion that
we had on the mailing list was a quite a
long discussion I think in the last
year or so was the longest if I dare to
say but 69 emails oh yeah it was pretty
good I would say
so and as I said before uh Kira was
suggesting a new use case
and we had discussion on that and also
uh Pascal in one of the latest email was
suggesting to use the routing header as
a way to move forward okay and go over
what we
um
the different points that were discussed
right so
yeah the main changes beyond the name in
the in the document is the fact that uh
uh we have now an extensive use case
section which better explains uh what
what where we see
this solution to apply because it's not
and should not be considered a general
solution that you you can use in all the
possible six slow scenarios okay there
are specific uh scenarios that were it
is very reasonable to be used okay
and we have a tighter connection with
the uh six slow use cases uh draft and
then there is uh the new header format
so the use of the six law routing header
in order to
encapsulate uh the the packet and this
is very very meaningful because it's
more in line with the general solution
that are designed in this group right
want to point out that actually the
allocation function which just to recall
you is the way we assign addresses in
the topology and at the end the
forwarding algorithm so the way you
decide where to send the packet that
piece of work remains on on changed that
is pretty stable it's just the way where
we use it in which use cases and
actually how we encode uh uh our pockets
okay
as I said we try to to have a to type
better
um the work with the six slow use cases
this is one of the the points that the
chairs put in the uh summer email
closing the call for adoption the the
clarification of whether we should use
this uh the main
use case is obviously related to PLC
where we have already uh three uh
topologies which is also the logical
topology that the passer X NSA
tried to build in order to forward the
packets and obviously the uh if you do
this stateless approach in order to
forward you are sensible to Mobility so
we
I mean PLC there are no Mobility
requirements there are other scenarios
who where the mobility is not a
requirement but then you have to build
the tree topology which may or may not
fit uh we can claim the star topologies
kind of a tree but this is a discussion
for another uh
so
I forgot to put the the animation here
actually the idea was to give you in one
slide a snapshot of the four uh main use
cases that we detailed in the document
basically this Market smart home data
center monitoring and we when we say
mono monitoring is not about the the
data traffic itself is monitoring of the
the electrical appliances itself is is a
different thing so basically it's based
on PLC again uh that we where we can use
Passa and the the use case that Kiran
added about the industrial operation
technology networks which is
uh uh let's say the the data based on
different layer to technology from which
you cannot necessarily natively
add up all the the the full six law
protocol stack program but you can have
a software update that allows you to
have stateless forwarding and yeah the
again this pasta solution seems to fit
well okay
uh I invite you to really go over the
use cases and see if this solves all the
the the the clarification requested that
we received in an email and also
suggested by the HHS
so as for the uh encapsulation format
itself uh what we have is now to use the
60 pound routing header I suggested us
Define it in RFC 8138 so we will have
page one this
um routing header and then the normal
low pan iphc so basically the IPv6
compressed header according to 60 to 82.
okay no special uh treatment there
what we do is actually once you build
the what we call the passer a rich
header is um
well the format is pretty simple we you
have to type that allows you to
understand which kind of routing header
you are using
then we have two bits that allows us to
to understand what kind of address you
have in this header the size of the
address and then we have a set of quad
squads so just two octets so it's a
couple of that's like uh we we cut the
IPv6 addresses with the columns right
so the idea is basically when we add
this header we take the destination
address from the iphc and put it there
and we do you don't need to to put in
the iphc you can delete it uh at once so
that we you don't need to have duplicate
and then each and every node what does
it's it looks at this header and it
takes the forwarding decision according
to the rules
um
uh that were all already there now and
this this piece of content that update
is something we we discussed at length
by email with Pascal I thank you again
for the idea and the help the people and
the effort to put in this document
so basically uh how these things all
works together
um
the password domain just does compress
and compress uh the the the packets
according the the specification in this
document
um
the prefix of the parcel domain
represent the context that we use to
compress according to 6282 so basically
you can shrink the the big IPv6 address
at least to a slash
to only 64 bits okay according to the
size of the the pass address you can do
even more if you if you wish on the way
back the the document describes how to
take the pass address and rebuild the
full IPv6 or just just the correlations
operation that is always already
described in 8138
Okay so when we send a packet we
compress uh uh according to 60
6282 okay uh based on the context and
then as I said we take the destination
address we put in the uh RH we lead it
from my phc and we said well we set the
size accordingly etc etc and we send the
packet
the receiving side what we do is
basically we take
the the address uh in the uh RH header
and we use it as a IID and we we can
rebuild the full like pv6 uh address
according to 8138 that is nothing really
special and this is the the
intra-domain communication in a passer
domain okay
from the the for external communication
uh things are a little bit different but
different because we need to send
outside
so this is something that we
I wouldn't say we're still working on we
we have to better the finance and the
document we are discussing again with
with pascalte but the idea is pretty
simple if we have to send outside
what we need to do is just send up to
the root nothing more right and when we
receive something from the outside the
root will will create the uh RH header
with the pass address and this becomes a
intra-domain communication and will be
delivered to the offly to the right
destination okay
so all in all this is uh the the the the
updates on this specific piece of work
with different names so if you have any
question or comments on this
okay so there's two people in the queue
okay uh thank you for your cool
presentation and thank you for your
report sixth row use case left I think
that sixth row you skate draft is a kind
of the information to other documents so
it is very good so I'm wondering so you
refer to PLC cases the PLC the PLC can
be utilized in uh G3 PLC or electricity
ucg so I'm wondering your idea is is
there any practical reference site to
use or do you have any plan to utilize
your uh this uh can you repeat the
question I didn't get it I apologize
what is exactly the point with PLC yes
in the sexual use case trap the PLC is
used for G3 PLC or the electricity
it is the Practical
site yeah so you are the pssa do we have
any reference site or do we have any the
plan to utilize your idea
not specifically I mean
no
we need to do to look in more details to
the to use that okay but yeah good point
Thank you thank you for bringing this up
[Music]
just a couple of quick question or about
a quick note
uh I wouldn't rule out or I would ask
you to state in document why you did
rule out all kind of hero compression
other than iphc for example for example
GHC or chic
uh I know that Rover brief for the
document it is more important to ex to
explain how
for iphc is uh
working the address expansion and
compression but there are other methods
as well
and the second is a suggestion for
addresses that are going outside of the
network I found myself very comfortable
with stateful compression for a phc that
sure enough it requires also to have a
distribution for the contextness but
it's very useful
uh just uh just because your scenario
seems to be
just fitting the idea that the outside
addresses or whether the addresses
toward the internet are just a handful
yeah
but I I agree on the second uh uh
comments that you did about the external
communication about the the first part
uh the first comment that you said are
we ruling out something
and uh let's say that we did not include
this something in this document but this
is my personal point of view this is
something to discuss also with the other
quarters and with you guys the working
Loop but uh uh uh we we don't
necessarily rule out other form or
compressions we maybe need other
specifications at that side
yeah it's not you it was just a point
that in this case good but you will have
to stay that the aphc is an example
in the document uh from the original one
let's say there was also some kind of
optimization in the way you treat the
the addresses that are external
and as I just said these are
optimization we don't need in the basic
specification but something we cannot
optionally if we wish
and the the group is interested but the
basic set of of
specification that we are converging on
looks okay
thanks
hello here
um yeah I was looking at one of the use
cases that you introduced so there's a
smart home use case and again about the
PLC there
so
um yeah what I was thinking if you look
at that topology then typically in a
smart home there's also something like
or what we call sometimes infrastructure
link so that's like Wi-Fi or ethernet
link that binds everything together
so that yeah
that I suppose we have that there and
then there are a number of PLC gateways
and those you can consider as a stop
Network so that was called introduced
and actually it looks to me like hplc
network is kind of a flat Network
headers one power line connecting all
the devices so
I don't really see the need for her well
some kind of hierarchical addressing so
that's not true actually because in the
uh in the different use cases and we
have
ASCII art in the document that uh
tries to explain what you there is also
in the text is the fact that at the end
of the day you have some hierarchy in
your privacy Network we have because one
thing is the end device which could be
uh something big or some something small
but all the the connecting uh
infrastructure
as small as a smart home might have some
hierarchy limited you don't have 3 000
levels but there is not necessarily
completely flat
okay so you mean that uh if you could
have a look do the use cases section and
send us all the feedback which you have
that would be great yeah I think okay
then it's good maybe to update the
picture also so if the PLC has some
hierarchy then I kind of understand
maybe better
yeah how that how that fits but
um overall the use case doesn't doesn't
look like the smart home that's now
usually introduced today where lots of
devices are Wireless like your lights
and doorbell yeah wireless networks
today excellent point and this is
related to the next presentation because
one thing that you have in this solution
is the the reliability aspects because
if you have this stateless forwarding is
based on the knowledge of your
neighborhood but if something goes wrong
and you don't have a routing protocol
that allows you to go around uh then you
need to to manage the reliability in a
different way so uh
what I want to say by that is that
this work in principle could work in the
wireless environment but there is a
reliability issue that you have to to
look at it carefully because the
wireless link is
is not as stable as a PLC wireless link
so so yeah so so this comes also to the
initial comments that I made the
solutions is not to replace Ripple for
example is and be used to as a general
solution there are cases that you can
use it okay this is
as meaningful it's not uh okay yeah I'm
just doubting a bit on home use case
that's all but okay I will check it
thanks
but please again uh read the the section
and send us all your thoughts that would
be good input anyway
oh sorry I was going to remove Esco from
the queue but I accidentally removed one
Peng as well so one thing if you still
want to make a comment
uh yes a quick comment uh Quantum from
Hawaii uh one of ulcers as men knew that
we had a good discussion on last uh
Comfort option for the ANC document but
for the past I suggest many people who
interested in in this document can send
it and set their concerns in the mailing
list thanks
foreign
if there are no other comments then I
guess we can proceed to the next
companion document which is on the
reliability considerations
thank you
um okay this is an update on what was
before called the NSA reliability uh now
choose to be said the new version of the
draft is more uh renaming update but
since we did not have the possibility to
present this document last time uh we
will go over it this time
um certainly
uh let's say this is an initial effort
uh
and might have some adjustments to be
done but the more important the point is
to receive your feedback so I I hope
that you at some point we will have uh
the possibility to discuss this on the
mailing list okay so new document
submitted in October as I said the main
change is the the naming we try to go
over the the whole document to replace
an essay bypass and and a few other
changes were the meaningful
but
um we will work more on this document
for uh 116.
okay so uh the main content is pretty
simple we have a general introduction to
the problem
uh the possible solution uh
uh classes which are pretty pretty much
two and I will present in the rest of
this uh presentation
uh there is also a section about
consideration how to detect the failures
and the recovery as well because this is
also a change in topology it's not about
only
a workaround something that is missing
is also understanding when this this
link for example or not that that was
not available is coming back and we can
go back to the initial state
and then some consideration about their
obviousness
um you know
so the the obviously in order to to have
a reliability the private requisite is
to have redundant links uh if you don't
have an alternative
if something breaks it breaks and you
you lose connectivity so this is
obviously the what you need at the
beginning
um
doesn't mean that you need to this
redundant links all to be active at the
same time so it could be an active
passive uh kind of uh usage okay and but
the point is the one you use the active
links you have you must be able to build
a tree because passer relies on this
logical uh three topology okay and uh
the other thing is what we need is to
have a secondary pattern a parent so
each node needs a
two parents okay
uh which is pretty natural so that we
can uh alternate and have a reliability
ability this is except the root nodes uh
in the sense that the root node is the
one that that is the the gateway to the
internet and starting from there you
have different kind of reliabilities and
you are outside the passer domain so
uh yeah
that's a different story
and uh the alternative parent could be
uh you know is connected in uh to a
non-active link uh now in when you have
this uh set of uh conditions that hold
then you have basically two choices
either you use multiple addresses which
basically boils down to have a
uh a different topology
okay so it's like multi-topology routing
so basically you have uh two parallel
instance or over to three topology that
not match in the sense that so that when
one link is down you have an alternative
uh pass on the other topology right or
uh you can use one single address or
like we do in the normal case
but then you need to store uh uh alter
some addresses in order to have to know
which is your alternative parent or
children
okay in a multi-topology case you don't
need you don't need that they are really
running in parallel so
but in a certain way both require some
some additional uh State on the
different nodes so I said this is pretty
uh trivial I mean there is not such a
thing as a free lunch right so
when the multi-address uh
case in case of a link you you will have
basically two routes and then you have
these multiple links you build a
parallel topology when something happens
like in this case in this example we
have the link between one zero zero and
one zero that he at some point breaks
um
after detection
one zero zero can use the other topology
in order to send a an icmp notification
to the root in order to say
this link is down
and this is this is done on the
alternative topology using the address
zero one one zero zero sorry for all
these bits going through the alternative
route and then the original route okay
this is from let's say from uh the
bottom side of the link on the app Sim
side the denote one zero just send an
icmp straight up through the different
layers to the root and for optimization
you can use some uh some some CMP
messages and also to to delivering
children
in this in this way Whenever there is a
a packet coming from the leaves or the
the sub trees of one zero zero going up
and in principle should go through the
link between one zero zero and one zero
you can tunnel
through the alternative topology and
send it to the root
okay
on the way back let's say that oh there
is a packet from the root
could have come externally or from the
local domain doesn't matter
when it is on the route and you look at
the destination address now the route
needs needs to remember that there is a
broken link and so that it needs to
Tunnel the bucket on the alternative
topology back to 100.
okay
so basically it uses the alternative
path goes to one zero zero decapsulate
you see the real destination and you
send it down to the real destination
okay
so uh
the the the the the state that you need
to add is in Niche no each node that is
um has a broken link uh absely more
donesting there is this additional
stated that you have to remember that
the link is broken but it's not that
much stage you still need to to have
this this information on the Note right
um You need to know the alternative path
but this is pretty simple because you
have the the secondary topology okay you
just need to encapsulate
there is some State on the root because
the route has to have the knowledge of
all ongoing failures and where to
um encapsulate in order to Tunnel the
packet to the right node
I mean now this is uh
hopefully limited State because you have
few failures but if you have a lot of
failures popping up in your network so
the state that you have to keep on the
root is not anymore your problem you
have a bigger issue with the reliability
physical reliability of your network
right
so if I may if you think it's possible
to speed up a little bit yes yes
so I described this this logic to us so
I don't really need to go over this
slide here
um I will go straight to the single
single address uh case with the simplest
uh the same scenario okay a link failure
between one zero one zero zero as you
can see now we don't have double
addressing it's just that uh
in this case we need to keep a bigger
neighbor State with alternative
parents and children in order to know
what to do when the link fails you
basically one zero zero send an icmp
message through 110 to the root in in
order to say to do the same notification
basically okay so we need to exchange
Samosa state but we still can walk
around the the link failure
okay
and when we go down uh The Roots knows
that something is wrong and it can
decide to
um
do some kind of source routing in order
to send the packet to the right
destination
looking to run through uh forwarding
through an alternative pass in that case
however you can have some hope at it
because uh you need to to embed the path
the alternative path which is the not
not the natural pass a path in your
pocket okay
for the sake of time I will skip the the
um the flowcharts but these are in the
document uh pretty easy so if we want to
compare a little bit to classes the
multiple addresses single address
the the amount of state that we see in
the root in the multiple addresses is
low because you just have a redirect
rule the single address the root needs
to know that your full topology knows
that when we go downlink we need to know
which path to build okay
in in the forwarder nodes the status is
in both cases relatively low some some
rules can be
um
there or neighborhood
and the robustness uh if you have
multiple failures the multiple addresses
there is no clear synchronization could
be weaker in that case
but in the single address case since the
route has a global vision
can do semester choices but again if if
you have a lot of failures then you have
a bigger problem
and that's it about being a little bit
of time if you have any question now or
later on on the mailing list please send
any feedback
okay any questions
from the room or remotely
okay okay so thank you very much thank
you for the presentation
so the next presenter will be me
actually so shweta if you can share
the presentation
okay thank you
so hello again I'm going to present the
last update of the draft and title
transmission of she compress packets
over IEEE 802.15.4 networks Mike author
is an Amina burum From macleon next
please
so first of all a reminder for the
motivation of this draft
as this working group knows well RFC 622
has been the basis for header
compression in six low pan and also in
six low with these rfcs possible to
compress a 48 byte ipp6 UDP header down
to just seven bytes in the best case
with global addresses however there is a
more recent specification called Chic
which is the main product of the lp1
working group which is able to compress
even further the same header down to
just for example one byte that's because
cheek uses static context based on a
priority knowledge of the header field
values of the packets that will be
transmitted
then if we take into consideration also
an application layer protocol like Co-op
uh there is no six low band style header
compression defined for Co-Op but there
is a way to compress Co-op headers with
Chic so here we are considering two
examples two cases of Co-op headers one
which is a means no header options which
means uh had the size of four bytes case
b corresponds to the example in Table
Six in RFC 8824 where the cop had a size
is 16 bytes so in both cases the seek
it's possible to compress those two
headers down to just for example one
byte which leads to a total Improvement
which is quite significant uh if we
consider the join IPv6 GDP Co-op header
size with six low pan we can compress
those down to 11 or 23 bytes depending
on the two cases but we think it's
possible to compress them down to just
couple of bytes in both cases
so for example this represents a battery
lifetime Improvement for battery
operated devices over 15.4 by a factor
which in theory could be even greater
than two although a disclaimer here is
that the actual Improvement will be
lower depending on the different
parameters and settings like the device
Hardware features such as sleep current
consumption different settings at the
Mac layer adaptation layer application
layer payload size Network topology and
so on next please
so just to provide a few more details on
this this figure shows the maximum
battery lifetime Improvement Factor as a
function of the co-op payload size in
the horizontal axis and here we are
assuming some things like short Mac
addresses intrapan communication and a
sensor that is battery operated and
periodically transmitting a message for
example containing sensor readings over
15.4 and we are considering also star
topology and mesh under so we may add
route over in in future updates of this
figure and as you can see there is some
improvement factor which is reasonably
significant and it increases as the core
payload size decreases
and anyway this is theoretical results
so the actual Improvement will be
somewhat lower next please
so on the status of this document there
was some previous uh document a
precursor to to this one which was
presented already in ITF 110 then this
document I'm presenting tries to provide
all the details required to enable the
transmission of sheet compress packets
over 15.4 networks and the previous
versions previous first four versions of
the draft have been presented in the
last four ITF meetings and today I'm
presenting revisions zero four and zero
five where the main one is actually zero
four uh which aim to incorporate the
feedback from the last ATF and also from
discussion on the mailing lists of the
six low and lp1 working groups next
please
so let's see the update in the draft
first there's some changes in the
organization of some of the content in
the document
previously there was section 6 entitled
multi-hub communication which now has
increased and now uh it's located in
Section 3 architecture also we have
modified the change of the two previous
subsections in the architecture part in
order to provide a better introduction
to the multi-hop communication topics
then in these multi-hop parts we
describe at the moment three different
possible approaches to transmit a
compressed sheet compressed packet over
a 15.4 multi-hop path
and then section 4 has been extended as
well because now we provide the frame
formats that correspond to these three
different approaches
and finally there used to be subsection
5.3
in Section 5 about header compression
examples however well the the section
still by the way needs to be developed
and now for the moment we are moving it
to an appendix which seems to be a
better place probably
next please
so on Section 3.3 on multi-hub
communication
these are the three approaches by which
compressed packet maybe transmitted
through a multi-hop path in a 15.4
network now the first one we are calling
it straightforward route over approach
in this case all nodes must store all
the rules in using the network for
compression decompression that's because
maybe a note could be a node in the
middle an intermediate mode which might
need to decompress and compress again
however while this is good in terms of
header overhead this is probably more
suitable rather for small stable
networks or perhaps without nodes
without memory issues
then there's another approach perhaps
for larger networks which we are calling
now tunnel Ripple based route over
approach where an endpoint must Only
Store the rules for the communications
it's involved in as an endpoint
so later we'll see the the details for
this one which is the details have been
added in these last dates and there is
also the mesh under approach by which an
endpoint must Only Store the rules for
the communications it is involved in as
an endpoint as well next please
yeah
so on the tunnel Ripple based route over
approach here the assumption is that we
are using Ripple non-stirring mode and
the overview would be as follows packet
sent by A6 Ln are tunnel upward to the
root and if the final destination is
another 6 Ln
in the same Ripple domain then the
packets are tunnel downward from the
root
so then we have RFC 9008 which describes
how a packet would be transmitted from a
6lm to another node which could be
another six land or the root in the same
Ripple domain or an external node so
according to this RFC for downward
traffic there is IPv6 in IPv6 tunnel
except when the route itself is the
packet source and there's the tunnel it
terminates at the 6lm if this is a
rotting away a leaf or at the last 6lr
if the 6ln is routing and aware node and
then for Upward traffic there is IPv6 in
IPv6 encapsulation performed by the or
initiated by the 6lr
if the signal line is rotting unaware
node
and by the way there is no tunnel if the
destination is the route and then there
is IPv6 in IPv6 encapsulation only
optionally from the 6ln if this node is
a routing aware live so next please
so
we understand that we need to have a
tunnel for Upward traffic
so we understand that this document
would need to update out of c9008 by
stating that when I seeks the land
transmit the sheet compressed IPv6
packet it must be tunnel by means of
IPv6 and IPv6 up to the root regardless
of the Final Destination
and then there's another point which is
a to-do at the moment which is address
the case of the 6ln being routing and
aware Leaf
um because in that case it is the 6lr
the first XLR the one who initiates the
tunnel or the last six dollar the one
who terminates the tunnel so we need to
address this case
and then for the sake of efficiency the
idea is using RFC 8138 to compress the
different routing artifacts the IPv6 and
IPv6 headers the Ripple option and the
source routing header next please
so these are the frame formats that
would be used the first one is the one
that we had seen previously in in
previous versions of the draft this one
can be used for single Hub communication
or in the straightforward route of
approach
so here this format starts with the Chic
dispatch some bit pattern in page 0 in
this case that signals that what comes
next is a sheet compress packet and then
what's new is the formats for the tunnel
Ripple based route over approach where
we can see the main downward the main
format for downward communication which
is inspired by uh product c8138
where we start with the page Suite which
indicates that we are in the dispatch
type page one
then there's the six low R8 headers for
the source routing header Ripple packet
information ip9p encapsulation and then
uh ship dispatch telling that what comes
next is a sheet compress packet but in
this case the dispatch would be in page
one so as you can see it would be the
same bit pattern but in this case also
in page one by the way this bit pattern
seems to be not allocated at the moment
next please
so for Upward transmission the format is
similar however in this case we don't
need the source routing header
and formation under the ideas that the
formats would be the same as those in
RFC 4944 however the compress header in
this case of the IPv6 packet would be a
header compression would be made by
means of chic
next please
so there are other fewer dates in
Section 5 which is about Chic
compression of IPv6 UDP called headers
now we've added that each row defines
the set of protocols whose headers are
being compressed or decompressed for
example in some deployment one could
decide to assign rule IDs one two three
for example to compress the IPv6 header
Only Rule like this fall to seven to
compress IPv6 UDP and Rule like this
8-15 to compress IPv6 UDP Co-op
and other than that we also have a data
Diana considerations because as
mentioned before we need to request the
allocation of a dispatch type for Chic
but not only in page 0 also in page one
and by the way it seems like especially
if we need to update perhaps a role RFC
well we may need to keep the role
working group in the loop perhaps more
formally even if some of the
participants are actually also seasonal
participants
okay so next please
yeah so the document is getting more and
more complete of course it's not yet
finished but the offers would like to
ask if the document would be ready at
this point for working group adoption
thanks Carlos so
oh
can you get a sense from the room
um on how many people have read it and
would be interested in
reviewing and continuing to work on this
as a work group document
should we do a show of hands or hum
yeah so I'm hearing suggestions to if
you maybe want to run the poll through
miteko Maybe
thank you
okay so shweta if you yeah so we have
about 16 people who raised hands in
support no one opposed it so we'll take
it on the mailer and start our group
adoption gone
okay thank you thank you
any comments or questions
so we are well we have one minute left
there is if you recall there is this if
time permits presentation so perhaps if
it's possible to do it maybe in five
minutes quickly
hangxi are you present yeah
okay hello everyone my name is Hunter
and I'm going to present an IP copy
extension next time please
yeah the background is really simple the
ipcon is compressed IP IP payload and
the the compressor penalty prepared with
ip.com header contains the compression
parameter index to indicate the
compression algorithm and is located in
the IP Circle this
registry no no sign please
thanks
yeah and under the problem with the IP
comes the first problem is that
incompatible with network function which
requires the name for information for uh
because and therefore information is is
already compressed
so for for example an ite file or ACL
menu to access this compressor
information
so they cannot deploy between the IG
comp nodes next size please
so the first extension is about do not
compress this Source proton destination
for the information
basically there are two options to do
that we can change the flags to add one
bit indication or we can change the CPI
to duplicate each compression algorithm
code point
and the second problem is that uh Auto
photo processing basically it's because
the ipcon May produce longer pay nodes
the compression is not effective for
example and the obviously says that if
uh if compression is not effective you
just send the uncompressed results and
the IP comp header but say in the
decompression side the packet with the
IP comp header will go through the
decompression code processor first but
if a package is without IP comparator it
will be forward directly so it's
different process is cause also of other
next
so the the second negotiation is about
so we add the ipcon header regardless of
the if the pain of this and uncompressed
or not we can just add a new CPI value
for the uncompressed packet next
next side please
yeah that's one basically we think a
signal also have some kind of
compression on the header so we think we
can ask a phone the suggestion about
this kind of design
thank you
anyone had a comments
so at the moment there are no comments
in the room or remotely perhaps it might
be good if you send a pointer to your
document to the secret reading list okay
just in case people have time to read it
also people who are not present in the
meeting okay sounds good
yeah
oh yeah okay
yeah so so did you hear the comment yeah
yeah okay okay so yeah
okay thank you
okay so the session ends here
thank you everyone for the participation
and hope to see you in Yokohama
thank you as well
thank you
foreign