it's working
okay folks it's uh 9 30. welcome to the
the best working group
I just I just hope people get settled
um I'm I'm Matthew Bocce uh man
Commander sitting with me is um
our working group secretary uh Stefan I
think is yes Stefan is online as he the
other chair
okay this is this is the notes well
um basically it's saying anything you
say here is considered a contribution to
the ITF
um I'll just leave it up for a moment
future Ponder
one other thing while while we're on
these sort of procedures please remember
to wear your masks in the meeting room
unless you are actively eating drinking
or speaking at the mic
foreign
so this is our agenda it's a fairly busy
agenda we've got a few minutes Slack
um as also I just wanted to note that as
some of you may be aware today is
Remembrance Day and it's
um marked in the UK and many other
countries by two minutes silence at 11AM
um so there was a discussion on the I
think the working Group shares list
about how to handle this and we have a
little bit of slack in it conveniently
if we keep to time
fits on our agenda so we we will if if
anybody if folks don't mind observe two
minutes silence at 11AM
any other comments or questions about
the agenda
okay so status update we don't have any
new rfcs um we have a couple of rfcs
still in the
um a couple of documents in the RSC
editors queue
um they are both waiting on Miss refs
um we have I think a few drafts with
Andrew Oren iesg review
um that's the IRB multicast draft
the evpn LSP ping draft
um evpm prefdf draft which is uh just
sitting at publication requested at the
moment
um virtual ethernet segment draft which
is in ad follower I think Andrew's
following it up at the moment
um
uh the VW BPW evpn vpws fxc draft uh as
you said publication requested
um and the evpn aggregation label draft
um is with Andrew
okay under we've got quite a few
documents under Shepard's review we had
a big queue of working group last calls
done over the last year or so and this
is unfortunately backed up a bit
um
so I think rank money you've done a
review of the evpn Redundant multicast
Source draft uh it's waiting for is that
still waiting for write up yes I'll be
sending it after okay
um
the evpn uh well Champion PA draft
um I think Stefan has provided a review
for that
um it's uh waiting for Stephanie waiting
for anything else on that before you do
your write-up
no I think it is okay now uh because I
requested Realtors to reduce the number
of offers and we documented and this has
been done uh so I think the next step
now will be to request the uh routing
directorate review as part of the of the
new process
if this is a really only missing piece
and before moving to isg
thank you
um the EVP engineer draft is is waiting
for me to do my my shepherd's review on
write-up um there's a kind of a we call
it a companion draft but there's another
draft in the nvo3 working group which is
describing the applicability of evpn to
Geneva
yeah one reminder can you
um use
your the
the on-site tool and remember to
register
um your presence for the blue sheets up
on the um using the QR code
so if you wish to get into my queue use
again and IQ on the using your phone
please
um the uh
right okay look Andre did you
for the next one the next one okay
um the first DF recovery draft is
waiting for a shepherd's write-up for me
I did send a comment to the authors
which I haven't seen the response yet
about whether this updates RFC 85 yeah
so look Andre Cisco we have received
that and we are analyzing that request
to see how much we need to look at 8584
and see how much it really updates okay
yeah the flag it as an update thank you
foreign
draft is waiting for right up from
Stefan
um the sd-wan usage draft
um just went through working group last
call
um but there is a routing area
directorate review of that draft
um which we're still waiting for the
authors to address to look at the
comments I think they were fairly minor
comments to be honest and
um just a reminder that we will be
sending all drafts through rooting area
directorate review from now on on the
request of our ad so when when we do a
working group last call we'll do that
we've been typically doing that anyway
but we'll we'll make sure that we do
absolutely all of them
Sasha do you do you want to say
something you're in
uh Sasha Weinstein ribbon
I would like to understand what happens
with the evpn young
uh it appears as one of the uh
objectives in the charter the draft has
expired uh has been there is a war group
document that has expired four years ago
I have sent a few emails to the authors
to the group to the chairs uh asking
whether this work has been known include
dropped or or if not whether it is going
to be resumed and I haven't got any
responses whatsoever
okay so if I can answer that question so
there was a kind of a consensus call
that we did I think just over a year ago
about what to do with the young drafts
because they weren't being progressed
actively at the time and we had a lot of
other protocol documents to deal with
then
um so they were they were parked
should say their parents working group
drafts I think on the on the tracker if
it doesn't we need to fix that but if
there's somebody who is able to pick
them up and run with them that that
would be good yeah at some point there
was a system we had to wait for some
dependencies for over young models you
know the working groups so for instance
the bgp one uh and so ones that we are
not ready at that time so there was no
way to really progress this document
until the other ones were were closed
a but
is it going to be to be
resurrected and uh progressed at some
time or is it just going of course no no
it's not it's absolutely not canceled so
I I would say it will be up to the
working group to design when to resume
it
it's perfectly fine to uh to go ahead
with the documents if we are now ready
and we if we have completely cleared the
dependencies that we have with the
overall young models
uh okay because this is something that
from my point of view is needed and the
we don't know my colleagues and I don't
know what to look for and what to expect
thank you
okay this EVP and I said CMAC flash
draft is waiting for a write-up from me
so I think you're waiting in the queue
for um the other drafts right
so the the evpn ipvpn working into
working draft so that that is still in a
kind of an extended last call at the
moment because we did we had a review
from the IDR working group
um and the chairs had some comments on
that draft
so go ahead
um this is
um this is the feedback uh the best
chairs suggest I provided this at this
time
uh this my review of this found three
things it goes against an
roc-4456 requirement for full
distribution routes with route
reflectors this can be simply noted as
we've discussed that with the best
chairs and find that the topology in a
wild garden works against it it also
specifies a transitive uh path attribute
bpath without an open capability
limitation and specifies changes to for
RFC 4271 without an open capability
limitation
the last two are uh could break I
understand the word could not must uh
uh break the b2p route selection in a
modified
4270 win in the case of a partial
deployment that may could could lose an
inconsistent in its Cur
um so the IDR chairs are concerned uh um
about the approval of a deep path in the
4270 changes without an open capability
we realize at this time there are wild
Gardens construct or AKA
constrained domains in VPN but past
experiences with bgp lead us to believe
that bgb updates can escape walled
Gardens and cause harm to the internet
and perhaps some of you know of
incidents where this occurred
um again we think that there are some
things because it is a deployed topology
where configuration can help that
um and uh we look to continue this
discussion with the chairs and with the
authors I want to thank Stefan and Jorge
for their great interaction on this
okay
Jorge
yeah so I just wanted to say that uh
first of all uh thank you sue for the
thorough review and all the interaction
as well
and uh yeah we are discussing among the
authors our understanding is based on
Sue's uh review is that the the blocking
issue right now is to provide some
solution to avoid the leakage
of this d-path attribute into uh Safi
one uh routes
to avoid uh basically the potential
issues that the ASU was referring to so
that's our understanding and we will
work uh with that in mind
okay
thank you
okay we also have the image split
Horizon draft I think stood in in uh
working group last call
right uh the evpn SR p2mp draft we think
is is ready for working group Master
call it's in our in our queue if there's
any other
um working group documents that the
authors think are ready and we haven't
listed them please uh raise up to the
chairs
okay we have quite a few expired working
group documents
um but we have a few non-expired working
group documents um which are currently
being updated uh some of these are being
presented
um on the agenda today
I think generally we would probably like
to see
a higher proportion of the agenda
talking about how we're progressing the
existing working group documents that we
have we have a best seems to have a lot
of uh it's actually very healthy that we
have a lot of new work coming into the
working group but we do have a lot of uh
drafts that we we uh they're in a fairly
mature state that we probably need to
move forward as and and we'd like to get
some updates and maybe at the next ATF
um from the
editors of those drafts
okay any any other comments on the
working group status
I think
foreign
and I'll be presenting
updates on two working group drafts
uh the first one is RFC 7432 bis so this
is the update to the base 7432 draft
that we've been using in uh best free
VPN
uh this latest version has
um actually a fairly significant update
both editorial and towards content so I
thank both Sasha and Marek for their for
their comments thank you
um and we did quite a bit of rework to
include content from uh other drafts in
the working group to have them be part
of the new base 7432 bits
next slide
so the changes from O3 so I did not
present the changes in o4 but from since
O3
this draft now effectively creates in
the ESI extended Community label field
a Ina or request an Ina registry for
this field
previously this field was effectively
just defining the
um no flag present being all active load
balancing mode
and 7432 the base defends uh defines
sorry the single active mode with one
flag
but we found uh through I forget which
draft maybe prefdf or um
I forget which draft but we found that
updating this ESI field led to some
collisions
so effectively uh this draft now defines
an i and a registry for uh allocating
fields or bits in this
uh in this Flags field
the best path sections were updated both
from the default gateway which was in
so they were taken from a a best pass
draft that existed in best
to to clearly Define or clearly order
the best path selection for evpn routes
uh and this the section currently covers
routes one to three
and
um
there was some question on the usage of
uh the usage of the label two field
which is effectively not defined uh the
usage of the label two field was not
defined in the draft and so uh there's a
reference to 9135 that is uh that is
added to the draft now
and apart from that uh just many
comments and um
significant editorial changes in between
all four and o5 actually
uh the next steps for this draft on the
next slide are
um we have received many reviews many
comments uh since it was first published
and even when it was first published the
the zero zero version of the draft
actually was based on
a plethora of comments on the bass draft
base 7432 so obviously more reviews and
more comments are always welcome but
this draft is nearing
uh working group last call stage so I
think we will be we will be ready to uh
to see class call on this draft
uh just to comment uh look uh I think if
I'm not mistaken you requested some
early allocation of cut point no
uh yes so I sent that email to Ayanna
and I think I see yeah either you or
yeah yes so so I did a pull to the
working group to see if there there was
anyone against the early allocation and
it was it was okay so I requested the
approval to Andrew but I haven't
received feedback yet so I will try to
pull Andrew again to give her his
approval before moving to Ayana okay
perfect thank you Stefan
the next draft I'm presenting
if there are another no other questions
is the is the evpn multi-homing for
layer 2 Gateway protocols so this is the
one that Stefan mentioned in one of his
slides for active working group
documents so we refreshed it
uh specifically in our case uh this evpn
multi-homing attributes registry that we
just uh that we just went over
so now there's a new load balancing mode
defined and instead of just allocating a
bit we now allocate an entry in this
load balancing registry or multi-homing
attribute registry
there was some comments received based
on clarifying the art procedures in the
in the draft
and so the diversion
um actually I think it's not O2 but the
version that's currently active I made
updates to explicitly reference
um 9135 so the irb-based our probing
procedures
uh but I have spoken to uh to the person
who made those comments due to Sasha
actually and he was actually seeking a a
reference to both our probing scenarios
right the IRB and the non-irb scenario
so I will include that use case of
non-irb in the next in the next update
and Define the art probing procedures
for non-irb
so other than that on the next slide
this draft has
matured quite a bit we have received
reviews and comments from many vendors
and operators actually so um
the there are implementations of this
draft it is in use so we would be
seeking working group Last Call on it
are there any questions
or comments
okay I don't see anyone in the queue
um so I think we're good okay thank you
thank you
so next up is Patrice
good morning my name is
um I'm here to talk about the evpn layer
3 multi-homing little balancing this is
a draft that
that came out about more than a year ago
and um so what we decided to do here is
to bring more calibrator collaboration
with
um or a and when for the other
um from Jennifer and Nokia
so I know for times constraint I may not
go through all the whole things but I
think what is really important is that
people start looking at it I think it's
it's a very good draft I explained very
well how the mechanics and how that
works
so can we go to the next slide please
all right so basically what we are
trying to achieve is it's exactly what
we what we have been designing for a
while in evpn but uh over LD interface
so you will see that we are taking care
of unicast multicast and a few of the
igp stuff
please next slide
so um so the mechanic also is
um you will see that whenever you're
going to read the draft is like we need
also to make sure that whenever the
synchronization is happening we can
refer to the right interface the right
Delta interface so all the mechanics has
been described there so in the new
version we put a bunch of clarification
to help the readers to understand how
that how this is working I think with
hurry and when we've done a very good
job on that please next
um this is pretty much the reptile that
are evicted and the use case that we are
covering
next one
and the beauty about this one is the
entire mechanics already exists so um
so it just pretty much explaining how we
use current mechanics to and get applied
for L3 interfaces
thanks
um yeah obviously we have a bunch of
advantages with that because uh what it
means then we are kind of going away
from direct ICI ICN link and the whole
Legacy mechanic
at Cisco we do have already this
solution being
being run on customers so
all right next
please
so please read it provide feedback and
we're going to move ahead of that
that's it thank you thanks any any
comments I don't see anyone in the
online queue
nope
thank you
okay I think you're
okay um yeah I have a short review of
three drafts here the first one is the
evpn vpws Gateway zero one presenting
this on behalf of my
friends from uh Nokia Junior Francisco
uh we presented this uh this draft
um uh to iets ago and uh I think now
it's uh
uh much more stable and better in this
next slide please
yeah I'm going to talk about a short
refresh changes that we've made in
version zero one and next steps
next slide please
the uh the draft
um in the introduction talks about
different ways of uh having
interconnectivity across domains for
evpm vpws services
it talks about three different solutions
which are all perfectly valid uh and
depending on the requirements you should
go to one or the other but if you have
the requirements that are listed here in
this table uh probably the best solution
is this service interworking uh spec
that we are
um we're specifying here
and uh there was nothing about it in the
in the best working group so that's why
we we needed to produce this document uh
next slide please
so the the draft is basically all about
uh making the water routers across you
know connecting different domains making
them uh service gateways
and in the draft we talk about
redistribution of the routes of the ad
per evi routes
and even though uh you know raw
distribution May mean different things
for different people so it's good to uh
to understand what it means in this
draft in the context of this document
so what we mean by that is when we
receive on a border router or a service
Gateway we receive an ad per Eva route
we process it according to the existing
RFC 8214
we also understand now the the d-path
attribute along with these routes as per
the d-path draft that I'm preferring
here in point a
we also need to program the forwarding
path uh based on the received route and
also based on the encapsulation of the
next domain
and uh and finally we need to
re-advertise the route to a different
domain this re-advertisement is really a
re-origination of the route meaning that
we can translate uh rewrite the route
the route distinguishers the ethernet
tag and and many other attributes in the
route
next slide please
as far as the redundancy is concerned we
defined two ways of doing it so the
first one uh here on the left hand side
is what we call the any gas gateways
redundancy
and this is a all about
um configuring uh exactly in the same
way the uh the service gateways that are
connecting to given domains right so
they when they redistribute the routes
they will do it with the same route
distinguisher the same ethernet tag and
everything
so the next four the routers or the peas
they rely on the pgp best selection to
pick up one of the the service gateways
the second way is a bit more
sophisticated
uh is Illustrated on the right hand side
and here basically uh each pair or uh
you know all their redundant service
gateways that are connecting two given
domains they are attached to what we
call an interconnect ethernet segment
the interconnect ethernet segment is
defined in RFC 9014 for Elan Services
here we are repurposing the same concept
for evpm vpws services
but other than that you have all the the
beauties of EVP and multi-homing so you
can Define the ethernet segment as a
single active or active you have all the
idea selection mechanisms Etc
uh next slide please
so the changes that we made in this
revision uh pretty much are these two
um we added support for fxc services so
you can also do this fxc Services across
different domains we updated references
in some other minor uh details next
slide please
so we already presented this draft it's
pretty much stabled and we believe it's
ready to uh work in group adoption so we
would like to request that
any questions
thanks
okay
um
all right next one is the vpnd bath
draft again presenting on behalf of my
friends from Nokia system Juniper next
slide please
uh I'll talk about a short refresh
what's new in this version and next
steps next slide please
yeah so what we are doing here with this
draft is we take the d-path attribute
that we talked about before
um
that is defined in the evpn and ipvp and
interworking draft the initially the
attribute was only for layer 3 routes
route type five any VPN or ipvpn routes
here we are using it for layer 2 evpn
routes right and we want to use d-path
for two purposes here to provide some
Loop detection
and therefore protection as well
specifically on service gateways
that are following IFC 9014 but we also
want to use it so that the uh the PE is
receiving the evpn layer 2 routes can
see the t-path and uh and Trace the uh
all the gateways through which the route
has gone
and uh there is also we use it
um you know in case the d-pad has
different length we also use it for
modifying the best path selection for
evpn layer 2 routes
next slide please
a simple example would be what you have
here in the in the diagram let's say you
have two data center gateways
interconnecting two domains and they are
attached to the same broadcast domain
so the two data center Gateway uh they
receive a given Mac IP route from uh
from ipe they redistribute that route
into the other domain and of course uh
the the two redundant data center
gateways they receive each other's
routes
but the the nice thing now is that when
they redistribute into the other domain
they slap the d-path with the identifier
of the domain of origin so now for
instance data center Gateway One when it
receives the Mac route
identifies that is coming from domain
1.1 which is a locally configured domain
so it can actually decide not to install
the route because it has a better route
coming directly from the PE
now the other advantage of this model is
uh for whatever reason if data center
data center Gateway One loses the route
coming directly from the PE
it has already another route that is
actually advertised from data center
gateway2 so you can do this U-turn thing
and provide the fast convergence for
in-flight packets
next slide please
another example that we have in the uh
in the draft is for imet routes for for
inclusive multicast ethernet Tech routes
or routes type 3.
same thing you can have gateways
interconnecting domains for uh in the
same broadcast domain so they both uh
exchange uh iMed routes in different
domains
so normally you would need to avoid
somehow manually to avoid the the two
parallel links to be created in both
domains to avoid packet duplication
debuff provides an automated way to to
do that basically you would tag the
diamond routes in one of the domains
with uh with the d-path uh domain and
that would be enough for the gateways to
modify the best pass selection and pick
up only one
next slide please
so what is new in this version zero two
um basically we modified this section
about best path selection for routes
type uh one two and three
now it's aligned with the with 7432 bits
that Luke was talking about before
we only modify that section of 74 C2
based in this draft with uh including
d-path for the best pass selection of uh
of these evpn layer 2 routes
we are also clarifying uh what happens
if you have on the on the service
gateways that are following the 9014
procedures and they have a interconnect
internet segments how you deal with the
ESI and the d-path because both could be
used to to detect Loops so we are
clarifying that in the draft
and some other minor changes
next slide please
again so this is uh version zero two uh
We've presented this uh several times so
we believe it's ready for working group
adoption
and but of course in the meantime we we
welcome any feedback
so thank you
thank you
Jorge thank you for the nice
presentation
do I understand the draft correctly that
all of the changes that you're
suggesting are within a single as
uh independent I would say in the same
way that RFC 9014 does not specify if if
the gateways are connecting domains
within the same as or not I I would
suggest my same comments from the deep
path if you're in a single domain you
need to put an exception 444
for the route reflectors if you're not
retaining the same
consistency if you're between domains
you should explain what the error
handling is there
just this and if I'm unclear I can take
it offline or do if you want me to
answer it here I can
yeah we we can we can certainly do that
the my only comment would be that uh RFC
19014 is one example uh that it's
already noticed in the that centers was
not written there right but yeah we can
do that if it happens I I would suggest
that addition
um I would suggest uh nine 90 14 bits
but let's just go on and suggest it
Filipino so there are some other
documents following kind of the same
architecture so
let's agree to disagree on the past and
go forward if that's my suggestion going
forward sounds good thank you
any other questions uh questions
okay so um one more this is about
um multicast forwarding for evpn to EVP
and gateways uh or eggs
um this is a new work and it's pretty
much based on some gaps that we
identified in in the different EVP
multicast drafts so I'm presenting this
on behalf of a bunch of people from
Nokia Arista and Juniper
uh next slide please
so I'll talk about introduction some
procedures and next steps next slide
please
all right so why why are we doing this
um there are two parts
um and again we'll we'll be talking here
about service gateways
and what I mean by that is you have
multiple domains and you have a service
gateways interconnecting those domains
it can be uh for Layer Two services or
layer 3 services
let's talk about Layer Two Services
first
so we know that we have RFC 9251 that is
defined in item pmld proxy in the
context of evpn in a single evpn and
broadcast domain
we also have
949014 which is defining uh the service
Gateway connectivity uh for Unique ass
and for bomb traffic
but not for IP multicast
because of of that basically
um
the the equation that came up is how how
do we interconnect two or more evpn
domains with uh you know gateways
following 9014
when uh the piece in in the domains
basically support the igmp MLD proxy VPN
procedures right
that was not defined anywhere so we
needed a place to do it
similarly for layer 3 we have the evpn
at pvpn interworking draft which defines
service gateways capabilities for IP
unicast traffic
we also have the oism draft or the IRB
multicast draft
that is defining how to bridge and Route
multicast with evpm procedures
that graph is actually defined in
service gateways between oism and team
Pim or mvpn
but the question is uh
we are missing a place where we specify
what happens if you have two evpn layer
three domains and you want to forward IP
multicast between them that was not
specified anywhere
so result of that we uh we thought it
was needed this uh we needed this
document so next slide please
so the document has two distinct parts
so one for Layer Two another one for
layer three
so if we talk about layer 2 first
the diagram is um it's an illustration
that is also included in the draft and
uh you can see that there are uh two
evpn domains right
uh all the piece and gateways are
attached to the same broadcast domain
right the gateways in between they are
connecting those to evpn domains
here in the example we have uh we assume
that one domain is uh is using vx9
encapsulation and the other one is mpls
or SRM TLs but any other two
encapsulations would be also valid
so what we are doing here is we assume
that the gateways are following the
c9014 procedures for for unicast and
bump including the interconnected
terminal segment
uh what we are extending here is that
now the gateways they import the sment
routes or the selective multicast
ethernet tank routes coming from the
piece
and they perform what we call a proxy
function of those estimate routes right
when you'd use when you use redundancy
in the interconnect internet segment
there is a DF and a non-df so we
mandated EF to do the proxy function of
the esmet routes there is an option too
if you wanted to to provide a faster
convergence in case of a failure there
is an option for the non-df to also do
the proxy function of the azmet routes
that is also allowed
and when you do that basically uh there
is a risk of a control plane Loop for
the estimate routes between the
Redundant gateways that's why we also
introduce the t-path for the s-met
routes
in the data plane there are no
extensions here so basically the non-df
will block the Ingress and Ingress
multicast as per the RFC 9014
and the draft also supports local
receivers and sources on the service
gateways
next slide please
um similar thing but now the service
gateways are layer 3 so you have an IP
verf instantiated
uh it follows pretty much the procedures
of the oism draft
the only extensions here is that since
there are two oism domains
the the draft talks or explains the
procedures using two sbds instead of one
SBD the usbd is the supplementary
broadcast domain that is defined in the
oism draft only that here we are using
two per ipverf
now it's uh it's important to mention
that the draft also says that if the
gateways are able to perform the all the
procedures with uh with a single SBD in
other words if the behavior in the on
the wires is the same as the the ones
you know explained in the draft
if the implementation uses only one SBD
that's perfectly compliant with the
draft
um there is uh there is also here we
Define one more flag for the multicast
texts and the communities uh that is
exchanged by the gateways on the iMed
routes for the SBD and based on that
there is a Dr election or a designated
router election so the Dr in this
context is the the one in charge of uh
doing the proxy function similar to the
the layer 2 case for the estimate routes
between domains
um yeah we also support her uh here's
local uh receivers and sources on the on
the service gateways uh next slide
please
it's a first version so of course we are
very interested in uh in feedback from
the working group
and that's it
any questions
all right thank you
okay thank you
Greg thank you
first step
hello I'm presenting on behalf of my
co-authors
um so this is an update uh to our draft
and advertising applicability of sbfd in
um multi-homed P domain and four inter
area next one at least
okay so I was invited and I was happy to
join as a coffer and uh we worked in
updated scenario descriptions uh next
slide please
so the BFD is uh well known and
established method of uh uh fast
detection of faults but uh it does bear
uh some extra operational
uh work that requires provisioning of
BFD sessions uh sbfd overcomes uh some
of this uh operational aspects uh but uh
just to simplify it
um does require their
uh information about the IP address of
their reflector sbfd reflector and the
discriminator that this um
reflector
um
allocates for sbfd session or sessions
um so
um the rfcs already established
um extensions to igp to edit for uh
systems to advertise their uh be sbfd
discriminators so uh this document uh
extends this functionality
uh into bgp next slide
for inter and intra area
uh scenario so this is uh scenario one
uh so as you can see
so the idea is that you have a service
CE uh double uh home uh with their uh
service please and uh then uh their
set of
um
access piece the idea is that uh service
B advertises its
um the discriminator so that xsps can
monitor uh this
um
a service six uh
locator
any questions about the scenario
okay next slide please
uh so uh scenario two is similar again
we have uh double homed
um service C and then uh service PES
advertise
um
um as B of D
um extension uh with the discriminator
and the source IP address and so the
access piece can monitor their um
status of their connection and the PE
because understandably uh in sbfd you
cannot differentiate whether it's a path
failure or not failure so you need to
have uh integral view in it basically
fall over and then uh separately do
um
fault localization and restoration but
at least because it's redundancy so
there is this uh architecture allows you
for the fast detection and fast fell
over
next slide please
so what's been used uh the bin used the
BFD discriminator that is defined in RFC
9026 so this is was case uh for uh point
to point uh BFD mode so in this document
we propose uh two new values for uh BFD
mode parameter uh one of them is to
detect a service 6 locator prefix and
another one is to um
uh
um
next hop
um locator in both cases
um
optional Tov carries the source IP
address so that uh the receiver of this
um
that attribute can understand what case
is uh being tested and uh next slide
please
so here's um
basically what each of the actors in uh
in this process does so as BFD reflector
um
uses BFD discriminator attribute to
advertise uh my discriminator uh value
and um
IP Source address to V to advertise is
an address so the
um expected sbfd initiator upon
receiving
um the the discriminator path attribute
can analyze whether it's a type 1 or
it's type 2 user scenario
and start
sending periodic uh BFD control messages
so that when they're
in our case uh service B receives it it
um sends it back
um and um
so their access uh D is capable of
monitoring the path and uh status of
given
service B and then if there is a failure
then switch over to a redundant
destination
next slide please
so with that we welcome comments and
discussions and we think that the draft
is uh uh stable and uh and currently ask
you for consider working group adoption
okay Castle is in the queue
um
but I don't see an on meet
so Greg I understand this is the BFD uh
discriminator attribute uh which is
already existing
and that's defined as an optional
transitive attribute uh in the RFC where
it was introduced it was applicable for
mvpn uh but my understanding that your
ex expanding its use
to probably all other uh office as well
here
yes correct actually uh
okay
um
going back to the original RFC in
discussion uh that we had
um and now can better appreciate their
uh suggestions from Jeff
um uh to make it uh more generic so now
uh and you are right and the scenario
that being covered in original RFC for
point to multipoint was different
because then
um for point to multi-point BFD it is uh
their head end advertises its uh
discriminator value so informing the
leaves in this case yes we're using
existing attribute but it's reverse so
it's a reflector advertises
discriminator value that it expects
[Music]
um
Ingress or
packets BFD control uh messages to
descend it with uh and use this value as
your discriminator so that reflector uh
the multiplexes them
right so uh that's what I understood as
well uh so uh my concern here is that uh
this is an optional transitive and I
know uh probably you may be aware or not
but there has been discussion in the IDR
working group about these attributes
going uh I mean and in your example
pictures uh you showed about Crossing as
borders right yes so I think uh you
might want to uh check on this uh with
that in the idea working group to get
inputs on how to prevent this
information from leaking out especially
because this also applies to every uh uh
everyone right so I I just wanted to
bring that up here
okay thank you for your comment and
suggestion definitely will uh educate
ourselves on that and uh
um bring it more probably more we'll
welcome more expertise with from RDR and
I guess we have Jeff
ready to comment
Jeff for you specifically addressing
this idea comment okay I'll let you go
ahead of going there okay Jeff has uh so
keitans made the point excellently the
thing the general advice idea I would
give and a number of these issues is
if the attribute gets attached to
something that can leak into general
internet or other context what bad
things can happen so framing this
specific issue here do you really want
the outside rule to have your BFD
discriminators and you know this what
you're sort of telling people is uh you
know spfd is a reflector technology
reflector Technologies are used for
reflector attacks so this is the danger
of having you know a service like spfd
which has no authentication for Echo
being advertised the outside world
certainly you can limit access to these
Technologies through firewalls you can
you know make sure your domains actually
are filtering things appropriately but
uh what you'd get is advice from the
security ads is that this is inadvertent
disclosure in some cases optional
transitive is unfortunately very leaky
for bgp and once you put it in there
it's sort of hard to get rid of it so
I'm not saying this is the wrong way
that bgp would want to do this but we
have to address the security
considerations thank you and um actually
um you pointing out and highlighting
this uh security uh one of the um
uh mechanism to mitigate security risk
is a use of
um Source IP address in BFD
discriminator attribute so basically
that gives uh the reflector way of uh
verifying uh the source of BFD control
messages and then uh protecting itself
from uh service attacks right and that's
great for control mode for spfd but for
reflector mode I'm not personally aware
of implementations that are quite that
picky yet
so this may move into you know
additional security or considerations
for spfd okay thank you
okay uh
yes
um can you hear me
yes so just a quick question you're in
the drafted mention the evpn but I'm
guessing this is also applicable to L3
VPN
or probably even mvpn as well
thank you
um
can you repeat that actually well
um we we well their assumption is that
evpn is interpreted as a VPN with their
uh bgp based control plane so if
you're using bgp to to do control of
their VPN then
that
technique will be applicable
okay you think in the drafted mentions
evpn so I would just mentioning that
like maybe explicitly saying ipvpn or
maybe even mvpn I guess just a variety
of different um you know okay yeah I
guess I see yes I might be that
clarification would be helpful because
uh you're right so basically that uh
what's
intended to be uh monitored as a
destination is uh related to a service
six
um locator and the policy So yeah thank
you for your suggestion we'll uh make
the analysis and clarify uh the scope of
this work okay so it's it's cut on an
energy and then I've closed the queue
because we need to move on
uh yeah I just took Ketone here just a
quick follow-up to Jeff's comments uh
and I'm wondering whether uh approach
that was used for uh the ELC V3 uh isn't
that some kind of something that is
needed in this case as well I'm not
really sure if just putting things in
the security considerations would be uh
good enough
I'm just wondering yeah
okay uh I I guess that's something that
we we need to talk with you as ideal
experts so
thank you
from Hawaii uh firstly I think uh the
motivation of this work is uh start from
the srv6 service
the spfd in that case well we also can
generalize it to other related three
vpns that is also possible we may add
some clarification about this in this
version and regarding the security or
the the
announcement scope of this feature
actually if we use it with a VPN in the
context.vpn the distribution of this
attribute will be constrained together
with the vaping rounds so I think that
is also uh controllable for VPN service
route right so I agree we can we need
further discusses with IDR about the
general cases yeah of course thank you
okay thank you thanks
so next is final
thank you
hello can you hear me
yes we can hear you
ah okay my name is
here is a closer of this draft
next next slide please
uh this document was published before
itf112 and a presented in item 113 and
8114 and there is a long Suite of
technical discussion on this document
with Jeffrey so thanks generally for the
discussion I was in the adoption and the
review request to working group after uh
itf114 but not replied too long
so this time I will choose the main
points of this document to present her
game next slide please
a long segment the interest Tower
establishment procedure with which
defend in RC
6514 and rc651
six six five uh one five fix some
problems in iqb6
infrastructure scenario in the regular
and whipping procedure of RC
6014 division long segmented in her as
Demarcus root using originator IP of the
root P to fill the sources field of the
mli and the SBR counters C markets group
locating between s along with the
reserved parts of intra sad using
artists and sources of C martial UI to
match against Rd and originator FC of
the corresponding interest ad the
problem is that the sources field of the
cmatic housing AI is four bet one
for Badlands cannot hold IPv6
originating IP in IPv6 influence
function scenarios
next slide please
so here is the proposed solution
for the propagating culture between
asses
svr steel cultural C markets locating
along with the reserved parts of the
instrument sad Studio use Rd of
cmaticals in our match against study of
the corresponding interest ad the only
modification is that the global
administrator field of the IPv6 thematic
has import RT is instead of sources
field of simultaneous URI to match
against the originated later IP of the
corresponding interest ad
all those IPv6 extend the community
carry in the simultaneously include more
than one
IPv6 input artists there is only one
which would will be used by the route
key to import the corresponding
schematic handle to its local where I
have
another only one IPv6 import RT has a
characteristics that the local
administrator field is non-zero which
can be used by the procedure to
distinguish it from the other input
artists it should be loaded that in GTM
scenarios the local administrator field
on IPv6 in polarity used by root P to
import the corresponding simultaneous
root is also
zero according to uh is also zero
according to RC
7761 so we suggest that the local
administrator field of the activistics
important GTM scenario is also filled
with a Long Level value which are sent
by root Shield through the way of
importer RT carry the new image rules so
in this document
so the solution complies with the
regular programming procedure in RC 6514
with only a language modification to
adapt the regular one to xv6 in
restriction scenarios
next slide please
if there are only one root key for a
specific grammatical Source the solution
is in previous slides is enough
here are the scenarios that a specific
multiple Source smart home into multiple
piece the long segment is the interior
as C multiple root must be discussed for
each individual root piece there are
three options option one each root be
configured with 16 Rd which is
recommended in
rc6514 option two each root C configured
with a distinct format emulation
distinguishers to use to fill the
sources field of C multiples in URI
option three only please use the comma
Hashi algorithm to calculate the uh 16
fat loot IPS 204 but unique unique
distinguishers to failure sources field
of C marketing AI option 2 and office 3
are used in the scenarios of English she
configured with a scene Rd gtms as an
example
in this document the sources field or C
marketing UI is renamed to root
distinguisher
next slide please
in the process we will write it will
reaching to fpv6 ipv4 and everything V6
infrastructure stress will cause in
providers Network
the following figure is uh
example is an example of pgp MLP enable
Evolution to activate six ipv4 and IPv6
power which sessions are established and
the number of passes of this route will
be doubled with each reflection
next slide please
so the solution is that to reduce BGC
and whipping routes in parallel ipv4
another IPv6 specification networks the
firing action should be taken by a
standard piece for interest iPhone
message routes and the new 3D route if
the originated root IPS address field in
the root is filled with the iqv6 address
is seen to the IPv6 laborers RS is
signature ipv4 BB labels for inner as IP
message root and Source active ad Roots
is seen through both IPv6 VPC labels and
ipu4pv labors for similar house rules if
the IPv6 we have Roots importing
external completely exists in the root
is sent to ipvc exp neighbors otherwise
it is seen to the ipv4 pdpc labels in
the reflector routers the part of roots
which are received from IPv6 speed label
will be reflected to other IPv6 specific
labels another other part of the route
which are received from ipv4 bit of
Labor will be reflected to other ipv4 PB
labels
next slide please
uh so comments are welcome uh uh we are
also seeking for working group adoption
I think they used to described in the
document is clear and the solution is
very low
as an adoption request after the last
item meetings but the no response
received so I request the key in this
time and which is a working group could
give some response it would be operation
you can give some suggestion or point
out the gaps for the adoption of this
document thank you
try to go ahead yeah Jeffrey Donald drop
her down from juniper
um so indeed we have had some
discussions on the marianist I don't
think we have reached agreement on
what's the best way to address this my
understanding that you have three
problems here in this script
the first problem
um there was another there's another
solution another trapped which I
presented in Las IHF as well and I
requested for adoption that draft covers
uh many
issues and solutions for
for symmetrical related issues and your
second problem does not seem to be IPv6
specific
um so
the the third one is indeed IPv6 uh
specific and we was not covered in other
drafts
um but going forward what's uh best uh
way I think we can we should discuss
more but indeed uh I just want to
mention that we also have requested for
adoption for the other drafts and
I have presented last time and also
followed up with with the
with the with the chairs with their
adoption request
thanks
yeah we have a lot of adoption requests
at the moment so if you could email the
unicast the chairs
um to best shows at least you have
thought that would really help actually
because I think just about every draft
that gets presented or asking for
working group adoption yeah I understand
I understand we have a queue yes yeah
thanks
I'm sure we haven't missed anything
okay
thank you
next is uh Swedish I think
yeah hi I'm swadesh Agarwal from Cisco
Systems
uh
this is a new draft uh this is for bgp
extensions for srb6 and mpls
interworking and I'm presenting on the
behalf of my authors next slide please
so there's a spring draft which
describes the srv6 and MPS interworking
architecture in the multi-domain network
where each domain run srv6 and mpls
independently and that document already
had the bgp protocol extensions so what
we are doing here is we are extracting
the protocol extensions in this new
draft and this is done to independently
State bgp protocol requirements and the
future applicability of them for the use
cases
next slide please
so we Define a new tlv as it is called
sr6 tunnel for label route
uh with the this is carried in the bgp
prefixed attribute to Signal the srv6
Sid along with the mpls label bound to
the bound to the prefix in the nlri
so SRC terminal tunnel for the label
route tlv signals and semantics that is
push the
a label signal in the nlri and perform H
Dot N caps with the destination as a
sr66 signal in this new tlv
and this tlv is encoded exactly like
srv6 services tlv in the prefixed
attribute Define already defined in RFC
9252 without transposition
set Behavior which is uh currently
defined for this uh tlv is a n dot DTM
but in future new behaviors may come up
next slide please
this shows how this uh tlv is carried so
we have a Services running from ah E 10
to E1 which is I'm showing here VPN
Services the VPN label and on one we
need a reachability to E10 low back so
it's at our left and the right domain
are mpls and the middle domain is srv6
so E10 doesn't know anything about a
middle domain it's advertised the
loopback in bgplu a regular one with the
prefix E10 implicitinal and the next top
on the seven what we do these we
allocate this set of DTM behavior and we
carry that acid in the prefixed
attribute of this new tlv type
and as well as we carry the MPS label
which is bound to the prefix a regularly
like bgplu
and the behavior is DTM and it is C by
node 4 and 4 will do a next top cell and
an advertise to E1 as a regular bgplu
update so now when the packet which
service traffic that comes on E1 would
be it's a regular encapsulation with the
ABR label and the bgplu label to E10 but
on node 4 if you see what it's doing
it's it's pushing both the it's doing a
swap operation for uh label for the
prefix for E10 that means 16010 as well
as it's doing H dot end caps with the
DTM behavior and for DTM Behavior which
is defined in the spring graph it means
decapsulation and lookup of look up the
label uh below the header in the mpls
table so that 16010 which is from the uh
will carry the packet to the E10
regularly next slide please
so there's another another case we we
need to advertise SRB succeed and in
this case this as I've said is bound to
the prefix in the nlri like mpls label
this is a set for each uh prefix in the
nlri
it is carried in the Safi it's a loop uh
this is this is of the DPM Behavior Uh
and it's carried in Safi 4 uh R1
I can go to next slide please
so we can see what happens is it's
exactly same scenario but uh we
advertising E10 in bgplu which is
received by the Note 7 but Note 7 here
allocates both the label and srv6 set
bound to the prefix that's important and
this document extends the bgp prefixes
attribute uh to carry the this this sit
in the srv6 layer 3 Services tlb Define
in RFC 9252 with rp12 and the Safi 4.
tlv is encoded exactly like SRV services
tlb in the prefixed attribute without
transposition because we are carrying
both the label and the SRV 68 so there
is no transportation we can do
such an update can be processed both by
the Legacy mpls AVR that means 4 could
be an srs6 capable or a legacy also both
will take and do the do the relevant
encapsulation next slide please
another case is what can happen is 7
only supports the srv6 Sid bound to the
prefix so it's not allocating the label
in this case since we can't use label as
Safi 4 Safi 4 needle label so what we do
is we use a Safi one and in that we it's
already defined in nine to five RFC 9252
to carry a sr6 sid for Safi one in the
prefix it attribute we do exactly same
procedures so there's nothing new it's
just a use case showing how we can
achieve uh in case we don't have a label
in the on the border nodes of srv6
domain
next next slide please
yeah so we will We would like working
group to review and provide comments
this is something which is already just
a background this is already defined in
the it was already defined in the spring
document we just extracted here so it
was there from last 10 versions here we
are presenting in the best now a
separate document
thank you
foreign did I understand right that you
are expanding uh what was originally the
bgp
uh prefix for Sid
just meant I'll get the RFC number if
you are you should be presenting this in
IDR because that's the original home on
the draft
but although sr66 like for services we
went in the best but if you wish I can
present in the idea also it would be
good also if it's a draft that you're
modifying that's an rrc in IDR Swedish
it'd be best to
present it and get some feedback that
way you get the the review uh that that
from the original review sure it may be
the same people but it could be helpful
no problem
um well thanks for presenting this here
in best I think it was it was needed
um I have just one question out of
curiosity so for the DPM Behavior you
have two cases uh either
binding only their service six
to the prefix or srv6 set plus the label
I wonder so the latter is just for
migration purposes and then the idea is
to have the just the yeah so if you have
a green field sr6 domain border routers
may not be allocating the labels so
that's the reason we gave that option
but most likely the way we feel is for
the migration cases we will use the Safi
4 only in which we carry both the mpls
label as well as the sr68 okay got it
thank you
any other comments
on your next
sorry I'm trying to find
hi can everyone hear me
yep okay hi my name is Gian Mishra and
I'm presenting this draft this uh four
drafts on behalf of co-authors so the
four drafts are
um it's I I show the first two is
related to the IPv6 only PE design so
this is IPv6 only key design and then
the second draft is a super set of the
first draft and that's IPv6 OMP design
all sappy uh the next few draft pair is
the ipv4 only P design and then the um
and then the all safety uh so I'll I'll
be going over all four graphs in this
presentation next slide
foreign
BCP it was adopted in April of 2021 uh
so the folks of this draft is a proof of
concept testing DCP for vendor
implementations and operators uh
deployment so with this the ipv is only
PE design uh supports Safi one two and
two uh it was then further updated to
support one two and then Safi 128 and
129 uh
the ad users from IP Design This the the
next draft uh which was mentioned about
in the in the first slide is is called
it's the IPv6 Olympic design but it's
all sassy so it's extensible to all
safety so we're taking the same concept
that was applied then we're testing with
it with with the vcp use case with the
original set of staffies but now we're
providing that extensibility with this
new draft to support false happy so the
force folks have just so this is
basically a superset of the first draft
uh and this one would be standards track
uh so the goal of this draft is uh to
focus on the P design change perspective
and language related to there's a
paradigm shift so what we're doing with
both of these drafts is it's an
alternative and and and a BCP as well as
a new standard that whenever you have
any type of p c e Peery or inner ASP to
PE pairing then now you're able to
use this new new uh Paradigm Shift
option where you actually have a IPv6
only PE so the PE would actually get all
the uh NRA SP to P peers or PE to P
peers they would it would be a single V6
peer and you're you're being you would
be able to carry it all safety
um and you'd still be able to support
both could both data planes so the V4 V6
data plan are supported but now you
don't have
two sets of peers a set of V4 peers and
aesthetic V6 peers so there's a
tremendous capex and Apex savings as
well as the big savings with V4 address
depletion so that that's a really big
one with um with this design
um next slide
so with this with this uh
designed with the proof with the IPv6
only P design and sorry with this with
the ipv4 only I'm sorry iqv6 only PE
design uh uh testing an update that we
had is uh we're planning to complete all
the tests the vendor testing so Cisco
Juniper and Nokia were planning to
complete by the end of this year that's
really the Target that we're looking at
uh all of the vendors support a vendor
Pacific nav reporting ipv4 package
without an ipv4 address so they all
support that and that's that's uh that's
a critical component of the testing
um and Huawei is uh planning to complete
by 2023. uh Aristo we don't have an ETA
but right now we're we're we have a lot
of focus on the first three uh trying to
get that all completed uh by The End by
the end of the year
next slide
so the ipv4 only PE design so uh from
ietf 114
um and I did mention it in the other
side when I was going over the IPv6 only
PD design but uh we we had some feedback
from the working group uh during the uh
itf-114 on combining drafts so in the
slide that I I had just gone over with
the IPv6 only PE design the first draft
had been adopted uh but however the
second draft is we're still progressing
that draft and we're hoping for an
adoption you know queuing up for
adoption call uh however
because they are because they've uh the
first draft had already been adopted
um our thoughts are actually the
progressive separate the second draft
separately and not combine the two
drafts but we would like to see feedback
from the working group
um as well as chairs on combining those
two drafts given that uh one draft has
been adopted and the other draft is a
new extensible drafty all safety draft
and whether we can still whether it's
possible to still combine those two
drafts and it would save on Cycles on
working through an adoption call so with
this draft these both of these drafts
are new drafts so what I've done is I've
I have already combined from the
feedback from ITF 114 I have combined
both of these traps so the V6 only
p-designed what I did was I took that
draft and combined it into the new draft
the all safety draft so now it's really
this all sassy draft that we would be
progressing forward that would be
all-encompassing it would Encompass the
the proof of concept testing that we
would be doing
with with the uh V4 LEP design with
safety one two 128 129
and then it would also Encompass all
safies the extensibility as well as of
the next top encoding so with this track
it does have an Ina code Point
allocation
um for a update on next stop encoding
and we'll go over that in the substitute
slide next slide
so so the IPv6 only P design and v4p
design timelines and caveats so with
this
this is an important slide as I wanted
to kind of key in on the timeline for
testing as well as
the staffies and what we'll be testing
and then as well as the uh extensibility
uh to all the others happy and that's
really one of the folks here just kind
of making that clear so in in the in the
IPv6 only P design so we will be testing
safety one 128 and I have a typo there
but Safi 1 128 and 129.
um those are the three statues that are
being tested for both the V4 and EP
design and the V6 only be designed so
that that's that's the folks what's
being tested uh
for the IP uh V6 only P design the
extensibility so here actually I have a
slight typo it's supposed to be igv6
only feed design so the support for all
safy the Paradigm Shift you know so that
part of the draft we're providing the
folks on the standardization and you
know to support all staffy however we
would not be testing any other safeties
other than just the one once that's
happening one 128 and 129 so I just
wanted to make that clear
um and then further testing related to
the all safety is really uh deferred
that as uh operator decide to deploy
um staffies other than these first three
staffies to support any of the other
zafies that uh they can work with the
vendors of their choice as they're as
they're working to um test and deploy
any of the other safeties uh you know
that are that you know that that would
be supported
the IP existence only if you decide the
plan is as I had mentioned in the other
slide that we plan to complete by the
end of the year and the ipv4 only PE
design testing we plan to start after we
finish the V6 only key design testing so
we want to get the V6 only pizza and get
that progressed uh to work with last
call hopefully once we could get all the
complete testing completed which which
we're we're on track to complete the
ipv4 only PE design
so this one so the new so it's a new
IPv6 that ipv is only feeds on it it
involves a new Next Top encoding which
we'll be testing
using the existing next stop encoding so
with this and we'll I have a slide that
actually kind of really digs into this a
little more detail but this this uh the
IPv6 only if you designed so since it
involves both a new next stop encoding
but we have an existing F10 Next Top
encoding what we would do is we would be
following in in our testing we would be
using what exists with the vendors so
whether they're using an ipv4 mapped
IPv6 address or an ipv store address so
following the RFC 5549 or 8950 next up
including style uh we wouldn't test that
or if they support the map address uh we
would we would test either option uh
we'll work with each each of the um the
vendor development teams to get their
support and agreement on the change to
the RFC 5549 89.50 next up including
style so that would be a four byte ipv4
address for safety one two and four and
then for Safi 128 129 the Rd plus the Rd
field of eight bytes are you know set to
zero a 12 byte next stop encoding
standard so it'd be a V4 address four
byte for one two and four and then 128
and 129 it would be a 12 byte in total
so including eight byte with an already
zero so once each vendor has developed
the new next stop and trading we would
go through and test that new next
happening encoding method and then
progress the drafting of RC next slide
please because your 10 minutes is up now
oh 10 minutes ago okay thank you so just
just
okay all right thank you um let's let's
uh skip over to go down to um
skip to the next slide
um
yeah so I'm just gonna just Breeze
through a couple of these slides so in
this slide we talked about the ipv4 on
AP exide so in this slide we're it's a
V4 address but basically all the
semantics of an actual dual stacking
this is providing a alternative to
existing uh existing uh dual stacking
but now you have a V6 address but all
normal functionality that exists with uh
with your peering would still would
still be the same the V4 V6 forwarding
everything that would normally happen on
a uh V4 Next Top the IPv6 only P design
is exactly is a similar alternative to a
dual stack pairing but now you know
supporting all the same functionality
that you would normally have a dual
stacking but now without that before
address configured
um next next slide
um
so in this slide I wanted to um go over
the next top encoding so with the next
top encoding So currently today there is
a where that with the IPv6 next Saturday
next up encoding standardization change
that that we're proposing in in this
draft so today you either have a itv4
mapped IPv6 address or there may be
cases where you have a AIP ipv4 address
so similar to the RFC 5549 or 8950 next
top encoding so what this draft is
supposed to do is really is really to
standardize that next hop encoding that
he uses a ipv4 address and not a mapped
address and that's a goal and
again just sorry we've got about 30
seconds till we we would start that we
would uh in silence so okay
um yeah maybe maybe just pause here and
then we'll take questions after the two
minutes okay great thank you very good a
few seconds to go
all right I'm just I'm gonna wrap up and
then I'll I'll take questions
um I'll go ahead and so so basically in
this in this slide it's like two seconds
to go now so uh okay
I'll go ahead and take questions now so
thank you afterwards yeah thanks
I think there's two people in the queue
does anyone have any questions they want
to ask
captain or or it's I see two people in
the queue
well I can go with kitten is not
does not want to go
so I think this is a pretty good set of
drafts and it's interesting to see them
progressing
um the
I have one thing that I want to
want you to look at and that's really
the abstract
um most of the time when people write
apps right they are too abstract so the
section doesn't stay much more than
um what the title says
I think you are making the opposite
mistake you are
way too detailed and my suggestion would
actually be to move the current upset
into the introduction and then write a
10 15 line abstract per draft on a level
level that
a technical
uh Advanced person couldn't understand
uh I think you should look at RC 7322
uh for guiding on how to how to write
abstracts thank you
thanks Laura thank you
all right
thank you
uh
period was up
because the clocks may not be
synchronized can you hear me
hello
[Music]
yes we can hear you okay
uh okay I I will uh I'm sorry about that
uh
I missed the announcement that the
period was over
um but uh I'll send it over the email
thank you
hi
can you hear me
hello can you hear me
yeah we can hear you
okay
so I will start my presentation now
hi everyone I'm Sue from Huawei and Mike
my concert is phone home who is also
from Hawaii too
um yes
so today I'm glad to present my new
version draft about the mvpn Upstream
designated for the selection
next slide please
hello
boom cannot hear us and yeah
[Music]
okay
um so next slide please
so was it two minutes or five minutes no
no no no no no no I I think kittens that
there is an audio issue with the room
now
so Matthew I don't know if Matthew is
unable to uh to hear us and we also
count irim
okay
so they are currently checking uh if
there is something going wrong
[Music]
okay let's let's wait to see if we can
fix it
oh hi
um maybe I need to check and not just
check my network and switch another
laptop so can I speak later after the
next president no it's not it's not
coming from you it's really coming from
uh from the London location
a London location yeah yeah so I I think
it's okay for everybody who are remote
but uh but the local guys are are not
able to hear us and we are not able to
uh together
it's it's a problem in London
yeah
now we can hear you Matthew can you hear
us
Okay so
okay so Matthew is telling that we will
do
okay so we'll do in person first and
then catch up with remote
Play Just displayed his presentation so
maybe I can use his laptop to try again
later
cover the design scenarios
and next slide please
so um this is the
the background uh unless you know this
is the picture shows that uh hard
standby mode uh uh we have
two uh redundant sources connected to
to V Taps there
um let me look at this
yeah it's a
so um basically in the mpos case we have
the ECI labels advertised in the uh
spz route to to indicate the SPG route
has served two purposes one to announce
that certain flows are redundant floats
it also carry the ESI labels so that the
egress P can use to tell which uh that
which flow is for from which
Ingress PE so in that case the egress
speeds can can decide which flow to
accept and which flow to discard but in
the IP based data plane and
where the ESI labels are not used so in
that case we would just use the IP Edge
Source address of the outer
encapsulation to tell which flow is from
which Ingress PE and so that we know
which flow to accept
in the I actually to to clarify in the
IP based tunnel there are two situations
one is the vxline and and then the other
one and is the genev
and I forgot which the other one where
it does also have the
equivalence of the ESI label so in that
case we can still use the ESI and label
a based approach for that purpose
next slide please
so
um in the DSi case
um
we have a pair of gateways between the
two between the data center and data
center interconnects
so the the gateways
will uh receive the both flows from the
Redundant sources and they will use the
existing procedures to to decide which
flow
like the Gateway should accept and after
that the normal procedure is that only
the
the destiny folder
of those two of those gateways will
forward the traffic into the next data
center or data center interconnect in
this case
um
we could follow the same method that
only the uh the Gateway will forward but
then we will lose the protection and
once we pass the Gateway and so now the
new procedure here in the data uh sender
interconnect case is the gateways
regardless of the
uh
testing the forward or not or for the
traffic
so now again egress piece will receive
duplicate floats and now they need to
decide whether to accept traffic or not
and to do that the gateways will
re-originate the SPG route
based on the received SPG route to
announce the redundancy case and
in case of mqos data plan internet uh in
the downstream we can use the again use
these ESI label
that is associated with that
interconnects a virtual segment but here
the one difference is that
those gateways they should have
different ESL labels for the same
virtual need in a segment so that's uh
the downstream piece or gateways can
use to determine which flows are from
which Gateway and then decide which
flows to accept
again
and that's the assuming when the
downstream segment a downstream is the
mpos data playing or genev or srb6 data
plane
um but for other scenarios like vxlan we
were used
Source address of the gateways in the
outer encapsulation to determine the
flow and to determine the whether we
accept or not
there is also a
another situation where
even when you don't have the
true Source redundancy then
the fact that the post gateways are
received as the single flow they can
still decide to based on the operator's
choice they can all send traffic to the
to the downstream whether it's a text
entry forward or not that's what we call
Gateway introduced flow redundancy and
similarly the um as long as the all the
gateways and all the peas in the domain
um act the same follow the same
procedure the downstream peas or
gateways they can know that some
there is this redundancy flow from the
Gateway so that they can pick which flow
to accept and which flow to drop
next slide please
um so we have described the procedures
in the uh in the draft but we need to
add more details on the normative part
of the the draft we we will add more
details
to the draft in the meantime we says
request feedbacks and comments from the
working group
any comments
do not see anyone in the queue
thank you
so say if you if you're still there
we'll go back to you now I think I think
it should be working again now okay
okay let's start
hi everyone I'm Steve from Hawaii and
Funko is my co-author and I'm glad to
present my new version draft about the
mvpn Upstream designated for the
selection so previously we have
presented a draft in the ITF 113 and 114
so next slide please
so when there are multiple PES in
English sites we need to designate one
as primary forward the traffic to the
leaf PE another PE is chosen as a
standby designated folder as a backup
but primary and standby receive traffic
from both primary and standard ape
receives the traffic from multicast
source in warm route standby scenario
only primary PE will fraud traffic to
live PE in IFC
1926 livpi needs to select primary and
standby PE however problems such as
inconsistency between the root and leaf
P will result in slow fare over time
therefore we propose the idea that the
Ingress PE should designate folders
themselves to avoid the inconsistency
Leaf PE will also accept all traffic
from root PES
so this time instead of the vrrp method
in previous version We propose our new
systematic and endogenous procedures for
Ingress DF election and phosphere over
we also introduced relevant attribute
and Community next slide please
so since the E Ingress PE will negotiate
about the IDF role we propose two
negotiation modes here the passive and
the active one in passive mode c will
decide which routes will forward traffic
to leave PE the interfaces that are
multi-home CE to PE are combined in each
trunk interface
the root PES will be bundled together
using the multi-chases protocol while in
active mode the routers inside the c
network and PE inside the Ingress site
will be connected using layer 3
interfaces the Ingress PE this time of
independent routers traffic from
multicast Source will be folded to all
Ingress PES therefore the IDF election
and negotiation need to be done actively
inside the Ingress site next slide
please
so we Define a new community called IDF
negotiation Community it is carried in
the Upstream multicast help routes and
its value will be allocated from the bgp
well-known communities registry for each
negotiation mode the um Edge routes will
be delivered to the root PES and leave
PE for root PE it is used to notify each
other peas that this PE will participate
the IDF election and leaf P will regard
the community as a symbol to install the
corresponding p-tunnel routed from the
root PE into the leaf p is any cost RPF
checklist
The BFG discriminator attribute is
firstly defining IFC 9026 and we reduces
the format and we add a new BFD mode
type called unicast BFD session type the
value is suggested to be two the BFD
discriminator attribute needs to carry a
mandatory Source IP tlv this time the IP
address of this iptlv will be used to
establish the BFD session for failure
detection next slide please
foreign so let me introduce the election
procedure in detail route B is firstly
originates the umh roots and the
negotiation community and the BFD
discriminator attribute are carried
inside the IP addresses the source IPTV
in vfd discriminator attribute is the
RPF interface of the root PE as shown in
the figure
according to the negotiation Community
leave PE will send distinct C multicast
rules to HP root PE and pitano are
installed and traffic from those
installed pitanos will be valid and not
be dropped
next slide please
so uh the root distinguishers of HP root
p e for the same and Libyan are
suggested to be distinct when um
attribute to client multicast Source are
advertised to each root PE they will
know each other's originator IP
addresses the key procedure here is to
generate an ordered list of these IP
addresses in ascending order just as
shown in the table
firstly if for different scenarios two
methods are defined here firstly if all
c groups uses the same primary and the
standby IDF the election occurs upon
receiving all the UN attributes of other
pe's according to each pe's position
within the list they will be given
different indexes PE have index 0 will
be the primary IDF and with index 1 will
be the standby PE
so next slide please
the second method is for the load
balancing scenario this time different
groups can use different PES or IDF and
the one C group will have different p as
primary and standby PE the order list is
used here also but with different
algorithms the election occurs upon
receiving C multicast drawing of the
corresponding group from Leaf PE p with
index I will be the IDF if I equals to
group mode n after the IDF is selected
is elected a new ordered list without
idfpe will be used to calculate the
standby p e and the equation becomes J
equals to group mode n minus 1 and p e
with index J would be the standby IDF
next slide please
so we have elected our primary and
standby IDF with above procedures
another very important function of warm
route standby scenario is to detect the
failure of the primary IDF and perform
faster over this time we mainly
introduce our endogenous method for
active mode
in order to detect the failure of the
primary IDF the standby IDF need to
initialize a BFD session the destination
IP address of the session is the ipf
interface of the primary IDF therefore
when the IDF device or its client facing
link is done the standby P will
immediately notice that and take over
the primary IDF role to forward the
traffic
when the traffic arrives at Leaf PE it
will not be dropped because the p tunnel
has already been installed into its any
cost RPF list
next slide please
so finally the data forwarding behavior
of the route and leave PES are discussed
in active mode if there are local
receivers at the Ingress site they can
receive traffic directly from the
corresponding root PES because all root
peas can receive traffic while in a
passive mode only one of the root PE can
receive traffic therefore the p with
local receivers will install pitano
towards the IDF the traffic will be
forwarded through the P tunnel and it
will only be forwarded towards the local
receivers to avoid the track traffic
Loop as for the leaf PES they accept the
traffic from hpe but at a time there
will be only one traffic that folded
from the source therefore they can
accept the traffic from the standby IDF
without latency
so next slide please
so that's all for my presentation so we
are welcome any comments and discussion
and thank you so if you have any
question you can ask
okay thanks very much I don't see I
think we should move ahead
um with the final final presentation
which is uh when then
are you there
you can try okay
let me just uh
um
so this is a proposal for a newly
extended Community to advertise
uh group-based policy ID
next slide please
so for EVP and vxlan there is this
concept of group based policy
um so that's uh
the Ingress p is
can
can signal to the egress PE in the data
package on what group policy to be
applied at the egress when the traffic
arrives there
um by the it could be that the Ingress
send the traffic to the egress and after
the egress applies the policy that's
steady signaled in the packet itself
then the decision is to drop the package
after we have got the packets of the
egress we want to avoid the situation
Next Step please
so we
want to apply the policy on the Ingress
instead of getting the traffic to the
egress and then dropped
next slide please
so this is the proposed extended
Community
um that encodes the group policy ID
um it's a non-trans transitive OPEC
extended Community we encode the policy
ID which is a 16-bit value there
um
I think we already got a type and
subtype allocated from Diana
this can be carried by the VPN type 2
type 5 and type 3 routes in control
plane so that the Ingress nodes knows
that uh for which traffic will apply the
policy on the Ingress side
next slide please
so um the DCI procedures uh will need to
be added we also request feedbacks from
the working group
okay
Nokia
yeah the the giraffe is is pretty clear
and straightforward my question is is
more about the group policy draft which
is a long time expired so uh is the
intend to resurrect it
um
I don't know the prank about that drafts
but apparently uh we have some uh
customer use cases that they wanted to
do
uh this kind of things
um I I think
uh need to ask wing and Zhang to talk
about the plan for that draft okay yeah
I think I I agree with you if this is
the first point there is no real point
to create something at the control plane
and try to standardize it if the data
plane is not standardized
so we may have to move forward
the the other comment and and probably
Matthews
can clarify but my understanding was
that the um yeah consensus was not to
extend a vxlan right but to if there is
an extension to do do it probably in
geneve or vxlan gpe right
but not vxlan per se
yeah we we didn't
so the VX Lan RFC anyway is was went
through on the individual track
um certainly from an nv03 perspective
the preference would definitely be to to
go for and use Junaid that's that's the
kind of ITF Direction
okay
um I actually I just realized that this
draft is
about using uh Ingress uh
uh policy enforcement to replace
the egress policy replacement so it does
it does not need a mean that we are
Reviving that uh group based policy
draft that's actually put into the uh uh
the policy ID into the vxn package
itself we are we're proposing a
different solution
okay so when you signal from the egress
PE to the Ingress is not used in the
data path right right this is an
alternative solution to that it's better
better option yeah okay I totally missed
it right thank you
I think uh one last comment from wendlin
is in the queue
disappeared
okay all right thanks so much everyone
and uh I think that's that's it
foreign
strange
sometimes technology
actually generally it was super well
um
foreign