thank you
okay so we are one past the hour uh we
can start a meeting and welcome everyone
this is the itf-150 meeting for the
co-working group I'm Marco my coaches
are I'm a humanity and Carson Borman
um before starting the actual meeting I
quickly share an external slide if I can
share my screen
all slots are taken good point
that's just to convey some good news
that most of you probably already had uh
huge congratulations to Francesca and
Christian uh for newborns and indeed
thanks a lot also for providing uh
likely future working group chairs and
ads and or
minute takers yeah as a fit
congratulations indeed
foreign
right as usual we assume people here
especially contributing to discussions
to have read the documents in the agenda
for today let's try to make good use of
our time
uh within discussion and as it comes in
the next slide not well applies
um please even on-site sign in with the
meet Echo app to be sure you are uh
taking the blue sheet uh the chairs will
keep an eye on the chat and we have two
volunteers for Undertakers uh Bill and
Rickard thank you very much uh anyone
else is more than welcome to
further out
yes and as an official ITF meeting uh
the note will apply so nothing well uh
be familiar with that if you're not it's
not just about uh IPR patterns and so on
it's also in the special about our color
conduct so be nice and professional to
each other
uh yeah a few practicalities if you're
not used to that already it doesn't
really change much from the recent past
for uh online attendees but for people
on site again be sure to sign in uh the
session with the mythical tool and if
you want to
um go to the mic please be sure to First
join the queue and then go to the mic
and then leave the queue as well
uh you may also have to relay a question
uh if it's better for you just type it
on the chat with uh Mike prefixed
uh this is the agenda for today uh we'll
continue this chair slot with the
document status update uh then we have
updates about the href document uh
conditional attributes and a new
document on a potential Target attribute
registry
uh then we enter into a series of
security Works
um group of score uh the profiling
availability establishment for cop
underscore and key update for uh Oscar
meaning Kudos and we conclude with uh
two slots covered by a single
presentation about the DNS of aircraft
document in core and the companion
document about encoding DNS messages
in seabor
uh does anyone have any bashing for this
agenda
heard in Reading none
then we can go on with document status
and we had uh the problem details
document now published as RFC in 9220
that was indeed a big achievement also
done in a pretty much record time and I
believe Carson can provide a little bit
more context also on related work also
happening in httpbs
yeah just a quick
piece of information this draft problem
details actually is a knock off from RFC
7807 which is solving the same problem
for HTTP and Json
so this is the co-op c-bar and energy we
didn't copy it wholesale because it
constrained
systems are a bit different so there
were some changes and
uh we would have loved to use the new
version of 7807
but that is only completing now so this
is pretty interesting
so uh well the ipf last call just
finished
uh but I still think if you find
something broken in there they still
want to know that
so if you want to have a look at this uh
this was would be useful
and
um well one interesting thing is that uh
to register these problem types you need
identifiers and the question is where do
these identifiers come from and we have
decided they come from ayenna so if you
want to get an edifier you go to Ayana
and register it there and this should be
sufficiently
low overhead that you can do it and in
this draft
the ideas that uh you essentially can
forge your own
Ayana your eyes as the referenceable
identifiers so we have integers
the original or the updated original
draft now has INR Uris and this is
starting an interesting discussion it's
probably more more an aerial General
thing about the reference it will
identifiers going into
um the Ayana Registries uh but uh yeah
if you're interested in this kind of
thing you may want to have a look
yeah the the one thing that that I'm not
going to detail is that uh this RFC
contains three pieces of Hebrew text
which took us about two months to
actually publish an energy
thank you Carson
yeah moving on we have um when
documenting isg processing uh course C9
version 19 and it's 4980 follow-up there
is plan to have further discussion
already during the um ITF week with
other people involved in coreconf and
and it covered also the later
intermediate plan for uh for December
but uh I believe this document can be
wrapped up pretty soon to take the next
step publication
uh we have a number of documents that
are after The Working of last call
um Library are also part of the corecomm
cluster they were put on ice and waiting
for um
the other two core of documents to be
completed first so these are also
supposed to be
taken up uh soon too
um we also have the Groupon score
document uh in in shipper right up which
is in the agenda for today following an
update app and uh before this cutoff
uh as to other documents we have two
currently in working request call uh
conditional attributes that got updated
we have in today's agenda and group on
this that is waiting for a second wave
of comments or confirmation to come uh
following the first one uh we have also
adopted DNS over cop after summer it's
also in the agenda for today and there's
a document group comproxy appending a
working group adoption call
and a number of other individual
documents were also resubmitted before
the cutoff uh not in the agenda for
today uh please have a look at those
provide comments on the list and we had
also a brand new uh individual document
that was uh already resubmitted uh
during the academic basically and it's
on today's agenda proposing you a new
registry for Target attributes
yeah so we can start with the first item
uh as a recommendation of course please
be sure to wear your masks uh possible
exception is up to you is if you are at
the mic actively speaking and presenting
thank you
I'll demonstrate the right way to use
the microphone with a mask hold it very
close and unless you have singers
training you cannot do this with a stand
just so you always have to take them
microphone so uh Sia eyes
the document is called draft IIT iatf
called href because we couldn't decide
on how to call them but they are not
called Cris so Cris are concise
equivalent of Uris
and URI references as we know them from
RFC 39 86 next slide
oh I can look there I'm stupid
um
so the interesting thing is when you
take something that has such a long
history as a UI and try to come up with
a structured representation of that
you essentially have to build a data
model
for what information is in a UI
and that's a bit more complicated than
maybe meets the eye immediately
and there are some dark corners
and we don't really care that much about
those dark corners but we need to cover
them to really make Cris faster citizens
so we started to make sure we can do
co-op and Co-op s now that's easy but
yeah there's some some weird stuff and
there are some features in particular
the percent encoding mechanism
that really is uh at three levels at the
same time lexical syntax and semantics
so uh Cris are the standard
structure are intended as a standard
structure for past UI so you don't need
a UI browser
anymore and of course every one of us
has written a URI parser that was about
20 correct
and uh yeah this is supposed to be done
for you before the CRI hits your
constraint device and of course the
other
attempt is to be concise uh use less
bytes than a URI in many cases next
slide
um so on this conciseness one
contribution to the Consultants is to
have uh integer representation for
frequently used scheme IDs for instance
HTTP https web and so on
and uh it's easy to do that for for the
maybe 10 or so we actually use a lot in
in the core environment
but of course you want to do this right
to make Cris as universal
um as possible and well we started out
with the I was the idea that we would
simply do the complete set
in the RFC and not provide extensions
so why why don't you want to provide an
extension
the problem is if you provide a text
encoding for something that can also be
encoded as an integer and that integer
comes in later
implementations need to choose whether
they use the text encoding or the
integer encoding and they will of course
look at the uh deployment situation out
there and say only
99.73 actually Implement that yet and I
don't want to lose the the other 0.37 so
I'm going to use the text encoding
so essentially adding something to a
registry after the fact
will have no effect in in many uh
environments
um so that that's a problem with just
saying oh we drop in a registry here and
and
that provides the extensibility we need
next slide
so the idea is
that we limit
or restrict the point in time when these
registrations can happen to a
the initial prefill of the registry that
happens when we publish this this drop
and B to the point in time when a new
URL scheme that we we couldn't know
about
at the time the
draft was was published as an RC
um when a new UI scheme is registered
so that's uh
relatively safe I mean the the UI
schemes the new UI scheme is going to be
and use in testing and so on
uh but uh yeah it kind of only gets
official when the URL scheme is
registered and we have early allocation
and so on so that that should happen
early enough
so we have a Wiki where we
try to connect collect data for an
initial preview and actually the dash o1
version of this internet draft
has a significantly expanded
set of of items to
prefill so yeah at some point we will
declare Victory on this Gathering
activity
but really the question is whether this
is the right way to do how do we get
people who register a UI scheme to
actually think about whether they should
be registering a number for Cris as well
I mean it's not not disaster if they
don't would it's just less efficient
so next slide
during the hackathon uh an idea came up
and the reason the idea came up is that
the URI scheme registry
already had a column
added to it
in the past so when when on your eyes
needed to needed an indication on the UI
scheme whether that your ice cream has
um when on your eyes or not a column was
added to the your ice cream register
which is defined in 7595
that provides the information
essentially a Boolean Value Plus a
reference to the RFC in which this is
described
so why don't we just add another column
with this number
so people who want to add something to
the UI registry and look in there and
and want to emulate match the existing
entries
they get kind of uh
uh they they get LED nudged to actually
register a number if that is Meaningful
I mean registering a number too many is
using up our space but we we are talking
about 100 permanent
UI scheme registrations at this point in
time so before we even
leave the first bite a lot of additional
registrations will have to be done so we
don't have a problem with that
so that's really something that we as a
working group
try to prevent
uh impinging on somebody else's space
and meddling with that we don't do that
uh but in this case it may be worth it
and it's they're pretty innocuous thing
so that that's what we are currently
thinking about and I would like love to
get
uh some feedback for that there's a
comment in the chat from Francesca or
add the note to the Ayana registry and
make sure Ayana asks the question with a
pointer to the new register yes
but yeah I mean why have two tables when
the information can go into one so that
that's the database person and we're
speaking
um yeah but we have to discuss what what
what's the best way to do this
but the important thing is that the the
registry the Ayana page for the registry
contains the information that there is
the opportunity to get a number
uh with the registration of the scheme
Market
so uh yeah but please look at the Wiki
page
that was mentioned on the previous slide
and to see whether your favorite iot
uh UI scheme actually is discovered
so that that's the big one well it's not
big but the largest one next slide and
we have a few more issues
uh open that essentially all have a
resolution already in the GitHub issue
discussion but the resolution needs to
be
written up we plan to have this done
before this IDF but it didn't
uh happen so uh the the ideas
that we will do this now and use the
next
uh core interim on November 23rd uh to
finish this up
and of course they're pretty important
issue here is uh having test vectors
so how do people know that their CRI
implementation is
um
approximately correct and uh of course
we don't want to fill this draft with
with uh fill the specification with test
vectors but where test vectors actually
are
illustrating the way Cris work we want
them in an appendix
so we will uh
make one more round on the test vectors
and then select a few to add to the
appendix next slide
so uh yeah the idea is to work a little
bit more on it to the next interim
to decide the remaining issues
we submit a dash 12.
do working plus call and profit
any comments on that
nothing on General
good there's comments for you in the
chat that are not requesting to be
relayed right now and you can read later
the comment said
yes
there are comments for you in the chat
not urgent okay yeah
great
so Bill I think your next
thank you Carson
control myself
okay I'm left-handed so I'm going to
hold the mic the other way
hopefully this works
hello everybody so uh this is the
presentation for
um a working group document conditional
attributes for uh constrained restful
environments so it's a pretty much of a
mouthful but anyway it's conditional
observed pretty much now
um there's not very many slides here the
if you can move it to the next page so
the current status has been that the
document has been in working group last
call for a while
uh we received one review Thanks Marco
for it uh if you're interested in the
review you can click on the URL and then
you'd see how extensive it was
uh
myself is the editor I I opened up uh
issues for every uh every little part
that uh Marco Marco remarked upon so in
total we had about 20 issues that were
open on GitHub
um 19th are closed one is still open
next slide
so the full the full list of the working
group uh last call review comments are
at that URL you can see them all
uh like I said 20 issues 19 Clause wants
to open
um the majority of these issues were
editorial in nature so it wasn't very
difficult to to correct them
um one close issue was just uh
referring to RFC 7252 and RFC 7641 for
the focal weapon and observe to be
normative references and instead of
informative
and um then one other closed issue was
just about a clarification uh to avoid
the um draft talking about uh value
changes and and transmitting values and
instead considering state state
representations and state changes
so so that was done
um there's one open issue still left it
requires a minor code review I hope that
can be done by this week
so that should be closed very soon as
well
uh next slide so um that's it basically
we want to complete the remaining issue
um
more reviews are always welcome we've
only got one so far we had some some
others before before we went to a
working group last call but obviously uh
more reviews are always welcome
now a question that came up was uh when
I was discussing uh uh a little bit more
about um getting more review as was
whether we should request an early
review from the iot directorate so I'll
leave that to the working group to
decide in the working group chess
if that's a good idea or not
and that's the only thing I have
um the next slide would say thank you
but um it might be premature yet if any
questions
would you like to take them
yeah thanks Bill I heard of it
personally volunteering to review uh
already and then I think it's a good
idea anyway to request an early review
to the IIT directorate
but I think we should
go ahead
thank you
yes can you hear me
uh yes we can hear you
okay yes uh that would be nice to have
it at the iot directorate so you
basically can click into the button
review request and then we take it
no problem with that I I can't review it
as well thank you yeah thank you thanks
okay any other comments anyone
so if not I think we move on to the next
right presentation thanks a lot thanks
oh it's costing again
well this is a really short one
uh
12.
um we invented this link format thing
with which became RFC 66 90.
and this link format has so-called
Target attributes
and uh yeah now this is coming up again
so about 10 years in the making this
draft it's already a dash or one because
yeah again it has an initial initial
set of registrations and then of course
is growing all the time next slide
so the the link from a Target attributes
are really meant
to to tell you with a link that may be
in the resource directory or in the way
known call
information
what kind of Link
this is well that's what the relation
says but also what you can expect to
find at the destination of the link and
what that's why these things are called
Target attributes
so uh we don't we didn't invent this
but took this from the web linking RFC
uh 59.88
and that has things like media type
so for instance for a link you you can
get a hint what you're likely to find
what kind of media type you are likely
to find at the other end so you can
decide not to use the link if you don't
support the media type
and for us in particular the the two
target attributes RT and if
uh were very important and that's why we
put Registries for the values of RT and
if into 6690.
but we didn't put in a registry for the
Target attributes because 5988 said this
specification does not attempt to
coordinate the names of the target
attributes but provides a number of
common Target attributes like media type
for the link HTTP header which which we
just copied
so we did not put a registry in 66.90
next slide
so uh 5988 is is 10 years old and uh or
a bit more than 10 years old and of
course has seen a revision
and that revision is 82 ath actually now
says
um those creating and maintaining
serializations of web linking and being
format obviously as a serialization
of web linking should
coordinate their target attributes to
avoid conflicts in semantics Authentics
and may Define their own Registries
because we don't really have a very good
way of doing coordination except in a
registry that this is kind of an obvious
uh thing to do now
so uh yeah this we should have done this
right at the time of 8288 came out for
some reason this didn't happen but we
already had a couple of close calls
for people registering uh attributes or
not registering using attributes
describing attributes in an RFC or other
document that had the same name and we
we want to make this less likely so
let's do this now
um so the idea is to add a new
sub-registry for Target attributes in
the core parameters registry
so in in the INR document you always
have a web page
which is the registry and then in this
web page you have several Registries
which are then called sub Registries the
terminology is totally confusing
um but anyway so the
policy for this sub-registry
would be expert review
so the isg will select an expert that
actually looks at each registration
request
and maybe helps this request become
better by
giving some information and at some
point it gets accepted
and we have some instructions to
designated experts and I think these
need to eat a little bit more work
um so I the idea was
uh well if somebody
uh registered
type or something
um you would look whether this was
something that is very specific to one
ecosystem one corner
of an ecosystem or whether it's widely
used so this is the frugal
thing
and the other thing is what RFC 8126
does not have
is specification desired they have a
specification required
uh policy which says hey you have to put
a specification in there and they have
expert review which doesn't say anything
about that and this is kind of in the
middle so we we really expect people to
do a specification unless uh there are
good arguments not to do that
and there is uh somebody in the queue
let's go you want to go now or
yeah I'm almost done
um yeah the the other instruction
is to use
a lowercase letter followed by lowercase
letters digits and minus signs
um because they
they the the ancestry of these web
linking things
really are email headers which were
defined in the late 1970s
they are case insensitive of course no
no same person would design something be
in case insensitive at this point but
because of this this
45-year ancestry
um they are
they need to be case insensitive and we
are just saying you always register the
lower case form so people get nudged to
using that and reducing for fees
next slide
so this is the prefill
um as you can see this has been pretty
Lively
um the href anchor Rel and Rev
are essentially things that are not
useful as Target attribute names because
they have a different meaning in web
linking a traveling media and title
Rd finders Target attributes by 808 so
they they are also gone
rtif size
are in the link format document content
format is in the co-op document Ops is
in the observed document JCT
um
JCP http
HTT
um it's in the
HTTP mapping document
um Oscar has a Target attribute
okay that's the the published out of
season obviously we put the pre-fill in
in this document because the rfcs cannot
be better actively changed to do the
registration
and then we have several drafts that are
in flight
and this has two examples
for for drafts one is IDF call Oscar ad
hoc which has half a dozen
of Target attributes
and uh yeah let's see which of the two
draft is published first and that
actually uh
decides where the registration will be
made
and uh draft you look it's called
Discovery has another set of
Target issues pretty many actually
and uh yeah they they since that
document is not in a really in a race to
completion with
um this uh
specification they probably will be
registered there because the target
attributes vertices should be in place
by the time
uh that happens so we have to manage
this preview but it's really historical
work to make sure we have all of them
and again
if you have a Target attribute you know
that
something in the IGA for some other
industry organization ocf Oma users we
probably would like to know to do this
briefly
next slide and we should replace the
underscores with dashes
oh yes also in the referred document yes
yeah we always have that problem but
it's really really funny so a b and F
for instance doesn't allow underscores
in identifiers and each time you're
reviewing someone who's coming in
someone
it's ABN F who's coming in you they use
underscores and the identifiers because
they're programming languages
forced them to do that but a b and F was
written by people who were programming
in list where minus signs are normally
identified as anyway uh next slide I
have nine seconds let's ask on the Queue
and those are Christian so I don't want
they want they want to jump in now okay
and no need to rush in general because
we are minus 10 minutes okay very good
yeah so first of all I support this
draft and adoption because it's I think
we have hit hit this issue a couple of
times in the past
so that that sounds good to have this uh
also pre-filled
and yeah make it also available to other
standards bodies that want to submit
their uh
elements with maybe a pointer to their
specifications
one thing I was just looking at you
mentioned expert review and
I did see that we have currently the
process of expert reviewing someone
sends a request I recall the last
request was in August and there was no
reply yet to it so it's not particular
quick process as far as I can see maybe
we did do something but at least it was
not visible on the core parameters
mailing list yeah do you remember what
that request was
yeah it was I think for one of the
standards organizations like something
like old ocf or
well I just answer the global platforms
one which maybe that one but
okay okay well it was not I just checked
it was not in the email archive yet uh
yeah maybe it's not not answered to the
list yeah that's the problem maybe yeah
so we we don't really have a good way to
get a transparent
sequence of messages between
the registrant
Ayana the experts and the working group
that actually may be interested in this
subject and right now we usually have
bilateral messages and that doesn't make
sense
but it's currently the way things are
being done and I think we need to to at
some point need to change this yeah
because our request comes in but but you
can't see if it was granted or not or if
anyone responded for example yes so for
instance we we might instruct
Ayana to actually send registration
requests to the core parameters list
and and yeah ask people to actually see
that list on on all communities
okay but it's something to consider
as an improvement then I think and and a
couple of things you mentioned like the
don't use underscores but but hyphens
and only lowercase I think that's also
excellent idea for this uh
yep thanks
Christian
uh does this document shoot this
document or did you plan to um
address the topic of whether the
semantics of that attribute pertain to
the link itself or to the link Target
because all the examples that I've seen
here except for title as defined in a288
um are about the target independently of
the link whereas other attributes could
be about the target when used through
that link or even the link itself as it
was in some iterations of dining link
will this document make any statement to
that or we'll just talk about the
formalities of registering and then
leave this semantics as they are
well that's a really good question I
don't think we actually want to change
82 88 or
um
go ahead
um it wouldn't do anything about 8288 it
would just be about
um which attributes can be registered
but
yeah but but 8288 doesn't give you a way
to
add attributes that are not targeted
attributes if I remember correctly no
the terminology is a bit confusing um
they are called Target attributes but
they describe a property of quote the
linked the link or its Target
so especially the one example 8288 gives
for title is next chapter which is only
a valid name when following this
particular link and not a property of of
the target your of the target Resource
as a whole
okay but that's just then my my mistake
of putting title in the second line on
the of this slide instead of the first
line
but are people supposed to put in more
information that really is about the
link and not the target
I I don't I didn't read 8288 that way
and that's maybe worth examining but the
type the title is an example the title
is an example of that and the authors
generally and I've I've made back and
forth with uh with them
um assume that it could also be just
um only about this particular way of
accessing that resource or possibly even
the uh the the link on its own
okay I think that that's really
interesting uh I I hope this doesn't
sort of fall into getting this document
out quickly because I think that that's
a pretty fundamental
question about web linking that we would
have to discuss with the HTTP people as
well
because we we just have copied that part
and simplify that a little bit
and and either way just one more comment
on the document registered for that
under the registry as a whole
um Coral will very much want to add a
column there that says and by the way
the mapping is defined like this and
that independently of what the answer to
my first question is it's just if the
answer to the first question is yeah it
could be any of those
um that second column will be a lot more
complex
yeah maybe we should get used to the
idea of adding adding columns and
Registries and in a later document
um so that because the we probably know
what how the race between the target
attribute registry and coral is going to
go and
so we can't really have a column in
there for a document that that isn't
done yet
uh
yeah but let's discuss this
good
yeah
last slide
so uh this is still an individual draft
we have discussed it
I don't know how often uh
in the last 10 years but somebody had to
sit down and actually write the thing
that has now happened and the next step
would be to
make this a working group document
I think it's pretty clear that this is
within our Charter because it's
essentially just to maintenance
uh housekeeping activity
but of course it's always nice to get
some confirmation from from the 80s
about that
and then do some working group work like
answer questions
uh do a working glass call and finally
profit
thank you
okay great
yeah I'd be happy to open for an option
called sonish
is there any objection
I think we can start an adoption call
this week great
thank you
yes
thanks yeah very well okay hi everyone
this is Marco uh this is an update on
the group Oscar document uh next slide
please
yeah uh before the cutoff we submitted
uh version 16 uh essentially merging
um a single Consolidated PR uh 98 and
covering fundamentally
um four things uh number one is the
major one and it was about
um improving the handling of some
particular responses that can happen
during the group of score communication
that we noticed was not completely
handled uh number two was uh also a
little trick to do to downgrade the must
to should to not lock down uh possible
cases well three and four uh were well
extended editorials if you want
improving the the presentation of the
security properties of group of score to
be more aligned with those of Oscar and
the way those are presented and
improving the presentation of the um the
properties of the features that the
pairwise mode has uh and inherits
actually from the group mode we've had
another discussion about this PR with a
crystals document Shepard that
encouraged us to not wait for his
Shepherd review and write up before
um going on um with this PR and this
merging uh still of course will
appreciate follow the comments from him
and others
and he actually realized that especially
point one had a more General
applicability in the context of
non-traditional responses for which
um an issue on the corresponding GitHub
wrapper was also opened uh Eric also
before emerging very carefully reviewed
that VR we're very thankful uh for that
So eventually we merged that and I'm
mostly going to go through
um well basically the content of the pr
that was merged in version 16 and and
for the end I have
um a little open point that came up uh
post cut off which is also related to
the Target attribute registry discussed
in the previous presentation uh by
carsten
uh so next slide please
yeah and I actually start with with easy
one uh number two we downgraded um a
must to shoot uh about the use of the
group mode for protecting a group
request intended to multiple recipients
uh we actually had uh already an
exception uh under our nose uh for a
while there may be probably more that
we're not even imagining now but that
was enough anyway to to switch
um to a should
uh next slide please
uh right on the main thing uh handling
of uh multiple responses uh I need to
bring up some some context here why uh
we had to to make some fix uh this is
text quoted from the group comb base uh
document and this text has been around
for a couple of years now after changes
in this direction that were uh discussed
agreed and even confirmed later on at
ITF 110 lastly and since then the text
never changed
um basically a cop client sending a
group request to multiple recipients
because of that preserves the token
beyond the reception of a first response
and taking advantage of that in
principle a same server can send back
multiple responses uh not necessarily uh
as of certifications and the idea was to
leave the final decision about what to
do in that situation to the application
at the client and not the stock at the
client since the application of the
client can have more context to take a
better decision for that particular
application like considering only the
very last response from that server or
produce some kind of aggregation of
those whatever so this is the context uh
we we had and we consistently built on
um in group or score
um next slide please
yeah and considering that context well
we had a problem uh most was okay
already and basically the handling of a
single response uh to a center request
or multiple responses if they were
observed notifications
the problem was if a same server sent
multiple
non-modification responses to the same
group request and then there were two
issues uh due to under specification on
the server side that was uh no text
mandating the server to include its own
sender sequence number as partial ID in
the responses following the first one so
that of course opened for 80 nouns reuse
and on the client side on the other end
there was nothing really mandating the
client to do any form of
um response uh ordering enforcement or
replay check and anyway there were no
means to do that because there was not
necessarily a partial ID
um in those responses
so those were the issues
next slide please
yeah we think we fixed that uh basically
relying on the same rational and
approach used for handling exactly the
same kind of problems uh for Observer
notifications only separately because we
still want observe to be a separate
feature optional to support that may not
be around or used only by some servers
in the group and not all of them so
separately we Define the handling of
non-modification responses to group
requests again using the same rational
useful Observer notification
we had to introduce a new uh term
already in the terminology section we
called it non-notification group
exchange I stress the word exchange
because it's intended to be an
environment like an observation is so
something tied to uh the group request
that the client send and the
non-notification responses uh that the
server sent to that group request in
such a context uh we'll have well on the
server side including the sender
sequence number is partially V in the
responses with the possible let's say
exception of the first one which is good
and on the client side the client will
expect responses to comply with that
and just like a client that sends
specifically an observed request
considers the partial idea of
notifications as a notification number
well the client will consider the
partial review of non-notification
responses as a response number uh
trivially and based on that we'll
perform Ripley checks and ordering of
the responses like it happens for
notifications and like it happens for
notifications at most one response from
the same server is allowed to not have
the partial EV and that has to be
considered the oldest one
um next slide please
and those are the main points related to
the actual uh message processing uh
there's a number of side things that as
a side effect had to be said but they
are exactly like for the case of
notification so
um if a client and server would like to
have this kind of exchange continuing
Beyond a group of King they have to
preserve the caddy context meaning the
group ID
originally used for the original request
and use it for the external AED to bind
all responses across for Kings to the
same request just like we do for observe
and similarly if they want to have this
exchange surviving beyond the change of
clients and their ID they need to store
a use for the future external idea of
responses the original kid meaning the
original Center ID of the client that
was used uh for the group request in
question
I managed on the extended editorial uh
revisions in the presentation of the
security properties of Grupo score those
were of course also extended in order to
capture the properties that we now have
in addition to version 15 in order to
cover also this additional uh new
handling
I think this is the last leg on this
particular topic so if there is any
comment or question on this Christian
oh yeah I didn't quite get why
notifications would need separate
handling from uh other requests with
multiple responses so at least in in the
correspondence document which I'm
working on
um they could be unified so why can't
they be unified here
uh with the with the multiple responses
just being a generalization of
notifications people
the idea was to keep observices separate
optional service to support like it has
been so far in Oscar already and then in
group of score uh so we had to start
this from scratch it probably could have
taken that path now it means a bigger
structure and I'm afraid but but this
but this um this feature is not
something that is ever negotiated or or
kind of being technically exchanged it's
just a matter of phrasing right so
you're keeping the phrasing of the
document so that people can follow the
one line of phrasing
for for the notifications under
different line of phrasing for
everything else but then it effectively
duplicates text doesn't it
partly uh yes it uses a slightly
different terminology to emphasize what
is about non-notification responses
so it does draw a line uh indeed and
bottom line to stress that observe is a
separate service optional to support so
one may not even read anything about
observing if not interested in it
but but they could but they would still
do effectively the same implementation
just by doing the different part and not
know that the yes I'll have to read the
document again but if if it is how I now
imagine it is I don't think that's a
good idea
because okay the document is not set in
stone yet and I think it would be better
to unify it now even if it's more
editorial work than than leave it up to
the readers to do the unification
mentally
okay
um do you have in mind the proposal
request
yeah
I'll I'll have a look at it
much appreciated things
so yeah I was just wondering uh you
mentioned the possibility that the
server basically sends multiple
responses in this case I think in in
group comb this we have written that
that can happen because of uh somewhat
of a faulty server implementation or
something or medicine bug or a malicious
server that tries to uh yeah
do something to disrupt whatever is
ongoing
but but are you considering that the
server could just uh yeah send two
responses basically to request just
because she thinks oh I have some yeah
updates
to send why why not do that is that a
that's another case one thing we
mentioned already in group of English
was the case of a client resending the
same request with the same token and
same message ID yeah and the server not
supporting messages duplication but
you've just mentioned yet another case
yeah yeah I think the intention was not
not to support necessarily that uh okay
said that the server start sending
multiple responses it's more like saying
uh okay it could happen for example due
to uh
yeah this this uh datagram getting
duplicated so the server could just
send back two responses but maybe it's
different if you consider the the score
security
on top of that I mean I don't know the
details of that but
yeah it seems to me that should not be a
case that the server would willfully uh
send multiple responses because it's
supposed to send only one right
says depends on the application and the
application on the client will figure
out
yeah that's right the client will figure
it out but the server isn't supposed to
do it that's the also the message I
think or what we try to say there in the
draft because it's not not promoting the
server to do that
it's just saying that the client should
be prepared to
handle these kind of cases right so so
it the clients could could also say I'm
just throwing away
any second or third or following
response with the same token so and
that's the application again yeah so the
client must still be ready to to to have
this happening and even in the presence
of group of score you may have an
adversal injecting replayed responses
yeah but you could have a client that
implements group or score that already
decides I'm only going to accept the
first
response that comes in and then that
client doesn't want any code for for
example for handling
uh future or future responses with the
same token so
that that means that maybe part of what
you're proposing is not relevant for
that type of client right
sure
um so it's more like an option that's
how it sounds to me like if if you're a
client that wants to
process multiple responses then yeah
maybe it has to to check certain things
but you don't have to do that as a
client right group of scholarship
working one way
let's say
in a more secure way regardless of what
tolerance the application will have
so if the application had not tolerance
well okay then group of square can be
aligned accordingly but if the
application is tolerance group of scores
should enforce the best security
possible meaning
being ready to to have replaced coming
and and being able to detect them to
stop them
for example
yeah okay at least deal with duplicates
I agree with that but I don't know if it
should be
kind of designed for having a server
that that necessarily decides to send an
updated response later on because hey
they're still timing and can send an
update that seems to be going a bit out
of the co-op specification that they
have
buttercream yeah
I'll think about that thanks thank you
and and Christian back also to your
comment probably we are already on the
site on the right track for that on the
server side because it is phrased and
Nigeria in a general way to say uh must
include a partial V in any response
following the first one
regardless of being a notification or
not so probably that's generally enough
the big thing is on the client side then
Christian you want to join the queue and
mentioned what you're writing on the
chat
briefly
um I can just repeat it quite quick
quite briefly yes I agree that
um
if a client doesn't solicit multiple
responses then it can just take a simple
processing
um with
for one response and that's either valid
or not but there can be multiple ways in
which a client would solicit multiple
responses observe being one
um group proxy might be another and
whatever that is if it solicits then
then it there is a way of processing
them so that's that's opposed to to the
earlier discussion and to esco's
question
yeah and this problem would come back
again the moment you consider proxy
supporting groups because they will send
back multiple responses to the same
request
to the client
okay so we would expect some more
detailed input from you Christian
um I'll bring that in as part of my room
yes
thanks a lot
okay
um next slide please
and it's a final one in fact
um yeah about Target attributes uh when
working on that PR we you know that um
as cars I mentioned before the Oscar RFC
defines an Ask Target attribute to to
signal that resource is accessible
um using those score and should be
accessed using those score of course it
didn't mention
um group of score that's something that
likes like missing so we would propose
to Define in a group of score document a
new similar Target attribute G osk to
indicate that the resource is accessible
using Oscar and or Grupo score uh so
very similar of course we need to to be
supportive of all the implementations
that may retrieve a link to such a
resource but they don't support a
specifically group of score and the
target geosc
so we could think of these uh rules of
use
so that if the link specifies geosc uh
it must specify also ask and well an all
device not understanding group of square
geosc would ignore geosc because it
doesn't understand it after all and it's
not interested in Google score
but if it does understand group of score
ngos it will focus on it and ignore ask
because it's practically overshadowed by
the statement
um from from geosc
any comment or objection on defining a
Target attribute like this this way
and it can be also one more addition
um for the pre-filling of the registry
in Carson's draft
okay and the next slide should be really
the uh the wrap up we can Surah submit
of version 17 anyway adding the new
um Target attribute
and then we wait for more uh input and
review uh from Christians Christian for
the shepherding
that's it
thank you indeed
yeah
I changed because I think he's going to
be
okay
yes so I will be presenting this draft
profiling adult for Coop and oscore
and um
yep slide changing works so yes that's a
recap
um what is this about well we have a dog
which is a lightweight authenticated key
exchange being developed in the lake
working group
and its main use is basically
establishing an Oscar security context
um however normally when you run edoc it
will take you two round trips and before
you can start using oscore so what this
document proposes and the main
contribution of this document is an
optimization to this procedure where
when you send your ad book message 3
you actually combine that with an also
protected application request
and you can do that because at that
point you already have a valid.com
context to use
um there are other supports also in this
document specifying um
some other details like oscar-specific
processing of messages
um consistent extension of the educ
application profile you know web linking
and some performance considerations on
the Block wise
and when what updates have been done
since itf14 when version zero five has
been submitted and there will be no big
changes to the fundamental mechanics of
this optimized workflow
and we did make some modifications Diana
considerations regarding
um shortening the text and only like
narrowing it down to option number 21
previously we consider other numbers too
we have renewed the order registration
for option number 21 which will now
expire the 8th of November 2023
and as far as these performance
considerations on blockwise I mentioned
basically restructured it a bit so we
moved some of that down to an appendix
in appendix a
um it's now still the same content as
used to be in section six
and to kind of summarize our conclusions
from that is basically that if you have
to use block wise specifically because
you're using this optimized workflow
meaning this combined request becomes so
big you have to use clockwise
then this optimization has no
performance benefit and you might as
well use the original normal edoc
workflow because it's less complex and
um since the optimization doesn't give
you any benefit in that case just use
the normal Network
we also expanded them the security
considerations
so um basically there are some
considerations now about like access
control because
you have to consider that you may have
access control also involved and the
fact that is like just because you
completed with another pair that doesn't
mean you'll get any specific
resource access and that still has to
rely on the normal Access Control
procedures that you're using
um
otherwise
we have some information now about
um that like let's say you have access
control information
um how and what information may need to
be provided before the end of execution
um yeah basically no considerations on
this watch about access control
um now what happened after the cutoff
well we actually defined
um in section six some Target attributes
for added resources and basically so now
these attributes can be registered in
this upcoming I am a registry and that's
defined in this new
draft by custom
and the thing that was mentioned a
little bit but the proposal here is that
in these new drafts from Carson we
pre-filled the new registry with the
target attributes from this document
but we still ask for registration also
in this actual document and then
basically it's like a race between the
two documents which get there first and
the one that gets there first gets to
keep the text the other one the text is
removed okay
yeah sorry that was opposite yeah the
one that the one that yeah
um
anyway so
well regardless we may want to also
revise the names of the attributes like
starting with some kind of prefix that
shows that these are specifically
related to our document
and yeah and of course any thoughts or
objections or comments on this plan is
very welcome
and yeah I go to the next one so we had
a proposal
from David Navarro so this is also being
tracked in a pull request at um in the
GitHub repository
and basically he noted that in one of
the figures we have we do not include a
response to the edit message tree
and then here the answer yesterday okay
why don't you add that documents before
in that figure just to make it clear
that the message before can in fact be
used but basically the way the reason we
don't have another message further
currently is that uh in the text of that
doc draft it says that
um if add that message was used or if
there's an error then edit message for
then the response will be sent from the
server
um as a as a response to message D but
basically like this that you may
actually it's not mandatory to have
another message for and you can in fact
omit that okay
um so well anyway the proposal is we
merge this PR and we add a note to say
that okay edit message 4 is best and in
this example but in general it is
optional and we basically take the same
text as he said in the draft itself
under equivalent figure
and you see the figure there on the
right hand side
and the red part is traditionally we're
planning them
yeah just to summarize uh Next Step so
the document is quite stable it's
aligned also with the latest static
version which is version 17. and we have
agreed to keep in sync and keep
discussions uh and depending on the
state of the actual ad book document
um just include a working group let's go
of that which has actually concluded now
on the 4th of November
and yeah our proposal basically would be
at this point to start the working
world-classical for this document also
thank you
yeah and that was the last slide so of
course any
yeah comments your feedback are well
welcome or reviews and other
input
if not I guess I will proceed to the
next presentation
foreign
and this is already a key update for all
score and Kudos and we're now up to a
draft version number three
and yeah again just to recap I mean
basically this document has um multiple
subsections
um one of the main sections and where
the document gets its title is the Kudos
procedure which is a key update
procedure for all score and the whole
goal of that of that is to renew your
master secret and master salt and you
also wish derive when you send the
recipient keys because you change the
methods you get master result that is
the end result so you have a fresh set
of keys to continue communication with
and you may want to repeat for a variety
of reasons
um benefits is that you do not change
your ID context which is like an
internal identifier of telescope context
and you also achieve perfect forward
secrecy with this procedure it's Loosely
inspired by the appendix B2 procedure
that also defines for performing the
update but with a number of
um benefits over that one the other main
part is this thought about aad key usage
limits for all score because it was
discovered and is also defined in other
documents like the c4d draft you see on
the bottom right that if you have
excessive usage of the same key
that may enable breaking some security
properties of aad algorithms so what we
want to do in this document is to Define
appropriate limits when using all score
and the limits are really tied to what
particular algorithm you're using
we also want to Define concrete
processing steps for messages like what
counters and keys should you use
um and what you do when you reach the
limits and the final part is basically a
section about updating Osco and sending
recipient IDs
yep next slide so this is normal of the
keying procedure it's pretty basic it's
a metrics exchange to exchange nonsense
N1 and N2
and these are placed in a new field in
those called Co-op option then we feed
this into this update CTX function that
builds a new score security context for
the players
and and we also see a picture there the
way we extend the Oscar option with new
fields to hold the nuns and the X byte
and the X byte holds the length of the
actual nouns and some flag bits
yeah and to go into a bit more detail on
these flag bits and updates we did so we
updated the registrations regarding this
bit 15
as before in the case this is a Kudos
message and you have the presence of the
nuns and the X byte we also defined now
that bit 0 instead of it one should
Define uh that you have a second flag
byte in those core option
and it say I really didn't have any
concrete use case otherwise so we took
itself for the extension
and this is also a point where Kudos
will be updating the score FC
we also changed the status of bit one
from a server to unassigned and we also
plan to register with 816 Etc as further
extension bits to have a consistent
pattern for extension and this was all
based on previous discussion on the
mailing list and other meetings
um we simplify the method for updating
context we used to have two internal
code paths one relying on the Adobe
update one relying on an extract and
expand and we discussed this at the
Korean stream and we said okay some
feedback was was why don't you just have
met.2 based on the extract and expand
because there's no additional benefits
from that docky update so we'll simplify
this now so we no longer have two
separate code paths we only go for the
um extra expand method basically you see
in the green box there that's a new
style simplifies implementations
simplifies for building external values
um they're no need for any fallback
because previously it may have been the
case that the Edo key update was
unavailable because the endoc session
wasn't valid anymore
um so there's no need to signal that or
kind of negotiate on that you don't even
have to support that dog or be worried
or think about if the original
keys were established using a doc
so this was a simplification without
them
loss of security properties here we also
updated the update CTX function to not
only rely on an hkdf and previously we
specifically defined it to use the hqdf
expand now we analyzed that to say that
it should use Kudos expand which is like
an interface to the key derivation
function used by all score and this
ensures flexibility and is also future
proof
I mean typically our scores today we'll
use an hdf algorithm in such case Kudos
expand is simply maps to hkdf expand as
you see in them
in the text there taken from the draft
however a potential future update to
Oscar May Define other kdfs in such case
that update can also defined on a
mapping between Kudos expand and this
new kdf
so we are future proof in that sense
yeah another part that we did was the
find ways that you can use end hook to
actually signal Kudos support
so let's say that you actually do
support and you have to be implemented
between the pairs then when the pairs
run a block they can use this EAD which
is basically optional data that can be
exchanged during a network execution and
we're defined EAD items for pairs to
signal each other whether they support
Kudos or not and in which mode
so basically register an ID label
and four possible values of this you can
see that on the right hand side on the
table what these values are so basically
it can be asked meaning you want to ask
the other pair if it supports kudos it's
none which indicates that me as
descending pin doesn't support kulis at
all it's full meaning me as the sending
pair supports Kudos both in the um
forward secrecy mode and the Note 4
secrets mode or let's call it the
stateless and stateful modes
and you can also indicate Port which
means you only support Kudos in the nor
forward secrecy mode
um
and um yeah I see Jordan is in the queue
there also
but you can also see on the left hand
side there's a small example basically
um when you indicate ask from the
initiator well in edit message too they
responder with an indicate full meaning
I fully support Kudos and that's saying
fully message to you also is an
indication to the initiator to indicate
what it supports so it will in turn
respond with full so after he said the
execution both pairs know that each
other supports Kudos in both fs and no
FS modes
foreign
yeah so my question was do we need to
Signal this at all or I mean it will be
understood by each party that we are if
one is proposing to run Kudos or not
it would I mean it's I would say that
like even if you didn't have this
signaling you could always do like a
trial and error approach so you try to
run Kudos with other player and see if
it works
um so you would eventually learn you
could try and see if it fails or you
could try in the fs mode and then the
other pyramid indicate no I don't
support FS mode please retry in the no
FS mode so it's not something that Kudos
fundamentally relies on this
functionality it's like an extra nice
feature that you may have this um
pre-established pin knowledge after
running a doc so you don't have to go
for the trial and error approach but
it's not a critical and coolest doesn't
rely on this basically
okay I think
um there's nice features and it's also
adding complexity so it's a trade-off
there
yeah I think that's a text for input
yeah I mean definitely if this can be um
then there's a trade-off like you said
is it worth the add complexity I mean
this is again it's if you use if you
have Network supported and even if you
have support with red doc this is not
um mandatory that you use
um
but yeah thank you for them
for input
and further updates yeah we now forbid
sending Kudos messages during a curious
execution
um we also indicate clearly that in the
client initiated version of Kudos and
the server must include a partial AV in
its Kudos response message and I'll come
back to that later but basically this
prevents are using the same pair of a
denouncing key in certain situations
and there's a little open point on how
to analyze this first score overall
and we clarified we have this concept of
a capable and non-capable device so a
capable device is more like a
non-constrained device yeah capabilism
non-constraining device and non-capable
it's a constrained device and we're not
defined clearly what mode of Kudos they
must support So if you're capable device
you must support forward secrecy mode
and you should support the no FS mode
but yeah you can see in the draft these
these concepts are basically related to
if the device can write to persistent
memory or not
we also a structure the section about
reasons for a keying and improved some
portrait regarding the retention
policies of old contexts
now I come to this point about partial
living responses
so basically if you look on the figure
to the right there and the blue arrow
you see that in that response one
there's a partial ABCO and we'll
conclude that the server must in fact
include that partial living in response
one and the otherwise it's not secure
behavior and and why do you need to do
this well it's because you don't want to
reuse the same adenons and key pair so
if you look at the table you see that
these are the request one and response
one and request two request two from the
client and server point of view and you
see that okay let's say the user nouns
placeholder value a it just stands for a
particular nouns but the point here is
that request 1 and response one
basically the client will use a certain
amounts and the typical behavior is that
the server mirrors and reuses the nouns
from the request so let's say it does
that then following that the client
sends a request 2 using the same nouns
um and you may I mean the thing is that
like the cloud from the client's point
of view the client switches context from
Context one to context new right so from
the client's point of view it's sending
two messages with the same numbers but
it has different key right so it's
completely fine however on the server
side server will send response 1 with
CTX new and the mirrored nouns from the
client and it will also send response to
with C takes new and the nearest nodes
from the client
and okay you may say why is the most the
same because the ctx1 has become CTX new
for the client and then you reset your
partial ID and so fundamentally
announced would become the same so
essentially to avoid this red line we
will see that the same key and the same
nonce is used you need the server in
response one to actually include a
partial ID
and now okay the way we fix this now is
just an adult fix for Kudos but we want
to define a more generalized fix
um to say that well this this can also
be a general fixed first score itself
because anytime you transition between
contexts like this you will want to
include your partial area so we have a
proposal for text there saying that um
if an OS corresponds is protected with a
different security context then the
corresponding response the corresponding
request was unprotected with the server
must include its sequence numbers
partial AV
as a Christian in the queue also and an
exception is appendix B2 because that is
constructed in a way where it also
avoids this problem yeah Christian
um yeah I think this is a very good
thing to do to just send the partial ID
again
yeah I think yeah
yeah I think it makes sense it's an easy
way to solve this problem but yeah the
problem is really like the the um
you will transition between the between
contexts in the middle of a message
processing right so you unprotect
request one with one context and you
protect the response one with a
different context and you may run into
this problem but including the partial
release and easy fix
and now I come to another question so we
discussed this in multiple earlier
meetings about the future structure of
this document so as I mentioned we have
kind of multiple ports now incense three
parts the Kudos procedure the limits and
then those scores and their ID recipient
ID update section so the question we'd
like to bring up here is um should this
be split out into a separate working
group document meaning the content about
the limits so
we kind of try to summarize the feeling
from the last coin dream where it was
people
um
expressed a strong preference to split
this out
and the name of it there is that the
limits document relies also on the
document in c4d and if we split this out
it can be updated independently based on
what can happen in the cfrd documents
and such
and so we got that impression that for
image poetry was a stronger consensus to
split it out
um
then a similar question comes for the
method for updating this under recipient
ID and this send me recipient ID
procedure it can run either Standalone
or embedded in a cureless execution so
the question is should we also split
this out into a separate working group
document the consensus from the internet
was well more mild preference or people
having no opinion regarding this
we still need a bit to work on this
section on preserving observations
mainly
so our proposal here is to keep the part
about the center and zip into the update
in the current document and when we have
that section more finalized we come back
to this
um but on the limits I would say we have
a
our stance is that you can actually be
split out today
um as a working group document and the
benefit of doing this split is basically
like
well then this document could in the
future be focused only on Kudos instead
of as it is now having kind of three
separate parts
yeah that's quickly the main next steps
we want to address token points that we
discussed
um about this restructuring and also
about the partiality inclusion more
General text on that and yeah we've got
some good feedback from ralpha Marine
Lopez on soft versus hard limits with
kind of references to ipsec and how they
have soft limits there
we want to expand the example about
those score ID updates to provide
textual description of the examples and
yeah any comments or reviews are very
welcome and also feedback on this
question about the future structure of
the document and if we should split out
and let's say the limit spot for now
yeah thank you that was the full
presentation
thanks Richard yeah thank you
well I'm just curious because it didn't
get it fully was the conclusion about
the split thing especially is it about
following the plans suggested in that
slide as is or is there any
you say so
it's a hard split of the limits for now
and we'll see
updates
oh
yeah since you asked for feedback so I I
think it's a good proposal to split out
the limits and keep the
these and the recipient ID options
in the code AS document
yeah I think that makes sense for now
like the limits can
um more and more freedom to update your
Customs coming up also yeah
because when I had this experience just
just last Friday
with the new student group who were
looking at
various ways to achieve a specific
objective
and in the end they looked at the two
documents one RFC and one internet draft
and said one has 70 pages one has 90
Pages let's implement the one with 70
pages
and I I suspect that's not happening
with students only so I think we need to
be a bit careful to
not create documents that have the
appearance
of being complex by by having stuff in
there that you actually don't need to to
read to implement it I think that's a
very good point because if someone comes
to this document only interested in the
limits or all interesting kudos
then they may be misled to think that
this is longer and more complex than it
is just because it has multiple
independent Parts basically so if we
could split out the limits it would make
the document simpler and make the new ad
limits document also simpler definitely
so thanks for the feedback yeah
[Music]
okay next is Martina with one
presentation covering the last two slots
actually
[Music]
uh so yeah
um for my talk yeah I will talk about
DNS of a co-op in the first part and
then about the DNS message format uh
using sibo
um these are two drafts one is the
working group draft for the doc and the
other one is currently a
person on draft
[Music]
um
yeah first of course I spoke to speak
about Dennis over Co-op the motivation
behind that for those who still don't
know
um is that we want to have an iot device
that requests a name and we want to
protect against uh potential
eavesdrivers and a typical
countermeasure there is to encrypt the
name resolution
and oh
and yeah uh with DNS over Co-op we would
have such encryption and additionally we
would also benefit from blockwise
message transfer and uh the shared
research systems system resources of the
co-op application so we can use the same
sockets and buffers and reuse also uh
The Cooperative transmission mechanism
and yeah since the last ITF uh not that
much has happened except for of course
uh the working group adaption but we
added some security considerations on
how ID 0 will should be used in an
encrypted or how the idea in general
should be used when an unencrypted use
um then we replace the layer violation
where we stated something about con
um with a statement of facts that well
if you uh use uh con you have you can
you don't need a re-transmission
mechanism
and we removed the doc server
considerations which were basically
moved to its own draft which a little
bit uh I will discuss a little bit in
the next steps also
uh then there is some open discussion
still on Doc uh we got some feedback
from DNS up
uh thanks for that by the way
um so the first question was basically
why there why it isn't just Doh via
Co-op Gateway
um that the draft should explain that at
least um then we uh use the different
TTL rewriting proposal that is uh
different from the one in Doh that
should also be probably explained a
little bit more in depth depth
was a question if doc lives on a URI
path of course it does and uh if there
is a default path that we can use as a
common practice in Co-op uh so maybe
something that uh some more Co-op Pros
can answer and uh then that is also
something that was brought up by Carson
in the GitHub um that we need some
uh recommendation how to bootstrap doc
with a service B record
um where we probably need to allocate
some almp n ID for Co-Op or the end or
dtls
um are there any comments already on
that maybe
before I proceed
okay then I continue
um
so for the next step
um of course addressing the feedback is
one big step then we still need to pick
an ID for the application DNS message
for Content format uh I guess I will
just propose one and um yeah for the
other draft where that was split out so
basically of that um where this you can
have a look at that but there was
already some comments that it might not
be that much of a
uh edit value so maybe we can just
leave it by the wayside so uh yeah we'll
have to see about that
uh so thank you that was basically the
first talk uh are there any questions or
comments
yes question
uh just a brief comment on the default
path uh while we don't usually do
default paths I would recommend that a
server that is just a DNS server just
place the lookup lookup server resource
at the slash resource it's like saving
at least two bytes compared to every
other message and if it's this piece of
software using doing just that and it
can easily do that there is nothing
special about the slash resource that's
available and why not use that
uh yeah I I think I agree on that so
yeah uh bench watch
hi uh so I think that that is a
perfectly reasonable recommendation but
the the question here is
is it possible to bootstrap a DNS over
co-app connection without explicitly
conveying a path
because if it is necessary to it's
always necessary to pay a path then that
places additional requirements on the
bootstrap mechanism that that is used
so for example in the context of
something like service bindings you need
a service bindings parameter that
conveys the path and that parameter
always has to be present uh you know the
client can't probe for the presence of
uh of a DNS server co-ops nerver on a or
supported for DNS over co-op on a co-op
server because it doesn't know what path
to look at
this is all stuff that has come up with
DNS over https and there is no default
path in DNS over https we have we have
this all working but we've had to plumb
through the path component through all
of the bootstrap channels
uh I guess Carson has an answer for that
yeah I think if we can emulate the HTTP
here then that's fine
um I think it's important to keep in
mind that uh in in the constrained
environment the discovery will not
necessarily run over DNS that will often
be in the resource directory and there
of course we can indicate the path
because that's just part of the link
that the resource directory
provides so uh one possible outcome I
don't know whether that's necessary but
one possible outcome would be to say for
um servers that use resource directory
discovery uh they can use any path for
servers that use a more limited form of
Discovery they are stuck with the mg
path yeah so that could just one more
suggestion on the table
yeah you're right
see who's next yeah
it's me no I I was thinking about uh we
could also reserve one of the
well-known something resources for that
and I've seen this also in other working
groups that sometimes that's useful if
you have a known resource path because
then in that case you can skip Discovery
processes and
in constrained networks it's often yeah
takes time takes network resources
to do this whole round trip of this
cover and then get a response back so if
you can typical situations skip all of
that and just make your message a little
bit longer
it's not not that many bites so it's
also useful to have one of these
well-known piles because I'm not sure if
we can assume that the server will if
you get an IP address and port for
example uh through some
some way and if you don't get a resource
I don't think you can always assume that
it's always at the slash root resource
or
yeah maybe we can actually there's a
similar case we are working on right now
in the animal working group where we
also want to play something at the slash
resource
and there the ideas what you discover is
basically in IP address and a port
and and you also know the purpose of
that so it's kind of a relay uh Co-op
relay function and then you also know by
that said oh the default resource is
slash so that yeah I mean we also have
like the uh content format where we can
basically
say tell the server hey I actually want
this DNS resource but maybe that's not a
good idea in our evaluations we use DNS
but then again we use four bytes in the
header so
yeah I guess that we we need to put some
thought into that more uh this is the
conclusion
yeah but at least consider uh like one
of those well-known Parts because a
server can easily uh support multiple
assets could support the well-known one
plus discovered one which may be the
slash resource so uh so it's fine to
have multiple
and if you have something to fall back
to then
if you already have an IP address and
ports where to go to or maybe it's a
default port then you can just go and do
the DNS request without needing to
discover anything first that's the idea
okay then uh let's continue with the
second talk
um which is about uh concise binary
object representation of DNS messages or
sibo in of this DNS messages
um so the uh
the
motivation is basically that we have a
huge drawback of DNS and constraint
messages that if we look at the diagrams
here we're on the x-axis we see for each
name length a pair of queries and quad a
responses
um and on the y-axis the size of the
packet uh with the fragmentation borders
marked
at uh as a dashed line we see that we
quickly even for very short names
um
can exceed the fragmentation limit so we
need some way to compress our DNS
messages
um
and uh yeah that's basically uh the
proposal we wrote application DNS
placebo
[Music]
um
the idea behind it is that we reduce the
packet size by the of DNS queries and
replies by encoding them first in seabor
and then emitting redundant or
unnecessary and DNS fields in the DNS
queries and responses and then we also
provide address and name compression
using packed Sable as a seabor as an
optional measure for the DNS responses
um for DNS queries you can see the
definition of them in in cddl on the
left side for those who don't know that
much cddl there's also an explanation on
the right side so basically a DNS query
is a sibo array which at minimum
contains the text string of the domain
name
and it also optionally provides an ID
and a record tab specification the ID
defaults to zero if it's not present the
record type defaults to quote a and the
record class to in if they are not
present
um the DNS resource record which is then
part of the response is defined to also
be a sibo array which at minimum
contains a TT a TTL and a resource data
and it optionally can also contain the
name and the record type and if both are
not present then they basically defer to
the question value
and the DNS response is an array of
arrays which at minimum contains the
answer section
which again is an array of DNS resource
records
um but this basically generally assumes
that the transport can map the query to
the response which for example for DOA C
or Doh is the case
but we can also provide the original
question and the ID
if that is not the case
yeah
um yeah for a simple example if we want
to query the IPv6 address of example.org
we have this uh basically in uh sibo
diagnostic format represented here
um this is then certain bytes compared
to the 52 bytes of wire format which is
a compression rate of 400 percent and
the correspondent corresponding response
you can also see on the slide which is
only 24 bytes compared to the 68 bytes
of the wire format compression
um of the wire format which provides us
with a compression rate of 284 percent
or three percent
uh
yeah
um for a more complex example if we for
example want to request the annual
record of a example.org domain
um
like we would do for dnssd
then we get a good compression for the
wire format still
but for the response uh not so much we
have then 200 bytes of the sibo format
compared to the 195 price of the wire
format
um so um we need some address and name
compression
um which with a little bit of past and
help we
provided so um
yeah for our proposal we provide an
optional cboard support for the response
which is negotiated by a content type no
media type negotiation
via this uh packed parameter for the
media type
uh in as a note in version one of the
drafts this is still its own media type
um but in the next version it will be a
parameter
um
yeah and then we make a shared value and
argument table one list instead of uh
compared to the sibo pack draft
and uh then basically we the response
becomes another area of two arrays
which the first parameter is the packing
table which is basically a complete
combined shared value and argument table
and the second element is a compressed
DNS response
the structure follows of course the
uncompressed DNS response button is
compressed
and if we look at our and the question
was that came up in other meetings was
why we then don't use for example stuff
like Chic there
um
the problem is there that we basically
have this this chick we have this
assumed Network structure and somehow
the rules for compression are exchanged
between the device and the shake
compressor decompressor
and so that the rule ID can be used for
the identification of how this was
compressed
and uh
that basically means there must be an
established connection between the
device and the compressor and
decompressor um which usually we don't
have when we just select the DNS server
with a DNS client we can basically just
select any DNS server there
so uh we don't have any uh agreed upon
rules between the server and the client
except maybe for a few Global
compression contracts that we have in
DNS for example the tlds
uh so that is why we decided for the
pack format
um and to give you an example how this
then would compress down
uh is that we have this table on the in
the first array here
um which is then referenced in the
response itself and even though in
diagnostic format it looks much bigger
than the original uh if you compile that
to actual cboard it's actually only 119
bytes so we have a compression rate of
164 bytes uh percent sorry
um yeah
um there's also maybe a way to how we
can even more optimize it then if we use
these Global compression contexts I
mentioned before
like the tlds to even Elite more stuff
but um maybe that's not that much worse
of an effort
um
yeah but for the next steps here we need
to Define some more details using packed
sibo's for example we didn't Define yet
how the packing table is constructured
constructed
and uh yeah again the global compression
context might also be a venue that needs
to be discussed and thought upon
So yeah thank you and if you have any
comments and
questions
please ask them
yeah pin
so there have been a few attempts to
re-express DNS uh over the past few
years and
uh in general I would say dnsop has not
been very friendly to these kinds of
proposals so I would I would say you
should start by by going to DNS knob and
seeing what the DNS Community makes of
it I think that the biggest concern
there has generally been about
ossification the concern being that if a
new format cannot express not only any
DNS message that can be defined today
but any DNS message that will ever could
ever be defined losslessly
uh if it doesn't meet that bar then it
is ossifying it's creating devices that
appear to do DNS but actually only
support a subset you know creating
problems for the evolution of DNS in the
future
so that uh that has been a a concern
it's definitely something to think about
in general
I I have trouble seeing the value here
because
DNS messages are almost always a tiny
fraction of the total bandwidth they're
a bootstrap mechanism for something else
so saving even 50 percent
off of the size of your DNS messages
doesn't save you very much it's not
really measurable in aggregate
um
I I tend to disagree with that that it's
not that little of traffic but uh
yeah we uh we actually of course we want
to go with DNS up into that uh so yeah
but first I guess we need to uh have the
general format uh done before we go
further into that
uh let's go yeah
um yeah I was just considering uh that
the the normal DNS format has basically
the packing already integrated there so
you can use it or cannot use it but it's
all the same format and I think that's
General easier uh
to to handle that so you don't need to
consider oh wait there's two formats or
I need to negotiate
so somehow I think it would be easy if
you just one format where you can with a
clients or basically sender of the
message can actually compress on things
or decide to not compress things and the
receiver side will always
be able to construct uh yeah back to the
uncompressed message so that
yeah beautiful the year behind that is
that the client might not support
Co-op so that's the way the negotiation
part is basically a way for the client
to say hey I support that and if you're
uh yeah the response is quite large then
please send it back to me okay yeah you
just want to be sure that that you can
have clients that that cannot do the
decompression okay
yeah and then one other just random
remark is I have a system on my laptop
running simulated uh Wireless nodes that
can talk DNS SD so register services and
query
things like that so just uh just to be
aware of okay thanks thank you
uh awesome yeah just just a quick answer
to Ben uh if you look at the the
percentage
of the DNS traffic to other traffic then
of course the the total
gain of a concise representation is
pretty limited but I think as Martine
had in in her first
slides the
um the environments that have limited
uh pdu sizes
um actually have a cost
for for using larger packets that is
going Beyond
just a few bytes
um so the the problem really is that you
you're using DNS when when you
when you're resetting when when you are
uh recovering from from a network
failure or something like that
and that's exactly when when everybody
else does it and uh your network will be
impaired a little bit
and if then you actually have to do
application data fragmentation so this
is not IP fragmentation but but the
adaptation layer that needs to do the
fragmentation
um you are further reducing uh your
performance so it would be nice if the
the actual DNS interchange would be as
resilient as possible and that that
makes it necessary to stay within about
80 bytes yeah and I mean what you can
see also in on the slide is that uh
uh larger packages also create more
overhead because they also include the
link and six Loop and headers and and so
we try to want to try to avoid this
uh there's yep and again okay
yeah
so
if you're trying to stay under this
limit deterministically then I don't
think a a concise representation is
sufficient right so like the the path
that seems more appealing to me is to
say we're not providing a general
purpose representation of DNS that's
more compact which is very difficult
because the base representation which is
already very compact
uh what we're doing is is defining a
very simple service like a name to IP
service you only get one IP Mac uh you
know very simplified
uh that could then sort of this use case
without claiming to be a general purpose
replacement for DNS
no because we of course also want to
support stuff like DNS service Discovery
where we don't just want to
resolve names to addresses but also
maybe other records so
uh uh I don't think a name to address
service would just suffice for that
I don't worry over time even in that
case I would suggest
uh seeing if you could specify an API
specifically for service Discovery and
think of it as a service Discovery
system not a DNS
okay
foreign
I really don't understand your argument
um why are you arguing against the
compression of the DNS messages I mean
that the DNS is a rather tiny part uh
also over a traffic okay fine but it's
not an argument to not standardize I
mean work on the compassion of the
messages
uh so I do think it is right like
complexity has a cost
um defining new new things with small
benefits is
um is not I think a good a good path
forward in general we should only take
the create all of this documentation and
complexity if there's a significant
payoff that actually benefits users in a
meaningful way but
uh but specifically in this case I think
that as I mentioned there are also some
systemic concerns about alternative
representations of DNS so for example
there's been a lot of effort to to try
to Define Json representations of DNS
that's and there are apis out there that
will give you DNS answers in Json format
but standardizing that has been very
challenging because
it's not enough to specify a Json format
that represents DNS as it exists today
it needs to be able to evolve forward
with any future uses of DNS including
things like edns options that have yet
to be defined
so
that uh that raises the bar considerably
I do think that it's possible to to
define a representation of DNS messages
that is a little bit smaller on average
than uh than the current messages and
certainly you can save a lot of space if
you're willing to discard some of the
information but discarding DNS
information is a very sticky area
um yeah customer I just want to say we
already have a resource Discovery
service so we don't need a new one uh
this really is about uh enabling uh DNS
usage uh as as it is being used
uh in other environments in in the
constrained environments as well yeah
yeah that's good John yeah I just
another comment on on this show uh what
I work with is actually a constrained
Network implementation so it's a threat
wireless mesh network based on six low
band but it's not the most constrained
so it still has the 2.4 gigahertz
operation so it can have a relatively
large
usage of the Bands so no duty cycle
limits so so I know there are even far
more constraints
types of networks I think than than
threats not for threats what we use is
just the normal DNS so for
doing server lookups but also uh DNS SD
so Service registration querying for
services so that's all done with uh yeah
let's say on my meta devices with with
the regular
DNS format so in that sense I understand
the argument a bit uh
yeah why would that yeah why do things
differently are we of course we already
have the DNS formats and it offers some
uh form of compression maybe not the
best but uh
yeah it's it's uh in terms of traffic
it's not uh you know not the main source
of traffic you can say for the
obligations
so I can understand that argument so
maybe it's good to think about well
maybe they're more construct even more
constraint implementations here where
you have to be uh like in the single uh
radio frame
for for common queries like looking up a
name to an RP address yeah which is the
most common example I'm not sure if
those type of systems would actually go
into service discovery
things like that I don't know but uh
yeah it's good good to think about
something that might be very compact for
for the the bulk of the queries which is
like okay give me the IP address of this
server and maybe they are slightly more
bulkier for for complex things here like
if you have a DNS SD maybe that that
just uses the existing encoding I can
also imagine that so yeah in that case
there is no there's no problem that that
you hit a limit that your new format
cannot do everything that's at Classic
DNS can do so that's also something to
consider as well so a bit of a hybrid
approach in that case yeah
so are there I think the queue is closed
so
yeah thank you
so there's going to be an interview on
November 23 already scheduled and it's
going to cover most vhrefs and Target
attributes uh we can also continue this
discussion on dnsc board
there's more interim already discovered
already
till then thanks everyone for attending
enjoying the rest of itf-15
thank you
uh just one thing I want to do
a Terrace and the working group it's
Francesca I have been going through the
um list of erratas and uh there are
currently 10 reports of the router and I
will post the remaining list I'm looking
for uh agreement that this is the right
way to mark them so I will send an email
shortly
look out for that thank you
thanks
foreign
remember that now that we
have
a problem