foreign
okay uh we have a full agenda we are
going to start on time
um I'm Mike Jones my
co-chair is Evo
and we will be having a lot of good
because I had discussions today
so note well the note well as I've heard
life and others say
it's a condition of participation
meeting tips
do sign in to the meet Echo light
uh without audio
you will use it to queue when you went
want to speak
um that is true both of in-person
participants and remote participants so
that we can be fair about uh
letting people participate
wear masks unless you're speaking at a
microphone
and if you're remote make sure you're uh
microphone is off unless you're actively
presenting
thank you
this is a standard set of resources
which has been in all the chair slides
including the agenda from which you can
join
we do have one volunteer for note taking
I would like
to get a second person who's willing to
tag team and help
Jesus
okay I'm gonna start volunteering people
if I don't get a volunteer
tell you what honest when you're not
presenting can you tag team on the note
taking
thank you very much
and maybe Russ could you do it when
hanas is presenting thank you
we have quite a full agenda I'm going to
be ruthless with the clock should I need
to I would ask the presenters to try to
stay within their time slots we have a
lot of interesting material and
discussions to be had
the good news
is that
we finished a bunch of rfcs and there's
two more about to be finished
um
thanks to Paul for encouraging us and
for those who did the work
for getting us there it's been a journey
but we now have an internet standard for
because they
and with that
I am going to switch to Russ
foreign
thank you next slide please
so the the topic is uh whether we should
support a couple of
non-authenticated encryption algorithms
we proposed this at the last ietf put
together a draft
the suit working group for their
firmware encryption draft is using it
and um
just last month
the this working group adopted the draft
to assign to code points next slide
basically code points for counter mode
with three key sizes and CBC mode with
three key sizes all marked as deprecated
in the
Ayana registry just to make sure that
people don't accidentally use this them
when they think they are getting an
authenticated mode the document tells
them it has to be used with some
mechanism such as a digital signature in
order to provide that integrity
next slide please
um
last week or the week before we got a
bunch of comments about the things that
can go wrong when you don't have
Authentication
we knew these of course but we did
address these specific things Ian
proposed security consideration text
um next slide
so there's basically three possible ways
forward one is we adopt that security
considerations text and assign those
code points
um it was observed in the um concerns
that the padding attack does uh have
some concerns above and beyond counter
mode uh the padding associated with CBC
so one thing we could do since the boot
loader implementation seemed to prefers
counter mode anyway as we could drop CBC
and proceed with just one of the modes
or the third thing is we can tell the
suit working group know if it's not
authenticated encryption we're not going
to register it
and then that what that means is at
least those boot loaders who are
insisting on using counter mode will not
implement the standard
so those are our three choices and uh
the consequences thereof
um and I'd like to know what the working
group wants to do
that's the question
um I I'm not making any comments I'm
just relaying a couple things from the
list in case people haven't seen it
please introduce yourself I was in the
queue so I thought I had introduced
myself virtually
um it helps the note taker fair enough
yes uh the first was there's been some
commentary that maybe we can say
something that's more severe than
deprecated like special considerations
or something like that I'm not sure but
maybe that's an option
um the other comment was that there are
some aeads that maybe do work out of
order if you squint at them just enough
I don't know I'm not a cryptographer
like prayer Rock
thank you Michael uh Pro Rock here um I
believe for sure option one should be
done let's add even though there's a
concern you know the security
considerations is getting along here
it's longer than the rest of them oh no
it's uh there are some similar things in
some of the other things that I'm
working on right with very long hashes
so
um but I do think there's a high degree
of value in registering even if it's
marked deprecated or do not use or some
other stronger language if for no other
reason is that then that will encourage
someone who thinks oh I found this neat
thing let me go look up what's going on
with this and then they see mountains of
security considerations and realize why
this might be a bad thing unless they
really really know what they're doing
and have a very specific use case so
that is not to say that there aren't
highly specific use cases for this
personal feelings are and having talked
a bit with some of the Sioux folks and
things like that is that there might be
a better way out at the very least if we
register this this might provide a
stopgap mechanism just to continue
proofing things out as long as we're
very clear we're not trying to advocate
for the use of this broadly right
Richard Burns
yeah hey just kind of riffing on
Brendan's suggestion about something
stronger than uh than deprecated I
wonder if
it would be possible to do something
like Mark these as reserved these code
points as allocates and code points in
the diameter industry but mark them as
reserved and then in some suit documents
uh Define their usage any a special suit
way
foreign
it means like no one's going to come
across the registry be scanning for
things and say oh there's a CBC thing
here I can use this
um and then you'll never even get to the
security
I'm good entertained by Michael's
assistant people are going to pull up
the document and see if the security is
considering
um
would prevent that sort of risk
so Richard I would not want it to be
hard to find out what algorithm that
code Point meant
which seems to be what you're proposing
um you could do something I think
maybe like list
the suit document that defines the
acknowledge should be mostly safe usage
as a reference in the registry for why
it's reserved
ah sure we could we could uh say only
for use with x
precisely so you basically Define a
special use code that was only
meaningful in scope of that specific
usage which you know if someone comes up
with a second usage for CTR or CBC like
could get awkward but hopefully you know
one might hope that those won't come up
too often
okay good
I'm not sure I understood Richard's
proposal there but they're all
legitimate uses of I mean there are
multiple legitimate uses of
of country mode for example so we have
in the sigma protocol the second message
only needs
indistinguishability against chosen
plain text attack so as CTR would be a
good fit there
so I I I support
options one or two here and I don't
think there should be
sort of restriction on how you use them
because unless it's a very easy way to
update that and that might be a very
long list of things where you want to
make this
special cases
okay chair how do we decide
um
so far I hear people speaking for option
one and two
um I heard one and two but not three
which is I'm encouraged by not three
and
not wearing my chair hat I would
encourage us to follow normal
registration processes
unless there's a strong reason not to I
did hear you're come to the mic say
there may be multiple uses for these
which I think argues against making them
special purpose uh with that thank you
for your time we can continue this on
the list honest it's your turn thank you
thank you Mike
okay HP key um
next slide
it looked like a very easy document uh
at the beginning
and we had a discussion at the last ITF
meeting which also was uncontroversial
about the encoding of the encrypt or the
output of the HB key uh uh then
following the confirmation call on the
mailing list it turned out that that was
um not quite true
um
and
with the Alternatives were proposed but
those couldn't uh reach or we couldn't
reach a conclusion either which is why
the the chairs specifically Mike posted
a mail to the list
um mentioning that outcome of that call
so
um I put a few slides in here and for
you to look at what the current
proposals are in addition to what's in
the working group document which I
hadn't updated because
obviously we need to First have a
conclusion on what we updated with
next slide
so
um Daisuke proposed made a very specific
proposal and I color coded the important
information here
so there is um so this is the
uh this is sort of like encrypt zero
payload
um
where the use of HP Keyes oops
one pack
what okay uh is indicated using this HP
key algorithm which we would have to
register and then the essence or the
core of the information that is being
passed around in is in this newly
introduced uh hbke sender information
structure which contains
um which is a map containing of a few
Fields
um namely the chem the kdf and the aad
which is uh which is populated with
values from the hpke established
Registries uh the ink
um field is the output of the hpkey
algorithm
um and it's obviously abbreviated here
so that's his proposal uh
the next slide
um Hillary's proposal
uh layers on top of this and instead of
um
he makes a few changes uh maybe actually
we go to the next slide this is sort of
the textual description of what you see
here is
um is to use an array instead of a map
thereby and making it non-extensible uh
and omitting the chem and he believes
that one can come up with uh processing
rules for sort of guessing what the
chemdan is uh
uh otherwise it's it's conceptual is
similar I I would say except for those
those changes
um although he did raise a few new
points on the mailing list um a new new
issues that we may or may not uh
introduce
um which I I
were kind of completely new
um weren't raised previously so I I
omitted them here
but in in essence those are the two
proposals and
that what the actually three proposals
there's the original one uh neither
Richard nor
um
no Hillary no I'm uh
uh or none of the the booklet proponents
uh like that idea but this is kind of
what we are these two proposals are but
we share it in and if you have any
preference on what you would like to do
uh that would be highly welcome
that's what I'm essentially saying with
the last slide
so
I we don't
it's like besides uh
small number of people who have strong
opinions we haven't
come up with something yet yeah you know
so I apologize I haven't really looked
at all the details here but you're
proposing the in it's a cozy key that's
what remains in the draft in these are
the two
counter proposals against that and
basically they are indexed by the
algorithm algorithm
which then creates this new this new
entire format so you basically read off
from the camera the the minus one but
this is a cam uh and then you oh sorry
this is an hpk and then your
all the rest of the fields are defined
is that understanding the proposals yeah
like um that that's correct in some
sense
um we are really talking about how to
encode the different fields that uh are
communicated and they're not that many
fields right uh there's uh the chem the
aadid
um the kdf and and of course the
encryption field and that needs to go
somewhere uh and the question is where
should that go
it
like on a very high level it doesn't
sound like rocket science
learned yeah uh Lawrence dunblade
um
so so in this Pro in all the proposals
the the algorithm top level algorithm is
just hpk hpke
and this seems like a Divergence from
what everything else is in cozy where
you kind of have us the the top level
algorithm is more of a cipher Suite
um that specifies all the things now I
know the fan out here can be quite large
but one of the advantages I thought of
with of the cipher suite at the top
level are two advantages I see at The
Cypher speed at the top level is you
just have to look at the algorithm ID to
know whether you can support it or not
you don't have to decode a lot more deep
a lot deeper into it and it allows us to
register only sensible Cipher Suites and
avoid uh some of the fan out so my gut
reaction is that's I I would prefer that
and not to diverge what code from Jose
has done in the past and I think there's
some good reasons for that yeah yeah
that's um that mirrors um
what is currently described in a working
group document but that approach didn't
uh find a lot of sympathy
um because the
the
Vision was that uh the hpkey guys would
register new algorithms and then they
would become instantly available in in
cozy HP key uh by reusing existing
registry that's why um
the the way how these field three fields
are structured it's kind of populated
with the values from the existing
registry whether that's a gigantic
benefit or not uh that's in the eye of
the beholder but uh yeah that's at least
um that's the rationale
Mike yeah Michael prayer Rock
yeah I'm gonna Echo similar support for
the way the document's written now um
I'm not saying a huge benefit to
diverging massively from the existing
methods that are being taken with kose
registry um it seems to make sense right
same reason like point at the owl go
after this right uh follow a common
sense approach there
I have a little bit of concern pointing
out to a secondary registry and then
just we magically get something right
maybe that's good maybe that's bad
I'm a little more concerned about that
approach especially because HP hpk is
such a you know special case right it's
not really
going down the same path as what we
normally deal with with saying oh I've
got this very well-defined family of
algorithms this
specific algorithm and parameter set
it's more facilitating use of that in
other
Richard and then we'll move on
so just one quick clarification on what
Mike said
um I I'm ambivalent on the question of
how we indicate algorithms for what it's
worth MLS and other hpke user did choose
to define specific code points that are
combinations of hbke sub algorithms so
um it wouldn't be totally interesting to
do that here but you would have the the
lack of agility as you must pointed out
I I do think that it is not an option to
go with the document exactly as it is
right now because we need to update to
fix this code State key problem
represent the encapsulated value as
specific plates so there's some changes
necessary here
foreign thank you any closing remarks on
us
I think Sean just keep this keep
discussing it and hopefully finding a
solution at the end of the day
all right next we'll have the uh
seabor encoded cert yes
excellent oh hi all
uh yes it's you will heard Leon speaking
and we wanted to give you a update on
the status and ongoing work on the
seabor encoded x509 certificates and
also to remind everybody to come with
input on those issues where yeah input
is valuable
next slide please
oh that's what I've already covered one
more please
and as a quick reminder of the overall
trade-offs so this is all about finding
the good trade-off between compactness
and convenience to parse and process for
iot devices while still being General
enough to encode as many relevant x509
certificates as possible so these are
the the different goals that we try to
balance
in this proposal and now I'm going to
quickly relatively quickly step through
a number of open issues and then
depending on time and interest
maybe actually gather some input but
most of it will be for your information
and then if there is interest there is
definitely we're definitely interested
in hearing input on basically all of
this even though we have our own
proposals for solving most of them
um so a recurring topic is whether the
the minor optimizations that was
proposed in the beginning should be kept
because they make the the processing a
bit more complex but they are needed to
actually reach the very most compact
uh cases for iot profiling so we are
basically inclined to keep them unless
there is a big outcry for making it
simpler and more streamlined next please
and so this is about the encoding of
signature algorithms and as some of you
might know there is still sha-1 being
used out in the wild meaning to actually
be a general purpose uh format we need
to handle these types of of
uh signatory encodings and there has
been some discussion of whether they
should be punished in terms of being a
longer having longer encodings but we
think that as long as they are used for
many CA certificates it doesn't really
make sense to actively punish them that
rather we should keep it in the same
range as other signature algorithms
so we propose to use normal to bite
assignments to cover these signature
algorithms next please
so this is also more on the info stage
that there has been already observed
it's been observed that what we're
proposing here should also benefit in
terms of revocation lists and OCS ocsp
messaging and the rice and Ericsson
together have been having a multitis
which has been looking into this so this
is something we hope to be feeding back
into the existing proposals
next please
and this is also just uh to to make sure
that it is self-contained the the draft
in in terms of actual usability for iot
because right now we we list a big
number of algorithms and not all of them
are of course suitable for iot so this
is just a sanity check to make sure that
we keep the knowledge on what are
actually good algorithms for iot cases
that we try to promote next please
so this is this is a bullet where input
from a larger audience would be valuable
even though from our perspective there
has been discussions on whether we
should make propose more complex
structure where broccoli uh well back up
one step so basically that that there
could be
certificate chain optimizations done if
we would allow to pass parsing of
certificate chains
uh but from our perspective we see that
this would add to Max much complexity to
the the parching ending and make it less
suitable for the iot device the
scenarios that we at least I care deeply
about and that rather it could be
handled through additional cozy headers
and external broadly compression
but this is somewhere if if the audience
has strong opinions we are very
interested in hearing them but now we
step on and take eventual discussions at
the end
next please
so this is a short break to to upload
many insightful observations from
Hillary and we are addressing them and I
will speak about some of them next
please
so this is the basically work in
progress to handle kind of more Corner
cases that we had missed in the initial
proposal so these are all
kind of fixes to make it more general
for the next version of the draft
next please
and this is an again an important
highlighting
that currently
the IP range encoding could
theoretically break the seaboor int
encoding if you would have since we
encode differences so if you would have
a crazy subnet where you would care to
cover too much of the IP Subspace you
could in theory break it
and instead of of trying to address this
as we see very much Corner case we we
should make it clear that this is a
limitation of the existing proposal
next please
oh this is uh yet the the last issue
where also input from audience could be
really useful
that Hillary made the real life
observation about the authority key
identifier
that the in in real life actual
certificates lack
one of the the sub parameters
and this can be fixed by allowing null
encoding to to cover these cases but
that leaves two of the other
subparameters which we in our
investigations have not found to need
null encoding as well but we haven't
done extensive studies so if this is uh
if this is a real life problem we should
allow also these submar meters to be
encoded as null and this we are open for
adjusting if if we think that it's a
problem that needs addressing otherwise
it's all about clarifying the the
assumptions that we have made
and that was the last issue that I
wanted to present to you and I'm of
course we're very
happy for comments now or on the mailing
list as we are progressing with this
work thank you
any questions if so please join the
queue
all right
um
thank you Joel uh at this point we'll
turn it to Tobias for
the BLS key representation draft
uh next slide
so this is just a quick update and we're
Fisher on this draft so it defines and
registers the required parameters
um Diana for the graphic key
representation for the Beretta Lynn
Scott elliptic curve family so BLS
curves for representation in both koseki
and jwk
uh next slide
uh so so why do it um well Beretta
Lynn's got um elliptic curves have a a
couple of special properties to them
known as
um they are known as peering friendly
um which allows different signature
style Primitives
um two of such Uh current drafts of the
cfrg BLS signatures is one notable that
has been addressed for some time there
is also a appearing friendly curves
draft that was recently updated which
formally defines the curves and then
lastly there is also another signature
scheme draft
um that I'm also a co-author of that was
newly adopted at the cfrg since the last
iatf meeting and both of these make use
of the VLS curve which is
um as as as per industry adoption the
most popular of the peering curve family
right now
next slide
and so just a very basic status update
um
as as spoken about it's a simple draft
primarily registering these perimeters
and the draft was adopted
um since atf-114 we published recently
an update which added jwk based examples
and I'm close to filing a a PR and
making a publication for adding the koze
key examples
yeah
it looks like
that's it
oh that's it
Tobias do you have any questions to the
working group at this point or what
actions would you like them to take
uh no no explicitations Beyond um just
helping to review the draft because the
key examples should be
um and um fairly soon in the next couple
of days
um so reviewing it
um
with uh I guess with an item next steps
as per the processes as
um
yeah as as probably the next steps
thanks
okay
are there any questions from
the floor
all right
um thank you tobios
um now I'm going to switch roles and be
an individual participant
for presenting another draft
that uh
Tobias and I had written together
this is the claims in cozy headers draft
so what does it do it enables us to
represent a set of sieber web token
claims
in a special cozy header
they're put into a header parameter and
a object in a structure
because otherwise there would be name
collisions or number collisions between
the header parameter namespace and the
claims namespace
um so why do it there's use cases and
this first showed up in Jose most of a
decade ago
where it's useful to be able to have for
instance an unencrypted version of a
claim
that you use for processing an encrypted
jot or an encrypted seabler web token or
cosay structure
for instance you might want to know what
the issuer is before you even try to
decrypt it
um
Jose and jots had that we did not we
adopted this draft to be able to do that
foreign
draft that does one thing it was adopted
in July thank you
we just published 01 it is a one-line
change from zero zero that changes the
motivating example to issuer
um I will say uh you know having reread
it again fresh with fresh eyes in the
last few days I think it would be
beneficial to add an example
and I know Kirsten had asked about well
should we have ADD cddl as Kirsten has
want to do I don't see Kirsten here
there must be conflict but I intend to
ask Karsten about that offline
um so my question and this is where
Eva's gonna have to chair for a moment
is it time for working group last call
this is stable and I don't see much
happening to it beyond the current
status other than possibly adding an
example
can
can we can
add a working group let's go and live
there
either you are muted if you're trying to
speak to us
why
here
thank you
so um
I'd like
um I actually didn't understand the
example you mentioned here
um with the um
unprotected
yeah why sorry why not use unprotected
header and put uh
information in that so so I think I
think an example would be great that's
that's that's true and maybe maybe
that's good to have before we have
working group classical
I know there's been something on the
mailing list about
unprotected headers it's not clear to me
that they're the same thing because
they're a different name space
one is claims one is header parameters
they're distinct
Lawrence
yeah I was just going to answer that
question is that you know if you're
if you're decoding uh you know mime
headers or content type headers you have
access to that parameter and then you
can switch on that before you you know
bring up the seaboor encoder or whatever
um so it seems like it's a definitely uh
benefit implementations
now just to ask the questions but very
concretely this ISS promotion applies to
both the protected and the unprotected
header or just the protected header
in a
because I signed zero there is no
unprotected header
um if you're using
because they signed one structure
I believe that
there is an unprotected header it's a
fair question whether we want this
header parameter to appear
unprotected ever
and that's something we could discuss if
we do
have working group last call which is up
to EVO to decide
um
you could add that as a working group
last call comment
um
are they hear me now
or is it still
can you speak louder
okay
um so
maybe we can
see in the room if there are people that
are for or against the working group
classical I think in either case we will
confirm it on the main link list if
there is enough support
so in the room
maybe let's use the 14th to
do you know how to start that either
I think so
so those that
uh are in favor of starting the working
groups last call please
and raise your hands and see if there
are people that are against it please
also
um
will have a separate
vote for that
I would a few more seconds
okay so I see 11 people
believe we are ready for working group
let's go there some
people that think
Heights
they would have a little bit early
um
for the minutes 12 people are
four and two are against
uh if the people have
um
if people want to clarify why they think
it's
are still not ready please pick up on
the
mic now
um
we we just raised two open issues uh and
the need to add an example and to find
out whether these fields also applied to
unprotected the unprotected header it
sounds like uh it would be good to at
least update the document briefly and
add that example to think that could
happen quickly actually there was a
third issue as well with the cddl like
having three open issues appears to be
premature to call it working for bus
call right
yes okay
um but with those issues resolved
I guess then we'll be able to go for
working group let's go
um
and
that this
migrating character results
uh so yes like please
and take those
action items on those three issues and
and we can go to working with classical
hmm
thank you we're at time and I see that Q
is cleared
um
so let's move on to
Mike Pro Rock talking about post Quantum
signatures thank you all
thank you Mr Jones wait for that deck to
pop up
uh Mike perock here
um uh kind of continuing on this is the
second update since the working group uh
gratefully uh gracefully accepted this
draft to help us move it forward
um next slide
uh just a quick recap
um on uh post Quantum and why we're
dealing with this and it largely is
because we're seeing interesting changes
to the potentially threatened the way
we've been handling especially public
key cryptography and certain signature
methods based on use of quantum
entanglement and all sorts of other fun
things with qubits that help us unpack
keys and relationships within data
sooner
we have uh selected to go after three
algorithms here and we'll come back to
some implications from that uh from
signature scheme standpoint
um but the ones we have gone after are
two lattice based ones as well as a hash
based approach based on feedback from
nist and where things are at as far as
the candidates for standardization next
up
uh so once again as mentioned we've gone
after three that's Sphinx Falcon and I
lithium and the key thing here is to get
us a leapfrog past and be able to start
testing effectively for interoperability
with things that do require signatures
whether that's cwts jwts verifiable
credentials over in the uh
um World Wide Web Consortium side of the
world and things like that so it's
really setting ourselves up for
cryptographic agility and to be able to
set a path for registration to Future
post Quantum algorithms and Signature
suites as required possibly by kose and
or Jose usage and also to get these Iona
registrations in and because of the
parameterization especially with some of
these algorithms that can be quite
tricky let's make sure we've very
clearly defined that and how we would
use those here pointing back to cfrg and
this next slide
so big downsides large key sizes large
signatures uh typically larger signing
times verification times are very nice
next slide
a couple of key draft updates here we've
gone ahead and completed out the
sections on Falcon and sphinx plus we've
gone through and detailed out the likely
parameter sets that we'll see usage
though these are obviously subject to
change up until these algorithms are
fully standardized at nist and elsewhere
we are using a combination because of
some of the unique parameters based on
the way especially the Jose spec is
originally written around kty and ALG so
that we have the family of algorithms
specified by the kty alga is specifying
the actual algorithm itself as well as
the parameter set in use next slide
next steps this is really the big
question for the working group
um gut feel at this point especially
seeing possible lags uh pot with one
versus another uh is should we split
this into three drafts now that the bulk
of the work has been done we can pretty
easily do that and instead of having one
post Quantum uh signature scheme draft
that covers the three initial ones we
could split those up so that they can be
actually moved forward should that occur
sooner with one versus another uh or so
that we can let one die if we need to
for whatever reason the proposed names
at this point would be draft ietf cause
a dilithium falcon and sphinx plus
um we are awaiting obviously
finalizational parameter sets love any
feedback from that if anyone's heard
anything that we haven't and generalized
guidance from the group since this is
kind of the first draft I started on
with iatf on anything I might be uh
messing up on or could do better so
thanks so much and do want to make sure
there's a good shout out to Ori all the
others who have been helping us out
especially Christine and uh
actually some of the authors of things
like Sphinx and Falcon Etc
okay
um I'm Quinta goodness uh just one
comments um because three of them they
they might come out at different times
so I think it's a better idea to have
separate documents for all of them
because uh yeah they're a good chance
that there will be finalized by this at
different times and you don't want one
to tie down the you know the unfinished
Hideout the finished one
thanks very much for that it's very
helpful
Richard
yeah thanks so thanks for interesting on
the Mike I think this is an obvious
no-brainer to get these uh algorithm
identifier specified basically as soon
as the algorithms are done so I think my
main concern here is not getting too far
ahead of the actual algorithm
standardization uh but it's like as soon
as those come out of nist like let's
roll
um as far as the document number I think
Quinn's point is probably good
um if if not for that I would say just
put it all in one not incur the process
I've ever had three times but if there's
if there's risk of if we can go faster
with some of them by by decoupling them
by all means
sorry
one of one of the authors I agree with
splitting them up for the reasons
mentioned and also for the reason that
the Sphinx test vectors take up most of
the specs
and and most of the container compute
time and generating examples in the test
vectors
John
hi yeah I'm just um we had a hackathon
on the weekend for uh the x509 side of
things doing exactly this with the PQ
keys and signatures so I'm wondering
there's obviously overlap here so we
should probably talk and you know make
sure because the object ID is the same
things that you are bringing up are the
exact same things that we're dealing
with plus we're also doing the composite
so that would be something to also maybe
considered for this yeah ABS absolutely
and uh also appreciate all your inputs
on the entry stuff we're working on and
um I'm very thankful that we're having
conversations and have like a mailing
list for this stuff because it's new and
we need to cross communicate on this so
thanks again for your support on this
what what working groups and or
individuals who are doing this work in
the context of X7 on yeah it's mainly
people from the lamps working group
because it's dealing with the pki
artifacts that was where we started from
but obviously PQ goes beyond just the
pki artifacts right it goes everywhere
so
um and so there was actually a side
meeting yesterday too about talking
about a PQ side working group and
putting together a charter for all that
so yeah I guess we'll see how that that
continues so yeah and in a quick context
for those who might not know Michael
Osborne and Christine Klosterman are
co-authors on this who uh authored kind
of the root level stuff over at uh the
lamps side of things so we're in very
close communication with both of them on
pretty much a weekly basis okay but yeah
yeah in terms of our hackathon like
we're going to have we're going to
continue to work so we can invite we're
happy to if we people want to test Koji
artifacts or whatever with us we're
having monthly meetings I sent that to
the labs mailing list I could send it to
this mailing list and invite people to
if they want to participate because I'm
trying to come up with a framework for
automated testing and to make sure all
these these new things work together so
so I'll do that then awesome thank you
thank you Ori and then we'll cut the cue
just just to say that Mike and I and
others have all had conversations around
the key representations and the
encryption side of this and if the
working group desires for us to you know
create two new documents in addition to
splitting these ones out I don't think
it's tremendous amount of work and be
happy to help support that initiative
any closing remarks otherwise we will go
to Hank no just really appreciate all
the time and especially the support is a
uh comparatively new author compared to
some of the people that actually know
what they're doing in this room so thank
you all
foreign
he can explain why that happened but
anyways so I'm Mike sorry hello oops
um yes
um I'm Mike I'm part of this git working
group that's been very newly formed
um some of you probably don't even know
it
um it's it's supply chain Integrity
transparency interest
working group we have our uh first real
session on Thursdays we're happy to to
join
um we wanted to
um discuss one specific Topic in this
group here
and that's around the transparency
aspect of it so if you know transparency
logs you know for certificate
transparency for example they all have
um specific formats on how to represent
um you know sign tree heads inclusion
proofs and all of that and this again
now becomes a topic for more General
Supply Chain transparency
and so as part of the skid working group
um we defined uh well an early
definition of what we call a receipt and
that's basically a bundle of
um assigned tree head and an inclusion
proof
for
counter signature leaves so what does it
mean
um it means you have a a cozy sign one
message that's your supply chain
um in a way artifact and then
um or statement I should say and then
um that becomes part of a transparency
log and so you bind those two together
with a
counter-sense structure for example
that's defined and cozy
um
so I'm not I don't want to say too much
about the details
um so I
I think the main point that I want to
say here is
um
we defined this new thing that's called
receipt and it doesn't neatly fit into
any existing cozy structures so it's a
new thing
and I think maybe you're switching to
the next slide actually makes more sense
here
so
we had an early attempt on trying to
shoehorn receipts and all the
transparency bits into a signature
algorithm and essentially reusing cozy
as it is
that was not well received in the
community because it was essentially a
bit of an abuse of what the signature
algorithm means and it was just too much
so a better approach is just treat it as
a separate thing and you know there's
this whole transparency aspect to it
when we don't want to hide it and that
is an inclusion proof and it makes sense
to
you know expose that to the to the top
essentially
so and I guess what we're asking the the
Cozy group is
um does this make sense in principle
um and then I guess there's a question
of the the Registries that cozy has so
where would that fit in exactly
um would there have to be maybe a new
registry for
things that are maybe parametrized in
our case so one example is that there's
not just a single type of
you know Ledger or transparency log they
have slightly different
um you know let's say Mercury algorithms
and so there has to be some some way to
to express that and yeah so there must
be some kind of algorithm or Ledger type
um and I think that goes a bit uh back
to the to the remark earlier that was on
um ciphos tweets you know shouldn't be a
single long thing or should it be a bit
split up
but anyway these are kind of details and
I guess yeah I have just one minute so
that's
um so think about that I don't think we
want an answer now but also join us at
skit and maybe
um yeah and we've we've got five minutes
that you
you can use some of that if you want
is this 40 seconds
yes we have uh five minutes of all other
business with no claimants yet okay good
thank you so so finish in a natural way
okay so that was this one topic I don't
know if you already want to get some
feedback because this is a completely
separate topic
um
Hank so what's up this is Hank just
quickly um on the receipt
um so that definitely is a core element
in the um the base work we are doing in
skit and and we we really need this in
cozy so uh we will do this as
um individual document here very
transparently we hope for our comment
we'll be talking to Russ a lot so so you
warned us for the biggest caveat so
that's why we are where we are and we
will create a stable proposal how this
looks like and then I hope uh if
everybody is satisfied enough that we
can actually ask for adoption but this
is it's not this this is not yet but but
Sooners actually I think so that's just
my comment that we want to proceed with
this
um not in a in a slow pace but actually
want to have a first uh stable thing
that is adoptable very soon
um okay so let's go to the other topic
okay so now clear everything you had on
your mind
um a very separate thing
um probably most of you know about
timestamp tokens than the whole thing
uh they're mostly used to
you know in things like signed a
software packages used in Microsoft
authenticode
but also for signing documents PDFs so
it's just to make
good use cases to make um the
verification of a signed document be
valid for longer than the original
certificate was valid for
so the idea here is cozy doesn't have a
header parameter that allows to embed
timestamp tokens in the unprotected
header so this is simply
a proposal to say let's define the code
point and
um including you know how to actually
what to do with that how to embed it
and then applications can use that to
timestamp Cozy messages so it's very
simple
um so clarification question did you say
unprotected header yes because it is a
counter signature by Nature
and that's why it can't be in the so
first you have to do the signature and
then the timestamp is against the
signature bytes okay Russ is nodding out
in the peanut gallery there thank you
anyone want to join the queue or provide
feedback
Hank
so this is Hank again and and this is a
comment not actual feedback so this is a
migration path uh solution we don't want
to use a tsts forever
but we accept the fact that they are the
most common and established thing to use
today and so uh if we want to uh move to
something cooler like say an Epoch
marker that's fine or assigned to see
what time check that's cool but for now
this is I think a necessary solution
when you want to use infrastructure that
is in place and that's why this uh could
be perceived as a mid
term
migration path solution
but if we don't standardize it oh just
random
that's all right all right
thank you we are one minute from time I
appreciate all the engagement today
as does Evo and we look forward to
seeing you all on the list thank you for
coming
okay
hello
everybody
thank you
for taking notes
like most of my comments
assert representation
how do we update those two do we update
those two in this graph or we make a
separate draft with
to get updates to go to uh
what are those two rfcs do one of them
is for brain games
which has also different certificate
types
I just just sent it to Village I
actually sent a list back in July
and it's a value to me Pacific I think
dance with me yes
but but that makes
your ass updated
saying you want to send this to the
others we have these two resource
records where certificates are held
right now
um
in mind
thank you