foreign
too far away
all right
yep
Janice it's uh next door if you guys can
see that last thing so I can remember
okay yeah we have her at the uh
at the end at the end just to think of
what you do
yeah
no we don't I was gonna have a group I
tried to set up
all right
I think that means they're great
all right okay
okay started
okay
sorry getting set up everybody online
give me one sec trying to get the
minutes in the right place
okay
all right as people trickling we'll deal
with that um people online can someone
write in the chat room if you guys can
hear me
perfect thank you Robin
okay
all right welcome to ietf 115 this is
the DHCP working group
here's the note well hopefully
everyone's seen it this goes through all
of the ITF processes and policies
um you sign this when you're registered
but here it is again please read it over
and follow all of the policies including
you know code of conduct and IPR the two
we always want to talk about and make
sure that people are following both of
those so if you're not sure this group
is
always been good to me so I expect that
to continue
um
the note well went on if you're not at
the mic
um please wear a mask that's been going
on all week that's the policy of the
community that's the policy of this
event so thanks everybody I think people
have been doing a good job this week
um for blue sheets Bernie still leaves
that in there uh meat Echo does uh does
that for us so
um please make sure if you're in the
room that you're signed into me Deco
that you're clicking on the right button
note taking I've started a doc people
could help out with that that would be
great
okay
Eric would like a volunteer because we
can't start the meeting until there is a
scribe in this case you know I'm solo up
here chairing so I won't be able to do
it so if we could have
um somebody start the notes or somebody
online or even um in the room would be
great
foreign
Eric's offering cookies for anyone
oh a beer tonight look at you just
just the best ad
[Laughter]
Eric if you just want to put it in a
note too you can just send it to me too
there is there is in the meetings
and I know if you go to the retail there
is a
good takes you to hedge dock or
something but I'm also okay Eric I can
track you down if you want to just use a
dock and make it up and send it to me
and I'll drop it in there after I'm just
thankful somebody's writing down my
musings
though
uh please don't do that
it's gonna be a real short meeting
[Music]
all right I'm gonna assume Eric I'm
gonna go on and assume that you'll
Chicken Scratch something down
thank you you're my hero
um
I'm Tim Winters I'm chairing this group
Bernie my co-chair is in Cuba scuba
diving so he's having a rough time with
it right now
so then Bernie is not here he misses
everybody
our agenda today administrative stuff
we're going to talk about 8415 to
internet standard for a little bit and
then we have a distribute Sr locator by
DHCP we have registering self-generated
IPv6 addresses and then we have a couple
of next steps
um anyone have any problem with that
agenda I want to change it Jen is in a
different meeting so I have her at the
end so I don't want to move that if
people want to move anything else at the
court we can do that
All Right Moving On
status
um we don't actually have any working
group documents at the moment
um I think we're going to have soon a
bunch after this meeting but we
currently don't have any so there's not
much for me to talk about there there
are three related documents right now
um all of which are presenting today so
that's good everyone's made updates and
they're all moving so that's good
um just a quick thing we put on the
slide is the Milestones we're aiming to
have oh that's a typo 3315 Bays should
be 84 15 days sorry
um we're aiming to have that done in
January of 2020 23.
um and then after we're done that we can
talk about rechargering and shutting
down whatever makes the most sense
all right let me switch slides
so I'm gonna talk
I guess the mic is still on I'm going to
talk a little bit about advancing um
DHCP V6 to an internet standard so
some of these are a retread but just
people aren't aware we're trying to
advance
um DHCP to an internet standard it's the
last main objective left in the DHC
Charter
um so last meeting in Philadelphia we
decided to take this on
um just a quick reminder here's all the
requirements for everyone to read you
can go read these later but these are
all the things we have to do as part of
the process of moving to an internet
standard
um independent implementation status so
on that slide there was a Implement you
know implementations that have to exist
here we have
um lots of
lots of implementations exist of DHCP B6
I don't think there's a problem there um
there's a little bit of trickiness here
measuring 8415 compliance versus 3315
compliance but ultimately there's a lot
of DHCP
um out in the world and it's being used
so that's good
um the proposed schedule for 84 15 Biz
so we just published
0 0 of this document we started a
working group last call that ends next
week
um
sorry
work and group adoption call thank you
in this book
um yes we're in group adoption call that
ends on the 18th we haven't seen much on
that so that's going to be one of my
pleas today is
everybody take a look at it and you know
I think this obviously makes sense as a
DHCP working group graph I think it's
something we should work on
um so I'd like to hear some noise in the
mailing list about that
um we're going to publish that republish
that document as a working group
document we actually got some feedback
from Bad links from Ayanna thanks for
their review
um they did some so I think we'll
probably stick those in the zero zero
one that goes to the working group so
that's good news
um we're hoping to put 01 out in
mid-December with any changes for as
part of the working group last call
working group adoption call geez
um review we want everything wrapped up
by February 8th
um we'll do as many updates in between
there and March 16th is what we're
aiming for yeah
yes 23 I have not built a time machine
yet
yes it does it's wrong
it's one of those days
yep so 20 I'll slash that through sorry
um
yes 2023 February so we're aiming to
have this all wrapped up by a March ietf
I think if there's anything lingering we
can deal with that in at the March GF
it's kind of our game plan
um one thing to note here is we're going
to need a Shepherd for this that is not
one of the two co-chairs because both of
the co-chairs are our authors so that's
something we'll be looking for if you're
interested please come talk to me about
that
I think
Suresh
so I should volunteers to Shepherd that
that's awesome
um Okay so
things in the 8415 Biz that we've done
since we last talked in Philly we
addressed all the erratas
um we removed iatas we discussed
removing them for 8415 when we did the
update from 3315 and this time they're
really gone we took those out
um we also took out the server unicast
option because don't find it
we didn't find many use cases for it
um that also additionally resolved one
of the erratas it was out for it so
that's been removed and then we added a
reference to
79.43 or the those are the four things
we did uh any questions about any of
that
so there was a couple of things we
wanted to get some feedback on
um one of them was the reduce the
background material sections in one one
and one two
um we talked about potentially bringing
those down there's a lot of extra stuff
in there that I think can get removed
now I don't know if anyone has any
opinions
I guess I'll go through these one at a
time
um if no one runs to the mic I'm going
to take these as we should probably do
these this is going to be my position on
this or
so is there does anyone have any strong
opinions about leaving the background
material in
no one's running to the mic
um we should remove all texts related to
unicast Transmissions so
we took out the server unicast options
but there's a lot of text about what to
do in unicast situations we could
potentially remove them all
of that text we could leave it in there
it's a little odd that you tip out that
option which almost I'm going to ask the
next question as well is should we
deprecate the use of the multicast
status code so the one thing that's here
that I wanted to see if anyone had any
opinions on was if it's an 84-15 proper
device it might be using multicast and a
new server might not respond with use so
I don't know we're not aware of any
deployment so I don't think it's a
problem but if somebody really wants we
can leave the use multicast status code
and all the text to unicast in case
there is what would become a legacy
device that's out there trying to use
unicast
um
I I you know personally I think Bernie
was leaning towards removing all of that
I I think that's okay
um but I don't know if anybody really
knows if if any use of the unicast
status code
um Tomah confirmed that KIA doesn't
support it at all
um I know that there's other servers
that do support it but it's not used so
anyone have any opinions on any of that
oh
okay
um I I guess what I'm taking from this
is we're going to go ahead and do all of
these changes unless we hear something
for one one
this is the play I was talking about
earlier
[Music]
um
please send an email if you're in
support of this becoming a working group
document please send an email if you're
not in support of this becoming a
document
um please say something about this uh
I'll I'll pack again probably after this
meeting but yeah ultimately we want to
adopt this and and so we can move
forward
yeah I mean obviously when you're
looking at it for the group to adopt it
please feel free to review or looking
for reviews I think that's my next slide
yeah my next slide what you can do to
help review the document when published
and Report any issues to the author's
working group
um anything the faster we get these
issues and quicker we can get these
things resolved so if you find anything
you think anything's out of place please
let us know
um I think we'll make all those changes
in o1 that we talked about that I just
talked about we'll see if anyone has any
issues with that and I think that's
everything so the main thing here is
please do the adoption call and then
review the document
any other questions about 8415
all right
I'm gonna move on
uh we have the SR locator
oops
I don't know if somebody's online or in
the room for this
looks like online
um guys
see both of you are on there I'm not
sure who's presenting based on the
request so one of you guys want to jump
on
into the queue so I can admit you
perfect hello
hi we can hear you just fine go ahead do
you want to do you want to run the
slides or do you want me to share them
sorry I didn't even think about that
yeah so
uh you will help me pay Jeff okay the
yep yep just tell me next and I'll
switch to the next slide whenever you're
ready
okay I think let's begin from this page
uh so
uh the
draft have been present in last ITF
meeting and
uh according to the comms we updated
the
draft
Johnson from
Channel mobile
so next page
yeah I will go through the
uh slides quickly because most of the
diamonds have been
revealed in last meeting so the
background for this draft is that the
operators
began to deploy ASAP six in major
Network
uh you know the number of CPS are very
big even more than 50 subset
covered the whole city with uh
High Mobility
however the normally
normally the CPS
don't deploy igp
so operator needs some way to this
distribute
the i76 locators dynamically to simplify
the configuration
next page
uh
the basic idea is that
the device
or the dhccp server treat the siber 6
locator as
the IPv6 prefix
uh then the
dgcp server can allocate sr6 locator as
the prefix
next page
here is some basic format of the i76
seat
there may be two cans of seeds
the original original seed format
defined in IFC 8986
uh the locator
like IPv6 prefix
the locator of the
comprised sr6c
is separated to two parts
located block and locate a node
one DHCP server allocate the locator
uh the structure
was a
post-original seat and a comprised the
seed should be covered
next page
uh
according to
the
comments last meeting
we introduced a new
uh identify
uh Association for the i76 locator
the structure
is showing in this figure
next page
uh
under the new IA we Define
the iae as RS6 locator
options field
uh which will be used to specify the
srv6 located
as a figure should the post original and
the comprised
s760 the structure are covered
next page
the uh
encapsulated format of the new IA
as you need the thicker
and I a Sr V6 locator option
may appear only
have IE as rb6 locator option
uh more than one I8 i76 locator option
you can papaya in a single uh I I cyber
six locator option
so it's similar to the
IPv6 prefix
X page
so here
uh
we will provide two application
scenarios
first is
what works as
a dgcp
server
um the behavior
we choose here
it will
allocate
locator subnet prefix
from the prefix poll and then generate
the locator sum item
router locally and distribute the local
subnet
router to other Athletics note so it's
very simple and next page
the
second scenario
is that the brass
works as
EGC pv6 release agent
so the behavior is also very simple it
is really DHCP
v6pd allocation messages
generate the locator seven item
routine locally
and distribute the locator prefix
routine to other rp6 node
so it's very simple next
so here we choose uh what we have
updated
compared to the origin of the revision
[Music]
uh a lot of them
so fortunately we Define the new IA
option
inside of
using the option in the IE prefix option
the second day
point is that we Define
IA i76 locator option to specify
a Services located
associated with our I as I was six
located
so
it's a uh just a
scene with the comments received the
last meeting
next page
so uh we are seeking for the comments
in DHCP working group
as well in the spring working group
in fact
we hope to apply a slot in Spring
working group also in this meeting
we have not
got it
we will
try to contact the chairs of the Supreme
working group to see if we can
look for some slot next time
so any question or comments
yeah um one of them is a procedural
question have you presented at Spring
about this yet
what is the status of the spring working
group with this document
so no uh we we have another priority in
Spring and uh
uh we send the
uh request to the working group of
chairs before the meeting but we did not
get a slot maybe we need some further
message exchange with the spring group
and shares
okay yeah I mean I think we definitely
need to do some coordination we don't we
don't want to make this option if the
spring group has no interest in
and making this work so I I think we
would need to see some interest on the
spring working group before we would do
anything more with this document
um another question I had about this one
was I didn't see what to do if the when
they send out the solicit if they get
multiple answers back from different
servers I don't know if you want to
write some text about that I know in
this case it's probably not normal with
B Razz's but it's definitely possible
so that might be something you want to
consider adding to the document is what
brows should do if it gets more than one
of these IA sr6 locators and how it can
choose or how it deals with that whether
it sends them all down or how that's
dealt with more than one server answers
it I didn't see that anywhere in the
document I could have been wrong but
that might be something for you to
consider
um as well
yeah I think you are corrected and we
should considered multiple uh
locator of multiple other options I
think we can add some text as you just
mentioned uh after the meeting and then
uh generator new Revision in the uh at
the same time I do think
the spring work group
is not interested in
this draft I think this draft day is
very useful for operators
we may try to send some email to uh
swimming working group
to trigger some discussion on that I
think this is a very interesting topic
for the spring guys
foreign
responsible LED for DHC
I fully second Tim's point we need to
get interest in Spring to use this
document before spending valuable time
of this working group on this so
it's very important to get support from
the spring looking group and from the
chair of the spring working group
sure we will uh try to trigger some
discussion there thank you
okay
um I think that's everything I have
so yeah get some I guess our feedback is
talk to Spring see if you can get
interest there and then come back to the
DHCP working group and we'll continue to
work with you on this
okay well thank you very much
thank you
hey Eric Jen's up I'm sorry for the late
foreign
one second everybody online Jen is in
another meeting and so we told her at
the end but we're running super fast
today so we're about 10 minutes before
she was supposed to go
so hopefully she'll come in here a
second
no you're perfect we literally just the
slide just appeared
uh
hello
uh I think I know almost everyone right
I'm Jen next slide please
so we're talking about
how to use dhcpv6 to record and
addresses which were not assigned by the
HTTP V6 quick recap to what Warren said
last time in Philadelphia so the usual
scenario is yeah you have slack or even
statically assigned addresses Jose using
it but some administrators prefer to use
dhcpv6 as a kind of
uh login system so they could easily
find out who was using what so it would
be nice if they might want to have all
the information in one place so they
could look it up for troubleshooting
forensics whatever like I want to know
yeah what what particular device was
saying in that particular traffic
so there was a link to the slides and
obviously there is a video of really
nice presentation by Warren so next
slide
so yeah next slide so what we've done in
the last few months
we try to address feedback received on
the list I do hope we address
most if not all of it so let's go
straight
so we clarifying how the registration
message supposed to be sent first of all
we're saying that it must be sent from
an address being registered that would
help on infrastructure which has some
form of layer 2 security Savvy to
prevent spoon so you cannot register
something you do not own well in IPv6
especially in slack own means a lot of
things but at least you kind of
responding to ND for that address
which also implies that you cannot
register multiple addresses in one
message so it's going to be a message
per address
secondly host sends that message from
the inter through the interface which
has that address so if you have multiple
home hosts with multiple interfaces we
need to make sure we are sending it to
the right place
and well obviously we signed and create
four addresses which are not provided by
the xcpv6 which means slack or
statically configured that the changes
next slide please
okay that was about sending now
receiving some clarification on how to
validate a registration message
I learned something I did not know there
is already definition for address being
appropriate for a link which kind of
means the DHCP server needs to know
something about topology so basically we
kind of the server should validate that
the host is supposed to have that
address so if you are on v1x with that
slash 64 you should not be sending
something completely ridiculous in the
registrator message
so what to do when the server receives
this the whole ID basically let's log it
let's keep it somewhere so administrator
could look it up later
so the server is supposed to log it
somehow
and draft currently says should Mark
addresses unavailable and do not offer
it
actually is that the question to the
audience
should we have shoot here on May because
it kind of requires additional
capabilities for the hcp server besides
just login so it's a kind of going
slightly more further not just let's
track addresses
next slide please
retransmits ah we now actually have
is it sub the dated slides but anyway
that's it uh retransmit so prop oh yeah
proposed approach which is currently in
the draft and I'll talk about another
option which we are discussing as well
so just send and packets by default
three with some delay between them
preferably jittered
and let administrator to change those
variables if they don't like it
so why we are not I can because there is
no real point of having acknowledged
because initially you still can't rely
on that right uh we deploy this on the
client and most likely the server would
not support it in the wild so you don't
know if the server does not support it
or it's just not hacking it
next slide please
so for refresh you registered it like
three three packets in three seconds
but obviously you need to kind of remind
the server that you are still alive
so again proposed solution is to send
the message either when one third of
valid lifetime in initial Pio so when
you create an address you go to Pio look
in the valid Lifetime and send the timer
or because by default valid lifetime is
like a month
uh let's use four hours like a Magic
Number Warren thinks it's a magic number
well as good as anything else
and yeah original Pio is Lifetime is
critical because you might get a
a subsequent arrays with different
lifetime
so it might you might get into
situations when you never sent an update
because it keeps changing otherwise
you're also like getting them in the
past
and refresh messages should better
transmitted using the same logic and
messages in 10 seconds next slide please
however
I like being it right here we've had a
lot of discussion in the lobby so there
is another proposal which is not in the
draft but Bernice I think suggested it
on the list yeah
so let's use standard DHCP
retransmission logic with exponential
back off
and actually if you're backing it off up
to one hour or four hours whatever magic
number we want to put here it basically
automatically takes care of refreshing
so you just start changing it faster and
then you slow down and then you send it
every hour or four hours or whatever
then we don't need to separate refresh
from initial retransmits
and we're also probably
minimize the chances of packet being
lost
so again think about it I don't know I
don't have strong opinions on what which
is better it just but remember this
option is not in the text yet it just
okay next slide please
yeah so this is probably the main
changes done since Philadelphia so as I
said to
like questions here it's about rear
transmit strategy also about here shall
we stop giving the registered address to
anything else and by the way another
idea came up the hcpv4 has
uh inform message so maybe this should
be called not registration but in form
and besides that the authors would like
the working group to consider adoption
if there are
no
objection strong objections sir that's
it questions comments yep we got some
people in line go ahead Eric here first
Eric clivia Cisco
yeah I have a couple of concerns with
this the first one released on the
principle
I I feel like if you want the HTTP to
know about your address
just has for an address and they will be
a lot simpler than uh
generating your address and then
registering it and you won't need to
have I mean yet another mechanism
I I see one exception to to that I would
be link locals but I mean you never talk
about link Lookers I guess you don't
want to register link it clearly states
global address valid address
so uh so that was kind of my first uh uh
concern
should I follow with the next one or
yeah
please
so I well after that assuming you really
want to go with that
at least try to make the protocol right
and in particular you know you you know
that well everyone in this room is using
Wi-Fi everyone in the world is using
Wi-Fi sending multicast over Wi-Fi is
extremely harmful Upstream I
do you have comments on this I guess
Upstream it should not be so bad
extremely
Upstream Upstream you're sending from a
client Upstream you don't get multicast
Downstream which probably it really
depends where your relay or server is
right so so you assume that that your
affiliary or your server is never going
to be on Wi-Fi uh
Wi-Fi
speakers
I know I did
yeah yeah I didn't see the reply yeah
so it looks and and in particular the
draft also States well that's the only
uh message in DHCP that's not going to
work with
request reply always you know it does
not require acknowledge it looks to me
would be a lot more efficient
if you just send your registration
and get your uh acknowledgment basically
or some sort of acknowledgment which by
the way could also tell you that the
DHCP server has you know you somewhere
it mentions that there could be a an
issue on the server
with the link not being adequate
there are some more cases right where
where the DHCP server is not going to be
able to register your address
uh first of all uh clarifying questions
in this case again we cannot rely on
acknowledgment because it's quite
possible that DHCP server does that
support that stuff right so what I'm
supposed to do if I'm not getting an
acknowledgment and how it's different
from not having acknowledgments at all
that not well if you don't get an
acknowledgment then you are back to
eventually be transmitting couple of
times which you are going to do anyway
and that's the end of the story it's not
worse but if you get an acknowledgment
then you are saving quite a bit of
messages
well with the exponential book of
probably not so many but yeah I guess uh
I don't know I don't feel strongly about
that yeah so we definitely can consider
that I don't think it's a like
critical here yeah and and yeah my last
point was
um if the the client is getting a
temporary address which is quite common
these days it would be nice to release
the address when it's done with it
rather than you know relying on the fact
that it doesn't feel fresh after a third
of the life cycle
you say release like as I did it is we
ah you mean when you get rid of Sandy
yeah when the client's done with the
address essentially
yeah
all set okay 10 year
so a couple things
um one I actually agree with the uh uh
point about acknowledgment I think
there's no real downside to
acknowledging you know it just you know
you get the acknowledgment you stop
transmitting if you don't you don't
um so it seems like a useful thing and
also it gives people an incentive to
actually put a server there that's going
to listen
and acknowledge
um I don't really care a whole lot about
releasing but you know it is
a nice little cleanup there was one
thing I it was a couple it was one of
the early slides and I can't remember
exactly what the point was could we go
back
um one more
uh
yeah
um
so I mean one way to
well one thing that occurs to me is a
way to make this a little bit more
um
so
actually it was I think it was a slide
before this sorry
um
yeah so um so this thing about sending
one message for Iana I mean
we're probably going to have like
especially if we're doing temporary
addresses we're going to have like a
fair amount of of churn here it might
actually be nice to say that that
um you know we send a message it's like
a DHCP and form style message and we ask
for some information about how to how to
communicate with the server using TCP
and then do that instead of doing like
all these multicasts I mean it's true
that we should probably not be sending
multicast to the to the Wi-Fi but it's
not clear that that's always going to be
the case particularly if you're in a
home network or something like that I
don't know what the home network is
going to do with a multicast so it'd be
kind of nice if if
um if there are a way to uh to make the
communication be unicast
um and it doesn't seem like it's that
hard a problem and then like doing this
suddenly just becomes a non-problem it
was this that kind of triggered me to
think about that I mean I don't know how
important this is but it just sort of
feels to me like it'd be better to do
these with unicast if you could and it
seems like you could I mean but just to
clarify unique costs instead of
multicast but the idea of one pay get
power in a is like prevents pushing yeah
yeah exactly so that's why I mentioned
TCP because if you use TCP you get the
three-way handshake so you know you
actually have a real thing there
okay so as I mean you still would need
to send one request your address because
otherwise I can establish a TCP session
using address which I have and register
25 different addresses which are
actually done correct right but but it's
it's pretty low-key if you're using TCP
to do these registrations one per
address whereas if you're if you're
using UDP and you're using multicast
then potentially depending on the
network it could actually be problematic
so it just seems like it would be lower
lower key
um and you know I think it you know
we're talking about inventing something
new here and also you know if you don't
get back an answer saying yes I can I
can accept these things then you're done
right you basically only have to do this
for one message like your message is
going to be high I want to be able to
registration can I do that and you only
have to do that once
like or that is to say there you don't
have to do that you don't have to
multiply it by the number of addresses
you have you're just going to do it for
any given interface you can only send
one
so interesting I need to think about it
yeah thanks yeah I'm not sure how
important it is it just sort of felt
like a thing
yeah
no no this would be Greenfield but you
know we're it we're adding we're adding
new capability anyway so it's not like I
mean there's a reason why DHCP does what
it does with
um with um
uh with with multicast right and the
reason it uses relays the way it does
but this is kind of a different
situation if we can establish the link
to the DHCP server then that gets us our
topology information we know where the
client is coming from we could even send
an identifier with that information and
then the TCP connections could all
include the same identifier so now the
DHCP server knows where you're located
maybe it's this case maybe just build
the completely new service which like
accepts registrations PCP and like yeah
it doesn't have to be DHCP right you
just have a client yeah
well no the reason I suggest TCP is
because you get the three-way handshake
so you yeah
yeah but you can get that you can get
that on the Discover right your discover
you're trying to discover the service
with DHCP so you get the line ID there
okay right here
yeah I just want to add a quick point if
if we are going to do Acts or some sort
of acknowledgment from the server it
could also be useful to have uh like a
Boolean just business to like yes I am
using this I'm locking it please keep
sending this when your address changes
or no I'm not using this so you don't
need to do the every four hours resend
or send it again when you if you don't
do this you can just say quiet
but if you stay quiet then you have to
keep resending it because you don't know
if it's been dropped or if they're not
using it so you can just it can be
optional not required obviously so but
it could just an optional hey I
acknowledge I received this but I'm not
going to use it
um because I have nothing to do with
implementions of stuff I have a question
how much complexity we are already like
willing to add for this well because
login a message is just one thing with
some minimal validation versus billion
causes State machine and other stuff I
have again
fine with either option because I don't
have to do this but yeah I don't I don't
feel strongly about the acknowledgment
but if that's being added I think that
could be an extra useful feature so
thank you I guess someone taken minutes
right
yeah
thanks
tell them I just wanted to I just wanted
to add something to this which is that
um so if you um
now it's shot out of my head uh sorry
um so we're talking about uh
it's
uh right so so if the server uh if
you're if you're sending the message to
the server
um and the server oh right yeah this was
the thing um so so one of the problems
that we have with with this current spec
is that you could have a DHCP server on
the link but it doesn't support this
message and so it doesn't reply to it
right on the other hand if we do the
Discover thing that I suggested that
could be done in a DHCP in form and now
you get an act back you're always going
to get an act back it might not have the
information you need if it doesn't that
means it's not supported info request
yeah whatever DHCP before yeah the
details details so so that that would
actually that would actually allow you
to optimize out a lot of Transmissions
um because you're gonna you're gonna get
back that information that says yeah
this just isn't supported on the network
and you probably want to retry every so
often
just to make sure that it hasn't
suddenly become supported but that makes
things a little cleaner
except Suresh Europe
okay thanks um so there's two things I
think like you know Eric you had a
really good point right like about the
um you know the uh ability to kind of
stop at some point right uh one thing
this is this is supposed to be a best
best effort mechanism right like you
know the idea would be to kind of keep
it simple and say hey I'm forming an
address with Slack
I want to try to see if somebody wants
to log this right because in most cases
it's not going to be recorded like you
know in home networks and stuff like
that it's not going to happen right so
it's going to be a managed Network
that's going to use this right so that's
one thing uh but the second thing was
like
um
yeah it sounds like Tuesday already
so what was the last thing you said Eric
no Eric Eric Levy uh
exactly Okay so uh good one thank you
thanks uh Lorenzo so I think the problem
exists with or without this right so if
you have temporary addresses like it's
going to fill up a neighbor cache at the
router right like so if we have a way of
clearing it I think it's a really good
idea no matter whether or not like it's
done here or not it's something we can
do because if somebody is saying I'm
Gonna Give You X
addresses per node right and like you
know it's never getting clear then I
think this is a good way to clear it and
saying like I'm done with it right I
think that could be a good thing to kind
of follow up
uh actually speaking of multicast if
like where shark on my machine now
amount of neighbor Discovery multicast
packet sent by a host
will probably will like much higher than
what we see in in this case anyway so
like I'm just yeah I'm fine I just said
can we actually not adding too much of
multicast here comparing to all other
things UIC and right like
like if you have V6 only Network and
host doesn't know about that amount of
our multicast stuff it's saying you can
get just ridiculous anyway
yeah so for them I think for there's a
very important distinction between the
ND cash size and this this is uh
received by the server committed to a
log or not and then it doesn't need to
be kept whereas the ND cache does need
to be kept so I don't know that this is
the right actually message type to like
clear the MD cache right and the ND
cache also does lru and it needs to
forget about stuff whereas the logging
is if you use this for forensics
purposes you have to keep it forever
right or at least until you rock log
rotation period expires so I I think the
only question there Lorenzo would be is
if you Market unavailable
that would be keeping state in the
server right yes if you had um but you
know like in theory dad will take care
of that because you know we have this
problem today with slack and hpv6 where
in theory like the dhpv6 server can hand
out whatever it wants and anyone can
form slack with whatever on some of them
I totally agree I guess my point is if
you're going to do a should here I think
you'd have to clean it up because the
servers yeah I guess we can say amazing
because if we put shoot and then you
start talking about it and they're like
yeah
yeah if you're having the DHCP server
keep track of anything you're going to
want to clean it so on the release
actually that is what I like one thing I
want to say is like yeah we we try to
make this as simple as possible also too
and you know particularly also to ensure
that like you know it wasn't a barrier
to implementation on the release I'm not
like sure I understand how it would work
because like the server needs to un like
needs to obviously Time stuff out when
when like because like clients can just
disappear right and so if it doesn't do
that then it runs out of space you know
like basically and the other thing is so
I'm not sure what a release would
accomplish like you basically like save
like maybe one message
uh but that's it really because you do
still have to refresh it while you're
still there yeah from a forensics
perspective I would assume it would let
you know when something left right to be
honest practically I don't know how
often actually privacy extensions
expires versus client dropping off the
network going home coming back next day
with different privacy I just don't have
data because I would expect I don't know
what's the what's the Privacy extensions
lifetime like at 24 hours yeah yeah not
so many clients actually stay in for
like some snow but there's another you
know there's another obviously issue
with sending the releases that like you
if you have to send it from The Source
address that you're currently that
you're not using you have to do that
before you release it but but I guess we
could I mean it would also like um
require an additional message type so I
I really think about it I really yeah
I'm really not sure about the trade-off
here but yeah it's not opposed to adding
release it's just I'm not sure it's that
useful yeah yeah yeah yeah
so everything without any yet not even
the head of somebody we've reviewed the
draft right so I didn't read it he said
the slides so
release I think it's it's nice to have
it it may mean in the in the locks
because if you see this address coming
up later you know something fishy has
happened but anyway
my point is more that why are you asking
proposing this only for the end points
you say you rely on the Layer Two And
The Savvy switches
they also know the mapping between the
IPv6 address appearing at some point of
time they don't get a duid of course
right I don't know what so send this
information from service switches
would be useful as well uh you know what
I I
try to say this is the draft is not a
silver ballet we post to be a single
source of information about all
addresses used in the network especially
if you start talking about forensics
perspective right ideally what you have
you have this you have your neighbor
cash entry from routers you have your
Savvy information all together will give
you a reasonably full picture about
what's going on right so
um doing it from the switches well I
guess you get this information from
switches it's much better way like
streaming Telemetry and other stuff
right
I guess right it will simplify the
operation on the network because you get
a single source of Truth as you say to
the HTTP if all the switches doing savvy
are implementing this and the release
then is is clear right
oh maybe
what Eric might be saying is like just
have just let's say in the draft that
switches can send this on behalf of
clients that don't implement this right
I I think that that's yeah that's why I
say you don't think you understand but
and that's I think it's okay except
technically as worded that the address
has to come the message has to come from
the source address and so the switch
would have to spoof it but maybe it's
okay uh yeah maybe it would put it in a
relay message right I don't know yeah uh
wait are we talking about DHCP clients
on switches now
are you going to be
younger people
yeah something to think about
um okay so two minutes left good job um
the only thing I'm gonna add is this is
a DHCP participant I would definitely
use the DHCP retransmit timer having
tested boatloads of clients they barely
get that right I think adding another
one would be
problematic at best would be my advice
but you you do what you want but I I'm
sort of with Bernie on that computer
smart people and suggestions yeah that's
why we're here
yeah so it's basically eight that's why
we put it on the slides uh because we
realize it might be better hiding yeah
okay so um yeah I think we can do
there's a lot of interest in this draft
so I think we should do an adoption call
we'll do it on list thank you very much
yeah thanks everybody
Okay so
here we are at the end
um a couple of things just to remind
everybody please work in group adoption
calls for I think we're gonna do one for
that draft and for we've already have
one going for 8415 please respond on
list if you can that would be great
um there are some chats also I see now
sorry Vicky in the chat room about that
draft too that Jen you guys should go
take a look at
um okay
all right that's everything
okay um I'll see you guys all in Japan
in March and thank you
bye everybody online
yeah I won't
yeah the chat's on you can go to the
chat anyway it's on Zulu
yourself
all right
come on
Spotify