tomorrow
please
yeah
okay but you're the ones who will be
saying
okay I'm fine again I don't want this to
be all wants it is okay
each other
s
I will sure
hold on
click on that then you can enter a time
and for sure
yeah
it's fine okay
okay yeah
all right
good morning and welcome to the folks in
the room good morning good afternoon
good evening wherever you are to the
folks on remote this is dnsop at ietf
115.
and we should probably go ahead and get
started
okay
hello welcome welcome group
um well team is remote but he sent his
regards of course and he will be
presenting the document updates
yeah they just sent a cute picture of
his dog exactly we can't
it's a good tradition here
um the chairs myself
Suzanne Tim
our area director Warren he's here in
the room
the chat room we have of course the
jabber room but also integrated in the
meter Echo and zulip so there are the
links in the reference
the minutes uh Paul Maybe yeah and Tim
will be back up or vice versa so Tim
will also take notes together thanks
okay so we're an ITF working group so
the node well applies here everything
you contribute mentioned at the
microphone will be recorded as part of
the of is the node will applies to your
work in your contributions
so we we expect that you're aware of the
node well
part of the node well is the IDF conduct
kind of sorry code of conduct
um well there are six points here
mentioned uh summary be respectful to
each other
if you think
code of conduct is violated please reach
out to the dean sub chairs
the meeting tips we are in hybrid
meeting so everybody in the room is
asked also to register
find the the meet Echo light client you
can scan the quad code
or just use the the full client
um also we are asked or it's ITF policy
here at ITF 115 to wear masks at any
time except for the presenters here are
allowed to take off their mask
other things for especially for the
people in the room the on-site if you
want to go to the my queue use the mid
Echo light app or the mid Echo app raise
your hand and then you are asked to come
over to the microphone
so it's equal for the remote
participants good
we go now to the agenda
we just have the blue sheets
note well
dream will give us an update of ongoing
work
the hackathon update traditionally part
of the chair slide is now moved to
current working group business so there
will be an update of the hackathon but
not here now
but in the regular agenda
after the working group business the
current working group business we have
for consideration and type of time
permitting presentations the agenda is
also published on data tracker
good Tim can I ask you to give the
document updates
yes oh yeah good morning all and thanks
for thanks for being here so we'll we'll
kind of go through this because I know
we have some busy stuff as you know in
the isgq
um 5933 Biz which is scheduled for the
teletracker I believe in uh January in
December
um and catalog zones which has warrants
as the action but I think they need an
update from the authors
um so authors I know you're there you
may have to
step up a little bit and do that but
everything else is moving along for
those
um
avoid fragmentation has been approved
and Ben and I are going to work on the
write-up on that
um
and we'll we'll sort of Chase that down
here very shortly so next slide
um things are moving along on some of
this
um of course in the editor queue service
B
um I think it's going to go for a record
and sort of sitting and the DNS type BCT
which is in there too which it looks
like it's been moving pretty fast so
fast so thanks for all for sort of
chewing on that chair on that so
um next slide next slide we've got a
bunches that are kind of so we have one
more than we have last call
the audio what's what's starting quite
well but it becomes worse and worse oh I
was afraid that I was afraid of that
um
well then um
because for some reason the audio uh
becomes worse and worse
how I turned it off in background is
that better oh oh much better thing oh
interesting thanks for that you're
sitting besides me almost so it's
excellent
um my big comment here on validator
requirements is we need more comments
from the working group to sort of move
these documents along and so we're we
get stuck and so the three of us have to
go chase down
um reviewers or or people to sort of you
know thumbs up thumbs down
um is there anybody in the room that's
against moving this the working group
last call please speak up
um or we'll consider that the working
request call approval
um and we can move on from there I know
we have one comment from Brian that
needs to be addressed
um so and we will get that address from
Daniel
um and part of the reason we're
expecting moving documents as long as
we're not we need more help from working
here on that
um yeah Tim
yes Tim yeah
so I'll
I'll I just that was all really the
comment I'd like to just get more folks
on the working group last call
um
to sort of help us get those things
moving along and I'll kick over to benno
then and I apologize me Deco seems to be
hating me this morning
thank you thank you
okay so oh sorry
um Jeff Houston yeah responding to the
previous slide please yes
um I think it's pretty sad that we're
moving a document into working group
last call with only one comment
and yeah the thing that's kind of
changed is of course there's now a DNS
directorate and as chairs I believe you
have the ability to actually request
an early review by a member of the
directorate and so one of the ways to
actually resolve this is rather than go
oh working group last call even though
no one has read it evidently is to
actually throw it at the directorate at
this point and ask for an early review
to see if it should proceed just a
thought
thank you Jeff
yep yeah thank you Jeff that's actually
really helpful um to have the reminder
that the 80s have spun up the DNS
directorate and that is another resource
we have as far as managing our documents
thank you I agree Jeff yep I agree and
Jeff why don't you take we give you the
action item of of asking for a review of
this one how's that you're now in charge
um this is Jeff I can assign a reviewer
but I kind of signed a document for
review I don't have that magic power in
the data tracker I think chairs or
someone can do that that bitter it's an
it's an area director thing so and I'm
sure there's an area director there
who's qualified to push those buttons we
will sort the buttons we'll sort the
buttons offline thanks
okay oh
so oh so
other current uh working group documents
um we think an author think is close to
working group last call
so not just any specific order here we
see blue note is not optional the RFC
84.99 base there's now discussion on two
terminology yes at the the belly wig I
think that discussion is
uh Billy Victor historical is well had
some replies but especially uh defining
glue
does see some discussion very good thank
you so we need to
take this discussion further to the
mailing list
preferably finishing up in one or two
three weeks but limited and then we can
make forward progress with both
documents
all TLD will be presented in a minute or
in five minutes
[Music]
um
the Nissan version uh the authors think
they Incorporated all the feedback from
the mailing list
they think it's ready for working group
last call
we will schedule it and please have a
second look at the document and give
feedback on the mailing list
and Dinesh error reporting my good
progress and will be presented later
this this session
so we're making good progress overall
um
we just just had a meeting with the
author of dinosaur oh sorry
dinasek bootstrapping I think the author
also think it's ready for working group
last call
the Incorporated a number of uh the
feedback from the working group there
was some discussion
so we also probably want to make
progress here I will discuss it also
with the author
and as revalidation
it will be some other authors helping
with the document because some one of
the authors has another job in other
priorities
uh rights
more work unisec automation that one uh
there will also be in another author or
author should be added to the document
it's in good shape maybe another
revision and we'll also ask for a
working group last call from the from
the working group
the domain verification techniques uh
will be up will be presented and updated
if time permitting let's put it on the
agenda yesterday
and caching resolution failures will be
presented so all in all uh yeah we make
a good progress with the documents
they're either close to working group
law or making good progress so thank you
and just adopt that SVC bit svcb Dane
um no well I will skip these slides
these are possible candidates for
adoption new work in the working group I
will reach out to some of the documents
authors
because it didn't have much attention on
the mailing list yet but there's big
continuous development in updates of the
documents so it should get more
attention of the working group or by the
working group
good
our work is also on data tracker of
course and on GitHub so check the the
links if you want to get the latest
updates or interact with us or with the
authors
this agenda I'll have somewhere okay
well this is
the current agenda for the working
current working group yeah I will yeah I
will go over the slides it's not so for
consideration we have three
presentations and if time permitting
other work has priority but if time
permitting we have these two
presentations at the very end of the of
the session
we can start let's get started I will
load the next slide here so you do the
introductions
oh sorry this is next
one right yeah
okay yeah so um we had a lot of
discussion on the mailing list both on
the process and the substance around the
all TLD draft and the goal today you
know where we gave it we're giving it a
strictly limited time
and a strictly limited scope
but Paul has uh very graciously agreed
to come up and and speak to
are there open issues that will benefit
from further discussion um we've the
chairs and editors have discussed what
seemed to be contentious issues the the
chairs posted some concerns
on the list and that I believe you know
have been addressed in the current draft
um if it seems we do have open issues
that could be closed by further
discussion we'll schedule an interim or
some other way of dealing with those
but if it seems we've said everything
and Views are not likely to change
further we will move to working group
last call
um thanks everybody for your patience
and we will we are getting this this
draft towards uh
resolution of one kind or another so
Paul if you wouldn't
uh just a very quick note Rob Wilton
who's sitting over there is the
responsible ad for this not me
because Warren is a co-editor the the
rules we all operate under mean that he
can't be also the A.D that that oversees
it's it's movement in the process so
thanks for that reminder Warren
so given that
um I'm gonna do
a mediumly brief presentation chairs are
going to run a mic line if there are
people who want to say things that
haven't been said on the list or new and
such and a new deck is being shared
yeah
indeed
give me one minute because come find it
now
foreign
it's overwritten sorry
excuses I already checked everything but
Victor
I see Victor and the queue Victor would
you Victor are you going to
proceed this
I don't know it's in the data tracker
but
on Mid Echo
did you click the refresh probably I
need to refresh yeah oh I updated the
slides this morning yeah
but um
my own
you are on Victor yes okay uh
right so if there's a quick spot uh the
the similar somewhat dot home TLD has
has a few hints for validators to try
and reduce leakage of traffic I was
wondering whether anything like that
should be said for an adult like you
know returning you know proof of
non-existence of BS while not sending
any other queries so I'll sort of cover
that but since alt is not going to be in
the root Zone
that doesn't seem possible to do
uh
you can still return proof of
non-existence off the whole domain which
includes proof of the existence of its
DS so it seems to work
I'm not index domain sure how you would
do that for a zone that doesn't exist
maybe send that to the list the the
insect records prove it's non-existent
that's dnsic for you
all right
you want me to share it yeah please
please because hopefully it works right
oh wow we're letting Warren take over
well the pro yeah the problem is that
it's listed in the um manifest but it
does not appear to actually but in the
meat Echo IDC uh twice the the chair
slides
explain it
somebody has to actually brought me
sharing oh you need to Grant Warren
shareability yes
you should have it now
this is very weird
chair sites
yeah same for me
yes
Maybe
are those the ones oh no that's
Suzanne's oh it might have been that two
things were named similarly but
shouldn't be
similarly but not this not right okay
all right the other thing we could do is
go on to the next agenda item you figure
it out
again Warren wants permission again
I did
you should have it
we're looking at Orange slides down it's
still saying shared so yeah
okay I guess
yeah okay
thank you
thank you that went more easily than I
thought it would
wow this is yeah this is new on me
um with apologies
um
so Roy was next
shows yes
actually if Roy Ahrens isn't here yes
yes but I will oh you were doing okay
yeah I uh okay
yeah so actually uh DNS error reporting
will be the next slide sets and also uh
hackathon results
because
DNS error reporting was a major Topic at
what we worked on during the hackathon
uh there were five in-person persons
working on it and one remote
and uh yeah
so uh Roy asked me better were also some
other uh projects worked on so what I
said why don't you present those other
two and then I'll do the hackathon
visuals for DNS air reporting
um
so uh next slide yes so uh indeed one of
the projects was working on netina's
resolver inbound
so nothing is uh is a bill DNS Library
works on primarily by dick Franks and
Dick told me once if it's nice weather
he goes out plays golf and if it's rainy
then he works on nattiness
and uh
he lives in London so it rains quite
often and
but nothingness is actually a early
adopter of many of the stormers that are
drafted index up so
uh worthwhile to to look at if you want
to compare it with your own
implementation or to see how it's uh how
your draft draft is implemented
uh so we worked on a uh uh bindings for
nutinas with lip inbound and that
involved adding some new uh functions to
lip and mount to synth packets directly
so this is not quite finished but it's
coming
next slide please
and the other interesting hack we did
besides the initial reporting is
implementation of handling of encrypted
client hello in a proof of concept
Library called connect by name
so
um
the server name indications is one of
the holes in the Leaky privacy boat that
leaks the the name to which TLS session
is set up and encrypted clients hello is
the solution to make that private as
well
so we have this uh proof of concept
library that sets up connections and
under the hood does everything but it's
good right happy eyeballs Dane you can
specify policies to say I want all the
DNS lookups to be opportunistically
private or authenticated privates
and uh yeah so Philip Holmberg worked on
that
uh for the library looking up svcb and
https records and using the encrypted
client hello configuration parameter to
set up
uh the encrypted clients hello with this
with this one server we know that
support is which is default.io
and filipio also later in this session
talk about the uh
policy uh uh uh option that is also a
part or came out of the connectpoint
name projects and next slide please
yeah for you
so uh yeah as we we have a really good
time so I think it's also for other
people working on drafts good to
participate in the hackathon if not for
the importion uh or the direct feedback
on uh
uh your drafts then uh for for the foot
because it was amazing
and we also learned that DNS error
reporting rocks
next slide
so this is these are all the people that
uh worked on it I see there's one name
missing we also had a remote participant
on Cape
and next slide Roy is going to take over
to talk about the initial reporting
thank you sorry thanks William
um I'm Roy Adams
um I'm one of the two authors for DNS
error reporting
um where are we um just smart
introduction
DNS air reporting builds upon extended
DNS errors
um it reports to the operator of an
authoritative domain instead of
reporting back to the client that's what
rc8914
um is useful to begin with
um the resolver where a small change I
will get to that in a minute the
resolver now indicates support for
reporting
um the authoritative Sheriff had then
sends an agent domain in an IDI in his
zero option
sorry I'll take this off eating a zero
option alongside
um a regular response and then the
resolver sends errors to the report
receiving agents format is actually DNS
query
it's pretty straightforward we've seen
it working during the hackathon also
during the hackathon
um folks were so enthusiastic that we
immediately thought how can we improve
this how can we make this more efficient
next next slide please
um one thing to make it more efficient
so instead of using the report instead
of usually queue type no to send a
report
and you want something back that you can
cash
initially we just had no error or any
domain caching NX domain caching is a
problem because you will cut off the
entire
um string for the the entire domain for
that but if you have a tax record if you
just
query using a text record then you can
tailor a response so you can basically
send a specific text
um record back with a TTL that is stay
loot so it can dampen the query load
accordingly
and now we also have that the resolver
must indicate support
so what we used to have is that you just
Spam with unsolicited Edina zero option
in a response every time always
um
the reason we change that is not because
um it's frowned upon to just
include unsolicited DNS option edns
options the reason for that is to avoid
later on cascading error reports over
error reports of error reports
um
so we change that another thing we um we
we changed and this is a small
optimization which is really really
handy so in the formatters query you
used to have
um the
extended DNS error as a as a label
before the domain name that was broken
it's easy to have it after domain name
um so before the underscore error if you
have read the draft and the reason for
that you have now the error code in a
consistent Place always it doesn't
change
um depending on the domain name length
depending on the remaining that's broken
all right next slide please
um we have a few implementations I'll
list them quickly um Willem who was just
up here in Unbound
um you can actually test it now
um by by going to these um open testing
resolvers
and next slide please
um we have Stefan boxmeyer Stefan had an
implementation
um he's named a drink
I hope it's an acronym otherwise it's a
really funny one
um
it's an authority server
um easily adjustable for experimentation
etc etc
um works as well
and the report processing so this is
basically the next step once you receive
the reports you can now process them and
do something about it
um next slide please
um Shane was there as well
um Shane worked on an Implement a
proprietary authoritative server called
Trax this is ns1's proprietary server
um he mentioned it was straightforward
on the authoritative side
um and you can configure unique report
receiving agents per server
next slide please
um Mark Andrews submitted a ticket for
buy nine
um I'm just going to leave you to that
I'll I'll leave it to Mark to um to come
to the mic later on to explain what it
means um I don't want to say they're
going to implement it it's basically a
ticket that says
um
have a look at this draft and maybe
um implement it in the future Tom Carpe
from home I apologize I didn't list him
in the initial slide with all the people
at the desk at the at the at the table
and Tom Carpe worked on an ldns version
a development Branch a version for for
ldns and ldns test DNS
test test NS sorry it can now easily be
used to fake an error reporting support
authoritative server next slide please
um oh yeah this is this is what I wanted
to make clear so version 03 we thought
it was stable enough
um after some experimenting we made some
optimizations not super major changes
but some optimizations so after Dash o4
comes out I haven't submitted it yet
after that comes out we'll give it a few
days a few weeks to let
um to let people read it and then we
will ask the working group chairs to
consider a working group last call
all right um if you have any questions
or suggestions
um there's of course the mailing list
yes up at itf.org
it's not really useful to to to to to
Mill me personally I'll do my best but
um your what I've noticed is that your
questions often are relevant to the
entire working group which I've got a
fair amount of feedback that's now in
the draft and better wording etc etc but
send your questions and suggestions to
the mailing list that's it thank you
thank you
um we have one question from Victor
fixer please go ahead
uh should any language appear in the
draft about validators behind forwarders
um they don't they aren't directly
talking to the auth so they can't see
these extensions
um
thank you Victor DM
um I think the question is related to
the problem of cascading errors when
when they um when a reporting resolver
forwards the broken error query in order
to get it reported to a forwarder the
forwarder might then do ediness sorry it
might might do error reporting as well
and then you get cascading error reports
now
um
one idea is to make sure that when a
domain starts with underscore ER
then don't send this option
in the um in the in the query that you
send out so don't send the edns option
in queries about error reports that's
that's one way to do it the other way to
do it if you if you're a forwarder
um
are you actually doing error detection
right I mean that's that's a question
with the forwarder if you do do error
detection you basically need to
implement the draft accordingly
so
um I will add some language into the
documents
um basically regarding forwarders or
basically clients that may not do error
reporting that may set the uh the the
reporting option thank you Victor
thank you Roy
okay
up next
yeah it looks like we have the slide
issue fixed if you're ready to try again
Paul thanks for your patience
foreign cool
next slide
okay so some people have been asking
what is the status of the draft
um the actual status I can do this
um is held by working group
um
Warren and I co-authors ask for working
group plus call shares ask for changes
we did those the chairs seem to have
accepted those changes
um there's a new draft now and then once
that newest draft came out a whole bunch
of discussion happened I'm going to be
covering the discussion here but
basically the status is we're still in
held by WG the chairs are still trying
to decide about working you know moving
it into working group last call so it's
still just a draft next
um there are two top issues and I think
probably two of the only issues that
really matter here
um this is the first one I've got two
slides on this and I've got two slides
on the second issue
um
so
basically we have this text which says
what resolvers should do when when it
comes to dot alt and the current text
basically says
treat it like anything else it's not
special some people on the list want to
make it special that is they want to put
text in this document and say resolvers
should or must do something here
um and the difference being that if the
if the text says a resolver should or
must be doing something then the hope is
that resolver operators I'm sorry
resolver vendors will read the draft go
I'm supposed to do something with this
and do it next slide
um
so
the reason for putting in a muster
should is to is to get resolver
implementations to not send things to
the root so the you know that's the only
reason to do it is to is to have an
effect the desired effect is fewer
queries will go to the root because
they'll just get swallowed by the
resolver itself
um and that has been shown to to be to
work in the past dot onion the whatever
the RFC that created dot onion says
resolvers should not send these on and
some revolvers don't some resolver
implementations don't and some resolver
implementations ignored that and they do
pass it on and and their root server
operators sitting in the room they can
look at you know how many dot onion
queries they get and such so it's
definitely not zero but if you look in
the code for some of the resolvers they
swallow dot onion
okay Paul do you want to take questions
now there's one in the queue or this is
this is totally your call and let me at
least finish this slide yeah okay but
then if you would like me to take
questions here that's fine
um
so the
um but since we know not all resolver
software I'm sorry Wes what are you
saying
keep going thank you yeah I think sorry
maybe take yourself out of the queue or
um so
um
the the the benefit is for adding this
code would be to the root servers it
does not help a resolver to have
more code in it you know more code can
always cause more errors it also doesn't
hurt as we know because this is true for
Don onion it's been true for years in a
couple of the resolver software and no
one's had any problems so really the
question is what do we want to do here
um about saying that a resolver software
should or must do something
um and then the last bullet here is the
note which is this is an informational
document which is fine but it's sort of
weird for an informational document to
tell all of the resolver operator all
the resolver vendors out there what they
should or must do
um so would you do you want to stop and
do this one first or go to the next one
okay so okay now we're switching topic
next slide
this is the second major issue that came
up on the list after we posted the last
draft
um which is some people said oh no we
shouldn't be we shouldn't be using the
current design which is just never
allocate dot alt in the root we should
allocate it and then have it Point as a
d name to as112.
um we have rfcs on that
um this was brought up five years ago
when the document was in working group
last call the first time it wasn't
accepted then but now there's a
discussion maybe we should really think
of this now
um
the reason for doing this that was
stated on the list and is backed up by
data is that it seems like resolver
implementations do better with a
delegation at caching the fact that it's
delegated then remembering that they
have a negative
um a negative uh answer in their cash so
as you can see if you go to
um that link
Dwayne has a long presentation but
basically when they dropped in a
delegation
the cash is kicked in much better so
this would this redesign would again not
help the end users but it would help
reduce traffic going to the root servers
next slide
um
so
this is not an easy fix because in fact
the whole point of this document has to
date been this TLD will never appear in
the root so when we say to somebody hey
please use this TLD you're safe to use
this TLD for all of your alternative
stuff they knew that anything that
leaked
wouldn't would never pass the root
servers that is they would come back
with an NX domain what doing as112 says
is
um we already have a set of of
um
authoritative servers that will then
include this for who always give back
the right NX domain answer
but this means that to somebody who's
writing something that might use this
they know that in fact it'll go to the
root server and then go to some other
server that's not controlled by them
that they are relying on to send an NX
domain so that's a very different
promise to the people who would be using
the dot alt domain
um it would require new agreements with
Ayanna
um but and some people said oh we can't
do it because you know you can't put
these in in the root Zone
you can make changes to what Ayanna does
it has to be you know asked officially
and stuff like that but saying this will
never happen is simply silly the ietf
gets to say what happens in the root
Zone on a technical level so that's not
an argument against it but the basic
argument against it is that this is a
complete redesign this is saying instead
of simply don't do this we're going to
design it this way and then just as a
side note Warren and I have talked about
this if the working group wants to go
for this
it needs to start as a completely new
draft because a lot of the text in the
document it would be simply wrong
that is the lot of the text in the
document is assuming this is not going
to be something in the root Zone
um and neither of us are interested in
this so if if this is what the working
group wants you're going to have to find
some new Authors to do it it's still
doable I'm not in favor of it but I'm
just one voice here and that's the last
slide so then you guys run the mic line
and you you say when not you know when
to stop
yeah um there has been quite a lot of
discussion on the list several times
over but the reason why we're doing this
is so that everybody knows where the
where the document stands now
and if there's anything you feel has not
been said or needs to be said
and again
um given where we're at and where we
have been in the discussion you know we
do have a few minutes
but this is my this is mostly sort of a
status
setting
Wes thank you Wes herediker uscisi
um uh not with my icann board hat not
with my baby hat but with my root server
operator hat because I think that's the
one you wanted right yes exactly right
um this is DNS op afterwards
so when I think about you know what
should be done so hey thank you for
putting the the document together in the
first place
um the right thing is don't send packets
to the DNS that shouldn't go to the DNS
right so don't leak yeah right don't
leak and and Dot alt is supposed to be
the switch that says don't use it
weirdly enough right but it will happen
we know it will happen I do see queries
for DOT onion I don't see a ton I don't
worry about the massive dot alt you know
queries because I don't see a massive
amount that swamps us for DOT onion that
being said don't do it so my suggestion
for the document is yeah do put in a
statement saying resolver shouldn't send
this if possible so they should know
about dot alt and not send it yeah and I
recognize that the code issue
um sure but we already have a code issue
for pre-existing stuff and again only
only I looked at all four of the the
common resolvers only two of them did
have that code in it but they already
have the code and it looked like it was
a way where they could extend the list
of what they have and so one of the
things I was going to add is we won't
get hundred percent deployment but the
reality is we shouldn't saturate the DNS
system with anything so I don't really
care about the root server system as
much because there's a lot of them I
care more about the constrained lengths
that you know maybe actually these extra
queries might actually you know affect
people way down the line or something
like that as far as it going into an
informational document it's still
guidance you know I mean the reality is
it should must are not enforceable in
standards documents either right so you
know I don't have an issue with putting
should and musk kind of information in
there before you go off to the next one
do you have a preference here for should
or must
foreign
does it really make a difference they're
either going to no no preferences a
perfectly good preference thanks I would
say should because the system's going to
operate without it right you're not
going to cause interoperability problems
if it's a should okay great so yep um as
far as 112 you know yes it it might it
probably needs to be a separate document
it could be done later
um again
it can't be done later if this is
already an RFC because this one says
shall never appear in the root Zone
we we could that the other one could
update this one to fix that statement
that's a broken promise then I I would I
would be very hesitant to be author of
this document knowing that we intended
to break the promise later
I in fact I can just say right now I
would take my name off this in a moment
if I thought that we were going to break
the promise made in this RFC later
that is fair but you so so why don't we
take this offline Paul because okay the
queue is already long but okay but we
can fight about it okay
yeah the other thing to comment on that
as far as the document status is that
it's actually currently tagged as
standards track and I believe that's
required by the registry policy
informational I believe
don't think so well what I was going to
say and that's not required uh the
requirement for 761 is either standards
track or isg approval which this would
have isg approval eventually
that's yeah that's something for the for
the chairs and the da data to sort
thanks
foreign
I don't like the idea of as112 it just
seems like a hammer for what shouldn't
actually really get to DNS in normal
working
operations I do have a question though
and this might be better for the root
operators what do we perceive as the
load increase of leakage of alt into the
normal DNS space I mean how big of a
problem is it actually in just leaving
this out in the sense that if we don't
even say should or must
um what is the actual load impact and
how much of a problem would that be if
we had that leakage
I'm not answering that one
I can switch hats long enough to answer
that one as
in my yes putting on the roots overhead
that Wes and I actually passed back and
forth the the actual impact would be
negligible it's just a matter of in
general what you get is is there there's
an awful lot of stuff that goes to the
roots that shouldn't
then we don't need to do anything really
it might be
the roots are massively over provisioned
is is sort of the right statement there
that doesn't mean that we want the
queries exactly exactly okay
so next is Elliot hi there Elliot Lear
here
um okay so uh a couple things first
thanks Paul for taking on the work
thanks Warren and thanks chairs and
working group for working through this
um as the independent submissions editor
this came to me as you saw
um through the DNS uh work and in in the
gns work depends on this work completing
and so again I thank the working group
for for working on this
um
there is we've we've had a discussion
about a second level registry you pulled
out the text there uh in the preview in
the current version only you sort of
half did that
and there is still text in the draft
that says
um that uh name service name systems
should add a unique uh field uh to the
left of dot all and I'm going to channel
Martin shenzenbach whose users said you
know
do or do not if we're not going to have
a registry and let's not have that
convention either it would be at this
point if we are going to have the
registry then let's have the register
sure absolutely send that to the list
especially with word changes you're
making it simpler thank you okay that
that's that's his point of view and I'll
just end with a third point which is
thank you again okay well again Warren
did all the work up till two drafts ago
so
is speaking as individual I just want to
say that I don't think the as12 solution
is very good because since it's not
specified what could be on the left side
of the of the alt part it could be a
three three thousand character string
and we only allow 63 on valid DNS so so
you're going to get form errors before
it would be following the D name up the
chain anyway so I think that the as112
will not catch the proper things or it
will catch things right actually has to
return form error instead of NX domain
or something so I think it's really bad
solution for this it's like the wrong
tool for this thanks
okay
Ben Schwartz hi
um on on queries to the root uh please I
I want to hear
sorry go ahead
on the topic of Aquarius to the root
the uh
I think that the right answer here is to
say that the
um from the Stubbs perspective a
recursive resolver's Behavior should not
be visibly altered by this informational
document
so while it's advantage while it's
advantageous to uh to the root for
recursive resolvers to synthesize some
responses locally for DOT alt uh and and
I think that's a good thing that
synthesis should not result in a
behavior change that's observable to the
stub resolver
uh and so what that means in my view is
that if we're going to talk about that
kind of synthesis we need to have some
very special language about how to
handle DNS sec because uh because I if I
ask the
uh if I ask my resolver whether dot alt
exists I'm asking whether or not all
exists in the root and I want a DNS set
validated I want I want the correct
signed and SEC record to tell me there's
no such thing and that can't be
synthesized locally
so uh I I don't object to local
synthesis in general but I think that uh
it's not it's not straightforward to
implement uh at a minimum you know the
simplest way to do it is to just disable
local synthesis if the do bit is set for
example
essentially what we're saying is you're
allowed to do local root
and since dot all these will never be in
the root you're also allowed to do the
special subset of local root where you
only do local route for not alt because
we guarantee that that's never going to
be in the root
um
but uh but you can't just blindly
synthesize uh NX domain responses
because you can't sign them locally
unless you are also basically doing
local Loop
foreign
I want to just make one last editorial
comment that the draft constantly uses
the has adopted the terminology
um the DNS context as uh the namespace
anchored at the Ayanna root
um I find this terminology very
confusing because DNS is a protocol it's
a protocol that anybody can instantiate
an instance of not just Diana and there
are a bunch of alt routes that
uh prior to this document have always in
my experience been described as
implementations of DNS the protocol just
not the the Ayana root so uh I I just
have trouble reading the document
because of that okay if you can send uh
suggested text on that that would that
would be helpful I think to everybody
right thank you and sorry to sorry to
step on you Ben
um we had closed the queue after
then but
um Robert Rob did get in the queue as
the responsible ID so I'm gonna you get
a special pass yes sir Robertson
um just to say thank thanks thanks for
working group for working this I know
it's a sort of contentious topic and
tricky so I get it I think we're close
to rough consensus here so I think we're
making progress so I think that's great
I love someone to say I don't know
anything about DNS but I just want to
make one comment as an individual in
terms of the the must or way state must
or should statements is saying
um is it the the stub resolver shouldn't
be sending this stuff on because
obviously you should be filtering out at
that stage and if so can we put the
constraint on that and not the recursive
resolvers is what is that one option
does that make sense that's an option
but I think that the folks who wanted it
for the recursives know that asking the
stubs not to do something is sort of
silly you know it's like saying to your
your dog you know don't do that and the
dog goes great I heard the do that part
whereas recursive resolvers we know in
fact the resolver sought vendors
actually do the right thing a lot so I
think that that was more we can also add
it in for the stubs but that that's
almost wasted text okay and I'll
absolutely defer to the experts on this
and then the end of the other point I
want to make in terms of the document
status I I'm lesser keen on the isg
approval thing that could be slightly
trickier so is the reason why this can't
go through a standards track now and if
the isg then says actually we wanted to
be informational would downgrade it is
that that's up to the working group I
think the original reason for having it
as informational is there's no protocol
in this saying don't put something in in
the root server is not really a protocol
thing it could be standards track it can
be informational should not be
experimental so in my advice I think
standards track gives it a bit more
weight as to so I think that'd be my
recommendation okay great thank you
that's for the chairs not for Warren and
I okay okay
great thank you
thank you very much
who is next
step thank you
uh and and either the the people that
were cute and well the the queue was
locked please send also your comments or
your questions to the mailing list
and next next up is Dwayne
right there we go
all right hello everyone uh so I'm here
to talk about the draft which is about
caching
um
negative caching of DNS resolution
failures
this was last presented at ietf 113.
next slide please
so as a quick reminder there are some
recursive name servers that seem to be
really really bad at caching resolution
failures or remembering that when they
asked for uh
for for resolution that they didn't get
an answer the the graph there on the
right is from the um the presentation to
this working group at ihf113 uh and
there's there's more supporting data
there so you can go look at that if you
want to but this graph in particular was
from the Facebook outage of last year
where we saw a huge increase in in query
traffic uh to the comnet name servers
during that outage
so the goal of this draft is really to
strengthen the requirements around
caching resolution failures and avoid
these sorts of unnecessary repeated
queries
so there's a little definition in in the
draft that says a DNS resolution failure
occurs when none of the servers
available uh to a resolver provide any
useful response for a particular name
type in class
so just to be clear we're not talking
about you know a timeout at one of the
name servers available we're talking
about timeouts say from all of the name
servers available or NX domain are not
sorry not NX domain refused from all of
the name servers available something
like that so next slide
uh so since the last version this is
probably the most significant change
where some of the requirements have been
rephrased previously there was there was
language in in the draft that said a
resident Evolution failure must be
cached against a specific uh query Tuple
of name type and class and server IP
address and and now that requirement is
is changed quite a bit where it just
says that a resolver must have a cache
for resolution failures and the purpose
of the cache is to eliminate repeated
queries uh that cannot be resolved so it
doesn't really you know it doesn't say
it has to be cached by Tuple that's now
sort of an implementation dependent
detail
um folks can choose how to how to do
that however they want
um and then provide some examples of of
reasons my why you might want to do it
by Tuple or my white might want to do it
by uh server IP address alone for
example
next
there's also some new text about how
resolvers should protect themselves from
possible attacks so since since there's
a requirement to Cache resolution
failures there's that sort of introduces
a new security risk where an attacker
could try to exhaust this cache uh you
know send lots of specific queries
designed to fill up this this new type
of cache and of course resolvers need to
protect themselves and and can can limit
the resources they devote to such a
resolution failure cache
next
um there's there's some text in the in
the draft about
um about timing and this is really
unchanged since the last version there
was a little bit of discussion about
this but what what the draft currently
says is that resolution failures must be
cached for at least five seconds
um and and the justification for this is
that this is the amount of time that a
user could reasonably be expected to
wait to retry or something like that
um there's a should level requirement
that the resolver should use an
exponential back off in the amount of
time that it caches these sorts of
things so you know five seconds to start
increase increase and so on but no
longer than five minutes
um and then the five minutes is uh it
matches language in RFC 2308
next
and so lastly this is this is kind of a
new uh a new thing that we would like
discussion on
um
so some implementations some resolver
implementations would have different
caches based on edns client subnet
values uh and uh
sort of open for discussion whether or
not resolution failure caching should be
should ignore edns client subnet or if
partitioning the cache by that client
subnet value would be appropriate or a
good thing to do
so
um I think our opinion is that you know
should be independent of EDS client
subnet but would like to hear what other
people think about that
and uh that's it
thank you thank you Dwayne
um in the queue beta beta Thomas
yes science Peter Thomason I think um
like a few slides earlier you showed
that um
the partitioning of the cache should be
up to the implementers
whether it would be Q name or IP address
or whatever and now this proposal seems
to contradict that a little bit Yeah
Yeah and and so the question is why
wouldn't you just leave it up to the
implementers if they think it's a good
idea or not
um yeah that's that's a fair question I
I think the argument I would make is
that
um you know if if there's an
implementation that normally has
separate caches based on eating this
client subnet that can really sort of
blow up the the size of the cache and so
there may be thousands of different
subnet values which would mean that now
uh
the resolver is is emitting maybe
thousands of more times queries than
than it needs to right so if if you're
allowed to emit one query per subnet
value per some amount of time then then
that's a lot of traffic still
a certain perhaps that concern should go
into this um protect the self section
uh Duane thanks for for doing that work
also to your um to your colleagues and
there's one minor thing the security
consideration section talks about
resource exhaustion by deliberately
asking for
um domains or cue names resulting in in
certain failures now given that most of
these resolution failures aren't
authenticated
um there's probably also an attack
Vector in forging so those responses is
that something you would consider uh for
adding to that discussion it might not
be catastrophic but it's it's a window
of opportunity as well sure yeah be
happy to add something like that thank
you
foreign
I sort of would agree that it would be
great if we could ignore edina's
clients.net but um
a lot of implementation sort of where
this would be hard and we've seen in the
wild that kind of uh depending on what
you give the authority
um sometimes the answer sometimes they
don't so
it would make the positive resolution
worse I guess
so okay so
you would vote for not saying anything
about this and just leaving it up to the
implementation to to do how they want
yeah I would leave it up to them okay
all right okay
that was the queue all right okay thank
you Dwayne thank you yeah
next is
um
I think Philip with uh rights
there we are yeah
okay
my name is Philip Humber I did this work
with Philip torup so if later you have
questions find either of us
um and this is basically about
making a try to make complexity of a
slippery solder a bit more manageable
while still letting the stop resolver be
in control next slide
um so this is when life was simple stop
resolve for censor query just out for
Port 53 and then hopefully gets an
answer back
um but then uh of course when most of
the traffic on the internet became
encrypted
um everything has stopped resolver said
queries say plain text uh it's not so
great anymore so the ITF took its Apollo
itself to create ways to solve that
backslide
um
and then we got this because one option
is fine but lots of options is always
better so we got DNS over TLS that
people about it DNS of HTTP but HTTP is
actually at the moment sort of two
protocols hp2 and hp3 and then there's a
separate uh DNS over quick and then you
can also create a nested implementation
so you get oblivious Doh
so complexity for a stop resolver is get
a completely uh out of head next slide
please
foreign
it's jumping ahead and
I think you want to have this slide I
don't know
well this
uh the next one after this yeah okay
background
um
we were working on
um a library called uh called connect by
name and the ideas you put in a name and
outcomes uh TLS collection and then does
all the happy eyeballs and Dane and
whatever
um simplifying the life of the
application and the on top of the gets
library that we have and and just doing
all of the DNS parts right sort of costs
what we wanted to Chase and get here
that's to completely explode because a
lot of this stuff is recursive if you
connect to Doh then you could also do
data whatever
um so we were looking for ways to
simplify it next slide
um
and we also notice like sort of in
general with this model
um there's quite a few stop resolvers
out there are they going to implement
all of these different transports what
if they don't
um
um UDP
to Port 53 has has basically no state if
I run Bing and it has to set up a DLH
collection to look up uh lrp at a name
and then tear it down immediately
that costs a lot of extra resources
resources are also show up on a
recursive resolver and in general you
can expect latency and stuff like that
so next slide please
um there's of course an obvious way to
solve that and that is just introduce a
local proxy and then the proxy can
maintain those connections for a longer
period of time so so it becomes more
efficient and there's plenty of those
proxies already around so there's a lot
of people who have a local inbounds uh
they're stubby more designed as a proxy
there's TNS mask has been allowed for a
long time and there's a systemd Softee
that tries to do several things
um next slide please but the problem
there is that the application now is
talking to a complete Black Box it's
like well what if the application would
really insist on having some sort of a
private collection privacy preserving
collection to recursively software if
you talk to a local proxy you just don't
know
um maybe an application has very
specific desires like it it's really
about to have a Doh collections to a
specific public resolver or something
like that
um
what kind of feedback do you get from
the proxy if it fails I mean you just
get the software usually I guess if if
the collection to the Upstream recursive
resolver fails and also for diagnostic
tools if if your deck or drill or
whatever goes directly out on the
internet any applications go through a
proxy then it creates a mismatch if your
diagnostic tools go always through the
proxy that you like visibility
um next slide please
um so we came up with
this as as a solution and that is uh the
step resolver includes this option in a
request when it sends it uh to the local
proxy and basically this option can
describe uh What uh the stock price
author would like to get from the
Upstream collection to uh
the recursive resolver and it consists
of a number of sections that's first a
set of bits which basically specify what
kind of uh encryption and authentication
you want whether there's a specific
desire to have or exclude certain
Upstream transports
if an application wants to be more
specific it could list IP addresses for
Upstream resolvers if you want to have
any kind of authenticated collection
that you need to have a name
um if for example you want to do do you
want to have a dough path so that can be
put in the SVC parameters as well as
support or LPS and finally all devices
were outgoing interface really matters
like for example on a phone if an
application is aware of interfaces then
it could also put in an interface name
but the basic idea is that an
application is not required to put
anything ill I mean if you just said
this option with all bits clear that you
basically tell the proxy will do
whatever you want if you just said well
I need authenticated connection that the
proxy should figure out a way to give
you an authenticated collection or
report a failure if it cannot do that
next slide
so
a key design thing of this is It's
stateless
um every so it sort of mimics uh the
original uh DNS to Port 53 uh set up uh
so we said the same proxy option in
every requests and then assume that um
the the proxy will do something clever
um
um to avoid having some sort of State
between the local proxy and the step
um we've had to maximize control given
to the application I'm not saying that
all applications have to use it but if
they want to use it they should be there
um
of course for for step resources the
benefit of moving to this model would be
that there's a very bigger potential for
caching certainly for short-lived
applications
um it also introduces opportunity to
implement local uh policies in the
blockchain instead of well try to figure
out whatever stop resolve your
application has it and try to do
something for that
um
the next bullet item is formulated a bit
sloppy here the idea is that the proxy
just forwards staff from an upstream
recursive resolver and it's not required
to do any additional dnsic validation
basically to say well either you do it
in the application itself or you leave
it to a recursive resolver but if the
the proxy would use for example Dane or
something like that then of course part
of data is that you should do uh that
you need to do the DLS acceleration but
it only does that for internal stuff not
as a server uh to the user
um and we implemented uh this not
completely but but most of it uh in a
branch of of Cathy and S uh people about
to play with it
um next slide please
uh thinking about this
um if you have
um sort of a current proxy then it's
quite possible that the current proxies
blindly forwards uh edns zero options
um and then if if you would end up with
the situation that's some because of his
authority the network would implement
this uh proxy control option which is
not ruled out then you could have the
situation that stop resolver thinks it's
topic to a local proxy that affects
traffic is just forwarded unencrypted
um so there's a separate option that
specifically a way to communicate
between the resolved proxy and then the
the proxy basically tells the surplus of
what sort of oh what sort of uh Network
Source adders that I get this request
from and I really if if a slippery
sulfur is very private see sensitive
that it should say well if this is not
host local then just drop it because
something is wrong but if you're more
lenient then you could say well if it's
still linked local and I trust my local
link then I'll go to allow it
so it's it's well
piece of puzzle that you need for for
the the slippery sulfur to to verify
that the whole thing is really contained
and then the next thing
um the left slide please
um this is basically a coffee this thing
that might need uh to a separate
document or something like that is that
if an application or a stop wants to do
a DNS check validation
and you want to sort of be guaranteed
that as a fallback uh trust anchor that
it would be nice if your local proxy can
just cash the other side trust or Data
Trust anchors and return that so there's
an extra option that basically said well
please give me this stuff if you already
have a local uh trust anchor that you
don't need it but but
applications needs a fallback and it
would be better if step resolvers
they'll have to set up https collections
to Eli and stuff like that
um
so that's the three different options
next slide please
uh so the question is uh do people find
this useful would they like this working
group to work on it or any other kind of
feedback or questions
thank you Philip
um just this last ITF the author sended
the document to the add group that was
discussed there but was out of Charter
so the different DNS working group chess
discussed this uh were to present it or
where should it learn
we send an email to the mailing list to
the DDS open list with this question
actually
and that's also why we scheduled this
presentation here we would like to share
the feedback from the from the working
group
uh Ralph please go ahead yeah so you
confused me a bit because when I read
the document I thought I wasn't clear
that it was local only then you said in
the in the talk it was local only but
then you could extend it so
what is the scope now because there are
probably different kind of
considerations
when you have it so the scope of the
draft is the communication between a
stop resolver and a local proxy
but for example at the moment lots of
people use Unbound as some sort of local
resolver which could be extended to to
support this option
it is communication on a machine between
two programs yeah yeah and you need to
change pretty much both programs for
stuff to work yeah definitely so
wouldn't it be easier to do a direct an
API like get DNS for for doing that
stuff
just
um so we're looking at doing
inter-process communication uh within
the host in a way that fits within the
DLS model so there's a fake that's
the actual problem is name resolution
and uh
so yeah
but the thing is the alternative of
doing it is for example a talk Alpha
debus
and do something like that and then it
sort of becomes completely outside uh
the DNS Community to to design anything
on how that works so so this is an
attempt like can we structure uh this
part of communication that just
definitely happening uh in the real
world in a way that that sort of we can
have a say on it instead of leaving it
to the random implementer of house
operating system
okay I mean I've just found on a machine
it better to do something with an API
and for going off the machine we have
that's probably why it comes out of 80d
DNR and DDR to make secure connections
from application to resolvers right
uh so those are protocols between in
this model that would be running between
the local proxy and the recursive
resolver whereas this would be specific
for a sub resolver at a local to to
reduce the complexity of the step
resolver because otherwise the step
resolver would have to implement all of
the add protocols uh creating more
complexity
yeah I mean if you could use apis that's
the
thank you uh Victor
let's go ahead sorry Victor you're on
uh hi can you hear me
um so um the the Dane mode that's
described in the draft is either no
mention of Dane or Dana's mandatory or
pkx you know mention or mandatory
um and it seems to me that that putting
the knowledge in the application of
which of these will or will not work
uh is fragile uh an application doesn't
necessarily know uh which authentication
mechanisms will or won't be available to
a particular destination uh one of the
great ways in which daneworks is
something called opportunistic name
which is use it when there are tlsa
records and don't use it when there
aren't uh so use Dane when possible
that's not covered in the in the draft
uh yes because if you set both bits to
zero that it should do exactly that uh
so the model should be that's sort of
everything can be clear
uh and then it's up to the the proxy to
basically do the right thing but if an
application has specific knowledge or
desired an application can override that
and say well this is now mandatory
because I want it uh
um is the proxy expected to detain when
TLC records are published there was no
language about that at all it expected
to do uh Dane yes so um it's expected to
exactly do a Dane lookup uh see whether
that would work or not and then use the
information yeah
of course if if the language is not
clear then then that can be added as a
more strict requirement uh but yeah it's
definitely expected to do that
okay
thank you Benjamin
hi
uh
I want I want to focus on something I I
just heard you say at the end I feel
like uh was was kind of crucial right
that uh this isn't formulated as an API
because the ietf doesn't standardize
apis and so the only way we can insert
ourselves into this process and and
provide our our proposal for how the
system works is to structure our
solution in the form of a protocol
and uh I don't know if that's exactly
true that the ITF has started to dabble
in API definitions but uh whether or not
uh it's true it doesn't it doesn't
strike me as a good reason to uh to
structure it this way I think that what
we're describing here is something that
that's really most naturally
characterized as an API and if the iatf
hasn't traditionally been very involved
in API definitions I think that's for a
good reason which is that those
definitions have to evolve pretty fast
and and the requirements
uh aren't always so clear up front in
this particular case uh you know I I
don't think that the specific behavior
that's laid out here would precisely
work on for example any of the major
consumer operating systems or for use by
any of the major consumer browsers those
all have very detailed and evolving
requirements for how they do their DNS
lookups for what security requirements
they expect Etc so
uh I think that if you actually look at
the the market for this I think it's
sort of not there
uh and instead we we do need to figure
out a a richer API for name resolution
for essentially the uh the longer tale
of applications who aren't willing to
deeply customize their DNS Behavior but
also aren't willing to be stuck on get
Adder info forever
uh but I don't think the answer is to
take all of the metadata about how you
want the request to be processed and
bundle it into the request itself in
particular I think that there's a
layering violation here where the the
client in this case doesn't
have any clear signal as to whether it's
talking to a DNS proxy that is aware of
this until after the query has already
been issued it only finds out it from
the response whether it's requests were
uh were met that's a kind of an upside
down design to me I would I would much
rather say okay we're going to define a
new interaction model ideally an API and
a platform relevant format but even if
it were an IPC I would still say this is
an or an RPC I would say this is a new
protocol being spoken between a new
interesting pair of parties one of which
is a in not quite a stub resolver but
it's more like an a smart forwarder but
maybe it's a steerable smart forwarder
the client can actually tell it where it
wants queries to go so
I think there's a lot of uh question
marks about what really what we really
ought to do here
so
many Bucks one is it seems that
at the moment there is almost nothing
uh for to allow sort of an application
to talk to a local proxy through an API
or at least I'm not aware of anything
that that works uh on more than one
platform the second part is that the
draft specifically has a probing query
to make sure that
um the the application doesn't leak any
privacy sensitive DNS query name but can
still probe whether this local proxy
that supports uh this draft is available
so in that sense the mechanism to to
interrogate the option the capabilities
of the local proxy is taken care of
sure um we're running a little bit
behind time so the further discussion
can go to the list are you sure Warren
okay thank you and I guess Peter
is next
okay
so um I'm going to give a quick update
on the draft that I wrote on mandating
consistency checks when processing CDs
or csync records
we've talked about this in Philadelphia
in July and got some feedback which is
not Incorporated
um yeah so this is a quick talk and the
next one will also be mine which I
perhaps will borrow a minute or two from
this one thanks
um yeah so this is mainly for
documentation for people who will look
it up later when they download the
slides so everybody probably knows CDs
records are used by the child to tell
the parent which are the future DS
records it desires it's good for Royal
office and so on and so forth and the
type publishes it and the parent can
digest it and similarly similarly for
csync the child can indicate what other
stuff should be updated like um
an S record so glue
um the finding is that the rfcs about
these record types don't specify how the
parents should be doing the polling and
the simple implementation would be to
just ask a trusted validating resolver
what the CDs record at a child for
example is and if you do that you end up
asking only one authoritative server
which may be giving you one response and
if you ask
another time or I don't know in another
microsecond you may be asking another
authoritative server which might be
giving a different answer and there is
no um no way to decide what's the right
one and the specifications so far don't
consider this problem so let's look into
what can possibly go wrong with this
next
so there's mainly two um scenarios one
is the multi-homing scenario which gets
more interesting if you add DNA SEC then
it's called multi-signer
um so consider um you have two providers
um which both
um
host a Zone and they sign it
independently each other announcing
their keys um
each other's and their own Keys now one
of them does a key role and accordingly
updates the CDs records for their with
the updated keys in that case when they
do that and they forget to include the
other providers Keys which may easily
happen when you update the CDs records
with your own new stuff and the parent
ends up querying this um it may happen
that the other provider gets thrown out
of the DS record set which makes the
general trust and breaks the solution
and similarly um with NS updates via
csync you can get the same kind of
problem and remove the other providers
and S records accidentally so that also
breaks a multi-signer setup and the
multi-homing setup it doesn't
necessarily mean the validation breaks
but that resolution breaks but it does
break the multi
um redundancy
promise that you have in a multi-homic
setup usually next
and similarly when you do a provider
change without turning dnsic off you
have to do a multi-signup period so you
onboard a new provider and then
off-board the first one
and that also involves multiple steps
with Ds record and NS record updates
um so particularly you have to prepare
the DS records for the new provider
first and only then add the new provider
to the NS record set and at that point
the new providers CDs records become
visible and they haven't been tested
before so if the new provider isn't
aware that this is even a multi-signer
setup they may not have included the old
providers stuff into their CDs record
set and then the parent might end up
adjusting that stuff and throwing the
old providers DS records out of the
delegation although it is still in the
NS record set and that breaks the the
things too so this is um kind of a
special case of the multi-seller thing
so to fix this let's look at the next
and I think final slide
um so um these problems can be
um mitigated if the parent is a bit more
careful and if you have a policy that
whenever you use a CDs or cdns key or
csync records
um as a parent for doing this kind of
scanning you um should check whether
things are consistent across all name
servers in the delegation you may
disregard unresponsive name servers but
otherwise if you discover an
inconsistency you must abort and not
change the delegation and you can do it
again tomorrow or you can retry after
five minutes or whatever your back off
um policy is but that would solve that
problem and if um multi-signer
deployments at some point get more
prominent I would expect
um these things to happen unless care is
taken so I think we should clarify to
people who have these scanning
implementations how it would be done
correctly and if someone discovers an
implementation that only does one query
to one name server you could easily say
look at this document and you're not
doing it right
um so this is what I think about it and
I I was
going to ask the working group if you
think this is reasonable if it should be
moved forward and so on and so forth
thank you wish
thank you West herdicker uscisi no hats
actually hat of the csync author
document I support this because I
actually think I wanted to do something
like this back when I published it but
there's some pushback so if you read the
feasting document in a particular
section 4.2 it says you have to take the
the most recent SOA so there is some
notion of how to make sure that you know
even if things are inconsistent you
still get the most recent up to date
record and things like that the problem
is is that in some deployments
uh my recollection from the discussion
is you
there may be some complexity and you
actually want to point at a at a hidden
server which is actually what this
document also talks about in section 4.2
it says you know the scanners maybe you
know or registrars might be configurable
to say hey go look somewhere else and
things like that so uh do I'd read that
section just to see you know what it
follows it but otherwise I like the idea
of mandating checking everything okay so
you said csync RFC section 4.2 okay I'll
read that
so you also support this and there were
a couple of things that I mean maybe in
regards to what Wes said
if you kind of ask all servers you still
might not have asked all server because
there's any cast and all the other stuff
behind that maybe it might be good to
have some text around that in the
document and then what is the reasoning
behind kind of if servers are not
responding to discount them
rather than doing some sort of retry
okay
um so two things regarding your first
um
point about various anycast nodes I
think the important policy is to ask all
providers involved and you can achieve
that by asking one node of each name
server host name so I think that's why
that's okay and then the second way to
disregard unresponsive name servers
um so sometimes there's maintenance but
more importantly from some corners of
the topology
um some stuff may just be unreachable
because of routing issues and you would
otherwise never have the ability to um
to do an actual update if you take that
as a blocking failure I don't feel very
strongly and it wasn't in the draft
originally but at the last ATF was
proposed to add it in I think it was
Victor
um so perhaps Victor can start the
battle
okay I mean if I just find it weird
because I mean yeah that's obviously has
an attack Vector yeah I don't I don't
feel strongly about it um so whatever
the the working group feels like
Paul Walker speaking as one of the
authors of the Celia record
um I just skimmed my uh our sales like
did we really not say anything about
this and uh we didn't so uh yes please
do this work this is our buck I'm sorry
it's not a fault back then there was no
multi-seller
Vector neuron
allowing name servers to be unreachable
my concern was about uh Hidden Monsters
and also about being able to remove name
servers that have died and aren't going
to come back
right when your name server is
permanently decommissioned you want to
be able to still make updates and it's
presently listed so you know what are
you gonna do
should I add these these reasonings to
the draft
I mean I said unreachable corners of the
internet and you said phasing out name
service and all of that do you think
that's important or do we just I mean
it's important but do you think it's
important for the draft or should we
just specify the protocol without
um
justification I don't know how it's
handled usually
I don't have strong opinions about how
to say it
okay thank you Peter
um wrapping up
um there's also been good discussion on
the mailing list in July August there's
a good feedback from the room
will schedule a working group adoption
call later with and we coordinate with
you okay next presentation
also by Peter
this one
all right
um so it's Peter Thomason
um
yeah so in the past few years
um multi-signing scenarios have been
discussed in various places
um
and I was sometimes part of the
discussion and I noticed that
um the the way that the key exchange
that's necessary between the
participating providers
um hasn't been um discussed on a
protocol level so far or well like
there's no no automatable recipe for it
essentially it's not really protocol
change
and I just wanted to um talk about that
and um put it out there to the group how
that could be addressed again I don't
feel very strongly it's just an idea I
don't know if anyone needs a solution
even maybe people like doing things
manually
um but so let's let's um just take a
look at it and then we can discuss or do
whatever so next slide
um so this is a bit of a messy slide um
but I'll walk you through it
um so to look at um
what's needed for the key exchange it's
interesting to investigate how the DNS
resolution works if you have a
multi-center setup and let's say you
you're asking for some record of
Interest let's say an a record and
actually you will need two separate
queries one is for the a record which
gets you the response and also the
signature and the other is for the DNS
key that you need for validation and a
reserver might end up sending these two
queries to two different name server
host names and then a multi-center setup
that might be operated by two different
providers
and so the DNS key record set is not
necessarily delivered by the party who
also gave you the signature
um so to make that work and to to um
keep it that way that reservers don't
need to be aware of any of this
multi-cellular stuff you need to make
sure that the DNS key responses include
all the keys that a validator may need
to do the validation regardless of
whether the record of interest is
delivered by the same provider or not so
um the interesting question here is what
exactly needs to be included in the dnsq
record set and it turns out of course it
works if you just include all of the DNS
keys of all providers so you just take
the global Union or something like that
but turns out you don't need that it
actually depends on the Queue type
because if you are looking for the DNS
key only if that's the record of
Interest then the signature will always
be
um
in the same response as the DNS key so
it will always be done with a key that
is part of the dnsc records that you get
as a response so it's actually just a
one provider problem in the DNS record
set so to validate DNS key record
responses you only need the ks case of
that provider not of the other providers
um and um
yes for everything else let's say for
example for an a record
um it may be that the signature is
delivered by a provider that's different
from the DNS key delivery provider as I
said earlier because then you really
have two different um
queries and then you need the other
provider's zsks right because you you
don't know ahead of time which name
server hostname belongs to who
so um
forget all about that um the summary of
that is so the bottom line is the DNS
record said that everybody has to
deliver is at least the local DNS keys
of that provider who's responding plus
the other providers is use case so
anyone who's sending a response needs to
have imported the other providers Zs
case
but not necessarily the case case
um and then very similarly for CDs and
CDN SQ records if you want to use that
and you also have to to serve the union
of all the providers ksk um type DNS
keys because otherwise things wouldn't
work out with the previous draft where
you require consistency
um so next
so let's look at what the um additional
requirements would be Beyond um what are
the keys you need so um we just learned
that providers need to discover each
other's Case Case and include them in
the CDs kind of records and to learn
each other's Zeus case and announce them
in the dnsq record sets and all of that
in principle has been described in order
automation draft I think together with
Schumann and actually
um the link is outdated it's been
adopted um already but um the draft
doesn't specify how to do it um in a
technical way
um and there are a few questions to to
answer for example one is which channel
do you use and another is how do you
decide whether a key that you observe at
another provider's DNS key record set
that you want to import if that is
actually a ksk or also used for signing
of other records in which case it's a
zsk or CSK
and that's hard to tell
um because you don't know if a ksk like
signs that other one record That You
Don't See from the outside
and then also if you have three
providers for example
um just for illustration let's say
provider a b and c everybody has
imported each other's stuff and then
provide a b
um obsoletes the key that they phase out
it'll have been imported by A and B
right so how should a for example know
that they should remove this key because
B has faced it out although it's still
visible in C so it could be C is key a
doesn't know and that kind of inference
doesn't work if you just look at the DNS
key record set in the child to um yeah
so so you get these orphaned keys if you
only try to infer from what you see at
the Apex so you need something else
and that's something else what
properties would you like um so so one
property would be it would be in band I
mean it doesn't need to
um we can use rest apis or whatever but
perhaps you can make it work in band
would be nice if it's if it is
authenticated
and because of the how to distinguish
different kinds of keys a problem that I
just mentioned it would be nice if
somehow it would be explicit about these
things
next
so there's two proposals one is for how
to do the key exchange and the other is
for when to do it how to trigger it
um the bootstrapping draft has a
signaling mechanism
um how the um
DNS provider the names of operators can
make authenticated announcements of um
stuff about their domains that they host
it's used in the bootstrapping draft to
make an initial statement about what the
DS record set should be before there is
a chain of trust and there is a label in
the beginning of the signaling owner
names in this draft that is the
signaling type and we can introduce a
new one like for example underscore
multi
and we can use that signaling mechanism
to have an authenticated signaling path
between the different DNS operators who
participate in a dnsic multi-signer
scenario and the idea is that under
these signaling um records each provider
would announce their own keys for which
they control the private part so no
Union and then all the other ones could
look at that and collect whatever they
find and import it into their local
stuff
that requires the host names of the name
server no incorrect the zones in which
the names of our host names live to be
secure because otherwise you can't do
the dnsic validation of whatever is
published there so it's the same
requirement as in the bootstrap draft
um the idea is to do it as shown at the
bottom of this slide so let's say you're
provider.net and you want to make an
announcement to your multi-signer peers
about the domain example.co.uk then you
would assemble the name as it's shown
here underscore multi.example.co.uk
underscore signal dot whatever the name
server host name is
and on this name which is a not an apex
name so it's a subdomain necessarily you
can't have a delegation there
um you publish CDs and CDN SQ records
and put your own C your own case case
there
and you publish a DNS key record set
which has your Zs case
of course you would have to update the
language of the other rfcs who Define
those record types to only live at the
Apex
and then if you have that you have an
authenticated signaling mechanism and
the other providers can query that stuff
and import things
that's the basic idea it kind of sounds
complicated but actually boils down to
just having providers publish a copy of
their own records under these names
um next slide
the question is then how do you trigger
this how does a provider know that the
other ones even exist and when does an
import have to happen
um so if you consider for example the
beginning of a multi-signer setup
initially the new provider is not yet in
the name server record set and before
you can add the provider you have to
um to set up the DNS configuration so
you can't do it based on the NS record
sets because it's not yet there you
can't find the new provider yet
um the proposal for Discovery is that we
introduce a new record type I have
called it tentatively CNS and it could
hold the prospective name server host
names in the final state after the
transition has happened that's analogous
to how CDs records hold the prospective
DS records and the idea is that when um
The Zone owner has provisioned the zone
at the old provider and also the new
provider and synchronized all the
contents like a records or whatever then
when everything is in order they add a
CNS record set which is the union of
name server host names so it would have
the old and the new name server host
names
and um when a DNS operator discovers
that that has been created they can look
at it and see oh okay so these are my
host names and then the other three are
from the other provider and then they
can go ahead and determine what the
signaling names would be from the
previous slide and import stuff
um this also works for triggering um
a rollover synchronization so for
example when you have done the
multi-signer setup you would of course
remove this CNS stuff again because you
don't need it anymore and then when one
provider does a rollover The Zone owner
can trigger a synchronization or
re-synchronization of keys between
multisand appears by recreating this CNS
record set and then they go and do the
queries and and collect
yeah
so that's the idea um for the trigger
um I don't care about what the name of
the record type would be I called it CNS
because it lives on the child side just
like CDs and csync and it conveys
configuration although not to the parent
but to the peers and that's what I
thought the CNS would be intuitive but I
know that some people at least feel
differently some people have told me
um
so whatever
um I just wanted to include the concern
here we can change it but I think it's
neat
um there's two more slides um the next
slide has an example workflow
so let's say you have example.co.uk and
you are provider a I mean you are not
provider a but that's the current setup
and this one dot provider a.net and you
want to onboard a second provider into
the multi-signer scenario the first
thing to do is that the domain owner
creates a zone at the second provider B
and um you know Provisions are the a
records and whatever the Zone contents
are and then when that's in order the
domain owner creates the CNS record set
which is a joint set of name server host
names at both providers they both
observe this and then provide a B for
example would
do whatever like underscore multi The
Zone name.signal Dot and then the other
provider's host names which are taken
from the CNS record set query DNS key
and CDs records to DNS ACC validation on
that because that's assigned with the
provider A's keys because the subdomain
of their hostname and then you can do
the import everybody can observe what's
happening because provider B can look at
what provider a is publishing at the
child's Apex And when everybody has
observed convergence then you can go
ahead and update the NS record set to to
finish the onboarding of the new
provider
it's possible to just do that by
renaming the CNS record set to the NS
record set and overriding that and then
do csync or you can use Epp or whatever
you want it's it's an orthogonal problem
to this one
um yeah so final slide um the summary of
The Proposal is um that it solves The
multi-signer Exchange problem in a way
that has a few properties that I think
are interesting it's automated it's
authenticated it's in band it's explicit
about the ksk versus zsk questions so
there's no guessing involved by the
importing party it's comprehensive in
that it covers onboarding and
off-boarding and key roles and it's
minimal in the sense that it has a
signaling mechanism which is necessary
and it has a trigger
mechanism which is necessary but it
doesn't add any protocol change
resolvers don't need to learn anything
um and all of that stuff
um I'm not implying it's the solution
maybe there's a better one maybe nobody
needs a solution
um
it's just
what I came up with and I would be
interested in what people think
thank you sorry thank you Peter in the
queue Victor but we have two minutes for
questions for Q a so please be brief
um you haven't talked about uh ongoing
is it a scale rollovers from the
individual providers the uh the
customers then not involved in
publishing uh CNS records they might
have removed them but the operators will
still periodically roll their own set of
SKS how's the timing of that manage
um so
it appears to me but I'm not sure if I
thought it through fully that if one of
the provider does is zsk roll over then
it would be unsafe
um to allow the provider to do that
unilaterally
and you always need to have the Zone
owner approved kind of by creating the
CNS record and say okay that's fine go
ahead and change it I'm not sure if
that's true
um but no it seems to me like that now
if you're saying perhaps there is a way
of doing it unilaterally
yeah probably there is right because as
far as a an operator is in control of
their part of the CNS records but doing
this signaling stuff why not let them do
it
um yeah so I I know of no method of of
triggering that
um synchronization
um I think that's worth discussing
because providers will want to roll
zeta's case if they're the operator for
the customer's own in terms of just
making the signing go
yeah that's a good point do you have a
suggestion
otherwise uh no we should discuss it
later okay
thank you
yeah
since it's um a new draft you know you
know we should go ahead and uh
bring the discussion to the mailing list
looking forward to that yeah thank you
thank you thank you okay uh our final
presentation for today's tiru
um
there we are
all right sure
okay good morning everyone I'm thiru
I'll be I'm one of the co-authors of the
draft uh structured data for filter DNS
was presented at the last IDF uh next
slide please
uh
a quick recap it's it's the primary
purpose of the draft is to assist DNS
filter troubleshooting uh next slide uh
at the last idea of we got feedback with
regard to this craft was uh how would it
interrupt with the RPC servers in case
they don't upgrade themselves to support
this specification so we added a section
to address that specific comment next
slide
so RPC servers are the ones which uh in
case if they do DNS filtering they would
put an NXT domain response with uh
clearing the array bit uh in those cases
in case if the client is upgraded to
support this specification uh but the
server is not it would continue to
accept the next domain response uh but
let's imagine a case where a server is
also upgraded to support this
specification in that case uh the client
would learn the server's capability
using the resin foreign type that's
being discussed in the ad working group
and I will be presenting that in the ad
working group in the next uh meeting and
then the client includes the Ade uh
option in this pseudo record type to
tell that it's capable of understanding
the Ade response so with that the server
knows whether the client is indeed
capable of understanding the Ed option
or not so it decides whether to put an
NX domain response or send an ede option
where it can now pass the fields that
are being sent in the extra text field
to help troubleshooting
next slide
yeah I think we've been presenting this
graph for quite some time and uh we've
been addressing all the comments that
have been received so far and uh we
request for working group adoption yeah
thank you
so the documents did have uh received
some feedback from the mailing list
I understand there was also interest
from the industry yes
so are there any comments here in the
working group
we also put it on a working or a chair
slide that this document might be up for
a working group adoption we will move
that to the mailing list and schedule it
we will coordinate it with the authors
yeah we have server implementation of
this I spoke to Apple and Microsoft and
they were interested in this so
thank you
okay
that's it thank you
um okay
and that's what we have time for today
thanks everybody in the room and out in
radio land
and um some of these things will will
take to further discussion on the
mailing list and um looking forward to
seeing folks
yeah thank you so apologies to Shivan we
we don't have enough time to give you
the floor but please working group reach
the updated document he has a pull
request ready
um this is sorry the domain verification
draft
um you want to add something and thank
you Tim for the dog pictures
so thank you all thank you for your
participation contribution to the
working group see you uh next in
Yokohama or online bye
foreign