foreign
thank you
well I see one o'clock on my uh on my
screen so I think we should probably
make a start first off a quick audio
check can you hear me successfully I'm
going to take my mask off
um because I'm speaking and just for
clarity for remote participants I hope
you don't mind it
um
hello welcome to ietf 115 dtn working
group meeting so uh just for clarity
this session is being recorded we're
doing this through me Techo uh it will
obviously excitingly all be on YouTube
afterwards so uh you can show what you
did at ietf to your friends and
colleagues when you get back home
uh next slide please
ah so as this is an ietf meeting this is
covered under the note 12. so I'm
assuming most of you have uh attended an
ietf meeting before
oh okay good
um if you have not you need to read the
note well this covers IPR this covers
your participation at the microphone in
the chat and within the meeting in
general it also covers your basic
Behavior Uh heated discussion is
fantastic abuse and bullying is not
there is a relevant codes of conduct
relevant information on copyrights
patents participations and the general
standards process all documented in
these very nicely written BCPS please
follow the links if you have any
questions
as with most things you have been told
about these things you can now no longer
claim you are unaware of them but we're
all grown ups and we will assume that
we're going to behave them responsibly
anyway next slide please so
tips because we have a still have a
large number of remote participants
thanks to the tail end of covid please
make sure you sign in to meet Echo
remotely obviously but also in the room
so we can operate a single queue there's
a really nice raised hands button you
can click to join the queue so please
use that rather than just standing at
the queue
remote participants uh try to avoid some
feedback by keeping your audio and video
off unless you are actually presenting
or sharing if you're asking a question
obviously you will need audio video is
optional
um strongly recommend a headset to avoid
the usual audio feedback problems
hopefully after two and a bit years of
covert we're all pretty good at remote
meetings over video conference but
problems happen
next slide please
so uh the agenda is at that URL we will
also put it on the screen in a second
the meet Echo information for those
obviously who are not remote and can't
see this but that information is there
for your reference if you get stuck with
uh anything during the meeting uh
there's a URL there for a an FAQ which
should hopefully help you dig out of
that hole next slide please
so the agenda um we are doing the first
five minutes from the chairs well
currently from me uh then we have a
35-minute discussion on the ipn naming
scheme update from myself
uh then Brian C plus is going to present
bpv7 administrative records we're going
to do the Cozy BP SEC security context
records again with Brian
um we've given him 20 minutes to do both
but
um there's two topics in there then
Sarah heiner is finally going to get a
chance because she got bumped from the
114 agenda to talk about the dtn
management uh dtnma architecture I think
that's double architecture if I think
about it which is all about managing
systems uh across delayed and disrupted
networks a interesting piece
and then Scott Johnson uh wants to give
a demonstration which is always fun and
we have real confidence it's all going
to work remotely from from wherever he
is in the US about IPv6 support for dtn
so I'm actually really looking forward
to that would be great as usual we will
have a little bit of Open Mic at the end
for any other business we will absorb
that if any of these discussions get
heated I would much rather discuss
um things as they happen within reason
uh rather than waiting to the very end
and then to dominate the end of Scott's
demo with talking about ipn for example
so we may absorb that 15 minutes we may
have to be quite tight on time if
discussions run on next slide
okay
there is the shared markdown based
notepad in Meet Echo uh although we have
a secretary here Adam who furiously
takes notes uh please help out please
it's a collaborative thing particularly
if your name is spelled wrong or I mean
Adam types fast but occasionally
keystrokes are missed or if you don't
think he captured your point correctly
please add to it it's fine equally to
help Adam if you're in person can you
state your name at the mic nice and
clearly so he can capture that as well
as usual this is an ITF working group we
have a mailing list
dtnitf.org also if you need to contact
the chairs about anything administrative
um subject matter stuff should really go
to the normal dtn mailing list it's for
the working group but if you have an
admin issue or want to suggest something
administrative there's The dtn Hyphen
chairs mailing list which will go to Ed
and myself and also our ad zahid who I
believe I just saw come in and sat at
the back of the room oh there he is he's
over there great right so we have our ID
with us as well which is great so one
thing I did not do is give a 30 second
chance for anyone to bash the agenda do
you think we have missed something vital
Brian is at the mic first go ahead Ryan
hey
Francis I actually had submitted some
additional slides about CLA service
definition if I shorten my other time
will I be able to
present on those as well if you can fit
them into the two 10-minute sections
you've got I I have no problem
okay thank you yeah can you uh submit
the slides to be updated and we'll get
them into the into the agenda pack
quickly that's fine sorry
they're actually already in there
we'll click the right button then
um I'm sorry I'm still at Marcus
struggling so Mark Blanche join the
queue by all means go for it I I feel
your pain thank you looks like sometimes
in this room the wireless you know kind
of Disconnect at least on my side
um
I don't know if it's an agenda at them
but I just reposted a draft that I wrote
a few years ago about
service registry and kind of a
application framework
um I just want to know from the working
group if
this is interest to be done or not or
you know so at the very end of the
meeting if there's a few minutes left
I wouldn't mind you know knowing if
people are of Interest or the working
group so that they kind of resume that
we're on that
absolutely yeah
yeah share the mic oh that's it is
Wireless so no completely agree uh don't
have anything to add to Rick's excellent
introduction and
why don't we start with our first
presentation
which is Rick
okay so for clarity
I am most definitely taking my chair hat
off during this presentation because
this is my draft primarily I'm the
primary author on this and so I will be
representing myself and not acting as a
chair of dtn so I want to make that
abundantly clear and I may stand here
for the whole of this q a as well to
indicate I am not sharing this so um as
many of you are probably aware I hope uh
I have published three revisions of uh
an ipn
URI schema update draft that recently
after the last call not last call the
working group adoption call was
successful after the interim we held
between 114 and 115 is now being
republished as a working group document
so although I
am the primary author on this this is
now a working group document and is up
for discussion and consensus within the
working group okay
next slide please
so a little bit of background for those
of you who haven't immediately read it
or aren't familiar with the depths of it
um this is all to do with the IPM scheme
Uris so a little bit of background
Within dtn
sources destinations of bundles are
described using a URI
so this is the Uris just like HTTP URLs
uuid Uris Etc but in both RFC 6260 which
was bundle protocol version 6 and 9171
which is bundle protocol version 7. the
ipn schema is defined as node number
which is an unsigned integer and service
number also an unsigned integer
there is explicit encoding instructions
for how to take this general purpose
text-based URI and turn it into the
relevant encoding for both bundle
protocol version 6 and bundle protocol
version 7. so although we are talking
about Uris there are specific encodings
for the two bundle protocol versions
that are in active use at the moment but
I will just refer to them as Uris the
discussion May touch on encoding but the
format is the key point
so
as defined in 6260 and 91 and 71 and
there is some weakness about that total
definition but it's reasonably clear
it's made of two parts the node number
which is the unique identifier of the
node on which a particular service
endpoint is expected to exist and the
service number which is the identifier
of that service on the Node
now the uniqueness constraint is really
important so
in both ppv6 but definitely in bpv7
an endpoint identifier which is the URI
must be unique for interoperability if
you have a set of connected dtn nodes
making a single dtn Network you cannot
have duplicate endpoint IDs I.E
sorry unicast endpoint IDs you can have
multicast ones ipn does not support
multicast so in the ipn it's all about
unicast so therefore they must be unique
otherwise you can't deliver the same you
can't address the same bundles as to two
things with the same name
so the combination of node number and
service number must be unique according
to RFC 9171
but in the descriptions in 6260 and 9171
node number is also implied to be unique
following the general pattern of IP
address and port number so there is this
is analogous but not identical
next slide please
so I I have
in going through and trying to really
understand what's going on with ipn I
have read quite a lot of stuff and I
have some perceived problems which I
have attempted to address in this draft
and they are primarily
there is only one Ayana registry for
node numbers at the moment it's called
the cbhe registry which stands for
compressed bundle headering coding which
is a way you do the wire format for
bundle protocol version six it predates
bundle protocol version 7 and makes no
reference to bundle protocol version 7.
and compressed bundle header encoding
isn't used for bundle protocol version
7. so
perhaps cbhg isn't the right name for
the registry and renaming it is requires
a document because it's good best
practice and it's what Iona requires of
us
not a great issue second point there are
some minor inconsistencies between 6260
7116 which actually is the draft which
introduces and Mark Blanche is one of
the authors of that draft which
introduces these Ayana Registries and
makes the requests and backs them up but
it doesn't change the spec much more
from 60 to 60.
and RFC 9171 inherits the ipn URI scheme
because it was very much in use for V6
seen as a very useful thing to have
but because it's described in three
different documents there are some
inconsistencies there is some
implementation
knowledge that has emerged there are way
people have interpreted these things
into interoper into implemented networks
where they slightly deviating behaviors
for example the node number uniqueness
isn't absolutely explicit it's just kind
of assumed
and really we should have nice clean
clear specs for this
and from my perspective I don't actually
care what that spec says as long it is
as it is abundantly clear what the
correct behavior is so that we can
achieve interoperability because that's
the point of the ietf is to achieve
interoperability between different
people's systems if you're building your
own thing do your own thing nobody
really cares
so the third perceived problem is the
single flat numbering space for all log
numbers
so
this goes back to the bungle protocol
version six days where there were node
numbers it was an unsigned two to the
64-bit integer space great lots of room
in there due to the way that um the wire
representation in bundle protocol
version six that could be encoded
reasonably effectively
um
but there was still a penalty for the
bigger the number the more bits need to
be encoded on the wire and with seaboar
that is definitely the case
so there is if you got an early
allocation from the single space you
could encode your ipn numbers in six or
I think it's seven octets
if you tried to register one now and
there aren't that many registrations but
they're handed out in Big Blocks
according to the registration policy
which is perfectly valid because you
probably do want a fairly big chunk
you can end up with the minimum encoding
being eight or nine octets and if you
know if this gets
allocated aggressively you could end up
forced to have a minimum 10 octet
encoding where
if you could just use a low number you
could get away with five and we're
talking about deep space and constrained
devices and having an IR and a registry
force you to add five octets to your
Source your destination and your report
to fields in your bundle protocol header
just to talk to between two devices
within your own network seems unfair if
I'm honest and undesirable
and equally the other problem is in that
original cbhe node number registration
there wasn't actually anywhere for
saying do you know what these really
convenient short numbers like one two
three four and five you know you build
one of these things in your lab and you
start numbering your nodes one two three
four and five because you know they're
they're easy
those aren't reserved for that use
they are actually reserved to be handed
out to someone so if you then go and fly
that
because you built it and it's been
signed off by the relevant authorities
and you've put it on the top of a rocket
and shut it off somewhere
you're using someone else's license
Spectrum or you're using spectrum that
has not been and I'm putting this in
radio terms because I know a lot of
people understand that in the space
Community you are using spectrum that
has been reserved to be handed out to
somebody else which means your equipment
that is currently out there
that Spectrum may be allocated to
someone else so
there is no official unlicensed Spectrum
to use for experimentation and clear
rules about its use and I also see that
as a problem next slide please
so the ipn update document attempts to
provide solutions to these
so the first one is to clarify the usage
of the ipn scheme URI node numbers and
service numbers with bundle protocol
version 7. so that's collate all the
information we've got between 6260 7116
and 9171 draw it all together and say do
you know what the rational superset of
all of these rules or the rational
intersection of all these rules is
not as reserved for the administrative
endpoint blah blah blah you know there's
a it's a pretty short summary of this
stuff and it tries to tackle the
uniqueness constraint and I will go into
these in a bit more detail in a second
the second thing is to say the CVH node
number registry is a misleading name and
frankly it's quite difficult to look up
and it's not very clear to see what it
is anymore so let us
rename and clone that repository into
the registry into two Registries one we
will call bundle protocol version 6 note
numbers because it's full bunt bpv6 and
it's the node numbers and it's exactly
what the cbhc registry was but we'll
call it bpv6 because that's what it is
and the same applies to service numbers
and we will make a copy of that called
bpv7 note numbers and bpv seven service
numbers and we'll tidy up the
allocations a little bit to put in a bit
of private space to make sure that we
understand it and it's and it's there
for people to use
including and that's the third Point
reserving load number low numbers in
that range for private use so the
efficiently encoded obviously used and
we know people just use I've built a dtn
network where I called my nodes one two
three four and five because why not
um that now becomes official unlicensed
Spectrum that's fine I can do that and I
understand its own license Spectrum
which means I will Clash if I am not
careful so don't go fly this where I
expect it to be interoperable with other
people it's just putting that
clarification in there
and the fourth point
is to introduce a new numbering
Authority let's introduce new numbering
Authority prefixes to allow flexibility
of allocation with efficient encoding so
this is to address the problem with a
single flat number range to say let's
divide it up and make it a bit more
hierarchical and I always mispronounce
that word
such that we can allow organizations to
hand out numbers in a controlled way
that are efficiently encodable
and don't need to constantly batter
Ayana for registrations or allocate
great chunks out of a single number
range and still maintain
interoperability with probably more
efficient encoding I say probably
because you can still do dumb things and
end up with inefficient encoding but
it's your that is now delegated from the
ietf to Regional numbering authorities
who can make their own decisions about
whether they want to be smart or dumb
look
look you've suddenly joined the cube
I'm going to go into all these points in
a lot more detail Slide by slide if you
want to hold it but keep going we can
take a question
um yeah up to you
um
I just want to make sure because the
registry actually has private use
it's space it's just that it's not low
numbers yeah it's way at the top end
isn't it yeah then you know there's
trade-offs here because
um you know private use is typically you
know in your lab or whatever therefore
packet size you don't matter right
bundle size or you know whatever
in space
or you know constraint networks those as
you said those you know
numbers are more important because
they're smaller therefore those number
are more precious to be used in
production constraint networks than in
the lab therefore I'm essentially at the
opposite of the spectrum of you in the
private one should be you know don't
care I completely agree with that
sentiment and without the introduction
of numbering authorities to solve the
encoding problem with a different
approach I completely agree I I will add
ignoring we have numbering authorities
having numbers 1 to 24 is the best thing
to have because we're using seaboor and
that's one octet so if and I'm gonna I'm
not intending to make it a political
Point here but if Rose Cosmos and NASA
both apply to Ayana for numbers 1 to 24
how do we decide that
I don't want to put that pressure on
Ayanna and turn it into a massive
geopolitical conversation
that's a registry policy I understand
it's a registry policy discussion but I
think we can sidestep that we can we can
type tied up the registry policy if we
want but that's it comes kind of a uh
can we come back to this at the end
after I've brought in numbering
authorities because I think it sidesteps
it
[Music]
and in the issue that you brought up
about the size of the header and the
space and that have you looked at at all
at LP wands static context header
compression pronounce Chic and whether
Chic is applicable in this particular
case
I have and one of the things I am not
doing is altering wire protocols
specified for bundle protocol version
seven I do not want to start rewriting
bpv7 that what I'm trying to do here is
clarify text in bpv7 and introduce a
smallest possible effects okay as long
as you looked at it and evaluated and
said bye yeah
yeah it just it dropped out a scope in
terms of pragmatism rather than any
argument about whether Sheikh had a
elegant encoding or not next slide
please
so quick one here we are what are the
clarifications I am proposing for ipn as
it currently stands for bpv7 and this is
as I said the intersection between the
three rfcs which talk about this trying
to work out what actually the common
not the lowest common denominator but
the common intersection of behavior that
kind of matches what people have assumed
when they're reading it as far as I can
work it out so
they boil down to the value zero for the
so remember node number component dot
service number component the value for
the node number component must the value
0 must not be used except as part of the
the magic ipn not DOT naught So within
bundle protocol version seven there is
this concept of the null endpoint
identifier it's nowhere dtn none and in
ipn that is the magic value not DOT
naught so you can't use naught for
anything else it just makes no sense it
it would danger in my opinion so you
can't have an ipn of notebook 2. service
number two kind of on the null endpoint
doesn't seem to make sense to me these
are all open for discussion but that one
hasn't proved to be contentious
it's greater than or equal to two to the
64 for the node number must not be used
because you can't do it in a seaboard
type zero unsigned integer encoding that
will change the wire encoding of your
Seaboard to use big numbers we don't
want to go in there the current encoding
as described in 9171 which introduces
the Seaboard encoding says this will be
an unsigned integer they have a natural
limit of 2 to the 64. that's never
actually written down it's implied by
two statements which
in combination say that so I'm just
saying it so there's no confusion
third
and this is contentious
all ipn scheme Uris for endpoints
co-located on a single bundle processing
node must share the same value for node
number component
and
this is contentious because either you
read this idea of note number dot
service number as analogous to IP
address colon port number
and think well obviously I've got an
address for my node and I discriminate
on the service on my node and therefore
my nodes have to be unique
counter argument is no no no no
bundle protocol version 7 makes it
absolutely clear that the URI in
totality is the unique element that's
what has to be unique
or you can have a service called ipn 2.1
AIDS can have a service called ipn 2.2
they are both unique
and it doesn't matter that the node
number's two
personally
I don't mind I think an argument can be
made for both yeah if you allowed no
numbers to not be actually the number of
a node and we'll just call them last
part or second last part and stop that
implied inference that it's something to
do with the number of the node
and then for the uniqueness constraints
apply this all works fine you can have
allocation policies for them it's all
good we're home and dry and we can do
multi-homing and we can do Gateway
devices and we can do all kinds of cool
stuff we have a question from Eric and
then we have a question from the chat
oops sorry I can't see the thing go on
here
uh yeah clarifying question if I think
what you just described doesn't
match at all how I read bullet point
three here
yes so I put an absolute rule in there
but I've had a number of people come
back to me and say I don't agree with
that I think that's wrong
well so saying that
um and two dot star has to be on a
single node is different from
uh everything on a single node can have
only one node number
those are two different things you're
right and I meant what you've said and
not what I've written
uh uh so you meant that uh n dot star is
always on node n and nowhere else yes
okay
that's about okay so we do we so 4.3 is
not in fact
correct as written at the moment
endpoints collocated on a single bundle
process processing node must share the
same value for the node number because
this implies that a node can't have node
number two and also node number three
you're saying they must have the same
note number and that's like maybe not
yeah okay that's that's an additional
restriction yep a very valid point and
and this is why this is the most this is
why this is one of the things we need to
discuss because the other point is
no
let's not do that let's say you can only
have one node number it's your node
number
and therefore it's got to be unique for
your node because then I can do
something like C and endpoint of 2.7 and
I know where 2.1 is so I can send it to
2.1 because I believe it's the right
node even if it's the wrong service so
you're in adding routing and uh okay
that's still technically a different
thing okay yes it is
of course yeah I can do that with three
as well if you have two and two and
three yeah exactly yeah okay so I'm so
just sorry just to jump in from from a
Time perspective I I think we'll have
this conversation reopened again in a
few slides so can we pause to that uh we
did have one question uh from the chat
uh which asked there is a must in this
third bullet uh do we foresee an
enforcement mechanism for any of these
uniqueness constraints so the only
enforcement mechanism I think we can say
is here is an RFC with RFC 8176 language
in it and if you write a specification
to say your satellite system will comply
to this RFC then it's abundantly clear
are we having dtn police force who go
out and check your implementation of
course we're not
um if people want to do interrupt trials
I think the best we can do is say we
will have a clear specification with
clear ietf language about the correct
Behavior such that people can go away
and write their testing regimes and
their QA and all that kind of stuff I
don't think we're gonna
we don't do enforcement we do
specification okay okay thank you
thank you so for service numbers
um there was some confusion uh RC 6260
and RFC 71 7116 both said the service
number for the administrative endpoint
or what it was called in bpv6 days it
was called something else but it was
fundamentally the same thing
must be zero in bpv7 it got turned into
a May
I'm suggesting it should just go back to
a must I don't see if we have a
well-known service called the
administrative endpoint why not just
give it a number zero which everyone is
kind of using as far as I can work out
it's kind of a housekeeping thing and
again 2-64 because sibo
next slide please
so the rename really simple this one uh
cbh e node numbers becomes bpv6 node
numbers cbhc service numbers becomes
bpv6 URI service numbers no alteration
to policy assignment nothing
cut paste rename in fact I think it's
just rename
next slide
clone them create new Registries for V7
tweak them slightly
call them the bundle protocol version 7
ipn scheme URI null Authority node
numbers registry and I will come back to
what null Authority means
all values and policies are copied from
the cbhg node numbers registry except
I've made the low numbers private use I
am very happy to have that discussion
I have kept the very top numbers as
experimental again probably part of the
same conversation let's have it on the
list
I don't mind there are pros and cons
that's fine
um
there was a weird block between two to
the 21 and 2 to the 28 which was
reserved for private and experimental
that's all part of that same
conversation let's just work out what
these things should be let's make sure
the reservations are there this is our
opportunity to do about housekeeping if
required
okay but the key point is by putting
private use rather than private or
experimental we are saying here is a
chunk of unlicensed Spectrum which you
clearly understand if it's for your own
stuff go ahead and use it
if you use it in the wild you probably
will clash with other people if they're
using it in the wild you do this is not
your spectrum to use you are sharing it
so we could develop protocols which
handle this and live in this kind of
unlicensed Spectrum I don't know someone
else can do that work I'm I'm I have no
idea how we start there but hey and it
also gives the range of numbers back to
the pool that aren't hugely high or or
tiny that we can reallocate for that
band okay we do have uh two people in
the queue starting with Alberto
thanks uh can you hear me well yes
um thanks uh Rick forward explanation
here a couple of couple of comments on
this one the first one is a question
um why creating a second registry why
can we extend the existing registry to
say it is a bpe CX plus the null uh a
null identifier a normal Authority uh
for bpv7
purely because I wanted to separate and
reorganize the current assignments to
clarify the difference between private
use and experimental however that I
think that is a very valid point to have
a discussion about what we do and if the
answer is there is no change then we
don't make the change that that's that's
fine
okay okay thank you um the second
comment is about uh the the use of the
term unlicensed Spectrum
um this has huge implications when it
comes to you know you build Technologies
for coexist in this case you know I tend
to agree with Mark that you know
selecting the the golden uh identif
numbers for private use would
automatically potentially create issues
that you know women don't want to have
at the end of the day
um
um you know similar to IP addresses in
this case
um they need to coexist if they are in
the same network and that would create
definitely forwarding issues if if we
don't create additional technology so I
wonder why creating that issue now
um
two reasons one having some private use
and I used analyzen spectrum in quotes
just because I know people a lot of
people come from an RF background but
it's not a it's this is about private
use allocation of numbers that's the
correct phrase for it I went for low
numbers because I happen to know someone
is currently
deployed a dtn node that they hope will
be interoperable with other dtn networks
that they hope will be interoperable
with other people and they've numbered
one two three four five
and they didn't ask for that
so but again
as long as we have some private use
space and people understand it's the
free-for-all space
and whether we combine that with the
experimental or split it and there's a
bit of nuance in the way Ayanna does its
allocations that needs to just be
checked and it's a slightly ietfe about
it
then it doesn't really matter where it
is I just
felt that moving load was useful
thank you
thank you Kevin Kevin just a really
small question I think uh
for this slide and the other one that
mentioned uniqueness in the ipn scheme
and if I want to
essentially create an anycast style
environment
where do I go in terms of what
allocations to use it's really clear
okay
9171 says you don't use ipn for that
they are so apologies for remembering
that but that seems pretty darn
unfortunate
yeah and I'm not trying to solve that
okay all right that's fair
Scott
yeah uh can you hear me okay
yes okay
um my remark at this point is just that
um if you do have
um authorities
um it seems to me that the reserving
load numbers for private use is moved
because the authority ought to be able
to use the low numbers itself right and
there's no
um it's responsible itself for
um ensuring there's no Clash on those
numbers isn't that right
I agree with you Scott yeah which is my
answer to Mark originally about
uh
having them as low numbers it didn't
really matter because it kind of once
you've got authorities in place it kind
of negates and moves around that a
little bit can we take that one to the
list because I think it's an interesting
topic and yes the
that's another aspect is if we've got
Authority numbers do we really care
about this and perhaps we should just
leave it as it is it is exactly yeah
yeah
okay so
anyone else
okay uh next is Mark
and then in the interest of time I will
uh lock the queue yeah I was going to
say you know it's fine if if you wanna
have questions at the end but
um two comments one is uh same as a
um
previous speaker and that's got the
Alberto
um I think I don't see the reason for
having two registries
it was only because I changed the
allocations
is there any reason
yeah but you know then we're kind of out
of sync if you know with someone yeah
yeah it's like so so an important aspect
is it's not the same protocol but yeah I
don't know and they are completely into
not interrupted yeah I know it's the
same URL URI scheme can we take that one
to the list yeah I think it's all
relevant argument I think it's a really
good discussion to have there and I
think we can conclude something
practical because it's it's not a major
issue this we just get just let's just
do the right thing yeah so it's fine I
feel bad about having same Reggie for
the same URI scheme with different
numbers
um the other point is uh I would like to
be
um
uh to learn what you mean the difference
between private use and experimental
because you define it differently I
haven't seen you know usually I in a you
know Registries private user
experimental is the same range which is
I don't care and those numbers should
not happen in production you know
networks but I was entirely with you on
this and then I went and read the very
detailed RFC about how to write a
registry properly because I thought if
I'm going to do this I just and it draws
them out and explains them differently
and claims them to be different things
however if we want to conflate them
together and say for us it doesn't make
any difference I'm happy to do that as
well yeah because it's just you know
yeah
okay this is why this is a working group
document and Stuart stew card critical
Technologies
um so two points the first one I think
this might be a restatement of something
that somebody else said but I want to
use different words to make sure I'm
clearing it that saying uniqueness means
that every node number must point to one
and only one node is different from
uniqueness meaning that every node has
one and only one node number so I hope
we can tease that out in the text
secondly
um what's a node oh this craft a
computer uh a core on a computer a
virtual machine uh
the closest I've come to that answer and
I don't think it's satisfactory is
things which share an administrative
endpoint
question mark
there is a point maybe earlier about for
private use why do we need
um an authority authority for private
nodes and to that
um also say that
um I don't know if it's a case in your
environment but stealth mode development
where somebody's developing something
that they don't want to share or
something else having the ability to get
numbers to work with without exposing
what they're doing is critical for those
sorts of operations so so push back on
any arguments against it because again I
don't know if there's such a thing in
your industry about Stealth development
that there's always a government
involved or something like that but uh
um so can I answer that question when we
get to the authorities so if you notice
this is the null Authority I you don't
have an authority you don't need to go
get an authority you just got some
numbers you can use and you don't have
to tell anyone about it that's why you
want because you have to be able to
support the stealth development I I
think that's absolutely something that
must be supported when however the final
text comes out thank you next slide I've
got eight seconds
uh so the service number's registry just
like I did with the v61 I cloned it
because I felt that it might be worth
jiggling it about to make the boundaries
work with C boring coding otherwise it's
pretty much the same
um I couldn't find any current
specifications for active well-known
bpv7 services that needed immediate
assignment they could be wrong if you
work for an agency and I'm kind of
addressing ccsds here who have things
that they consider well-known services
that are something that should be
globally interoperable and registered
with the ietf rather than just used
within their own sort of work uh speak
up let's get these ready to go into the
service registry to avoid clashes mark
blanche's draft on service members there
again Mark I did mention it
um I think is really good it was a
really timely up uplift of that uh draft
and republication of that draft it
introduces the Ping service or the echo
Service uh needs a well-known service
number just for General op stuff so you
can ping a node see if it is actually
there in a delay tolerant manner it's
going to need a well-known number
it doesn't have one at the moment this
is an opportunity to tidy up again
private use experimental use interesting
debate let's take it to the list
um that kind of stuff
next slide
because I just want to get to the
contentious stuff any questions so far
no move on
numbering authorities okay brace
yourself
so allocating from the flat number space
is inefficient it is that simple really
if you turn up late to the party you get
a more inefficient encoding for all your
node numbers tough
that's the current state of play
next slide please
The Proposal
let's put a prefix in front of this so
let's divide the space from a flat space
into a tree
so optionally
you can put an extra number dot in front
of your node number to say this node
number was assigned by this numbering
Authority
so a numbering Authority is an
organization and there's some question
mark about how we Define what the
credentials to be a numbering authority
to stop me going and grabbing two
personally for my entire Space Race
um
why not to stop but to ask serious
questions about why is Rick registering
all of two
but fundamentally you're saying
I can encode my numbering Authority
efficiently I can then as a numbering
Authority hand out all those precious
short
good encodings you know the one octet
two octet encodings according to my
policies without clashing with anyone
else from a number other numbering
Authority or from that registry of the
null Authority I.E the register used
when you don't have a numbering
Authority I can therefore get Global
uniqueness when I need it so this is for
interoperability
and it it just simply encodes shorter
and gives more flexibility to assignment
and if you are a vast if you are ccsds
and you are representing multiple Global
space agencies you can add naming
sub-authorities to give you even more
bits to play with
so you can then hand it up to two two to
the 64 sub-authorities I mean the big
ones come with a price
and they can then so you can have
ccsds.nasa or my Global program for
world for space domination dot project a
DOT Project B because I am a global
megacorp
it gives you that little bit of
flexibility but both of these components
are optional
the numbering the naming authorities or
numbering authorities and I need to be
clear about getting I've called it two
different things stupidly I've been
calling them numbering authorities in
the draft numbering authorities have a
global registry in Ayana
so you that maintains the
interoperability
but other than that they can hand out
their own numbers and I have added a
registration for them and
next slide please
okay reason for it
one of the arguments is people have been
saying oh how do I detect these things
oh hold on you're changing the wiring
coding for these things
um this should be a whole new URI schema
um no first off you can detect this in
your stream parser or your buffered
parser one octet later than you
currently detect it
so in the wire protocol when you receive
a c-bar encoded URI the first octet
indicates the type of the URI type
number two is ipn
following that is the length of the
array which contains the integers of
node number and service number currently
it should always be 2 because that's all
that's defined with this change that
number maybe three or four and that
tells you how many more you need to read
so you can detect these just as simply
but one architect later I consider that
a
easy
first compatibility they're optional you
don't need them there's a registry go do
what you always did that's fine
that's it
absolutely fine
and
yes and it also removes contention on
that registry so that's a no-brainer we
don't have everybody fighting for that
single numbering range for their
assignments they can just ask for a
number or look at the numbering
authorities that have registered
themselves and ring their closest who's
offering the best prices if you want to
use a commercial model you know
next slide please
that's it right
how big's the queue
the queue is a very good size right now
it is empty uh but but I know that we
had some
questions prior
so well I will I will I will bring back
up in in this instance
um oh well I'll let Scott go first and
then ask my question Scott go ahead
uh actually uh if if you want to go
ahead and ask a question first that's
fine with me I can why don't you start
sure okay uh in in reference to uh the
the understanding that different nodes
cannot have the same node number is a
different consideration than a single
node cannot have multiple node numbers
uh those are two separate constraints
is there can I call for opinions on
whether both of those constraints should
always exist
should there be a one-to-one
relationship between nodes and
numbering Authority sub Authority node
number you know that that set of
identification so I will toss that out
there in case anyone has opinions on
that if they would like to come up and
speak to it but then otherwise would go
back to Scott for his question
people
yes Scott it's it's to you okay uh well
uh I will start by
um uh responding to your question and uh
uh what I would point out here is that
both the IPM scheme and the DTM scheme
are
um uh valid and are defined in 9171 so
there is uh already a precedent for
having multiple uh unique node
identifiers uh for a single node that is
uh the ipn node number is not the only
is not necessarily the only unique
identifier for that note there there can
be a dtn
um node identifier as well and so
um the possibility of aliases in that
sense already exists and it stood I
would say difficult to legislate it away
um I I don't I think it's bad practice
for a single node to have multiple
little node numbers so I'm not opposed
to
um excluding that in a specification
um
I just want to point out that that there
are
um
their existing mechanisms that that can
frustrate that sort of uniqueness if we
want to and and those are difficult to
go to damage it it I definitely agree
that
um
um that the same node number uh should
not be used for multiple different nodes
and um and and that I think is an
important thing to uh document in the
specification I would also point out
that
uh node actually is a technical term uh
that is defined uh formally in RFC 9171
um
um the other thing I was going to bring
up at this point is
uh if
um if we say that there are authorities
and the absence of the
um
encoding of an authority in uh in an IPM
endpoint ID
um
implies a null of authority uh I would
suggest that that null Authority think
think of it as as an authority that that
uh is uh there's nobody
uh managing necessarily or or that
there's a an authority uh number zero
someplace that is in charge of it and
not even have a node number registry in
uh Ayanna uh since node numbers are
going to be assigned by authorities uh
anyway
um so if if you if you want to have a
formal central location for
um for assigning those uh node numbers
where there's no specified Authority I
think that's a the easiest way to do
that is for there to be a zero Authority
whose job it is to do that and then
everything is in the same model and you
can eliminate
Ayanna having to be responsible for
handing out node numbers
so Scott can I reply to that one
um of course
so
I think we are in effect creating a zero
naming Authority and it's called Ayana
and it's maintaining the registry of
things we've already handed out to
people so that they don't suddenly lose
their their allocation
but what we're also saying is because
it's zero and if you notice in the in
the in the draft I have reserved at the
number zero in the number naming
Authority you can't be you can't go
register zero it's it's held back all
we're saying is if your naming Authority
is zero you don't need to put it in
there
it's and and then things which are
currently not putting anything in there
and using that registry just work so I
think we're kind of agreeing here
uh yeah yeah I was
um
I was just arguing for
um having a uh uh
um something other than Ayanna handing
out the uh zero Authority node numbers
because I thought it might be uh easier
but
um I'm
um if if that's the the best choice
yeah so that just certainly by having
that the the existing behavior of
node.service is unchanged but if we feel
uh any differently about it I would say
let's let's take that particular part to
the list
uh and then the other thing of course
um I was uh certain to bring up is
um a a preference for
um limiting the size of authority
numbers and
um and the
um and and
uh no number assigned by an authority to
32 bits each so that they can be
combined into a 64-bit node number
um as they currently are and minimize
the impact on existing implementations
and deployments of
dtn that use the IPM scheme
so so Scott I got a response to that
which is
two-part first I don't want to now
reduce
the existing two to the 64 address space
that that is through the null Authority
that the step the behavior as it
currently stands which is you get two to
the 64 services and you get to the 64.
load numbers I don't I don't want to
suddenly say oh and with this change
we've just have not you know what I mean
we've gone down to half the number of
bits you're allowed now that that that's
a that's a real change
and also in in my implementation I'm
using AVX 512 bit wide uh multiplexing
instructions so I can load all four of
these numbers into into single registers
and do high performance math on it and I
don't want to lose that ability so and
that's an example where you what works
for one implementation doesn't work so
much for the other and kind of we're
supposed to as well we're looking at
implementation so I'm I don't know
wouldn't the 64-bit combined
um uh Authority and node number
um and and aggregated work just fine in
your environment and and conversely
128 or 192 bits uh would work very very
badly in
um in environments that are much more
constrained such as a lot of space
conceivably but I think it's less
important than Breaking backwards
compatibility I think that's more
dangerous
and said
um no in fact who is it it's basically
packets have number allocations outside
of the 2 to 32 range in the Ayana
registry and we're basically turned
around to them and say I'm sorry your
registration just got removed I I I we
can do that I'm confident that they took
that registration because that was the
rules uh for our allocations and I'm
confident that they don't want
necessarily numbers that are bigger than
32 bits
that that are much smaller than that and
I think that that in practice uh numbers
that are bigger than 32 bits are in
general not being used all right let's
let's stop this one here we do have a
couple of other people in the queue sky
is that you repost this to the list uh
so that we can have any remaining
conversation and I ask that as we go
forward we we get a chance to clear this
queue quickly so that folks like Scott
will have time at the end of the meeting
uh Alberto go ahead
thanks Ed
um quickly just to give my opinion on
the uniqueness of the node number
um I agree with this card on the on the
first one which is I I think we
shouldn't prevent a node having more
than one node number or or any or a
processing unit having more than um one
node number and then on the second one
uh I'm not sure we should be putting
imposing that limitation when we think
about the potential distributed
implementations in ground
um to you know to have uh you know
something closer to Edge processing that
my that might require
um you know depending on the
implementation that might require to
um
um you know the option to um have you
know that the same node number in
different uh processing units uh this
may be at the same Processing Unit
um but you know I'm curious about
whether that limitation would impose or
limit any of these implementations
and I'll bear to my request uh same as
Scott is if you could make a post to the
mailing list specific to that topic and
we could capture uh that what is likely
to be very good discussion around that
there
thanks I will do thanks sir
uh Brian
uh Brian cpcpl uh just mention and I'll
put this on the list too that uh IPv6
made the same kind of clarifying
distinctions between the node and what
they call the interface
for address assignments and the same
kind of thing could be done here to just
clarify what actually has the number
assigned and what is The Logical
aggregation
thank you Brian that's a very valid
point from my perspective we should be
identifying nodes and not interfaces I'm
with I'm with John Day on this that it's
it was a mistake I mean I see why it
happened but I I don't think we should
do that with dtn
because we don't have host names we just
don't have them so let's get that right
okay
and Rick you were in the queue I was in
the queue but I've already made my
comments so I will yield to Bob
um you were playing Ayanna some very
specific work have you done asked for an
early Ayanna review on this art craft we
will be very soon it's only just been
working group adopted and yes we will
okay I've also gone through early
reviews and they are extremely important
and valuable uh completely understood
and noted thank you
Felix
so this is Felix so I would like to go
for something for the IPA nameless teams
that you simply say the note is
something which has a signal and just a
single node number I think it will make
everything much easier to understand
I don't want to have a node number which
is failed across multiple nodes because
if I would like to place my routing on
node numbers it will not work anymore at
the same time I don't see a reason why a
a single node should have multiple node
numbers if I need multiple node numbers
I can just make multiple nodes I think
also the argument from Scott does not
really hold here because these are
really separate naming schemes so
there's no danger of confusion for
example regarding the service numbers so
if I see it as a kind of R yes I'm not
sure if I'm talking about an endpoint ID
1.2 and 2.2 whether it's actually the
same service in the end although that's
really separated the same is for me are
similar things regarding the
administrative element it's an alias it
would be the same it's not the areas I
would have a notice to administrative
elements so I think unless we've
identify clear use case we would say
single node multiple node numbers we
should not try to go that way because it
will really create in my mind it would
create difficult problems and I guess
these questions whether this note this
service 1.2 and 2.2 would be the same
would probably the outset could be
different answers in the room so it's
just confusing for me so unless we have
a very very clear reason we should not
do that
so thank you for the comment and also
ask that uh you reply uh with that uh
because the the best part of capturing
this is the traffic in the mailing list
so my final response to Phoenix and that
was the thing I remembered that I
yielded on
I actually think one of the beauties of
ipn is its Simplicity I mean yes I
turned around earlier and said you know
no any cast know this no that it's it's
unicast it's simple it's got basic
numbering it's it should be really tight
and Light
and that should could be a very good
reason to say of course we can do
multiple node numbers onto a single node
but that is perhaps going against the
spirit of ipn and remember we've got
this dtn URI which is very rich and
completely unspecified and and can be
used as a Dumping Ground for all this
cool stuff so why not keep ipn quite
simple
that's my closing comment thanks guys
thank you Rick uh next we have uh Brian
sipos Brian I'm going to ask instead of
the 30 minutes that we have allocated if
we could uh pull this down into 20 or so
and why don't we start with bpv7
administrative uh record uh quick
conversation
sure yes so I didn't prepare slides for
the administrative record topic only
because the document itself was not
changed it was only recently adopted by
the working group
um there have not been any substantial
uh feedback or comments yet on the the
document there was one editorial change
to clarify that it didn't
um
uh it didn't change the Ayana
registration policy so it's just
clarifying that there is no change in
the policy uh so that document has now
been uh adopted by the working group and
uh a new version has been uploaded uh
for the working group so really at this
point it's just soliciting feedback and
comments
well may I may I then ask the working
group uh to please take a moment and and
read this uh this newly adopted draft it
is short uh and uh please provide
comments on it if we don't get comments
on it uh within the next uh you know few
months then we will assume it is ready
to go into the next step in this process
and I will mention also that the Acme
working group and the security area
director
um are depending on this document to
progress to the iesg
for the other work to continue
so with that we can then move on to uh
the next presentation which are the Cosi
BP SEC security contacts
and Brian are you able to share your
screen
I
should be able to
do is there a way to get the slides
up I don't know that I can
actually so there's a little hi Brian
there's a there's a little button under
your name in the top left hand corner a
meet echo which says it's got another
kind of file icon that will share
previous slides for you and then you'll
get the thing at the bottom perfect okay
so uh this is uh discussing a an
individual draft currently
um that I would like to eventually bring
into the working group
um I've prepared previous slides and
these ones are very similar so I'm just
going to go through quickly as
background the context here is that the
bundle protocol already has
what are called the default security
context that gives some basic symmetric
keyed algorithms and they do their work
well but they're limited to the
symmetric key that are limited to some
narrow situations
and
for larger networks for internet-facing
nodes
and even for
currently envisioned networks that are
coming out of the uh ioag and NASA
there is a need for pki security and
this is just something that also falls
in with
the general overall best practices of
current Internet and network
um
authentication and security and we don't
want to have to reinvent the wheel for
how to do either pki or to do the
algorithms that rely on pki and so what
this is proposing is to use the cosay uh
message encoding
and algorithms in bpsec
and actually since these earlier slides
Jose has actually Advanced to internet
standard it was draft standard
previously
so the high level goals here are we
don't want to alter any of the BP sex
structures we don't want to alter any of
the existing pki infrastructure that
already exists and we want to reuse as
much as possible
both the tools and the protocols
and the other thing is that looking into
the future we want to get gains that
others are making in the domain of kosai
so kose already has working uh groups
for using more experimental things like
uh compressed uh pkx certificates and uh
post Quantum and hybrid cryptography so
the goal here is to eventually be able
to take those benefits with very little
tooling change in the bundle protocol
now the they're I'm not going to go into
all the details about the the current
Jose context but the the concept is that
it's reusing existing logical structures
and we're using existing encoding
structures so it's very little new uh
for this context
and
the key thing about making this work is
that we have an interoperability profile
cos a is more of a container for
security information it requires a
profile to be able to say here's what
actually is expected and required of the
message content so this minimum
interoperability profile and this is
something that we can negotiate and work
out what in here is actually required
what in here shouldn't be required
whether here might need to be prohibited
this is really the meat of what this
document is combining together
and the focus currently is on pki
algorithms and here you can see that the
elliptic curve algorithms RSA is
represented but things like more
experimental hpke and post Quantum stuff
doesn't exist here but in the future it
could be expanded
the the main goal though still is
to get uh bpsec working with current
existing pki
tools and systems
so that's the the push here and as it's
written as it currently stands this is a
mechanism that is usable today you could
actually
um use this with pre-existing
pki
and the existing certificate profile
that was established in 9174.
and that is the end of my presentation
so uh both feedback is welcome on this
document as well as
if it seems valuable enough to have it
adapted to the working group
so so is that then a request uh to the
working group to consider adoption
uh yes
we have one person in the queue uh
Stephen
Hey Stephen Farrell so I think this came
up when the Acme document was being
processed I guess was the extension
attacked me to automate validation of a
node ID
um
you said that's the next step do you
mean that thinking about that is the
next step or you have an answer in the
document in the document already I
haven't had a document sorry
oh no the the relationship here is that
um
the the Acme extension that is already
uh in that working group that is
intended to address where did these
certificates come from how does an
authority validate these identities this
uh document is saying how do we use the
certificates uh in bpsec currently the
certificates are profiled for TLS for
being used with the tcpcl
but this is saying we can use them also
for BP SEC so that we can get end-to-end
security
whereas tcpcl is single hub
okay so I guess the comment is I don't
think it's fully figured out how you
might do the equivalent
as to what let's say let's encrypt do a
dns-based uh domain validation
so I don't know that there exists an
equivalent to that that's useful and I
think that that's probably warrants Okay
so
so that actually is the other the other
document the Acme document that's the
intent of that
right but as I recall so I did a quick
review of that because somebody asked me
and
if I recall that that document just said
oh there's a problem there uh that we
don't really know how to solve but maybe
I'm mischaracterizing it
no it's it's actually gone through
working group last call and it does
have a specific explicit method of of
doing node ID validation
okay in that case my claim is that when
I reviewed it I didn't think it was that
convincing
okay
Stephen I I think that's resident in
Acme that's an Acme document so I mean
we'd love to see it happen if you want
to go and poke Acme to to get progress
on it we'd love that but it's I think
it's an accurately document that part
and based on I I do know based on your
feedback in the Acme working group and
for the purposes of Acme it is an
experimental method and an experimental
document
right so my recollection of the
resolution in the Acme working group was
um
we kind of notices that you know
acknowledging the lack of existence of
something like the main validation was
where that actually document seemed to
land
and what I'm saying is
if you want to figure out something
better
that's probably something to do here
because it's only here that you really
know how do you know how could you
meaningfully have some clue that the
node ID corresponds to some keeper
thank you
Bob I have a bit of a point of
information here as you're moving and
looking at pki
the international civil aviation
organization ikao
um has plans and development on an
international scale pki
they have a CP policy and the rest of it
the whole model for including all member
states in this pki all 179 signatures to
the Iko treaty and many of the
organizations like NASA and so forth
will end up being part of this for their
Aviation components
so I recommend that you look at this
particular pki and how you can
potentially leverage it and the policies
and the C organizations which be rolling
this out over the next couple years to
be able to to leverage and take
advantage instead of doing yet your own
PK and all the tremendous headaches that
that entails because for those of us
who've lived pki it hurts it hurts a lot
absolutely and and that is one of the
points of using these existing
structures is to not have to reinvent
the pki this this leverages all of the
existing x509 pki infrastructure yeah
you you also mentioned that you had a
short set of slides on an additional
topic can we go through those yes in
five or six minutes
yes okay yep
do I need to switch or change deck okay
uh so this short topic is about CLA
services and
the short background is that um there
were some earlier discussion on the
mailing list that about can we Define a
generic sort of abstract definition of
what a CLA is supposed to do in its
communication with the bundle protocol
agent
and
currently the lack of a common logical
interface has risks in that
implementations are free to completely
choose how a BPA and a CLA interact with
each other
this means that it's inevitably going to
result in in different terminology in
the CLA implementations different
terminology and the BP implementations
different configuration between the two
and potentially a lack of
inter interoperability of people's
understanding and configuration of
things so this is not talking about on
the wire interoperability but this is
talking about
um
when I say I've acknowledged when I say
A BPA has acknowledged reception what
does that really mean
right now there isn't really a clear
definition of that
and what this also does is it makes it
more difficult for a a node
implementation to swap out a BPA from a
CLA from an administrative element right
now those those three layers are
distinct in RFC 9171 but in
implementations it's not so easy to swap
out somebody else has a really good CLA
and I want to use it with my BPA if
they're not following the same service
model they're not going to be able to
work together and it becomes really
difficult
so um
I'm going to skip over the goals but the
the basic thing is that it's it's a
logical definition it's not an API uh
it's not talking about uh changings to
clas it's not talking about making
changes to to any of the existing
definitions it's trying to
come up with a a
harmonized definition of what's
happening in the same way that
um
when we talk about Network traffic
versus something like a posix socket
interface
um
it gives people a basis of how to think
about things
and helps understanding and
interoperability so this is a summary of
the current service listing
um for
for uh in relation to the current uh
udpcl tcpcl ltp CL
and Vibe and and the goal is to get
feedback on all kinds of strange clas
that people have been and plan on using
and how it fits in with this model
go ahead Rick
Rick Rick chair hat off
um I think this is great Brian I think
this is missing uh I I would love to uh
give you a better review and I will go
look it out when I get a spare moment I
think it is really important work I
think it also has use not only for CLA
implementers and BPA implementers I also
think it helps guide the working group
into understanding what we're doing with
forwarding
because forwarding fundamentally is
selecting clas understanding what a CLA
can do clearly will help us clearly
understand
how we express forwarding and how we get
on top of naming and addressing because
there is still some confusion
amongst all of us and some of it goes
back to the confusion about what a CLA
does doesn't do and fundamentally is so
I totally support getting it written
down
so and the other interesting thing on
that same topic is that there have
already been in the appendix a
discrepancies identified with the TCP
and the ltpcls and these are
discrepancies that are not necessarily
things that are wrong or incorrect about
the spec the things that are just left
open-ended that implementers are free to
do what they will but if they choose
different options they are losing some
aspects of interoperability
so part of this is just saying beware be
careful or negotiate you know different
implementations need to negotiate on
certain points that are not specified
cool
thank you
hey Brian any anything else before we
move on to the next presentation
uh only that uh feedback and
contributions are welcome uh this is not
being requested as a working group
adoption at the point but getting some
feedback is helpful thanks and just to
Echo Rick this is tremendously uh would
be a tremendously nice thing to have uh
and a request that that you also started
thread on the mailing list uh to so to
solicit those comments
and by extension a request from me to
the working group to say please join in
that discussion let's let's kind of get
this done I think it's handy
all right uh the next presentation uh is
uh Sarah heiner who is going to be
giving updates on the dtn management
architecture not the dtn management
architecture architecture
all right I think that's better
okay
so um Sarah heiner presenting the dtn
management architecture
um not dtan m-a-a oh okay sorry
I'll do my best but please remind me um
if you aren't hearing me well
um so I'm going to be talking to some of
the highlights
um and changes that we've made to this
document
um but there's of course not enough time
to address everything so I would
definitely encourage you to check out
the most up-to-date version which I
think is version three which is posted
online but we'll talk through the
problem space and then get into some of
the highlights like the reference model
and autonomy model
so as a quick sort of Rapid Fire
introduction to the dtnma you might
recognize it as the AMA which was the
asynchronous management architecture
we've renamed because asynchronous
doesn't capture that problem space the
way that we'd hoped to it wasn't the the
right term to be describing this work so
for now at least as a a useful
placeholder we've switched asynchronous
out for dtn dtn based management
architecture
and the three main components of the
dtnma
um is the response to needing to support
asynchronous Behavior so acknowledging
that you're managed and managing device
are not always going to be in constant
communication
um we need an autonomy engine to enable
self-management of those managed devices
and we need compact encodings that are
provided by our naming structures to
address the fact that we're operating in
a constrained environment so really high
level overview but we'll dig into these
pieces
foreign
so the first change that we made to the
document was defining the problem space
a bit better so we started by
identifying a dtn as a constrained
Network which emphasizes why we are
interested in Compact encodings and then
we refined that definition further to
say that a dtn is also a challenged
Network so that addresses the
asynchronous nature of the communication
and the fact that we have to deal with
challenges like disruptions and delays
which makes us focus on autonomy as a
way of responding to some of that
thank you
it's apparently a wonderful point that I
just made
so after we Define that problem space a
bit better we took a look at the
existing Network management work
um to see what could inform the design
and the structure of the dtnma
and as a quick review of some of that
research we took a look first at SNMP
and netconf and said that that
well-structured approach was good but
the low latency sessions that we need to
support an approach like that are not
something that we can guarantee in a dtn
we move to looking at rest conf which is
stateless but it still requires the huge
use of https and in some cases large
data transfers which again we can't
guarantee
and then core comp which is running over
coapp that provides the concise
encodings that we were looking towards
um because they use seawor for encoding
but they still require
um transfer of data using the Yang
schema and don't provide the autonomy
model that we thought we were looking
for
next slide please
so I've tried to distill that research
into a
something to let you visualize this
problem space but I will definitely
issue the disclaimer that this is an
oversimplified view into this problem
space so bear with me in trying to
justify how you should look at this
diagram
um
we think that the DT anime fits into the
intersection of these three circles
these three priorities for this network
management approach and we acknowledge
that there is existing good work in all
of these circles but we haven't found
something that lies at that intersection
so the dtnma for example prioritizes
autonomy there's work done in the anima
group here but this is for distributed
calculation of network data for data
centers it's not experiencing the same
constraints that we might in a dtn
similarly there is support for
asynchronous Behavior by Russ conf but
again requires running over https
using core comp we're getting those
efficient encodings but there is no
autonomy model that's associated with
that work
um because that was not the focus so
work in all of these three distinct
areas but how do we find a solution that
gives us all three uh autonomy support
for asynchronous behavior and those
efficient encodings
so following through on some of the
feedback that we got from the working
group one of the changes that we wanted
to make was to update the dtnma
reference model so on your left you'll
see the old AMA model
um and the feedback was that this was
just too generic in describing the
autonomy that we needed so we've updated
the DT anime model to show the use of an
autonomy engine and how that's
configured with policy and I promise
that
um
this figure will get a lot larger as we
dig into the details there so don't hurt
your eyes trying to look too closely
just yet
so before it gets even bigger I promise
we will actually talk to the details
here I just want to highlight the three
what I feel our main points for the
reference model that enable device
self-management which is ultimately what
we're trying to support with the dtnma
so first we are making use of pre-shared
definitions while I can't guarantee that
the managing and manage device are
always going to have a connection we
need to take advantage of the times
where they can have those brief periods
of connectivity so in that moment
um there is data and models that are
going to be pre-shared and the managing
and managed device are agreeing on data
definitions so that they can continue to
work when they are not connected
the second major piece is the dtnmas
agent self-management so this is where
that autonomy piece comes in that
managed device is often going to be
disconnected and it needs a way to act
on the policy sent over from the
managing device to tell it to react to
different events and how it should be
handling those different events
and then the third piece here is
command-based management so a command
and control interface that is provided
for that managing device to get
information like policy over to the
managed device since we can't support
bulk updates or moving large data stores
back and forth or instead using that
command-based management
okay so details as promised so we'll
start at the bottom of this diagram
um we're operating in a challenged
environment so real-time data
negotiation is not always guaranteed
um so we need to pre-share information
between the managing and managed device
and this includes information that
supports our autonomy model
also adms or the application data models
which are
standardized data sets that both the
managing and managed device agree on
and then we'll talk first through the
managing device and then move over to
the manage device so at the top of the
managing device are the applications and
services which are the source for policy
which informs autonomy so these
applications and services are creating
policy statements and they're also the
target for reports which are coming back
from that manage device
um they are operating with or without an
operator in the loop and this is an
example of an open loop control
the dtnma manager which sits on the
managing device serves as the interface
between those applications and services
and the dtnma agent
the DT anime manager will take the
policy statements from those
applications and services and translate
them into something that the detail
anime agent can understand so in this
case those are rules
the DT anime manager is also responsible
for reporting that's receiving reported
data back from the manage device and
then Distributing to the applications
and services that need it
and then
administrative configuration so keeping
track of things like agent mappings
and then if we move over to the manage
device we also have applications and
services sitting here and these are
being monitored by the agent which also
sits at the manage device
um and the agent is using a control
interface into these applications and
services to collect State information
um to alter the configuration of these
applications and also impact their
behavior
and we have one question from Rick
uh thank you Rick chat off and hack off
um you've got applications and services
on the managed device and I think I
understand what those are but you've
also got applications and services on
the managing device is that are they the
same ones and there's some kind of
mapping or do you have managing
applications and services that are
talking to applications and services
that are being managed
I've just got confused because it's the
same text in both places is are you
doing did you are you doing uh digital
twins
or are they just two different groups of
apps and services two two separate
groups thank you
thank you Rick and uh another question
Postgraduate School is a really helpful
talk to kind of frame a lot of this the
interface with application and services
going down to these controls
could you speak at all to some of the
the transport
uh control of that is there a
verification of delivery that's ever
done because obviously on uh dtn's
packet loss things not actually arriving
at the destination is a huge concern
sure absolutely and um
can I talk to you
yeah absolutely
um so the asynchronous which maybe is
still not the right word to use but the
asynchronous management protocol is
something that we've proposed to be
sending these controls back and forth
from the managing and managed device
um but I think that something that's
valuable about this approach here is
that that underlying transport to send
those controls I think that that is
still flexible we're not tied to what
we've chosen at this point
but
oh they both but was that the question
you were asking I guess it's uh if we
think of um you know it's like TCP
addressing everything delivering that
has a historically hard time on these uh
networks where the cause of packet loss
was not congestion
um and just you know this being the
working group that might have better
ideas of optimization for addressing
that in a tolerant Network so can I can
I just talk about this Rick chair hat on
I think the answer to this is
held elsewhere because what we've done
is tried to separate the reference model
for architecture
from the protocol specifications and the
recommendations for each of the lines
which actually do the communication so
if the communication between the
managing and managed device that was
running over dtn then the architecture
oh well ignoring what it runs over the
architecture will say you will need some
reliability or if you don't have
sufficient reliability here are things
that must be considered Etc so it's it's
describing a framework and reference
model
and I know somewhere in the pipeline
whether it exists as a draft or just in
people's heads at the moment saying and
here would be an implementation on top
of dtn possibly using custody transfer
bundling bundle in order to add that
reliability constraint a reliability uh
requirements to meet the requirement
from this reference model so it's kind
of where we're splitting a very big
piece of work into the bits which need
to be specified and standardized and
stuff which implementers can go away and
find Cool Tech that they have to fit the
gaps if that makes sense
yeah absolutely and thank you that
framework helps okay and and I would
just uh add a comment to Rick's comment
which is from from an acknowledgment
perspective because certainly one of the
questions is when policy is generated on
a managing device and is then sent in
some way to a managed device what is the
acknowledgment associated with that uh
some of that is uh considered and held
at a transport layer did the did the uh
policy actually get there to be
unwrapped uh alternatively some of the
policy in an open loop management system
could be when your policy has been
received one of your policy actions is
to produce and publish data associated
with this new update to the system
uh and so there are sort of a couple of
different ways in which a managed a
managing device could get information
back that's something it had sent prior
had been received either because there's
a transport acknowledgment that it was
received or there's new Behavior such as
additional reporting that comes back
from the device and then you know
because it is doing this new Behavior it
must have received its new policy
so there are a couple of layers where
that kind of question could be addressed
thank you
okay great
um so then next slide moving to the
dtnma agent
so the DT anime agent is
um interfacing with a few pieces here so
monitoring the state of the applications
and services that it knows and doing
that without a regular connection to the
managing device
um it's doing that uh by maintaining the
rules that are in its autonomy engine so
these rules are instructing it to act
based off of the state data that it's
sampling from these applications and
services
it's also performing data Fusion so
creating new data values or putting
together reports based off of the common
understanding of data definitions from
those pre-shared definitions at the
bottom of the diagram and then again
performing some administrative
configuration so keeping track of the
mapping to the managing devices for
example
looks like
so I've been saying autonomy quite a bit
but now we get the chance to dig into
the autonomy model a bit better
um and the autonomy model is important
because the manager and the agent again
will not be in constant communication so
how does the agent know what steps to
take based off of the data that it's
sampling
so if we start at the top of this
diagram here the manager is sending
policy Expressions to populate a rule
database that's local to the agent so
these rules are if a stimulus event
occurs then respond with this action
and those rules are informing the agent
of how it needs to be reacting
and the next slide to talk to the bottom
so when the agent is acknowledging one
of those stimulus events and needs to
react there are several ways that it can
do that it might impact the local rule
database itself
um the autonomy engine may also issue an
application control so in some way
impacting the behavior or configuration
of the applications that are being
managed
there might be a generation of a report
to get data then back to the manager
which is in charge of then Distributing
that further
um and it might also update the runtime
data store
which is local to that dtnma agent but
is updated as well by the manager in
times of connectivity so populating
information beyond the standard agreed
upon data definitions that are a part of
the adms
yeah
I think that that's my last slide so if
there are questions
[Music]
I'm gonna jump the queue because I'm set
in the chair
um
thank you Sarah I think this is really
good work and I know there's many other
people involved behind the scenes
getting this document put together I
think this goes back to my earlier
comment about framework having a
framework where we can talk and address
about these things in generalities
without getting caught up in a binary
representations and wire protocols and
all that exciting stuff and actually
understanding what we're trying to
achieve and and that very
um
simple but effective and non-turing
complete rules-based system that's very
clever stuff and uh yeah uh can I
request to the working group please
review this stuff this stuff is clever
and and it needs a lot of eyes over it
and it's an enjoyable read so thank you
Alberto
and uh and and so again uh there are
others for
um you know creating analypt in this
document it is it is a great read
um Echo your comments you know I
encourage every
single Latin need to to read the
document it's um it's very informative
and you know put a clear path to
implementation I have a few questions
I'll be sending all of them to the
mailer list but uh I think some of these
are interesting to the audience the
first one is uh why are you referring
directly to
bpv7 only in the documentation instead
of you know bpv7 and bpv6
well so I I can jump in on that uh just
for a moment to say that we actually
have users of potential users of this
model that aren't using either bpv6 or
bpv7 or BP at all so I I don't know that
that we specify or require bpv7 but I
kind of jumped ahead Sarah if you had an
answer to that oh I it was hard for me
to hear the answer to the question so
honestly I was just going to ask for a
repeat sorry hey yeah okay yeah it's not
mandated but there are you know even in
the in the abstract it goes straight to
bpv7 and
you know every time bundled protocol is
mentioned it goes straight to VP since I
was curious to see if there was you know
um any specifics there
um the second the second one is more a
comment you know I went to the document
the you know the use cases are fantastic
um one thing and this is you know
analogous to the discussion we had
around BP sex security context uh
it's that it doesn't talk about
coexistence with a non-challenged
segment of the network
um basically you know when we think
about etn networks and the ground
components how you know how you envision
the architecture could you know coexist
with other management implementations or
how you know DT anime would run on you
know scenarios that are you know a
segments that are not that challenge
sure that's a great point that um you
know we want to develop an architecture
that is robust enough that we're
handling the the challenges
um like I've mentioned with a dtn but at
the same time we don't want to be so
focused on addressing challenges that we
can't take advantage of the underlying
strengths of different network segments
um definitely an important point
awesome and and the last thing and this
is very responsiving there is a I'm
sorry go ahead but both Rick and I had
also a quick follow-up comment to that
one is uh several ietfs ago we had
someone present whose Master's thesis
was a netconf to amp Bridge uh to serve
uh that kind of boundary and and if you
can find that in the meeting minutes uh
you know for a past ITF uh please look
for it if not uh send me an email and I
can find it for you
my quick response was I'm not having had
to clarifying question my question
clarified earlier on the applications
and services on the managing devices one
of those or more of those could be
interoperable Bridges with existing
Management systems and that's how it
plugs into the model
so so you could you could view those as
Upstream management devices
okay awesome and and necessarily is one
thing that posted me a little bit on the
intermittent
um use case
and there is a sentence that says that
the you know in case of disconnections
the agent you know may store uh those uh
reports or may rely on the underlying
transport protocols some of it you know
I was a bit possible because I think the
whole idea was to rely on you know
bundled protocol type of networks but
then if we're imposing storage
constraints or
um not constraints but if we're inclined
that you may need to store messages I'm
not sure how this would uh you know
would help the whole architecture
sure
so if I could just jump in for a moment
I so so the concern is a Reliance on a
store and forward Network
um while we're also making the claim
that we are not dependent on running on
bpv7
is that your what is
you know it says that the agent May
store uh the message or their reports
until you know the link is available or
you know it could rely on the transport
protocol so I think that uh you know
that that post I mean a little bit
because the whole yeah at least that the
rest of the document
tends to imply that you know things like
a store and forward are you know
all right uh noted my only comment was
to say as well that there are some
instances of uh perhaps use of this
architecture uh in places that are not
running over bundle uh six or seven
but but certainly a bundle is there it
provides the service
okay thank you
uh thank you for the close read of the
the use cases and otherwise
so so thank you so much for the
presentation uh excellent presentation
my my request for the working group is
this document is a reef uh a an update
to the original AMA document and uh we
would like uh to finish it and so if you
have not had a chance to read it uh
please do please provide comments uh
back to uh the working group mailing
list
all right and next we have Scott Johnson
who wants to provide a a demo of IPv6
support for dtn Scott uh would you like
to uh have us present anything or would
you like to share your screen
um I think I'm going to go ahead and
share my screen if that's okay
sure
okay
um so I'm gonna go ahead and do that
foreign
Loop okay and so um hi everyone I'm
Scott Johnson and I'm presenting live
from inside uh hurricane Nicole as you
can see here
um I could tell you about myself at this
point but I I would rather talk about
ideas so I'm going to do this the
Hawaiian way and talk story a little bit
in lieu of uh autobiographical content
um the title of my talk today is
extending the reach of the delay
tolerant networking into IPv6 networks
or the ultimate Nat avoidance
as some here can attest from bearing
direct witness or their own personal
participation the internet was
conceptualized and designed to provide
end-to-end connectivity between any two
publicly numbered hosts between then and
now things have changed address scarcity
uh due to use and monetization has led
to the rise of that Scourge Nat in ipv4
Networks a spot check pins the going
market rate for IP address transfers at
approximately fifty dollars per ipv4
address between isps consequently retail
costs of the consumers has risen a
premium on static addresses to the
consumer further encourages the use of
that foul Kluge Nat and further breaks
the end-to-end design principle but hold
there is a way to restore this core
concept into the evolving growing
Network it is IPv6 and uh it holds the
promise of addresses of Plenty for all
just as it has for a couple of decades
now since we stood up the three ffe uh
six bone networks and put the protocol
through its paces
these days uh over 80 percent of mobile
networks are numbered uniquely only with
ibv6 according to your recent internet
Society study these Edge clients have a
particularly nasty strain of nat called
DS Lite used when connecting to ipv4
only hosts which makes an ipv4 and IPv6
tunnel two forward and added packets to
the client via dynamically allocated RFC
1918 address space
so in short we have
um IPv6 native mobile networks uh check
off of our list
the largest uh reaching eyes isps in the
Aaron region are now widely deploying
native IPv6 service to the client
devices via slack or dhcpv6 uh at the C8
at the CPE
from speaking with colleagues in other
rir regions similar or better deployment
is generally the case this tends to
restore the property of end-to-end
connectivity network-wide eliminating
the need for Nat and Nat traversal
techniques when trying to use the
internet as designed allowing
universally accessible services to be
offered if desired by client devices on
the edge of the network
adding to the tally IPv6 native fixed
access networks check
by adding IPv6 functions to Applications
previously only capable of ipv4
operation the reach of those
applications increases significantly all
the way to the modern terrestrial
Network Edge
this presents distinct opportunity for
the dtn community IPv6 enablement of bpv
BP based applications allows scalable
protocol stress testing and new
application development due to increased
use case scope for delayed tolerant
networking
in this light I have endeavored to add
uh ipv V6 support to the open source
branch of jpl's implementation of bundle
protocol and the associated software
suite ion
thus far the IPv6 enabled
UDP LD ltp over UDP and TCP convergence
layer adapters have been completed as
well as the new core Library functions
which they call
these convergence layer adapters have
been tested in both private land
environments and in Coast to Coast tests
on publicly numbered Networks
um as I demonstrate these three modes of
IPv6 operation running on a single node
concurrently for you I would ask that
you all consider uh which other
protocols that are implemented in ipv4
capable convergence layer adapters are
most desirable to be ported uh to IPv6
operation next
and so what you're seeing here is uh
five different nodes
um
on the top left the larger terminal is
um the primary node that I'm going to be
running the demonstration from the
remainder of the nodes will be receiving
uh bpings and responding uh knock on
wood because it's a live demonstration
I've written a small script here to
perform various functions to keep me
from having to type things
so here's a list of running a
convergence layer adapter protocols on
this node you can see we're using ltp
UDP and TCP and this is uh the command
BP admin L protocol uh showing this now
we need to press only the any key to
continue
uh here we're listing all bundle
protocol index on the Node you can see
we have an ltp node that is numbered
with basically packets allocation and
then we have a UTC UDP and TCP
um convergence layer adapters or index
rather that are listing on that IP
address
here the adducts for the node we have a
loopback on ltp and then two uh remote
nodes
um being two of these here on the screen
uh the UDP and TCP representations there
as well as the active TCP socket uh at
the bottom
here's the local ltp seat
that's running
here are the ltp spans that are running
and we're going to Ping
all these nodes to make sure we have
connectivity before we be ping test
it's worth noting that the top left uh
that's being now in the top right
terminal are running on the same host
under different user accounts
and both of those are running on a bgp
speaking router
which is announcing the ipv4 and IPv6
addresses that
um
are being used
here are the open sockets on the machine
and here we have our B pings you'll see
in the bottom left we have our
bundles being echoed back our visual
indication of the dots across the
terminal
and so that is from California to
Florida here in my data center which is
underneath the hurricane
uh this is locally on the same host from
one user account running a node to
another user account running a node and
this is over ltp by UDP the first test
was to Via UDP only
and here we are testing UDP uh ltp over
UDP Coast to Coast from California where
it's basicallypackets.com is uh residing
to my data center here in Florida
and finally TCP functionality between
Florida and California
and there we go
and so
um
once more or two or tally IPv6 enabled
delay tolerant networking check this
greatly broadens the terrestrial reach
of delay tolerant networks enabling
applications using BP to extend to the
true Network Edge
uh
I'll return you to my question what I
enabled convergence layer adapter should
have ipv V6 functionality added next
and I thank you all for your time
well first thank you very much uh and
second uh Rick
uh again thank you very much Scott I I'm
going to answer your question
um I think they all should I I think we
build conver any convergence layer that
runs on top of Ip should should support
V4 and V6 I I think that's a no-brainer
I'm not meaning
I think you've done a great piece of
work there it's great to see ion V6
native
um I think it's really good but the
answer is if we support IP we support V4
and V6 that's that's the way so great to
see that running thank you very much
it's always nice to see actual gtns
happening as a demo so
um thank you and enjoy the hurricane
thank you very much for uh for having me
and uh you know these these networks
that I operate here are designed to
withstand uh these hurricanes
um through many years of trial and error
that's why we wound up uh deploying our
own autonomous system for
um redundant routing
and and you have uh one more question uh
from Kevin
hi it's Kevin Paul it's really for
everyone um because it's it's been a
long time since I've put my nose into
this community so back in the day when
we were sort of thinking about different
clas and and uh
dare I say the FIB that we were that you
would do at the node
um the the vision was oh well the next
hop could be email the next cop could be
you know person on a bicycle with USB
key uh or one of my more favorites is
write the message up on the wall
somebody comes up later copies it down
and it goes on its way
um
you know this IP is obviously sort of in
the ietf but I'm wondering has there
been progress or work in any of those
more kind of wild ideas we had back in
the day so Rick chat on as far as I'm
aware that is still absolutely the
ambition uh
underwritten by the statements
convergence layer adapter that clear
separation between the act of creating
moving generating bundles and the things
which will do it so we keep that nice
layer separation I don't believe and I
would personally strongly push back
against anyone saying a CLA is always an
IP based service absolutely not never
intended to be no never a man on a
bicycle is a very valid cla a group of
them is probably more effective but yeah
I mean reindeer as CLA or reindeer as
transport I think has been rolled out
before
I see Scott got in the queue I mean
there was I recall years ago discussions
about a USB key is it a node or link for
example and it's you know
maybe it's a beer conversation but so we
have one one minute left I could I can
answer that actually
um there or or provide an answer to it
there is a um
uh member of the uh ipn Sig here with us
Sam agrasic who has just completed his
first uh uh running code for a uart
adapter uh so that's a Serial console
and that I believe he is using to
connect to Laura radios for
um uh long range Wireless uh terrestrial
connectivity but he can speak to that
more
hold on sorry Scott I'm gonna I'm gonna
call out there's a difference here
there's a difference between
putting
bits on the wire to carry things that
are built around a TCP streaming or a
UDP streaming packetized format and the
high layer concept which I think Kevin
was pointing at which is I can serialize
a bundle in some way and give it to a
thing which moves it
um it's great to see uh you know a patch
TCP or UDP running over over serial or
some kind of chunking that that moves
bundles over serial great great example
but I think Kevin's aiming at a much
higher concept which I agree with him of
if we can serialize it and move it
that's great
uh let me just uh interject here that uh
I think this is Laura uh it actually is
not tcpip
um it's uh it's it's native Laura uh and
and and the you're you're right other
clas that are not based on uh on IP are
certainly uh things we should be doing
and I'm gonna uh claim that we already
are
good
all right so with that uh we are at time
yes so thank you all very much again
please uh continue to use the mailing
list uh and if you were presenting
please make sure to post additional
questions and requests for review to
that list
otherwise thank you all very much speak
to you all in Yokohama if not on the
mailing list we might do an interim if
there's excitement about it
um enjoy
um
[Music]
have you not considered Tour de France
net yeah end of USB keys with the water
bottle
thank you