uh okay
oh
yeah that's right is it just one page
maybe
no I'm wondering
that looks better it does why did that
do that
okay sorry
foreign
command minus
there you go
ask me for sure
[Music]
all right after a two-minute launch
today we are ready to rock and roll uh
let me welcome Kevin uh who will be here
with us in room to represent project
Callisto an extraterrestrial
collaboration with webrtc and ab1 if
you're in this room and you are part of
the RTC web working group raise your
hand
okay so several people
um
cool other codec and other friendly
people here take it away
thanks Ted uh it's an honor for me to be
here speaking to all of you uh esteemed
internet engineering task force members
thank you for having me I'm Kevin I'm
with Cisco and I wanted to share with
you a brief version of the story of how
we came to participate in Project
Callisto we partnered with Lockheed
Martin
together with other companies in the
industry like Amazon with their Alexa
Technologies and Apple iPad Technologies
um to try to solve the problem of real
time or as real time as we can do given
the latencies uh Communications and deep
space exploration
and I want to give credit to the the
folks who worked on this implementation
and uh and built the original version of
this presentation
um I'm just here to share it with you
all
so what is Project Callisto it's a
technology package on board the Orion
spacecraft to test the viability of
commercial Technologies in space
exploration
uh and I mentioned those Technologies
already as WebEx by Cisco Amazon Alexa
an Apple iPad tablet mounted inside the
Orion spacecraft to allow future manned
or crude excuse me crude uh
space missions to collaborate in near
Real Time with folks on the ground
and Orion is the deep space exploration
spacecraft built by Lockheed Martin and
Artemis is the series of missions to fly
that spacecraft to the moon and
ultimately to land on the moon and to
perform Moon exploration and and
ultimately Mars uh
exploration
okay okay sure thank you
you can scan that QR code up at the Top
If you want to learn more or go to that
URL and sing tiny font up in the top
right hand corner Lockheed martin.com
and find the Callisto page there
so Artemis one is the first of the
Artemis missions that will launch from
Kennedy Space Center now targeting
November 16th launch window at 1am
Eastern time that's 6 a.m here in London
for those of us that live here and it
will circumnavigate the moon and return
to Earth as a test flight of this system
we're all super excited and uh crossing
our fingers that that November 16th date
holds
um they've been monitoring uh the
hurricane weather and there's they've
had a few uh resets on the on the
calendar but November 16th is the the
current scheduled launch date so we'll
see if that happens
and the challenge that we were asked to
solve
is real-time video HD collaboration in
space
and there was as you can imagine a few
technical challenges
the first one is It's a Long Way to the
Moon
you know our industry standard is 300
milliseconds round trip for real-time
collaboration
uh with project Callisto we were asked
to engineer it to up to 20 seconds or 20
000 milliseconds round trip which is uh
awfully a long time in the world of
Video Communications as those of you who
work on video now
and if you want to see what
to 20 000 milliseconds looks like uh
oh this is not a build slide I lost my
bill it's because I converted it to PDF
never mind
the PowerPoint version that line draws
out over 20 seconds so you can kind of
experience it
so obviously the questions are are we
going to have delays in the various
protocols not only at the video
bitstream layer in our ab1 codec but
also in protocols you know setting up
signaling uh you know connecting the
Call Etc
and how effective are our error
resilience and Recovery techniques going
to be in the face of these huge
latencies and packet loss and Jitter
thank you
I've got seven seconds remaining
what does that mean
oh
thank you Ted okay thank you yeah do
that do that okay well there we go
so this is how long it takes to send a
video frame
from the Earth to the
moonlander and respond right
awesome thanks for the demo tip
so the second problem is the satellite
network uh has pacquelos and Jitter and
very low bit rates so it's an
asynchronous network of 200 kilobits per
second Upstream from the ground to Orion
and one megabit down from Orion to the
ground and of that 200 200 milliseconds
160k of that is video
and 40K of that is audio so you know
that's a challenge to how do we get high
definition 30 frames per second video to
work at 160 kilobits per second
um and there's also pack of loss and
Jitter to contend with
the third problem is the first Artemis
Mission Artemis one is an uncrewed
flight there's no humans on the thing to
to touch the iPad and launch the app and
place the call and all of that stuff so
how in the world are we gonna solve that
you know how are we going to launch the
application how's the application going
to know when to join the call how you
know what happens if the app crashes
what happens if a pop-up gets in the way
of the application
um
and so there's no buddy to touch it and
there's no you know we couldn't use
Audible commands either because our
system is the thing that is receiving
audio from the ground playing it out of
our speaker uh on the iPad tablet and
then you know we could try to Loop that
back into the microphone I suppose but
like what what we'd have to we would
have to have a call up in order to have
that pathway established so like uh so
we had to come up with clever uh
Technologies for that our clever
techniques to solve that problem
so our solution
was to build a custom version of our
WebEx app
highly customized for this mission
and we built a new protocol translation
server that sits on a container
co-resident with our conferencing server
on the ground that we called the ground
control server
and we implemented a new UDP based
signaling protocol that gave us a single
round trip transaction
request response to join the call
eliminating all of the normal TCP and
TLS handshaking and multiple round trips
to get a call up
and that protocol converter simply
converted that new UDP protocol that we
implemented to the normal standard
webrtc HTTP websocket based
Communications protocol that we do
normally on our server for our normal
application
and we set up a simulated network of 20
milliseconds of latency and pack a loss
and Jitter and surprisingly it just
worked like out of the box we were
shocked except
uh h.264 video Codec kind of fell apart
at these low bit rates and looked pretty
bad
so we introduced ab1 into the project
which we had wanted to do but we tested
it with 264 before moving forward with
ab1 so we said yep okay confirmed 264 is
not going to work let's let's go ahead
and Implement everyone
so
uh just a few words about av1 I'm sure
many of you in the room are aware of it
and many of you I'm sure have
contributed to it but av1 is a new video
Codec designed by the alliance for open
media which was uh
sponsored by several companies but three
of those were Google Cisco and Mozilla
contributing our very our respective
video Codec Technologies into this
effort to produce a codec that would be
as good or better as h.265 while being
open source and royalty free and you can
read more about it at the you can read
more about R
contribution to that at that link down
at the bottom and I just want to shout
out Jonathan Rosenberg in the room here
for uh initiating and leading this
effort when when you're at Cisco thank
you Jonathan
um so we have our own implementation of
the Cisco av1 codec and that's primarily
because the aom version is not super
optimized for real-time low latency
bi-directional video conferencing
real-time communication so we have our
own implementation of the av-1 encoder
developed by colleagues in UK uh uh
Norway and China
and highly optimized for real-time
latency sensitive Communications for
decoding we use the open source davit
decoder from video land that was adopted
by aom
and that gives us these uh our
implementation gives us about 30 percent
uh better compression or 30 percent less
bit rate at uh the same complexity or
the same CPU consumption as our
reference open h.264 codec that we uh
publish in lots of other companies use
and we've integrated av1 into our WebEx
product in WebEx meetings and uh we also
implemented it into this custom version
of the WebEx app and the server the
conferencing server that we created for
this project Calista
so what were the challenges and
solutions at the video Codec bitstream
level that we had to solve so first of
all it had to have great quality or at
least good quality at extremely low bit
rate 160 kilobits per second and to
solve that av1 itself has inherently uh
in it you know lots of tools and
techniques for getting pretty decent
quality at very low bit rates like quad
tree super blocks and context adaptive
entropy coding and various other
techniques so we employed all of those
Second Challenge is the huge uh latency
up to 10 seconds in each Direction so
obviously uh packet loss requesting a
keyframe uh is not going to work so we
just simply ignore keyframe requests and
we generate keyframes periodically
um and then there's packet loss so we
implemented normally uh and I really
enjoyed Luke's presentation earlier
about quick over media uh so if you guys
attended that this morning then you
remember the IPP or IP BP you know Gob
structure that Luke talked about so we
implemented a a broadcast like Gap
structure with discardable P frames
and uh to make it more resilient to
pacalas and then the problem of
keyframes being traditionally very large
and subject to being just uh corrupted
by packet loss in in transit we
downscale have to half the resolution
then encode and then upscale on the
other end when we decode and and we also
allow the quality to kind of build up
over several frames if there's not a lot
of motion in the video
and the server and the app switch
between normal mode and this error
resilient mode described on the right
hand side of the slide based on the
frequency of IDR requests so if we start
getting IDR requests we switch into this
resilient mode and then we switch back
out of it to try to increase quality
when
IDR requests are not coming through so
we ignore them but we still get them and
we switch into this mode when as needed
so uh lastly I'll just say that um the
no touching and no audio interface the
solution to that was a custom
like MDM like uh thing that's sort of
like just a URL that says you know push
this URL to the to the OS and it will
launch the app and then we just
automatically join a predetermined
meeting URI so that's how we solve the
the no interaction problem
and I just wanted to close with giving
credit to my colleagues who contributed
to this I was the director of
engineering at the time uh and Thomas
and Dimitri and Alex on our team worked
on this together with many other uh
Engineers uh at Cisco and our colleagues
at Lockheed Martin so just wanted to say
thanks to all of them for making this
reality
fingers crossed this thing Launches on
November 16th thank you for having me
[Applause]
the queues are open so if you can please
use the tool I realized it was a little
bit hard for people uh because the
because of the URL uh problem on the
agenda
um but uh if you if you can't get into
the tool you can get in line and we'll
recognize you anyway but uh if you could
use the tool to to form a queue that'd
be great
uh Darren Dukes your first
yeah um so what was that what was that
user experience at 10 second delay you
know in One Direction is that going to
be a usable thing for when you tried it
in the labs we did yeah that's a good
question it is you know to be honest
it's a bit of a walkie-talkie kind of
mode
um you certainly can't interrupt each
other uh like you can on a normal video
conference uh even in normal video
conferencing interrupting is you know
you can accidentally step on each other
because of the end latency here that's
just exacerbated right that you really
need to kind of wait and let them finish
talking and uh before you try to speak
over them
um but other than that it works great
and the uh it's not just video but it's
also real-time whiteboarding and and
content sharing I should have mentioned
that in the presentation so imagine you
know we could draw together it would
take a while for what you've drawn to
show up for me and what I've drawn to
show for you but it works but so in
those space movies where they've got you
know something's gone wrong and the
engineering team's figuring it out they
could like whiteboard the solution
exactly in somewhat slow real time
exactly all right thanks thanks
uh I'm sure yeah
uh I think that uh you you choose the uh
av1 over H2 264 is because it's very
efficient right yes yeah but H2 uh 265
is also very efficient so what's the
benefit
between everyone and yeah
yeah I think from our perspective and I
don't know that everyone in the industry
shares this perspective but from our
perspective at Cisco uh the challenge
with h.265 is the patent um okay uh
challenge right so
for us ab1 is is open source and free to
use and uh so it makes sense even if
they're roughly equivalent technically
thank you
Jonathan yeah I can't I've tried a
million times and I can't get on the
on-site queue so I apologize Jonathan
Rosenberg super happy to see this this
is awesome
um normally there's a trade-off for
video encoding between computational
complexity and bandwidth uh and so to
get the bandwidth down you know you
could do a lot more work on the encoder
side did you also have computational
constraints but it's computational
complexity leads to I guess weight or
power or something that are all
considerations in the moon so what
what's the compute environment here
uh that's a good question I don't know
the details of the Apple iPad uh because
it's a it's an Apple iPad mounted inside
oh I missed that it's literally an iPad
it's literally an iPad Pro I thought
there was something
then then I withdraw my question thank
you
laughs
yeah it's a it's a very customized
version of our IOS app running on
uh Darren
uh yeah so just uh just maybe
um
one more with with the uh protocol that
you'd invented the the UDP based one to
get to the spacecraft uh do you see are
there any advantages to that did you did
you kind of discover anything
interesting with having to come up with
that is it usable outside of this use
case
uh that's a great question actually
I guess from our perspective we didn't
think that it was usable outside of this
very constrained use case because you
know we basically are doing you know we
disabled srtp we disabled TLS you know
so not the kind of thing we would
normally recommend you know customers to
do
um
so it was very like purpose Built For
This closed Network system
where confidentiality and and data
integrity and all that are less of a
concern okay and it just there was a
previous uh group above that was in
where we were talking about you know low
power stuff and you know uh it's
particularly
um things that were time sensitive as to
how much bandwidth was available and
whatnot it'd be kind of interesting if
you were to build up from what you got
to with that and minimally add back to
it what you'd end up with that could be
very low bandwidth but still have that
high quality in order to reach those
kind of rural areas yeah maybe on the
moon but yeah it made me feel like the
moon so it's an interesting question
yeah
yeah because I do think that there's a
huge opportunity there and like you know
remote farming communities or or other
places where you're yeah near Earth
orbit satellite networks and being able
to do really
low round trip transmission yeah
Communications yeah yeah I'm from more
Northern ish Canada not very Northern
Canada but uh yeah once you get outside
of the cell ranges right there's not a
lot of bandwidth right yeah thanks okay
Alyssa
um hi Alyssa hey nice to see you good to
see you thanks
uh can you talk a little bit about the
the limitations in terms of the features
and conferencing like could you have two
people on the ground joining a
conference with the moon like like in
terms of our normal typical experience
of video conferencing like what's
available in this context versus what we
are accustomed to is terrestrial users
of WebEx I love that you ask that
question because I should have mentioned
it on the slide because I lost the build
I kind of maybe missed some points
um
so on the ground they have normal WebEx
devices and like our board and our room
systems and our desktop systems like the
um
uh The Desk Pro for example and they're
they're all connected in a conference
with the Orion uh
spacecraft right so they can all have a
you know be having a real-time meeting
and the application that I believe NASA
wants to use it for is to invite you
know students kids other people from the
public into
their Ground Control uh
facility to
experience this and actually collaborate
with astronauts which is pretty cool
yeah that's awesome thanks
Juan Carlos
yeah so
I was curious because this is definitely
very interesting uh first use case and
looking into the future uh
we probably will face situations where
we will not have line of sight right
because this is the first time to the
Moon
the yeah that's right around the back
side go around and even further into the
future right you can think of Mars and
that's when normally Leo and stuff like
that right will come into picture when
so that we can
work when there are situations when
there's no line of sight in which cases
most likely there will be satellite
relays right so
have you thought or do you have any idea
in this case you showed that
architecture showing the proxy how you
simplify the the signaling uh onto the
space station but uh if ever we put more
relays or an Leo satellite network with
that
also work or have you guys thought about
that multi-hop
architecture that is a really good
question and and we didn't because we
didn't actually have a lot of detail
from NASA about the in in trick you know
the the inside details of how their
network works but it is a satellite
relay-based Network which is why the
latencies are up to 20 seconds because
the average distance from the Earth to
the Moon is much less than 20 seconds
it's like three but they said you need
to engineer for up to 20 seconds and
that's because it's going to be bouncing
off these satellites when it's like on
around the back side of the moon it has
to hit a satellite before it comes to
the Earth and so forth so but I I'm not
as familiar with the you know the
underlying details of how that satellite
network works and what we could do to
optimize it further so okay so there is
already multiple release yeah
extraordination release it goes from
their near-earth uh satellite Network to
their deep space satellite Network as as
it as it goes out even further away to
the Moon I think it switches to their
deep space Network
but you don't know how many hops to to I
don't know how many hops okay no
yeah
thank you you just joke what you just
answered my question because I was
curious how the 20 seconds do come into
place how they would decompose given the
architecture you showed in the beginning
yeah so so it's it's multiple realize
they are further out and and Bridge
large distances and there's just no one
not an easy shortest path yeah exactly
okay would there be any details on that
available at some point Sorry would
there be any details on that structure
available at some point that just let's
just be curious yeah we're super curious
too those details would have to come
from Lockheed and from NASA we were
asked not to I mean they didn't share it
was sort of like they shared with us
what we needed to know and and nothing
more
okay understood and I had to get
permission to to give this presentation
because even this amount of detail is
more than we had previously disclosed in
our uh you know respective marketing
announcements and stuff so I had to go
to them and ask for permission to share
this with you all right cool thanks yeah
oh yeah duncs like maybe you know when
your comment about that tells me you
know and someone asked my customers you
mentioned you disabled all the TLs and
srtp
was that just for practicality or was
that a policy like you know we want you
know people on the ground other people
on the ground people to watch it
live or no is they uh that's a good
question the disabling of TLS was for
practical reason you know to eliminate
around multiple round trips and
eliminate TCP and go with UDP
um but for srtp that was simply a
convenience thing that's like well we
don't need it it's an enclosed almost
like a closed circuit television kind of
network you know it's not connected to
the internet at all uh they're only
wondering and if you had any
thought maybe this isn't directly what
you're working on we had any thoughts
like if you did need to encrypt it how
would you do keying when you have a 20
second latency yeah exactly and like
rollover counters and stuff like that
come into play right did you have any
thoughts about that or just you turned
it off yeah we just no we didn't think
through that very hard we're just like
oh we don't need srtp we'll just disable
it and then so therefore we didn't have
to worry about rollover counters you
know so so we'll point out that if we
were doing this super quick you could do
uh zero rtt resumption if you started
the sessions before they left the Earth
that then you'd always just be resuming
something that you already had
um uh set up with the tickets anyway um
oh uh sorry something's wrong with the
um the in-room tools not letting a lot
of people in so uh yeah if I wasn't
clear about that if you can't get into
the tool you can get in line and we'll
just recognize you from the line sorry
about that so um mosinati um just
wondering if uh so this was obviously
for Converse or for human to human use
but I assume that there's a lot of video
you know from you know Telemetry systems
coming back and maybe even you know
robotic control that's you know delayed
in a lot of autonomous within 20 seconds
but maybe human controlled beyond that
is this is some next steps to maybe
think about broadening this to use this
core real-time uh communication
technology to go across all the video
feeds all the or even any sensory feeds
not just the video but any kind of
sensory data that's streaming back to
ground stations and then maybe
something that has a 20 second you know
reaction time that could usefully
feedback and and change the sensory
systems is there any future work to look
at doing something like that I I don't
know we had speculated on some things
like that too like for example somebody
on the ground could say hey
um Alexa you know turn the lights on or
turn the music up or whatever
to the uh to the Alexa that's running in
the Orion spacecraft right
um and I don't know if this is true at
all this is a total rumor but uh I
thought that I understood that they also
had a GoPro mounted inside the
spacecraft pointing at the iPad so that
from the ground they could see what's
being displayed on the iPad so there are
other systems and then I don't know
about the actual spacecraft itself and
all of the Telemetry and instrumentation
and all of that on the spacecraft itself
I have known but this was a human to
human intent intended communication
right okay
um while you were talking I I wondered I
know some of these uh WebEx and things
have the ability to do
um closed caption real time do you use
the closed captioning in real time did
you try doing that because I think
that'd be quite useful because of the
time delay being able to refer to the
text so
that that's a fantastic question and
there's a challenge with that which I
can't speak to authoritatively because
I'm not uh on the Amazon Alexa team but
they had the same challenge as uh you
know normally the device is able to
interpret the Wake word
so but then all of the actual
um
you know automatic speech recognition
and all of that stuff is done back in in
the cloud well this system is a closed
system there is no Cloud there is no
back end so they had to build a custom
version my understanding is Amazon had
to build a custom version of Alexa to do
a lot of that locally
and we would have the same problem
within the WebEx app is for real-time
closed captioning and real-time
translation we rely on back-end systems
to do all of that ASR and text-to-speech
and natural language processing NLP and
so forth uh all of that would have to be
built into the app itself
or into the server on the ground and not
connected to the internet and you know
it's all of those dependencies would be
the challenge that we would need to
solve
yeah
maybe in the future Mission they'll ask
us to to work on that
foreign
so um I'll take a moment then to thank
you again and I have to say uh I'm going
to reveal myself as very oh there's
somebody coming to the queue now
just just speak no worries okay sorry
um I just had a quick thought you said
that the terrestrial WebEx clients were
just normal ones right so did you ever
think about
um relaying the cloud processing through
those so that you can do all the
captioning of those kinds of extra
Services because those aren't in the
closed Network only I imagine they're
kind of fuel honed
so they are on the closed Network my
understanding so I think the entire
system is not connected to the internet
is what I
was led to understand oh uh so I think
it would still be a challenge too but
but yeah if you could
you know if those could be dual
interfaced with one leg and the NASA
Network and another leg connected to the
public internet then absolutely we could
do something like that yeah yeah
excuse me
okay
all right
I can't remember whether it was in your
slides but do you sort of took a FEC for
uh some of your Transmissions because it
seems like a
kind of useful thing you're right you
can't do arq for yeah you're right
that's a very good question and and we
should have we did not use FEC just for
this
simple fact that we didn't implement it
in that custom version of the app but
you're right in normal WebEx we
absolutely use FEC and we also use now
RTX re-transmission uh and in
combination so like we can dynamically
switch between forward or correction and
RTX free transmission and we can protect
the RTX packets so that the
re-transmissions have a higher chance of
getting through but we didn't have all
of that in this custom version of the
app so
um but yeah maybe a future version of it
if if NASA asks us to be a part of
Artemis 2 or Artemis 3 maybe we'll do
that because you're right effect would
definitely be useful
I guess sort of to drive that
potentially when it might be useful to
understand what's all lost patents are
around the um
transmissions and what drives those
whether it's solar storms or uh weather
yeah or some other kind of space weather
that then you could maybe alter the
level of FEC that you're using depending
on whether there's a sunspot or
something like that yeah
yeah you're right yeah okay
okay uh so let me let me say thank you
and let me also say uh this is a
wonderful Blast from the Past for me my
very first ietf I was here is a
representative of a contractor to NASA
um helping out with uh the very very
early days of the web so uh seeing this
work come here uh and get talked about
picking up some of the work that was
done here in webrtc uh some of the work
that many of the companies here have
contributed to an av1 and AO media it's
really great
um to see how far we've come and how
close it looks like uh the experience
they'll have and Artemis two and three
when they become crude missions uh to
what we can give our customers so that's
great thank you very much for coming
thank you Ted
all right
that was great thank you very much
well it's been a long time since I've
had to fight with lawyers