hi everyone uh we're going to get
started soon but just in the meantime a
reminder that you should scan that QR
code and get in the meet echo system so
you can put yourself in the queue
um also a reminder to wear a mask
and just give us a minute while we set
up
thank you
oh
um downstairs at the registration but um
I can go
thank you
I'm just gonna notify I don't know meat
Echo but we some of the slides we had
uploaded are not yet visible
not really sure how to refresh that but
we've got a few minutes before that's an
issue
okay I see it now cool thank you it
works it's so funny because
this shows it but when I go to share
pre-loaded slides it doesn't show us
that's probably fine
see they're only these three isn't that
strange
yeah yeah
okay yeah sorry I'm just speaking to the
meet Echo folks we've got the slides
um that we need in the uh materials list
but then when I go to share them
decks ready to be shared only has three
of the five
three of the five we've just had a
recent upload in the last few minutes
but um
yeah see there's a difference between
data tracker meeting materials and decks
ready to be shared
Colin's fixing everything right now
thank you Colin
got it
that is fantastic thank you okay we're
back on track folks we're going to get
started
um and really the
um
stick to get off this window okay
we're all set I'm just gonna pull up
chair slides and we'll go ahead
so this is the human rights protocol
considerations research group
um this is a two-hour session we have a
two invited talks and
um some pre
-loaded aob
um and so this is our agenda
do folks have
comments on this agenda at all
would you like to add yourself to aob
actually this is not accurate we do have
another update on a on a draft so Sophia
isn't here but I know she wants to be on
the agenda later for some of her work
other things
all right
um so in
um in that vein I'll also just remind
folks that this is being recorded
I'll again remind you to scan the QR
code so that you can get into the meat
Echo System put yourself on the Queue
when there's time for questions and
discussion
and also my last order of business at
the beginning is to ask if anybody would
mind taking notes during the discussion
this will be
not capturing the talks but rather
capturing the discussion after the talks
and discussion about our drafts can I
get a volunteer
thank you thanks very much Michaela
appreciate you
all right so just in um in the
introduction
I have to also remind you of the note
well you've maybe seen this a lot but
for those of you that have just come
today
it's important that you disclose any
intellectual property interests
when you're speaking at the ietf and the
irtf
um we also have a privacy and code of
conduct in our note well that's really
important if you haven't read that or
aren't familiar with it you should
re-familiarize yourself
um and so also I wanted to remind us of
the goals of the irtf because this
research group is within that so we're
focusing on the long-term issues
specifically This research group is
looking at the human rights
considerations of um internet protocols
and the standardization of those and and
we aren't setting standards uh we really
are
um publishing informational or
experimental documents
um but a lot of it is just discussion
and talks
which I think is a really valuable
Converse contribution to the community
and so we're chartered to research
specifically
um how internet protocols could both
strengthen or threaten human rights
and we use their two main documents that
we rely on to Define human rights that's
the universal Declaration of Human
Rights
um and then that's also the
international civil and political Rights
Convention
we've continuously begun like discussed
um two rights for the most part it's
freedom of expression freedom of
assembly
privacy is of course also a human right
but that is in a different research
group Siobhan is in the room he knows
there's plenty of overlap between our
research groups that's a good thing
and then I think also another wonderful
thing about our objectives is we bring
folks first in human rights into this
space to also hope that there's
pollination cross-pollination and the
other reduction where they become also
more familiar with
the technical community and the inner
workings of the ietf
foreign
we do have some drafts we're going to go
over them we have some published rfcs
[Music]
um
there are other outputs I think that are
less easy to quantify but tend to be
around sharing information publishing
blogs that sort of thing but you really
have to sort of follow the folks of us
that have been busy in this group for a
long time I'm wondering if aubry's in
the room I see Aubry online she's not
the previous co-chair of this and does a
lot of that as well
um
so work to date
um we you know we've been chartered
since 2015.
um there's a film online that you can
check out
um and then we've had our major work
published RFC 8280 which is really lays
out all of the human rights
considerations
um and we're currently working on a
document that's near publication well
it's in it's further in the publication
queue
um each and every meeting that sort of
takes 8280 and distills it down into a
sort of more bite-sized work I would
also say that the work to date I'm
including all the talks the invited
talks we've had the meetings we've held
we've held approximately 23 meetings
which is quite a few at this point
um and I'm just approximating because I
haven't actually counted but we've we
usually have about two sometimes three
talks per meeting so we've had 50
invited talks on a variety of different
topics
um there's a lot of discussion about
censorship which is going to be a one
that we will hear about today
um privacy and encryption
various forms of digital security
measures or considerations for groups
that are at risk and most marginalized
variety of emerging Technologies
including blockchain based things and um
environmental sustainability there's
probably things I'm missing but I just
tried to off the cuff remind like
remember what we've talked about in the
past
we have two current drafts
um we'll hear about both of them today
the updates on those they've both
progressed since the 114 meeting in
Philadelphia this is what I mentioned
before the guidelines for human rights
protocol considerations is a companion
document to RFC 8280 and then we have a
um a specific draft on free association
um and then this is for later so we'll
get back to these slides I'm going to
first
have us pause there's an important
um piece of the agenda right now I'm
going to ask Tara
to come on if you can
to explain the context here but this is
a sort of last minute addition to our
agenda that we're putting at the front
because I think it's an important
reminder for folks in this space so Tara
I'm just going to hand the mic to you at
this point
thank you Mallory
um
yeah thank you for
um holding this space to talk about uh
Allah and his in his mind of freedom
um
in his own words first and foremost was
uh there is a free and open source
developer He's a Part it was an
important part of our technical
community
he's also a writer a tireless Advocate
and activist with people's rights and
also for many he was one of the symbols
of the twenties of an Egyptian
revolution
um last but not least he's a beloved
colleague friend and member to many and
a loving father to his son khadid who
has been deprived from him as he spent
most of the nine last nine years as a
Prisoner of Conscious
I know it's a special person but his
situation unfortunately is far from
special
thousands of people language in Egyptian
prisons unfairly with no access to
lawyers tried under martial courts and
trumped up charges many just for being
in the wrong place at the wrong time
tens more dying because of terrible
conditions in these prisons in fact a
large crime was sharing a social media
post about one of those stories
furthermore his lawyer was also arrested
when he went to attend one of Allah's
interrogations
Allah was tried under a State security
Court which is a martial Court
while that was the official reason Allah
is in prison
Allah is also being punished for who he
is
as a symbol for many and for being
someone who always advocates for justice
even when it's not convenient easy or
popular
um
I think as a way in order to deter
others from standing up to tyranny and
in a way to teach him a lesson
Allah is also father and a friend who
has paid a big price for his activism
the past nine years with almost no sign
of improvement or recourse to Justice
and I went on a limited limited calorie
strike earlier this year
and escalated to a full hunger strike at
the beginning of the cop 27 U.N climate
Forum at the beginning of this week
and I did this because he wants to live
with his family friends and his son and
also because if he were to become a
symbol or a lesson he wanted to do it on
his own terms and teach the lesson he
wants to teach
um in many ways Allah has already won
his fight he exposed the Tyranny and
Injustice he and thousands of others are
are facing by the Egyptian government
and helped share their stories uh of the
thousands and prisons on a global
platform
he highlighted the empty Planet
attitudes of our world leaders and their
timidness to take any action let alone
on climate change
he also mobilized and gave hope energy
and urgency to hundreds and thousands of
people who share his desire for a better
world unlocking new avenues of
solidarity and Global mobilization all
from his prison cell and highlighted the
importance of the human rights as a
Cornerstone of human progress
Allah is doing what Allah does best he's
fighting to save us with all the means
at his disposal
what it means to be seen is what price
he has to pay and whether we can save
him back to give him a chance at living
his life again
we have heard no news from him since he
went on his full hunger strike the
Egyptian government is not giving access
to his lawyers
or um his legal comes is his Consular
access since he's also a British Citizen
and we have not heard any news the only
news we've heard is that there's a fear
that he's currently being force-fed
which is considered a form of torture
at this stage I would have loved to have
like a call of action for you of any
sort in order to help
um ask for your help and and not as
struggle for freedom
but unfortunately like the options seem
very limited at this stage I would ask
maybe that you
um look for the freedom for Allah page
on Twitter or and follow like whatever
actions they propose there at the moment
um in the meantime I thought the best
way to
um the best way to celebrate Allah at
this point was to share some of his
words because I think like as someone
who is really passionate for technology
uh new technology and
as someone who's also equally passionate
about human rights he would have
appreciated the work of this group and
would love to have critically engaged
with it
so I'm sharing some of the words that he
wrote that might be relevant to the work
of of this group that I found
um in this article written in 2016 Allah
was reflecting on
um platform economy and platforms like
uber and how they affect people's rights
um and he was reflecting on it from his
place in the prison cell not having
access to news on demand and just
whenever he could read or hear from
magazines that were available to him
um
Allah says
seeing as the standard cues of casting
doubt on official narratives and being
an inverted an advertent offender when
it comes to challenging hegemonic ideas
I find myself in intrinsically doubting
this account of disruptive Technologies
this is despite my usual enthusiasm for
modernization advancement in technology
Information Technology most of all and
despite the many benefits these Services
networks and Technologies offer me
it may be true that the Industrial
Revolution brought widespread affluence
but the painful convolutions that
accompany that were by no means quick to
subside and it was Generations before
things settled neither the luddites nor
their children nor even their
grandchildren reap the fruits of the
Industrial Revolution
and what relative Prosperity abroad was
not the result of Technology alone but
of the interplay between technology
technological innovation and political
reform
the periods of the regularization of the
work hours the prohibition of child
labor the establishment of industrial
safety regulations and traditional to
minimum wage the negotiation of wages to
collective bargaining the introduction
of regular statutory holidays an
acceptance of the idea that health and
education has rights to be granted in
the form of Public Services funded via
taxation from the profits of the
industrial revolution's beneficiaries
along with many other rights and
protections for the two age liberals
that we take for granted today
it is the same rights and protections
which the fourth Industrial Revolution
is threatening
if industrialized societies had
continued to allow Factory owners to
employ children for long hours in
inhuman conditions or fail to introduce
progressive taxation based on profit
as was the case early in the industrial
revolution it would not be possible
today to consider Luddite as a synonym
for stupidity and backwardness
most importantly the process of
transformation was a path of better
conflicts between different classes of
interests
liberal rights were invested by force
from States governments and Factory
workers after Decades of protests
struggles and revolution
yes the Lord has were defeated but in
their place came working class Fighters
and activists who did not reject
progress but sought to impose their own
terms on the course it would take
Elites and ruling classes treated them
with the same violence in the region
method out to the luddites but the
resistance continued and sometimes
protests were so hated that the workers
sabotaged machinery the difference of
course being that where the related Soul
design was a sabotage machinery the
workers so sabotage as a mean to exert
pressure which was rapidly replaced as
unionization and Industrial action
became legal rights designed to take the
place of violence in counter violence
to characterize the historical process
by the Industrial Revolution as
temporary birthing pains that gave away
to affluence and ease not only obscures
the details of the class conflict within
the major industrial Nations but also
the differing ways Nations experience
those transnational transitional pains
the Industrial Revolution brought about
Colonial expansion and increasing
Colonial violence as industrialized
nations opened new markets and select
new raw materials and Savage competition
between industrialized nations over the
fruits of modernization which resulted
in the outbreak of World Wars
in short the invention of new
technologies may be a given but their
growth in dissemination and the
structure of the markets and power
relations which are based upon them are
far from it they are the results of
political changes which are in turn the
outcome of conflicts within Society
understanding technological innovations
analyzing their effect and cultivating a
healthy skepticism but the propaganda
propaganda narratives which necessarily
accompany them is vital
fighting these Technologies and interest
behind them with the aim of directing
their course curbing the harms they
cause and expanding their benefits
increasing the number of people they
help and compensating those they harm is
therefore also vital
the only people more stupid than those
who stand in the way of History are
those who prostrate themselves before it
they leave no trace or memory at all
even as a cautionary tale to Developers
um that would be that's all I have for
you today
um please um in any way if you can if
you can I know talk to people uh let
them know more about the case help
um we just want to know what's happening
um to our friend and colleague
um whether he's still alive whether he's
still
um whether he's being force fed and we
also want him to get out safely and um
I'll leave you with his words
you have not been defeated
they have not yet been defeated
thank you Tara
um
we'll go ahead and move on
we won't uh take questions right now
um but thank you Abdul Salam for getting
in the queue um you can feel free to
express in the chat if you had a
question or so on but we will
now move on to Dimitri's talk
um
so come on up Dimitri I've got your
slides and you can use this pointer but
stand on the pink X
um
second because I don't see your slides
it's
like
for you
and I don't
yeah the slides are loading I just want
to say hello to everybody
and uh
very difficult presentation to follow in
the mica sorry I mean so you have to
speak right into the microphone sorry
plus that plus the Mask doesn't help
I I remember
um working with Allah in early 2000s on
an Arabic translation of a digital
security reference manual we were
building and
it's been difficult to follow this
unfortunate progress so I do hope that
if you have any means you know via
social media by physical contact with
relevant participants here at the
conference that you do bring up the case
as strongly as possible
all right to the presentation then just
testing the clicker and I'll come back
okay
I just had a recent cover test so don't
worry
how do I go for the slide so do I just
ask you all right
so my name is Dimitri vitalev I'm the
founding director of a digital security
firm out of Montreal called equality
we've been operational for about 13
years now I've been working in the space
of digital Security Solutions for the
protection and promotion of human rights
for about 20 years
the name equality assumes that this is
what we want to bring to the internet we
want to kind of equal out the playing
field between the users and very often
the victims of this network and the
powers that be you know the corporations
the governments that in large part
have built and control this network
we focus on web security capacity
building sensor resistance I'm going to
be talking to you about our work on web
security and censorship resistance
um today
and
I think
to mention right off the bat that all of
the solutions that we developed are
released free and open source
and you can find them on GitHub as well
thank you next slide
all right I'll mention briefly four of
our projects today
um a website security infrastructure
deflect a machine learning framework
that is operating inside this
infrastructure in order to help us
mitigate malicious requests sent to our
clients
a censorship circumvention system we
have built called Sino
and an emergency communications project
we have stood up in Ukraine since the
beginning of the war there and that is
basically helping people communicate
with each other when internet
connectivity
is not present I think by and large all
about Technologies are built in defense
of freedom of expression and Association
online
thank you Mallory thanks lab
all right so since 2011 the deflect
project uh has protected numerous uh
Independent Media Human Rights group
democracy movements from various cyber
attacks now these can be the sort of run
of the mill cyber attacks you know which
everybody faces when they're being
online
all the way up to a very well
coordinated and quite massive
um cyber attacks
with uh you know
sometimes evident State adversaries
behind them
and we've been doing this yeah for 12
years now so the deflect Network kind of
offers four Ps to its clients obviously
protection
um and performance it is really a
reverse proxy caching network with quite
a lot of load balancing and intelligence
and elasticity built into the network
by a virtue of you know being in many
locations around the world and doing
caching you know it also kind of speeds
up
the delivery of a client's web pages to
their readers
in difference to many other uh efforts
out there this is a network and a team
that is very much defined by its
principles we don't work with simply any
website out there we have criteria for
the type of content our clients
may not present on their websites
including assignment to violence hate
speech so on and so forth and we Define
the processes for how we go about
resolving various abuse complaints that
come in and they do come in quite often
some of them legitimate some of them
social engineering
and by and large this is a philanthropic
service it has a commercial arm it has a
non-profit arm uh all profits you know
derived from offering the commercial
Service uh
channeled into supporting and offering a
free service to various civil societies
out there next slide please
so yeah just briefly how it's built
um as I mentioned before reverse proxy
caching clients point the DNS to the
deflect infrastructure
we make sure various requests are
distributed across our servers in about
25 different data centers now
and within the infrastructure itself uh
clients are obviously offered caching
human support in about six different
languages
uh various analytics on the traffic both
malicious and legitimate coming at their
web presence
it also offers secure hosting for
websites developing the WordPress
framework
and machine learning about detection
which I'll talk about a little bit later
being an open source infrastructure we
encourage third parties to stand up
their own versions of the left and they
can call it whatever they like really
and this is 12 years of work packaged
into an easily provisionable and managed
architecture
and that you know probably costs tens of
millions of dollars to rebuild from
scratch so go and get it it's free
next slide
about a million people come through our
Network every day about 75 million
unique IPS served on an annual basis
it's around two percent of people
connected to the internet
um and yeah quite a lot of experience
mitigating various attacks
slide
there's a sum of the attacks that
deflect protects its clients from
uh possibly none of these are new to you
uh we are layer seven
uh defenses primarily and we also
protect our clients from quite a few
legal attacks
uh which happen uh you know often enough
several times a month you know we're
getting
quasi-legitimate legitimate to
completely false and erroneous and legal
attacks
by and large without a sort of an
experienced partner protecting a website
you know an invalid dmca take down
request just works even if there's no
DMC content you know that they're
complaining about so we're also there to
help with that
next slide
now
in order to get evenings and weekends
off you know we've had to develop quite
a lot of technology to help us mitigate
these attacks particularly
we also delved into the whole world of
machine-led mitigation you know trying
to figure out how we can train a model
to differentiate between legitimate and
malicious requests
after three years of r d and a lot of uh
wrong turns and directions we finally
found the approach that has become
basketball so we basically trained the
model on recognizing what is human
behavior and thereafter looking at
algorithmic machine-led Behavior as
anomalies
this is an infrastructure called
basketball
and I think one of the main advantages
to it
for us and for anybody else who adopts
this kind of framework on their own ends
is that a lot of the pre-processing
uh happens at the network Edge and only
you know Vector features are being
communicated into the Clearinghouse so
this is what we believe is a sort of a
private by Design system
even though you're using it to ingest
and make sense of web logs we're not
communicating any pii across the network
um basketball
yeah
is also open source and also I welcome
you to take a look at it on GitHub and
to try and deploy it you can deploy it
either
as a SAS service where you are the
client sending us the vector features or
you can take the whole framework
including the Clearinghouse and try it
out with yourself we ship with the
default model not with the deflect model
next slide please
um yeah on the right hand side this is a
gift that obviously doesn't give inside
a PDF
um
but yeah at the moment basketball
settings are two minute sliding window
uh it can adapt to any web traffic every
IP log entry generates a prediction
and we don't allow the machine to make
the final decision on whether
an IPS representing a human or a bot
anomalies above a particular threshold
are then challenged by the deflect
system uh we send the basically a
reverse shot challenge to the browser to
prove that there is a browser behind
this IP and and it is not about
on deflect it is doing about 40 million
lines uh per day and over 35 behavioral
features have been modeled already
next slide
yeah you can see an attack basically in
action
where in the last 24 hours 150 000 IPS
uh have breached the threshold they were
all challenged
and as you can see as well you know a
thousands of those IPS had passed the
challenge meaning it was a false
positive so again I think we feel it's
important not to let the machine make
the final decision here on who's who in
the network
and um
yeah send the challenge to make sure
thanks sly
from about a week ago an example of what
an attack looks like this is a Ukrainian
media from the town of
uh three various attack types
33 million malicious requests quite a
large botnet over over a hundred
thousand Bots
I mean this is basically what the
day-to-day on deflect looks like because
we work quite a lot with heavily
targeted websites you know we're really
uh are I guess a Honeypot for a lot of
the malicious activity happening on the
internet today
next slide
right so moving from the protection of
freedom of Association and uh on the
internet we feel that you know bring
down a website is another form of
censorship you know you can block a user
from accessing particularly resource so
you can destroy that resource as well
um moving on actually from destroying
that resource and the protection that
deflect offers I want to talk to you now
about blocking the user from accessing
particular resources
or the internet in general filtering
censorship and network shutdowns that
we're seeing more and more today
I'm going to focus here on the Ukrainian
use case I think it is very much a focus
for my organization now
you can see here quite an old Network
map
of Ukraine with Crimea still connected
to the Ukrainian Network and the donbass
the east of Ukraine
also connected to the Ukrainian Network
now that is not actually the case
anymore a lot of the occupied
territories have been rerouted to the
runet meaning to the Russian internet
meaning that people living in these
temporarily occupying territories are
part of the Russian internet now and
therefore behind Russian Network
surveillance and Russian censorship
next slide
so I'm going to talk about two types of
internet shutdowns and what kind of
solutions my organization is bringing to
bear
to challenge these kind of shutdowns
um the most prevalent of which
um that I call scenario one in this
presentation you know and that we see
quite a lot around the world you know
from Russia to Belarus to Kazakhstan to
Iran at the moment you know and to quite
a lot of countries in Africa so on and
so forth Northern India
is the disconnection of popular internet
services you know the Internet by and
large is very much dependent on a few
companies now and if you can block the
IP space of these companies of this
Cloud providers you have virtually
blocked uh any usable internet uh from
the population usually when you
implement a shutdown like this you also
want to Target you know VPN services
that people might use to circumvent
these blocks
next slide
so as a solution for scenario one we
have devised the the Sino browser C
knows an abbreviation of sendship.no
with the model share the web and I'll
explain why
we shared the web next slide
so see now is trying to kind of change
uh or introduce a new generation of
circumvention technology which is not
reliant on connecting to sort of a
single Hub proxy solution whether it's
VPN or something similar
we have actually built uh Cena to use
the BitTorrent protocol for routing and
for distributed storage
um it is the first web browser of its
kind which is actually using the
BitTorrent Network in order to fetch a
particular resource have it inserted
into the bittern DHT and then delivered
back to the user
biggest difficulty was really in
rebuilding this web page on a user's
browser you notice so that it shows you
know in the same way as before allowing
for dynamic connectivity with the
website as well
next slide
Now by virtue of using the BitTorrent
protocol and by virtue of networks
allowing incoming connections to a
particular device
every user of Sino also becomes an
active node
this means that we have as many nodes as
many proxies if you like as there are
users
now this allows any person
here in the UK wherever it is that you
live that
is possible in a network not being
censored to become a routing node for
somebody living in a network that is
being censored your phone's connectivity
is automatically registered inside the
DHT and people in Iran people in Russia
people in other countries undergoing
shutdowns are able to connect to the
rest of the network through you
this is particularly important because
in a scenario number one of Internet
shutdowns your IP is not part of a large
corporate public IP space urp is usually
not included on the block lists of when
internet shutdowns are being implemented
and all you need to do is install the
app and have it open and running a new
phone
this is what we call Cooperative
browsing inside signal
next slide
now also by virtue of using BitTorrent
we have
the ability to do decentralized caching
now this is very interesting because
what it means is that when you have
opened a page which is censored in your
particular Network environment the next
person to open a page doesn't need to
leave the network the national Network
anymore they can simply get it from your
phone
and this has been you know a huge Boon
really
for preserving the connectivity between
IPS inside and outside the censored Zone
because frequently requested content is
often important content particularly
during a shutdown
it is only neat it only needs to be
imported into the network you know once
or twice and thereafter thousands or
Millions
of readers can access it without leaving
the Network anymore
this also allows us to continue
content distribution among people inside
the censored Zone once the internet has
been completely external connectivity
has been completely switched up and I'll
come back to talking a little bit more
about this
next slide
in shutdown scenario number two total
disconnection
so
sorry not yet
um
so total disconnection means that either
a cable connecting your particular
Network Village
town maybe even City or the various
cables that connect you to the rest of
the national network which connects you
to the rest of the global Network
are no longer functioning
in the Ukrainian example this is
happening because of military activity
because of bombardments you know regions
are being disconnected from the rest of
the Ukrainian internet and the rest of
the global internet of course that by
default
this means that no proxy is going to
save you you know no clever method is
going to get you out of the Zone because
there is no connectivity
this means that you'll never get to
Facebook or Whatsapp or telegram or
whatever it is that you need to get to
because that is located physically
outside of a town or region
next slide
so to to deal with this problem you know
we're using decentralized uh protocols
and services really I mean um
this centralized internet is being
pitched as number three at the moment
and really I think it's you know number
one
you know the first internet plus you
know internet 2.0 of social media the
centralized internet has equaled the
decentralized internet really but I
think it's a future that is actually
revisiting the past
so
all we need to do in this case is
actually bring the services the servers
the protocols that people need
to have in order to communicate with
each other back into their Geographic
localities back into their Networks
it's not a very complicated idea but
we've just moved away from that so far
in the last 20 years or so
um I think now with the pushes behind
web 3
we are beginning to realize the
opportunities that were lost and what we
can regain once again by bringing
either the servers closer to the users
or getting rid of this notion altogether
and considering that we are all you know
we can all be service to each other
obviously email is an old example of
this as now you know growing popularity
is the Matrix protocol you know
decentralized Federated protocol and
decentralization is really key behind a
lot of the technology that we're
developing now for censorship resistance
next slide
so once again back to Ukraine uh the
project that we stood up uh in early
March after the second invasion began
was based really on collating and
presenting
um a readable menu and a few user guides
and to the Ukrainian population we went
and sourced machines with as many
[Music]
um
isps who actually still had hosting
racks in their vicinity in the locality
um at the moment the decoms project is
uh in nine different regions of Ukraine
uh also inside occupied territories
and each of those servers basically
presents ready to go uh Matrix chat
rooms
um actually next slide
and ready to go Matrix chat rooms with
the the new sort of interface that the
Matrix team is developing element and
that allows people to have a either web
interface or an app interface in order
to talk on Matrix channels there are
public rooms
uh where hundreds sometimes thousands of
people are using to communicate with
each other there are obviously private
rooms where we don't know what is
happening
um aside from metrics we're also
offering them the decentralized micro
blogging platform Mastodon uh so in nine
different locations also with Federation
set up and working
uh we're offering each of the services
also a Delta chat server and Delta chat
is another messaging system that is
actually using the SMTP protocol for
communications with end-to-end
encryption by pgp
and the Briar chatting system uh which
by default uses the tone Network as its
primary Communications protocol and
fails over to Bluetooth mesh device to
device connectivity in the absence of
any internet altogether
now mesh connectivity you know is not
necessarily an ideal solution for every
use case but when you consider that many
people
in Eastern Europe are living in large
blocks of flats
or may find themselves you know inside a
bomb shelter
or you know maybe even protesting or
being outside in the street in a similar
space you know Mesh networking
becomes a very useful tool in the
absence of any other communication
options
and obviously we are also
um offering offline downloads of some
technology including the senior browser
next slide please
now the Sino browser is underpinned by
what is essentially a core technology we
have developed called winet
um so win it is the library that is
doing all of the the centralized caching
content delivery
bringing requests to the edge of the
network where
um web pages are being imported into the
DHT signed distributed delivered so on
and so forth so we net is uh available
as an SDK
for the Android platform and as an open
source library in I think
C plus
uh which can really work with any type
of traffic you know with instant
messaging with the email so on and so
forth so CNO is the application layer
sitting on top of vnet and we net is a
library that you can be using inside
your Technologies for decentralized
Content distribution
authenticated content distribution
next slide please
so what we're trying to do now for
networks experiencing disconnections
is not have content imported to the
network simply by user requests but
actually
um preemptively going to crawl an entire
web resource let's say it's Wikipedia or
let's say
it's the Guardian news side or whatever
and preemptively injecting that into the
network
so the weekroll tool uh also in
collaboration with web recorder is now
tasking itself with the crawling
scraping whatever you like web resources
that we believe are essential to people
um living inside uh Sunset Network
and these web resources are then
accessible to the user as the guardian
website is normally via this in a
browser you know even if there's no way
to get to the guardian but we have
injected all of their resources into the
DHT
they can access it by the web browser
using the normal URL as before
next slide
then we need a Content delivery
mechanism we need a transport you know
to be able to bring this script packages
into a disconnected Network so obviously
this internet satellites and you know
Elon Musk is
had his Heyday in uh
in Ukraine until recently until some of
the latest outbursts uh with a promotion
proliferation of The Styling system
um
internet uh satellite internet is a
solution in locations where it is
accessible and where it doesn't present
a greater danger to the users by virtue
you know being quite easily geolocated
um another thing that we're doing is
actually looking into placing data
packets inside
um TV satellite streams TV satellite
broadcasts which are obviously one-way
Communications but that is kind of all
we need
so we can have a overt TV channel and a
cover Channel inside that
delivering data into a country where
there are a lot of TV satellite dishes
next slide
so we're trying to piece all of this
together now
basically figuring out which web
resources are in demand and hopefully
we're not the ones really deciding all
the time that we can
have a way to crowdsource these requests
you know which web resources people
living inside a disconnected Network
want to have present on their Network
then
um scraping those resources turning them
into web cash
delivering them inside
the sensor Zone
and using the winet infrastructure
present on people's devices on people's
computers
to propagate it inside the censored Zone
thereafter so basically rebuilding
pieces of the internet
pieces of a static internet by virtue of
whip cache inside a sensored Zone
next slide
and this is the penultimate slide and
with the proposal for the protocol stack
right there at the end
um
the
ability for us yeah
to use this Sino Network as a means to
propagate a web cache
is efficient because we only need a few
injection points you know we don't need
the entire population to have the
injected content you know we only need a
few people nodes to be able to receive
it thereafter propagates peer-to-peer
at the moment we are trying to come up
with a sort of a multi-thronged approach
to see how best to deliver this content
and not settling maybe on a single
channel of delivery but weighing up the
pros and cons of each different Channel
and I think a goal for 2023 will be to
decide what to do with a lot of the web
cache that we already have by virtue of
running the deflect Network
and this is with a protocol pitch comes
in you know deflect as I mentioned in
the beginning is a web caching
infrastructure as well reverse proxing
creating web cache distributed to to
users a million people are generating
cash on our Network at the same time
ideally we would want to have this cache
immediately available inside the winner
Network it just makes sense a for us as
a company running both infrastructures
disparate infrastructures
both of them dealing with web cache in
various ways and for
um
a similar goal and that is content
accessibility
we don't have a protocol that would
allow us to take you know web cache
generated by nginx and put it into
um the BitTorrent DHT so that it is read
in the same way you know on the Firefox
browser it is something we're beginning
to actually
uh think about and hopefully present to
you in the upcoming conferences of how
we can have a interchangeable web
caching standard
and the final slide please
um since you'll have the PDFs of this uh
you'll be able to come back through this
presentation that I went through rather
quickly here you have the links to the
various projects that I mentioned one I
didn't mention I'm just actually out of
Kiev now where we launched the naidino
platform which is a national digital
security helpline
um that is meant to serve the entire
population with the most basic digital
security questions
and we are working with the global nog
Alliance on the keep Ukraine connected
program
um at the moment you might have uh seen
on the news power is a huge electricity
power generation power delivery
distribution is a huge problem in
Ukraine and many of the isps cannot
serve their clients during blackouts
um It All Happened very suddenly of
course Russia targeted electricity
distribution centers
and although Ukraine has the electricity
needs it cannot distribute it everywhere
including to these isps they only had
UPS's you know there as a normalized
speed would which lasts for about an
hour
so we're trying to import about a tons
of batteries
um lithium gel
anything we can get our hands on the
nearby region uh has been kind of
stripped of batteries
and through the global nogalines deliver
these batteries to various isps so if
you do have some time use the QR code
check out the global novel lines and
cooperate with them donate to them and
yeah help us keep Ukraine connected
thank you I'm not sure if I have time
for questions we we certainly do have
time for percussions um I think it's
important so I there's somebody in the
queue also a reminder to everyone to
just join the queue if you can through
the meet Echo
um function and yeah go ahead Carlin
uh Colin Perkins with no hats
um so I think this idea of the um the
Sino browser using uh bittorrents and
the super skills is interesting
um
obviously there's a lot of personalized
content in the internet
um do you have measures of how effective
the web caching is given all this
content because you know clearly
something personalized to me can't
effectively be cached
yeah very much so yeah I mean
the internet really at the moment you
know isn't built to be cached and
recreated somewhere else so actually
quite a lot of the you know the five
years of trial and error and that went
into Sino was to build the intelligence
into the Sino client itself to figure
out what to cash and what not to cash
um so any kind of cookie authenticated
content
uh automatically is only transmitted to
the requester and isn't cached in a DHT
um also the user inside the settings has
the options to switch on and switch off
whether they want to Cache this content
and share it with others yeah
okay makes sense my other question was
um you know this is obviously very
effective for providing connectivity
um does it provide any form of uh onion
rooting or
um so traffic analysis resistance
um by default no and we're very clear
about that in our documentations that
you know this isn't a network anonymity
this isn't really even a network for
privacy it doesn't really add too many I
mean I think it kind of balances out the
primary properties it adds and the
Privacy properties that actually gets
rid of uh so yeah we're trying to be
very clear that this is really content
delivery system for censorship
circumvention uh having a content
uh sharing your content with others you
know allows you to see who's requesting
that content from your device as well so
yeah we're trying to be very clear in
our documentations of its advantages and
disadvantages too by not misrepresenting
what it isn't yeah yeah sure sure I
think it would be interesting to explore
to what extent uh the the pin Network
could be used for onion rooting style
um
you know to try and provide some of this
resistance very much bouncing the
traffic around yeah anyway yeah yeah
okay thank you thank you
uh hi there thanks for the presentation
dkg you're just a little soft
you're going through the presentation
and
um and thanks for the interesting work
um I had a question that was similar to
uh what Colin asked which is um
uh so
so in addition to the sort of risks of
targeting a distribution I mean we just
heard
um
about the you know risks to people for
sharing specific content
um it seems like your devices can share
specific content through these uh
through something like Xeno
um even more explicitly this is your
your device right
um
I I wonder if you have any thoughts
about how
uh
if there are defenses there and then the
other uh similarly with a
with sharing content you know it seems
like this is a Content distribution
means of getting information into
censored areas but it's not clear to me
how it gets information out of censored
areas
so somebody within the censored area
might be interested in what people are
outside because they're saying
um but uh
I don't I don't know from the
description I didn't understand whether
it was possible to also uh
uh get news out from within the firewall
can you talk about that
yeah thank you dkg
um so yeah on the kind of uh guilt by
connection or Guild by association front
I mean what we've tried to do is make
DHT traversal
um
very complicated if not impossible in a
way that we're using uh the particular
bits are in protocols so you can't crawl
the DHT to figure out
who is doing what you can see people
connected to the DHT you cannot see the
content that uh they're requesting a
sharing inside the DHT itself
yes you can be you know a malicious
actor or let's say a law enforcement
actor
and download the legal content to see
who connects to you in order to retrieve
it but then you're also guilty of
downloading it as the people maybe
unwillingly so connect to your device to
get it from not a very strong defense
but nonetheless I think that has some
uh legal footing to it in some instances
um
all PDP
efforts I believe you know I have this
chicken and egg problem you know we need
a big haystack
and until there are millions and
millions of nodes and users and a lot of
you know content of various
uh origin and uh various interest in the
network
um
these problems you know are I think a
lot more serious and a lot more
prevalent until then
when there is a huge amount of content
inside the network of all sorts and
types I think
the statistical probability that you're
going to figure out a network of
activists by downloading you know the
amnesty org page through Sino and then
seeing who connects to you to share it
uh decreases
um
so I I want to understand how you how
house you know is thinking about the the
authenticity questions as well right so
your your description of one of the
legal defenses
um
for say law enforcement seeing who
connects to the MSC page well
unfortunately simply claim that they
have the amnesty page right inject that
claim into the DHT and then the law
enforcement wouldn't themselves be
retransmitting the NFC page they'd just
be looking to see who comes crawling the
DHT
to think they have the amnesty page
right so they wouldn't actually be
redistributing the content themselves
they're just doing a surveillance
Gathering or something like that are
there authenticity protections available
um
I think
[Music]
um
I'll deflect your question a little bit
uh for the interests of time
um I will just talk quickly about one
type of authenticities that I think I am
qualified enough to discuss maybe we can
go back to slide 23 just quickly
uh authenticity of content injected into
the network and then delivered to the
user happens through uh content
signatures which are made by injectors
as you see on the right hand side of
that diagram
uh run by well in this case equality but
anybody can stand up their own winit
infrastructure and if you want to serve
you know web content through it run your
own injectors
so injectors are signing the content and
this content packet carries the
signature throughout its life cycle
inside the DHT
um
signature validation is hard coded into
the casino client
um but maybe yeah on your other question
of authenticity
inside the DHT I'll I'll just deflect it
for I think lack of
uh uh ability to give you a concise or
maybe even a correct answer
um but please uh maybe post it as an
issue in a censorship no
uh report on GitHub and uh
we'll answer it there if you don't mind
so I have sort of a related questions to
Ted lemon um
first of all uh there it seems like
there are two ways that you could attack
this in order to by the way this is
really cool I don't want to imply this
is bad I'm just like thinking with my
how do we defend it hat on
um two ways to attack this uh one would
be
is it possible for a bad actor to put
bad data into the cache
simply by deliberately providing enough
instances that are producing that data
that nobody else feels like they need to
produce it is there a defense against
that
do you see what I what I'm saying yeah
okay
um
the request for new data
uh
uh in the current Sino architecture
comes from the user Itself by the URL so
the URL is a really key piece of
addressing and routing in our system
um
this request is communicated to the
injector
inject their IPs are also unfortunately
for the time being hard-coded into the
client
and
if the injectors are not accessible
because the sensor as well can get you
know a copy of the Cena browser then you
know the entire network of others you
know users that have incoming
connections become Bridges to that
injector now as I just mentioned
injectors are run by quality in this
instance and it is them who fetch
content requested by the URL and then
sign it before injecting it okay so it's
signed with your keys yeah okay so that
that's that seems like a good defense
against that attack the other sort of
obvious attack is if somebody manages to
suborn your infrastructure so that they
have access to your keys and potentially
your infrastructure and can inject bad
data that way have you what's your
feeling about the or what you know what
are you what's your thinking about that
problem
look I mean also not a short answer yeah
uh also we do understand that in this
particular use case where people want to
browse the web because that's where the
content is we need to deliver the web we
need to have an interface between the
web and the DHT which is the injectors
the injectors are a point of
vulnerability we do do protect them
using just you know internal
um company experience and you know
um best practices
and to protect them we do have a
some experience because of the deflect
project on how to do that
um but yeah there are several points of
vulnerabilities in the network uh
definitely not foolproof and definitely
yeah
the more
heads we can use to improve the system
the better cool yeah I mean it seems
like there's an opportunity for uh you
know right now web web uh Publishers
don't generally they do provide
authentication for web pages but it's
not provided with this particular use
case in mind no yeah it would be
interesting to see if there's a way to
leverage that so that
the burden is no longer on you to be
you know that's it and I think this is
where the web caching standard uh could
come in very handy yeah because okay if
we are moving to web point three we're
gonna need to deal with decentralized
content in the centralized networks
again
you know we can't assume that there's
going to be a Tillis connection to
Twitter all the time and we don't want
that actually in web 3. so we will need
to figure out you know
how to deal with uh you know with a HTML
kind of uh ecosystem and
um
decentralized protocols which I think
you know it's not very difficult we just
need to actually come back to that space
cool thanks so much thank you
Dimitri thanks so much
um and thanks for the questions I think
they're really good this is part of the
reason why we really wanted to invite
Dimitri here today because they I think
have a lot of real world use cases for
this kind of hard problem and um it's
not the first time it's been brought up
in the ietf either so hopefully we can
continue that conversation
um but yeah we're now going to shift to
um Corinne who's giving the next talk
um Corinne do you want to share the
slides yourself since you're remote or I
can I can also pull them up and pass you
the control however you prefer okay let
me do that
foreign
you should have control now
so go ahead
I'm not sure your audios oh there you
are okay good that invites me welcome
green I think it's uh muted
pick up Sophia yeah yeah that's yeah I
think Korean is muted Corinne we can't
hear you unfortunately
um you look like you're unmuted on in
Meet Echo but maybe oh no she can't hear
me either
Corinne
okay we're not able to hear you
no
um
yep
so that we heard you for a moment
um
let me try again
is video and audio coming through okay
now
it's great
so let me get your slides back up
and pass through the control
thank you go ahead welcome
um so hey y'all I really appreciate the
opportunity to to present some of my
research work
um today I really wanted to be in the
room but unfortunately I had to leave
somewhat early
um so we're gonna do it like this
um
this might be a little bit repetitive
for some of the people who were at my
irtf talk uh on Wednesday but I just
want to make sure that everyone is at
the same level
um so I wrote both my master thesis and
my PhD on the ietf
and what I'm going to be talking about
today is some of the work
um
in my research which tracks what hrpc
has been doing and then raised some
critical questions as to like where we
potentially could go next
um and as I said for those who attended
my anrp talk the first slides will be
familiar but I do promise I will take a
hard left at around slight uh 10 or 9
and really focus on the human rights
work
so there's really four sections I'm
going to talk again a little bit about
being an anthropologist in the ietf
the work that hrpc has been doing since
um some of my findings in terms of the
role that human rights have played in
the ITF actually way before hrpc existed
and where we go next
um uh just a bit of context hi my name
is Karin I'm an Anthropologist of
Internet governance cultures
um I'm a research affiliate at the
University of Cambridge
um some people might also know me in my
role as the VP of research at the open
Tech fund
um I'm not presenting here in that
capacity this is very much me as the
left academic
um some of the people might know me as
the person who occasionally gets quoted
um when there are kerfarfels in the iitf
about what appropriate behavior is this
is a key part of the research that I've
done for my PhD and if you want to read
more about some of the problems that
I've seen in the community you can find
it on the link below in a piece aptly
titled what is wrong with loud men
talking loudly the itf's culture wars
now
um
I always find it easier when talks start
off with sort of the one of the key main
takeaways also has a bit of a
provocation to keep you engaged and for
you to start thinking of the different
ways in which you're going to argue that
I am wrong
um so the main takeaway from this talk
is the sum of controversial one at least
for this community and if there's one
thing that I truly hope that sticks with
you today it is that the ITF is
political inherently and that it always
um has done political and policy work to
different degrees
uh and the question uh demo comes is
that has happened not just in political
explicitly
um political spaces like hrpc
um so what does that mean for for this
group's work going forward and what kind
of an impact
um it would like to make
so
um I've been involved in the hrpc work
since its beginning actually since
before the group was was founded
um and
I just remember those early
conversations really showing me how much
of a fascinating place this community is
for anthropologists like myself
um and to do that I have to talk a
little bit about anthropology as a field
um many people tend to think of
anthropologists as social science
researchers who go to like far away
um islands and um study cultures of
people who are very different from
ourselves
um to sort of study the Argonauts of the
Western Pacific to bring in some really
classic anthropological work and this
for the longest time was the focus of
anthropologists but that is clearly no
longer the case
um anthropologists at this point in time
are are everywhere and especially since
the 1970s there's been this real
critical shift in the fields where
instead of
um
often focusing on people who are less
powerful than the Anthropologist
studying them we focus on people who are
more powerful we call that
um lifting The Gaze up at the most
powerful in society and we study our own
societies and not just societies
um that are different from ours and that
means that we now also study
um well-known tech companies I mean
there are anthropologists in places like
Facebook Google
um Twitter
godspeed to them but also in lesser
well-known Tech communities like the ITF
um so a bit of work about what we do as
anthropologists now we study human
behavior and cultures through a very
distinct set of methods and methodology
so direct engagement with people that
that collectively make these cultures by
participating in their world so in my
case to make this more concrete for my
PhD I essentially spent three years
doing field work within the ietf and the
irtf uh and I did in the interviews
field work as well as analyzing mailing
lists and RCS and a bunch of other
documents produced by the ITF or around
the iitf
and what this type of research really
allows me to understand is the kind of
cultural conditions
um that have shaped how Protocols are
made and for this particular talk
um I'm looking at like what hrpc has
done within the ITF and the irtf and
it's and how to think about the kind of
impact that the coup has had
um
which brings me to my talk today
um human rights works in the ITF and
irtf uh where are we and where are we
going
now
some of you in the room might actually
recognize the still on this slide from
the net of Rights movie that was made in
2015 by Nielsen over and Joanna Varon
for which they interviewed various ITF
Engineers to explore the relationship
between internet protocols and the
promotion and protection of Human Rights
um now it's really tempting to start a
talk about the role of Human Rights
advocacy within the ITF by saying it all
started in 2014 when the hrpc group
was was started and approved or started
by Nielsen over avidoria and Joanna
farron and approved by Lars and I will
certainly get back to that moment in
time but I do think as a researcher it's
also my role to say we need to trace the
work on rights within the ITF Beyond
these more recent times because it
doesn't if we just start in 2014 I'm not
doing Justice to what essentially I see
is the long Arc of public interest
technology advocacy that has occurred in
the ietf
um so
it would be possible to also start
tracing debates within the ietf and irtf
about the impacts uh impact of protocols
on a number of items known in Revelation
um that is another starting place
but there's also an argument to be made
uh that we can point to the publication
of RFC
6973 on privacy considerations
um spearheaded by Alyssa Cooper I know
this in 2013 as a starting point of sort
of Rights conversations in the broad
ietf
or
um I could start even earlier with the
participation of folks like John Morse
in the iitf who wrote one of the most
sort of explicit IDs uh internet drafts
about the policy implication of protocol
Works in 2010
or uh if you follow the work of
Professor sander Brahman who is
essentially done very beautiful and
comprehensive uh studies of early RCS we
can essentially Trace policy including
human rights considerations all the way
back to the founding days
um of the ietf
so uh I think I have sufficiently
belabored the point that I'm trying to
make which is that political questions
including debates about rights have in
one form or another always been part of
the iitf's discussions
um for one because technology in many
ways is politics by other means there's
various academics uh convincingly shown
but more practically I guess
um because ITF Engineers have always
considered their technology also in the
context of its deployment in The Wider
World which inherently means about
thinking about politics in terms of like
the kind of power relations
um in in historically contingent
um structures that end up influencing
how protocols get used
now this does raise an interesting
question
um if human rights and policy
considerations have always been part of
the ITF why has the work of the human
rights protocol considerations group
been so contentious
um upsetting so many people especially
in its in its early days
um and to do this I will now move back
uh to hrpc and give a bit of an overview
of its um trajectory
so
um as I mentioned in October in 2014
three human rights Advocates Nielsen
over avidoria Navarone essentially came
to uh Lars Eckhart the irtf chair at the
time with with an interesting idea
um they wanted to research how internet
standards would impact human rights
um and related as part of that they were
interested in developing guidelines that
ITF Engineers could use to Think Through
the potential impact of their uh of
their document of their Technologies on
uh on rights and the idea in their words
was to preserve the internet as a human
rights enabling environment
now to achieve these goals they set up
the human rights protocol considerations
research group in the irtf
and then in 2017 the group published its
uh its first RC RC RFC 8280
um which uh is entitled Research into
humanized protocol considerations and
that outlines different questions that
one can ask of the technology to
understand how it might have broader
implications
for policy and rights
now after the publication of this human
rights document
um it has not it has not seen a lot of
wide take up so sometimes you do see
people say we have a small human rights
consideration section uh in our document
but not very often and on Wednesday I
talked a little bit about how that is in
part due to the fact that there is some
cultural hesitancy on the part of of
many in the ietf to explicitly talk
about rights
um given that they worry about what kind
of outside scrutiny that might invite or
how it undermines how the ITF does work
which is not
um because it's just not very
comfortable with not human rights as
such but the different
um centralized institutions like the UN
that are tied into the human rights
people framework
um that being said
the group has had
um has had influence and impact in in
very different ways
um their work their presence is well
cemented uh not just in irtf but in ietf
um a number of people who came into the
ietf uh myself included
um are now present in different ways
they are
um with ITF leadership they've set up
other research groups they participate
in ITF working groups
um Etc
and
[Music]
um
all of this to say that the HR PC group
might not have had the kind of narrow
impact it had initially set out for
itself namely getting ITF Engineers to
take on our c8280 but the existence of
this group of people with an expertise
at the intersection of standards and
rights has had a really interesting
impact on technology development in the
iitf in a much broader way in a way that
perhaps the folks who started it hadn't
even imagined
now I want to get back to some of of
these more interesting and positive
impacts of this community in a later
slide
um but first I want to sort of go back
to some of the discussions we've had
here uh over the past years in
particular the one around politics
um there are multiple reasons why the
hrpc work was so contentious
um part of it obviously has to do with
like the political uh the political
economic reality of protocol development
and deployment which meant that adding
human rights considerations to documents
was seen as perhaps slowing things down
adding complexity doing all these things
when it wasn't clear like what the
benefit would be necessarily
um
likewise you know there were some issues
around potential mitigation strategies
for human rights impact that were in
tension with economic considerations of
latency or efficiency a problem that is
obviously well known to the ietf we see
it come up in in other working groups as
well
um
but one of the the concerns that I
really want to foreground today is a
cultural
um sort of conditions that shape the
human rights discussions
and the worry that exists amongst the
many ITF Engineers about making these
um these impact these political aspects
of their work more explicit
excuse me
so the concern being that if the ITF is
more explicit about how it work is
political
um this might actually
um invite unwanted scrutiny and outside
regulation
um there is also a worry that it would
open them up to the demands of a number
of actors including governments uh who
will want things that many in the iitf
considered to be bad technical practices
like undermining or backdooring
encryption scheme for example
um
and the the problem is that or the
apartment for the hrpc group is that
their demands
um of human rights were seen as being
unwanted impossible
um even if maybe technically they
weren't
um and so for instance one of my
interviews interviewee said so for
example I agree that it would be wrong
for the ITF to start taking positions on
economics saying that we need an
anti-capitalist ITF will be kind of
stupid right
um it's never going to happen anyways so
for the credibility of the organization
for its sponsors for the people here who
make use of the Technologies developed
it would make no sense to do overtly
political things
um
that being said uh following the Snowden
Revelations sometimes the political
moment trumps these worries and ITF
Engineers do take up political debates
and translate them in technical ways as
for instance we saw with RFC 70 to 58
um pervasive monitoring is an attack
that came out after the Zone Revelations
now some of the folks who co-authored
that might be in the room I mean
obviously can't see if Stephen is there
and he and I have been having some
conversation about the extent to which
this was or was not overtly political
um but I would love to hear uh your
thoughts on what made that moment so
unique that it was possible to actually
get this document uh published because I
do see it as a political stance even
though it's couch in technical terms
uh and for those wondering about my
choice of slight pictures here I guess I
was going for the message that sometimes
politics are as run-of-the-mill in the
itfs as our cookies
now uh going back to hrpc how do we
think about its role in the ietf and the
irtf
um and if we look at the use of RFC 8280
it seems pretty minimal
but I do think that no pun intended this
would be too narrow a standard for
judging the impact of the group uh and
in my PhD research I outline hrpc's
influence in terms of its role as a
landing pad for people who are
interested in the intersection between
politics and protocols
um as a bit of a
safe space for engineers who are looking
to
repoliticized protocols as a place where
people can be mentored and grown help to
grow into different roles in the ietf
including in leadership as a number of
hrpc folks have done
um so in other words how I have have
theorized your group is really as having
various bridging function functions so
merging between new folks and people who
who have been here for a long time
between end users especially from the
majority World whose views are not
necessarily represented here in the sort
of technical slash awkward interests
that are well represented at the IHF
um but also between activists who focus
on systemic issues around racism and
sexism and those working in the ITF to
make it more open and accessible
a bridge between the research in the
irtf and the technical work that happens
in the ietf approach between political
and Technical debates etc etc
so
um where in the first couple of years
uh many of the people who started in
hrpc actually stayed within the Narrow
Lane that they had carved for themselves
in the irtf that is clearly no longer
the case
um and that's also where some of the
strength of the group really lies in in
its way to provide a virgin function and
a landing pad and a place for
experimentation and contrarian views
um that you know that the ITF tends to
say it really appreciates
um but more importantly what I want to
drive home is the notion that
the work that the hrpc has been doing is
not necessarily
um
exceptional
um or totally coloring outside of the
its boxes
um it really I truly do see uh hrpc as
an extension
um of the long Arc of public interest
representation within the ITF
uh but bringing in a new and wider set
of concerns uh including around issues
like environmentalism and racism but
also by connecting the kind of work that
some people do in their day jobs too
that is maybe not as technical nature to
discussions that are happening here
um
corvadis okay cover this a really fancy
way of saying a Latin uh where do we go
next
um the biggest question that I see for
hrpc is how it wants to keep
repositioning itself within the ITF irtf
ecosystem
um there are obviously a number of
different routes you could take uh
including one in which it becomes a
space uh for broader consideration of
politics and policy development and how
those impact the ITF
um and and how to potentially respond to
those
um now there are plenty of thorny
questions I believe that could benefit
from the unique perspective perspective
that this group can can leverage
together and whether it's ongoing
government repression and surveillance
um or like the kind of examples that uh
D matches brought by the work that
equality is doing having those kind of
voices have a space within the irtf and
ietf is is incredibly important and I
feel the Community Values it as well
um it's not necessary for me to say what
the best way forward is
um but I am very interested as I know
you are and having that discussion
um so I think I will I will leave it at
that and just thank you for being given
the opportunity to present and if you're
interested in my research there's a link
below to the entirety of my uh PhD
thesis
um I wouldn't recommend reading the
whole uh 19 19
000 words but maybe
skimming a bit here and there if you're
interested thank you so much
[Applause]
thanks uh thanks Corinne folks feel free
to get yourselves in the queue
I'm going to cut it though because we
have to move on
thanks Quinn this is Elliot
um once again congratulations on your
NRP award it's very well deserved
um as somebody who's been participating
in this group as an engineer from the
beginning with some amount of
trepidation at different points a great
amount of trepidation I want to make two
comments
uh the first is
um
I think a lot of us especially uh senior
engineers
uh struggle with this group in in not
just the group but the concept of Human
Rights because at the end of the day we
find that there's no right answer for us
uh that anything we do can be used for
great harm
uh or great good
um and so that brings me to
uh
my second point which is where to go
from here
um
the value I think of this group
to me at least has not been in
Publications
from the group but rather
in the presentations to the group
um which I've learned a lot from by the
way and uh for that I'd like to thank
both the current chair the previous
chairs and the presenters themselves
um
one of the things that I would suggest
is that we figure out a way and I don't
I don't think we just means the hrpc but
we meaning the broader Community uh to
surface the presentations perhaps the
ones that are uh that maybe this group
thinks are most important
um to the broader Community
um with uh maybe some suggestions about
the ramifications to uh uh the ietf I'm
not quite sure how to do that
so I'll I'll stop there just to say it's
an inkling of an idea and I think maybe
uh maybe the group can pick it up or not
hi uh Colin Perkins
um
thank you Elliot I think that's an
interesting idea uh I
um
I think I you know thank you for the
talk Karen uh I agree very much with uh
your your points I think hrpc has had a
pretty wide impact in the ITF and the
irtf um
and I I agree I think also that it's not
so much with the documents uh it's worth
bringing the people in let's bring it's
with
be explicitly bringing in people with
different viewpoints uh and bringing
them to the ITF community and exposing
the community to those viewpoints
um I think this is a very good thing we
need we need this diversity of use
um we are nowhere near diverse enough in
the ATF and the artf and the more we can
do an hrpc does that in one small way
and in one access of diversity and I
think that's a great thing and I think
if we could try and bring in more people
from our proxies of diversity I think
that would be uh
a very beneficial thing for the
organization
um even if there would be growing pains
with the different viewpoints and the
different clashes of view
so I hope we can continue to do that
um I also strongly agree that we have
always discussed politics in the ITF
one of the examples I thought you were
going to bring up but didn't is RFC
1984.
for example which is a very political
document and one which we explicitly
discussed economics from back in 1996.
um I think what's changed now is that
we're finally starting to admit that
we're discussing politics
and I think that's a very good thing
thank you
uh thanks Karen this is uh Adrian
Farrell
um
yeah I I rarely managed to get to these
physical meetings because there's this
sort of agenda going on where where
people are having other working groups
um and I think that's part of the issue
so when I work on a protocol document I
know I need to have security
considerations but I also know that I
don't know much about security
and
um the ietf helps me with that by
providing a core of people I can go and
consult
um
what I think we're missing and is
probably the next step is to try to get
a human rights directorate I don't like
the word directorate in this sense but
in a review team Maybe
who cannot tell me what I'm getting
wrong in my protocol and what I must do
that can ask me the questions
so when I look at the guidance RFC I I
get to about page three and I've glazed
over because I've got protocol work to
develop I need somebody who can help me
bridge the gap
um from my protocol to what should I be
thinking about
and possibly by the time I'm writing a
detailed protocol spec in the depth of a
working group it's too late
what we need is a kind of up level
uh almost like a working review of The
Working groups
not review the protocols
Niels you should be able to
come on Mike if you want I closed the
queue but I'm I'm happy if you want to
jump in
we can't hear you though
no
there you are yep
you hear me no
okay
thank you for the question I I do not
have a good academic Citation for
landing pad I actually try in these
talks to stay away from academic
academic lingo as much as I can because
I don't necessarily find it super
helpful
um but I think the question in that
sense has answered itself
um because three of the people who just
took the time to listen to my talk and
come up with really interesting and
considerate responses to it we're all
people who have been at the IHF for for
a long period of time and who all
self-identified as Engineers so it's
definitely a two-way street and I think
again like the the point that Colin made
that like one of the one of the
strengths of this group is that it
brings together people
um and that those people are also taken
serious uh is is really key
um Beyond or in addition to all of the
different documents that that the group
is producing
so I I put myself in the queue
um to kind of come back in on some of
the suggestions and to thank folks for
making them and also to thank you
Corinne because you've created the space
and the discussion that really is
self-reflective and helps us I think as
a as a research group grow and get
better so some of the suggestions to
make that work more visible I I could I
couldn't agree more I think we need to
think about that
um as well the idea of a directorate I
mean it's been tried as somebody also
mentioned in the chat
um there wasn't always it wasn't always
well received but I do think your
iteration on the model Adrian was useful
and that it's not about
telling people what they've got wrong
um although that is what directorates
and the IDF usually do right I mean from
a security perspective or whatever that
is you know what they're set up to do I
think it is more of a come along and
let's try to work out some of these
trade-offs or actually even expose that
there is maybe a trade-off so
um
I think that point is well taken I would
also say
um that's what maybe the guidelines
draft is meant to do as well is to sort
of document that write it down make
people aware that that work can be done
and then come to hrpc for
um the expertise so that all explicit
goals I agree we could all be doing
a better job so
um I think we ought to move on because
actually we have we have to update on
drafts and and a few
um pieces of aob including
um which we probably won't get to
um a request to maybe recharter slightly
so grin let's thank her one more time
congratulate her for her award thanks
for coming we wish you could have been
here in person
all right
um okay so let me get back to
my slides
okay well the current work we have so
I'll have
um folks who are working on any of the
current work go ahead and throw
yourselves in the queue we'll go sort of
rapid fire update
um but the first one is on guidelines
this is under
irsg review if I'm not wrong gershabad I
don't know if you have anything to add
on Mike about this
yeah go for it it would be good just
hear where that's at
hello
um
yeah uh the guidelines draft if if you
don't already know about it is an update
to 8280 it um
condenses guidelines for people trying
to gauge the impact of the protocols
they're designing on human rights it's a
set of guidelines this document is under
IRSC review we received two reviews from
Jane coffin and Brian Dremel and we this
week all of the comments have been
addressed um
so yeah uh just uh I'm hopefully the
draft will proceed after that but um
yeah the I I signed a summary of the
changes
on the mailing list uh yesterday just
some reordering of the sections nothing
uh major yet so thank you
thank you for that yeah so you have uh
really appreciate that update and it's
also in the data tracker good
cool check check
um
yep go ahead Nick on freedom of
Association so this is I'm a co-author
on that so we've got Nick as doc
Shepherd
um and also Neils so
yeah feel free to give us an update
please
yeah just a very brief update um
last
um IDF we talked about uh making some
edits uh Niels to that and I've just
finished another
um round of review and I have an open
pull request with some edits there
um I think we've addressed the sort of
confusion about considering the same
protocol and different issues I think
that's um sort of clearer to read now
and so I'm I'm hopeful that after those
minor edits we could go back to the
research group for our last call and and
progress from there so uh no no big
changes but I do think there have been
some improved edits and and hopefully we
can make it even more readable
so if I'm hearing you right Nick there
will be
you're requesting a few additional
changes and then we can progress is that
right
that's right
thanks for that Niels I don't know if
you wanted to respond but I'm going to
as a co-author with my hat on I'll need
to look over what those are
in terms of what timeline I think that
will take
okay great Neil says thanks
we'll work on it all right so we do have
one more
um piece of work that I would um didn't
put on this slide but is in our agenda
so apologies to Sophia for that Sophia
come on the mic and I know you have
slides as well you can
um you can go ahead and share those or I
can share them and pass you but
I think
all right go ahead and tell us all about
it because I've not got on the slides
there you are perfect
there you go uh so hey everybody
um we also wanted to talk a little bit
about upcoming work that is happening
right now this is not an official draft
but there's some work that has been
happening over at GitHub so it's just
kind of a Call of our actions of a call
for action on if you want to be part of
this effort as well so you can involve
yourself on it or if you have any other
ideas or what should be part of this
work you can give us also a feedback so
this is a draft that we have been
putting together that was born from the
Las ietf ITF 114 we had an invited from
Sita
um Lana ramij who gave a presentation
about how digital tools and different
protocols and different technology is
used to enhance intimate partner
violence and in this case we think about
intimate partner balance of any kind of
balance that is executed with a partner
but also someone you have a intimate
relationship with it could be a
caregiver it could be your parents it
could be someone else it doesn't have to
be always a romantic or sexual
relationships
um so basically we because of that
presentation we decided to create a
document that tries to provide the
standards with recommendations that that
if they are put in certain kind of
protocols or systems or any kind of
technology that they are describing what
kind of implications can that technology
have into enhance abuse in the cases of
domestic abuse or more broadly in the
case of intimate partner violence so we
put together already a kind of a
structure of a draft there's already
some definitions so for example what is
technology-based intimate partner
balance what kind of attackers exist in
this place
um the specific abuse technology that
happens in these cases some
recommendations to protocol designers
and we also added security
recommendations in case
um there's some from security that has
to be taken into account
so if you are very interested in this
work uh please join us in the GitHub or
in the mailing list if you think this
all sounds reasonable and this is
structure sounds reasonable also let us
know if you want anything else also to
be added let us know and if you want to
participate actively this draft also let
us know
and yep just without a quick update on
that thank you
because this is new work I do actually
want to open the queue or invite folks
to get into the open queue for any
questions about this
um for folks maybe who didn't come or
didn't watch the 114 session you should
it's a fantastic presentation and so
it's really wonderful to see it's really
wonderful when we have speakers come
and then those speakers Inspire work
that's actually the ideal case it
doesn't always happen that's all right
but
go ahead Khan good to see you in the
queue hi uh so just one quick question
for clarification first uh this draft
has not yet been submitted right it's in
progress no it's a still in progress
um we do have the first initial
structure on some texts and potentially
in the next weeks we
mix with tracker yeah okay great thanks
all right awesome thank you Sophia okay
thank you yeah thanks so much so we have
oh yeah go ahead Colin uh I'll come back
I was expecting more people to comment
on that
um so yeah uh Colin Perkins uh I think
this is a really important topic um
obviously I haven't read the draft since
it's not yet been submitted but uh I I
would certainly encourage work in this
space
I'm really glad to hear that
thank you
so I'm I'm not going to pull up the
chair slides again but on our agenda we
have a short amount of time for
um cross-pollination from another
working group in the ITF um Adrian if
you're here you've put yourself in the
aob on gnat oh good you're remote
wonderful so you can also load your
slides or I can load them and pass them
to you whichever you prefer
uh I can uh you can hear me right uh yes
we can I can do the slides
fantastic
um
can you see them
not yet but sometimes it takes a minute
oh wait I have uh
uh
it's fine if you want to share your
screen but it might also be faster if
you just share the slide I don't know I
cry uh okay let me uh
you can uh do the slides because uh
Chrome is asking me to change
permissions Etc
okay uh so I
um
so
um how you can go to
um uh so yes uh I'm involved in the
ganap grant negotiation authorization
protocol uh which is a successor to
oauth uh the editors uh were uh you know
editors and principals in uh much of the
oauth and Uma uh protocol work
um this slide uh and I'm going to go
pretty quickly because I wanted
very interested in feedback from the
group so there's only uh five slides but
anyway so uh this gets an authorization
protocol has privacy issues of course uh
that are significant in the next slide
I'll talk about that but I am trying to
and I've been invited to introduce a
human rights consideration into the uh
into the document for gnap
um where uh the issue that difference
from privacy is that it doesn't consider
delegation it ignores the power
asymmetry of the participants in the
protocol and the hrpc force Association
uh perspective is directly applicable
here
so
um what I'm trying to do is convince uh
the work group the gnap work group that
unrestricted delegation to the
authorization uh uh unrestricted as
selection by the subject by the resource
owner should be a must or should next
slide please
okay so uh just uh a quick review about
what gun app is about uh it specifies an
authorization server that processes
requests from a requesting party uh and
provides it's a token Factory what they
call and provides access tokens
authorizations to access a resource
server this is a list of the Privacy
interests that all meet at the
authorization server and in particular
what I'm concerned about here is to
avoid lock-in to the resource server
business to avoid the ability to have
policy surveillance uh the resource
owner's policy should stay either
entirely to themselves or to our
surrogate a delegate that they choose
and to avoid the opportunity for traffic
analysis uh by the uh buy and
authorization server processing request
that where that authorization server
wasn't selected by the resource owner
next slide please
um and uh I uh the last ITF uh I was
asked to provide a PR
uh there's a bunch of discussion after
that uh it's a human rights
considerations PR I proposed three
mitigations uh
but the issue is technically all three
of them uh are possible uh the issue is
whether these must be the human rights
issue as I frame it whether it should be
a must or should rather than voluntary
uh next slide please the last one
so uh the call to action uh for hrpc and
ganap is what you see on this slide
first of all I'm not familiar with a lot
of any much of the work in ietf but it
seems to me like an app is the best
example for the concerns that are being
discussed in hrpc at this time and I'm
curious if there are any other examples
that might be considered as good uh in
recent memory
um yesterday at this time there was a
discussion uh which there's a link
directly to about 15 minutes worth of 20
minutes worth of discussion in the ganap
work group what's interesting here is
that the various commenters and editors
and chairs as individuals not
necessarily uh officially basically
pointed out that uh agreed that
hyperscale platforms are an unintended
concert sequence of the way oauth links
the authorization server and the
resource server
they discussion of the fact that
regulatory capture is a risk and I think
people in this audience understand all
about that and
um they mention uh how ganap is intended
to work with these standardized
verifiable credentials and decentralized
identifiers that are coming out of
uh w3c and the Linux Foundation as data
models but standardizing these uh data
models
has a huge potential for Mass
surveillance
now that didn't exist before with less
standardized or of course analog
physical credentials
so uh my claim is that forced
association with hyperscale platforms is
not not no longer an unintended
consequence as it was with uh oauth uh
and uh therefore it has to be dealt with
uh in the nap by uh making uh
hands delegation a must or should thank
you
thank you and thank you for bringing
this work in to hlpc I know that um gnap
or gnap met yesterday and I don't know
if there was also a parallel discussion
in the working group about uh this issue
I I myself was unable to go because I
had a conflict can you just give us an
indication of how that conversation went
yesterday or whether it did
uh well I can do better than that one of
the editors uh Fabian uh has agreed to
and he's on the Queue so thank you I yes
thanks yeah welcome well hello everyone
uh thanks thanks for this Adrian it's a
very interesting work uh just to say
that I'm one of the creditors of nap uh
we are taking this work very seriously
um it's just as was discussed earlier in
one of your previous comments uh we are
quite aware that we need to do security
analysis where we also need to do
privacy analysis and we are putting
measures in place and for us it's it's
kind of something that's new for us to
actually
put put measures in place against
human rights uh consequences so that's
at least something where I think we
would need some some additional support
and I think that's
kind of the message from Adrian and we
we'd like to thank him for that and
yesterday it was it was discussed in the
group and actually it was one of the
main points where a debate was was quite
open
um the main problem we have is is really
to find actual technical ways to to do
that in in practice and so that's what
we're working on so thank you very much
foreign
thanks for that overview I suggest
because we've run out of time that
um you engage both in the hrpc list and
asking for folks from this group to
potentially engage in gnap
um directly and
um talk about that there although
because this is maybe a Cross Research
group cross working group topic
um I would encourage folks to try to CC
both lists
um as the conversation progresses but I
don't think we can get into it too much
more now although I will wait just a
moment in case there are folks in the
room
um who've not yet signaled they want to
be in the queue
all right again uh thanks yeah Colin
please always it's Friday I didn't move
that quickly
um uh Colin Perkins uh so I I know
absolutely nothing about the map other
than reading the draft abstract in the
last sort of 30 seconds or so
um from what you've been saying that
there's clearly things that that are
worth discussing with this group
um I think one of the challenges is
perhaps going to be uh connecting the
two sets of people with very very
different uh expertise
um and so uh I think uh you know as
Mallory says posting to the lists is is
a good way forward it may also be useful
to
make some direct connections and set up
some small groups to discuss to avoid
the two the two sets of people with such
different backgrounds talking past each
other
so just a plea on the mic and to the
group if you are interested in this
you've engaged in hrpc you're familiar
with
um reviewing documents if you can just
indicate to me
um at some point or call an event that
you want to engage in this be really
grateful for your help and thanks again
to the folks uh who brought this both
Adrian and Fabian for coming on Mike
um I will just
so just to stop this particular
discussion and tap very quickly to the
last
um of my slides
there's been some suggestions
um also coming from me frankly that
um perhaps we could consider a slight
recharter I will also note that we um
the research group was recently reviewed
by the IAB and
um that's a process that happens
occasionally and I I myself have gone
through two
um two of those
um reviews and it's just maybe a good
time to reflect so I've had some I've
had some of my own thoughts on what a
recharter might look like I was hoping
to go through them with you in this
meeting but there's not really much time
so again like would just say maybe this
is a this is definitely a conversation
we'll take to the list
um
and we'll welcome your feedback in that
list discussion we can also maybe make
sure to allocate more time to this at
the 116 meeting in Yokohama since you're
not able to totally read it right now of
course I understand
um but I think the goal would just be to
take on some of the feedback that was
delivered here today even about our
ability to do
um reviews
um bring others along into this work
mainstream it a bit more in the rest of
the community and also be able to take
on a bit maybe what more we're thinking
in terms of policy discussions because
it's not a word that we typically use or
it's not even present in the charter as
currently but certainly something that
we in fact are
um are doing so to to make that and
expose that make it more explicit and
expose that
um I think might be actually be a useful
exercise those are just my personal
thoughts as the chair
um but Sophia and I will do our best to
facilitate a conversation on the list
and then at the next meeting so I
apologize that we ran out of time I
really want to appreciate our speakers I
think it was worthwhile taking the time
to hear them all out and especially just
to take us back to the beginning I think
it was really useful to have Tara talk
about a lot of situation because you can
turn on CNN and see it in the cycle
um and it's just no knowing that there
is actually a touchstone in our
community to Allah and his case and it's
not just an abstract human rights abuse
case
I hope has moved you as much as it um
has been moving me to
read about the situation all right
thanks everybody
we're going to close now
thank you
very much
foreign