okay
it is 3 30.
uh Henry if you could turn your
microphone off until sorry your video
off and and unless you're you're
speaking that'd be appreciated
uh let's go ahead and get started this
is http
uh we have two sessions this week both
of two hours uh we have a relatively
full agenda so we're going to try and
keep it on time if at all possible I'd
like to introduce my floating head coach
Aaron Tommy Polly Tommy Take a Bow
um
so uh first of all first and foremost uh
the note well policy uh you should all
be familiar with this by now but if not
these are the policies under which we
participate in the ITF regarding things
like intellectual property and privacy
and harassment code of conduct copyright
there are many different aspects to it
so if you're not familiar with them
please do familiarize yourself with it
it's important we take it seriously and
you can find it by just searching in
your favorite internet search engine for
I ietf notewell
wait any waste users here you may have
trouble
but otherwise ietf note well
this meeting does have a mask policy I'm
hoping you're aware of that by now too
uh if you're not speaking uh or or
eating or drinking please do wear a mask
and and exercise common sense
and yes I did notice that someone left
their power cord here hi hi Lucas well I
didn't want to name names
so please do uh remember to keep your
mask on and if someone gently reminds
you take it in the spirit which it was
intended
uh can we have a scribe for this session
is anyone willing to take minutes
please
anyone in the room there are some
familiar faces that I could call on but
they have done it many times in the past
so new faces would be much appreciated
thank you very much uh and that's
Jonathan isn't it
I don't have my glasses on but I know
it's Jonathan if you could uh um just
take notes in the um
what do we call them now I think it's a
hedge dock it should be linked from the
top of the agenda yeah
and I I already filled out the agenda
there so you should just be able to oh
thank you
thank you um and and if folks could help
Jonathan out that would be much
appreciated so that it's not falling
just on his shoulders
so the agenda for today
yes
I learned about Dynamic backgrounds in
keynote this week
so
excuse me today we've got signatures
alternative Services where we have a
reasonably large amount of time reserved
origin H3 a brief update cookies and
then client certs now we've we've had a
request to rearrange so that partition
cookies can be after the cookies
discussion just for to keep us on on
topic there if no one's uh having
trouble with that we'll we'll do that so
we'll do cookies then partition cookies
then go back to concerts and then
finally we'll end up with an update from
our friends over and the enthusiasts
over in The Mask working group
they are very enthusiastic if you can I
don't think you can see that on camera
but there's already enthusiasm
uh and then on Friday we'll go over
there Jennifer that uh then but we have
a similar kind of lineup
so like I said very packed any agenda
bashing beyond what we already heard
okay let's go ahead and get started then
uh with the signatures discussion
and I'm going to see how far I can take
this just projecting my entire screen
take it away
all right hi everybody I'm Justin richer
this is going to be a short presentation
next slide please on uh update on HTTP
message signatures uh we've gone through
a couple of revisions of editorial
updates added more examples we added
something called the tag parameter which
was very briefly called the context
parameter until we got some feedback
that that was a dumb name and
um so there's the tag parameter in there
now it's optional don't need to get into
it and we have gone through a one month
long working group last call after which
a lot of comments came in about the
document so thank you for those that uh
that have done that so far
um right now there are only a couple of
uh small things going in uh
so first Lucas needs to apparently get
me an update on uh the digest example in
the draft
I think
thank you
I guess apparently it's wrong I'm not
sure how it's wrong but if you could
make it not wrong that'd be awesome
um and we can touch base in the hallway
or something if that's easy to do
um next slide though
um but uh there is an open question
about what do we do with trailers
um Can the fields that we've defined can
they be trailers currently they're
allowed but uh does that do we need to
be more specific about what that means
when they're trailers
um and can we sign trailers
um and and if we do so uh there's a
couple of things that we could do right
now everything is just sort of defined
as fields and we kind of mash them all
into the same namespace which is what I
thought we were allowed to do but
somebody pointed at a line in HTTP
semantics and I'm getting some head
shakes in the room so this might be a
very short discussion next slide please
um
so uh so obviously uh if we have a
hypothetical field that can exist as
both a header and a trailer do we both
call these both food next slide because
the naive thing to do uh would be to
just cram them together to look like
this that's what the spec says to do
right now I'm getting a lot of head
shakes uh this is why I tagged you guys
on the GitHub issue so I wouldn't have
to have these slides but I'm glad we're
here so next slide uh the alternative
proposal uh is to just explicitly call
something out as a trailer as a data
source
um using a Boolean flag that tells this
uh that allows the signer to signal and
the verifier to know where to Source the
information and then otherwise we just
treat it like any other any other field
uh next slide we actually have precedent
for this with the request parameter uh
that's already in there when you're
signing a response you can get the
related request information and Pull It
in there and uh so I think I already
have the answer but uh uh let's let's go
to the key I'll interject and then
Martin might have something to say
um so in in HTTP uh the most recent
series of updates we recognize that
trailers had some really fundamental
interoperability and deployability
issues and so we defined them as a
separate namespace from headers so they
are distinct you cannot just naively
combine them unless the definition of
the header field or sorry the field says
yes you may do that oh gosh and so we
flipped that so so your approach uh the
approach that you talk about here we're
using TR might be workable the only
thing that I would add to that is you
have to realize that it is completely
legal to drop trailers on the floor both
you know intermediaries and by
recipients they can just disappear and
so you need to account for that if you
want it to be robust yeah we definitely
um need additional implementation
considerations for trailers uh in that
case I think there's already some text
in there but it needs to be more robust
um for sure I mean you might even
consider if it appears it should look
like this is kind of semantic
Martin Thompson goodness you wouldn't
want to be short
um Martin Thompson
presumably you can add both TR and Rec
to the same field name interface that
it's a trailer on a request this can you
do that
yes
right so that's if uh I want to ask you
two but if you go back to like several
slides my final question on trailers is
are they even real because I actually
found that in some of the libraries I
was using I can't get to trailers oh
yeah this is a common complaint uh so
they are real uh
they're probably not a great thing to be
signing
uh for the reasons that Mark stated but
yeah and it sounds like you're trying to
get everything so yeah it seems to work
yeah I I can't see a compelling reason
to disallow it so I would rather have it
be very explicit like if you're doing it
this is what it is and these are the
problems you're going to run into
this is a great way to make stuff break
if you sign these things but uh
that's what people yeah want sometimes I
guess yeah the observation I'd make is
is that the the people who do use
trailers tend to really like them and
they tend to do weird things and so it
wouldn't be out of that question for
them to want to do a weird thing with
signing them right exactly and this is
this is definitely off in in corner
space somewhere but um we wanted to make
sure that it was covered so anyway thank
you I will put in a PR to to add the TR
flag uh with the definition for that and
um and toss that around but
um yeah apart from uh tweaking a couple
of examples here and there the the
working group last call feedback so far
has been pretty positive
um and I've also been discovering a
handful of more uh implementations out
there in the wild uh which next slide
um I'm going to be talking about that a
little bit at the SAG on Friday morning
this week uh where I'm basically going
to uh
be presenting what the draft is and how
it works and very very briefly to The
Wider security community and then tell
them to come at it with pitchforks and
pickaxes and whatever else they can get
on hand and basically help us figure out
like did we leave security holes in here
that we don't know about are there weird
Oracle attacks or gotchas or other
things that uh that are hiding in this
space
um so it's going to be exciting time
after that I'm sure
um but uh oh right the second bullet
which I'm pointing over here now
um the second bullet is that if you have
an implementation or you know of an
implementation of the HTTP working group
draft not the Cabbage draft
um I'm going to be putting up a tab on
httpsig.org our sort of demo site
playground space to start listing these
implementations because I've had a lot
of people coming at me uh lately asking
for that list so I'm gonna put it up and
then just have a link to like make a
GitHub pull request if you want to add
your own
um but you know get in touch with me I'm
I'm seeing more and more out there and I
think that's all I had great
any questions feedback
okay thank you Justin all right thank
you
and if folks are able to uh attend sag
uh it conflicts with us on Friday but if
you happen to be there uh that's a good
conversation to watch because there's a
an open question about what the
appropriate level of review is for this
kind of really pivotal spec
ific great and and if you could do us
the favor of maybe reporting back in on
the email list or something that'd be
great
uh next up alternative services
Mike
I'll skip over the joke that inspired
the picture there but uh
flood
so we have all this uh nice complicated
infrastructure of how we handle the
user's request and where it flows
through
okay
I don't know where that comes from
all right
um but slide
what we're trying to handle is when the
user accidentally winds up over there
where we'd really like to get them on
the red path that we had planned for
them and we want to redirect them a
little bit so slide
there are a couple cases where that
happens that we'd like to make sure that
we handle one of the most common ones is
when the DNS resolver is not near to the
client
and for privacy reasons or otherwise
does not pass along the client Subnet in
edns0
there's also for those cdns that use
anycast anycast can wind up in the wrong
spot it happens there's a lot of work
that goes on to make sure that doesn't
happen but it still does
and in some cases we have endpoints that
can offer you better service based on
where you are or who you are that we
didn't know when you did the DNS
resolution so
we might like to be able to point to to
some endpoint that we control that
special that would give you faster
service
and the most common use of alt service
right now is for protocol availability
so you spoke to us over H2 we'd like to
tell you that we also have our H3
endpoint
or you spoke to us over each one and
we'd like to tell you that H2 is a
different port hypothetically although
that mostly doesn't happen in the real
world
we've got Julian and kids join it do you
have a question of clarification or can
it wait to the end
uh I wanted to mention that apparently
the chat doesn't work or no it actually
works so I had actually questions for
Justin early on
but um the messages didn't come through
so apparently
questions for for Justin so so the news
is zulub is down uh from for most of
things so all the chat is busted ah and
so Julian's got some sort of low
priority questions that he can't get
answered
ah there's an iits but it seems to be up
now
oh okay it's back again so okay sorry
so and so perhaps that's a request for
you to go into zulup and field some
questions
all right so we at this point have two
main ways to redirect the user we can
either do it before the request happens
using DNS
or we can do it after the request
happens using alt service
and
those are both great options slide
Trouble Comes when we have to combine
them
right now what the service B spec says
is that if you implement alt service and
https
you take all the host names you found in
alt service look up https records for
all of those then filter down to
everything that's consistent with both
the https records and the alt service
record
and then attempt to connect to
whatever's left from that combination
which produces some confusing results
notably there's only one resolution here
that is even in the original Origins
domain
yeah
you can set this up but it gets a little
confusing and we're trying to Define
a better coexistent story moving forward
and so the simpler version slide
And Delay
oh okay so the trouble that we have
other than just using them together is
what do we do when we get both sets of
information
because the old service is potentially
old
so how do we make sure it's still valid
but it was received over a TLS
connection directly from the origin
whereas DNS comes through other servers
along the way possibly unencrypted
how much do we trust when they don't say
exactly the same thing
so we want a way that lets us make sure
things are fresh before we use it one of
the concerns that we've heard is an ALT
service that says you can come talk to
me over H3
but when you resolve the hostname you
get pointed to a different CDN that
doesn't support H3 and your connect
fails in your timeout which is not great
big slide
so the draft that's been submitted
um just before the deadline was to
replace it with
very close to the straw man that we had
talked about last iatf which is this alt
service B
which provides you a hostname that you
should go resolve slide for semantics
slide or okay
it's just lag
so basically right now
the first step of it is ignore any
Legacy alt service that's there
so that helps avoid any of the
collisions that we might care about
just do an https lookup for the hostname
do all the service B required connection
stuff that's in the https spec
and use that connection instead of this
one so we're trying to move you over to
a different endpoint now
and then in the future remember what
endpoint you wound up on and give that
some preference
when you do future https resolutions
connecting to this origin if you don't
see that endpoint oh well you just go on
with what DNS says
and you forget it
the next slide
and this does leave us in a little bit
of a situation around stickiness which
is that if you're not remembering
uh or if you don't have that endpoint in
the DNS all the time
then you're going to go to origin get
redirected without service the next time
around you go back to the origin and
it'll tell you to go go over to the
alternative again
so you might wind up flip-flopping
unless you put all of your possible
endpoints in the DNS some providers
don't want to do that because they don't
want to enumerate all possible endpoints
in the DNS
but if you remember it too long then you
override the ability of a site to do
multi-cdn or otherwise change where
they're pointing you so this is a
trade-off that we're going to have to
make
now we had a long conversation about
this at the HTTP Workshop slide
and we had over the course of that long
conversation we basically redesigned the
proposal and then wound up right back at
the proposal that was submitted because
everything else we tried didn't really
work out or had some
uh some conceptual difficulty that made
us drop it
so where we wound up with is DNS is
always reasonably current for the time
that you look it up
probably have short ttls that's where
CDN load balancing happens
it always gives you the endpoints of the
the properties of the endpoint that
you're actually talking to
so we always want DNS to have
more or less exclusive real-time control
over who you talk to and what you should
expect to do on that connection
and ALT service is more interesting for
once you get to that origin if it wants
to move you to a different node so
distributed origin CDN whatever
it's mostly interesting for redirection
in real time and stickiness may not be
as much of a concern as it originally
was for all service or as we thought it
might be
so
um I think at this point we're just
going to open up for discussion
on the draft that was submitted the
current alt service bis
and how we want to move forward with
this
and I see Martin getting his phone get
in the queue
I also see them
Ben you you beat Martin go for it
hi Ben Schwartz uh this all sounds like
a a bit like a good Improvement to me
I'm for it I I don't understand the
stickiness where did you end up on
stickiness
um so the issue about stickiness is
how
how does the client verify that the
information it has cached is still valid
for an old service that potentially has
a very long long time
so so you have conflicting we would like
to have a long Lifetime on the alt
service advertisement because we want
you to remember what protocol to use
especially at the different endpoint
when you come back on a future
connection
but on the other hand
load balancing happens at a much shorter
time scale so we don't want you to
remember
so we want some some amount of
stickiness
but we want DNS to be able to clear it
or override it at the time of your next
connection and it's trying to strike the
right balance of that that's difficult
right now
okay
um yeah I think the
uh it's perfectly reasonable to
uh to say that the alt service B is a
sticky indicator of which of the alt
hosts or which of the alt RRS is prep is
preferred and that its lifetime is is
the
um and that it it applies after DNS
resolution so on some you know a week
from now I want to connect I re-resolve
the name I I get a an RR set and then I
check it against my sticky post name and
if the sticky host name is in that RR
set then uh the hint applies otherwise
it's discarded
um I think that gets you what you want
right and the the current draft as
submitted actually has a flag that you
can put in an rsat or on a record
that says never use this alternative
unless you've explicitly told to
yeah one thing that I wonder about here
is should we just make this stickiness
thing a like general property of
uh of the https record of service
bindings like
you gotta you know you tried various
service bindings in the past and you
found that one of them was the one that
actually worked like do you really have
to try them in priority order next time
since you know that so the other ones
didn't work and this one did or your
selection algorithm selected this one
last time
so from the discussion at the workshop
that is actually something that certain
clients do
um I don't know that we need to specify
that per se
right it just seems like you could you
could effectively just say uh this is
just a special case of that
yeah
okay that's enough
pardon
yeah so I wanted to make clear here that
the The Proposal from the the design
team that's been working on on this
whole service thing is effectively to
take
this or something approximating this as
the complete replacement for Old service
so the draft proposes that we
I think that I've got to use the right
words now obsolete
not deprecate is that right
um uh we obsolete 78 38 and
um
that seems to be the general sense that
that I've gotten in discussions is we
want to effectively say that all
services no longer useful
um
there are some suggestions on how we
might improve there are a number of open
questions that we have
um Mike probably didn't touch on all of
them
uh the more interesting ones for me is
um uh https records have priority order
that gives you some control over where
people end up and you can always put
these Alternatives that you don't want
people to use as the primary entry point
to your service down the priority list
on your https
are assets that you return
but maybe that's not as not definitive
enough so we also defined an attribute
on on each one of them that says don't
use this unless it's an alternative
um that you've been told to use
explicitly those two mechanisms both
provide you with some amount of control
over the use of an alternative we're not
sure if we need those things
someone on GitHub has actually proposed
that we have an alternative way of
spelling the the stickiness which I
think would be quite interesting I've
asked them to post it to the mailing
list and if they don't I will because I
think it's an interesting idea but um
we're sort of trying to get a sense of
the general shape of this thing to see
if people are interested in
you know does this does this solve your
problems uh we've heard from a number of
people that simply deprecating old
service and relying more on https
records solves their problems adequately
and they don't necessarily need this
thing we've heard from others that they
like the idea of being able to steer
traffic using using the the old service
records uh the old service advertisement
as we've defined so that's the sort of
feedback we're looking for here so just
to be clear that the potential path
forward then is once we get enough
Comfort around this to stop working on
service bests and to adopt this new
draft correct that would be the idea but
I think we at this point we're just
putting this in front of people we're
not quite ready for that time to to
think about it right and also recognize
that there's a few things that we need
some input on as well but it does sound
like we we probably should Park old
service business until we know yeah the
the alternate spelling of that is to
incorporate the new draft into all
service business there are lots of ways
we can do this yeah yeah
uh Eric knier Apple so I just wanted to
reiterate a little bit and you were
saying is this useful for people and so
I thought I could say heck yes it is
um so we we strongly prefer uh getting
this kind of information from DNS it's
much nicer because it's for the place
that you're actually going
um and it's something most importantly
that you know up front at the time that
you're going so rather than saying for
next time you can say for this time uh
and that has been shown uh I think via
some data that was presented the
previous ITF that that makes a
significant and measurable difference in
the amount of H3 that we actually use
um so that much is awesome being able to
take https records and say these are
lower priority and have a separate
signal for do not use this in less
houses on fire uh both of those signals
I think we find are super useful and we
have a number of people where we are
asking them to do that and they say we
do not have a mechanism so we can't do
that so if this gives them that
mechanism then uh like both of those
unique signals are awesome yes please
and then beyond that
yeah we can go into the rest of what's
left for alt service after we've moved
that out but I just want to say we do
very much have a need for that and we
would be shipping it yesterday if we had
it
thank you
um it probably is important to note that
at least at 1 14 we did have some people
saying they didn't want the ability to
indicate H3 with a header to go away
entirely so we may
that may just be solved by okay you can
use the obsolete thing if you really
have to
but
it's important for us to remember that
some people do still need that
affordance for a little while
that's a question what the time skills
are and yeah yeah David schenazi uh
that's pretty much exactly what I was
going to say and just to explain that
um Chrome and other web browsers today
don't always have access to the https
record
because like apple platforms are awesome
and they have good apis but if you look
at Posse's cross-platform get Adder info
gives you
pretty much what existed at the time so
realistically speaking in some platforms
where Chrome has its own DNS resolver
everything's fine I know there's some
people at ITF weeping that the
applications are all bundling their DNS
resolvers now but for cases where we
don't we'll still need to use the old
thing I
don't love that we're obsoleting the old
thing because it's still useful but you
know at the end of the day it doesn't
really matter as long as we're on the
same page that we might still make
changes to Old service if we have a
reason to then everyone's good so like
empty was saying we can obsolete it but
we're not deprecating it and that seems
fine I forget what all those words mean
anyway
Tommy
all right uh this is a question for
David if he's still up um
I I think there's some comments on the
list around
uh can you know when are we going to
update posix get at our info
um you know I don't think that functions
function signature is going to change at
any point soon
um
just to confirm I imagine people would
probably be okay with a separate
function in some standard DNS library
because you know get Adder info already
probably is coupling too much of the a
in Quad a queries synchronously and so
you know your svcb lookups should be
separate anyway so would it be
sufficient On Any Given platform to have
a somewhat bespoke
DNS API for these things
um yeah well David schenazi uh Happy
eyeballs Enthusiast
um yeah like in practice it's a matter
of time at the end of the day like
um and resources
um Chrome today has like all the energy
like we don't have a huge networking
team as we used to and so the energy
goes into the client DNS like I don't
work on Chrome anymore
um the the energy is going on to like
the DNS resolver that is bundled with
chrome and the like cross-platform
fallback
users get Adder info and pretty much is
not going to see any love uh probably
unless it becomes like a pressing issue
so give an infinite time totally will do
it it makes sense it's possible but it's
in Practical things there's always
another shiny API web API to do instead
but just to clarify I think the goal is
to ship the um its uh chromosome
resolver on all platforms and that kind
of makes this go away just it turns out
to be like trickier than expected so I
think at some point we'll get there and
this becomes a non-issue at least for
Chrome I don't know what Firefox is
doing when like they're not using dough
Lucas
sorry I didn't use the tool my phone ran
out
um no recovery from that
um so is somebody responsible for
advertising H3 and wanting to work and
being involved in the design team I
support the shape of the solution that
we've got as Martin said that the the
suggestion on GitHub the other day is
kind of interesting be willing to see
where that goes or doesn't but
um I really like this because I don't
have to do anything like I would support
this because the clients need to do some
things and change stuff and we already
do HBS records and it would all kind of
work very straightforwardly but I'm not
in a humongous rush to to remove the old
service header tomorrow or or whatever
like we can leave it there and it has a
place for me the important signal here
is is for people who who are suffering
now with the the problems of the old
service header they're asking us to try
and find Solutions around it and and
having the ITF give them a clear signal
that this is not the power to be
explored for future Solutions but it's
not a dead end either in the sense that
it's going to be turned off and we're
never going to speak anything and you're
just going to be left in limbo with no
way to use H3 that's not what we want we
just want to make it clear with what the
future is in our mind and that dates can
just come in the future whenever it is
yeah so Mountain Thompson I find it
funny sometimes too when we're talking
about lack of engineering resources at
Chrome when it's often the other way
around but
um the I think I think that's the
transient problem uh I think probably
the more pressing one is the
availability of https records and how
able you are to to make a query for them
we've done some research that hopefully
will be published relatively soon uh
that that talks about the success rates
for for different types of DNS records
and off the top of my head I can't
remember the exact numbers but it was
something in the order of sort of two
percent for A's and quad A's five
percent for https failed uh it was more
like 45 for our DNS Sac related uh
Records for those who are who are
curious about those sorts of things so
um
that that to me speaks to to having some
amount of https uh sorry alt service
Legacy style uh around it may be that we
want to encourage people to to start
shortening their max age on that side
something closer to this sort of
behavior from from the systems and we
don't run into the sort of two caches
problem that was a major issue with
without service in the first place
um that said I think uh
this really hinges on
like how much HTTP 3 you're willing to
sacrifice to
to the altar of just making progress I
think probably at the moment for those
people who are you know maybe strapped
for engineering resources this is
possibly you know too much HTTP 3 to to
leave on you know unrealized but there
may be a point in the future where we
can sort of say well that sort of
incremental you know three or two or
three percent of networks that don't
pass https records just
if I get the H2 and that's okay but
that's a discussion we'll have to have
later
any more slides that's okay
all right so it sounds like uh We've
made some pretty good progress we still
need to do a little more work and a
little more
socialization maybe
um so I think we'll continue to leave
the old service best document parked
yeah because please read the draft
provide comments yeah continue to work
on that and then we'll get to a point
where we need to do a call for adoption
if we think we're right for him yeah
and figure out the disposition of all
the other pieces at the same time yeah
any other questions comments for Mike
okay all right thank you very much Mike
that was that was very productive and
also the next speaker and and you've got
a little extra time too okay
so uh next up origin H3 which I believe
is this one yes
once again okay
um so this is the origin frame that we
had on H2 recast in H3
however much you like it or you don't
that's where we are
so first we should recap all of the
semantic changes from H2
there they are review them carefully
next
so structural changes uh stream zeros or
request stream in H3 so we have control
streams so we have to map those terms
and then Lucas filed an issue that we
hadn't caught previously that H2 has
Flags
H3 does not have Flags
so here's what the original origin spec
has to say about flags big slide
which is we don't use them but we might
in the future
so then there are four flags that are
mandatory to understand if the flag is
set and you don't know what it means
ignore the frame
the other flags are not mandatory to
understand if they're set and you don't
know what they mean shrug and move on
keep using the frame as you understand
it
so we have those
in H3 we would have no way to set them
if we ever did Define them in the future
next slide
so what do we do about that we could
take the very simple path of deprecate
flag usage from H2 and say we haven't
needed them so far we're not going to
we could not say anything and fix the
problem if we need to need to down the
line although that could be kind of
awkward if we decide to retrofit them
into H3 later
we can stick an always zero byte in the
frame which makes me a little sad but
you know it's one bite
or we can stick and optionally present
Flags byte on the end and if it is all
zero you may admit it
um none of these seem fantastic all of
them will work
opinions and then let's move on okay
Martin Thompson before we go on I'm just
going to note the very nice options pun
on this slide well done
yeah
yeah so
um we have mandatory Flags turns out
mandatory flags are just called frame
types so we don't have that problem uh
if you want to if you want to define a
flag that's mandatory to understand
pick another frame type and off you go
so problem solved there
um the optional ones uh optional in
which case we can solve that problem
later when someone wants to Define one
of those flags and we might do it in any
number of ways by defining new frame
types or by defining this stupid hack
thing with the bit at the end that you
cut off if it's not there
I think these are problems best solved
by Future Ross who I predict will
probably never actually care to solve
them anyway
oh David
uh dude it's kanazi similar to Mt I
think yeah we have a fourth option which
is Kick the Can down the road uh we're
not painting ourselves into a corner
because if we need it the correct thing
is the frame types we have one extension
joint that we should grease well we
don't need 17 of them so just say we
don't use them
done okay and sure maybe I won't even
bother deprecating them from H2 like
just don't use them don't don't
accommodate them Lucas Lucas Pardo um
yeah so I created the issue and I didn't
think of any solutions for it sorry um I
forgot I'd opened it but it was in a fit
of late night spec reviewing
um yeah I don't like any of those
options I don't think we should change
H2 at all so I agree with David there
adding adding bites and stuff just seems
weird
I don't this is a lot of the time with
with H2 and H3 we're trying to mitigate
kind of proxies that might pass through
frames even though you're not passing
frames through you're reconstituting
them from their parts kind of thing
origin is a bit of an odd one I don't
think there's many anyone kind of
passing origin across multiple proxies
like that like I don't think we know
enough about the problem to be able to
design anything
that would make sense and not complicate
stuff no good use so if we want to
Define four frame types that just
basically all know up so it's just this
is these are all the types for origin in
H3 and they're all the same but since
fine it's not it's no harder to write
that code than for one type
do you think we need to define those
frame types now or just leave ourselves
the possibility to Define them in the
future I I don't know I have no strong
opinion I I had a weird idea a few years
ago about maybe a use for one of the
flags in the H2 frame
um so maybe but without a concrete use
case like printing on it would be fine
we're not We're not gonna we're not
short of space for frame types
I'll just give my own feedback to me
that the the clearly worst option here
is the last one for the reason for the
reason you point out it is not worth
doing that to save one bite okay
um
but it sounds like we might be
converging on
kicking it down the road giving the
problem to a future us and closing the
issue with no action I think is the
outcome which I think is a fine solution
I'm seeing thumbs up is it worth a hum
I don't know
um I've done a home for so long you know
or sorry just or it's like
never mind
um I will point out that in terms of
actual structure of the frame
um reserving multiple frame types to
account for all the flags is exactly the
same as sticking one extra byte in in
fact it's slightly worse because of the
varanth and the two bits for that
but you're saying actively reserving
them not just kicking down the road
correct if we if we were to reserve them
then we might as well just stick a bite
down
if we're getting him down the road then
we don't worry about it we don't know we
don't discuss that part of the spec okay
one more question does anybody really
care about this
hmm
look all right
that's all you got I will go close the
issue so the remaining question which uh
is implied by the picture
are we at the Finish Line working group
last call
all right I see nodding heads and thumbs
up things all right yes thank you thank
you
pretty well on time
uh next up cookies
and how long did we reserve for this I
think we're gonna talk for 15 minutes at
most
foreign
hello all my name is Stephen bingler
Google Chrome and I'll be going over a
status update for 6265 this for anybody
who was present at the last interim
meeting these slides are going to seem
very familiar
uh next slide please
um
so there hasn't been a new draft since
actually that's
that's not true as of about five minutes
ago when we just pushed a new draft but
I'm going to talk as if we didn't do
that there hasn't been a new draft since
ITF uh 114
um so all these changes are since that
previous draft during previous meetings
I've stood here and read through all
those bullet points and that felt
stilted and weird so instead I'm going
to leave them on the screen for a few
moments and if anybody has any questions
I can go into more detail about them
later next slide
one moment two moments next slide
um let's see
there's only one change here that's
actually worth talking about
um
just landed one where cookie prefix
names are now checked cased
insensitively
um previously they were checked
sensitively meaning that you had to get
the exact case for the guarantees for
cookie prefixes to be applied these are
the underscore underscore secure and
underscore underscore host Dash cookies
um but it turns out that servers don't
always check cookies sent case
sensitively because of course they don't
so servers were setting prefixes without
realizing that they weren't getting any
of the guarantees from browsers and
that's bad so we fixed that
next slide
we have three open issues currently
um same-site cookies and redirects click
recap on this
um
the there was a bug in the original spec
where same site did not take the
redirect chain into account so if you
redirected from site a through site B
and back to site a we would consider
that same site and happily send you your
same-site cookies
um that's wrong
the spec was fixed but when Chrome tried
to launch this or enable this feature
we got a ton of complaints and there was
a lot of site breakage so we disabled it
and currently trying to figure out next
steps we're collecting metrics on how
sites are using this Behavior to try to
get a better idea of what to do with it
but with the US holiday season
approaching I'm expecting I'm not going
to get anything useful until
until q1
uh the other two open issues internal
white space and cookie names and values
this was recently filed uh turns out
that the three major browsers Chrome
Firefox and Safari all handle internal
tabs somewhat differently internal tab
being that you have some other non-tab
characters a tab more more non-tab
characters
the spec was modified uh somewhat
recently to disallow control characters
but it accepted tab characters
what this means is that now the spec
says you should accept those internal
tabs
but not all browsers do so I'm trying to
figure out if that change to the spec
should have happened and whether we
should revert it
um final one is
a mouthful uh the spec should more
clearly advise which parts a reader
should Implement I filed this one
because we've had a number of
issues with implementers implementing
the wrong requirements because they are
confused on what they should do and I
can't exactly blame them it's not an
easy document to read so this is kind of
a task for myself to go through and
write some pros that makes it a little
bit simpler for someone to know what
they need to implement
all right next slide please
um so we've already have some work plan
post RFC 6265 this the first is cookies
having independent partition State Dylan
will be up here in a few minutes to talk
in more detail about that the second one
is Cookie spec layering
um originally Johann Hoffman was going
to speak on that unfortunately he wasn't
able to make it so I'm going to say a
few a few words about it
um yep I'm hitting things on my computer
here
so
um cookie layering is an effort being
headed by Johann Hoffman and Anna van
kestron the idea is that the cookie spec
has kind of intermingled itself with
the browser specs
um with same site and partition cookies
and blocking and this is an effort to
sort of decouple the cookie spec from
things that could be better handled by
say the fetch spec
um
let's see
um this was brought up during TPAC as
like an initial idea and request for
feedback and
seems somewhat positive but there's a
lot of work ahead for it
that is all that I have do we have any
questions
so I I think the idea here is you want
to close those three issues
go through working group last call go to
the ITF isgq publication process and
then we'll we'll talk about starting
almost an immediate revision again
uh to address your your deferred issues
and and these work items is that kind of
yes that's correct once the once the
file once the three open issues are
closed I'm hoping to go into last call
okay and the cookie spec layering and
there's been some background discussion
about that I think that's we've for a
long time talked about how to make the
the cookie spec more accessible more
user friendly I think we want to try and
involve uh non-browser communities as
well to see where the right line is to
draw about making that separation but
that that's a discussion we can have I
think that's very reasonable uh David
spanazi
hi I'm failing to find the issue but I
remember there being some discussion on
the topic of uh utf-8 characters and it
just allowed characters in general
about how the spec allows a different
set for setting cookies than for sending
them
and like I think April King kind of
found some issues there that were even
somewhat were worrisome from a security
perspective where did that discussion go
I just couldn't find it sorry
um that discussion happened in a pull
request rather than an issue uh that's
why uh I spoke with uh April
um just you know face to face and we
decided that at the moment
um okay so context April has found a
number of issues where browsers will
send in safe cookies that servers then
won't accept
this is a problem primarily because
nowadays a server is not a single entity
companies will have
SAS products that they use that will
send cookies but then their python
framework or PHP or whatever won't
accept back the same cookie that that
origin sent out which when the spec was
developed I assume the the authors
thought that oh if a server is going to
send something can obviously understand
it when he gets it back
um after talking with April we decided
that simply changing the spec to say
that oh hey server should ex should
accept this expanded character set was
not the correct
correct route
um
I I think there is no I know there's a
deferred issue for the for the next
version of the spec where we are going
to more formally research look into
allowing expanded character sets and
kind of what the effect that's going to
have
um but at the moment it's the plan is to
keep the status quo
thanks that that's reasonable I like mt
and I are working on an active protocol
maintenance documents that talks about
these considerations so having the spec
match reality is important
um maybe if you know I don't want to
volunteer you for work but if we could
have like a paragraph explaining that
there is a foot gun in the spec
um that might be useful just you know as
a warning note that this is different
from this and you you here be dragons
might be good yeah that's exactly what
that final long-winded issue that I
filed is which is like make it easier uh
yes thank you highlighting perfect I
think that's exactly what that's
supposed to be
yeah that's been kind of an ongoing
theme for a little while so it's good to
see that addressed
yeah all right should we go into
partition cookies then
yeah all right thank you all thank you
foreign
my name is Dylan Cutler I am also on
Google Chrome
um and I will be discussing partition
cookies with you guys today
uh slide
um so just a quick overview
um so when we say a cookie is
partitioned as opposed to unpartitioned
what we mean is that
um when a cookie is
and when an unpartitioned cookie is set
in a third-party context it is available
on essentially any top level domain that
makes requests to The Domain that set
the cookie
um and by partition cookies we mean that
um these third party cookies would only
be available on the top level site in
which were they were created and then if
the user were to navigate to a different
top level site
um then the third party domain would
receive like a brand new cookie jar
um also this is like a forewarning this
talk is going to be like because it's
partition cookies a little more browser
heavy than some other like talks um so
if that's not your thing feel free to
tune me out uh slide
um so the partitioned attribute is a
proposal for a new cookie attribute
which would allow sites to opt into this
Behavior
um and just to go over the design really
quickly it would require uh secure
um domains would be allowed up to 10
kilo uh kilobytes
or 180 cookies per partition and we
determine how much memory a domain is
using per Partition by the size
of the name and value of the cookies
um and then another detail is that clear
site data would also only clear cookies
in the current partition that it was in
and this would be to prevent uh cross
domain entropy leaks essentially there's
a tax you could set up where you
intentionally call clear-site data on
different top level domains in order to
essentially like build enough cross-site
entropy to develop a like persisting
cross-site identifier
uh slide
so um today I'm just going to be going
over some of the open issues we have for
partition cookies
um the first one will be how do we deal
with Partition cookies in what we call
quote-unquote unpartitioned contexts
um also we want to discuss whether the
partition key should have
um a field called cross-site ancestor
bit
um we also will discuss how to handle
partitioned and unpartitioned cookies
which have the same name
and then finally we'll go over
um should there be a way that user
agents convey that they are sending the
request from a context in which only
partition cookies are allowed if we're
in a future world where
um unpartitioned third-party cookies are
obsoleted uh next slide
um so first we'll talk about partition
cookies and unpartitioned context and
I'll start by defining what we mean by
an unpartitioned context
um in this case it would mean a first
party context and so in that case the
um it's a request where the top level
domain and the domain making the
requests getting or setting the cookie
is the same or it would be contexts
which have received
um a privilege essentially through user
consent through something like storage
access API for example
um and
um one like Nuance we like to point out
is that
um Chrome and other browsers
particularly firefox's implementation of
unpartitioned contacts differ
um this is kind of where the issue
arises Chrome supports both
unpartitioned and partition cookies at
the same time and uses null for the
latter's partition key whereas in other
browsers as soon as storage access API
is granted
um the partition key for that context
essentially switches to that first that
cookies domain as if it were like kind
of originating from the cookies site
um and so the question is how do we
handle cookies that are set with a
partitioned attribute in these contexts
um you know do we set the partition key
to be like the current top level site
which is what we are proposing is the
right answer um or do we just use like
whatever the current partition key is we
think that we should just set it to be
whatever like the current top level site
is even in these more privileged
contexts
um just because the site is including
the partitioned attribute because
they're opting into this Behavior
explicitly and there are also ways to
use cookies in these contexts without
using the partitioned attribute
next slide oh and then one more note
about that asterisk point when I say
like Chrome supports partition and
unpartitioned cookies at the same time
what I I don't mean that Chrome will
like continue supporting unpartitioned
third-party cookies into the future
posts it's third party cookie uh
deprecation timeline
um just wants to like kind of clear the
air there in case I accidentally store
any fires um and so uh moving on from
there on the next thing we want to talk
about is whether the partition key
should have what's called a cross-site
ancestor bit and I think the best way to
explain this is visually so
um let's say a server is setting a
partition cookie in a first party
context where the uh request domain and
the top level domain are the same
um in this case
the crossline ancestor bit would be
false because the request is originating
directly from the top level frame uh
slide please
um
but in this next scenario here we see
that although the request is coming from
the same site as the top level domain
there is a third party ancestor or
cross-site ancestor between the um top
level site and this frame or context
like making this request
uh next slide please
it takes a while yeah it's fine
um so
this cross-site ancestor chain bit was
actually originally introduced in the
w3c as part of like the storage
partitioning effort um where browsers
are partitioning JavaScript storage in
the same way we're partitioning cookies
so that they aren't accessible to sites
across different top level domains
um and the reasoning behind that was
like primarily to like correctly compute
site for cookies in Partition service
workers
um
and effectively by adding this bit it
would separate the partition that top
level contexts get from
um
context with a cross-site ancestor
and
on the question of whether we want to
add this to the cookie partition key
um there's a pro which is that
um there are consistent cookie sorry
consistent partition boundaries across
uh cookies and storage which is nice for
developers but there are some cons for
example this would essentially be a
re-implementation of same site because
developers can already restrict which
cookies are accessible in and out of
these contexts by setting a cookies same
site locks or strict
um and then another con is that there
are cookie use cases
um if you want to know specifics you can
ask me after
um where the top level site and uh same
site in bed with a cross-site ancestor
actually need to like communicate with
each other with cookies and so we think
that adding this ancestor chain bit
would be harmful
uh next slide
um and so the next issue we wanted to go
over is how to handle partition and
unpartitioned cookies with the same name
um and it turns out there's actually
already precedent for this
um domains can set cookies with the same
name as long as they differ in either
their domain or path attributes
um and so in order to account for
partition cookies we propose adding the
partition key to this Tuple of
attributes that we use to consider what
cookies are unique and that if a browser
were to set a cookie with the same name
and value but one had the partition
attribute and one would not we would
send both cookies and the cookie header
and subsequent requests
next slide
um and then the last issue
um how can user agents convey if a site
us all right how can user agents convey
if a request comes from a context in
which
um the browser would only accept
partition cookies
um and we think that this shouldn't
really be a blocker for specking
partition cookies this is kind of a
long-term question and has implications
Beyond like just partition cookies
um and so kind of our solution for now
is just pump this down the line
um next slide
um so the next steps would be to
continue to align with spec work with
this group and also um the w3c to align
with uh things like the cookie store API
or document.cookie
um and also chips or cookies having
independent partition state is a uh
good example of actually how iitf might
benefit from cookie layering because
essentially if cookie layering happens
and we move some of these more browser
specific things into the fetch spec then
really all the ietf needs to be
concerned with is how
um how user agents parse the
a partition token in the cookie line and
then they can kind of let the fetch spec
handle the rest of the partitioning
Behavior
um and that's it so anyone has any
questions feel free
so I think from a process standpoint
here
um when we talked about adding major new
features for 6265 bits we had a
relatively rigorous process for getting
consensus around here's a proposal with
a draft does the community want to add
that to 6265 scope and so um this is
probably too late for 62.65 this and I
don't think that's a surprise to you
which is good
um and the question is you know when we
do this next revision that we were just
talking about you know are we going to
use a similar process and if so you know
what would our folks interested in
taking this on as as a piece of work and
as before I think you know in in 6065
original as well as this we kept the
focus very firmly on implementer
intention uh and and so you know folks
who have cookie jars they're not the
only people who matter but they do
really matter to this discussion so
that's who at least we we should hear
from Martin
yeah so um during my Mozilla hat but the
Privacy CG chair and w3c that that group
has pretty broad support for this work
and would very much like to see
the work proceed and I I think we have
agreement also that the ITF is the right
place to do that
um because the ITF owns the cookies back
and it doesn't make any sense to put it
anywhere else uh I I think we're willing
to be guided by everyone else in terms
of timelines and whatnot and it very
much seems like this cookie revision is
like this close is my impression
um and I see nodding so that's good
because I would really like to say it
finished as well as much as it's been 15
years or however long it is so
um
I I think this is probably something
that I would sort of advocate for
some sort of signal that it's uh working
in the ITF process uh so I sort of would
prefer if this were adopted here
um perhaps parked on the side so that we
can continue to work on it and refine it
and answer some of the interesting
questions Dylan's asking here but not
um block other important work that would
be my preference here
to me that sounds reasonable and I think
one of the questions in my mind is do we
launch that next cookies work at
Yokohama or even beforehand but I guess
that depends on a lot of different
things
okay any other comments thoughts
anyone online as well
Brian
there's maybe sort of a naive question
but can you explain a little bit more
the rationale for providing this
at all uh versus the the browser just
making its own decisions about how it
will partition or not partition that it
it's always felt to me like it's a a
question of how the behavior of the
client itself the browser or whatever
behaves and putting it onto the wire and
part of the cookies
back
um
um it's hard hard to articulate it more
than that but
referring to like the attribute
um and like the opt-in behavior and just
say like yeah okay yeah like at least
it's my understanding like uh Firefox
Mozilla basically partition cookies
right or has the opportunity to
partition cookies in their client and
they just did it they partitioned them
top level domain lower level domain it
just sort of happens
so bringing this into a spot trying to
give servers the opt-in behavior is
never quite
I've never quite understood the the
rationale or the motivation behind that
and it almost feels simpler to not to
just allow it to continue to be a
behavior that the the client decides on
um at least Karma's philosophy on this
is that
um we want to encourage this to be like
an opt-in Behavior at least in the time
between now and when on partition
third-party cookies are turned down and
the reason being is that like a lot of
servers rely on third-party cookie
functionality for various things some of
that's cross-site tracking which we're
not okay with but then some of it are
some use cases that we are okay with and
um in this sort of transitory period
where we move off of third-party cookies
um we think that like providing this
attribute and this opt-in Behavior
provides developers with an opportunity
to kind of migrate their systems over to
this partitioned World
um
you know before
we just completely kind of take the rug
out from under them and remove on a
partitioned third-party cookies
um
so it's kind of a web compat
I guess uh reasoning behind it wouldn't
again I apologize for I'm not fully
understanding but in terms of
compatibility it always it feels like
there's cases that are going to break
then if you're expecting
third-party cookies that will otherwise
work in a partition context and you're
not opting into them so like a server
that you know does whatever it does in a
in a frame or something
and continues to get set cookies get
cookies as they would you partition
those it doesn't know the difference in
terms of How It's behaving but if if
suddenly it's changed such that you have
to opt in with their or partition
cookies then that would I believe stop
working with unless you
make the migration so it feels like that
area is not compat at least not in the
way that I think about it be a breaking
change
and require software updates to well
continue working I think like kind of at
some point there is a breaking change
that needs to be made either it's like
removing third-party cookies entirely or
it's just partitioning them by default
so at some point we're going to be
breaking sites I think it's just like a
matter of difference on sort of how we
want that breakage to occur
um I think that like our philosophy is
that
um you know the the server getting the
lack of cookie back once we do turn down
third party cookies is a signal that
like it's not working as intended versus
having the user agent just sort of like
change the behavior of the cookie from
underneath the site without really
giving it any indication that that's
what's going on
um is like kind of just as bad in our
opinion
okay
yeah I have almost the opposite
perspective that
that just to have things continue
working
to the extent that they can without
requiring any changes to opt-in a
behavior that should just
yeah
it seems it seems unnecessary and sort
of backwards um but maybe I'm often that
weeds
here
kind of feels that way there is an
explainer correct there is yes
um I can if you want to come up to me
like after this and if you have any
additional questions to or I can also
like send you a link to the explainer
where we talk about things in a lot
better detail
um so yeah I encourage you to do that
okay thanks
so Martin Thompson this has been debated
at length
um in other forums and
um it was it was a the consensus view I
think was that that blocking blocking
cookies in these third-party context was
the desirable outcome it was not
necessarily uh unanimous that that was
the the outcome there were there were a
number of reasons the ones that Dylan
articulated uh for doing it this way I
also believe that certain other
platforms have a little bit of trouble
when they tried to um
implement partitioning properly and
those were limitations around
um devices not being particularly
performant when partitioning was in
place and so
um and those were also rooted in the
architecture of those systems as well
which I think was a little unfortunate
but
um
ultimately our experience with
partitioning is that it mostly almost
completely works and so you could do
without this but we were sort of in the
minority when it came to the discussions
there and and we want to respect the
um the consensus process there and uh
the ultimately
this is fine
it's not great but this is this is what
gets everyone doing partitioned and
um State properly so this is the this is
the Compromise
okay
well and and you know we haven't
formally adopted anything yet uh it's
continuing discussion but it's a good
start I think
anything else
thank you
okay
thank you very much and we're on time
too
uh next up we're going to go back uh to
a rearranged agenda and talk about
client certs
right
I recognize that photo
I thought so in London some time ago
okay so yeah client search uh I've only
got five minutes here so this is me
pretty short uh go to the next slide
I Know It Takes a Minute
Martin if you want to clear yourself
unless you already have comments
uh so
Mark uh encouraged us to just focus on
issues questions Etc and not give any
context or anything it's hard for me but
I take a shot at that in interest of
saving time here so uh back in October
we published uh 03 really
um relatively minor changes stating that
the certificate chain is presented in
the same order as it would be defined in
TLS rather than trying to copy a bunch
of language from TLS that that is
difficult to get right and sort of
problematic did a bunch of reference
updates to things that are now are now
rfcs uh made HTTP semantics a normative
reference some of the normative
informative stuff's a little tricky to
get right here but that one made sense
mentioned that uh in the case the origin
server Access Control decisions
um need to be conveyed at the HTTP
application layer either by selecting
specific response content or sending a
403 or something but uh be pretty clear
that we're not trying to invent any sort
of cross layer signaling about error
conditions or Access Control decisions
um October 30th started working group
last call and
um next slide
I did this sort of last minute because I
did have a saying that said there was no
open issue
um Lucas Conley did a review and put a
number of things up here thanks Lucas
um there are a number of issues that are
open I don't think any of them are very
controversial uh we have a little bit of
a discussion going about sort of text
and what it might look like in the
future versus now in context and so
forth but it will work through that I
saw another one come up do that as well
um but there's uh yeah the these are
open I plan to address them
um I don't think there's anything
uh of of consequence of consequence in
terms of progressing things along and uh
we are still in uh last call for a
little while
um
that's it that's sort of a boring
presentation but that was I think the
goal okay
uh any questions comments have people
looked at this draft
Martin here in the queue I assume that's
from last time
hello Lucas it's here
um yeah I just had a blast of the draft
like you say loads of these are just
really low-key there's a little things
you can pick and tidy up but it got
caught in some other reviewer
um some other editorial like I say we
disagree that's okay you're the editor
if you want to do it that way that's
that's your discretion so just just
wanted to give some kind of
contrast and feedback so that in case
you didn't think of it that way so I'm
happy however we resolve them all right
thanks for saying that I I didn't think
about it that way until you brought it
up but even as I think about it I'm I
still sort of like the background and
context but
um let me think about it a little bit
also in reflection this this is an
informational draft that is correct yeah
so I I think I might have forgotten that
so
um on reflection you know it's having
some context is that there might be they
might continue to be other drafts that
or sorry other other headers that
provide this capability I'm afraid
they're almost certainly will be long
under the foreseeable future as I think
this this sort of came along a little
too late and so it
yeah and and so phrasing it as you've
done is is kind of uh reflects the
reality of that this is a way to do it
but it's it's not the standard because
it's not a standard yeah cheers
thanks for that
Jonathan
wow you're already tall
um Jonathan Hoyle and cloudflare
um I I haven't looked at this draft so I
just looked at it now
um but the security security
considerations is super light is that
not
absolutely terrifying
um I I thought they were
pretty well done but you know I wrote
them so that doesn't uh necessarily say
much the security considerations are
meant to cover the
I don't know how to answer that I guess
it sounds like you might have some
suggestions yeah if if they're specific
so I I only looked at the security
considerations because I was just
curious about how this would work
but
how is the the proof that the client
owns the certificate transferred to the
oxygen in the way that it can tell it's
not in any way so the the there's an
expectation that that the
intermediary the reverse proxy is is
trusted to do this and it's simply
conveying the information to the back
end in which case I stand by my previous
statement this is terrifying
and that's why it's informational that
is part of why it's informational
Jonathan thank you for your uh for to
contribute to PR
aise
so actually uh to to follow up with that
statement this is one of the use cases
where this and the signatures draft uh
are intended to work hand in hand and we
actually call this out in the signatures
draft because something that a uh a
terminating TLS terminating reverse
proxy
can do with both of these drafts
together is send back is is to do the
TLs validation and then sign like add a
signature for this header to the message
on the way in that the original client
obviously isn't going to add in itself
so that the origin server sitting off in
a back in a back end somewhere will be
able to check the reverse proxy
signature against those inputs and then
that's how that trust is conveyed it's
it's a transitive process it requires a
lot of out-of-band uh configuration and
knowledge but it is one way to string
this together and you're still sort of
taking the reverse proxies word for it
it just is signing its word versus
relying on other mechanisms yeah so
there are all kinds of like obviously
you don't design protocol standing on
one foot but like
the the easy or not the easy huh
there seems to be an obvious way of
trying this with sort of exported
authenticators or like some kind of
certificate that's actually bound to the
TLs connection and then you just pass
through a proof that the
the the
terminating proxy controls this
particular session and that that
particular scientist client had signed
that particular session
like to prevent it
mismatching and swapping and so that was
discussed some I think when we talked
about adoption and uh the place we ended
up at was that this is the intention of
this draft is is to standardize existing
practice within the bounds of of
described thank you existing practice
and and align on a single header uh
because frankly a lot of reverse proxies
and cdns already do this
um and and so uh that that's one of the
reasons it's informational because we
don't want to put too strong of a
recommendation behind that realizing
that there are better Solutions it's
just that many felt that this would be
an improvement and uh uh it would be
more Deployable in at least in the
medium term
thank you
thanks for saying what I was trying to
say and sorry no no in better words I
appreciate that I was struggling over it
but that's a that's good context and I
think the correct
um summary of kind of how we got here
and what we're trying to accomplish yeah
anything else I think we're probably at
time on this one
all right working group last call will
continue if other folks want to take a
look and suggest some improvements uh we
should we should be at a working group
let's call pretty soon all right thank
you thank you
uh next up we have
cap of the day
a presentation about what the wonderful
people in mask are doing and how it may
or may not affect the world of http
sit back
get ready
to enjoy a mask Enthusiast at work David
skanazi
hello hello
everyone uh David scanazi mask
enthusiast
big surprise I know
um so uh the chairs of HTTP reached out
and asked if someone from Mass could uh
just give an update to the HTTP working
group about whatever the hell is going
on in mask because it's totally
different people sometimes mostly the
same people but not everyone knows and
some people might care and they don't
know next slide please
geez that is slow uh so what is mask so
the acronym is multiplexed application
substrate over quick encryption which is
quite a mouthful
um we came up with the name back in 2018
uh it was quite unfortunate that there
was then a global pandemic
um for actually more reasons than this
but um
but so now everyone Associates it with a
covet mask but that's not what we were
going for anyway uh why do we care next
slide please
so in a one-liner sentence it's we run
the internet over HTTP and if you think
that it's completely insane you're
probably not wrong next slide
so just kind of a quick history lesson
here back in the good old days of HTTP
before they had this thing called SSL
um
like bandwidth was expensive and people
will building cash servers especially if
they were on other continents where
things were really really far away uh
now we call them intermediaries
um
and then there was the idea like an
Enterprise or School networks that you
would intentionally go talk to that
terminatory because it's getting stuff
to you faster because it's already has
it cached
um that was you know in what we call Web
1.0 these days
um because everyone was loading the same
thing so you could cache it and nothing
was encrypted
um but then eventually SSL happened and
as usual the security people ruin
everything for everyone by making things
safer and not working anymore
um and so
people had to deployed these boxes and
were saying no if you want to reach the
internet you have to go through our HTTP
proxy because that reduces our internet
bill but now if you want to do TLS
through that you were stuck so the
connect method for H for HTTP was
invented so you could run a TCP through
and then run your SSL everyone's happy
again
fast forward multiple decades and we
eventually remember that the internet is
not just TCP
um quick is a thing quick becomes
standardized as at the ITF ah crap quick
runs over ADP how could we have
predicted this how do we get that over
http
next slide please Q mask
oh wow that is slow uh so the idea was
let's we already can proxy TCP turns out
that UDP is becoming even more of a
thing now and there are things that are
neither TCP nor UDP like the sctp people
still talk inside ITF and there are
other things so let's just add a add a
thing for that so let's just do connect
for UDP so let's call it connect UDP
and then we got to arguing for about
three years on how exactly to do that
and you end up with a solution that's
kind of as simple as you would imagine
where you take the UDP and you put it in
in the packet and you send it uh so we
got that published a few months ago
which was really nice
um
fun time and
because we had to have quite a few bike
sheds we decided to split the baby in
half so there's one RFC for proxy UDP
and HTTP and one RFC that it depends on
which is HTTP datagrams and also the
capsule protocol because we didn't
couldn't come up with a better name than
capsule so HTTP datagrams the idea is
that in addition to your regular HTTP
stream which is a concept that we've had
since HTTP 2 you can send datagram for
little bits of data and that's really
handy if you want to send UDP you just
put them in there the really reason for
that this exists is that you can then
map it to a quick datagram frame which
doesn't get retransmitted which is
exactly what you want for connect2db
because if you put it inside the stream
you'd get bad performance
um and
the capsule protocol that I mentioned
was something that we thought would be
useful a it's useful for like HTTP one
and two or you don't have the quick data
grab frame and it's also useful for
other things or more we wanted it for
that and we said well let's toss in a
tlv so it's extensible we have some use
cases for it so it allows you to send
something all the way through all the
intermediaries
um reliably
and so those were our first deliverables
here I've seen shipped a few months ago
we are working now on proxying IP and
HTTP we had a whole nice fun detour on
writing a requirements document uh for
that first
which I was kind of annoyed at Mark when
he suggested that at that first but he
made a point that like oh you're not
actually all agreeing on what you mean
by proxying IP and you were right so we
ended up arguing on the requirements
document instead of arguing on the
discussion on the solution document but
at least when we went to build the
solution we knew what we were going to
build so that's been taken care of we're
building the solution and we're pretty
close to done uh so we'll be discussing
this at the mask meeting which is
sometime this week uh come if you're
interested but we're pretty close to
done next slide please
so what why would you want mask
um
one of the things we discussed at the
beginning of the the effort was
do we want this to be over HTTP we all
agreed that it had to be on quick
because quick is the best thing ever uh
but then do we put it over HTTP 3 or
other things and we're thinking well
sometimes it's nice to be able to run
over networks that block qdp so putting
it out of http means you have access to
http one and two uh I really like the
fact that if you put it over HTTP then
it starts looking like web traffic so it
makes it really harder to block so now
you have a VPN that looks like web
traffic hard to censor I like that uh
don't say that some people don't like
that
um another part that I hadn't thought of
at all but that we realized was
companies like Google have already put
in a lot of effort in having a really
good HTTP server and so a quick stack
that's efficient and security reviewed
and HTTP HTTP load balancers and if you
build this over HP you kind of get to
reuse all of this for free so we end up
like in places where like oh can we use
ipsec and people were like no we'd have
to review that whole new stack and we
don't want to can you just find a way to
make it work over quick
and then there's a fun story there where
Alex and others back at Google actually
implemented a VPN over quick way before
the mask effort and
was kind of the Catalyst for the whole
thing and then we are closing the loop
on making that use mask now which is fun
um and then when we built this
um folks that like to use buzzwords like
zero trust and other things that and
serverless and things that I don't
understand said oh this is great can I
use this too uh and they were apparently
much the problem they had was they had
VMS in the cloud somewhere that needed
to talk to each other but there were
HTTP load balancers in the middle and
they wanted magic crypto and we said
well actually they had built something
using connect because that was the
simplest thing for them and then they
had a customer who wanted UDP so boom
this actually works for there like
reusing stuff is useful next slide
so where are we going from here uh the
mass working group was very tightly
scoped to make sure we didn't get too
distracted and to make it to kind of get
us to focus on shipping connect2dp and
connect IP
uh but now that we're almost done with
that uh we're talking about a sculptory
chartering for future things so that's
also on our agenda
um we don't I don't I don't think the
current plan from what I hear far on my
isg overlords is that they don't want to
mask maintenance working group that
lasts forever we'll just re-charter for
a few scoped extensions do those and
then potentially shut it down and say
future things happen in the HTTP working
group we'll have to discuss those things
it's not entirely figured out but I
guess that's what's going to happen but
what are the extensions that we've been
discussing that might happen before then
so first we have extensions to connect
UDP
so connect UDP is similar connect kind
of gives you a connected five Tuple
but if you want to do something like
webrtc where you're talking to multiple
hosts you're one proxy it doesn't work
for that so we have a little extension
for for doing that we have an extension
for doing quick over connect GDP you can
run quick over connect2dp non-extended
but Tommy had some clever ideas on how
you can optimize that and make it better
we have extensions kind of at the HTTP
datagram layer
Marcus and Erickson folks have an idea
for adding sequence numbers to catch
reordering when they're doing multi-path
quick
uh there's an extension from Ben
um about uh having a way to figure out
your path MTU through the entire chain
between your client and your endpoint so
that way it makes it easier to run
protocols unlike quick they can't do it
themselves Lucas has a draft about
priorities in HTTP datagrams that he's
very excited about next slide please
and we have some
um generic like other HTTP extensions
that the authors were thinking like
mainly in the context of mask but
could also be applicable to other HTTP
use cases so we haven't selected the
view in a venue like all this feature
work that I'm talking about is
individual drafts so Tommy has something
about sending more DNS information as
using the recently published proxy
status header and Ben has documents on
describing what mask services and HTTP
origin has and on modernizing connect
itself next slide
all right so we are meeting this week on
Wednesday we have a mailing list a
GitHub like all the cool kids uh if any
of this sounds interesting to you uh
please show up please come and we're
happy to bike shed on all the things as
we always do
that's it any questions
[Music]
any questions
this is mostly informational and then
some of the folks are already uh very
familiar with us we just thought it'd be
good to make sure that everybody in the
working group here was aware of what was
happening over there especially as you
get a little bit closer to stuff that
happens inside of http
so thank you very much for that really
appreciate it
um and with that I think
we're done for today let's check the
agenda
yes we are
fantastic sorry
oh what time is it well we have 25
minutes
your presentation from Friday being
which one on profited authentication I'm
prompted
um
in principle I don't have a problem with
that I'm just worried that somebody who
was expecting it on Friday might be a
little surprised by that but of course
there is always the mailing list uh
where if if we do adopt something or
whatever it'll make these senses so as
long as whatever happens goes to melon
must I think yeah which it would yeah
um
I think so sure any instructions to that
Tommy are you still awake I I am I'm
hanging in there got my coffee um yeah I
think that sounds fine
um
yeah
okay thank you reordering is something
we're still a little unfamiliar here in
HTTP land so you know I know
we have a mask for that
there's a better way to phrase that I'm
sure
all right hello it's me again
um David's kanazi HTTP Enthusiast
um so this so this is a draft that was
initially
part of the original Mass proposal so
this is actually not a bad segue and
people gave me very good advice at the
beginning that you don't merge
everything into a big castle in the sky
and otherwise it doesn't work you split
it up into small bits that makes sense
and so this was one of those that then
went dormant as we were all focusing on
mask itself and now people reached out
that were interested in it and I'm
trying to resurrect it and see where we
want to go with it
um so this now we have multiple
co-authors this work is joined with
David Oliver who's I think attending
virtually this time and Jonathan who's
right there next slide please
so
um the the draft initially was called
transport authentication and the reason
for that was that the
original mask proposal was uh I think
the term is monstrosity in terms of HTTP
semantics because it took over the whole
connection and did things that were very
evil by HTTP standards and so the new
version of masks as we talked about fits
into HTTP semantics but because of this
the old version needed a way to
authenticate the whole transport
um now we don't need that anymore so the
draft has been kind of completely
Rewritten the cryptography bits are
still in there but now it it fits in
HTTP semantics similar to how mask does
uh next slide
so the the motivation we have is we want
the client to authenticate to the server
uh to the origin as is commonly done
with HTTP Authentication
um we want to use asymmetric
cryptography because there are some use
cases where you want to be able to
share the like access list with their
public Keys across multiple Origins that
don't necessarily trust each other and
you want to avoid having an Argent be
able to impersonate one of the clients
and then the third requirement is we
want the server to hide the fact that it
serves authenticated resources so what I
mean by that is if you try to get this
resource you don't want a server to send
you a 401 and the reason for that is
let's say you have your personal website
but you want to offer some mask services
to authenticated clients you don't want
someone to be able to probe your server
and go oh no no that offers Mass that's
blocked on my network bang bang
um so those are the three like I'm gonna
dive a bit into the solution space in
this presentation but the the goal or
the interest of this draft is really to
get in see if there is interest in those
requirements and that motivation because
everything of the solution is completely
like Up For Debate or any discussion I'm
just this is what I care about
personally with this proposal next slide
just to be clear your third requirement
there is that the server hides the fact
that it can serve authenticated
resources uh yes so not that it is
serving ah so yeah let me rephrase that
I guess that's not very well written um
let's say that the the server offers a
resource to only authenticated clients
that's a common thing and an
unauthenticated client must not be able
to find out whether that's the case or
not so it can't probe the server to find
out that the resources there you're just
not allowed to see it
okay
I'm thinking about the very header but
okay about what the very header yeah
so the why don't we already have this in
our very large suite of HTTP
authentication methods
um so if you're doing cryptography and
you're using a signature you need
something to sign
and you need that to be fresh otherwise
this is things are replayable so in
common protocols today the way we do
that is the server sends announced the
client signs that nonce sends the
signature back and the server goes great
that's fresh
um but that breaks our requirement of
the server not
letting on that it does this because if
it sends a nonce you go oh I got an
answer from you I know you all you you
support this scheme uh so hoba is a is a
means that that does that for example
that's already standardized
um but that leaks the fact that the
server does this next slide please
so
the idea we had where I think the clever
part came from Chris Wood I think but
anyway is if you use TLS key exporters
uh that gives you announce because both
the client and server have fed
information into the TLs key exchange
so you know that a key exporter is fresh
the
uh I'm blanking on the name
um
Channel binding use that as well um but
we're not doing Channel binding very
different but like just that same idea
of using a key exporter not to generate
a key but just to use it as a nonce so
that doesn't link any information
because any side can export the key
locally
and it can be replayed either empty
I don't know if you've uh thought about
this one but it it's possible that in
certain contexts say like web browsers
an adversary might be in a position to
uh
for example
um make requests and
[Music]
um this only prevents
the authenticator from being moved to
another connection that doesn't prevent
it from being reused on the same
connection
so that's
but you like you still need the private
key to be able to you don't need the
property you just need to see the output
and if you can copy the output
you get to so how could you get access
to that output
or sorry what output
so the headers that you're sending this
is this is somewhat theoretical of
course but if the if the head is on on
one request leak in some way oh I I see
what you mean reduced on that same
connection again so this is the attack
we discussed this at the at the last ITF
and uh so Jonah Jonathan and I thought
about it for a bit and that's a real
Attack if you leak that you sent a
header with this on one request you
could put that on another request but
the threat model there is an attacker
that
kind is already like inside the TLs and
so we decided like
that wasn't practical in practice so we
added a paragraph to security
consideration saying that that was out
of scope uh but it's a real Attack as
long as you thought of it that's all it
just it just occurred to me yep no no we
thought about it like we could if we
wanted to solve it by putting something
like the
stream well the stream ID would be gross
but something that's unique
um it's not the end of the world but
like we thought that in practice it
wasn't a problem so we document that if
if this is part of your thread model
then don't use this
you could bind to things in the request
so that's not portable between requests
for instance the URL
um I don't want to pull too much in but
yeah no we could do something like that
narrow the scope of reuse I don't know
that that's worthwhile yeah yeah so the
the advantage if you you have the same
thing is that then it gets compressed by
each pack or qpac and we thought that
was a nicer benefit than this attack I
mean that's totally we can go either way
both work
um it's a it's a you know security
versus performance trade-off as we often
have Alex sorry is there clarification
or follow-up to the discussion okay
different quickly uh yeah I I Alex
fromowski Google um I just wanted to add
that I also previously brought up a
similar thing around the fact that this
was a connection oriented export and it
really did weird things around streams
so like I think if we uh Incorporated
Martin's idea about making it be request
or stream oriented somehow it would also
make it clear that this wasn't a shared
resource
so maybe somewhat repeatable but not 100
repeatable like URL is definitely a nice
one that would still get you some of the
compression yeah well we can we can
figure that out cool next slide please
oh boy come on
there we go
uh oh so this is kind of a description
of the solution
um we renamed the draft to unprompted
authentication
um
I really wanted to call it masked
authentication but I was told that
wasn't funny
um so we went with this at least it's
clear about what it is
um the server doesn't tell the client
that it needs to authenticate the client
does it without being prompted and it
indicates a single request and you send
uh what kind of authentication so
signature hmac
um and then
which algorithm like for a signature
algorithm or hash algorithm you're using
so initially we use the IDS and Mt found
that gross so I grabbed something from
the Ina registry and I managed to get
that wrong too but that's fixable
um I I got some good comments in the
GitHub I'll that's easily fixed and then
you know a username and the proof
base64 encoded
um
next slide please but that's not a
structured header is it
ah I have a slide for that it it is
unless I messed it up
well that first you you messed it up
um I'll I'll get back to that uh in
terms like we kind of discussed this
with the client search idea similarly
this can't be transparently forwarded
because it pertains to the TLs
connection uh so the intermediary checks
it and then tells Upstream what the
result was that part we've declared it
out of scope you could build something
like the the previous presentation if we
wanted to but I don't have a use case
for that so we decided it's out of scope
of this draft for now and it can be
built separately next slide
so what we changed since last time
because we got some pretty good feedback
when we presented this so we renamed the
draft we removed the oids we added the
security concerns to discuss this the
issue that we just talked about uh
Jonathan joined as co-author to make
sure that I stopped shooting my toes off
security wise uh and we switched to
structured Fields maybe I got it wrong
again I'm an HTTP Enthusiast not an
expert but I tried to switch to
structured Fields because I hear they're
all their age I did a bunch of editorial
work to try to make the document better
um next slide please
so we have an independent implementation
by The Guardian Project uh so multiple
entities kind of interested in this uh
we're wondering is it the HTTP is
working group interested in seeing this
progress here should we take it
elsewhere what do people think
um is this completely insane is this a
good idea do other people find it useful
um any thoughts questions this is my
last slide so come on up uh Mike
Mike Bishop
um I do think it's useful I feel like
you're kind of re-implementing some of
what's already an exported
authenticators
so you might be able to just get one of
those and then base64 encode it but I
don't know
I don't know what the Gap is on that but
it might be something to explore so
exported authenticators don't have that
property
um I
I think from memory and someone can
correct me if I'm wrong do you need like
that kind of exchange that kind of leaks
that the server does this
um
yeah okay it has been to a request then
okay
all right so we'll um building many of
the same mechanics without binding to
that request should be fine
um yeah at the end of the day it's not
horribly dissimilar yeah
um but more broadly written yes I think
this is of interest it's uh it's a
useful property and there are already
HTTP servers that will refuse to admit a
resource exists unless you're
authenticated
they just have some other endpoint that
you off to first so this would be a nice
Improvement in security for them
thank you
uh Ben
hi sorry my Network's a little unstable
uh so uh I definitely want this uh I've
even sort of been involved with
deploying A A system that attempts to
achieve this property but I still don't
understand the the use case that
motivates this design
um thanks for helping me understand a
bigger piece of it I'm closer but uh
the thing that I'm most confused about
is this the if we assume that there is
no indication that a given origin
supports this uh
then
client presumably must be configured out
of band with information to know that it
can use this mechanism with this origin
but any mechanism that could configure
this client to know that about this
origin could have just provided this
client with a per origin symmetric
secret a password
that would allow that the client would
send unprompted unprompted
authentication yes
um to that server but this would not
authenticate the client right this would
just reveal the client as being among
the set of clients that knows this
information about the server and then
the server can respond with a challenge
we can go through standard challenge
response authentication so why didn't
you do that
um so it's the general question about
shared cryptography versus or symmetric
cryptography with uh versus asymmetric
cryptography and yeah pretty much almost
everything that's done with asymmetric
you could do it with symmetric and N
keys but then you kind of have to tie
the list of potential Origins with the
keys and you get like a bad scaling
problem whereas here you can get the
keys once and then later over time get
the origin simpler so it gives you like
more flexibility I mean there's yeah I'm
I'm not convinced that it actually uh
provides that kind of efficiency
Improvement in this case because again
you need to be provisioned out of band
with this information about each origin
that you could potentially contact
and so you already have and the clients
are already being provided with with
order and information here adding
passwords on top of that doesn't
increase the the order of information
that's required to be shared with
clients and if you want this kind of
shared cross-origin authentication of
clients where clients use a single
credential across or all of these
Origins you can still do that you no
longer have to do it within an
unprompted context for example you can
do it in a hoba context and then you
don't have to worry about this thing of
like I'm bound to the TLs session I
can't Traverse intermediaries you know
I'm doing Channel bind
foreign
yeah that that really depends on your
use case it sounds like you don't need
you don't need the symmetric part here
thank you well so I'm I'm telling you
that you don't need it like Guardian
Project I'm very familiar with their use
case they do not like the system I'm
describing is is their system like
that's
that's how it already works that's how
the the bridge distribution system is is
already defined so I think look I think
if there's an advantage here I could
argue that it like it saves a round trip
like it avoids the need to sort of
pre-authenticate and then you know and
then actually authenticate as a as a
second step you can do it in one go
maybe that's important in some use case
but I'm not actually aware of again of a
use case where that efficiency gain
would matter
um and so I think that basically there's
a more flexible less complicated
solution here
um I think we should solve the problem
um but I I'd like to see this a little
more strongly motivated for this design
fair enough yeah I mean complexity is in
the eye of the Builder so I think we can
agree to disagree on that one
well okay yes but like the
working group work
um you know is has to ultimately proceed
by by consensus about this so so that's
uh you know it's also for the working
group to consider whether this is the
right approach all right great thank you
so let's hear some other opinions then
Kyle
Chris
um I'm it's not completely clear to me
what is being done here that couldn't be
done with token binding so can you get a
bit closer to the mic please
um yeah what has been done here that
couldn't be done with token binding
so from memory it's been a while since
I've done I've looked into that I
well I mean one problem is it's it's
more complicated machinery and it's
at the uh TLS layer I well of course
it's at the TLs layer but for I don't
know if it has the property of client
speaks first or directly uh tied to a
request
um
so the standard way of doing token
binding does involve a negotiation at
the TLs layer
um but I think that could be emitted and
get the property that you have here in
effectively the same way where the
client would derively
uh ekm from the TLs connection and then
create a signature of it put in the
token playing header so I would have to
double check from memory there was a lot
more involved uh in token binding and
the interactions with the TLs layer that
made it uh quite a more complicated
beast and would be harder to just have
like a little token that you send uh I
can that's a reasonable question I can
give you a let me do some research I can
give you a better answer
um because it's been a while since I've
looked into token by Nick
anyone else
I'm kind of wondering if we could get a
sense of the room of who's interested in
continuing the discussion no that would
be great yeah so so without making any
commitments or saying that yes we'll
drop something or that you're going to
implement it just a show of hands uh
online as well as in the room I don't
know how it works online but we'll sort
stuff out
um uh who's interested in continuing
this uh uh
this discussion that there might be
something here
okay so I see a smattering of hands in
the room
including some implementers online I'm
sorry I
this big sign here says please do not
touch
so oh because you're presenting full
screen oh that's what's happened okay
I guess
they don't have a way just to
cue if you're interested in your online
and then get out of the queue let's do
it that way
just cue yourself
we're getting plus ones in the tit
that's good and I see a few people in
the queue
that's helpful information we're gonna
we're gonna adapt the tools we're gonna
pay some calories oh it's funny you
could see the people in the queue then
falling down the infinity well yes don't
don't look too hard
all right I think that's good
information it sounds like there's at
least some interesting continuing the
discussion uh uh so let's do that cool
what would you like from the authors are
we at the level of an adoption call are
we not there yet I I don't know I'll
talk to Tommy I I suspect we're not
quite there yet but maybe a little more
on list discussion some exploring of the
issues like Ben said making sure we
understand the use case and why the
solution is the right General starting
point for that sounds great yeah yeah
awesome if I'll see you all on the list
on this topic if you're interested one
more question for you actually what's
your sense of urgency around this uh not
really uh I mean it's uh it will be nice
because we have a use case I mean you
know you can ship thing without having a
standard but it will be a nice bow tie
to the mask story as well to have all
these things like wrapped up so
yeah all right thank you
and uh we've got five minutes left so
unless we have any other business I
think we can close for today and we'll
see everyone on Friday
thank you
what do up here
great presentations
so
I feel like there's a lot
of iTunes
and it is
um
yeah four years I believe you
I like
I haven't thought
as he was presenting I was
what's going to be talked about tomorrow
which is the protests
public resources available that look
like
for authentication that would be
us anymore
it's weird