not positively
okay my clock just turned to 1500 so I
think we are going to be starting this
is ipsec ma working group I'm
terracividen and my co-chair is there in
the big screen
you can say hi probably oh you could
just be okay that's fine all right so we
have a faithful agenda today we have
five minutes overtime in that agenda so
get closer to it and take the mask off
so it makes it easier all right so just
a note well you'll probably see have
seen it several times already
and
and we have already have two note takers
that's fine and there's links for the
you know meteco and notepad if anybody
else go to that page and you can
actually add especially if you are
making comments on the uh you know uh
microphone just go there and check out
their comments are properly or or type
them in you can even type them in before
you actually make the comments that
makes you very
all right so we have a full agenda uh
any comments on the agenda or any I I
pretty sure we are not going to be
getting to the last two items which are
if time permits because there are so
many other items in the before but
any other any comments on the agenda any
bashing
note we go forward so our current status
is so that we have four four drafts that
in the RFC editor queue that should be
out at quite soon I guess
and uh
let me see
okay and then we have two documents that
are still in the IST or ITF last call
one still waiting for the chair review
and write up uh Paul is complaining
about that all the time
yeah
uh Paul voters yes I would like to
complain about that because it actually
has been in the
um the shepherd's review was was added
in March it is now November
yeah I will do it after ITF yeah
yeah yeah
but um yeah please do this in the next
couple of weeks all right nothing next
week but in
Colorado after that go next week sorry
you Mumble there could you be more
specific and clear
I will try to do it before the end of
the year
Valerie you have some comments
P2 is uh in the last call too but this
last call is lasting for I don't know
more than half a year and uh it is still
waiting for more reviews and I remember
that uh a couple ATF uh meetings ago a
few people volunteered to provide the
review for this draft and I just
determined it's a friendly reminder for
those people who volunteer it that it is
still not too late
yes so g i question two there were
several people who one of those are
actually commenting there well other
things that are not done a promising to
make a review and haven't done that so
yes that actually would be and I it's
also in my list to do the review one
more review and then push it Forward
regardless if you get more reviews or
not but I hope to get more of those uh
there's this working group last call
First ADI which I completely forget so I
will actually push that one to be say I
think we are going to be pushing that
one out and we have a couple of comments
waiting for the you know adoption course
which I think are also going to happen
Okay Valerie more comments uh yes just
forget I think that also knows is quite
ready for last call because uh I don't
know I I read it recently I uh actually
I don't see any issues and probably if
you uh if the draft is a last call was
issued uh more of you will be for this
draft and yeah I'm not planning to
change it anymore so all right I I don't
see any issues right now
so we have labeled ipsec which is should
be going to the you know publication
requested very soon if I get the charter
review there are a still rebutron uh we
have open group plus code for Ada Ike
which is
done and then we have an Ike analysis
announced should be going to work into
plastical and giac version 2 which
should be going out from the working
group last call after we get a couple of
reviews Paul and me probably until we go
out and if anybody else has any comments
on it please read it and check it out
all right so then we go to the
presentation so the first presentation
is Paul
the next slide
sorry
um so there's a brief history um you can
read it if you want um basically the
last version only removes the special
fallback I say this was the essay that
we said always should be up
so that you always have one essay to
send a packet over people didn't like
the fact that it was special so we
removed it and basically now becomes an
implementation specific thing if you
really want that functionality it is
just not specified in a draft but it's
like implementation specific thing you
can implement
that required a little change for the no
device to be sent and
um there's no more issues left that I'm
aware of
so hopefully this will make Valerie
happy and uh well actually so to be fair
Valerie and Taro didn't like the
fallback I say so um other comments were
not outstanding so
if there are any please let us know as
soon as possible
oh there should we have more slides oh
sorry yeah and it's implemented please
use it
all right so we have it
so next step is working group adoption
call and we get some comments on if
there's two people in the queue so go
ahead for
Paul first
hi uh Paul Thompson from Cisco Meraki so
we are actually facing the similar
issues and we completely agree with uh
the problems based as you're facing for
performances with this draft we just
want to raise a concern we have which
might be that by adding more essays we
could face some scalability issues on
big uh hub for instance ipsec hubs but
uh yeah
yes sorry so you're using
um one disadvantage of this solution is
that you get more essays more than one I
say per tunnel and that has a hardware
implications
um and use the queue by the way for
those people who are coming up to the
mic use the queue before you come to the
mic because we have remote people there
okay
it's not in the case where you would
have like a few more essays but I think
in some situation you might have uh a
lot more child let's say that you would
want to create to benefit from the the
performance advantage and in that case
if you already have a lot of already
existing tunnels that could multiply the
number of essay by a significant amount
okay so so let me comment down in
general when you have a a lot of clients
and a lot of tunnels and you're already
spreading those over your multiple CPUs
so then you're not really gaining much
more from adding even more tunnel so
that you have like you know each of your
10 tunnels uses 10 essays for the 10
CPUs because your CPUs will be maxed out
right so there's no point in putting
multiple on them so in general the
expected use case for this is that you
fill up your CPUs with tunnels and if
you already have like 10 CPUs and 10
customers to different tunnels then
you're kind of already filling that up
recover I'll try to cover a bit more of
the problem we're facing at the end of
the session sure correct so the next one
is then Valerie
I just want to say that I support I
would support the option of this draft
as a starting point and we also have
some implementation experimental
implementation with small TSA that is
slightly different became a
then the draft defines so my
I think that we can make we can try to
make
the draft so that it will interoperable
with implementations that implementation
it implements slightly different
approach to the multi-say so anyway I
think it's it's a good starting point
so thank you
okay next one
Daniel
so um I I think it's a problem we have
to solve
I would have wished that we I mean
that I think I think a more complex
solution would end up in the creation of
the multiple essays
um
and I I think that is a
something that should be added to
um
to this negotiation
and and I also I don't want to talk
about uh regarding the presentation
that's going to be
um done at the end
um but I think we should also try to to
limit the the number of creation uh of
essays so
um I'd like that we pay attention to
um to the last presentation
all right then Christian
uh I was just excited to hear you have
the implementation do you have the link
somewhere
it's in the draft it's an implementation
section awesome
all right so I think that was still
comments we had from the that documents
so we will probably start an adoption
call after this uh meeting
all right so then we go to the next
presentation which is the ipsec workshop
report Stefan
okay
yeah hello everyone
okay hello everyone
this is a report from the IP secret shop
that was held last week here in London
next slide
first some background about that event
that event is funded by the ipsecant
network security Association
there's a yearly event and it was held
first time in 2018.
it will somewhat seeming public event
because we tried to limit a number of
attendees below 20 to be able to run all
that in Workshop mode with discussions
and so on
topics are usually ipsec implementation
protocol
but also other security stuff that comes
up as welcome
next
so we started a workshop with a
discussion about fips requirements for a
Year's GCM
Paul came up with a question and he were
asking if we can use the same key for
more than due to the
the issue packets in fips mode
so we had a
discussion about it looked at the specs
and finally we agreed that yes that's
possible even in fixed fips mode but
there's one limitation so if your IV is
on icv is only eight octaves then you're
really limited to two to the 32 but in
all other cases it should be possible to
use more
okay next
so next topic we had was decorated
policies and how to avoid overlapping
policies tiro presented about that
he gave an overview of what D Colonel
policies are gave us some examples
and showed
that just gives a rather nice flat SPD
data structure where you don't need
to use priorities to find actually the
right policy and that makes lookups much
more efficient
okay next one
yeah next topic we had it was
presentation and discussion about a full
heart rate data part of flow for ipsec
Ian romanovski presented about that
and the point is we want to do all
lookups encapsulation and crypto
operations are flow to hardware
we have an API for that that and Linux
and currently the melanox Nvidia CX-7
card support that type of offload so if
you use Linux with that kind of card you
really can run the full IP set data path
in Hardware currently
next
okay next topic was about a forwarding
fast path with packet parking in Linux
the idea there was we just take out a
net filter flow table with with that as
possible to skip the entire L3 data path
then we are creating packet box so that
each bug consists of packets that are
matching the same as a and with these
packet piles we are running small code
Loops that are rather cash friendly
and we were able to show that in our
test setups we got a performance uh
booster Factor five
compared to that what we had before
okay next
then Michael Richardson presented about
anema and the use of ipsec there he gave
a brief introduction about what anima is
and how ipsec is used there and
presented the problem that she was
unable to cross network name status with
vti interfaces we discussed that a bit
on a proposed solution is to use XM
interfaces those interfaces were created
to replace
ETI and Linux because vti has uh well
vgi is basically broken from most of the
use cases so we intervented inventor
text frame interface a couple of years
ago to
get rid of that so next
okay next was Chris presenting about
iptfs he gave an introduction to that
and showed us the state of the Legends
implementation So currently aggregation
and fragmentation is supported thanks
Chris
uh what's still missing is the constant
rate sending uh but we hope that Chris
will help us there too and we're getting
eventually just also supported in the
nuts
next slide please
okay I think well Paul talked about that
one I think I can skip that slide next
so then we had a longer discussion about
reassigning efp so during the last time
there were quite a lot of proposals
around you support the multi-cpu use
case quality of service classes Hardware
flows and so on and so forth so and all
that boiled down to the fact that we
kind of need some separate anti-replay
windows
there are quite a lot of false Solutions
some where it take some bits from the
SBI or from the anti-replay window or
just add a new field to ESP or whatever
additionally to that Google came in
April and published the PLP crypto
protocol which also looks pretty similar
to ESP but it's just not it
so we agreed that it might be time to
rethink ESP put everything on a table
and eventually try to create the new ESP
V4 version with that but well time will
show next
okay then we talked about beat mode the
beat mode draft is rather old just from
2008 and it's still unfinished and
uncontinued
but actually
um beat mode is implemented in Linux and
people are really use it so we agreed
that could be a good idea to continue
that work that we can eventually finish
beat mode and get it to a proposed
standards
so next
okay that was it okay so that was the
report from the Ibiza workshop last week
I have to say it was a rather productive
event
thanks to all attendees and looking
forward for Workshop next year
that's it from me thank you any comments
on that Chris are you still in the com
queue in the last time or are you
okay I will review all right so any
comments on that
if not then we go to forward next one
next presentation is IP comp extension
uh hello everyone my name is harsher and
I'm going to talk about an IP config
extension which excludes the transport
layer next slide please
yeah first some background on the IP
count is a IP field compression protocol
it's just a compressed IV payload to
save some binder weights and the
compressor payload is prepared with an
IP comp header the ibcon has A3 part the
first part is the next cutter and it
puts the original next header in there
and the second part is flex now it must
be zero and ignored by the decompression
side and the third part is the
compression parameter index to indicate
the compression algorithm used and is
maintained in this and
registry now it's only for file
next entries
yeah and we see there is a two problems
with this ipcon protocol the first one
is that is incompatible with the network
functions because the layer 4
information I mean the the source port
and destination Port is compressed
so you cannot put any network function
which relies on this information for
example the firewall nity or some kind
of HCL
so this will limit the the IP count
deployment
science means
oops
yeah so we propose the first extension
to solve this problem uh the statistic
extension is very simple it's just
excludes the protein info from the
compression range to do that to
basically we have two options the first
option is that we can change the flags
to to add one bit indication to say this
compression will exclude the source
proton destination port and the second
option that we can duplicate each
compression algorithm code point for
example in in this table we can say the
the CPI value one is the idcom or UI and
there is another
CPI value to indicate the test the same
compression algorithm but the four bytes
which contains the source port and the
destination Port is is concluded from
the compression next
and the second formula of the IP company
that it may cause some kind of odd order
processing basically the reason is that
in the IB count biopsy is specified that
if a package is the compression is not
effective meaning the compression May
produce a longer pay node then the
packet is sent uncompressed and the
results the ipcon header but in the
compression side a packet with the ID
card will go through the decompression
code processor first but if a calculate
does not have the idcom header it will
be forward directly so it is the process
has is different for the cost out of
order out of order is very bad for the
open air protocols such as the TCP
no no the same thing
so we propose the second extension to
solve the auto order from the uh
basically we uh we can change the
behavior to
to add the ipconocator email if the
payload is sent uncompressed so to do
that we can use a new CPI value for the
uncompressed packet basically this news
API means this packet is sent
uncompressed that next sense
Yeah so basically that wasn't what our
drop is about and we also would like to
talk about the IP comp the relationship
of ID compound ipsec
currently the CPI code point you don't
know created in the ip7 Regulatory and
is negotiated using Ike but actually the
compression is not related to the
security and the CPI value does not have
to be unlocked by Ike maybe there are
other control plane protocol can be used
so maybe this can decouple from the
ipsec and for the transport layer it's
including this L4 information we want to
hear your opinion about whether we use
the CTI or you use a new flag
thank you
all right comments there is you are
first
yeah Channel some stuff that was said
there on the zulup
for most ipsec implementations ipcon
well it wasn't really removed but it's
kind of deprecated hidden in a d player
in the GUI so
kind of as much deprecated as AHS so um
uh if you want to decouple it from ipsec
I think that's a good idea I'm not sure
if it's
I don't know how useful it is outside of
the context of ipsec
and they're not even a commenting the
asset chair if it's decoupulated from
ipsec 10 it doesn't belong to this
working group it's closest somewhere
else yeah actually with some musics
travel to the sixth man because we think
it's an ipcome kind of go into the
maintenance mode but someone uh Samsung
guy in sixth amendment is IP IP sexy
it's also in go here yeah to to hear
your opinion
all right next poll
ockos
so so one way how this issue goes away
is to not use ipicom so the question
becomes why are you using ipcon when if
it's for the MTU then boy we have a new
solution for you that's coming up soon
it's called iptfs
no it's not about MTU you just want to
save the batteries because some very
high quality 90 is very expensive so we
want to send as needle data over that as
possible
everything and the interior ad and we
just get a draft over there which also
compressed directly over the IP layer
it's called Chic over IP that's a draft
you may want to have a look at it as
well the ratio for compression will be
much higher okay thank you
so this documents as well commentators
there's also you know if you think about
the cases you have this uncompressed
payload that's using the IP competitor
there even the reason why they didn't
into this is that that expands the
bucket which makes the MTU problems
start to appear when they didn't appear
in the beginning
so that was the reason why they made it
so that it can't expand the bucket so
this solution is actually not very good
for that
yeah actually uh first uh uh first this
uncompressive panel is secure IP comp
enabled payload uh flow so it only
affects a certain amount of load you you
personally need to match your flow to to
the ipcon so I'm I'm seeing here the top
of order is happening in the IP I
becoming enable the flow not any other
package okay so the next one is Daniel
yeah so just to complement with
um Eric just said uh about chick we also
have uh one protocol which is die tsp
which is about compressing um
um some of the fields in the um in the I
mean well ESP IP packet
um and it's
um it is expected to interface pretty
well with Chic as well I mean that that
that's what we should work on also
okay thank you
so I think we get entered of Q then so
that's all for this thank you thanks a
lot
so the next one is new like version two
for portal payroll formats Valerie
hello uh next slide please
so uh uh
you may notice that there is an um
uh
a question in the title so uh the
purpose of this presentation it is not
concerned with any with any particular
draft is to go to an interest in the
working group of their wise and
likely to openload format
so uh for existing payload format we
have some limitations first uh the
landfill occupies only two bytes so it's
below its size is limited to 64
carbohydes okay
to both so
um it made me not enough for some use
cases especially for post Quantum
algorithms that have large public keys
and I must note that there is no
problems there is a message size itself
which which is limited to four gigabytes
so the next piece
and the other issue with the current
format and both with generic format and
some particular formats is that they
have a lot of redundancy so we have uh
a lot of not a lot but just a noticeable
number of reserved fields that are
always zero and never used a load field
always occupies two bytes and most
payloads are smaller especially notified
pillows and most parameters in say
pollute also occupy uh to buy it so
while very few numbers very few will you
satisfied so far this is just an example
so before I say below uh with
these parameters uh
the lens is 48 bytes among them half of
these bikes are zeros
so the next please
and
why it is a good sin to leave to 64
kilobyte size limits so it would allow
using some cool post Quantum algorithm
with some public keys and signatures
uh and uh currently nist approved
algorithm
have a smaller public key size and
signature but for example classic make
Elise is still an Eastern for candidate
and it is also recommended by some
national state organizations like BSI in
Germany
and there may also be cases when we need
to transfer that chance of data for
example in configuration below
and it's
and why do we need to make a lot smaller
uh it would decrease power Network
bandwidth consumption which is important
for iot devices and it will also
decrease the chances of Ip fragmentation
in I can say anything changes and
recommendations that follow exchanges
and these chances grow especially for
you can say you need when we Define more
and more new transforms for example for
post Quantum algorithms and the full
combination of such
will
make a simple little clutch larger and
larger especially if you take
integration uh
set but Quantum algorithms may have
different parameters
as the next piece
so uh what do we have now there are a
few existing proposals uh first a large
internet key exchange version 2 payload
draft uh then beyond 64 call limits on
my equator pillows and compared for much
of IQ products as
latest draft is currently expired but uh
it was active for quite a lot as the
next please
so uh I will try to analyze to Quick
analyze uh all of these proposals so a
large internet key exchange version took
a load IT addresses only 64 by its
limitations it is a generic Solutions it
is suitable for any preload and uh below
it in all the different light can be
mixed in a message
and this feature is explicitly
negotiated a re-exchange of 95s
for this reason it cannot be used in
initial Exchange and it is a relatively
easy to implement but it depends on the
basic with your code because if you if
implementers uh just uses uh 16 beats
for reload size inside the chords it may
require some effector but otherwise it's
it's pretty easy to implement
and I'm not aware of any implementations
uh yes please
so beyond beyond 64.
gigabytes a limited 950 loads it also
addresses only uh 64 capellites
limitation it is suitable only for
sample loads so for those that most
probably will have a problem
with post Quantum algorithms it's key
exchange authentication and set
certificate and existing bullet format
is fully preserved
but encrypted per load is mainly somehow
to make uh possible
to have a message size greater than 64
kilobytes so there's no explicit
negotiation and duplicitly this which is
negotiated when
peer negotiated an algorithms having
large public keys it also cannot be used
in initial exchange at in Reliance on
mandatory use and hypermentation and a
relatively easy to implement and
Implement some implementations exist
so the next please
and compact format of 502 payloads IT
addresses redundancy a fight with fight
pillows and
this proposes suitable for any preload
uh but some preloads are well compaction
centered pillows can be mixed in a
message sample loads have special
extremely complex format there is no
negotiation and
a new initial exchange is used instead
alternative I can say neat uh this is
semantically equal to I guess in it but
allows uh for compact below to appear
and there is there is some kind of
negotiation because again initiation can
also can always relate to it because
they need if if it receives a fatal
error or uh timeout of descending
initial message it is a moderative
difficult to implement it can be
implemented as post uh procession of
reproduction of the standard iq2
messages and an implementation exists
so the next
so uh the question which is a working
group
do we want to provide cycle load format
if yes then what problem should they
address or should you address uh just
make it possible to
to help the Lord greater than 64 car
or decrease Mass Equity message
redundancy or both and it is not in the
presentation uh if both then should it
be in a single solution or should it be
different solutions
so is there any interest in this book
something else please
well there are some backup slides but uh
Sergeant is very tight the backup slide
just proposes some way to address both
uh both problems uh some preliminary
approach so if the time permits I will
show it but if now that we can go to the
questions
foreign
I think it's interesting um one of the
questions I have is that
um
when we decrease the redundancy do we
end up in something easier to pass or
um something more complex
oh well uh it is a bit complex sense
that's a simple solution but I think
it's moderate actually the draft was
written that it can be implemented as
post-processing of the ready ipt
messages and preprocessing of the
received messages so it is it can be
yeah relatively easy uh built into the
current implementation without breaking
it but it requires well
some
some amount of work but
not much from mind
well at least the 60k limitation is
something we we may have to address
so the question to uh chairs
oh what do you think about this work
so to start again and so
um I think both of them are actually
separate items in our Charter so with
actually the 64k limitation is coming
from the you know post Quantum algorithm
and I think we need to solve that and I
hope we get one solution for that not
two so I would actually like to have you
know people to discuss of those two
because we have to implement it two
different drafts for that so I would
actually like to have a people to
actually discuss and and agree on this
of those proposals to go forward and
hopefully when we can decide on one we
can actually go forward with that and I
would actually I think it would be
better to have a solution that would
actually work for all payloads because
there's some other like like somebody
was saying you know having a
configuration payload covering the whole
networking structure of the company
which is completely messed up uh by bike
week or more than 64 kilowatts which I
think is usually provide that the
Enterprise you know ID department is not
doing very well based they have to have
that many networks separate Networks but
anyway so so I think it would be useful
so at the
compression or or or small things I
think that's a separate issue and I
think we should be probably keep them as
a separate also
and and for that we also have multiple I
think we have a diet a couple of diet
versions that we have at least I think
we have multiple versions of that also
so I would try to have an outers to
actually
try to find a common ground and common
solution
well uh so if I try to write a draft uh
and present it to the working group easy
to uh okay
yep
okay
thank you and I I think as I said
they're both or in Charter so I think
there is there has been interest and I
think they're still interest
yes
just the mere existence of two separate
drafts is some evidence that there's
some interest at least
yeah
let's give it a backup file slides
yeah and the next one is Valerie
so uh this presentation
um was presented a few ideas ago and I
just want to
raise an interest to this problem and to
to to get an impression where this
problem should be solved or should be
ignored
so the next slide please uh well uh this
is uh this diagram shows synthetic using
cookies in iq2 so according to RFC 70 to
90 96 uh the most recent I can say need
request message is included into the
output load calculation I think that it
goes exchange so uh in this diagram it's
it is a request to impose initiated and
responded so it is standard way so the
next please
but what happens if we have some packet
loss and the original
uh well these there are two possible
problem scenarios and both are concerned
with the responded States change in the
middle of I can say you need request for
in this uh
problem scenario one uh first the
responder since that it is under attack
and request a cookie but this message
get reordered and before these the
initiators sends another request
and at this point the responded since
that is no more under attack and it just
responds with a usual response uh
response uh rest to and uh one of the
message well the
one of the message get lost from the
initiator and after all of that both
initiate and respond to end up with a
different View at what was the most
recent
only received track one so
authentication would fail
it's next please
and tonight's a problem scenario if they
responder changes a secret key that is
used to
produce a cookie in the middle of I can
say neat exchange again this is very
simple to prevent a scenario some
packets are reorders and someone pick it
is lost but the outcome is the same
the most recent I can say I need
requests and by initiative is rec3 but
I'll respond to other only received a
rec2 so syndication fail again
so the next please
and so since the problem is that I can
send requests can be sent several times
there's different content depending on
the respond to state
and uh
if there is high probability of packet
loss and Georgians and B is my complete
I guess I need exchange having a
different view of what was the most
recent and like I say any digress and
this request message is used in
calculation
and if PSU is different messages for the
calculations the education would
erroneously fail
yes please
and what is about severity of the
problem
uh there must be some precondition
for the problem to become noticeable so
high package hyperability of packet loss
and delay
and a relative frequent frequent change
of responder state
and in a real situation it's extremely
rare
but on a stress tests that we performed
a few percent of the essays failed due
to this problem and I think that the
most problem for implementers for
vendors is that customer would want the
voice education sometimes failed with
with absolutely proper credential
this is just the flow in the equity
protocol
so it's the next piece
and uh how can we fix this
so we can Define the reverse cookie
processing by excluding notified per
load containing cookie from the hospital
calculation
and I think that
it it will not
bring a new secure security issues
because the cookie was already verified
by the responders so there's no need to
verify it again but including inside
records
and foreign
can be negotiatable
let's please
so negotiation uh so if responder
supports a wise cookie purchasing it
will Center wise cooking notify
in the response of the I can say need
along with cookie
so it is only the case if it requires
cooking and if the initiator uh also
supports the Civilized cookie process
and it will include the include the
content of the cookie notification into
this new upload rice cookie and so the
reporter I would know that the revised
booking processing is needed
so the next please
and if yes agrees to you to to go with
the revised cookie processing that uh no
change time to antiquality function of
cookie and uh responded still send steak
is Cookie
but uh when uh house politics
calculating
uh the way it is done uh so initiate the
sign of tests uh is equal to real
message one and non-state and marked ID
for initiator if Cookie plot is present
then we
change a real message one with a new
construction in the next slide next
piece
so we just exclude uh from this message
for the purpose of the calculation of
icos of holes below
uh we exclude the notify containing
cookie and also uh make a modification
to next reload in Arcadia and message
learning
and that's all
if we do it then the
calculation will be
equal even in the case that uh cookie is
different because it was something
different like Ascent responses
so my question is is this problem is
most to address
and if so that
it is possible to issue a call for
adoption of the draft because draft is
around for a while
so
so they're still coming so
I think this is that I'm talking about
some individual chair so uh
this is a little bit you know
questionable if it is worth of
addressable I think it's it's a flaw in
the protocol so that's why we should fix
it uh the question is that if it's a
flaw that doesn't affect security it
only affects you know funny error
messages now every now and then when you
are doing stress tests
and fixing it we will actually you know
of course a completely new you know
quite a you know big modification the
authentication system
I would be very hesitant but I think we
can actually find a solution that
actually is so works better one of the
problems what you are doing here in out
I say calculation
is that the those two messages might not
be exactly same we say that the repeat
retrospectors must be bitwise identical
but there is nothing not nothing they
are saying that we can't for example add
padding or put a you know uh payloads in
different order in the cookie message or
or or or you know when you are actually
adding cookie or not adding cookie so
that's actually would be a different way
but what we could actually do
is when we are uh where is this one this
case for example
uh the real issue is the authentication
file or a notification if you could get
the separate notification saying oh
Cookie changed in the middle
uh then the you know any theater would
know oh the cookie change in the middle
I start from the stretch I start again
and everything works take a time most
likely okay so one solution would be
that that the initiator would in the
last you know Ike out it would include
the cookie that is using for the out
calculation
so it would have a repeat the cookie
there
now the responder
can verify that the cookie is saying
that he thinks that he was using if it's
a different
he probably just returns an error
message saying that cookie changed
please try again
he could in theory go and modify your
initial pocket but there we have the
same problem that if the cookie changed
you know the some of the paddings or
something especially if you know cookie
length is different uh there might be
you know different amount of paddings
because the cookie happens to be you
know
17 OCTA slang along and somebody had
some padding somewhere or something
stupid so that's why I was thinking
about it this would probably work better
in that way so we only modify the code
in case you actually detect this issue
and it would be actually optional to you
know people to actually implement it and
it would be very easy for the imitator
side to implement it they just need to
repeat the cookie and it's a
notification you can add there without
any notifications without any you know
uh negotiation beforehand you try to add
uh no cookie copy in the ike out and
everybody will just ignore it because an
unknown status notification
a responder can either do or not do the
you know do you think this one would
solve the problem and do you think this
would be suitable solution for this also
or instead of date here
um I would I think that sending uh
cooking aikos is a good idea but
uh if you go further and use the respond
to notify and notice that the cookie is
different
in the in the I can say in each and I
goes then uh well what what what should
we do then so my my easy proposal I
would say that you said there's other
other notification error notification
saying that cookie cookie changed
that would be a lazy way of doing it of
course you could try to you know if you
have still the original edit there's a
full packet you could actually go and
try to
switch a cookie to be the one that they
used you know check out this
authentication track seeds but that's
quite a lot of work for very Corner
cases so I probably wouldn't be in my
implementations I wouldn't be doing that
I would just take a easy way out and say
oh separate error message that is not
how the education failed
for me well well it's possible but it
will just complicate it's the right
stick machine because it will a new
non-fital errors that you must um
handle gracefully just to repeat and if
you are sending a cookie notification
sorry cookie copy then you are you know
already know that you you are approached
you can actually process that
notification
okay Paul I think
um
I I it seems that this idea is actually
a nice idea so I do like it um so if you
need volunteers I can help Valerie
um I I was um on a few slides I can
start a few slides forward you had some
statistics about how bad this program
became I was running what that was based
on was it based on the error condition
one or the error condition two because I
think the one where the secret changes
couldn't responder who might remember
the last secret and the current secret
like C like if that is the case or not
like like is that really a case that
happens because you know that like you
cycle between two Secrets basically
right so if the first one fills you try
oh maybe this was a cookie from the old
team you are active as part of the
cookie you prefix a byte that says this
is secret current or secret or one or
two and then if you cycle between one
and two then you know that that cookie
was generated with the previous secret
so I don't think the secret case
actually happens in the world
uh it does because the world responder
can verify cookie and it's okay with
verification of the cookie but then uh
the responder uses these cookies that is
it it verified
it uses this cookie um
in the icons calculation instead of
using the previous cookie so it should
not verify it should reproduce the
previous cookie that should that was uh
actually generated with a different
Secret
and if it is possible to do it then well
okay it's probably will help but it's
it's not the problem that it cannot
verify it's not elegant I agree yeah so
so actually what we're starting to hate
that video you know because it's cookies
the irritator use things that we are
using the first
that's a you know in its out payload but
the rest Pottery is only seeing the
first one which has a different cookie
and it used that as an out calculation
Basin and so they do the out
calculations in different cookies and
there is no way of knowing of course you
know if you actually have a cookie copy
here then you know responder can see oh
yeah we are using wrong coupon it could
actually go and you know replace it but
as I said modifying somebody else's
scent packet is
I take it back I was wrong thank you
all right so
so I
think this is I would like to get some
other people's feedback on this and and
I would actually want to get people's uh
comments on the list and so on do you
think this is something that we want to
solve and uh
do we actually want to solve it in which
way
so um
the purpose of the presentation yeah
yeah so Valerie if you can send an email
to the list and ask for people to
actually comment that and and request
the comments of this document sure
all right
then we go the next one
it is then
what
yes yes
okay hello everyone this is coming from
qinghai University today I will talk
about the receive rpk and episode best
as2s approach for social gradual Edition
and here shows the document links in
data clicker and our workspace at the
GitHub
next page please
first I should introduce the source
address relation problem as defined in
RC
2827 Source address validation is used
to defend the new or service or Tech
well as defined in RFC file to one zero
it has been refinished three
difficulties that is vulnerability it is
difficult to resist the attacks by
disabling the IP Source address
directly and the second
credibility
attackers could conceal location and
identity
by using a spoofing address and the
second major ability it is difficult to
realize building and other management
through the IP Source address because
they may use a supporting address
projects that about 20 percent of
network prefix could be spoofed
Distributing in about 40 percent as in
IPv6 networks so does in ipv4 Networks
uh next page please
thanks so we promote and desire is safe
in general we saved is a
cryptographically based inter as source
to address relation protocol it is ipki
and IP stack to add a message or
authentication code and source as for
the router website and delete the max at
the destination as for the router for
validating The Source address
here shows the main process are receive
on the left picture
first rpk process the five Regional
internet regress piece authorized by
Anna use their root certificate to send
the certificate Authority that is
certificate of the local internet
registry
which is used to authorize the
autonomous system sometimes in
indirectly without the internet service
provider
when they aborting their own CA
certificate the as would sign an under
entity certificate with the road origin
authorization
that is Roa
which is a cryptographically signed
object that states which as are
authorized to originate a certain prefix
this authenticity bounding of the as
number two is IP prefix is published in
the APK database this is the requisites
for restave
and second ACS is certificate Pro
versioning the ACs would need its own ee
certificate for ikv2
this e certificate is required like the
bgb stack realtor certificate funny RC
and the third receive announcement
each participating as announced is
support for receive in the rpk database
including the IP address of its as
contact server
and the IP address we call it as contact
IP
and the third on the first
secret security or storage Association
negotiation and delivery the excess uh
negotiate and
security Association using ikev2
after our synchronization all is for the
routers would get the security
Association including the second key and
other parameters
and the last
highest tag communication receive your
ID stack authentication header in
transport mode for authentication of the
IP Source address by default while s
model router in ASA send the package to
ASB it is established a reset channel to
add the required
as authentication header the export
router in Sp while this authentication
header to ensure that the package was
not spoofed and removes the header after
or validation
next page please
thanks
[Music]
this part includes the enabling and
disabling receiving control plane when
you have when enabling or receive it
includes the following steps announcing
that let's as suppose we save
and
published in content at least
and the last performing abstract session
initialization that is ikev2
videos
idiots receive announcement which is a
stand object in the rpk Repository
a receive announcements includes Awards
as number the contact IP address and our
Boolean type testing field for
indicating whether the content IP is
potentially unreliable
each as is as content server which has a
contact ID
uh recorders that were accessed for
operation ACS is used to present the
whole as to initiate ake negotiation
with other es ACS
where a key negotiation completes each
as for the router in one participate ins
will activate the same functions
and the next part is disabling is safe
when disabling receives the participant
team as would first stop requirements
receive authentication of incoming
package second remove Reserve or
announcement from the article Repository
third when the end is 24 hours
and
last stop sending receive and shut down
the counter IP
well there may be a open question shall
we use an authenticated permanent
rejection options that helps to disable
receive
as we have Scan RFC
7 to 6
96 the latest iq2 protocol it has two
nonification message tests that may be
used here as RFC
6023 defense countless activity to
supported option
it could use PS are acceptable or no
proposal chosen as an error code here
which means for Ikea to client should
not try and shouldn't try again after 24
hours
next take place
thanks
uh let's let's introduce data planes
when two participating as Communications
it would add a receive header to each
other package from one participating as
to another participating as after
receiving a package coming from another
participated yes as for the router would
check the SCV field and remove the
receive header
the headphone format depends on the mode
it use transport mode are turning mode
as it style has two modes the same also
supposedly two modes in default we may
hope to use receive
authentic header in transport mode the
only difference between the same Edge
header and standard absent Edge header
ask is that we save removes the sequence
number field for its
twist them to be a multi-centered
security Association
this mode is only used for S2s
communication here we think the endpoint
is the whole
autonomous autonomous system
for distinguishing we save and standard
abstract we single receive a security
association should be indexed by SP SPI
and the counterpart as number generally
regardless of source of IP address and
the destination I will address in assay
database
foreign
router and the ACs content IP over
another as
each as border router should maintain
its own assay database the index of
assay is the same as the transport mode
I will receive
uh however we also think there is
problem as you may know the isability of
the USP is an optional field as it says
in RC for
oswego3 but here it should be our
required field ESP doesn't protect the
source IP
in default so our package could be
replaced by changing the source IP
currently negotiate extension to ESP
that covers IP header or could we always
send from the contact key and encoded as
for the router ID in the low bits of the
SPI
on next page please
this this slide shows the possible
extensions where is the possible
extension for received here the force is
head only authentication as a source
address relation we save basic layers on
Max in the IQ field is that our tag so
it increased the computation cost here
for efficiency it could use the East
this extension by just authenticating
the IP Source address and IP destination
address and other constant skills in the
IP header but this tag for the same flow
could be always the same when the K is
unchanged
so the attacker may we use this tank for
launching our player tag this could only
be used for some non-expensive traffic I
think
and uh the second
extension is 10 best K rotation for
elevating the about problem this is the
10 best resident machine key generating
this will sharing the active time window
of the key after receiving or security
Association the two party will use the
key in a security Association as their
initial State and rotate the K
periodically based on the truth and
Status transition algorithm or
the tag is generated as a set product
the best way maybe to use the one-time
password
but it is not so easy in practice in
sync
and the last one is static static ecthk
negotiation that is defining an RC 6
2 8 8 7.
uh sorry 78
uh it would allow us to agree on shared
uh
circuits simplified by thinking
synchronizing the rtk database also Ike
is also stateless as it is iudp
button here's littlest simplifies the
provisioning of as border routers as we
may not use too many security channels
for S models and ACS communication
however this may require a new episode
negotiation mechanism as a supplement
the FC
6023 and that is cloudless initiation of
iq2 security Association may be a good
choice
on next page please
thanks
and here is some security consideration
operational consideration
uh
and uh
about the security is consideration with
with shows certain model in general we
save six to provide us strong defense
against arbitrary active attackers who
are external to the source and
destination yes
however different real estate modes and
the configuration of a different sequel
properties
underway is which shows two attacks one
is replied and the other is done great
attack
and we single receive also has provides
significant Security benefits even if it
is not only deployed by a fraction of RS
and we also think the series can
comparable with current episode and
even with other or social address
validation approach
and
yeah option operational considerations
we talk about a way questions about
reliability multiple
uh
as for the rotating synchronization and
performance and until on the net
scenaries
uh
next page please
uh so that is the
questions that we have in country in
writing this graph
and we need your help
[Music]
that's all thanks
yes
so I was gonna just um give three
answers quickly for the things I saw so
if we go to slide four
um the question was just like video of
an authenticated permanent rejection yes
that's a delete it's up to each end
where they will restart a total or not
but those are independent decisions so
if you delete the tunnel then then it
it's up to both peers where they decide
to establish the tunnel again or not
there's no negotiation to say don't ever
come back to me
so next slide so
uh sorry go ahead uh I'm a benchwartz
I'm a co-author on this draft
um I want to ask for a clarification
there my impression is that the uh is
that Ike the the ike authorization step
also produces a child essay
uh unless childless Ike V2 unless
there's a child with like me too
um
maybe I mentioned us to the permanent
rejection you mean not permanent
rejection of the ike peer not of the
child essay
I know I do mean of the child essay my
question is does delete
um is there a race condition basically
where the ike auth handshake generates a
child essay and then you have to delete
it afterward quickly that is possible
yes if if if you set up a child to say
and you end up not liking it and you
have to send a delete again
right but in order to the only it is
childless the only way to not set up a
child essay
yes okay
yes but there are there can be several
um reasons why you would want to listen
the RFC mentions at least some of them
thank you
uh next slide
uh the icv is optional uh I think this
needs a clarification because the icv is
mandatory for those ciphers that require
it so if you have a uh AES Shot 2 then
the ICP is definitely required because
that's where your integrity is if you're
using an aead then since it has a
built-in Integrity there's no icv so you
don't need it so optional is for the
packet format but it's not optional to
send the human gets to choose you have
to comply to your cryptographic
algorithm
foreign
how do peers Express a preference for a
requirement for transfer mode you can
only set a preference by saying use
transport mode and if the other end
doesn't agree with that you must use
total mode
and that was by Design and I understand
that a lot of people hate this word
uh thanks Paul uh if there's anybody
else who
um
yeah I've got
uh one quick comment about uh static
static defeat Hellman one issue you run
you will run into with that is there is
no post Quantum equivalent for that
uh so unless you want to run into big
problems in the future you're better off
avoiding it
okay thank you I want to emphasize that
these are possible extensions they're
not extensions that are actually uh
proposed in the draft their their sort
of notes to self about things we could
propose if we if we find it necessary
um
I just want to briefly add that this is
a very very early stage proposal and
we're still uh sort of looking through
the various ip6 specifications and
trying to figure out which pieces fit
what and what's missing and really this
is very closely connected to to things
like the anti-replay subspaces proposal
this is fundamentally about trying to
figure out how to operate an ipsec mesh
really at very large scale and trying to
figure out how to minimize the amount of
state to make that practical
all right so no more comments on that so
let's go forward then
and the next one is then raypan
um hello everyone my name is
go closer okay okay no yeah okay
um next please
um first I'd like to introduce the
background of this draft and in RFC 72
96 section 2.8 it says that when we're
keen the new child essay should not have
different traffic selectors and
algorithms than the old one so you don't
need to you can just resend the TS and
the sa payloads but furthermore you can
omit the essay and TS payloads during
the key and it doesn't violate the RFC
72 96 and also it can save the bandwidth
and reduce the CPU operations next slide
please
um so
um this is the solution recap
um it's it um after itf113 and there is
no change to the solution and um
um
there was a lot of discussions
um about this draft in the previous time
and so after but the solution gets uh
got Pure stable and mature um
step uh since itf113 and the solution is
quite simple first if the negotiating of
the support for this optimization during
the uh during the for the between the
POS and uh
next is to just send the new Optima
notification payloads instead of the
um TS and sa payloads for working the
iksa and child essays uh next slide
please
actually just joking about the comment
on the middle option is wrong because if
you read the previous stage it says
child essay
it doesn't cover ICS IKS can have a
different algorithms
so the optimization for Ikea doesn't
really apply but the other two actually
are useful
uh yeah yeah but uh yeah
so
um
um next about the updates the version 9
was updated for itf114 and there was no
change and version 10 was updated before
this meeting and only two types typos
were fixed and the next slide please
and for uh in the itf113 Ibis acne
report it says this work might be ready
to be adopted next slide please
and in 104 report it says this should be
ready for adoption next slide please so
these document should say must be ready
yeah
next slide no no shoot blush actually
next slide uh yeah so we sincerely ask
for working group adoption of this trap
because now we think they uh it's as
clear and mature and also in the future
we will do the interrupt test yep
any other comments on this
so I guess people are okay so there is a
couple of comments coming so great
hello I'm from Telecom
I have questions uh did you have a
deployed this technology in any
operators network uh actually for our
base station products as far as I know
they have deployed this um
this function yeah
for the you know the 5G scenarios yeah
to protect the because you know the base
stations will need to use the ipsec to
protect their Communications so uh they
have deployed this uh function yeah okay
yes I think it is very useful in the
network which deployed uh ipsec in large
scale and uh yes in personal I'm very
interested in this solutions thank you
thank you very much
all right next
chain mailing
mailing train from China mobile
uh I'm a covers on this draft uh it's
very reducing size and capability of i2v
I gave me to exchange to optimize the IP
set used by low power sensitive devices
and that was concerned environments
these two historical reports do call me
back that the choosing this draft is
ready for adoption
so no matter Master urge you to be ready
for the adoption I support this draft to
be adopted by the Sun
thanks
thank you
all right Valerie
oh I read the draft and I think it it
can be a good starting point because
it's relatively easy to implement and it
provides some optimization in many cases
so I think that it's a pretty reasonable
to adopt it is the issue a call for
adoption
thank you
all right anybody else
if not then I think I will
save
and now it's in the working group
adoption call
thank you very much after the data
tracker returns
after the presentation
thank you very much
what data tracker seems to be slow okay
the next one is uh IP secondary play sub
basis
and I got an error restricted access
foreign
and I'll be presenting the issue we have
with anti-replay in the multi passage
and multicore processing uh for ipsec
next slides please
so we have a problem that is quite
similar to the one that is addressed by
the
um
draft from power watches and other
previous draft as well which is to do
improve their performances of ipsec in
the context of multi multi-core and
multi-pass and Qs as well
the difference is that we are trying to
do it on a quite a large ipsec apps with
10 or thousands of
ipsec peers and in that situation if we
try to increase the number of child
let's say for instance assume we have
six path a cause aqs classes and it's
still quite a conservative number so we
get to like around 4 million uh child
let's say we would have to exchange to
establish all the tunnels
and so we fear that this will add an
unnecessarily load to the the ike
negotiation and re-keying as well uh
I've will have some issues with the the
cash and memory uh in the CPU to do that
next slide please
so uh what we want to do is uh try and
to to change the slightly the entry play
processing and because it cannot be done
efficiently across multiple cores and in
the context of multi-path it it is quite
easy to have out of other packets that
gets dropped because they're out of the
window so for that we want to uh for a
single child let's say I have multiple
anti-replay material anti-replay window
that we can spread across multiple
Subspace ID
and we just need to set the the sender
we just need to set the Subspace ID in
the ESP editor and when the receiver uh
see the packets it just has to get the
Subspace ID to uh use the correct
anti-replay window
next slide please
so we want to start uh some discussion
about that on the the emailing list the
first one is uh the ike negotiation uh
currently in the draft we have an
address that at all so any input from
the working group is warmly welcomed and
next slide please
the second one would be to where to
store the the set space ID in the ESP
Adder one option we started from was to
use the sequence number field in the ESP
editor but that limits the number of
bits we can use and on High beat threats
B trades link it can have some resync
issue and custom outage one solution for
that was to use an explicit extended
sequence number field in the ESP editor
in that case we can use more bits and
won't have this issue uh the second
option would be to have an additional
field in the ESP editor uh which like we
would get for instance 16 bits uh to to
encode the Subspace ID uh but yeah next
slide please
the last discussion and this is already
started on the mailing list was to have
the fips compliance uh especially we
talked about the AES GCM Phipps
compliance so there is a maximum number
of time you have to you can use the the
key material so we need to make sure
that you don't go above the 2264 usage
allowed and for that we think if it's in
the extended sequence number it's for
free if it's not then we just have to
divide that by the number of zip spaces
you will use
and we also need to make sure that the
iv used every time is unique and but we
think that is should not be a big issue
and should be quite easy to do next
slide please
so uh we want like what we actually want
is just the input from the the working
group to see if that's an issue that
other people would have and uh are there
like how to solve it and come with a
common proposal for for that so for that
problem
thank you if anyone has any soul
for this
for the GCM uh uh a nonce issue uh
remember 32 bits are actually coming
right now from the from the key exchange
from the key exchange the obvious thing
to do is take your Subspace ID and stir
that into those 32 bits and therefore
not Collision is impossible
okay
uh benchwort's alphabet uh I think this
is as I mentioned uh one of the main
problems that we ran into while trying
to draw up the resab so I would love to
see a solution here uh I would prefer a
like pure stateless solution it looks to
me like option two is the one that's
that that allows the recipient to be
um
basically stateless specifically the the
really important thing is like the for
the recipient to be able to lose all its
state and uh and only lose replay
protection and still be able to decrypt
packets
uh so anyway option number two looks
looks like a good approach to me there
are a lot of different approaches here
uh the another one that we talked about
was trying to uh
trying to Hash the
um
The Source IP of the sender into the
um using hkdf to to add the source IP of
the sender into the secret used for
decryption and validation
which means that every Source IP
automatically gets its own sequence
number space so if you are if you know
that you don't have Nats if you don't
have to be Nat compatible then I think
you might also want to consider that
kind of design
okay thank you
um Danielle from Erickson
um just to mention we thank you for for
the presentation
um we do support
um this work
um
and we are happy to
to find find I mean we are facing the
same the same problems and we are
willing to find a solution in that space
too
foreign
so we already have 32-bit sender ID
which tells what its reply counters use
it's called SPI so having multiple
essays is actually the solution for dust
uh the other thing is you have to
remember replay protection the sequence
number generation is mandatory the
checking is not
and I actually are very I don't think
actually the replay protection in this
kind of
in the middle tunnels gives that much of
benefits because they're gonna still be
replaced happening after your ipsec
gateway or before I pick this up Gateway
which is not detected by repay counter
so you can't actually really trust that
there is no replays ever in the network
so your upper layer protocols need to
have a sequest numbers or protection
from replace anyway so I'm not sure if
it actually gives that much of benefit
in this level
so I would actually just you know
generate separate spis for or separate
child essays for each of these and then
simply you know disabled or or or
perhaps even disable to the replay
checking if you have problems with that
uh this this was our individual comment
yes definitely go ahead
I don't want to make a comment comment
on any of the possible options to solve
that but a lot of people have the same
problems and this really shows that we
should try to solve that rather sooner
than later
and so I would propose to do a virtual
interim before the next ITF put things
together with all the people that are
untrusted and come up with a possible
solution and Screen done
we would be glad for that
good evening
Ben Ben Schwartz again uh just
responding to tiro to say uh you know
this presentation proposes that the
receiver might need to hold
um it might need to be able to talk to
four million different separate senders
uh with their own sequence number space
even without replay protection that that
that
um or that that recipient or that that
that Pier or those peers would you know
potentially then need four million child
essays and uh no they need one
one per each because I mean if you have
if you are not caring about replay
protection window you don't need to
create a separated
no you don't need to separate the you
know different parts or different cores
so you do because you can't use the same
sequence number twice on any of those
two so I if you
yeah but I mean quality service classes
require separate essays or Republic
replay counters and the parts we only
because uh they might come in the
different order they are sent in the
same location which means that they can
generate sequence numbers very I mean
sequels number generation is easy and it
can be done on multi-core environments
without any locks we just you know uh
you know uh what one SPI because it's
it's impossible to do that there's you
know tricks to do that it's an
implementation data but even if you
actually can't do you have to have a
course and you can't actually have any
communication between the course you
need to have and then you need to have
one SPI
or one essay for each score but then we
come to the back to the what Paul was
commented earlier that if you have 10
000 people or peers peers you probably
don't need each core to have a separate
uh you know uh a child essay for each of
those ten thousand because I mean the
ten thousand is probably going to be
spread up with each core anyway
yes but in the context of multipass you
easily come to a situation where you
actually have you can't have one essay
for a car yeah you can't specify that
each channel is going to be on one
specific call and so you have the issue
of steering packets between the core
quite easily that appears in that
situation and so you would need like
multiple like quite a lot of these essay
maybe not all the four million but a
number in the same magnitude than those
next one
can you hear me yeah hopefully it's
working yes hi everyone uh yes so I'm
here I'm one of the uh co-authors of the
drafts I just want to react to uh some
of the commands uh terra made the first
is on entire replay
um I think it's pretty much a concern I
mean the replay of packets from an
attacker the IPC Gateway or the ipsec
route or whatever it's used to protect
the internal Network
entirely is actually expected from uh
Standard Security standards and
um you even okay the attacker could not
create other packets but it could pretty
much close or help close DDOS attack
inside the the network if attackers
could just send more
um more packet more of the same packets
it could it could help cause the Adidas
um second command was about the SPI and
we could use the the SPI to do that and
so more shall they say really on that I
want to stress even though it was
mentioned that this has really serious
security not security scalability
concerned in the implementations
right now
um you know like I looked at the VPP
numbers because they are public uh
um the top uh speed can be achieved with
1 000 peers if you get to 10 000 here so
10 000 child essays you already get the
performance
um downgrade uh reduction
um so if you multiply by 10 or 20 or 100
the number of challenges that you have
then you you really lose performance
um finally on the the spreading of the
flows and the tunnels to the course so
one aspect is that
um okay so when you receive packets
um those typically of one one tunnel
typically goes to one specific core
that's that's correct but when you want
to transmit on a tunnel
um then the flows that you want to put
inside the tunnel they they get
processed on any core that you're
processing you don't control where the
inner flows they come from so you you
might have you might want to send
packets coming from the 32 cores into
the 10 000 tunnels that that pretty much
happens because you don't control where
the flows come from before utx
so actually yeah we actually already 67
minutes over time and cookies are
already gone
so so if I think that's we actually
managed to get to the end of the agenda
we didn't have time for the extra items
and there seems to be a lot of
discussion look we should do in the list
so
let's bring it back to the list
thank you
thank you everybody