all right
foreign
thank you guys
can you hear us now
okay now I'll repeat myself entirely
because the poor people uh remote
couldn't hear that at all uh welcome to
moq now in 3D as a working group for the
first time
uh this is our first meeting as a
working group at a plenary ITF as you
know we had an interim but this is our
first one uh for those of you who are
not used to the ITF by this point in the
week people gather a little bit slowly
for the first one so we're going to give
it a couple of minutes but not too many
because we have a pretty packed agenda
uh so please find your seats as quickly
as you can uh remember uh
hopefully by the by this point that you
do need to be wearing a mask if you're
not actively eating or drinking so if
you're drinking go ahead and take your
mask off but then put it right back on
foreign
all right good morning everybody we're
gonna get started uh
so uh this is the note well it's
Thursday I think everyone's read the
note well uh if you haven't please do it
contains a lot of important information
and guidelines about how we do work here
at the ietf
next one
uh again it's Thursday I think most
people have figured it out but uh if
you're here make sure
can I turn it up can I just I can get
I'll just get nice and close hello
thank you uh all right if you're uh if
you're in person use the little mute
Echo client to get yourself uh into the
queue uh and make sure you're wearing
your mask uh unless you're speaking as
Ted has said uh and uh remote
participants uh make sure uh your AV is
off unless you're presenting or talking
uh and use headset Etc
thanks
um if you need any general information
about London uh agenda Etc
you can find it here
our agenda is here I'm Alan this is Ted
gory has volunteered to take notes uh
Luke is backing him up if anybody else
wants to jump in the note stock and uh
and help them out I'm sure they
appreciate it uh is there somebody who
will relay comments from uh zulip
thank you
it's okay I think the chairs can
probably also keep an eye for that
video
okay so what are we going to talk about
uh administrivia and agenda bashing uh
we're going to give a report from our
interim uh which was just last month I
think some people might have missed it
uh because it happened so quickly uh so
we'll just talk about some of the
decisions we made there
um then Luke's going to give a
presentation on the combined proposal uh
from the authors of uh Rush warp and
quick R uh and we'll spend some time
discussing that Colin is going to talk
about uh relays uh and how they work and
we'll have a I'm sure healthy discussion
about that and then we'll talk about
possibly having interim an interim in
January before uh Yokohama does anybody
want to bash the agenda
okay
uh you may have seen this note on the
list uh zahed has been appointed as a
mock technical advisor so if you need
technical advice
fund sorry
uh okay uh things that we talked about
at the interim uh we're going to use
GitHub to manage our documents uh as all
the cool kids do
um
and we're going to use issues mostly to
track and PR's for changes please try to
keep discussion off the PRS and uh just
into the issues and also on the list of
course
um some folks were concerned about uh
the way retention works for slack so
we're in the process of setting up some
kind of bridge for slack so that we will
have a wage a means to retain the
messages but until that time uh please
don't uh conduct working group
discussions over slack
um stay tuned on the list for more
updates there
um and we talked about what we're going
to put on this agenda and uh
we are here and you had your chance to
bash the agenda so moving on
so all right with that uh we'll bring up
Luke to uh talk about uh the combined
proposal
oops
oh I need to request
it looks good
hello media real quick
um good morning uh I've got a lot of
slides this is going to be quick uh but
let's let's start going uh I'm Luke I
work with twitch and I've been working
on the uh combined rush and warp and
quick R draft
um just to try and find base Common
Ground between them
uh so before we begin there's probably a
lot of quick enthusiasts in the crowd
maybe not so many media enthusiasts so I
really wanted to cover some Basics
um starting off just medium coding uh
it's not it can get complicated but it's
a really uh simple level you have
iframes that have effectively just
static images and then as time goes you
can have uh keyframes that will
reference one or more frames in the past
so this is Delta encoding the idea is
it's just two there's too many bits if
you try to encode every image separately
and every so often you'll see we'll
reset the chain and make a new iframe
but this is a kind of common encoding
actually this is um really simple but
it's low latency and you see this a lot
with like webrtc and conferencing
uh we could have more complicated
encoding uh this is one possible example
we have B frames they they're annoying
um because they can reference future
frames as well
uh this this has a lot of ramifications
on how you write these frames to the
wire uh but in this example we have um
some B frames that will reference the
eyes and the P's but themselves are not
referenced
um and it you see this more common from
like Hardware encoders that have a very
fixed structure but the benefit of stuff
like B frames and more references in
general is that you can enhance the uh
the compression ratio you can
effectively more references you use the
less bits you need to encode typically
and then finally you can get some just
really gnarly encodings especially if
you let a software encoder and give it
like a you know a few hours it will
produce the most jumbled mess the most
complicated possible encoding uh every
frame referencing every other frame more
you know uh just creating a tangled web
of uh dependencies and it's really hard
to know how you're supposed to send this
over the network
um but we try
one nice property worth mentioning is
that when there's a new iframe uh we can
you typically have what are called
closed gobs where you do not reference
the previous group of pictures so that's
a nice property you cannot have a
um a dependency go across this uh this
line uh so we abuse that and a lot of
protocols abuse that
so we're making a live media protocol a
live media transport and there's a few
high-level goals that I've been um
really trying to adhere to so number one
make sure we respect the encoding over
the network so the idea being is we want
to send media as it needs to be decoded
and as it is encoded we don't want to
try to do our own delivery mechanism we
want to make sure that uh if this Frame
depends on this Frame then over the
network this Frame also depends on this
Frame
um I've been mostly focusing on number
two minimizing latency during congestion
I've been trying to improve um our our
live video system uh to try and reduce
latency but the idea being is that when
networks suffer you need to have a plan
to decide how to keep latency low
and number three of course use Quick
um it's in the working group name after
all but um funnily enough uh we've
discovered quick later in the process
and it just kind of had all these
natural properties we did not set out to
use Quick initially
um but yeah it's in the charter
so some more little history
um we have this existing you know this
kind of annoying Gap structure with B
frames how do you serialize this over
TCP
um how do you make like rtmp hls Dash
how do they work
and more or less they take this
structure and they put it into one big
chain uh the idea being is uh you make
sure that everything all dependencies
are first in the chain and this is
what's called decode order
it screws a little bit with timestamps
if you see the very bottom because of B
frames don't worry too much about that
but this is one of the reasons why B
frames add latency uh and uh effectively
we just have a long continuous uh string
of uh frames this is nice and easy this
is why like rtmp sees a lot of use still
today is because
you just have this chain send it over
the network it arrives on the other end
and you can decode it
the problem though is congestion
what do we do in this congestion let's
say we can hypothetically only send half
the frames
which is simplifying a little bit
because frames have different sizes but
let's say we can only send half of them
what do we do
well the solution really is uh the
congestion controller will come in you
know Reno cubic bbr whatever and pick a
point in the TCP stream it will send
everything before this point and
everything afterwards it will just queue
and as new frames arrive we just append
them write them to the TCP socket they
get added to the end of the queue
and this continues and continues where
new frames are put in further deeper and
deeper into a cube there's some ways you
can get around this to some workarounds
um like you can avoid flushing frames to
the TCP socket until the last possible
minute
um and you can do stuff like ABR with
hls Dash but more or less you have
headline blocking and this is one of the
you know it's very similar to http um in
terms of uh the analogies here where
we're we're introducing a lot of
dependencies that shouldn't actually
exist
um a lot of these these new frames these
B's and the p's don't necessarily depend
on any of the previous frames that have
been written to TCP but we make them
dependencies over the network
so rule them this is these aren't hard
and fast rules but typically a goal one
I would say is don't introduce
dependencies over the network the idea
being is we should keep the media
dependencies like this Frame depends on
this Frame and at a transport level we
should not introduce new dependencies
just because it's easier
um because otherwise we just add latency
during congestion
it's an oversimplification but
as are these slides
um so how does RTP sold this uh the idea
being is uh hey let's we can't use TCP
let's break frames into individual
packets
and MTU boundaries so we take our
existing frames and we we slice them up
um and transmit them ourselves the idea
is that we do fragmentation congest
control reassembly everything in user
space all by ourselves but we get away
from TCP by doing that
and now with congestion what do we do
what do we do when we can only send half
the frames
well the idea being is because we do
Transmissions ourselves we can choose
which packets and more importantly which
frames the transmit so we selectively
decide which packets to transmit and
re-transmit such that we try to avoid
something like the B frames in this
example they're spurious they they're
Leaf nodes effectively on our graph
um and we try to make sure that there's
dependencies so we really prefer we
really make sure we send the newest
iframe that's the most important thing
and we'll spend extra time
re-transmitting that or using FEC or
whatever to make sure it gets there so
in the best case we've got four frames
that arrived on the other end
unfortunately there's also a worst case
where if you don't if you're not
intelligent or let's say you don't have
congestion control that's rapid and you
just like fire hose the network with all
your packets and they just drop randomly
you get this case where you get hearts
of frames arrive or you don't deliver
frames based on dependencies like we
lost a packet for our iframe and that
just causes decode failures going
forward so we lost the same number of
packets in this example but we only
decoded the first frame and everything
else was lost
so it's very important when you're doing
RTP to make sure that you have a very
clear understanding of the media
encoding the dependencies and how the
packets are all related to each other
um but rule number two just to simplify
is don't drop partial frames technically
slices but you need to deliver if if a
frame is split over multiple packets
they should all be delivered or none of
them should be delivered ideally you
don't want to waste bandwidth delivering
partial partial frames they're not
decodable for the most part
so how does rush solve this so this is
what meta's been using for like four or
five years now apparently
um is uh
um you split the media into Quick
streams so every frame is a separate uh
quick stream
and the idea being here is like quick
make sure that all the the frame is
fragmented and uh and uh transmitted and
uh arrives at the other side in order so
frames can arrive out of order into
um in relation to each other but within
a frame it will arrive reliably
um so same thing what do we do here and
I should note as well is quick handles
just again all the networking stuff you
don't have to do a whole lot in user
space so you just have to split the
media into frames it's a lot simpler
um but what do we do what do we do um
when uh there's congestion we can only
drop half the frames
well just like r2p there's a similar
best case what we call reset stream we
effectively say I want to drop this
Frame or we don't even make a stream for
it in the first place
um uh very very similar to RTP use case
where you can pick and choose which uh
which frames you should drop
although if you don't make the right
decisions in this case we dropped two
frames only but we've dropped the worst
ones or some really bad ones and you
cause decode errors again like
if you drop this iframe a great example
nothing after it in that Gap is
decodable without causing artifacts all
over the place
um so one of the things that Rush does
and quick R does is we put the
dependencies on The Wire the idea being
is that the sender already knows the
dependencies but relays also know the
dependencies so they can make these
intelligent dropping decisions and this
is foreshadowing a little bit to
Cullen's presentation
so I won't cover it too much
so rule three don't drop dependencies
in graph Theory terms drop the leaf
nodes first you don't want to drop the
root of the graph because it just causes
everything else to be lost as well
there is a caveat there a lot of these
Leaf nodes aren't that big in terms of
file size like B frames really don't
contribute much of the the bitrate but
they're still the best to drop first
so why am I here why am I standing up
here because I've been working on
something else for like three years now
um something called Warp
um
the idea being here is it's closer to
actually TCP where we just have uh
things in decode order but we we make a
quick stream per Gap so the dashed line
is missing for some reason but every
iframe effectively we make a brand new
quick stream
and what we do is uh we mark them with a
delivery order a little bit of metadata
that says that this stream should be
delivered before this stream
or this GOP segment should be delivered
before this segment so I color coded
them here but in this case the green uh
on the on the right these are the newest
frames and these are delivery order one
I want to deliver these first because
we're live we care about new frames
first older frames are less important
it's a heuristic but generally that's
what users prefer
so what do we do this congestion
we can only deliver half these frames
again same congestion control like as a
lot of the uh the other examples we we
learn that there's issues on the network
we need to figure out what to drop
and the way that work works is we
deliver based on this order so we
actually kind of reshuffle
um the the order we send packets so we
send the newest packets first in this
case the iframe the packet five is sent
first or frame five is sent first
and then we'll do the p and then the B
so we've delivered the newest frames
first and then with the remaining
congestion window
um we will actually go back and try this
in the original iframe uh frame zero but
it's a requirement for all the frames
that follow it
um the idea being is that the congest
controller in my case I'm just using bbr
just tells you what it can send these
are the packets I can send right now and
we go in in descending order and and
send the streams until eventually we hit
the bottleneck which is uh we just can't
send anymore
and as new frames are generated so this
is a new and a PB frame
um these are appended to the newest
stream which is delivery order one and
uh what's really cool is these kind of
jump the queue like in a TCP World these
are added to the very end
and this prioritized world or this
delivery order these um some of the
frames might get sent like the P frame
was is now in the congestion window it
gets sent
uh whereas the B frame is falling on the
other end uh we will starve that and we
will starve the older uh frames as well
um these frames just sitting in Ram
they're these are again these are quick
streams so there's two quick streams in
this example the yellow quick stream
sitting in Ram using a tiny bit of flow
control like Max streams but it's not
using anything over the network it's not
competing uh with other packets
and eventually what you can do is you
can just reset the stream it's not
required
um but at some point it's going to be
you know after like some number of
seconds you're gonna be like hey you're
not you're just not going to get sent
anytime soon so we should just free up
this memory and stop worrying about
having this you know you don't want to
have an indefinite chain of frames that
need to be sent from like minutes and
hours ago just sitting in Ram
um
so this is optional I will mention and
I'll explain why
because one of the things that warp I
really really hope it um I claim it does
is it offers variable latency and relay
support
the idea being that the receiver can
choose how much latency they want the
latency versus quality trade-off and
this works across relays which I think
is really cool
so just to kind of visualize this it's a
hard concept so I've done my best to try
and um visualize this but we've got
we've got a playback session right now
we've got two two frames in the receive
buffer two video frames and a little bit
of audio
um I should note in this example audio
is slightly prioritized over the video
but that's up to you in our case audio
is more important
um we had the live playhead that dash
line that's what the encoder is spitting
out and this is the earliest we could
possibly receive a frame over the
network you can think of it like min rtt
um and then we have these other
playheads on the left the idea being is
the receiver in outcasts the uh the
video player chooses when they want to
start playback and they choose the size
of the Jitter buffer to get into
networking terms
um so as we continue we generated a
little bit more audio and we delivered
some that audio over the network
uh the encoder also generated frame
three of video but there's a little bit
of congestion it hasn't arrived yet
um but either way we started with this
low low latency playhead for real-time
conferencing in this example it's got
two frames of latency which is a little
absurd but it's just an example uh the
idea being is it starts playing out of
the Jitter buffer almost immediately
so as we continue
um we've got some more congestion
actually we're not seeing frame four
should have been delivered at this point
and we we don't even have audio for that
equivalent of frame four
uh so at this point the low latency
playhead is already running into a
situation where it doesn't have any
video to display
and it's just going to show the previous
frame
um next slide and um we uh we have a new
new kid in the block interactive latency
interactive versus real time it's a
debatable I say interactive latency
being just just higher latency it's like
twitch style agency I would call it
um but there's some debate over with the
best name for that latency range is but
uh anyway they start watching video
they've started and now low latency a
real-time conferencing uh latency is
just running out of the audio buffer
it's gonna start
just having silence uh very soon we
still have a massive congestion none of
the new frames have been generated or
delivered sorry they haven't been
delivered they have been generated but
they're sitting blocked based on
congestion control
but the important thing is because we
prioritize or because we have this
delivery order
frame five and a little bit of audio
that that uh corresponds to it was
delivered just in time it's an iframe so
we're allowed to deliver it whereas all
the previous frames we weren't allowed
to skip there were peas
um but just in time for our real-time
latency user to get a little bit of
something
uh as a medium latency uh viewer catches
up and they're about to hit a gap of
missing video
um we add one more uh viewer to the mix
this is I'm just calling our
non-interactive latency this is somebody
with maybe a poor Network maybe it's
somebody in Brazil on their mobile phone
you know like they cannot sustain the
latencies that the other users uh uh
need or they don't want it maybe they're
just on the couch or something like
they're just they there's no reason to
have low latency they're just trying to
watch football
um
so they they joined the picture too and
we're recovering a bit from congestion
on the right side you see that we've
delivered frame six we've delivered some
audio we're catching up there's still a
big gaping Gap in the middle which is
where the medium latency is
um so that user right now is they're
listening to audio you see the audio is
continuous they hear it but their video
is um is Frozen or stuttering much like
a conference call if you've ever used
everybody's use a conference call at
this point where um that's what the user
experience uh is like
and then finally we keep going forward
we get some more frames popping into the
picture we've now caught up to the live
playhead everything's being delivered
um and we can go back and we can start
back filling the gaps in the buffer so
we've delivered frame three and
um just in time for the high latency
user to get it even though the medium
and low latency viewer did not get it
and then we deliver frame four uh so we
uh we finally managed to save the day we
patched all the holes in the Gap
um just in time for that viewer didn't
see any issues at all
and then there's a there's a fourth one
added this is a archive worker it could
be like 30 seconds delayed the idea is
that it's sitting there it will just
scoop up all the frames eventually and
then upload them to storage for a
Flawless of odd so the same stream you
could have somebody with real-time
latency that gets a lot of lost frames
and you have the other Spectrum
no loss at all but just High latency
so just to recap this is the exact same
delivery exact same network conditions
exact same packets being sent over the
network but what the site of the user
experience is how far how big the Jitter
buffer was
more or less
um but because we we had this delivery
order we can have these different user
experiences so the real-time latency
user had the lowest latency but they
dropped video and a little bit of audio
which is is usually required if you're
doing real-time conferencing but it's
not ideal I would say in higher latency
situations like a medium latency they
just dropped a little bit of video but
audio was Flawless that's what we're
looking for from twitch for example like
users don't need real time they prefer
to hear the broadcaster the streamer
even though they might miss a little bit
of video and then a high latency where
they just didn't see any issues at all
they didn't even know there was
congestion
um maybe ABR kicked in at some point and
they would notice that but in terms of
frame losses and frame drops they didn't
notice anything
and then finally the archive worker it's
just whatever latency you want you could
wait wait as long as you want uh well
Ram persists pretty much
um
until the streams are eventually reset
uh either side could reset like the
sender could send a reset stream and the
receiver could send to stop sending to
say like please just don't send me
anymore I've already skipped over this
content
that's mostly just to say bandwidth
though
so anyway with all that in play uh we've
got um this combined draft I've been
working on uh we're trying to combine
warp rush and a little bit of quick R
the the main concept is any number of
frames per stream is a segment uh
there's a lot of bike shedding on this
name uh so don't don't get too attached
to it
um and the delivery order and
dependencies are written on the wire and
this is to support relays the idea is
that these dropping decisions can be the
same no matter where the congestion
occurs uh if the congestion occurs on
the first top versus the last hop should
be the same experience
um so here's our example encoding again
um there's many ways you could break
this into segments uh so you could do
warp which is effectively you just break
into gaps very easy uh this is backwards
compatible with hls and dash more or
less you just take the same segments and
send them over quick
uh you can fragment a little bit more
you can say what if we send reference
frames and non-reference frames as
separate segments separate quick streams
we have a little marker at the front
that says here's the here's the delivery
order and maybe in a little market that
says here the dependencies between
streams
um uh but yeah we could break it further
because in this case we have these B
frames at the top depend on each other
even though ondexual encoding they don't
you could break them into individual
segments too you can break it down as
far as you want in this case we've got a
segment for an individual frame so it's
not fate sharing with the other frames
when it doesn't need to be
and then finally you could just break it
every frame into its own segment this is
effectively Rush
um
the numbers here like the delivery order
uh one two three four five all the way
up
those are arbitrary it's based on your
application uh in the use case in in
this case we want to deliver the newer
frames first
but there's certainly use cases where
you want to deliver the older frames
first in our case like for example
you're serving an ad
you don't want to skip any of the ad
video so you you kind of flip it around
you turn on the head of line blocking
and say that actually the first iframe
which is delivery order for make a
delivery order one make that the first
one that we deliver so there's no
skipping allowed
um so there's a lot of business logic
we'll kind of talk about this at some
point in the future about delivery order
um there's no right answer effectively
to how you prioritize frames somebody
has to decide which frames are more
important somebody has to decide it's
audio more important somebody has to
decide even like which Renditions and
whatnot are important
um so what's next uh I I forgot to draw
a bike but this is a shed uh
the the names are really hard so we're
not sure if we should call this warp or
rush or meaver quick or some made up
name
um and especially the name of segments
like all these segments are they layers
are they fragments chunks media quick
prefix things fubars like
every word every name we've looked at
has like existing connotations that it
clashes with
um and then uh I've been working on this
draft mostly um there's a GitHub repo
kicksolated warp draft I found a lot of
issues but there's a lot of core things
missing like a wire format
I've defined how media should be sent
but we don't even have a way of how the
bytes should be written to streams uh
yet
uh we're also trying to figure out how
CDN support works
um right now the protocol is push-based
it's very simple web transport you push
but we want to figure out what's the
middle ground we can find to make sure
that existing cdns that are all HP based
and pull can still work with this
protocol
um so it doesn't really matter if it's
push versus pull so long as you send
media the same way over quick streams
but we want to ideally have one protocol
for both contribution and distribution
um and we need to figure out where the
middle ground is there
and just all the media stuff like
how do you send tracks how do you choose
tracks how do you do you know which
codecs which container even uh the
current draft has like uh cmap but we
still haven't even decided
um so everything that's actually
required to make sure media playback
works is currently missing just just the
networking stuff is what I've been
focusing on
um I've also been working on a demo uh
quick.video demo I will say it's very
crude it's just hosted on a single host
uh tiny instance in US West 2.
um I'm working on it too but there's uh
this code also on GitHub to show how
this works and some examples and then
finally with adoption I don't know the
process I don't think this is ready for
adoption yet but I really want to get
the idea from the room is this the right
direction how do we feel
um what do we think is missing what do
we think should be laid out first
um a lot of contributors so I'm Luke
again representing the twitch folks
um most of them are online and then uh
from Cisco we've got Suez Cullen and
meta Cairo Allen and Jordy have been uh
helping a lot with this draft among
others I've seen uh there's a few folks
have uh left a lot of issues uh lately
too
and that's all I got
speaking of contributors uh the queue is
quite full uh at this point Sam you're
up first
between
me
good morning uh samhurst BBC r d uh
thanks very much for the presentation
that was really cool uh and Kudos on the
handwritten slides I love that
um so I have a question about the
delivery order number that you were
showing up there is that just a
constantly incrementing number as it
goes through or is that a
uh more sort of dynamic value that
changes depending on one particular
instance in time
yeah so um
we still need to work out as this is one
continue right now it's one continuous
number space it's just a un 64.
um how warp Works in production for
right how I've coded it is it's
effectively just the presentation
timestamp
plus three seconds if it's audio just to
give audio a little bit of a head start
but effectively it's an arbitrary number
so long as the lower number is um
delivered first
or in my case I'm doing the presentation
timestamp but anyway
um it's arbitrary okay okay
oh
um great overview
um Grosso for simplification like you
said but I think it's the right
oversimplification for uh transport
folks one important aspect that I I'm
not sure was
um was convey which I think it matters a
lot to the the for the transport folks
to understand is that there's
differences between congestion control
and rate control and
um and even within congestion control
there's also you know when you talk
about prioritization there's different
concepts of the partition about whether
you're talking about your local cues or
whether you're talking about marking
things properly so that the network cues
um handle your congestion the way that
you intended so first I think we want to
make sure that people understand that
over long time Windows we're not using
congestion control to to instantaneously
decide which packets are said that the
the congestion controllers overall
average
um bandwidth estimate gets fed up slowly
to the app and that changes the media
encoding rate so you're not just going
to drop individual parts of your of your
stream you're going to select a totally
different stream encoding in order to
meet the budget that your condition
control is telling you over a long time
that's not useful for an instantaneous
decision that the congestion control
says you know what I I know I'm not
going to send this packet because I
don't have a window open this in this
packet so that's where an immediate
priority can help on on a marking from
the app layer to the to the quick layer
it can drop something immediately or
hold something back immediately but the
longer time windows those are going to
be controlled by rate controller
feedback to change the media encoding
itself
so I think it's important to keep keep
those things in mind and also the
difference between
congestion control decisions to do
something for internal cues versus how
they get marked for Network cues because
you know Wireless you know wmm and and
Mobile Wireless qcis and and we know
wired dscps and things like that
there should be different ways to map
the application Level priorities to
those Network priorities and I think
it's important to get that right in in
these drafts as well
yeah one thing I didn't mention and you
rightly pointed out is that these don't
have to be the same bit rate like these
segments the encoder as it sees
congestion can start decreasing the bit
rate in response this is meant to be a
response when you can't change the
encoder in time especially for
contribution like you have to switch it
switch Renditions and iframe boundaries
um but yeah and and prioritizations only
as effective as how quickly you can
detect congestion if you have something
like buffer bloat
everything's over the network
unprioritized so giving more information
to the network layer helps as well and I
think this this order that you have
um
I think it came across in the
presentation as this is something baked
into the protocol but that's an
application Level thing that it can just
decide whatever
um you know delivery Priority it wants
uh for things because for for some
people the user experience may be
terrible if it's stuttering that that
order that you showed before would be
under congestion you your video is
constantly stuttering right you you
cancel something that's being played
right now and you try to play the Live
Edge and so you get someone you know
always for half a second of the Live
Edge instead of a full second of
continuous video so I think that user
experience is up to the app to figure
out what the right you know order and
priorities should be not something back
into the into the protocol
uh thanks for that I will notice that
some of the discussion that's currently
happening uh on the uh chat uh has uh
has touched on ABR and other things like
that so if you're watching this on
YouTube please do go seek out uh that
chat stream as well uh which should be
linked from uh the iitf site uh because
there's uh certainly some working group
discussion happening in that I'm sure
I'm from Huawei and I see is a combined
protocol from three dropped but there is
a lot of things in quick cards missing
here I think the pop sub relationship
and they use Quick datagram and for the
pub sub I think maybe it can bring a lot
of State in the Renee I think that's why
you drop it
yeah this is meant to be a base draft as
when we take everything combined and the
idea is something like quick R could
either be added on top of this draft or
just a separate draft entirely we're not
sure yet this is meant to be the common
ground
yeah I can see the pops up being
implemented over over these drugs and
maybe you're not in there but the quick
datagram scene to do something new to in
the bass drops so uh
I think in um quick streams are more
than capable of doing even real-time
latency so as long as again you have
some way of deciding which quick streams
to send first and which fragments to
send first so I don't think datagrams
are necessary
um which is a controversial statement
but um uh yeah by having more tight
control over what the quick library
sends
end of the day it's the same media
getting fragmented the difference is if
you do it in the application layer or if
quick does it as long as you can tell
the quick library to fragment in such a
way it's the same thing yeah I think RTP
is a kind of like the quick datagram
instead of the stream right so the
benefits by using the datagram is that
you can pre-plan some metadata to each
datagram
so you can drop it in more more
fine-grained way
okay yeah possibly
fierce
I guess the the Assumption I appears a
handle on the BBC r d is um
the Assumption here was was is sort of
traditional kind of representation kind
of breakdown of the video as opposed to
like SVC type uh kind of so then if you
think if we're thinking that then it's
then are you gonna is there an ABR stage
or is this really the ABR
um because I guess that's happening in
webrtc already
um with the SFU approach where you just
pull things out I sort of wondered you
thought about that because it's just
sort of seems to be quite sort of low
level
ipb based but
so first off we're I'm doing ABR for
we're using this approach uh the idea
being is that the sender chooses which
of these segments to send So based on
the congestion window it can switch down
a rendition uh you did mention SVC now
very quickly
switch to just in case somebody asks
um this is an example don't overthink
this but the idea is you could have a
base layer like 360p and then you can
have segments that build on top of
um so SPC people don't know you have a
basin layer 360p in this case and you
could have enhancement layers on top so
we're pretty much just sending SBC
layers as quick streams is more or less
this proposal but I don't know enough
about SVC this is just like an idea
right okay yeah I thought it should it
seemed like it would naturally extend to
it in a way but then in another sense it
would then maybe
uh you wouldn't necessarily need this
would become the kind of ABR
um aspect although I don't think we want
to require SVC
right and and the prioritization thing
so that would be happening kind of
in in a potentially some kind of switch
relay entity or some kind of a quick
relay kind of entity where so
so then I guess it was a previous one
about how that Maps down to the actual
Network
priorities we're going to cover that a
good bit in the next okay so if you're
going to hold that for the next fine
fine okay thanks
um and just uh the treasure about to
lock the queue so if you feel like you
want to be uh following up on this
please get in the queue uh now
Christian
uh nice presentation Luke I mean I I
like the simplification it makes the
thing easy to understand
uh one thing that is missed in the
simplification is the effect of these
segmentation on relays
because if you have a set of streams as
you describe then you are going to get
head offline blocking on these streams
and if you have a series of relays then
you are going to get head of line of
blocking at each of the relay
and the delays induced by head of line
blocking will combine
and that's the reason why I had been
exploring how to do the same kind of
architecture with datagrams so that
effectively when you have three layers
you get fraction of the streams in the
datagrams and you can decide to for them
immediately thus avoiding the end of
line blocking
yeah I'll let Cullen cover that more but
just really simple response that assumes
that you're reading streams in order and
then writing them in order but you can
get around that if you can read and
write out of order to Quick streams uh
beholden to flow control
uh so that's that's that's that's yeah I
I understand what you said there but
that's extremely hard to do because the
reading in I mean
basically if you're doing datagrams your
application being in control can do
whatever
if if you are doing streams the
application is not in control and this
business of reading steam out of order
is really really hard
I would say this is a general problem
for quick relays like even HTTP suffers
from this where a gap for packet loss
will cause
um on blocking but yeah for sure
Victor
uh Victor vasilia for Google uh I just
wanted quickly to say uh that uh
supports this proposal I'm not sure if
in a stage for adoption but whatever
there is that's not how to do looks very
good uh and thank you very much for
working this
foreign
okay is it better now cool so thanks
Luke for the presentation on trying to
kind of combine things good things from
all the protocols and I agree this this
is a good start and we have quite a bit
of things to cover to make it more
usable uh especially uh thinking uh
end-to-end protocol not just the
transport but also the relays and
consumption side how do you ask for
things they all depend on how do you
break the things to start with so that
we can Define the internal protocol I
think we need to cut some of those
pieces in and I want to kind of talk on
a couple of things that was raised uh
some more on someone else uh on on the
delivery on the priority I think there
are two different concepts uh like
priority is more like saying what how is
one thing important in relative to other
and delivery order is more like how my
decode decoder wants to get it in so
that it can do some good work and and
probably we need to kind of spend some
more time on thinking how uh relays
would
understand the data but not making too
much in protocol but leaving it to the
application space to Define how it is
done that would be helpful and another
point on the datagrams I agree uh at
some point as a group we have to kind of
make a decision on
um how do we meet the use cases that we
have mock chartered for
HTTP does not have to do real time so
hence it's okay but mock is not
constrained by that we have more use
cases and we might not do datagram it's
a a working group decision at some point
but we need to say Can what are protocol
be develop in water transport we do
works for the use cases thanks
Peter thatter
my audio working
yes
okay uh first I'd like to say I I think
it's good that you're building on web
transport uh that solves a lot of like
multiplexing issues
um
and it allows for I think you should
allow for either streams or datagrams I
think streams are fine to use but I
think it makes sense to allow the client
to do either and that's I believe the
direction RTP over quick is doing
um
during your presentation you mentioned
that you haven't defined it all the
media protocol are you looking for
contributions on that front I have
ideas that I'd be happy to contribute
yeah of course
um
if any if anybody wants to help either
on the protocol or on the demo or just
just want to talk to me go for it
looking for contributions
okay great thanks that's it
Randall
uh Randall we can't hear you yet
that I think will do it
there we go can you hear me now
yes
okay
um
uh I notice you have the SVC example
here
um
and
for the case where you're not using SEC
but you're just feeding multiple
different
um resolutions or bit rates up I'd be
interested to see how that Maps here but
also I notice also that all the
playheads you've defined in your other
diagram appear to be at the same
location I you know as in there all
these things are arriving at that
location and you have different
playheads which appear to be running off
the same buffer stream whatever okay
is that actually what's what's
anticipated here which would seem odd
except for maybe like the recording
stream uh recording head uh
uh or is there something more complex
going on here I uh
I think like it is actually getting fed
out to the different two different
locations which I imagine it is which
may be consuming different portions of a
multi-layered
multi-bitrate stream
okay sure so first off for simulcast
which is sending multiple Renditions
that don't depend on each other uh it's
effectively this SVC example you just
remove those arrows between layers so in
this case you'd send the 360p rendition
I got the highest priority will be
delivered first and then any extra
bandwidth will be sent on higher quality
ones so sending multiple Renditions
works very similar to SVC there's just
no dependencies between segments and
layers
and then finally for the playhead uh you
would not be receiving those all that's
just an um just a visualization the idea
is that different viewers will have
different network conditions so they all
have different starvation congestion I
just wanted to explain that even with
the same network situation you could
have different experiences based on the
size of that Jitter buffer and the size
of that Jitter buffer depends on the use
case
the desired user experience but
everybody would get a different
experience
yeah I think it would be more
illustrative and more better for
discussion if if we use a slightly more
real world case for that because that
affects some of these these questions
and answers about how to do this
thank you thank you
uh I think that brings us to the kind of
next steps question here the discussion
has been great today uh we definitely
have kicked off a lot of different
issues both at the mic line and again
I'll I'll point out during the chat uh
almost a distinct set of issues we've
gone through and Luke I entered you to
go through the chat and anybody who's
watching us uh post facto to do the same
uh we're definitely not going to do a
call for adoption today it's pretty
clear there's a lot of stuff that people
need to cash out first
um but please do keep the discussion
going on the list even though we will be
talking about an interim uh later on in
this meeting we really want to make sure
that we don't have to have the pace of
discussion only at these meetings
there's definitely a lot of this that
you can do in either uh mailing list
discussion or on the issues for uh the
GitHub repo uh so thanks very much
uh our next thing on the agenda is
a different presentation Colin you want
to come up and by the way if you have
not actually signed in to the
uh
the tool because you weren't thinking
you were going to get up or something
like that we'd really appreciate you
doing so because this is a pretty tight
fit for a room and we'd love to have a a
little bit
um
uh more
spacious space uh when we get to
Yokohama so
whoa I forgot I had to stand in the pink
Square here okay awesome
um thank you
dust that working okay when I step away
from the mic abuse me
um so I'm going to talk a little bit
about uh the relay stuff here and
whoa huge lag
um the goals of this discussion is uh is
really around
um understanding some of the commonality
of some of the questions that come up in
every one of the relay drafts that we've
had a lot of these drafts had relays or
things are a lot like them in some ways
so I want to try and hit uh some of the
similarities differences there's lots of
more nuanced things that even some of
them came up in the previous
conversation which which unfortunately I
don't really talk about at all in here
but I I think we're just you know it's a
first working group meeting we're trying
to figure out what are the the big
things and
and get them moving along and get us all
sort of talking on the same page and
having a good discussion about things
that need to be I was really um thankful
to like I like I love the last
discussion lots of good ideas came up
and it wasn't about like oh
a versus B it was like ah this is a
property that we need in the end system
we're going to do and that's that's a
great way to think about stuff at this
stage of a working group
so
uh where do relays fit in here
and you know in every one of these
systems that we're talking about on the
ingest side our producers are creating
some content they're pushing it over
some protocol up to something you can
call it a server you can call it a relay
you can call it a CDN but it's going up
to something we're going to talk a
little bit more of that second on the
other side something up probably in the
cloud and again it may be a CDN it may
be a relay it may be however you think
about it an SFU these types of things
are bringing the data down to the
consumers and
the key Point here is we're not trying
to Define and figure out exactly how
that CDN relay internals Works what
we're trying to make sure is that the
protocol we're defining here which is
going from the a to the X's or from the
Y's down to the C's has enough
information in it that the X and the Y's
devices whatever they are have the
information that they need to do they
need to achieve the end end-to-end user
experience that we want to achieve here
okay
so there's you know some things in there
that you end up having to know you know
if consumer C has twice the bandwidth as
consumer D and producer a is making
things in different resolutions or
whatever you know there's some
information you need to know in here
that helps works there's not much
information we're going to get to that
later
now the other things is
um we talk about the security on this
stuff so I wanted to just sort of hit a
little bit of the terminology in here on
this slide to just there's not
um I'm defining just by definition that
the ends are the producers and the
consumers things that have the ability
to uh encode or decode the video decrypt
it can see the media those types of
things
the relays in the middle here are not
ends they're middles
so they cannot do things like that
um and when we start talking about the
ability in our Charter we have a strong
requirement for end-to-end security
we're talking about the producers and
the consumers being able to do it if
there was a transcoder in the middle of
this network it has to access the media
obviously and which means it's an end a
transcoder is probably both a producer
and a consumer of different streams and
is is in the end
um you know what I think my audio is
really messed up I'm gonna take a mask
off here so
so
uh that that's what I mean by ends and
and such
next slide Maybe
back a slide maybe okay
so we do get the question of like well
do we have these who's going to provide
these relays and was one of the
questions that was raised a lot in the
beginning it will anybody build this
type of stuff and so uh there will
probably be a range of different people
to do it there's some companies that
have a CDN or something like it today
twitch is an example of this right they
have this they operate it themselves
they can deal with this stuff they want
to probably use some of the existing
thing to have and don't disrupt about
them uh there's companies like that you
know WebEx part of Cisco that uh today
does its own media nodes near the edge
and pushing them out to all of these
places but uh would would rather run
that on somebody else's infrastructure
and buy and there's there's companies
like Akamai cloudflareoplasty of all uh
talk to me about mock in various forms
and those types of things this company
likes interdigital that has drafts here
that are looking at relays that are
tightly tied to 5G Network optimizations
so they can provide a better experience
uh for the media than you could if if
you weren't so that there's there's a
range of those types of issues
so do I have a cube built up here warn
me if I do because I won't I will stop
if we need questions so what what really
drives the need for these relays why do
all these existing networks happen well
there's a bunch of different reasons uh
some of the sort of high so the two
biggest ones for me are one is on the
distribution side you you need fan out
you need some device that can you know
take your your content instead of just
going to one person spread it out to
hundreds of people or millions of people
and scale that up and these are a
convenient way to do that type of thing
and the closer you move that you can uh
have some bandwidth savings and some of
those types of other issues as well
then there's another point of you're
trying to get these relays closer to the
consumers or the producers so let's talk
about in the consumer case for a second
the closer it is uh the faster the less
round trip there is between the device
consuming it and the and where the
device that has a valid copy of the
media you're trying to receive and the
more you can squeeze the the time like
that that it takes to get a message back
and forth between those the more you can
use Quick streams and things like that
to re-transmit data you lost and still
not have it slide out and still not have
it extend the latency of your overall
delivery of the media from a glass to
glass point of view so this is why you
see so many CVS like any of the major
media networks today just even doing
Dash Ratio or something like that I mean
you don't try and uh deliver video to
users in Australia by using a CDN server
um in London it's it that's just not a
very effective way to do it you try and
get it close to there so that when
there's loss on a local land link it's a
slow it's a much faster place that you
can say I lost this packet please return
it and get it back to me so bringing
those things up now
some people like the 5G people want to
extend that much farther and closer out
to the edge than we've traditionally
seen in today's networks and that's one
of the things that's changing that
allows more bandwidths so that's some of
the things we're trying to hit here and
why we have these relays at all
so these operational requirements a few
of these comes out um
you know you want to minimize load and
make them easy to scale you know normal
sort of things and trying to develop
develop any Cloud Server
um you know you need to make them
configurable but fundamentally they're
making decisions about what to forward
what to drop okay that's really what
they do they take some packets in they
send some packets out and you decide
which one of those go in and out
um a lot of the requirement is drafts we
saw some sort of requirement to clearly
hand off a client to a new relay to
reschedule relays or reload balance take
something out of service and this is the
sort of go away messages you see in
several of the protocols so this is a
relay redirect type idea
um low latencies obviously the whole
point of this sort of thing uh and rapid
recovery from buildings these are all
requirements that we're going to have to
figure out how our protocol will help
what it what our protocol needs to be
able to support those operational
requirements
the um
again I'm just defining this as
terminology by by definition not some
logical sort of thing I'm splitting the
stuff that relays see or this goes
across the protocol into an envelope and
a payload okay so the payload is the
video content the audio content whatever
the media is from it may be encrypted it
may be DRM protected it may be anything
uh or it may be totally unencrypted as
well but the key point is the relay
can't depend on being able to look into
the payload to see it the envelope data
on the other hand is really what this
presentation is going to mostly be about
and this is the stuff what is it that
the relay needs to see you know in an IP
sense like you need to see your source
and destination IP addresses or a router
can't route it it's like that type of
stuff obviously our goal here will be
put the minimal stuff we can in the
envelope for for a lot of reasons
um and and do it so that that's just the
terminology I'm using to define those
two different chunks of sort of data
that we need to deal with
so
I don't want to delve deeply into what
all the drafts do on this but you know
warpad you know an ID for a stream and
some delivery Priority stuff perhaps
dependency list uh the deploy draft had
you know similar set of stuff with a
bunch more data that might help it work
in a 5G context uh you know quicker had
some sort of different things with you
know time to live or time stamps and
discardable but
the exact details of all those drafts
don't really matter what matters as we
start figuring out what our use cases
are that drive the need for chunks of
data that go into this envelope and and
what they are and I'm going to talk
about a couple of those in the slides
coming up
I can't see if anyone's on the Queue so
we will see it up in the right hand
corner oh okay cool I will see it then
so probably the biggest one and we are
talking about that earlier as this
priority and delivery order type stuff
and
all of the proposals have some form of
idea that there's there's sort of a base
priority related draft and I'm
struggling because different terms we
you know Luke says it's terminology is
hard here different drafts I've done
this a little bit different ways but
there is definitely a concept in all the
drafts that if your audio if your
application business logic feels that
audio is more important than a video
there's a way of indicating in there
that relays should forward audio before
they should bother forwarding video for
the same thing and similarly different
types of video might matter differently
um I was thinking about you know your
360p videos more important than a layer
than an adaptation layer that it goes
720p on top of it but you know as Luke
pointed out too uh if you have
advertising video and non-advertising
video your business application may say
business logic may be that the the ads
are more important right so there's some
application layer of things at that type
of
um idea
and then there's this stuff that has to
do with sort of delivery order
um some sort of numeric counter of these
things and that was a lot of what Luke
was talking about and helping to helping
try and motivate and explain his draft
of
look if if if you have some data that
depends if you have a p frame that
depends on an iframe but you can't
deliver the iframe there's really no
point in delivering the P frame it's
that data is useless there's nothing you
can do with it so there's some sort of
you know sense of of a natural ordering
that way there's also data that is so
old it is useless that's really what we
mean by real time when we talk about
real-time video right is is there's
stuff that's too old to be of any use
um and so the warp drafts you know took
the approach of uh the the newest thing
was always more most important in this
sort of context that might be uh that
might be completely right or mostly
right with some fine print and hand
waving and I'm sure the working group
will will dig into that deeper as as we
hit that but we we need some way of sort
of understanding uh the the decoder
order of these types of things uh of
what's needed at the other end and what
makes the sense to be delivered in that
so this is similar to you know an RTP
you had sequence numbers
[Music]
um
we have different stream or segment IDs
whatever we call stream segments layers
fragments
um we have you know that type of way we
need some way of ordering that and we
need to decide how that that ordering
number relates to the priority of it
being sent within the broader priority
of uh the audio is more important than
video so I see these as two different
things um we can I mean both
conceptually we clearly everybody agrees
there's two different things and we need
both of them here how they get mapped to
bits may be one thing two things we can
sort of debate that later but I think
that the key thing for us is to
understand what it is we want the the
protocol to deliver and that we want
relays to be able to look at this type
of information and start to to deal with
it as they forwarded something on and
remember if if if a video stream was
sent up
um
you know in multiple Renditions one at
one megabit and one at two megabits and
there's a relay that has access to both
of those there's we will be doing the
normal thing of clients you know
connecting and asking for the one that
has the right bandwidth for what they
need none of that's taking away from
that but you still need to understand
what's priority to deliver inside of
that
uh no questions okay
so this is actually what I think is the
most thing to land in the envelope paid
actually
uh dependency indication so this gets to
how explicit we want to do get about
this and I think this would be a great
thing to get some feedback from the
working group on today as mine yes so
one way that we could do and one of one
of the warp uh drafts had a proposal for
this is I mean we could have a
dependency list where we could say these
uh chunks of data segments of data
depend on these other
um chunks like by named ID and that
relays and things could look at that
figure out what to do with them
um
some of the other drafts quicker being
one of them use the idea that there'd
just be like a priority like you know
audios Priority One uh you know 360ps
priority two 720p is priority three and
that the application would pick those
priorities but with a small number of
set of numeric priorities they would be
able to deliver you know get the the end
effect they wanted on the relays so one
of the questions that we'll have to
figure out uh from the working group and
is
should we have a dependency an explicit
dependency list or can we get away with
just having this sort of you know
General priority idea to be able to do
this in the relays
um and what you know what do we need to
do there that's sort of one of the areas
caching is a is another uh area where uh
the quicker drafts did assume sort of
this but we could or could not have this
so this is not very important on the
Ingress side this is all about the
distribution side where it's probably
more important
and on that side you come to the idea of
is it useful for uh one of the relays to
have a short-term amount of media data
that's there available to it and this
can help deal with tasks like when a
client first joins there's already the
previous iframe is there in cash and
they can get the previous iframe instead
of waiting for the next iframe to be
transmitted and sent into the system it
could be pushed a little bit farther you
know some interactive applications Skype
long ago even sort of did it but you
know various applications playing with
the idea of well if you missed some
packets you could you could pause the
stream temporarily roll back in time and
then play quickly forward you know those
types of ideas where you can catch up
um we could or could not support those
this could be something that the
protocol if we did this at all I'm sure
it's something that would be optional
for the relays to ever cash more than
zero bytes of data
um but you know caching and whether we
want to deal with that is one of the
issues that we'll have to touch on on
that side it can be done as completely
extension draft right it's those types
of things
let's see uh security and privacy so
as I said at the beginning
um the relays can only uh read the
envelope data uh the and other network
elements can't uh you know routers along
the way this is all inside a normal
quick TLS connection between the
consumers or producers and the relays
okay so this doesn't change quick TLS in
any way like everything's encrypted over
the network with quick TLS exactly as
you would expect
and exactly like today's cdns as well
um on on a classic CDN today yeah every
connection might be encrypted with https
and uh the media that's being moved
around inside of that connection uh you
know maybe DRM encrypted right so
I think that we're trying to very much
follow that same model that's worked in
that space uh and allow for this now
one of the things about this that we do
need to sort of you know hassle is like
do we need techniques for
dealing with Integrity of what happens
of the envelope data my view is that
there's no let me go to the next slide
on this one
oh sorry I took the slide out I'll go
back one okay so uh my view is that the
relays shouldn't ever change envelope
information that they should they can
read it but they shouldn't change it and
if you were on a system that chose to
use MLS group keying then you could get
away uh with
uh with actually providing real a a
Integrity protection of the envelope
data at the ends it's not like the
relays in the middle would do the
computational work to check it probably
but they they could
so Spencer you had had some questions on
the list and I see you on the Queue now
does this hit Does this answer my view
anyway on the where we should go on
these key items
okay
um
Spencer Dawkins uh too long don't read
or don't listen is yes uh but uh the
thing to me that seemed helpful for me
to be asking uh about this is
um
what a what a useful name
for what are called relays now would be
that would be clearer uh and the
probably just the functionality kind of
thing uh we talked uh yesterday recently
about uh me asking so or you know is
this a general purpose relay I think not
or if it's not what kind of a relay is
it
and uh I think after
seeing that part of the discussion in
your slides which which are incredibly
helpful to me thank you
but uh I think that
uh
what I what I think you were saying was
that this would be a relay that relayed
whatever uh Rush warp is
it ends up being called is it would you
agree with that
it it it so I view these relays as a
hundred percent tied to the the protocol
that's coming out of this working group
to relay the data you know that with the
media that this working group's done
that's what side now that makes it sound
like a specialized relay it's only a
relay for the mock protocol
um
however given the mock protocol is meant
for moving any media and nearly anything
you ever want to move can be considered
media in some form or another it is an
incredibly General thing so what this
working group is really talking about
building from from day one whether you
think about it or not as soon as you
talk about moving media over quick it or
media over anything uh in some real-time
way we are talking about building a a
better set of ways to move real-time
data around the network and it will turn
out to be incredibly generalized if we
get this right right okay right I like
to say I think my biggest thing on on
being able to explain to people what the
scope is is you know number one figure
out what the name of
Russia is
so that you can say we relate among
whatever else we do we we relay that
so
um from from a church perspective uh
thank you very much for the intervention
um but I'm going to ask not you actually
spend a lot of time talking about names
because right uh what what I think you
were asking for is a description of
relay functionality that's absolutely
cool
um but uh we don't want to spend a lot
of time on on names because it's an
enormous bike shed and I will note that
the cube ballooned the minute you said
names seven additional people who no
doubt have great ideas of uh of their
favorite name if you're in the queue to
talk about the name please get out of
the queue
um if you're in the in in it to talk
about relay functionality welcome we
look forward to your insights but we can
keep talking about this as the mock
protocol good name coming future and the
mock relay yeah functionality to be
discussed no name discussion please
right thank you
just in terms of processing the queue I
think Colin you only have one more slide
after this is that right
sure
um or is it you want to try to finish it
up and then take all the questions
please do that okay
to get back to where I can actually do
that okay one more slide here uh so the
this
this slide under cells the connect the
the problem here but uh when the mock
client uh connects over the mock
protocol to the mock relay
um we need some idea of what it is that
is used to authenticate and authorize
and allow the relay to decide that is
going to be willing to forward this
traffic in a meaningful way okay and
basically uh initially what I had
written on this slide when I first
started was
um
that you know
there'll be an authorization token and
some form and really I I think that we
come around to that uh that the you know
there's an authorization token that the
application got that the consumer or
producer got in some out of bound way
that it allowed it to pass it to uh the
relays it probably also found in the
same out of bound way what relays it
might want to use
um and that the relay say that now that
is such a fluffy hand wave to the whole
problem it's completely useless okay so
I recognize that uh but I think we're
going to end up something along those
lines now option two which was I forget
who proposed that to the list right now
I'm just blanking I apologize to you
over but but you know what oh it was
will so you know will said hey look
actually we need uh we've had this
problem Lots we've thought about it lots
in existing cdns and there's some really
good approaches to steal from here that
have a bunch of advantages over what was
being discussed and so I I'm as an
individual they're very much in favor of
going down this sort of you know number
two type option where we take the same
type of ideas of what has worked to be
very scalable uh in existing today HTTP
cdns and apply it to these mock cdns so
that was really my my last slide and so
we can talk a little bit more about that
Wednesday so let's go back to the
question queue okay before we do I just
want to do a time check for people it is
10 45 we closed at 11 30 and we have a
pretty hard stop because they need to
set the room for the next uh host talk
uh so please make your interventions
pithy
um and uh be ready to uh have quick
responses the first is Emma
nice presentation so quick question
running the last slide so I love you
said minimize the information the
envelope should have for the Relay but
should not keep it as is because several
developers love to have everything if we
keep it as it would be vague so I think
we should include what information
should be available if it should not be
there
plus one okay
yeah it's implicit in what you were
saying in the intro but I don't think
you
we need to be able to have a relay that
is doing a meet Echo function
this is completely unaware of any of the
content
that is being gated so you know I want
to do me TECO
but without the relay being an end point
so I think if we could add that to the
use cases it would be useful in making
sure that we keep enough information to
make that possible
oh okay let me paraphrase what you're
saying here and make it a little bit
tighter than what you said but I agree
with you so obviously if we're doing an
application like meat Echo we can
definitely make uh the relays not have
access to any of the media content for
sure and be used to help scale out
something like me could Echo but mean
Echo also probably requires an SFU
somewhere and these relays do not 100 do
the functionality in SFU you'll still
need an SFU in some sense which also can
be end-to-end encrypted but yeah okay so
yeah that works for you yeah there's got
to be enough metadata to to to to allow
the switching
to happen got it the other thing on the
authentication piece
um
if I've got a large fan out
and I've got Fred who's been creating
um data and we're using Mac or whatever
to authenticate
I don't want Fred to have to have a
million Association uh uh shared secrets
with all the end points I don't want one
endpoint be able to impersonate Fred
so The Logical implication of that is
the relay is going to Fred is going to
authenticate to the relay and the relay
is then going to re-authenticate to each
endpoint in that
scenario
okay I think that is a hot and deep area
you're not wrong of course and I think
that'll be a great topic for the working
group after we get past some of the
easier stuff but we're not like but
you're totally right but I mean we're
this like people aren't even ready to
It's Gonna explode their heads though
hello uh Robin marks Akamai uh I've seen
Luke and you talking about priorities
for streams and dependencies between
streams and not doing the just at the
origin but also in between and it starts
to smell a lot like HTTP 2 dependency
tree which is a notoriously bad idea
that we're still suffering from today
um especially people like me
um uh I don't think I think this is too
complex for the new extensible
priorities that we have in HTTP 3.
um but what I really want to say is keep
it simple
great feedback well yes I I will I'm on
the same page
mercenary so quickly on the dependencies
uh I think uh if you look at um what we
do in RTP in in a lot of us assumptions
is that sequence numbers are always
implicit dependencies on the things
before them the difference here is that
now we're talking about
independent quick streams and is there
going to be some sort of signaling of
the dependencies across those quick
streams because they may not truly be
independent they may be in the SVC case
different layers in in each of the
streams or for various different reasons
you may have different encodings that
split things up across streams and you
might be able to describe the
dependencies of those streams I think
it's pretty simple to have a simple and
flexible way to to describe those
without too much complexity we have the
frameworking draft we have 81 dependency
descriptors and you're talking about you
know like a simple one bite thing that
that gives you almost everything you
need to know but within a stream I think
it's just simple to keep the basic rule
everything is in sequence what came now
depends on everything that came before
in that stream that's that's a simple
assumption to start out with
um and then secondly um I'd like to
understand from
um from the uh meta and twitch folks you
must already have some relays assume
that just your own built realize if you
had to replace those with my cloudflare
fastly whatever what would you do
differently or what would you have to
encode in the protocol to work with a
third party I think that's an important
thing to get out of the protocol is for
people who wanted to have vendor
infrastructure it's not their own what
would we need in the protocol to enable
that
yeah
um it's interesting around this envelope
information and the security if you're
actually going to sign Etc it needs to
be stable across the whole system which
has been a classical case which doesn't
work in RTP because you have leg by leg
or basically and point-to-end point
dependent signaling so you're gonna have
to have an interesting actually ensure
that you have a global namespace for
identification Etc this type of
information
so
yeah 100 agree and that's part of why
MLS is in the charter
the Piezo handled I'm just um going back
to the um ABR stuff in that um
you kind of have this very fine grain
kind of behavior happening at the solves
um like per stream representation level
but then the ABR sitting in some kind of
browser sandbox kind of trying to
measure throughput on a JavaScript sort
of API and making an ABR decision there
there seems to be quite a big disconnect
between the amount of information that's
kind of you've got this very
fine-grained stuff happening
per per rep but then switching reps
you've got sort of crappy information
that sort of you're getting uh kind of
quite messy like timing uh and data
arrival stuff I mean the streams API for
example doesn't even give you a
timestamp when you get a call back so
trying to measure that
I'm thinking sort of signals or
something like that from relays that
could then help that but
a cool cool idea to get some signals
from the relay to help that I hadn't
thought about that I had thought a lot
about given this is all running in user
space the quick and all of this is
running in user space and application I
was hoping that this working group at
some point would be sending some
requests over to the quick working group
to expose some API information that we
can use uh for example the current you
know bitrate estimate that the quick
layer has which would be really useful
for
um yeah I mean that's a constant kind of
thing net info API has been sort of like
in and out of uh yeah like it's not
really kind of flying anywhere apart
from chrome and uh so that kind of thing
is
tricky uh it seems yeah but there's such
a huge advantage to having a lower level
feedback on the the information allows
you to react much quicker which allows
you to deliver a much better end user
experience and I think that that's one
of the things that we need to optimize
the group is well you know
yeah
this information is all in the same
computer but our layer stacking has
caused us to have not have the
information we need that would allow us
to deliver a much better end user
experience that's nuts yeah yeah it's
true although sometimes in some ways
there is actually information that's at
the server the relay that the client
doesn't actually have like the kind of
effectively the sea wind
um you know how to draw transport info
that basically tried to do that
um but uh yeah that we've got some stuff
in cmsd that potentially does something
like that but
uh but anyway so we should drive all of
that discussion forward it's a great
discussion I think very important thank
you okay so uh we started out with 12
we've had uh seven people at the mic and
now we have ten so I would like to say
we're gonna close the queue very quickly
here so if you think you're going to
have comments on this probably go ahead
and get into queue well it's pure uh
sorry will next yeah thank you uh will
the lack of my I'll be quick I agree
with the vast majority of the points
presented here I I think Mark has the
luxury of looking back at 12 years of
Dash on hls which used relays in a very
similar context and look at what would
we have what should we have added to
those formats in the very beginning that
would really help with operations today
and there's two aspects that that are
not the the attractive ones we like to
talk about one is request tracing being
able to debug as soon as you're going
through components owned by different
people in multi-cdns how do you know
where a problem's occurring so request
tracing tracking where it went and then
also logging if you ask people today
what is a quick or web transport log
look like uh you're going to get 50
different answers so we might start
thinking about standardizing that so
that if you are collecting logs from
five different cdns operating your
relays that they're going to be
consistent
thank you I love it and I hope whoever's
taking minutes got all of that
Corey
since he's our uh our minute taker you
can ask him whether he got all of that I
saw from his face that he was doing his
best but not I tried yeah going first I
was just going to say and we'll talk
about the intermediary being a relay
there's probably some interaction with
the network that was that might be
possible can we take that to transport
area tsbwg or something and talk about
that completely separate to talking
about the relay but if you're exposing
things in the real way then maybe
something to the network might turn out
to be the right thing to do
100 agree Mo touched on that earlier and
you're the person that helps us do that
all in the past with every other media
protocol we've done I hope we can get
you involved again
yeah Stefan Wagner regarding the
dependency indication question you post
um
this is very very tricky the one reason
why previous dependency indications in
the video coding standards nh64 uh had
two bits for some priority thing never
worked out was because there was no
defined uh Behavior what to do with
these two things and with these two bits
and therefore people set them anyway if
they wished and no one cared about them
at the end even if the encoder choose to
do that so this particular problem here
for this protocol is even harder because
we now have
um different media types some of which
we don't even fully understand that the
lifetime of this protocol is probably
larger than the full understanding of
what you need say for hat takes uh type
of
priorities or whatever right so the um
my recommendation there is to have a
single one-dimensional now number not
any for complex dependency graphs with B
frames or whatnot but the single number
with a limited range and a defined
behavior of how a Gateway reacts to this
number and then the encoders uh and the
the sending mechanisms can figure out
how to set this accordingly thank you
thank you that sounds like a really good
advice for us
Luke from twitch uh I was just on up
there but um my day job is I work on the
CDN team
um so I've thought about this a little
quite a bit
um one thing that I'm grappling with
internally is just how successful HTTP
and HTTP cdns have been because they're
stateless the idea being is we have
millions of viewers across thousands of
streams and we don't care like we you
don't actually need to keep track of
them it just kind of funnels all the way
through so I'd like to have more thought
about how much state do we really need
in the system how much state do we need
for media for quick and how much can we
defer
um like for example slide one the origin
is the final decision maker probably
wouldn't work at scale
um for this uh point we that's that's
one thing I want people to think about
so look before we walk away totally
totally agree but I want people to I
constantly have people tell me it's
stateless and I'm like oh how do I
request something they're like oh you
give us the URI and from the URI we know
given the state we store what to deliver
to you I mean it's it's I mean stateless
is a wonderfully bizarre term to use in
the context of a file server right so it
is stateless but I think that the thing
that the point 100 agree with you on is
we have to really carefully think about
what the state is there's TLS State
there's all kinds of State in the
servers we need to really think about
the state and how we make high
reliability cheap scalable systems uh
you know how we engineer that and get it
um we decided the state at the start of
the broadcast when somebody joins and
then we just encode them the URL and
from that point forward it just follows
a fixed path more or less so yeah pretty
simple yeah exactly which sounds like we
could do the same thing here yeah
foreign
poly can you go back one side to the
security sure give me just a second here
there we go yeah I think the another
point that the quick stream is one two
one I think there is a drop about a
multicaster quick you need to make a
quick become the one to earn so if we
use that we may be able to do the end to
end quake and for the metadata maybe we
can put it in the
outside of the quick uh of course you
need to encrypt it yeah
thank you for correcting me then I was
unaware of this multicast quick work I'd
love to read more about it and it seems
like this might be a prime use case for
it if it all works I just this is a my
mistake on this slide and I will pick
yeah and and I think during the end to
end quick may enable very nice Stadium
uh kind of because Renee doesn't have to
decrypt all the quick quick package you
don't need to look at metadata it's very
small amount of computation Maybe
interesting okay
can can you send a link to that work to
maybe the the chat room or something
in the mailing list yeah the mailing
list
Randall Jessup Mozilla
um uh plus one to what's uh Stephen
Winger was saying I was going to say
something similar
um I think that what this does is it
helps push the
um the complexity on the choice of the
priorities and so on out to the
application which will allow for future
you know changes and improvements in in
what's going to happen there whether it
actually comes down to a single number
or not I wouldn't want to decide now but
I do think we wanted to simplify and
tightly Define what the relays are going
to operate on uh so that so that then
you can innovate at the edge at the
edges
thanks Randall 100 agree I I that makes
sense to me and all the input from you
and others here has really convinced me
which way Direction I want to go on this
so
hello
um Ian sweat Google
um as a person who spent a ton of time
trying to kill hp2 priorities
um I actually would make an opposite
argument here and say that I don't think
we should immediately assume because
HTTP 2 priority was like a complete
dumpster fire
um that it actually applies and my
argument is as follows so one is in hp2
the client is attempting to guess what
the correct prioritization scheme is
here the producer of the content knows
the structure uh of the Gap and it
understands the premium dependency there
is no it's unambiguous it's absolutely
like it knows it or not
um another thing is we had things like
reprioritization there's no need for
reprioritization there's no redirect
re-parent things that do all the things
that are very complex
um and for example like in hb2 when you
cancel the stream everything under it
got like re-parented automatically hero
would argue either you don't allow that
at all or if you do allow it you just
basically like kaibox the whole Stream
So you because they're all dependencies
you can just like kill that entire tree
you don't need to wait and like trying
to re-parent it and all those things
um so because we understand the use case
I think it's a completely tractable
problem to use trees however I also will
say I'm not sure it actually provides a
huge amount of value over like the
stream per Gap approach
um and so I think that's something for
the working group to decide is whether
the marginal complexity is actually
worth it um but I don't think it's I
think it's a completely different
situation from hp2 because the problem
is different
um who's sending the information is
different
um like again a huge problem with hp2
was Firefox had a prioritization scheme
that it kind of like invented based on
like looking at the spec and trying to
figure out how to use it but like there
was no right answer like everyone did
something different on the client side
none of them were right and most of them
didn't work particularly well here
we have a fairly authoritative answer on
what the right prioritization is at
least within a gap so those are my
thoughts um thanks
thank you a quick question uh I showed
that you were trying to to uh request
the screens uh did you actually have
something you meant to be showing or is
that just a that was a fat finger okay
no worries thanks
thanks Karen for bringing everyone on
the same page on what relay on some of
the requirements we need here a couple
of points uh I agree on the state
argument that you and Luke made we need
to make sure we keep the state as
minimal as possible as it helps for the
distribution uh anything other than that
we need to kind of discuss in the group
and see if we really need it or not uh
second thing uh on I want to Echo what
Randall and Stefan said on the
dependency or prioritization scheme
whatever we do relay should not be made
to aware of each and every video Codec
and dependencies they bring in they
should be asked me agnostic as possible
but should be able to give minimal
information to make a forwarding or drop
decision and if you can come up with
something that fits that requirement
that would be easy to build scalable
relays uh last part is that I don't see
uh you're talking about how the clients
would pre-warned relays uh in case
whether they wanted multiple qualities
so that they can easily switch between
different qualities maybe have you
talked about it but missed but something
that we need to keep in mind on how can
relays kind of of subscribe to various
qualities so that when our client uh
because of what our Network conditions
goes to different qualities it would be
quick rather than going through all the
way uh through chain of fillers to get
the qualities if needed at some point
right um yeah I carefully just avoid it
in my my
um my slides the whole topic of sort of
naming or or that that evil subscribe
word or anything like that
um but I mean one way or another we will
need to be able like all of these things
imagine that we'll be able to you know
something could express it could get a a
consumer could get a 4K stream and it
could realize they didn't have the
bandwidth and switch down to a 1K you
know a 720p stream or something I mean I
clearly we need to deal with that in the
working group I just didn't feel we had
the right drafts and agreements in place
to really hit that problem yet so we'll
need to figure out that that type of
stuff down the road a little bit but I
just sort of chose for that for the
limited time to kick that can down the
road a little bit
uh
here
uh on the topic of congestion control
there's nothing stopping a native or
mobile app that's using a quick library
from getting to information
about the congestion control however for
a web client which I assume you will
want some
web clients that do Ingress into the
into a relay
um you do need an API that can expose
information luckily we are working on
that in the web transport uh working
group in the w3c so if there are
specific things you need beyond what
we're already doing there that might be
a good thing to uh ask for similarly on
priorities I think we've mostly been
talking about priorities
that are sent to the relay but there's
also the question of the local
prioritization
um of streams uh at the at the client
and that also relates to a web client
API and that's also a topic in
discussion in the web transport to be 3C
working group
so um if
there are things that need to be
requested of another uh working group
that might be the w3c web transport
region group lastly
um
oh I forgot I'm sorry let me see if I
can remember
uh nope it's gone so Peter before you
get to your last thing just 100 agree
what you said and I might ask you if you
could just send a little bit an email to
the list here I mean I know you're
deeply involved with all that stuff you
can just send a little email to the list
with with pointers to people where they
might be able to read a little bit more
about what's going on there um I think
that that would be I mean this this
group's gonna have to have a Synergy
with you know transport uh web transport
uh quick uh and so getting people aware
that would be awesome
I could do that oh I did remember the
third thing the third thing is
um basically everybody wants
implementations of quick that have a
real-time friendly congestion control
algorithm and I haven't really seen one
yet
um and I think that in order to write
one for example if I were to Port the
Weber typical webrtc one called googcc
over to Quick uh it would require some
more time stamp for information in the
feedback messages and that I've seen two
drafts for that uh proposals for adding
that as a quick extension but I don't
think either one is
you know progressed a lot so that might
be another thing that might be a request
to see one of those progress
so a 100 agree with that I think we do
need to move that over along over time
for this group to be successful I don't
think it can be done in this group I
think we probably need to take that
somewhere else but the people here can
and you know probably are the same
people that need to do it to somewhere
else and explain what our needs and why
the current bbrv2 doesn't quite work but
what could be or whatever it is that
we're going to decide to do to have
better congestion control for our
applications I do think this application
will that I do think that media over
quick will work reasonably well with
today's uh congestion control but it
could work much better with slight
changes to the congestion control that
we should try and get from the
appropriate working groups or something
so that's another thing that we should
poke on moving forward 100 agree and
just you know maybe now that this is
really moving and is real it's an
incentive for the people who have those
drafts to to resurrect them and get that
going again
next
stanhurst BBC R D
um so it's not specifically a comment on
your on your presentation which is great
by the way but more uh something which
keeps coming up in other comments that
people have been making and I wanted to
make sure it got captured somewhere we
need to make sure that we don't end up
focusing on frames as a unit so I love
the idea of walk being able to
arbitrarily chop up gops and have
different numbers of frames within one
stream we've got to be careful because
when you're thinking about audio what
what's the application data unit there
and is that a sample and if we end up
just having a new sample per stream
we're going to use up streams like
there's no tomorrow
um and there's also then other media
types like what do we do with subtitles
what do we do with haptics which is a
new one coming through we just need to
make sure that we don't specify that
there's one for every Adu uh and give
the ability to have more than one of
those and then how do we synchronize
them but that's an entirely different
not that's an entirely different topic
great Point 100 agree and we tend to
over rotate on video and forget about
other things but yeah
hi Jonathan Lennox I mean uh something
that I was thinking about when the
medical case was mentioned and generally
like the case of if you're trying to
you know essentially live stream a
conference
um is the case where you will have cases
where we have in where we have media
from Independent Media sources we
probably want to send those over the
same mock connection for prioritization
reasons and we need to make sure we
think about that both for prioritization
then for the protocol to figure out
how that works and I just want to make
sure that's
you know on everybody's mind as they
develop this
yeah and I think that that uh comes up
and as you said in the the conferencing
scenarios but it also comes up in the ad
insertion scenarios
um but yeah that we need to keep that in
mind
uh I think we have an empty queue
thank you everyone much appreciated for
all the people showing up here today
moving this long and I will pass it back
to the chairs for whatever happens next
uh thank you very much and thanks
everybody who was at the mic line or
commenting in the chat I I will say if
if we're seeing this level of engagement
on the mailing list we would be having a
weekly uh interim calls so please do uh
bring these same uh issues up now that
we've we've kicked off the working group
uh on the mailing list or in the uh
appropriate repos and we can go from
there
um
uh pull up the
get the chair slides back up so we can
go on to the next thing
all right uh so before we get to aob
which will uh which will possibly
include uh Spencer's presentation which
he gave us as a backup a quick question
on uh possible interim uh and I think we
can run this as a poll I'm going to try
and do that in a second
um we think there's a a lot that's
that's happened here today in a lot of
discussion that have been kicked off at
the previous interim and so we'd like to
think about having maybe an in-person
interim over a couple of days uh What uh
Alan and I have been discussing is late
January of 2023 that's that's next year
surprisingly
um and
um the U.S West Coast uh there are a
couple of people already in queue so you
have clarifying questions or comments
before we run the poll
okay please please go up Spencer
anything we would do would of course be
hybrid not only in person but Spencer
you had a clarifying mode did you have a
clarifying question
I don't know if you can still get from
it so uh mozamati I was going to ask in
the prior interim we identified two
major points of discussion that we
wanted to try to cover either in person
this week or you know in the in the near
term that was the congestion control and
prioritization aspects and then media
formats we haven't started the media
formats discussion is that going to be a
focus of this in interim or do do we
want to start that just on list and not
uh so I think we can understand it a
little bit uh today when people were
reminding us and including Stefan and
and others that we need to consider
media formats Beyond video uh and not uh
not only video but I definitely agree
that we need to have uh deeper
discussions of those on on audio video
and potentially
um upcoming uh it might or might not be
at this interim we if we get agree in an
interim then we'll start the agenda
bashing so you don't have a specific
agenda for this interim yet uh no we
think there's plenty to talk about so
we'll be list discussion to to hash out
who can be there in person and in
particular which topics we people will
have drafts or or similar to uh Spencer
uh Spencer Dawkins uh I've made this
coming in chat but uh I I you know I
don't know the chairs have been able to
keep up with everything that's happened
in chat
um the
the
you might want to also poll on how many
interim meetings and I I'm I was
thinking virtual interims uh between now
and Yokohama
um and it I had a couple of thoughts
about possible uh topics and neither one
of those was the one most suggested so
um I you you all are talking about a
in-person interim yes please that would
be lovely but uh
I I would I would suggest that you uh
wait for the working group to make
progress on the mailing list as opposed
to when
slack or you know something like that
um
before uh you decide that we only need
one
uh I could see multiple reasons why you
might need
two or three but let's let's ignore that
for now
okay I have suhaus and Cullen behind you
in line and then we're going to run the
poll
um I think we can at least figure out
whether we want zero or one and if it
grows beyond one we can continue that
discussion but uh just a clarifying uh
thought here uh Luke's presentation had
some of the next things that we want to
do that might be a starting list we can
think of the possible topics and and
also depending upon the topic we might
uh get a different audience and and we
need to make sure that we have the Right
audience in the meeting if not it will
not be useful thanks
Cullen
uh love to have them but I think the
really important thing asked us is
January late January is incredibly close
when you consider the holidays and
everything so I think we should nail
down the dates soon if we're going to do
this like before the end of November
type soon
that's partly why we want to to have the
poll run today
okay so the way I put this is if you if
we have an in-person interim in late
January 2020 through 2023 please assume
I said U.S West Coast here because
apparently I forgot to type it can you
attend either in person or virtually in
that time zone so please understand uh
that there any place we have this there
will be support for
um remote attendees but that that time
zone late January uh
raise your hand now uh if you can do not
raise your hand if you are not available
there and we will see how it goes
foreign
so so far only about a third of the
people in this room have either raised
their hand or clicked do not raise hand
so please go ahead and
do one or the other as quickly as you
can thank you
okay the numbers are starting to change
pretty slowly I'm going to close this
off in 30 seconds
okay so uh certainly quite a few people
were able to do it the raised hands were
52 that do not raise hands 10. that's a
significant number uh so what we'll do
is go ahead and come up with a concrete
suggestion on the list Alan and I have
the token to do that
um it looked like there was somebody in
the queue but who may have since dropped
okay
so we do have a couple of uh minutes
there and there was a uh update on the
mock use cases and requirement stock
uh Spencer do you want to do a quick run
through that
temperatures
so I'm Spencer Dawkins uh I want to call
people's attention to the picture of
this on this on the cover slide pretty
maybe more than anything else you know
the idea that use cases would interact
with requirements and that those would
uh Drive protocol specifications if
that's that's if that's uh shocked
anybody please
tell us now our next slide please
um
so what we said we were going to do was
uh
work on
basically dragging out a lot of stuff
that was in the individual
draft for
um require for use cases and
requirements uh that would not belong
there some of them were talking about
things were not in the approved Charter
and some of them were just history and
observations and opinions
um and so what we did was update the use
cases section well we updated the draft
this way and
um
went to update the we were thinking
update the use cases to reflect working
group discussion on the slide three
questions from uh the from the uh for
October interim there wasn't actually
any discussion of those questions from
the for children uh so uh we submitted
Dash zero three and uh
Forex for extra credit uh did a proposal
of uh initial structure of the
requirements section uh based on our
understanding of the implicit
requirements that they're into
approved Charter which was based on uhas
uh understanding all right next slide
please
yeah
so uh yeah that
um
so and like I say added a little uh
introductory text in each subsection of
the uh the requirement section
um next slide please
um
so this is uh I did talk with
um James Michael author uh since we got
the uh comments from Cullen uh that were
that appeared on the mailing list thank
you for those calling
um so uh so thinking we would do a-04
revision before requesting that the
chairs would uh adopt anything
um and then basically after something
that uh the working group can adopt we
would be drilling down to the next level
of detail in use cases index level
structure in the requirement section
next slide please
um
so I did have some questions there like
I say which we will follow up on the
Mike mailing list uh for all of these uh
we were trying to
we were trying to categorize uh the
live media of uh gaming and video
conferencing use cases uh and then think
about that some more again we'll follow
up on the mock mailing list anyway and
once we get to that point uh
talk about any additional use cases that
would need to use a simple low latency
media delivery solution for ingest and
distribution
um
as we mentioned earlier there's those
are out there but the ones we would be
we would need to know about is our use
cases through all our own capabilities
we have not previously identified uh
next slide
and so we had basically a high level
structure from our understanding of
zuhas's high-level structure from the
interim meeting and uh which I really
appreciate
and they're basically agree on a
starting line for that the requirements
and then proceed in the usual issue PR
emerge way on GitHub is that my last
slide I try to remember
no we are not
um
I like I said uh Cullen sent uh comments
that were uh helpful enough to where uh
we would need to you know James and I
both agreed we need to do a dash 04
before asking people to look at it
seriously and we're committed to do that
in the relatively near term
um and uh
any other thoughts
okay okay that's everything I know thank
you
uh thank you very much Spencer note that
we will not be waiting to an interim
meeting before issuing a call for
adoption on this once we've gotten the
mailing list discussion uh to a point
where we feel like the working group is
ready we'll issue with a call for
adoption on the list so please do
continue to uh join us on the list so
that you can do that we have reached the
11 24 Mark and the question is is there
anything else for the good of the order
sorry thanks David skanazi process
Enthusiast apparently uh no just uh I
wanted to provide a small suggestion to
the chairs uh because um this reminds me
of when we did a requirement stock in
mask and it was helpful
um but we uh ended up not publishing it
which was quite disappointing for some
of the folks working on it so just they
make that clear at the beginning whether
or not you plan to just have it and not
publish it or if you're going to publish
it as an RFC both are valid options but
I would make that clear during the
adoption calls so no one's surprised
uh thank you for that point
um certainly uh as people are commenting
on in the run up to adoption uh you can
consider that but
um and and make comments on that then
even in advance uh back to the previous
question is there anything else for the
good of the orders
there was someone else
okay uh
thank you all for all of the great
conversation uh both in the lines uh
remotely and on the chat today uh we
look forward to seeing you on the list
thanks again
different
ly
foreign