thank you
okay so audio is the mic on this mic is
working right
not that we really need it but for the
extremes the remote stream we do
and this one's working well this one's
definitely working okay
oh yeah
audience mic test
mm-hmm
osphere
we'll get started in a moment or two I'm
waiting for
um Eric who's going to help me co-chair
this
foreign
because I don't know
the other thing while we're getting
started um is there anybody ordinarily
ditch or helps take notes but Dieter is
not well today so I was wondering if
anybody else would be willing to help
take notes
anyone
excuse me
okay
foreign
so we will go ahead and get started
um
as I mentioned ditter is not feeling
well so we wish him a speedy recovery
um
this is the ntp working group
welcome to the last session of
the week for ietf 115.
um
and thank you for everybody who is still
here at the end of the week
this is the note well which you've seen
all week
you agree to this when you register for
the IHF it's the set of rules and
processes that govern the the way the
ITF operates so please make sure you are
familiar with it you have agreed to
abide by it
and if you have any questions feel free
to see diatri or Eric r a d also I'd
like to remind everybody that we want to
uh trying to we want to abide by the
code of conduct and basically be nice to
everybody
so our agenda for today
um this
uh
is this is the agenda for today it's up
on the notes pad
um if somebody
a little bit faster on the link wants to
stick the link into the you should be
able to find it from the agenda page on
the ietf you'll see which one is the
notepad or somebody could stick it into
chat for folks that are unfamiliar with
that particular thing feel free to add
to the notes as we go
that will be turned into the minutes at
the end so
uh with that
are there any is there any agenda
bashing any comments or questions
nope
okay
so the first thing is uh we have our
document status review update page
reminding us of the things that we are
working on
um
the uh first thing is we do
a second thing I did forget uh I'm sure
by Friday everybody knows this please be
sure to scan the QR code that's what
we'll use to manage the queue and it
also does the attendance or the virtual
blue sheets so don't forget to do that
um we do have a new RFC
RFC 9327 which is the control messages
protocol for the use with ntp V4 this uh
has been published as a historic RFC in
the category historic as opposed to
experimental informational or any of
those things so um
a special thank you to Brian Haberman
um and to Eric for a great deal of
patience uh in getting this through the
process we have three more documents
that have sort of passed the working
group
um and into
um at fdiesg in various stages uh the
first one is the interleave modes
which we
believe we're basically going to defer
to V5 but we wanted to discuss did you
want to talk about that
works
words words are always good
uh yes so Eric client the um interleave
modes we brought it to the telechat it
got uh um
One Security ad abstained uh and some
other people were very operational
people were very concerned about the
safety
uh my proposal was that if we wanted to
continue with the document we should
I think the why this is safe stuff is is
spread out through each different
possible mode description and it might
be worth reiterating all of that in a
one common section before that that says
look this is really not scary and not
only is it not scary it's actually
running now and
and things haven't blown up
uh but uh if we you know we could do
that and then I can bring it back to
telechat if we want or we could not
pursue interleaved modes for V4 anymore
and just leave that as a feature to be
baked in from the beginning for V5
that's whatever the the authors and the
working group wants to do I don't know
so but uh Lars is pinging me saying hey
why what are you going to do with this
so uh it's currently in some limbo State
basically between maybe we'll do
something with it and maybe we'll
abandon it but if we get to know what
the working group wants to do one way or
the other
right so I think we we
um
we basically have have two options one
would be to send it back to the working
group and then to update it
um with the additional safety
information in a more concise manner
like you're talking about or we declared
a dead document and then just plan to
work on it as far as
data tracker statuses go those are our
two options right uh well for the first
one bringing you back to the working
group is an option uh it could also just
be handled by
the author uh you know I mean it depends
on on how significant we think it is if
it's a restating of text that already
exists and has consensus then uh we're
just like copying that and putting it
out into one place for clarity I don't
think that has to come back to the
working group because we haven't changed
anything okay uh if we do decide to
dramatically alter something the meaning
of something or whatever then yeah we
would probably read back to the working
group but I think it can be treated as
editorial oh okay uh and it could just
be handled by the author and just reply
to the people who have the feedback at
this point the document has changed
telechat has changed iesgs
uh so the objections were from some
previous members who are no longer on
the ESG so I would have to bring it back
to telechat but Miroslav could just take
some edits and
we could bring it back okay I'll try
again
and and marisolv has conveniently
already joined the queue go ahead
marisloff
oh hi uh yeah
I think
at that time this was discussed last
time I think there was a suggestion to
try to change it to an informational
document and that would be more likely
to
be accepted by isg
[Music]
is this still an option or
would it be would it make it more likely
to work
um I I think some I mean possibly I
don't know what would change the minds
of of everybody who still holds uh
concerns
I think the main concern from the Ops
ads
was that they they did not believe it
was safe to do they were not convinced
that it was that that widespread
um problems would would not happen uh so
I think they just needed some my
impression or my recollection is that
they just needed some convincing they
needed some reassurance
so uh I don't know that changing the
informational is required
so I think it was more about wait wait
wait wait wait why is this safe how is
this not going to break everything it
didn't really
they weren't able to glean that easily
from the document and if we made it easy
for them to see that it was in fact safe
that was that was
that's my current understanding yeah I
don't think the status of the document
necessarily would change that
information
sorry it's still they might still be
concerned about safety
how do you write do you like this
version of the draft that has a new
section on the safety of the protocol I
think this was published after the last
round of discussion so I'm not sure if
they
cylinder
I'm not actually sure if I if I know
that you had uploaded a new version if
you have then I can go chase down people
to to re-review it
well it's a few years ago so I'm not
sure
I
okay that's on me then I will take I
will take the action item to go review
the diff
and uh and then chase down people's
additional uh re-reviews
okay thanks
so so marislav
did I understand you correctly you
uploaded a draft that addressed that or
did you send an email with a suggestion
I think I
I told long ago that I'm not sure
anymore but this was after the
the email discussion we'd have we had
with isg
and I I haven't seen any anyone
responding to that so I'm not sure if
anyone actually read it
um
I can I can take the action item too
catch up on all the threads and make
sure that everybody has uh seen all the
new proposed texts whether it's in email
or in document form I'll do that okay
all right thank you marislav
so I think the
so you're going to check on the status
but the plan is to still continue to try
and publish and not to defer
hmm
yeah that's what that's what I heard
okay okay we might as well uh take
another run at it and and see what
happens
if everyone if if everyone's hair is
still on fire then we'll we can
reevaluate after the after the second
attempt
okay
um
so that's where we are with interleave
modes uh updating the ntp Registries uh
has been
uh submitted and uh
is in the process of being reviewed and
the Enterprise profile has been
submitted but it's still lacking a
Shepherd right up so
oh you did an ad eval and it has a
revised
um
yeah I think the tick tock uh doc I I
reviewed and I gave some comments and
I'm waiting for a new version to be
uploaded which possibly I missed in my
inbox but uh yeah yeah I know I don't
there has not been an an updated draft
okay
so I missed that you did a Navy eval so
I thought I sent some comments I'll
double check that too I'm sure you did
and I missed it
and that can go to ietf last call as
soon as there's a new version as soon as
we get a new version on it okay great
uh so this one
so updating ntp Registries is waiting on
Eric to double check and Enterprise
profile is uh waiting on the authors to
submit an updated draft
um
so that's where we are with all of those
the next
uh
set of topics these are all things that
we've had some at least a little bit of
discussion on since the last meeting uh
for Kronos uh
uh Netta is on the call this has
a past working group last call and all
of the comments have been addressed and
the latest draft address is the last of
the typos that were found is that that's
correct right Neda
so I think it's it is random right now
I hate to do this to you could you say
that one more time please
uh sorry
um yeah I I fixed the type of that
Denmark was found and I also went over
the draft once again top down to see
that to make sure that everything was
clear
so I think
um and and looking at the slides here I
realized that I forgot to change the C
to a k so for those who who are who are
following this work at a distance uh the
name got changed from Kronos with a c to
Kronos with a K uh because of some uh
conflict issues uh we're not going to
change the file name uh itself but it
will be changed in the documents and in
the title
with that uh Dieter and I talked earlier
this week and
this is ready to go to the isg and he is
going to manage the shepherd right up
for that
how much
did you have you had nothing did you
have anything else you wanted to say on
the Kronos
nope
okay
um
so the next thing we're going to talk
about is ntpv5 on a number of topics uh
the
first thing we're going to talk about is
our we did have a small
hackathon team here on the weekend and
David's going to talk about what they
did
okay hello I'm David
um uh during the hackathon we spend a
bunch of time on entity particularly uh
next slide please focusing around
the the main problem questions of
can we build uh
experimental interoperable
implementations for this and are there
any major technical gaps uh in the draft
as it currently stands
um the results we have next slide please
uh for that are there is now two
experimental implementations one of
these existed already before the weekend
continuous labs and the other one came
about mostly this weekend
um we verified that they are indeed
talking happily to each other they seem
to be synchronizing all the loop
um detection algorithms which is the
main part of what we're now focusing on
where what the current draft mostly
focused on uh initially seems to be
functioning correctly seems to be
reasonably easy to implement across
implementations
um
so we've identified a few minor issues
in the ntpdrs implementation uh these
have since been fixed and a few more
have been found since the hackathon and
have also been fixed so if you were
using it for whatever reason uh there
are updates available now again
um and we've also had uh We've
identified a few minor
things as well with the draft but we'll
get to that in a minute and we've had a
lot of discussions on time skills and
leap seconds because those are fairly
hard and I will get to those
at least to some extent later as well
um next slide please
so the main takeaways we've had is that
time scale offsets especially for ut1
with uh as they currently stand in the
draft won't fully work
particularly should in the future it
ever get decided that UTC moves away
from having leap seconds as at that
point the ut1 offset would be larger
than one second in the current draft
just assumes it's below a second
and we've identified that there is a
need still for a case of that type
mechanism that was an ntp before it also
have like an 1955 and that we need to
start adding that to the current draft
um
these were the main takeaways next slide
please so these were the people who were
involved in the hackathon and a short
list of links for all of the main things
that were touched during the hackathon
for those interested are there any
questions about anything I've said so
far
no questions
uh thank you all very much
it was very productive
um
okay
I don't
I don't see James in the meeting there
has not been an update to the use cases
and requirements document there has been
some discussion about uh needing some
more detail and and the feeling that
we're not quite hitting the hard issues
yet
um
and
we would like to wrap this up I was
sort of hoping to wrap it up by the end
of the year I think we probably ought to
Target the um
next meeting that the next uh physical
meeting so maybe the Yokohama ietf if we
could Target having that at least sent
to the iesg that would be really helpful
does anybody have any comments on the
use cases and requirements has anybody
reviewed it recently
oh wait
you can walk that way
uh hi David again
um there there's one thing
um I think we should still work on
getting a little bit tighter
on what our priorities are going to be
around synchronization performance
versus security uh in the in the
protocol in the requirements document
uh because I think we're going to at
some point have to make trade-offs in in
that and it would
I think we need to think about those
beforehand uh before we start getting
down into the weeds but
um are there any thoughts on that from
commercial in particular
foreign
do you have any comments on the oh he's
joining excellent
[Music]
I think you are referring to the
correction field which wouldn't be
authenticated maybe this is the
discussion we had I think on the
hackathon
if we need to
authenticate everything or if it's
acceptable for the correction field
because that would be difficult for
Implant to implement in the networking
devices too
re-authenticate
10 DB message if it was modified so
there is a question if
if it's acceptable to make some fields
um
outside of the
authenticated payload
um in my opinion
I think that's okay because
the impact that
an attacker a man in the middle attacker
could have
by modifying the data in the
unauthenticated
part of the message is still smaller
than
the impact
that for example the delay attack has
basically
delaying the message as a bigger impact
on the
measurement of the client then
uh
would have the
the modification in the unauthenticated
part in the correction field
as long as the client
verifies that the correction is not
larger than the measured delay
so yeah my opinion is that
this is okay but maybe others don't
share this with you
um yeah to respond to that that is one
aspect I think we should consider but
also in general when we start
introducing
mandatory signing which is one of the
things the the requirements now
pretty much hints I thought we should do
um you're going going to add crypto
crypto to the uh response
uh the request response path at the
server which is gonna inevitably add
additional resonance time on the server
side
which
will impact some of the uncertainty in
these algorithms
for synchronizing everything and I think
we should we should we should be
thinking about what what Traders are we
willing to make there
um
they're there as well as in
do do we find that an acceptable
trade-off uh
and and how how are we going to be
looking at that moving forward
go ahead mayor sloth
there is with the internet there should
be no impact on
on accuracy or stability of the
synchronization
with respect to the great operations
that may take longer so I don't see
these are as a concern
okay Rick
foreign open Fortress
um I'm very happy that as if if the
cryptos actually made very strong
and because many cryptographic
algorithms base uh they really heavily
on time and this has been very very long
been a problem that we looked away from
it because that was nothing that really
allowed us to synchronize with
cryptographical strength it's an
important thing to have proper timing
and to be sure about it
so please don't make any trade-offs in
that respect and especially if you can
just measure the signing time and take
that make the part of your calculation
any anything else on this topic
um
I think given the uh
I think what we're going to need to do
that this document is fairly solid I'll
check with James and see
we might need to do a working group last
call to see if we can get people to
review it for the last time
in the meantime feel free please to
review it on the mailing list that would
be great
all right the next topic is the ntp V5
specification this has been stable for
quite a while
um
and we now have two interoperable
implementations it's been out for
a call for adoption
I've heard no opposition to the fact
that we plan to adopt this document so
with that we will be
adopting it as a working group document
is there any comments or questions on
that
okay I'll do the data tracker magic
later today and marislav if when you get
a chance if you want to
submit an updated draft with the working
group name on it that would be great
okay
um the next item was a discussion of
time scales
um as as David hinted there was some
discussion of this at the hackathon so I
think it's top of mind
go ahead
ali
um
yeah so after having a couple of
discussions with a number of people I
started to realize that the requirements
document is not as clear
as the opinion some individuals might
have as to which approach we're going to
take
for uh time skills essentially there's
from from what I've been able to tell
and please correct me if I'm wrong on
this uh mayor swath there's there's
roughly two approaches we can take here
we can
um say that all-time stamps included in
in ntp exchanges
are always time stamped according to
whatever best approximation a server has
of one specific time skill for example
Thai or for example UTC
and then we provide sufficient
information
in addition to those timestamps to be
able to get to whatever time scale an
end user might want to use
depending on what asks for or there's
the approach and this is the approach
that's as I understand it is currently
in the draft is we leave these
timestamps essentially
leave it open which time scale that is
on the protocol packet of course
specifies this but there's not all ntp5
package used this time scale for their
um for the timestamps and then
optionally on top of that provide the
mechanism for exchange of information on
how to translate between these different
time skills
um
I I think we should have the discussion
which of these we prefer
um perhaps that is a discussion for the
mailing list
um I'm
but I I think we need to explore what
the advantages and disadvantages of each
of these approaches are because
um
I don't have a full feeling for which
option we should choose at this point
go ahead Miroslav
oh yeah I would like to add that my
focus was on to allowing the server
to have a preferred time scale because
you know in the basic mode the time
critical
part is between uh capturing the
timestamp
from the clock that the server is using
and
putting that in to the message so
the idea was that
the server could have a preferred time
scale which could use for the transmit
timestamp and for the other timestamps
because it's simpler
to
specify it and implement it and if the
client
needs a different time scale than yeah
it should be able to get the missing
information to convert the plans
into its own preferred time scale
so
you know the focus was on the server
side to make it
easier to implement
the protocol by allowing the server to
to use for example for instance Hardware
timestamping where
it might not be possible to implement
UTC
only without leap seconds so
the client would need to be able to
convert it
to UTC if the server is providing
timestamps in time
any thoughts on this topic from anybody
else
anybody else online
I know 1588 has done a fair amount of
work looking at Alternatives time time
scales as well so we should probably
make it take a look at what they're
doing to make sure that anything we do
would at least be aligned somewhat with
what they're doing
um because a lot of ntp and PTP systems
need to coexist
um
okay
um so that brings us to the end of our
ntpv5 list of topics the next agenda
item is rough time the last
um
update of the
I just lost my data try others the last
update of the rough time document was at
the end of September
um
I know Marcus had planned to have a
during the hackathon he had planned to
have a virtual hackathon effort there
were a number of parties that had
indicated interest
but they were all going to be remote
participants and at the end of it we
actually ended up with none of them
except for Marcus coming Christopher
from net node was here and was working
on it a little bit as well but um he
ended up focusing primarily on ntpb5
um
so we didn't have much activity during
the hackathon on rough time
um
and the authors of the document are not
here
so I think about the only thing that we
can do is ask for um
some additional comments and review on
the list I don't think there's been any
comments on the list of this document
since it was last published
um
is there anything
the other thing was is that the uh just
as a comment the rough time
ecosystem document has expired
so is there anybody here who wishes to
speak to rough time
oh hi Ben go ahead
hi there
um yeah we're quite interested in rough
time at Google and actually we've we've
just been going over the draft there's a
there's a group of us who are planning
to do some work on it uh we've gone over
the draft we got pilot comments which we
will a small pile of comments which
we'll post to the mailing list
um uh next week sometime uh and we are
planning to do an implementation
um of
some future ID when it's in the shape
we're happy with
uh we're planning to use it as part of
our work on supply chain security stuff
in general
oh thank you
good to know
um
so with that uh we'll look forward to
the Google comments coming on the
mailing list and if anybody else could
please review the document and put some
comments on the mailing list that would
be very helpful
anything else on rough time
okay
we have two pieces of work that we have
not had recent updates on the ntp over
PTP it has been out for a call for
adoption I've seen no opposition to
doing that and so at this stage we will
be adopting that document
um I'm assuming mayor slav you don't
have any comments you're just waiting
for us to adopt it correct
okay
um and the um
oh that's funny there's an edit a a copy
and paste error on my slide so ignore
everything after NTS over PTP
they might look suspiciously familiar as
the items that were under the document
update slide three slides ago
um
so the NTS over PTP effort there is
still interest in doing it the primary
author
um
was doing some collaboration with an
industry partner and they have not
gotten that update done yet
so there is no update to report
last I heard they were hoping to get
something out
in the November time frame so hopefully
we'll see something coming out of that
pretty soon
anything else on NTS over PTP
okay
um
so we have
any other business and Way Forward at
this stage
the any other business does anybody have
any other business that they'd like to
bring
oh
yeah sorry if this is like an aob moment
I just wanted to say two thank yous uh
one thank you to everybody who helped me
close out all of the
open erata that was super helpful and
very much appreciated uh and to uh thank
you to everyone who uh did some uh very
nice hackathon work that will be good to
show in the shepherd write-up that there
are interoperable implementations
so
thank you all
yes thank you
um
any other any other businesses
okay
um
as I mentioned earlier the attorney I
met earlier this week and and we're
discussing ways to keep us moving
forward on a more steady Pace
um
I think for the ntp working group in
particular sometimes the virtual
interims are a little bit more effective
just because
of the
the
they're more effective in keeping us
moving so we do plan to have uh some
virtual interims we're currently
planning three between now and the next
ietf those are our tentative dates
um
this will be in the minutes if anybody
has any
uh
strong objections to any of these dates
so please feel free to speak up it's
it's roughly a month or every month or
five weeks between now and the March
ietf meeting
the March ietf meeting is in Yokohama
we will be thinking about uh what we can
do in the context of a hackathon I think
the lesson we learned with NTS and that
we are relearning with ntpv5 is it
really helps to focus the work and move
it forward if we can have a little bit
of hackathon activity on the pro
protocol as we're moving forward
um so we'll be needing to figure out who
from the ntp community might actually be
able to participate in Yokohama or be
willing to participate remotely
on hackathon activity during Yokohama
working hours
so keep an eye out for that
the other thing that we have talked
about doing is I think we have
um
you know we're a little bit you know a
couple years into the deployment of NTS
and we're beginning to see some
deployment reports and experimental
results that we would like to talk about
and see how that's going and what
lessons it might teach us going forward
and so we are planning
um
to have
a discussion specifically focused on the
deployment status of NTS to see if we
can get some idea of who who's using it
and how they're using it what kinds of
results they're looking at
um
and so I I think since this is such a
new
protocol it would be really helpful to
get some perspectives on that
um
and with that is there any other
anything else people want to uh
bring to the floor
next time I'm going to bring popcorn or
something maybe maybe sugar snacks
that's what you need is sugar snacks
so with that uh I'm going to close the
ntp working group meeting for ietf 115.
everybody have a safe trip home and uh
hopefully we will see you virtually and
in person in the future
foreign
because
the important part
on Monday
oh that probably will
I am intending to be
happy
it's the first one that's reasonable
post for me
uh so that one's definitely doable
it would be really nice if I could swing
it but
MLS Joshua yeah
find out