foreign
welcome all to ohai
um
we are your chairs Siobhan and Richard
which is joining remotely
and uh
we have uh note takers I think Martin
and Sean
are going to help thank you so much
I'll put a link into the origin if you
can put a link into the chat for the for
the notes we'll do
yeah already
[Music]
um
this is the note Bell you've probably
seen it by now but please do note it
well uh it concerns um the patent policy
and
um and as a reminder like there is the
ombuds team that you should feel free to
reach out to
and also just specifically for
um this meeting there is the on-site
tool that you should be using that helps
um get numbers for it kind of serves as
a blue sheet
and it's also really helpful if you can
use that to join them IQ so that we can
be Equitable towards people joining
remotely as well uh helps with Cube
management essentially and also if
you're remote then make sure that your
audio and video are off unless you're
presenting
um
and
headset is always recommended and as a
reminder that if you're not speaking
then you you must wear a mask
um
and
yeah
I think that's everything so just to
make sure everyone knows the main
protocol draft for obliviously HTTP was
submitted and it's in the ad review
stage so that should be
hopefully getting published soon and
then we also adopted one new draft since
last meeting uh and Tommy's going to be
talking about that
and unless there's anything
to be said about the agenda
um going once going twice
I'll ask Tommy to present
all right
okay hello everyone
so
I'll be presenting our Discovery uh
draft and this is about uh bootstrapping
the use of an oblivious HTTP Gateway
uh using records that we find in DNS
this was discussed at the last ITF but
as it's newly adopted I'm going to give
a brief recap of the use case and how
the protocol looks
uh before we go into the open issues
okay so this if you saw the presentation
last time this should just be
a reminder but if you didn't uh the
Discovery Model
assumes that we have a client
that knows about a Target service that
it wants to
communicate with some HTTP service out
there and the client also knows about
one or more oblivious relays that it uh
is willing to work with or it has
credentials for or
what have you
and the target service
Also may have an oblivious Gateway that
it works with which
can be co-located with the target
service
um
but essentially you can think of this as
the target service is willing to be
accessed over oblivious http
so that clients that would prefer
oblivious access to direct access can
use it
and so the goal of the Discovery Model
is to let the client use some relay that
it knows about it or it selects to reach
the target through the Gateway that the
target indicates
um so this is the main model you can
have a variance of this where the client
is strict and will only communicate with
this target service
if it has an oblivious Gateway because
it's not willing to communicate directly
but either way works
so in order to do this we need a couple
different protocol mechanisms
and there are three of these that are
defined
in the draft
first is a DNS service binding parameter
and this can go within the svcb or https
DNS records
which is effectively just a Boolean
parameter that says this service has a
oblivious Gateway
foreign
the second mechanism is we have a
well-known URI
that is the URI for an oblivious Gateway
that is discovered in this manner
and the third mechanism is a way to
actually look up the oblivious key
configuration
on a Gateway URI which in the case of
Discovery here will be that well known
the reason the protocol has this shape
is that
we need to make sure that the discovered
Gateway and its config are actually
strictly bound to the Target because
access
to this target
through the Gateway is replacing any
other certificate evaluation other trust
you have in that Target and so you need
to prove that the Gateway has authority
over the target resource and this
effectively means that you have to
co-locate them
um at least in terms of something that
is able to uh do TLS termination for the
Target
and um past the normal client uh trust
evaluation
so as concrete examples
based on how the document currently
spells things we have an example of a
DNS response which
would have its normal
um svcb parameters it can have some alpn
but it adds a new parameter which is
oblivious here
the
um actual well-known location is dot
well known slash oblivious Gateway
and the way to get the key configuration
is to instead of doing a post you do a
get and you say that you accept
application ohtp keys and then you get
the key config
so it's quite simple
um
if you have questions
I guess we could take him now or at the
end but this is just a recap and we have
a couple different open issues that I
wanted to highlight
uh so first I think this was from Ben
was about the parameter name currently
it's named as oblivious he was pointing
out that this that is potentially too
broad you could have other things that
are oblivious in the future particularly
if you're using this not on the https
resource record
so the suggestion was to change it to
ohttp
that seems fine to me does anyone
have thoughts or objections or should we
just do it maybe
hi uh so after considering the the sort
of one of the other open issues here I
think that um I think let's park this
until we've solved some other things uh
in particular if we I that oblivious
changes the behavior of the DNS client
for example telling the DNS client to
not use DNS cookies then uh maybe we or
for example if it tells the DNS client
don't use other transports if they don't
support obliviousness then maybe it
actually is a cross-transport flag maybe
it is not HTTP specific so
uh I guess it's not clear to me yet
okay
all right so let's come back to this one
then and let's have the other discussion
the comments in the chat seem to be fine
with ohtp in principle so
Ben let's come back to this
so the next one uh
was a source of confusion and
was a problem of a lack of clarity and a
bit of confusion in the document that
needs to be cleared up
the issue number 29 was originally
raised about the media type being used
for DNS cases so
The General
uh the generic use case let's say you
have an https record and I'm just going
to some random HTTP resource
in that case
I think it's quite clear that you have
just normal media types being used for
ohdp with OHP request and response and
you have bhttp binary http
one of the use cases that we have that's
a variant of this is
using this discovery to have oblivious
DNS
resolvers that are accessed over http
and so this is the case where we have a
DNS scheme svcb record and it's not
https
the current text has issues
um I think based on the discussion on
the issue the correct
outcome is that you know really the
media type from the perspective of the
Gateway and the target are all the same
as they would be for http
um this is the Gateway does not see
anything different it just sees oh HTTP
Rec and response it has binary HTTP
inside that gets turned into an HTTP
request to the Target
the target itself
is a dough resolver and it just sees a
normal do request over http
um
that is distinct from a theoretical case
that you could have which would be
uh ohttp wrapping just the raw DNS
message because technically you don't
really need uh the other bits of the
HTTP response every request and response
that are in bhdp it's just a wrapper but
uh that does add media type complexity
and is no longer just a generic Gateway
and I think we should avoid doing that
based on that
um any questions
oh and the nice thing is uh you know we
had Odo before but now technically this
is
uh DNS over oblivious HDPE so we can
call it a Duo d-o-o-h
anyway I'll stop now
Ben
so just as a document matter I want to
stress that this is creating a Divergent
so I I agree with Tommy's choice I fully
support it uh I wonder if we should
claw back the the ohttp draft
and make some changes because right now
section 4.6 of the ohttp draft lays out
a sort of speculative design and a
couple of paragraphs of like here's how
you could use ohttp for DNS but it's not
this it's the other thing
so we're now going to be in the
situation where we have a spec for how
you do dough with ohttp and we also have
another document that outlines that spec
incorrectly
um or outlines essentially a competing
design that we do not have a spec for so
uh I think this one we could certainly
remove
I mean I can let Martin no other speak
remove the example
um I think you definitely you can have
other things other than bhtp inside
and I think though oh the main ohtp
document is correct in its advice
of what to do if you do that but I don't
think we need to do it here
Ralph
I feel like so this means if I'm sort of
riding a doe server I'll have to support
kind of door over H2 the whole Rage 3
and then uh
dough over
hdp and then there's the Adaptive DNS
draft that is a different encoding right
that is odor
yeah so right oh Odo is its own thing I
I think actually this this approach
makes it simpler for implementation even
though technically you have a little bit
of extra packaging because you can run
a completely unmodified
H2 doe server
as the target service
and then you have in front of it
an ohtp Gateway that receives the ohttp
request encrypted decrypts it gets the
binary HTTP and translates that into a
request
to the unmodified
H2 doe server
now these are co-located so you're doing
decapsulation Etc in you know two things
right next to each other
but it allows you to have unmodified doe
server code if you have the DNS message
directly within the ohttp encapsulation
then that effectively is meaning you
have a doe server that has to directly
speak
the oblivious HTTP request
so that is potentially more work
foreign
in it right
right but once we eventually get to a
world with only ohdp you just need to
OHP Gateway that's generic and you have
a dose over that's generic you can just
slap them together and there's no custom
code written for this all right thanks
Martin
thanks Sean for doing the note-taking
um Martin Thompson I'm not really sure
what sort of
um
thing we're talking about here
because you can do all of these things
we probably should choose one though
and I think for anyone doing
uh oblivious dough then this makes a
whole lot of sense I think this is the
natural wrapping what's on the slide is
what what is the natural wrapping for
that sort of thing you have an oblivious
HTTP Gateway that's just a an oblivious
HTTP Gateway you have a doe Target and
the two could be independently
implemented and everything will be fine
I think there's there is a separate
design that says that you've got an
oblivious dough I I believe it's DNS
which looks very much different to this
potentially has a different rapper
potentially has a different thing on the
inside but that we don't need to Define
that here
exactly that's what I'm saying as well
um
and
really the only
thing that's relevant for this document
is
saying when you receive the oblivious or
whatever we're going to call it
parameter over an svcb record for a
resolver
do you then assume it is this and we're
just going to say yes it is this
this time
okay
I guess Martin are you out of queue now
um
so that is that one
I think it sounds like people are okay
with
re-clarifying the document to just mean
this because it's a natural thing to do
uh the one last issue I was going to
bring up was specifically again around
the
DNS case
if you're getting this from DDR which is
the thing defined in the add working
group where you have learned about your
resolver from a
special use domain name dns.resolve.arpa
in that case in order to trust the
resolver you need to validate the IP
address
in the Target certificate
and the text currently in this document
says you know if you were doing
um the oblivious dance to get that
Target
then either before you're doing things
obliviously you need to just directly
connect to that Target and validate a
certificate or you create some separate
proxied connection through a connect
proxy or whatever you can still validate
the target certificate
and if you have validated the target
certificate then you can go ahead and do
the oblivious requests
I think this is
the simplest way to make sure we solve
the security there
um but the issue was raised so does
anyone want to do anything else
Martin
yeah mountains again I think this is
probably something we can leave for the
DDR uh draft in the sense that
um you have a reference identity that
you're using to authenticate the server
that reference identity may be different
to the thing you put in DNS to query it
but you still have reference identity
and all of those rules apply on the DDR
side of things as much as they apply
here maybe a note but I wouldn't put any
normative language around it
if that's at all possible yeah
that sounds good
I I would need to check
the current document but I believe it
doesn't have normative language
okay so that
those are the main issues we have
um I guess going back to the naming
now that we've talked about this
Ben did you want to
so
the the question I I ran into was uh on
the one hand uh so in the DNS record you
run into this thing it says oblivious
um does that only apply to if I'm trying
to use do
um or does that apply to any use of this
DNS server so as an example I'm a
suppose I'm a client that is fully
prepared to speak oblivious doe and I
get one of these service B records back
um if I also support DNS over quick
uh does the oblivious instruction also
apply to DNS over quick in pursuit of
some future specification for oblivious
DNS over quick which doesn't exist right
now or is it only for uh for use with
oblivious HTTP so like maybe one answer
so one answer is it only applies to
oblivious HTTP your options are DNS over
quick and there's DNS over HTTP or an
oblivious DNS over http
so forth another option is to say it
actually applies to the whole record and
so what we expect the client to do is
speak obliviously
um to any of these endpoints and uh and
if it doesn't know how to do that then
it shouldn't use transports if it
basically if it supports oblivious
communication over some of these
transports but not others then it should
probably only use the transports that it
can speak to obliviously
so maybe that's totally coherent can I
answered that I oh
so that that's not how DNS works you
have resource records so that means in
every research record you have a kind of
oblivious or yes or no
so if you have a quick uh record and
this would be an additional resource
record
uh the the service B DNS binding uses a
single resource record to represent uh
HTTP TLS quick etc those are all wrapped
in no no there are no recent record sets
you have a couple of lines each having
kind of a specification one for DOT one
for doe one for whatever no a single
well it's not that's optional but uh you
can form a single service binding record
which says alpn equals H2 H3 doqdot
yeah I don't think you should just to
respond to event I think
your original issue
and your suggestion was correct I think
it based on this really needs to be ohdp
because otherwise
we do not know what that future thing is
or what it would need in a parameter so
the presence of this means you can
access this over normal vanilla ohttp
with a normal Gateway doing binary HTTP
in it and that is all it means if you
have some other protocol it gets a new
marker and that is not done here
which is Richard Burns is an individual
and I was exactly what I was going to
say here like
to just like off fortiori like we don't
you know you we don't want to bundle all
these protocols together because you
don't know who they are and because this
is providing the contact point we don't
want to force all of those things to be
implemented on the same contact Point
um so like yeah definitely let's keep
these things separate
how about this that should be better
so uh I I agree with the prior speakers
um in part because it was very confusing
for me to hear you can do uh DNS
obliviously
um I don't even know that we know what
you can do DNS obliviously means as a
client the client's not oblivious right
the it's the the point of oblivious
these oblivious protocols is to keep the
intermediaries and the and the server
oblivious about what's happening uh and
so the client needs to know what what
kind of state it needs to trim uh to
reject
um all of that stuff and I don't think
we actually have answers for that at the
different levels so
um
uh yeah so so ohtp
yeah
um
yeah I I concur with what everybody's
just been saying I mean the the
specification is two things it is an
encapsulation format for talking to to
the terminal Target HTTP server and it
is a set of indicators that you provide
to the Gateway and like in the in the
end and so if in order to provide this
functionality for some other
hypothetical protocol like DNS you would
then need an encapsulation format that
is used to talk to talk to those
um those systems and things and in the
cases of you know in the in in the most
likely that is like called TLS or called
quick
um and so like it's not like
understandable like that's just like
completely asking for this working group
so like um so really specify the HTTP
thing and and leave other things other
people
um and in particular like you know just
to like harp on this a little bit if you
were to say if what you wanted was to
provide like a like a conceptually
similar service to this that did DNS but
was like the military they were
tunneling the name of the Gateway is
called mask
foreign
I think that
is all of the issues so
on uh authors and I think we have enough
to rev the document
and take it from there
I think that's it then
thanks Tommy
all right
um we're doing really well on time
tiru are you going to present the um
oblivious relay feedback
do you have any friends right yeah
hello everyone
um good afternoon I'm thiru I'll be
presenting updates to the obvious relay
feedback draft uh this was presented in
the last idea of when we had received
some good feedback and we updated the
draft to address those feedback
uh next slide please
yeah next slide
yeah just a quick recap uh for those who
haven't read this draft this is
primarily written for the case that was
often rate limit incoming requests for
various reasons
um if the server rate limits the relay
then it would harm all the clients using
that way and that's the problem we are
trying to solve with this draft
next slide please so just a reminder
that we are required to wear a mask
inside so please do put on your mask if
you don't have it on already
foreign
clients uh the feedback we had received
from the working group was to use the
work happening in HTTP API working group
and be co-authored with the author of
that draft and he helped us update it to
use the service parameters that's being
defined in that uh right limit headers
next slide
yeah so that's the change that we're
bringing in to update the right limit
policy to have a new parameter to Signal
the rate limit to the relay
next slide
so this was all there in the previous
version so that was just a quick recap
so what the draft does is it it sends
two values one value to integrate to the
relay to rate limit all the clients and
the second value was breaking beta
finding clients uh the big comment that
we received from the working group was
can that be abused uh by the Target uh
if the relay starts rate limiting
clients so that it would help the target
to De anonymize these clients so we
updated the draft to address these
comments next slide
yeah so uh if if in case the rate limit
is for a client which is probably
sending some malicious request which the
target has identified uh then what are
the prerequisites for the relative even
start rate limiting so the first the
first two uh prerequisites have to be
that it has to be serving a large number
of clients sending large volume of
requests otherwise it's going to ignore
that it needs to have a very large
number of benign clients for which it is
not doing any rate limiting versus the
number of clients for which it has to do
the rate limiting the third rule is that
uh really does not immediately rate
limit the offending client so what it
does is it basically starts watching how
many requests from the client are indeed
malicious for which the value 2 was
provided versus the request for which
there was no value provided uh for
instance some important it is sending a
large volume of malicious request the
idea behind that rule was malform
request typically has some pattern which
is matched by let's say a web
application firewall uh whereas valid
HTTP request should not be linkable in
case if you want the Privacy protection
for obvious HTTP so that way the target
will not be able to partition the
anonymity set of legitimate clients so
that was the idea that we enhanced this
specific section to handle uh the big
issue that was raised with regard to Red
limit being abused by the Target for
malicious purposes
uh next slide please
uh even in case where I think Ben raised
this comment that a rate limiting uh
field for all the clients could also be
misused in case if for instance there
are very low volume of clients sending
uh requests once in a while so we have
set email prerequisites for that that
after the rate limiting there has to be
a good enough high volume of messages
from a large volume of clients and uh
dividing the rate limit uh fairly among
the active clients could create a timing
pattern of requests that could possibly
be uh strongly correlated by the Target
to the anonymous clients so we're just
relying on the mitigation technique
that's already defined in the obvious
https which discusses delaying requests
to increase the nonhead we set into
which in which the requests are
attributed to so that should that we
think should uh with the previous one
and previously two we believe that
should address the side effects of rate
limiting all the clients uh next slide
yeah I think we have addressed all the
comments from the working group so far
and the requests for working production
um I'm not sure that I understand your
argument about
um
about how this preserves the uh
anonymity for the clients I I understand
that you it doesn't permit the
Target to fully partition the state
space of all users but it seems to me
like what you're saying is it's okay if
the anonymity uh or the or the is able
to partition a small percentage of the
users is that is that is that the
mitigation that you're proposing here
yeah if there are small number of
clients then they will not apply a
medication because that makes it quite
easy for the Target then to identify the
clients yeah
but if there's a large number of clients
then uh the relay and the relay receives
this feedback that says this is the
particular you know block further
request from this client and the relay
acts on that behavior acts on that
request they can still you know that
allows the
identification of those specific that
specific user right
no it does not because the if you go
back to the previous slides where we
were discussing the the previous slide
yeah we really does not immediately act
on a request from the target it starts
noticing how many requests are getting
these kind of malicious requests so uh
for instance if let's say there are 100
requests coming from the client and
there are like 99 requests which are
being said that they are malicious and
there's just one legitimate request
which is one uh then then I and it meets
the other criteria then it starts doing
that and and for a Target it's it's
quite impossible to know that all these
requests are coming from the same client
if it had already known that then there
is no need for it even to send that
signal back to the relay
uh this doesn't sound like it has the
guarantees that I would want as a client
to use this but but maybe I'm
misunderstanding I'll let uh next books
in the keyboard
hi
uh so
in general I think that this is if we
take
the full sort of cryptographic
seriousness approach of like you know
there shall not be any leakage or like
all leakage shall be Quantified and
understood exactly but this is a really
hard problem uh this is like because the
timing we're talking about like timing
correlation things that depend on you
like what actual clients timing
behaviors were and it's not even really
clear to me how to formulate it like
what are the assumptions that we're
making that how much does our threat
model cover
um for example clients who are whose
timing is supposed to be uncorrelated
you know that they're issuing requests
randomly but their timing becomes
correlated because of a rate limit
applied to them by the relay uh I think
that so like even the threat modeling it
seems non-trivial here and then this
like client-specific targeted rate
limiting is even harder to understand uh
it's not clear to me that this state
machine has a bunch of mitigations in it
which uh which actually are so strong
that I'm not sure that it actually works
as a defense anymore like a malicious
client can just send a lot of requests
for a slash like a lot of really boring
requests along with whatever it's
malicious requests are and now the relay
looks at the percentage of malicious
flagged requests and that percentage is
not high enough so it doesn't apply any
rate limit
uh so
my advice would be
forget about the client targeted
requests
let's just try an informational draft on
the question of like good practices for
a relay to
um to implement rate limiting which by
the way doesn't even have to be explicit
even if you don't have an explicit rate
limit from the Gateway at some point
you're still going to have to turn away
some fraction of requests and so I think
there's some some interesting questions
about what are the best ways to do that
that leak the least amount of
information how do we model that problem
that's an interesting solution but if
we'll look into that yeah thanks
sorry I'm a little puzzled how are you
defining malicious not like technically
but we're using the properties of
malicious are
any many malformed requests which
matches for example your web application
firewall patterns of attack right sorry
which what
if you have a
if you have an attack pattern in the
HTTP request right like like a large
garbage volume which matches some
specific web application firewall rule
which you have seen some alternate
family using and you see that they're
using some specific headers that's how
you detect that it's coming from that
and and you don't see that coming from
average directly so I'm sure tkg is
concerned about the anonymity set
there's no way for the as far as I can
tell there's no way for the Relay to
verify that these are malicious and not
just cleaning wishes and it seems quite
clear you can use you say you can't be
used for partitioning but of course it
can because I just like so so I I
believe like
I see a set of requests that I think are
all from one person and
um I don't know for sure but they seem
to be correlated and so what I do is I
fly them all as malicious and then I see
if that to see if it throttles back and
if it does then then I verify the
guesses for one person and since you
have no way you're going to find them
malicious that doesn't work so I think
if you want I think so I think like I'm
also concerned about the ability to
actually demonstrate this is safe I
think
um you know one potential Avenue would
be to
um uh um would would be to um have the
uh the server the server Supply the key
to the relay so they really could verify
for themselves they're malicious of
course now we're in key committing um
I'll just say that right now
um but like I just don't understand I
don't think it's gonna work to make the
servers more that things are malicious
for the reason I just indicators
okay
um and I I guess I understand people
think it's a problem but like
you know
like like I mean it seems I guess I
guess it seems to me the example you
just you just said like filter it out
like I don't really understand I don't
understand what the value why is it
helpful to throttle this data
you can already attacked the problem
those malicious requests typically a
filter that you drop those records
yeah but if it's if it's getting
overwhelmed right and it wants them to
be dropped right why
if it's getting overwhelmed pretty scary
but I mean but it's because it's slower
to process those requesting the other
requests yeah it's it's just trying to
save its uh resources from processing
those bad reviews yeah
like I guess I'm just not that I'm not
that excited about computational Irish
attacks here
all right so we're at time on this slot
um thanks for the presentation too it
sounds like we need maybe a little bit
more clarity on the threat model here
before we we move ahead
um so
yeah I think we're going to take that uh
take that back to the list thanks
all right
checking the agenda here looks like next
up is Ralph Giles presenting remotely on
uh unreliable ohttp extensions
Ralph
all right I'm trying to get the
slides to show up
did you request a SlideShare there we go
great
take it away all right so my name is Rob
Giles I'm presenting work I did at Brave
along with Chris Wood who was a Cloud
Player and this is a proposal for an
extension to oblivious hdb that for
unreliable delivery
so uh for those of you who are new to O
HTTP which is probably not most of you
but was certainly me
um so the idea is this works is that you
have a client that wants to send stuff
to a Target and without them learning
too much about each other so there's a
relay service the client encrypts the
data for
uh using the gateways key send it to the
relay the relay forwards it to the
Gateway stripping the IP address so
everybody doesn't learn what's in the
client's request the Gateway doesn't
learn what the client's IP address is
and the Gateway proxies the unwraps the
request since it's the target
the target responds like a normal HTTP
server would sends it back to the
Gateway the Gateway encrypts it to the
client sends it to the relay who
remembers who the client was
and sends the encrypted request back to
client
okay simple enough
so for uh we have an application where
we're using the star protocol which is
there's been some interest in over in
the Privacy surveying measurement group
to do Telemetry submission like things
about it or things that applications are
doing they want to submit it to some
server and the way this works right now
is the client
uh constructs the message sends it to a
web endpoint and rather than the web
endpoint doing processing directly or
speed and simplicity we just shove it
into a queue and then there's a batch
job that runs on separate uh with
separate missions elsewhere that pulls
the log down out of band and analyzes it
in a batch and so this simplifies the
infrastructure the endpoint can be
really fast all it has to do is append
to a log and uh because we're doing sort
of aggregation of the data it's not
helpful to look at the data individually
but we can look at the IP address if
it's coming from the clients who can
associate the eventual things that we
process with the client's IP address so
we could build a profile of individual
visual clients from what they send so
that's not as privacy preserving as
you'd like
so if we use oblivious HTTP we can solve
the IP we can break that link with an IP
address we just start to relay which
talks to a Gateway which talks to the
endpoint but now we need two new
services
and since we already have this custom
thing that's listening to for the
endpoint maybe we can just teach the
battle oblivious HTTP and combine the
Gateway in the endpoint so the relay
talks to the endpoint which then stuff
thing is into the log so one less
service we have to run
and then the log could be processed out
of band later so that works sort of the
same as before we just added the single
service we have to put in
to handle the relay
but teaching the endpoint about
oblivious HTTP complicates the code a
lot I mean remember it's supposed to be
really simple it just takes bodies from
like Jason bodies that's been submitted
by the client and it shoves them in a
log file so now we have to implement
oblivious HTTP we have to do so we can
do the request and response
serialization we need to provision keys
for it
and so it's a fair amount of extra code
and security service we need to audit
and the endpoint was supposed to be
simple
so the inside I had think about thinking
about this is the only reason we need I
believe it's HTTP parsing and hpac
encoding and all that sort of stuff and
so we can return a 200 okay because this
is just a submission service we the
client sends data it's a report or
something it's done and it doesn't the
server doesn't ever actually return any
data it's just yes I got your response
and because we're doing our aggregation
processing offline in a batch job we
don't even validate the message content
so the client is sending nonsense we
don't find out in time to tell them you
send nonsense
so there's actually no real value to
encoding the empty body with the 200
okay Response Code with oblivious HTTP
but that's what the spec requires
so to address this we uh Chris Wood and
I wrote a draft for unreliable delivery
is what we're calling it which is just
an extension that says instead of
requiring that the Gateway return an
encrypted response to the relay which is
sent back to the client what if you were
just able to say 202 accept
and return an empty body and that way
the Gateway doesn't actually have to
understand anything about oblivious HTTP
other than this is what you respond with
so it's two lines of code instead of 500
or whatever it takes to implement uh
oblivious http
so simple enough
uh the client could opt in by setting
certain headers uh what we suggested
except and then a message oh HTTP
acknowledgment message type so signal
that's okay with this Martin Thompson
suggested maybe we could use the prefer
respond to async header which has a
bunch of stuff you can attach to it to
say how long you're willing to wait for
an answer and things like that uh also
given that the in at least in our
application the Gateway will probably
only support this method uh probably it
should be possible for the out-of-band
configuration that tells the relay how
to talk to the Gateway could also say we
only accept this so the Relay can reject
traffic right away
that doesn't that tries to do something
else
so it seems to be there are some
advantages to this like it makes it
easier to secure the Gateway code
because you don't have to do code you
don't have to do key provisioning and
it's just much simpler code it gives you
more ways of deploying oblivious HTTP
within different Frameworks
and another nice Advantage is that
because you don't have to deliver right
away because the Gateway and and the
Relay can just respond 200 accepted
right away and then buffer the message
by H delivered later that gives you a
much larger window when you can Shuffle
the data send it in a different order
and that helps defeat traffic analysis
where you try and figure out which
clients and which message based on when
it was sent
on the other hand there's more config to
worry about and the relay at least has
to be configured to accept this and not
reject it as a not valid oblivious HTTP
and it's not suitable for a lot of
applications because you don't get any
acknowledgment other than the relay hurt
you
um
there's no way to re-transmit if the
transmission fails there's no way to
transfer State and confirm the state has
been transferred if that makes any sense
um Ted did you want to ask a clarifying
question right now or was that just in
the queue for a later
question
okay well I'm at the end anyway this is
so that was our motivation and so I was
just curious if
is there interest in the working group
in addressing this as a use case
um what do you think of the draft are
there any technical improvements you
could suggest because it seems like
there's lots of ways we could do this
and it's unclear how it interacts with
other things like service discovery
uh Ted Hardy Cisco uh
I
I usually try and come up here and say
what I'm enthusiastic about here and and
unfortunately in this case I'm afraid
I'm up obvious uh occasional curmudgeon
hat on
um and I apologize for that I think what
you're actually trying to do is to
create an oblivious star service so
looking through the draft and and
following through to the distributed
secret sharing for private threshold
aggregation I get why you would want a
um an oblivious star service but I think
what you're doing to try and get there
sets my teeth on edge
uh there's a whole bunch of stuff in in
your draft in the way you're using HTTP
uh that just kind of
hurts
um so an example of this is is 202 in
general for my experience is a a final
server's answer hey we've accepted this
but we haven't processed it you're using
it in a relay in a way that I don't
think actually matches what people in
the web world are going to necessarily
expect and in your description of how
you signal this
um you're using
you know accept headers in a way
um that that really are bizarre to me in
particular using
um accept headers where star dot star
means that you might use this just it's
bizarre
um I I think the the basic idea here
that you want an oblivious star service
well good go ahead I just don't think
that trying to make the oblivious
HTTP become the star service by throwing
in these
um
uh these message headers and and reusing
202 the the way you're doing it is is
fine so if you think what you want this
working group to consider is adding a
um a deliverable for for an oblivious
star service I think I would be behind
that but I wouldn't actually want to
start from this draft and I apologize
for being the occasional curmudgeon uh
in that response
I'm just going to inject myself here
real quick with a clarifying question
um could you clarify to what degree this
draft is specific to Star and to what
degree it's kind of generically
providing a service where there's no
response needed it's just a submission
endpoint
I think of it as as completely
orthogonal to Star I mean the way star
Works means that we have this particular
architecture where we have to submit
things and we don't care about writing
back because we're relying on the crypto
to make sure that's Anonymous except for
the IP address
but it seems like you wouldn't have
any example where you have this sort of
simple input thing where you want you
don't want to have to generate the keys
you don't want to have to have a key so
that you can just respond okay I think
it applies to any application like that
so it's not specific to Star it's not
even specific to Telemetry it's just
sort of this Edge case where
it seems simpler not to have to run two
services to talk to your target when
you're already having a custom endpoint
so that's really the use case that I
care about
okay thank you oh actually I'm sorry I
think Tommy is next to the cube
time
all right here we go audio is on
um
yeah I mean I I agree with Ted that the
spelling in the HTTP bits needs more
discussion however I am pretty positive
about this
I think the you know I don't want I
don't care about a response use case of
oblivious http
makes sense
um I don't personally like the use cases
I've had for oblivious HTTP have wanted
responses so far but
metrics collection and others can
definitely use this I think it is
applicable to more than star
and so I think it fits within this
working group
so I think we should adopt it I think we
should adopt it with this document
um acknowledging that
the details can be respelled I
I imagine you and Chris are not
particularly wed to I'm not what is the
way it's written at all like I just want
to be able to not have a key in the in
the Gateway
right and I think that's something that
the working group can work on together
and I think it is an ohdp problem and so
we can do it together here
um the one suggestion I would make is
maybe renaming it uh saying unreliable
every time I hear it I have to remember
what it is again
um so maybe something like no response
submission only one way ohtp something
like that
all right thanks
yeah
um I I guess I'm less positive about
this
um so I think for several reasons so uh
first I think like
like the the sort of like the motivation
for this of like you know I'm gonna
Implement like a secret sharing protocol
just polynomials but I'm too lazy to do
hpka like I just like does not motivate
me at all
um like um it's not lazy stuff it's
about protecting the uh but simplifying
the implementation so there's less
Security Service like the endpoint
that's doing the HTTP hpac is has to be
open to the internet whereas the thing
that actually does the decoding in our
proposal is it's not by log server yeah
you've heard of rushed I imagine
um so uh I I just I this just seems like
I like like
I'm sorry the the motivating case of
like you know of like this whole line of
operation is that is fine to expose
those things the internet so I like that
this is like a substantial security
Improvement I just don't buy
um the um
all right so but I mean but I think but
they're more like relatively like this
just changes the entire properties
lectures of this system of HTTP in
general where HTTP is a protocol where
you send a message and get a response
and that response says things and maybe
it just says thanks but it says
something and so to say well no I just
don't want the ACT that's not the way
designed to work and and so it's like
and and you can and you can see it
actually has a significant impact on the
threat model which is you taking a
system which had an end threat model for
delivery and now has it in the middle
front mobile for delivery and so if the
um you know if the if the uh if for
instance the proxy decides that it
simply wants to like gag some set of
clients because if we do something so
that's the reason two reason three is
that the designing a protocol that is
like by Design
um you know one way like this where the
client gets no feedback whatsoever when
something is wrong
um is like I understand you don't want
to do the VSS checking in line but like
format checking like lots of things can
go wrong and to have a design that
basically is like the client should kind
of blind these 10 things to the server
and not care if they cannot care if
they're valid like that seems like
fundamentally incorrect critical design
even if you know all these topics so I'm
like less positive about this workout
yes um I I don't think it needs more
break time at least
all right thanks
hi uh Ben Schwartz I think the the thing
that I find interesting here and and
compelling is really the batching
idea the delay in batching
um
for privacy and for efficiency reasons I
don't really see a security benefit and
it's not about the efficiency of the of
the Gateway or Target really they can
always batch and buffer on their end if
they want it's really about efficiency
and privacy provided by the relays this
I view as an increase in the Privacy
that that can be offered in oblivious
HTTP in some cases
um you know I I think that the points
that have been raised here are
definitely valid this is in a sense a
very deep HTTP level change
um and you could imagine spelling it as
like a header to the proxy that says uh
you know I don't need a response that
has otherwise in a sense nothing to do
with with the rest of oblivious http
um it could apply to any HTTP request
proxy
so uh but I do think that's a very
interesting thing to be able to specify
uh I think you know to some of ecker's
points it would also be really
interesting to take this in in really a
like high latency messaging Direction
where you sort of treat this as
um as like oblivious SMTP
like this is uh because this really
looks like a an email mixed net and in
that case you actually can get a
response it's at very high latency and
that high latency response can be useful
for things like detecting
misconfigurations or confirming that
you're not subject to a long running
attack
foreign
which is like besides gagging clients I
wondered if this gives a method for the
Relay to identify clients by batching in
certain ways to indicate properties
about the clients or you know there's
funky things I think you could do and I
I don't know that's like an addition to
the threat model here that's something
to consider
thanks
great
David scanazi HTTP Enthusiast I'm
find myself agreeing with a lot of
people including people who are strongly
disagreeing here so
um on one hand I I see why this is
useful I can kind of uh buy that like in
some submission case you want to
simplify things but I also see that like
uh when this goes in front of as you
know it would because it the way an
impacts HTTP semantics we would tell the
HTTP about them and they would like
probably pass out uh how do we uh square
that and I was thinking about it
uh so you have two benefits from doing
this one is that the client can far and
forget quicker and the other is the uh
less cryptography on the uh an
encryption on the uh gate weight if I'm
getting the terminology right which one
of those do you care about is it both or
a single one
my motivation was mostly the Gateway I
mean the client okay
in my case yeah all right no no that
makes sense in that case would it make
sense for you to keep HTTP the way it is
and just send an empty response
uh because like you know HTTP we already
have a flow for errors where you can say
like no I'm not going to give you an
encrypted response because like I've
forgotten the keys or something and you
could add a response that is like yup
A-Okay I'm just not sending you a
response so the and then that triggers
the relay to say oh A-Okay back to the
client the same way where today if it
sends an error the uh the the relay
sends that error back to the client so
that I think addresses ecker's concerns
that uh like there's no longer a
response you don't have any way of
hearing errors back because I think
that's a real concern but it solves your
cryptographic problem so that might be a
way just a thought
okay I think that's what I'm trying to
do but unless I'm misunderstood I don't
think that address is ecker's concerned
because it breaks the tunnel between the
encrypted tunnel between the client and
the Gateway
because the Relay can see that you've
returned an empty response
as opposed to incurring in returning an
encrypted blob which represents the
empty response
yep that makes sense thank you
again uh I apologize for for getting up
to to kind of restate something but I
think I want to pull on something that
was set up in the chat room and connect
it to something that that Eckert said
it's like if there is a use case for
this that doesn't require the oblivious
property
um then the clear thing to do with this
document is to take it to http and work
through the HTTP process to to figure
out whether there are new methods
involved new response codes involved Etc
that's if if that is true this is the
wrong working group for it because
that's where we do core changes to http
if there isn't a use case for this
submission service that doesn't require
the oblivious property then I think you
have to do a much clearer job about
describing what it is about the
oblivious property and the submission
property that have to be tied together
in some way that's better than the
threat model change uh that I see in the
document now I I honestly don't get that
personally and it may be just because I
didn't read deeply enough into the
interconnection you're making with with
your use case but the document I don't
think carries that out of why if this is
a submission service it must be
oblivious to be a success and if that
isn't the case then this is the wrong
word
oh I'm out of order I guess
oh
um cool I think to move on uh Ben did
you want to present thanks Ralph okay
uh causing that rough it sounds like the
feedback here is that you know there's
there's some folks who are um in tune
with the use case but it sounds like we
need to drill in a bit on the how we
measure the HTTP semantics and kind of
how we make things fit together nicely
so thanks for the presentation
thank you
okay
double check
so this uh I presented about this idea
at the last ITF meeting
um and since then this draft has had a I
I've made a lot of changes to the flavor
text and basically no changes to the
actual technical content but a lot of
the normative language has shifted
um definitely people seem to think that
it was too normative
uh and it seems like people still think
it's too normative but um so the the
technical proposal has not changed the
biggest difference I would say
is
that I've tried to generalize the
description to also talk about
how this idea applies in the Privacy
pass context and it seems like probably
uh in the future this draft will will
move to privacy pass if there's interest
in continuing to discuss it at all
and uh and so that you know fair warning
if this is a topic that interests you
you might want to start coming to
privacy pass sessions
so just as a reminder there's Now new
terminologies that I've changed the
terminology compared to the previous
draft but this is the same idea there's
a client there's a proxy and there's an
origin that holds some desired HTTP
resource it could be any kind of
resource and our goal is to fetch that
resource in a way that guarantees both
consistency and authenticity consistency
meaning everybody sees the same version
of the
who wanted to send
uh I think I probably just lost my
connection to meet Echo I'm going to
reboot
you're fine now oh no
sorry about that I I've had an unstable
connection to meet Echo
hmm
so that
the key idea here really is uh that if
you need key consistency you probably
also already have a proxy and you
probably already trust that proxy not to
reveal your identity to the the
destination where you're trying to use
this key consistency because otherwise
your IP address will give you away to
that destination and uh and so the key
consistency won't be sufficient to help
you protect your privacy and avoid
becoming linkable
so if we're sort of willing to make that
assumption or narrow our use cases to
cases where that assumption applies
then uh the whole problem becomes a lot
easier the key consistency problem you
only need key consistency among the
other users of this proxy because you're
distinguishable by essentially the
proxies exit IP from users of other
proxies so
that narrows the problem enough that you
can actually solve it using plain HTTP
caching rules and we don't need to
invent any new logic when we apply the
HTTP caching rules in a very specific
way which is one of the intriguing
things about this design
um I'll just note that the design the
draft has a bunch of language in it
about how to avoid different kinds of
leakage there are a lot of different
ways that you can leak and and I think
these these ways are not trivial they're
not it's not obvious how this leakage
happens so I think it's worth
documenting but uh Martin on the mailing
list pointed out that this normative
guidance is not actually necessary for
the protocol to work so we'll have to
figure out some way to
um put up warnings of the appropriate
kind without necessarily invoking
normative language
but the real thing that I want to
present to the working group is this
question is this actually how we want to
do it because
the remember this is not an abstract
design about like here about key
consistency this is a very specific
protocol and there are a lot of
different ways that you could build a
protocol like this and they have quite
different properties
so I want to mention two things that are
not what's in the draft
one would be
to employ bespoke consistency logic
at the proxy slash relay point
this The Trusted proxy intermediary that
is uh that we're trusting to help us
protect our privacy
right now the draft
essentially applies some some very
subtle and specific interpretations of
some existing HTTP Concepts like if
match and immutable and if you just
while the those interpretations are are
essentially within the standards they're
not necessarily the default reading of
those standards and so this is a little
bit of a sharp edge right we we're
claiming that you can reuse effectively
I'm I'm claiming to you that we can
reuse existing HTTP Machinery but
actually only if you configure it in a
very specific way and the other problem
is that because HTTP resource caching
doesn't have any built-in concept of
multiple versions of a resource like one
that's about to expire and one that sort
of is already also valid and then the
Cache can hold both of them and make
sure that the clients are gradually
updated from one to the other before the
old one expires as far as I can tell you
can't do that just using HTTP caching
logic and so because of that this design
has a Thundering Herd effect where all
clients have a single version of the
resource and if the resource ever
changes all clients need to flip
essentially simultaneously to the new
version and so you could get load spikes
at times when that happens maybe
obviously I have not implemented this
and another question is do we really
want this double check or do we just
want to sign the object because if we
just sign the thing like in the ohttp
context if we sign the key config with
uh with essentially the certificate
chain of the of the origin
then of the Gateway origin then
we don't need this double check we only
have to fetch once and and everything
becomes
well that the network the flow diagram
becomes a lot simpler but the setup
becomes a lot more complicated now I
need to build some kind of signing
system and you know handle key rotations
resign my object before my certificates
expire
so so this is my big question really
like how do we want to do this
all right so Ben is that uh time for
discussion yeah
all right
I have a suggestion on how we approach
both of these questions and that is that
we ask the Privacy pass working group to
take them on
this um
this this sort of line between these two
groups has been sort of a little fuzzy
on this consistency question and we
decided to adopt the key consistency and
uh correctness uh draft in that working
group and it seems to me like that's a
good place to
to have that discussion where the sort
of architectural questions about how we
do consistency and the requirements and
what what have you and the general
approaches I discussed there along with
this as a fairly concrete instantiation
of these things
I'm not sure what you mean by the first
alternative here in terms of concrete
specific steps and so I'm a little leery
of saying let's just take existing specs
and then reinterpret them very
creatively that's
risky
and I'm certain that I don't like the
second one because uh the signing thing
it is much harder to reason about and I
prefer to avoid that sort of thing I
think two requests is
for the for this sort of thing perfectly
tolerable
okay
Tommy hello
um yeah so overall I like the approach
of doing a get and something through a
forward proxy
um
and that part I I like that it doesn't
require any new
protocols being designed or applied like
it is merely a technique that a client
can apply if it has
proxies available to it
I think specifically for the document
all of the dependencies on the access
service descriptions and other stuff
I think that should just
go away like that that's fine if that
ends up existing but I don't think
that's fundamental
to this yeah I have removed that uh
those are those are now they are I've
still structured the examples that way
um but there's no there's no longer any
normative dependency on that got it okay
I was
I guess I was looking at the most recent
version and
it is I guess yes
examples as like kind of like a
unadopted thing like it's a bit
distracting
um okay
um
so I agree with Martin that we should
talk about this in privacy pass uh now
that we have key consistency adopted
there
I personally think also like that all of
this can probably go into that document
if it is just about technique applying
and not new protocol work
um
and then the question I had for you just
about the caching bits
what happens if the caching headers you
get back are not what you are
normatively requiring in your document
but the values of the keys still match
via my double check
what's the failure mode there
so the the client is supposed to
essentially reject right this means that
the origins
the attack is uh so if if you don't have
cash control immutable for example
then the server can send you uh can can
reply to the sorry the the Gateway can
rep or the you know HTTP terms the
Gateway can reply to the relay with a
um with a key config with some long
lifetime
you know a week
um and that can go to the client and
then the the Gateway acting as a
different client can can send another
HTTP request to the relay that causes it
to flush that cache entry and replace it
with a new key config so now the next
client gets an its own you know
different key config that also has a
cache lifetime of week now both clients
have long-lived distinct key configs
so and the
and the requests that go over like the
forward proxy
uh
the relay server manages the timing
perfectly so that it gives out the same
evil config to the same client
uh
uh so the the client keeps it cached
locally for a long time
um it doesn't need to
the relays but the point of double check
is that I'm checking that I get the same
key via two different methods that are
presumably unlinkable and so if you're
feeding so for the ease
right so then so client a and client B
have different key configs
um they send get requests um directly to
the uh to the Gateway origin
with if match header with an if match
header saying here's the basically the
version of the key config that I want is
this one valid and and they get it back
again and the reason for that if match
header is that the Gateway needs to be
able to rotate the key config and it
doesn't know a priori whether a given
client has the old one or the new one
so
uh so it can't just always serve the new
one or the or the it sounds like maybe
we're
that part of this match is causing us to
trip on ourselves a bit and maybe there
are other approaches to handling key
rotation anyway we can discuss more
thanks Becker so I found realistic
caveats quite concerning
um
um like and I'm quite concerned that
like perhaps AGP caches not behave the
way what everyone hopes they behave
um and they won't be very sad people
um
um so I think like by the way to try to
tease a couple things apart which is
detection from uh in particular
detection from enforcement right so like
if we just went back to the dumb design
right and forget about caching you say
look I just query directly and like
we're through a proxy and the IP
addresses are different and now you're
not timing attacks I suppose this is why
is why you don't want to do that right
um that's how we get to this this design
right
uh
yes locations different IP addresses and
check the match right
yes you also like I said need to worry
about uh how to handle cases where the
key config has actually changed but
sure okay so I can imagine it's all that
like you know um forcing the server to
get a list of every key it's ever used
and and that kind of thing right um you
know you haven't maintain our block a
blockchain basically of you know a hash
Channel lookies
um so
um I guess this gets me to my second
point which is
um that say that we have mismatch what
then
and
um and the natural Thursday is okay well
I'm like culinary times
um and but like
I don't want to be right and so I think
you actually need the key to be signed
by by the DVD certificate anyway and the
reason is simply that that's the only
way you can demonstrate that you can
Target someone's reputation in this base
and so like if you think of the logic of
CT right logic is a t CT is is that the
certificates are all signed and there's
an assurance by the um by the ca
that the certificates of the log and any
time you see a signed value does not log
that's evidence in office right and so I
think that I think that we need the same
structure here which is basically some
kind of structure here which is
basically that there's a plot that that
there's an understanding of what the
values or value is supposed to be and
any value any value that's outside of
that of that period
um if self-verifiable or self-verifying
therefore it's kind of official evidence
of fraud but I just like I guess I just
worry that we're gonna build cooperatus
that's going to allow us to detect this
kind of malfeasance and then you're
going to like and you're going to be
like you know like basically reduce the
posting on Hacker News does anybody else
see like this right like this book is
key and it's like oh but then like I see
the hacker newspaper I take it down it
just seems like very complicated I think
we're going to end up having to sign
anyway and so maybe I'd like this so and
so like I guess if you buy that argument
then I'm not sure what that gets then I
think maybe by that argument then you
may have to step back and say if I'm
signing
then what other pieces of the puzzle um
are are changed right
um so that that's I I don't know what I
think about this but I'm just trying to
like work through the entire problem at
once instead of in pieces
so next again speaking this individual
contributor here
um yeah your very first slide here but
had uh end Beyond um so I kind of wanted
to push on that a little bit kind of ask
what the right level of thinking about
this is um you've talked a lot about key
consistency but as I think Nick Jody
pointed out in the chat there are a lot
of other resources on the web that one
would like to be consistent like you
know the Nick reads privacy policies I'd
like to like make sure that I'm getting
the same jQuery as everybody else
um
so I mean you you could scope this it
seems like the requirements are broadly
pretty similar with regard to those
things even to the level of reactions
like Ecker uh which is phrased
um so I wonder if this is actually a
pretty General thing now it may be that
um you know if this is a critical
property for something like privacy pass
that would be you could it could be
addressed there first and then
generalize other things but yeah it's
not really this is seeming more General
than an Ojai problem so like maybe the
right direction uh to go with this is
kind of you know if it's really critical
for privacy pass which it seems to be
like hit it there first but with an ice
these other applications
that's an interesting point this is
really talking about HTTP resource
consistency at this point not just key
consistency
is Eric in person or remote or remote
perhaps Eric is trying to find them
available now for some reason might meet
Echo is taking forever load up for me
today but you're on Audible yes okay yep
so
two comments first just sort of
for the info people in here repeating
something I said the Privacy pass
working group a couple of weeks ago both
this and the the other consistency draft
the informational one they both work
well in my mind either here or in
privacy past so let's pick one and work
on it there and looks like at least for
the other draft it was adopted over
there in privacy passed so okay let's
let's shift this over there now too just
so they can be together in one place and
that makes perfect sense
um in case anybody doesn't know I am one
of the co-chairs of privacy pass
um and in a way that's part of what I
wanted to present this here in this
cycle
all right but I and many others seem to
think yeah let's just push this into
privacy pass and
Ben gets to deal with the hats problems
from that but
as far as the actual Solutions here
I maintain that this is
one reasonable solution this problem
um I think that the fact that we rent
all these caveats and potential pitfalls
and stuff is
the big proof that this is a very
difficult problem that anything you have
is going to have those so that's why we
need something like this draft to spell
out a possible solution because
otherwise there was some time with their
own bespoke solutions that just have all
these problems because they didn't
realize the issues so we need something
like this whether it's this specific
solution or the other two Alternatives
you present on this slide I don't have a
huge opinion it would be nice to solve a
Thundering Herd problem but at the same
time
Solutions I've tried to kind of to solve
the Thundering herds problem was had
problems poked in them so it's always
comes back to this is a difficult
problem so we don't come with an
absolute better solution it might be a
matter of yeah let's publish this draft
with this solution and it's usable for
anyone that isn't quite as susceptible
to the Thundering Herd issue and when we
come up with a better solution that
isn't thundering or hurt susceptible
we'll come with a yet another draft for
another alternative solution that people
could use is
not a huge problem with having different
options of the space if we have to
publish multiple protocols so that's
fine so
thanks I do want to try to avoid you
know defining a ton of these I think no
I think we're all going to be happier if
we can more or less Converge on on the
smallest manageable number of these yeah
but uh two solutions one is simpler but
subjectable of Thundering Herd and the
other one is a little more complicated
requires more logic but is more useful
for
bigger parties that care about huge
amounts of traffic spikes and all that
sort of stuff
that those two solutions seems like a
reasonable number to end up with Mutiny
so
yeah
cool
um
yeah I think it sounds like we have
consensus that this should follow draft
key consistency into privacy passive
if the chairs of privacy pass agree
which then can speak to that
um
uh yeah so so future discussion of the
draft will go in the Privacy pass
working group
um follow us on follow us uh if you if
you want to talk about it more
all right sounds good um we do have a
little bit of time in case anyone has
any other business
um
going once going twice
if not thanks all for joining um Richard
did you want to say anything else
yep thank you thank you everyone good
session
yeah see y'all next time
thanks to our note-takers
Sean Martin
foreign