as well
we have time as in our agenda it's not
too tight
we have a buffer time of 10 minutes okay
maybe we can wait a couple
once for the video
there was food downstairs all right yes
it's the food that's why so it's gonna
take a while yeah very hard to compete
this is not working
I don't know I've not seen anything
you need to plug it in your yeah no no
but can either this should not work
because this is you're not doing screen
share we are doing the SlideShare
doesn't support it
there is no
keyboard
okay
um
hello everyone
hello hi John
we propose to wait for a couple more
minutes there are beverage downstairs so
for people on medical Don't Panic the PC
walking group session will start
but just wait for people during the room
about
like take that operational seconds but
it makes a lot of sense to me
would certainly be
easier to progress I think
we've had a couple documents recently at
the top chat
a bunch of other stuff
like that
but it's easier
take all the information
yeah yeah
thanks thank you John
suspects okay
hello again everyone we propose to start
this is the past competition element
work group session
so as you may be aware November 11 is a
special day for many countries so in the
UK it's
quite uh significant so
just as a reminder for people involved
at War
was nice to mention the specific date
okay back to our ietf business the usual
not well you should be all familiar with
them especially we're on Friday already
so usual IPR request on the ATF
processes from the ATF and
you should
get down to those reference if you don't
our Hardware already aware of them
okay
mixed meeting again people are joining
both from the room on mythical so we use
the medical tool to manage the cues so
that's the main impact for people on
site remember to learn the queue using
the medical tool there is a light one
that is appropriate for mobile phones or
laptops for Riemann participants you
know the deal you you're already using
the medical app whatever
thanks next
uh the usual pointers that you may be
aware of
there is no one on the minutes there
it's after
the data yeah
um the guideline for conducts
nothing new there but it's always
useful to remind them
so we have Harry acting as a mini taker
but as usual if you want to give him a
hand it's always useful especially if
you were involved in discussion
um for people on site name spelling
checking
could be useful so
you may join the minutes on the link
there and give Harry a run when you feel
like it
thanks
um usual reminder on the process in the
ATF especially on the use of the mailing
list we know that from time to time
there are many things happening in the
background
so remind let's remind that ITF process
is based on touching consensus to
progress work so this needs to be
visible at some point on the mailing
list there are also some critical steps
on the ATF process related to the main
Linux use so when it comes to working
with last calls document adoption and so
on the more people are involved the
easier it is for the chairs to judge on
the consensus on the support of a given
work item we also manage a Wiki
especially to keep an eye on the
existing queue for document adoption on
working of last calls there's still some
backlog there but it's improving
so
feel free to
update in cases we missed any item there
the chat that may access directly from
that link or also using the medical tool
is already up and running
and in case you need some implementation
with interrupt on
there are some opportunities to request
a code point from the Ayana
so it's been used in the past for a few
drafts and please don't forget to go
through that process in case there are
interoperability at stake in the short
term because
it's easier to get a record point and
modify existing deployment later in the
process so you don't necessarily have to
wait for full RFC status to
use that code point from the Ayana
the agenda no change from the published
one any one want to bash anything
hope not
okay so let's move on
hello reviews so as you may be aware
there has been some suggesting uh
process about early reviews in the
rooting area
uh the good news is that from the PC
standpoint we will use the um
earlier review process from time to time
so nothing brand new from the PC
perspective but it good to see that it's
a jewelry guideline that we are already
following and that it's another that is
enlarging uh we feel it's a very useful
process step to consider early reviews
from the rooting area perspective as you
may know we usually get interesting
feedback from the reviewers
so it's good to see this process with an
enlarged scope and we will
keep on using that good
step or way of conduct
in case yeah documentary referring uh
to balance the work on how the
the chairs flushed the queues
using Shepherd for the last stage of the
document is a useful way so if you're
interested
uh please
contact the chairs we'd be happy to
discuss with you what document would be
relevant for you to Shepherd that's a
useful way for the shepherd to to
understand the ATF process especially in
the last stages
and for the chair to balance the work uh
we thank Harry who's been already taking
some of them as a shepherd and if there
are other people happy to to join our PC
usual shipper that would be great from
the chair perspective
so working good status
we have no numeracy since the last ITF
meeting but the work has still been
progressing quite well uh three of the
documents and the in the RFC editor
queue one of them is
has been blocked for a while
pending for a spring document or no
segment voting document which is work in
progress so uh we hope to resolve that
dependency in a short term or reasonable
term
uh the other ones are progressing so we
can hope that by the next ITF meeting we
will have
several addresses published
uh we have to order a documents in the
iuc hand
so that's him the regular
level of cues in uh working group which
is live which has a document progressing
towards iot studies
apart from that we have a recent
Collision that came from the it UT so we
need to join the
routing array for there to update the
list of relevant documents that we will
point
to the igut when responding to their
license so it's a usual communication
between the gsdu
so nothing special to mention there if
you feel there would be something to
point out specifically ready to given
work please contact the chairs otherwise
we will probably just send an updated
list of relevant documents for them
we also have a reminder of the existing
heli code Poitier location from the
Ayana there with the deadlines so
everything in 2024 for the next steps
some have been renewed some are
progressing towards Seas so
everything's fine so far at this stage
for corporate allocation
okay so a little flow to my co-chair
hi everyone we'll now talk about all the
working group documents just a reminder
in our agenda we had only one working
group document with status is being
presented but working group documents
are very important this is where we have
the consensus to progress the work so
please use this time if there is any
open issue that you have with these
documents or if there is any feedback
that you want to provide to the working
group it's very this is the key work
that we want to progress as part of our
working group activities and that's why
I have put a little bit uh time on the
agenda for all our working group
documents as well
so let's start with the first one uh
this I am a co-author and uh Julian is
shepherding the uh the document the
document is currently still in the
working group last call stage it has not
been closed uh we got comments from uh
Tom patch specially related to the use
of TLS 1.3 and there is a document today
on the agenda which talks about how psip
can use TLS 1.3 as well as from the Yang
point of view it also has a slide there
where how we plan to how we have already
handled the comment that came from Tom
and then uh once that is done most
likely I'll ask my co-chair to progress
the document to The Next Step as far as
update is concerned uh apart from TLS
1.3 issue the main changes was we had a
new RFC for flow spec capability so that
capability flag was missing so that got
added and related to security also in
the igp we had a recent document that
went through igp they're also based on
the comments in the Ops uh section some
some things was pointing out which we
have updated in the Yang model as well
so everything is well aligned and we
hope that this document which is a very
important document for p sub this is the
base Yang model for us would soon see
publication
is there any comments please use this
time uh people in the room or online if
you have any thoughts we have some time
for discussion on the any of these
documents I encourage you to come to the
mic
so this is the document on which the
binding set is waiting this is the uh
our srv6 document uh the authors have
made an update there was also a comment
from midmoy regarding some error codes
that were misaligned between srmpls and
srv6 and authors did a pass for not just
that error code but all the error codes
and I think in the latest update they
have handled this well so please review
and we need to progress this document uh
next uh because as we just talked about
it that it's blocking one of the
documents in RFC editor queue as well as
this document has Ina allocation which
is going to expire though we can of
course ask for renew uh no this one I
think maybe we cannot ask for a new it's
like two things already run so we should
progress this and get it out in the
normal process of course we can ask ads
permission but let's try to do what we
promised to the working room uh and if
anybody has any concerns please let us
know
uh the other set of documents which are
almost nearing working group plus call
we have a document related to Native IP
uh this RFC uh the corresponding RFC is
already published in teas working group
uh there was uh there is it has things
related to bgp and uh John in past it
have pointed out to the IDR mailing list
it got discussed in the IDR mailing list
idea chairs gave some comments which
authors have also handled so I think we
have done our due diligence and we are
ready to send this document and do
working with last call and of course
notify IDR about working group last call
as well so we will do that soon
the other document that is nearing
working group last call is flexgrid this
one has been refreshed we haven't
received many comments the authors
haven't made any big changes looks to be
okay but if you have any concerns please
use this time and let us know otherwise
we will be progressing this work soon
this one which is enhanced error this is
one which we have kind of stuck we
presented the same slide in the last
1114 meeting and I'm
have to repeat the same slide again in
one one five uh we have no inputs the
document is still not being used by
other things which is also giving a
signal that we could see what to do but
again this is your opportunity uh let us
know if you have any thoughts regarding
progressing of this document both to the
authors as well as to the working group
and we will be making a decision very
very soon
so rest of the working group IDs uh we
have path segment document this has been
updated uh mainly editorial change uh
be asked an explicit question in 114
that currently this document has two
ways of doing the same thing it uses PCC
mechanism as well as using the tlv we
have done that in the past it's still
aligned but we wanted to give the
opportunity to the working group to make
sure that they are aware that there are
two mechanisms being standardized and if
there is an issue please voice it out
now otherwise the author's preferences
to use both the mechanisms and they have
Justified that in the document as well
so please review and give your feedback
that's the only issue otherwise I think
path segment in Spring is progressing
quite well so we should be doing that in
PC as well and Publishing this soon
a similar document is about
bi-directional path again mainly
editorial changes looks to be pretty
stable has a similar work is already
done uh
so we will be progressing that soon so I
think we have a question Ahmad uh go
ahead
oh looks like it was by mistake so let's
continue
uh then we have a documents related to
Sr policy Sr policy candidate path this
has been mainly a refresh uh from our
look it seems to be ready like we
haven't had a major update in a while it
was presented in the past ITF has good
support so we will be putting this into
almost ready for working group last call
queue so if people have any thoughts
comments implementers please uh give
your feedback on this document soon
the second one is PCC Sr again no major
update
looks like nearing working plus call if
you have an issue uh please let us know
so with the idea of presenting the
statuses we just want to know what our
thinking is so it gives you gives the
working group an opportunity also to uh
to align and review and give feedback
timely rather than at the wait for the
working group last call only better to
do handle comments as a part of working
group process itself
a multipath has not seen an update but
it is being used uh it has been
implemented the implemented multiple
vendors claim to implement this so which
is good so we would like to progress
this as well soon
uh State synchronization not have been
has not been updated one issue which I
it might be a personal issue that I have
is that document doesn't talk about uh
how to set primary and secondary it says
it's out of scope but anybody who's
implementing it would have to have some
knobs so I wanted to make sure that
people are okay with it to not keep that
part of as a part of the document
and keep this out of scope if you
disagree please use our mailing list and
and let's discuss this
uh the next set of documents are PC
optional no update looks to be ready
uh we have uh if anybody has any
objection please use the mailing list
we have a document stateful into domain
it has expired it has not been updated
but the authors have told that they have
planned to make an update soon and also
they plan to handle the comment related
to enhanced error which I was earlier
talking about that whether this document
can use the extension that is uh that is
suggested in the enhanced error for
stateful interdomain I also there was a
document in the spring working group as
well which was talking about interdomain
currently they focus only on a single PC
case I did bring it up that if they want
to handle multiple pce this will be the
approach of stateful interdomain that
they can explore so that is also
something worth checking across working
group as well
with respect to SRP to employee policy
there has been no update but this is one
of the recent adopted working group
documents so let's give it time for
people to adjust and Implement Etc
uh L2 flow spec this was the document
that was moved out of the original flow
spec document mainly because of IDR flow
spec V2 work it is basically pending uh
the flow spec V2 work to happen in IDR
as well as the L2 flow spec being
published in IDR once those two are done
in the idea working group then I think
psap work can also progress so right now
we are on the waiting stage as far as
the L2 flow spec document is concerned
the Sid algo was adopted I think uh two
ideas ago currently it's in the expired
state so it's a zero zero draft that
that's been expired they are even
pending comments from the working group
adoption stage so I really request
authors to uh refresh this work like
there is all this energy during adoption
but after adoption authors kind of
forget about the work so that should not
happen please refresh your work please
keep it updated please handle the
comments that you received during
adoption process just a reminder to
everyone
and some recent documents we had peace
up uh path MTO when we adopted this work
uh we we are we pointed out that there
should be a work in Spring that should
coordinate this that should Define what
path MTO is in Sr policy context and
both IDR document and P sub document
should refer to that the new ID has been
published in Spring it's been presented
twice now uh hopefully it will get
adopted there as well and then the
dependencies will also be clear and we
can progress the work uh in peace up as
well
uh we have a document iFit which is
anyway on the agenda so I will leave it
out for the uh for the actual
presentation
uh a recent adopted document we have
srv6 Yang which is adopted it is of
course being dependent on our peace of
yank so let's publish that and then we
can make progress good thing is that
it's been updated and the alignment work
between PCP and srv6 yang as ongoing one
thing to note is the document is called
srv6 yank but it has Sr policy as well
as srv6 stuff so please take a note of
it that the document name may not
actually reflect what uh what it
actually it contains both the things so
please be aware of that
we have a working group adoption called
queue uh it's in the wiki uh please give
us feedback if you have a need for for
instance you are implementing it and you
need code points and you want to uh fast
track something your chairs are
listening please reach out we try to
keep our Wiki up to date so that you
have visibility on where the cues are
what's the priority that we are thinking
so please use our Wiki as well
so we have two discussions the key
discussions that happen between the
meeting and we wanted to just highlight
that in the working group session as
well and give people time if they want
to talk about it further uh there was a
proposal for how to enable BFD there
were multiple suggestions whether we use
Association whether we use some other
mechanism but uh all those things are
currently still only on the mailing list
so I have sent a personal message also
to the authors that let's bring the work
into ITF by writing your first internet
draft so that we can follow ITF process
and give comments rather than like you
know exchanging Word documents and doing
this that's not how we do work in ITF so
I'm waiting for the internet draft to be
published and then we can
move work forward
uh the second discussion that was
happening was with respect to PC
operational draft this was presented in
the last meeting and we did discuss what
should be the next step whether we
should break the document into two uh
have a very clear uh standards track
document which clearly says what needs
to be updated and have a much more
bigger clarification document that talks
about uh how to apply uh PC in various
different stateful PC in various
different scenarios give clear
description uh this has been discussed
we started a thread a thread kind of
mellowed down I did respond yesterday we
got one more response and I see now John
wants to say something as well so the
queue is open
thanks John scooter excuse me um yeah so
I I
saw your your comment and thanks for
teeing this up
um
and went and just very quickly glanced
through the current state of the draft
um
I
we can
speaking you know
in terms of like sort of progressing it
through the iesg we can do it either way
as you know one unified draft or as two
separate drafts as as you proposed
through but I will say that I think it
will go more smoothly I mean often I
would prefer to have one draft just to
progress fewer documents but I think it
will actually go more smoothly to have
one
tiny standards track document that's
very crisp and clear
and one informational document that can
provide as much color commentary and
detail as you know the working group
deems necessary
so just you know from sort of my selfish
perspective of of wanting to have an
easier time of being able to move it
through the iesg
um I would encourage you to consider
encourage the working group to consider
the the two document option thank you
thanks John
anyone no let's move on
uh this is again in our Wiki a page that
we created mainly focusing on
coordination with other working group
and research groups so again Wiki is
open to everyone it's not just for
chairs and securities to maintain it's
for the whole working group so when we
have any work that you are similarly
doing in some other working group where
the coordination is needed please come
and keep this Wiki up to date for
instance we have a lot of work coming
from beer from detnet from various
different things we want to coordinate
as as much as possible because as you
know we have noted problem later in this
thing where IDR does the same thing but
in a different way and we miss out
something in PC so we want to avoid
those things going forward so one of the
steps that we thought that we could do
this coordination visibility much more
uh much more better by using our Wiki so
please keep them up to date I have put
many documents list already but I would
prefer if authors do that and they have
the best visibility so please use this
so I just want to send a reminder there
thank you
and that's it
any last thoughts from anyone on any of
the working group documents otherwise
we'll go to the agenda
nope
Sean
foreign
it's very odd this microphone is at the
right height almost
um thank you very much
get away from everybody
um hey so um
Russ Housley and myself are writing this
draft
um in net cloth and we said hey what are
we going to do about TLS 1.3 and the use
of net cloth and it's got some dragons
and drove rightly noticed that maybe
this draft pretty much equally applied
here
so he was like hey what about this draft
so we pretty much said Hey how do we get
together and do this draft together so
we took the text
tweaked like very slightly and over here
so next
so basically the motivation is that 8253
defines how to protect PCP cap with TLS
1.2 and with 1.3 you can just say
something as well you can't just say
next version because this little tweak
that we've um defined called zero rtt
and with zero RTG there are some dragons
because this uh particular mode of using
TLS the the the the flight of messages
includes some
um Badness so it's replayable and you
have to make sure that you have you have
the ability to like protect against that
and depending on your protocol you also
don't need it so the idea that you can
um essentially profile a particular
version of the of the protocol you can
do that so that's what this draft is all
about so the idea is to basically be
explicit about the protocol
um profile
um and it's really about like mostly
it's like don't use this particular mode
um and uh you know otherwise just
basically be exactly like the other
version
next
um so early data is really simple again
so the idea is that like if you've
connected to a um uh
site before when the next time you talk
to them you don't have to worry about
reauthenticating you can just use this
this pre-shared key that's been given
back but if you don't do a lot of that
you don't need it so don't do it so if
you send this particular flight of
messages you can send it quicker but
don't bother if you don't need it a lot
so that's really what it is if you don't
have a lot of reconnection
options or you don't use it that way
just don't use it so because you don't
have to worry about it because to set it
up you essentially have to like do a lot
of Replay protection and it's not needed
so
um and the comments during the
discussion of the working group was
actually really interesting because Tom
was like hey you don't need this and he
said a lot of very strong things which I
don't agree with everything he said but
I was kind of like all right he's kind
of right
um at the end of the day it basically
said like hey if you're going to run
this you don't if you're going to run TS
1.3 you could do it you just don't need
it so actually we reported the comments
from this we're in group adoption back
into netcomf and the net conf working
group was like okay that's great well
let's take those words so at the end of
the day the drafts are actually aligned
already
and the work that's in netcomf is
actually going to go out for working
with last call very shortly so it's kind
of a great way that it worked out
and then Cypher Suite so that they're
slightly different
um in the way that you actually specify
The Cypher Suites you specify less which
is okay because the actual like
mandatory Implement cyber Suites went
from like
a long list to like four and so we
picked less and that's better because
it's
you know the the ones that were picked
by the
um overall uh ITF or better but there's
less to pick from and that's in some
respects better because that means
people concentrate on the ones that
you're picking and so go with those
and and there's there's this little
option about forward secure forward
security which people may or may not
care so the idea is that
um if the force security is that if you
are able to
capture a connection
or a sequence of of flights of messages
and then later on break it you can't
later go back and break it so it's good
that you're able to ensure that the
things that are that were done in the
future are all right so at the end of
the day the protocols is better it's
more provably secure
and that's that's next yeah so Yang
module I don't know if I want to hand
over now let's do that okay
just one slide since I'm the author for
the piece of Yang let me just explain
what we did here so uh basically we use
the netcon document which has the all
the groupings related to how we
configure TLS client and TLS server and
that grouping basically says we can
configure any version of TLs but we are
going to recommend that you use TLS 1.3
and we know that in psip there are still
implementations that are currently using
TLS 1.2 we want our Yang model to be
able to be used in those scenarios as
well and we just want to clarify in our
document that yes it is still possible
to do that you have a feature tls12 that
can still be enabled even though the
Yang model says it's not recommended but
that doesn't mean that it cannot be used
so we added this description a specific
section on how to use how to handle this
TLS version issue in our precept Yang
and hopefully via this update we handle
the comment that Tom pointed out during
the working group last call of young so
this was pretty good conversation led to
a new document as well as clarification
hopefully that would help people who are
implementing and using a young model in
future thank you
so I'll stand up here for like one more
minute while people want to ask me
questions and if not I'll sit down
thank you
so I don't see anyone queuing
so I believe that this is a
straightforward uh draft on this is very
great that it shows that already while
reviewing some existing PC documents so
it's good to catch up with the security
level of the ATF
as a result uh I'd be happy to see a
show of hands for the Abduction of the
document and the progress of this work
so if you agree on support this item
raise your hand if you oppose don't
raise your hand and ideally if you don't
care just
don't respond
let's give a couple of tens of seconds
I see a hundred percent support so far
which is great in any case it will be
resumed as I made English questions so
it gives yeah a great idea
no one opposed okay
so thank you for responding I think we
can end it right now it gives a clear
Trend so we will send a question to the
mailing list about the adoption of this
important document
thank you Sean so the next presenter is
who ammo
who's coming to the mic
hi everyone I'm Juan from future today
I'm going to talk about a pce for Miro
bunting next page
pce has been extended to distribute the
Sr pass
to network nodes
that Sr pass may contain bonding so
bonding here means The Binding sheet
Plus or associated with these sort of
seeds that list of seeds is for another
pass segments
contain a planting seed PC will send the
data bonding which is a
contains binding seed plus these
services
to the node
for example here we have a path from pe1
to P1 to node n
and then to node P3 P6 and then to p
4 so basically this is Sr pass
contains
blue segments
and green segments and then blue
segments those cool reading segments are
indicated by bonding which means that
PC we're also an abundant to know the N
so that binding will contain an
abundance seat B seed plus the city list
here which is S1 and S2
so when node n receive a package with a
binding seat
note n will replace that button sheet
with that list of seats which here is
node n will replace brightness seat with
S1 and S2 so SL1 S1 S2 determines that
Grim per segment so note n
well sit in the package along that green
past segment and then the package was
sent along the path
green per segment and then blue segment
to the destination PE 4.
so here
when a Sr pass contains abundant
PC we're sending to Notre n
so in order to provide protection
for the failure of lot n with the
binding binding seat
PC will be extended to send the funding
information plus
the load ID of load n to the adjacent
node of node n so with this information
the adjacent node of node n can provide
protection for the failure of load n
regarding to The Binding seat
so for example with Note any fails
node P1 will detect the failure of low
go to P1
will pop up the seat for a lot of n
because those rain is already gone it's
failed and then but for the bundling
seat on No 10
P1 will just acting as a proxy level
then replace that abundance sheet with
the list of seat for example S1 and S2
and then send the package along the S1
as S2 for example to P3 and then P3
version packaging along
the Korean paste desolation
here uh in the last
Angel Stone Research some questions
regarding regarding this one
so
so first question is that
so for the adjacent node
so that node
need to figure out something for example
if a segmentalist for example S1 S2 here
is adjacent is adjacent so in this case
because as Jason city is local
so P1
need to do something
so in this case
if
second list for bonding contains
the adjacency basically the first one
which we just considered a
we just care about the first
seat whether it's a adjacency
so here we assume S1 is adjacency
in this case P1 will figure out
the remote
note of that adjacency here
so
P1 will figure out through the adjacency
adjacency
to get the
the remote node ID or remote node seats
which is a p P3 and then
P1 well
replace the banding sheet with
the notice leader of a P3 and then for
the package
to P3 and then P3 will use
whatever is the weather is the adjacency
that will notice it of S2 and then send
the package along the path along the
green pass segment and enter the
destination so that's one question
raised by Angel Stone and then I just
answer here uh
do you have any questions for regarding
this part
good good
foreign
yeah so I saw your reply this morning
thank you for that
um I think I've got a few comments on
just the general solution so what you
commented on yeah totally great makes
sense in that situation thank you thank
you um I think though it creates an
assumption that P1 in this situation
actually has the capability of pushing
the node Sid to reach in this case for
example P3 as well as the remaining SIDS
that are in the stock being provided by
The Binding Sid so imagine if your
binding Sid is instructed with five
labels or five SRV six labels the
assumption is now P1 can do you know
four plus one to work around that or
three plus one to work around that
um so I I think that kind of
creates an implied assumption that the
neighboring node has the sufficient
Hardware capability to push all of those
labels of the path
and so I think this brings probably a
more fundamental question of if we're
trying to protect n
and The Binding Sid do we still want to
route along the complete path that the
Bindings that has taken or do we want to
rewrote where the writing set terminates
because you've got those label in
position on that neighboring node and so
it could be possible that your
neighboring know that you're transiting
through P1 in this case
actually can't carry all of that traffic
that The Binding set is providing which
is why The Binding sit exists in the
first place
um so it kind of leads then into I think
another open question of
or another open challenge is that the
assumption is P1 can resolve where
n is going to go right so the local
adjacency said
I agree with you if it's you know an igp
adjacency SID it can figure it out from
the igp information but if it's in a
different domain it can't
if it's a epe sid it can't
you know in the future there could be
other segment IDs where it just that
local P1 can't know what is the neighbor
Beyond
so I think it raises the question of
should PC actually tell P1 what see what
Sid or stack of Sids it should use to
actually protect that node Zid or sorry
protect that binding said
so for example instead of telling P1
here is a binding sit of your neighbor
here is the path of the binding Sid
instead here is The Binding Sid here is
a list of Sids that you shall use to
protect that binding Zone
yeah that's a good question yeah so
right now we assume that igpe will
distribute those kind of adjacency and
then the P1 figure out that one and so
you you imply that maybe pce can do
something if the the planting segment is
contain the adjacency and then PC may
just figure out the node seat of a P3
right so that notice since then notice
it to
P1 and that is P1 can make Poise work
easy right is that your comments yeah
and it yeah and it handles and it
handles other situations especially with
multi-domain or pcecc and just
situations where P1 doesn't know where
that said is going to go and and it and
it opens up the door for PC to decide
like as I mentioned instead of rerouting
to the next node you can rewrote
somewhere Downstream which can even be
traffic engineered right it or other
binding sets it opens up a lot more
flexibility
um and I think after reading the email
this morning and I'm still planning to
reply to it and then coming to this
working group I think the solution of
protecting the node that's carrying a
binding Sid I'm worried that we might be
repeating different
you know descriptions in both PC and IDR
and so I'm wondering if the solution
should be taken out into let's say
routing working group or even spring
and then worry about the encoding after
the fact because the encoding between
bgp and P sub is going to be very
similar situations it's just how do you
actually want to solve the problem
and I think in our discussions right now
I think there's a few different ways to
solve it and I think there needs to be
some consistency on how we want to solve
it yeah in fact that this is a
we have a protection drop in Spring
and then child suppose uh I think
in order to provide protection for node
failure responding seat and then we need
a
PC or igp IDR extension that's why we
come here we already have a draft for
protecting the planting seed in Spring
group okay and then we need and then we
did a support from the other
a political extensions okay such as pce
I might have missed that I'll take a
look for that but uh I think
clarifying exactly how we want to
protect it and then deal with the
encodings after
because there's some weird quirks here
especially when you start talking about
multi-area multi-domain different types
of Sids if if it was just node SIDS in
the stock and if P1 had enough Hardware
capacity that's not a big deal but
unfortunately that's not the reality
sometimes so anyways thank you
yeah thank you for your for your comment
on the suggestions
I think this is for the SS Angel
mentioned that this is so for the node n
is which in the domain is easy
so if that note n
is a border node
yeah that case is even tougher because
border node
and then
the previous over the uptrend node do
not know
the past segment because that uh domain
so in in that case
so we needed to have equals production
because that no 10 is an eagerness node
so we need to have a backup equals node
to be assigned to protected node end and
then we have those kind of a
that's the requirement you you said
question so if node N is a border node
and then the board node we have a backup
border node and then in that case and
then backup buttoners know the
information about another domain with
same information as another n
um I think it's probably debatable
whether or not it's considered an egress
node because it's still an end-to-end
tunnel and The Binding Sid is still part
of that end-to-end packet that n10 path
there's no de-encapsulation at that
point
so
at that point when it's leaving you know
a domain it's still part of that tunnel
so it's not necessarily egressing the
tunnel it's just egressing the domain or
the forwarding instructions where
the control plane in that domain has a
view and perspective of what's beyond
but it's still in the same tunnel so I
think the egress protection is more
applicable onto egressing of a tunnel
man yeah you're right you're right yeah
the technology is another yet because
these are final touches Nation this is
the Border note yeah more personality
you're right
the next page so here is the extension
to species
first we have a need to
have a new capability so this capability
is for distributed binding information
for protection
basically in the
past setup
type capability we need to need to
include a new
PSD type for distributed funding for
protection and then we may have a
special TRV
which contains the parameters
so if we have a PCC then we just Define
new new beat which is B beat
that's a b bit indicate
the capability for
distributed bonding for protection
next page
for distributed bonding to the adjacent
node
so because this is not a really funding
so we need to have indications
to indicate that this is just for
funding protection
so here we have extensions to RP and the
SRP object
so in this object
we have a percent of POV so this is tlv
will contain a new
password
PhD type
which indicate that this is just for
distributed abundant for protection
in addition to that because we also need
the ID of that that post will fail the
node so we just have us
TRV contain the ID
of that possible failure
so next page
I think that's all and then we would
like to uh have a comment from all of
you
let me put myself
uh one comment as a contributor uh
especially I think I agree with a lot of
things that Andrew mentioned so I think
we need to take at least the core of the
work in spring or in rtgwg where we
describe how this thing process needs to
work and there are various options as
well like should we only node IDs needed
do we need destination do we need path
do we need uh what we are protecting
what all the information that we need to
exchange from a PC or from IDR point of
view that we need a little bit more
clarification on that and then once we
come to the extension uh that work of
course will belong in the PC working
group and even with the extension part
uh we can debate on what will be the
best way to encode this information but
that is premature because we don't
really know right now what all
information it is if it is just node ID
maybe what you have makes sense but if
we also put paths and all so what you're
currently the encoding by adding this
tlv and RP may not make much sense so I
think let's postpone that discussion and
first focus on at a higher level what
all information that we need to pass to
make this mirror binding work
John
John Scudder um actually I think all I
really want to say is plus one
um
please do the work once in a group that
has the uh the core expertise to get the
architecture right and then it'll be
really easy to do the rest of it here
after that's done thank you
Sean thank you
okay thank you everyone thanks thank you
Emma
next
next presenter is
Giuseppe
about iFit to Transmission in the
working group introduction
hello everybody this is an update about
this draft that has been adopted
just last ATF so
next slide I'm present I'm Joseph I'm
presenting on behalf of the co-authors
so yeah few words about the background
and motivation so with iFit with the
notes the data plane on path Telemetry
in particular in c2im that is defined in
the RFC 9197 and Alternate marking
that which the standard track documents
are in NFC area editor 2 the 8321 bits
and 8889bs so let's say the data plane
methodology are stable so here we want
to define the psap extension to
distribute paths carrying iFit
information so a PCC can indicate which
I fit features it supports and the PCA
can configure the specific behavior
at the PCC so the effect attributes can
be generalized and include as tlv
carried in the ls in the lspa object so
next slide
so the draft defined two tlvs basically
the capability advertisement tlv and the
attributes tlv the capability tlv
is an optional tlb in the open object
for the capability advertisement of psap
so we find we Define Five Flags
according to the RFC 9197 and the
alternate marking uh in addition uh we
Define also the attributes dlv that
provide the configurable option for the
features for the fit feature and it can
be included as an optional tlb in the
lspa object as I also mentioned before
and so the five sub tlbs that are
defined are the four tlv for nc2m and
one for alternate marking
more details of course are within the
draft time I missed here the details
because we already presented last time
so next slide
yeah I just this is maybe the last slide
I just want to summarize the changes
from the zero zero version because we
had some comments uh after the adoption
and during the adoption so we we
addressed this comment uh we clap mainly
we clarify that the head end needs
support the if it capability and it is
supposed that at least two nodes
on the path support uh the fit
capability we also clarified that the
fit methods are more mature for srv6
compared to SRM apls in fact
in in the implementation of
uh bought in c2im and Alternate marking
for mpls are still under discussion with
so uh there was a comment to remove all
the references to this draft that are
not stable so we only uh keep the
references for the srb6 implementation
that are uh the the references are quite
stable for example the application for
alternate marking is again in RFC editor
queue and also the the eom extension for
a pv6 is in isg review so we can say
that this methodology are stable then we
also clarify the relation with the IDR
draft
uh you know that bot psap and bgp can be
used to instantiate Sr policy so it is
reasonable to have the same mechanism
for both psap and bgp so we are also
trying to keep the two drafts aligned uh
and we also clarify the methodology with
regard to the framework
and then we had also added additional
editorial comments so next slide
yeah
[Music]
um
we found let's say this is a document
relevant to enable bottom and Alternate
marking control mechanism of course we
always welcome question and comments to
improve the document and to keep aligned
with other work thank you
secrets
any question from the group for Tuesday
pay
no no
thank you Elizabeth okay thanks for the
follow-up
so the next presentation is for
uh control identifier space
by Han
okay
I've given okay you should be able to
okay hello everyone my name is Hunter
and I'm going to talk about the psap
controlled ID space an extension to the
PC
yeah uh as we all know we use pce to
allocate the
srmps enable and the srv6 seat but this
route assume the naval and ID range to
be used by the VC is normal and set on
both PC peers
so our document specified the intention
to support the advertisement of the IDS
base to the PC to control
yeah uh basic news it drops is very
simple to to delegate in the ID space
the ID space TRV is included in the open
message and the etlv corresponding to
each ID type should be included only
once in the open message if it appeared
more times only the first one will be
used and we Define two kinds of ID
controls with TRV the first one is for
srmps enables it's called enable control
space and the second one is for SRA 6 C
functional ID space is called the
functional ID control space
yeah the the first one is the naval
controls with TRV it contains the
following Fields the first field is the
number of the ID blocks and the flags is
zero and follow the apply the
various the enable range
and for the srv6 function ID control
space TRV we also have the following
structure and
the first is the number of ID blocks
and the flags there is a one bit is
indicated if the location and locator
field is included
and followed by the C structure to
describe the the structure of the seed
the the same structure is shown in the
next side it's including the the Nokia
tournaments the functions and arguments
and then we have uh see the range and if
the air bit in the flag is that the
locator will included if the lbs is not
set that means the the seed function
range is applied to all locator
and basically it says it's a
Samsung update from the NASA
presentation we expanded the sra6 pass
ID to various function ID and we add the
C structure to describe the the seed and
we add the block of field for better
expensibility then add me as a new new
co-author so we are I always we think
the content is stable so we are asking
for the working group adoption opposite
draft
the document is already in the working
group adoption queue based on the past
then thanks for keeping it up to date is
there any concerns from anyone on this
document any comments
chank go ahead are you in the room
foreign
so thank you for putting presentation
it's really clear and as a course I
think URI the the content is stable so
we should ask for working for adoption
and thank you for all guys for listening
thank you
same presenter for the new one
you know same same
somehow
change
able let me do it just wait a second
and then I'll give you control
share
and then let me pass control
now you should be able to control okay
so my second draft is about a pce
initiated IP IB terminal
yeah basically the motivation is that in
the sty use case
ipturnal is needed to Traverse the one
and pce can use as a control protocol to
initiate this IP terminal
and this is also a simple draft
basically you need to divide advertise
the the hypertonal compatibility and to
set up maintain and tear down the IP
kernels initiated by the pce
uh since this is only the first draft we
do not include the internal stage
synchronization and various timeout
process session final process in the in
this draft
yeah uh the PC initial internal
capability TR we designed as follows
yeah uh there is a 32-bit Channel type
if a PCC can support this kind of Kernel
One beta is set we pick the we pick the
mostly used terminal in the in the right
table
foreign
with design the following message the
first one is the PC internally initiate
message to initiate alternator tunnel PC
is sent to the PCC and there is a flag
that we indicate if it's initiate what
it did
and the second one is the PC terminal
update message to modify the parameter
of the kernel it's also sent by the pce
to PCC and the third one is this
internal report message is for the PCC
to report the state of the terminal to
the pce
and this message compromise the SRP
object
it contains the ID to coordinate it
between the initiate and Report or the
PC error message under Arsenal indicates
that in
initialization origination and the
message also contains Eternal objects
yeah for the kernel object there is many
some TRV
for the first one is the internal ID TRV
contains the source stress that
designation dress internal type internal
ID and the second one is the internal
name TRV and the third one is the
internal parameter it depends on the
ternal type we reuse the tunnel
parameter from the bgp Eternal type so
it's basically in the same format and
the terminal attribute TRV contains the
metric or the T metric The Matrix is
used as a kind of the T metric used as
the the requirement and the metric is
used
for the for the report
yeah since this is only the the first uh
basically the first round we would like
to solicitate the feedback on this route
for example which type of alternative
support in this uh in this kind of five
internal we currently use this DGP
tunnel
registry but is the first comprocessor
registry or we can pick the mostly used
and do we need to add the thermostat
synchronization in the in in the in the
future
yeah that's all
any comments
Andrew
I um I guess the root question I have is
why use piece up for this if there's no
path to compute
you can sing called The Eternal as some
kind of the past you Traverse the one
because there will be multiple choice
but I mean like couldn't you just use
netconf to provision this or just SNMP
or just any one of the flavors of
mediation protocols yeah it's possible
but we can also use pce to do that right
I guess I just see what is the benefit
of using psup to do it compared to
something just you can program anything
with netcon for example so it just seems
like a lot of defining to be done for
just essentially at the end of the day
just basic configuration because you're
not doing make before break path
calculations you're not doing state
tracking in order to react to those
States information so it just
it just feels heavy to me yeah when you
create a tunnel you can attach your team
metric to request that you create a
certain
internal correct bounding to this T
metric there's kind of the use case so
okay maybe I'll have to go back here
thanks
okay then go ahead
so I think it can it removed yourself
from the queue I think Robin
foreign
years ago because but later we found
that we found identify this the new user
cases that use the ip800 to transfer
this the network for example in the sd-1
use cases because maybe that's used to
utilize this IP tunnel to Traverse this
underlying Network so that we need to
initiate this IP tunnel by the
controller so we think use the pce that
is has achieved this better
sustainability and performance so we we
start this work and the comments will
come okay
okay then go ahead
as for the presentation uh in the
introduction section of the draft uh the
the use case or what is uh what is
mentioned there is that this tunnels
help in uh addressing the label stack
depth issue MSD issue uh uh I mean it's
different from what was presented today
and my question is uh uh how does it
help there and is that really the use
case
yeah there's also another use case but
we think that C1 is more relevant now
you know
okay so what I would suggest is uh if
you could uh kind of put some more text
to explain or Justify those use case and
how these things would uh help there uh
that would be helpful
I I concur with what Andrew mentioned uh
so we need to probably help understand
uh if this is really needed or a right
way to go about it thank you okay
foreign
thanks for the kittens suggestion in
fact we had this another draft used to
talk about this the application
scenarios and free work of this tunnel
segment so later we send this in the
main list for references so here are
there so we can discuss more about this
possible use cases
foreign any other comments
let me have myself in the queue then uh
thanks for uh thanks for your comment
but uh I think the motivation is needed
in the draft itself we need to clearly
specify why we need this functionality
and not just because why we need IP
tunnels that part is clear basically but
why we need to use psip as the interface
for that IP tunnel and that we need a
Clarity uh before we progress this then
when it comes to encoding again we have
to make a choice is do we want to go
through new messages for this or we have
path setup type we already allow path
setup type to handle srv6 which is sort
of an IP tunnel in a way so do we need a
brand new set of messages to go or
should we use our existing Machinery
that already exists in psap if we want
to continue with that work but first
thing is like I think we need consensus
on whether we have enough motivation in
this working group to do ipt tunnel wire
reset that would be my comment but thank
you for your work
anybody else this was our last
presentation anybody else any other
business
I think you should close
so we've reached the end of our pch in
there for today so to see the end of the
ITF week
here in London thank you for attending
whether it is remotely or on site and
hopefully see you in Yokohama
thank you
thank you everyone safe travel
thank you thank you cheers
um
[Music]
consumerator
yes
um
so I was on
it yeah