foreign
uh I guess it's 9 30. correct at the
local time okay it's 1 30 in the morning
in California
so welcome
everyone no matter where you are thank
you for coming
so good morning good afternoon and good
evening
and uh
hope you've been enjoying the ietf week
in London
this is the reliable and available
Wireless or raw working group and I'm
Eve Schuler and I'm remote in California
and Rick is in the room
I am here so uh yeah let's kick off
let's make the slides
okay
well it's like tuna oh there we go so
um as with every IDF meeting this
meeting is covered by the note well if
this is your first session given it's
Friday that's that's I hope unlikely
um or your first ietf and you haven't
had a chance to read this uh the note
well covers the IPR your participation
in meetings that's a bit of feedback
um Please be aware that uh anything you
state at the microphone plays onto the
mailing list or
um comment in general or is covered
under the IPR regulations of the ietf
and do you have agreed by that if you
are unaware of any of this please check
the relevant pcps which we normally call
out I think from the next page yes on
the next page on the next page so here
is a list of various pcps which should
uh introduce you to the internet
standards process uh and the processes
of working groups uh
talk about your about copyrights patents
and participation rules but also I will
draw attention to the Angie Harrison
procedures harassment procedures and
code of conduct although we promote
vigorous debate
um bullying and unacceptable behavior is
obviously unacceptable and there is a
process to address this so if you feel
the behavior becomes I understand out of
hand please let the chairs know it's our
responsibility to prevent that from
happening and there is a proper well
thought out formal process to handle it
just to draw your attention to it
foreign
[Music]
because this is a joint remote and
in-person meeting and I must say it is
very nice to see so many people in
person this is feeling like an
old-fashioned ietf again which I'm so
sorry Eve there's a really nice Buzz
here and you're missing it someday
because we're going to use a shared
queue for the mics please make sure you
use the little app on your phone or or
click the uh join the queue button on
your laptop so that remote participants
can also join the queue fairly so we
don't have two cues
um as ever if you're speaking please
state your name first it's just useful
for the note takers
um mask wearing yeah mask in the room
please it's policy unless you are
actively speaking at the microphone
myself as actively speaking at the
moment also to avoid feedback can you
mute your uh laptop audio particularly
if you're remote to save on feedback
headphones strongly recommended if you
are at home
um
yeah that's it so
we will be using the integrated
meteco interactive markdown for minutes
um
this is a collaborative tool I don't
believe we have an official minute taker
so please either if you want to take
copious minutes please attack right now
but more importantly if you want to make
a point and you don't believe it's being
caught or your name is not being
captured spelled correctly please get
into that online minutes and and make
sure that's properly recorded
the probably collaboration is everyone
assumes everyone else is going to
collaborate rather than you and then we
don't capture the minutes correctly so
it's a sort of group responsibility to
make sure we've got some proper minutes
taken uh the meeting materials uh I'm
assuming by the fact you can see these
slides you can get to this URL so it's a
bit of a recursive problem but
um all the meeting materials are
available through the data tracker and
through the low speed Echo integration
and as ever we are an ietf working group
which means we have a mailing list which
is raw.etf.org I hope you are all
subscribed uh that is the best place to
have long and lengthy discussions
um and if you need to contact the chairs
for uh admin purposes there is a raw
hyphen shares mailing list to be used
for
um
administrative purposes not for topics
of uh content discussion and there's the
um
let me take us come back again right
we've had some
had some networking issues this week
is it recovering
yes
oops maybe not
shall I give it a shot from over here
find the slides again
sorry
small technical details we do not
apparently have reliable and available
Wireless in the room so
so Eve do you want to go through the
document status otherwise it's just been
talking
sure
um so uh for those of you who may not be
tracking uh on the mailing list uh the
um the status of things we are very
close due to the hard work of the
authors and our A.D John Scudder the
ldax document is on the brink of uh
ready being completely ready it's uh the
last of the discuss
um
status of various
ads and reviewers
have now been converted to abstains I
believe John is uh wanting to give it
one last very detailed read so we may be
within a within the next week or two
um having the ldax document Advance
through the RFC process so we're very
excited about that and uh again thanks
to the hard work of all the whoops all
the folks involved the the let me just
see if I can
I'll share the deck it went away again
let me yeah let me just see if I can get
that
over at this end are you can you see
that in the room
yeah we can see that okay here you go
um
so and the use cases draft
uh has similarly begun uh to progress
through the iesg and has received
um let's see a routing review uh and uh
it's been through the tsv so the
transport and gen art uh reviews as well
and thanks to I believe
um
is it Karina who is the uh Shepherd for
this
um we are now at uh a REV of the
document I think it's eight
um having Incorporated all of the
feedback from the three reviews so far
uh we still have quite a few that we
await
um then the Technologies draft has begun
that journey and so
um uh Carlos bernardos has
um you know solicited the feedback from
the uh authors on IPR so at least at
this moment in time we haven't uh gotten
any uh there's nothing eventful
happening in on the IPR front I mean no
one has any
um anything to declare there but in the
meantime we've had a funny exploration
of the draft but I think uh once things
open up again
um it will be resubmitted there was also
some interesting activity on the 3gpp
front in the SAT at SA
can I interrupt you just calluses at the
mic just hello sorry I was just looking
at the document I was like
ahead Carlos
um just to to basically apologize for
not taking or not progressing on the on
the separating for that document I I
started I expect to have the
the right up in the next one or two
weeks while the IPR uh declarations are
are made so I just wanted to update a
bit on that and apologize for taking a
bit longer than it should have been
clicking so thanks no worries we are
greatly appreciative of you uh taking on
the shepherding and um in the queue as
well Eve sorry go for it I'm looking in
the wrong places I got I don't have
enough Windows here hi Pascal not pop up
in the corner of your screen no it is I
was on the wrong View at where I am so I
wasn't seeing the
go ahead let's go just for Carlos since
you have to indicate the number
um I owe janash to publish a slight
update
of the technology draft because of the
new references that the inertia has
provided and probably that's what Eve is
alluding to as well so I will publish it
like next week arrive so you know
perfect and for those of you
um who may not know that there was a
detnet study group in the 3gppsa2 group
and um and so they have a new
publication and so there's some slight
wording updates regarding
um the recommendations there uh that
once things open up
um Pascal will resubmit on
and um and then life goes on with
regards to the other documents uh we'll
hear a lot today about the architecture
document
um the framework document is a little
bit uh off into the future oam is
progressing
um we do need to understand what's
happening with our industrial
requirements document our last
correspondence was that there was going
to be a new rev uh but we're uh we need
to close on that
um and then of course there are three
um documents I think they're all
Carlos's uh uh at least he's a co-author
on them
um that are under consideration for a
working group adoption have I missed
anything
if if I'm corrective call us as
published personal drafts because
they're interesting but I'm not sure you
asked for working group adoption I think
you said no we have not do a bit more
work on this so it's it's not really for
consideration of the working group as
work but certainly of interest to the
working group is that right Carlos is at
the mic uh yes basically
um I I was waiting a bit for the working
group to be done with the other uh
actual Milestones to then ask to the
working group if this may be considered
as something interesting so I will be
waiting until the other things are out
of the line
I think that makes a lot of sense
okay all right I'm controlling the
slides
the thing that the sleepy person in the
room or the virtual room needs to
remember is to advance those lives
um and so our agenda today is uh really
to focus and give time to the
architecture draft
um and Pascal has done a tremendous
amount of work on it with his co-authors
and there's been lots of discussion both
on and off the list and he will be
giving us a very detailed update on that
at this point so
um
I'm conscious that we have a good size
session today and and the architecture
draft is
um it's getting a lot of review it's
getting a lot of comment and it's it's
slightly blocking our work so really
what I would like to see is uh us really
tackle the architecture draft almost
Workshop it we have the time we have
relevant people in the room and and as a
precursor to this uh Pascal uh
[Music]
myself had had a pre-meeting to talk
about how can we how can we make
progress what are the main sticking
points here are they insurmountable can
we make progress or have we have we got
a problem here
and the answer was actually we didn't
have a problem we could make progress
but the recommendation from in fact the
decision by the chairs and and thank you
Pascal for for letting us make that
decision was
given the architecture document
actually has two introduces two new
Concepts one very much about how does
raw make deterministic forwarding plane
decisions and a separate
novel piece of work which is a new kind
of service function or a forwarding
plane uh protection function which is
the the pareo function
by introducing both of these new pieces
of work within one document firstly the
document got big
and the bigger the document the harder
it is to review and the harder it is to
maintain readability Etc as we all are
well aware and secondly
we felt as chairs that the
um
the introduction of the new uh
forwarding plane control ability and
that fast feedback loop around PSE was
the architectural piece and the perio
piece could be introduced in parallel at
a slightly slower rate
so we can have an architecture document
without having to get the details of
perio correct in one big bang
we should just split the document in
half and that means we would have a
lighter architecture document that would
talk about PSE and make sure it was a
good quality document that framed a
bigger pardon that framed what raw was
hoping to achieve and then we could take
time to get perio nicely described have
good quality discussion and review and
so on
the complication when splitting a very
large document is there is now quite a
large group of contributors
and
it is always difficult trying to
attribute the right text to the right
people particularly when there have been
many revisions and many contributions
some which may have not survived the
different revisions and so as chairs we
took the often unpopular decision to say
both of these documents will now have
one editor all contributors will be
placed in the acknowledgments section
and acknowledged as key contributors to
the document but there will now be an
editor rather than a set of authors of
both of these documents
um I will say the chairs and the ad are
very happy to discuss that decision to
make sure people understand that the
authors understand that clearly but
we'll take that Offline that that isn't
really a matter for the working group
it's a it's a matter for the chairs
given we are moving to the there is an
editor and a group of and and the
working group contributes to it model
you have to name that editor as Pascal
has been carrying the editorial pen at
least over the last couple of revisions
and he's happy to do so uh we wish to
make Pascal the editor of these
documents again if you feel that is
contentious and you have any complaints
about it please talk to the chairs and
the ad and we will get this resolved in
some way as far as the working group is
concerned I believe this decision will
help us make progress on Raw
architecture and let us do proper review
and consideration on perio and unblock
some of the workers Carlos alluded to
which is sat in the backlog waiting for
adoption or for those of us to find
review time to look at when we have a
nice architecture document we're really
happy with that can frame our our
decisions and our reviews
would anyone Carlos is at the mic go for
it
thanks Carlos
um I I don't have any issue with the
decision uh I'm perfectly fine I think
this is the right one to
keep Pascal as a leader of documents I I
had just a qualification question so is
this a split meant to be like one
document is will will be like taking
care of how the uh raw architecture
entangles with the dead net and ensure
that everything is coordinated while the
other one will basically take care of
the very much Wireless specifics and in
this way kind of
uh facilitate the integration I mean
because you mentioned
optimize functions will be in the new
work document
to me that's fine and then the
interaction with the OEM generalized.net
will be in the other one to me that
would make sense but I don't know if I
understood properly the idea behind
yes I believe you have understood
correctly
um you you said one thing there which I
would qualify which is
um the architecture document is the you
said less one is focused I would
disagree there because I would say in
that architecture document we still talk
about the fast feedback loop with the
OEM plane because Wireless moves much
faster than than in general wired
networks and so we have that faster
feedback loop and that PSE concept which
I would suggest is
very much uh
uh Wireless focused you know these are
Wireless adaptations but then the the
details of the the protection function
uh perio specifically Wireless optimized
protection function makes more sense
yeah I agree I express myself not very
clearly of course the the pses the quick
architecture component enabling this and
this is in the first document I mean
that then the specific function that
this component may do to do these things
is in the other one yeah okay thank you
I'm going to pause here if anyone else
has any comment on on this decision this
is a good moment to air concerns if you
have any
otherwise
Carlos is still in the queue no he's
gone
um
otherwise we'll move on what's the next
slide I think we're going to get
straight into the into the guts a bit
aren't we yeah so
Pascal you have plenty of time
let's
okay so uh probably I'm entitled to take
this off I'm the lucky guy in this room
I that's probably not going to work for
my laptop so
um
try it it's not paired with my machine
and I'm showing the slides so I don't
think oh yeah
okay
well next slide please
okay so
um I will start with the draft with the
slides I prepared before the meeting
knowing that with the recent discussion
some of that is partly resolved or
appears to be on good way of resolution
to be agreed with the group and uh so
we'll see where we are for which those
slides might be slightly obsolete
so what happened recently is a lot of
great reviews I mean a lot of exchanges
with lu yeah thank you all for for the
time you you spent on on
reading the document and and considering
it and Etc
uh part of the results is uh Lou is uh
added as a contributor to document and
but now she strongly acknowledged I
don't remember if it is on the published
version but you are certainly in the
acknowledgment Village
um
and then there were lucaments about
pario that we are still need that still
need to be discussed and with you know
the decision that the chairs made uh
those commands now will apply to a
separate document and so they will be
made separately and they are not
blocking the architecture document
anymore
we did a lot of restructuring to help
the new readers because we're all used
to what we are saying but the new reader
may want something more serial so we we
reorganized a bit the introduction got
simpler
um and based on the comment by Liu of
what is raw exactly we we extracted a
new sections free
also the term UDA appeared many times
that it was a fundamentally new thing so
that has been there for like 50 plus
years
um and the fact that it respects the UDA
model is not the fundamental fundamental
thing the fundamental thing is we have
this fast control Loop
UDA is a model for control Loop is the
model the model that we are following
but it's a control Loop so we we renamed
the section row control Loop to insist
it is a control loop as opposed to
insisting that it's following the
odometer
right
uh there was also these points I mean
it's my French here uh where I said
something like Row versus Net in one
section title and for me it meant
nothing
but probably in English
there is a sense to that
and we I really made you know how do you
compare this and that that was the
meaning but these verses that appears to
be a conflict
certainly rowan.net don't conflict the
goal is that you know it's we are
providing a plug-in functionality into
that net and so there is it cannot
conflict it has to smoothly integrate so
certainly the title gave the wrong
impression sorry for my French
um so yes we clarified that you know row
is a specialized announcement that
mostly applies to wireless but since we
are layer 3 it could apply anywhere
but the needs really appeared in the
context of ILS through RS mesh
next slide please
a number of issues that we discussed
there was one and probably it's against
again my French all the way expressed
things but seemed that the text could be
read as if we were changing something on
wireless we are not touching Wireless
that would be a layer violation the best
we can do is Prov provide hints to the
lower layer about the sort of thing we
would like to see achieved
and we currently don't have even the
apis for doing this but the architecture
should show that we expect that someday
we might have something and we need to
position it and that something is
basically some capability to
hint the lower layers of the sort of
result that we would like to see an
example of results is if you send
something on Wi-Fi today you'll get by
default 64 retries which could take
forever
in in row that doesn't make any sense
because we have we have a bounded
latency
so at some point we need to tell hey Mr
Wi-Fi I know you're doing your best but
if you don't send that within that
bonded latency drop it
or a if you can please do at least a few
retries right you don't know you're
doing that that's Layer Two but try to
make the reliability of this packet a
factor five I don't know how to express
that but make it more reliable than this
other packet
by doing more retries doing retries
faster I don't know the way you do it
okay so conceptually the architecture
should represent
that service access point basically
between layers three and lower layer
where we can express more than just here
is a packet do your stuff
okay
it may be that this interface could be
useful for wires as well because at some
point if we don't have a time-based
shaper and we have something like a an
essential shaper it may be that we want
to provide a lower layer with the
bounded latency as well
um so yes we we clarify that we we are
the architectural layer so what we are
doing is conceptual but we are basically
adding new services
and they are considered and meant to
apply at least to the technologies that
we we support we have in our Charter and
are listed in the Raw technology
um
there is this this problem of one Hub
which could be solved at Layer Two and
multi-hub which is what we do at layer
3. and certainly we
we already have a lot of work and
capabilities for
getting information from the lower layer
and then we use that in writing we
compute we have our SSI we lqi we we can
do it TX there are tons of things we can
do we've got delete and we want to build
on all this
and at the same time we need to to do it
over Malta help
so um
we need to differentiate this concept
and see how they work together that's
part of of what the architecture must
represent
and then there was this this question
from it was coming from the blue but one
of the parallel functions is is over a
yearing meaning that one sounds
and you know by the magic of of the
radio transmission there will be
multiple receivers
and again it's probably my French I must
have written it such a way that it looks
oh it's completely new to write jokes
radios and obviously yellow wires were
like that so it's not like it's
completely new to radios uh if you
configure a switch with promiscuous mode
on one port that bot will get all the
packets mostly we do it for tracing not
for forwarding but but that exists you
could even illumination that you could
even have an underlay which is a
multicast to send your unique aspect
I've never seen that I don't know why we
should do it but it's feasible
um so yes over a yearing could happen at
a cost just happened that for wireless
yes one transmission from A to B is less
C compared to wires but there are ways
which are other properties of the same
medium by which this disadvantage can be
compensated and and it comes from the
same magic that causes the loss is that
others can listen to it can we do
something to compensate the fact that
one point to point radio obstruction is
low C with the fact that in fact
physically speaking it is a pawn to
multi-point thing
and that's really what we want to
discuss with these promiscuous over
hearing thing don't say hey yes you you
receive ratio drops if you consider the
link as point to point like we would on
wires typically
but on this on the other hand there is a
zero four ratio on the other guy here
that we could exploit because he got it
if we consider that in the overall
routing a maybe the the loss here is
compensated by the received is there and
rho is a lot about doing that and one of
the methods effectively that we can
Leverage is this of our urine sec
so we we insist that
it's not it's something that yes it was
always there it's not the question the
question is here we intend to really use
it and build on it and consider that it
exists and include it now rotting
thinking so that if the the packet is
received by the wrong guy and the wrong
guy is on the right path yeah the packet
can continue
see that that's that's part of raw
next slide please
okay so when I said that some of these
slides and that's basically a third of
them is probably obsolete by now this is
this is it
so um
we need to discuss Barrio we need to go
into the details of how it works what it
does whether it's new or not is not so
relevant more relevant is how we're
going to use it
how we're going to abstract it how we're
going to talk to the lower layers to get
them to do things for us because we
don't do it for the most Peace by
ourselves at day or three
but it's another document so this
document is supposed to give the big
picture so we have we have this tension
it's not on the slide but I realize we
had this tension with Lou about a new I
mean you know you're free to come to the
mic anytime if I'm not misspeaking but
we have this tension where I had an
intention that this architecture is the
big picture I did not focus so much on
what's new what's not new I focused on
here is how it works right here is there
is the map of London
and if the the London Bridge has been
there for 200 years it's still on the
map it's still a fundamental component
of this architecture
whereas another reader could say hey all
these things I know them well I just
want this document to focus on exactly
what's new well if I just give you
what's new you don't have the map of the
city you just have the shot right so
there is this tension about you know
wasting time of the reader by saying
something he already knows and yes in
everywhere and the fact that you still
need to provide the map of the city
so that's something we have to arbitrate
but um personally I'm happy with the
current content of the document I would
not like to strip it too much so I focus
really only on the very new things I
want to to show how the components are
integrated together the new and the old
and then there was this track segment uh
T path and I still need to lose help on
exactly crafting the words but we we
inherit from Two Worlds like this Java
class which originate from two to
interfaces and and there might be
collisions and effectively we've got
collisions
um
in the small tiny iot groups
we have agreed that the term path was so
overused overloaded that it lost a lot
of its significance and we kind of when
we talk about path we end up not really
figuring out what the guy is talking
about
so for the thing that we built
for radio multipath Etc we crafted this
term of truck
and so I as I'm coming from that world
I've been using it and using it and
using it it's using the 60s architecture
it is in the role documents it is
everywhere
and if you look at it it does not
represent a path as most of us are used
to call a path a path in the past
research working groups and stuff is an
observable thing it is the result of a
packet going through a network the path
is where this packet has been to go from
A to B it is a consequence it is an
observable I I have listed in the
document the quote because if I don't
speak it correctly at least the code is
in the architecture
um
now if you go to other documents you
will see other definitions of path and
they're they got more and more wide and
more and more elastic
and then Lou understands the definitions
that are done in teas Etc so but but my
concern was
path is supposed to be an actual thing
it's supposed to be where the packet is
going to be and it's observable it's
measurable you know what it's going to
be just like my example for that is the
moon around the earth which has an orbit
you know where the Moon is you know it's
going to be and if there is something
which should cause the moon to change
its strike like we send this big uh bomb
on the moon to make it change like in
Cosmos 99 for those who have seen that
it's still predictable we know will
control we'll know we're going to do
that we'll throw the truck out at the
Moon it will change its orbit and we'll
know the new orbit
now track is not like that the truck is
the aggregate of all the possible place
the packet can be
but at any point of time you don't know
where it is the packet can be Network
coded meaning that it's turned into
smaller chunks which are sent on
different paths there is not one place
where the packet is
okay and because of the PSC activity at
for for this packet and maybe a few
packets
it's going to be a subset of all those
hubs which are going to be used for this
packet it's not the whole track the
whole story of what we are doing here is
to not use the full track
but always use a subset of it that is
enough to get 2.5 copies of your packet
to the end
but it's never the same until you stop
the system and observe one package you
never know what the packets will be
so that's why I like this Quantum thing
uh this Quantum analogy because
the track is to an orbit what an orbital
is you know for electrons the electronic
orbital is a statistical representation
of where quote-unquote the electron can
be but unless you stop the system to
observe it you will never know where the
electron is
and in fact we take some work even if
you stop the system if you don't know
but
um the analogy is there the analogy is
the track represents a statistical
aggregate of possibilities where our
path is the observable result of
a packet I've I've been that has been
flowing through the network
and if we use the same term I was
concerned that's why I had all that
discussion that it be the term path now
is is even more abstract and people less
and less understand what they're talking
about
so I was all for a special term now Lou
told me yesterday that maybe there is
the term that net pass or something that
is in the detnet documents
that we could use the bottom line is we
kind of agreed that the terminology must
provide all the terms
and provide the synonyms and kind of
explain that this actually comes from
different place but means the same thing
as that
kind of
so I'll try to craft that and I hope Lou
will help me do that terminology then
we'll have to the thing which will be
around on me but I have probably have to
do it is going through the text and see
every time I use the term track and
change it to this new thing which comes
from the cheese world
uh it's less familiar for me uh all of a
sudden I feel that I don't Master what
I'm talking about anymore but um so can
I jump in at this point uh I am in the
queue as well as kind of with my chair
hat on
as I see it
Rory has a very close relationship with
detnet we are very much a sibling group
of of debt net so I think there is
relevance in making sure the terminology
we use in our documents Maps very
closely to the terminology used in
detnet so someone in in the world of
deterministic networking can understand
what that net does and what raw does
using the same terminology I absolutely
understand the point of within the
Wireless World completely different
terms are used for
things which may or may be close to
terms used in the debtnet world so I
absolutely agree with the suggestion
that some kind of glossary to make sure
that there is a mapping between the
different terminology universes out
there but I would
suggest strongly that the main terms are
you that are used are the debt net terms
so that cues up Lou Who is behind me in
the queue and I would like you to step
to the queue
this track concept because I'm very
happy for this session to be quite
workshoppy here
what is the corresponding debt net term
that we should be using instead of track
or do we need to Define
and I actually don't care what the word
is do we need to con to Define this
potential total
Transit across this orbital
go
so what is a track I'm not I'm being
serious what's a track give us a tight
definition of a track the track is
defined in the architecture if we could
read it to make sure we have other words
it's crafted I spend time on it but it's
basically the the collection of hops on
which the packet may pass depending on
what the PLC decides to try and the
radio accepts to forward
so in ietf traffic engineering we call
that a path
the the
buff
in ietf traffic engineering I'm not
talking about you know
pattern research group I'm not talking
about other research groups I'm talking
about in the context of traffic
engineering that's called a path I I
understand that and you gave me links
and I read those links
and I was not convinced that we are
talking about the same thing because
when I looked at the text on path it
still indicated something which was kind
of deterministic where the Tre the track
is statistical
in terms of operation I mean once you
you configure your track your path to
work like this even if it does
replication not replication you cannot
say do this from it's not from a local
Loop or anything that that is kind of
hidden inside the system but it's
something which is recontrolled by the
outside then for a long time quote
unquote in those orders of magnitudes
it's just a matter of orders of
magnitude and time but for for a long
period of time which is observable by
the PC Etc the the network Behavior will
be exactly that
and then you can decide for whatever
reasons most reliability to change that
and then there will be an action that's
visible that's from the outside and so
the path is always very well known at
each point of time it's completely
controlled do I misunderstand
so in the context of ITF traffic
engineering
a service may be supported by many paths
they're often called primary secondary
or protection or alternate
and a the
um the actual path that is used and that
may be one or more is based on a the
protection switching function that's
being used yeah so we've had one plus
one protection of which uh pre-off and
net is a new type of packet one plus one
um we've had one for end protection
and in for various Technologies to me
Paro sounds like a new one for n
protection scheme that is being used
um being defined for wireless and maybe
it's not one friend maybe it's one plus
or fourn because sometimes you might use
multiple sometimes you might use one
that's what I mean by orbital
I prefer to stick to terms that we've
used in the ietf and really you know
we're operating within the context of
ITF traffic engineering from teas that's
further downscoped to detnet which is
further downscope to Raw so it would be
good if as we sort of proper you know
populate up in terminology that we
inherit uh terminology from the groups
that we are inheriting technology I I
understand that desire but at the same
time understand it I'm all for it
conceptually incompetual for it I'm
discussing because
each time groups like traffic
engineering have taken the same time as
before and extending its meaning the the
sense of that world has become to
started to become more and more fluid or
something and so two people unless they
really speak within the same context
start not talking about the same thing
and they don't even realize it that's
the danger of overloading terms and
here I have the cells that we make a
small step
overloading path yet a little more
because in my view I mean I I want to
use these I I want to do it anywhere
there is one desire I have to change and
and you would not even need to ask is
for everything I called a sub truck
which is a definitely well organized
subset of the truck I wanted to call it
a t-path or use your words I mean a path
because that piece is deterministic it's
well organized it's exactly that now the
track is the collection of the model set
of all the overlapping
so you could I expect the PC to design
five six seven ten path
and place them in the same set which has
all the links of all those paths if you
like so so the links are the track
and the PSC selects out of that subset
which is the track on which we do oam
and all those games all the time
regardless of whether we use them or not
the PSC selects a path
inside that set the track is the set the
path is what the PSC selects at one
point of time that's that's my intention
so I have this term subtract that I'm
very very happy to remove because it's
effectively in my mind matching what you
define
and and for exactly the reasons the
exact reasons you say I want to do that
change now for the track itself which is
the set of all those things the the
coalescence of all those t-path I think
it's uh it's it's it's a little more we
are stretching the term and I don't like
to stretch your thumb even more mostly
because at the end one is a set and the
other one is is a t-path as you as you
define it
I'd really like to go find an old ccamp
presentation
so C Camp was created well no it is when
it was rechartered and when T's broke
off it was uh its scope was set to help
new technologies reuse iatf traffic
engineering uh techniques terminology
Solutions
and that old presentation talked about
how it's very common for someone who has
a new technology to show up
spend a whole bunch of time adapting to
what they think and saying okay we're
we're ready to go this is our solve
salute this is our solution it's time
for an RFC and then to enter the c-camp
group and that's the start of what ccamp
does is help take what is this unique
technology well from the perspective of
those people who are coming in with the
new technology here's a unique solution
and saying how much of this solution is
actually unique and how much is generic
and part of the the process is is
teasing out the terminology to get the
terminology aligned with what's in it
already there with ietf traffic
engineering and then by getting the
terminology right you help identify
which mechanisms exist and clear used
which mechanisms are brand new
we are in them in that process now we're
not quite at the very beginning we've
been the working group's been running a
little while but I don't think we've had
that good synchronization and we would
might benefit from talking to the Sea
camp chairs and that C Camp working
group and maybe even doing like a joint
interim and say help us you know merge
our now well-formed architecture
document into ietf traffic engineering
so we're repeating a process that we've
seen many times for many different
Technologies
by the way microwave was one of them
it's it's a it's a wireless technology
that is point to point so you don't have
overhearing you know so it has different
characteristics than what you want but
it's still Wireless so they've been down
this path before I think we could
benefit by trying to work more closely
with them I mean I completely buy that
it seems to me orthogonal to the fact
that there's there's still this question
whether the truck as I figure it
is
within what that net calls a path or if
it's just a subtract that's being
selected which is what that net calls a
path
so From a.net perspective we have
something called a service the service
may be supported by
um a set a forwarding layer paths I
agree with that and that there could be
a protection function that Maps the
service to those paths
I see nothing here that you're
describing as being different from that
and there is I
no I'm going to join the queue I'm going
to join the queue
but I need to cure your question because
it's it's we are born it's all turning
around the same problem
so you want to speak first
yes
I have two comments the first I have
really Deja
vujabi sorry for my French
um
when we started in the death Network
group
TSM worker already done in 93 plea
and we had exactly a very similar
discussion those days because TSN
already had the terminology
in that net this was okay in in that
we have not yet had the ietf terminology
for all this stuff so there were lengthy
discussion and and similar methods like
like Loop reports uh we definitely had
the luxury that having the TSN guys also
in the room during the discussion and we
have made that happen in the
architecture document so there you can
find also some IEEE technology and
terminology and it is pointed exactly
what is that net relation that the
terminology relation to those
terminologies so something similar here
I think would would be excellent to that
uh the the second comment is is about uh
distract track story uh so I think in
the document you have
uh also complex path and then I have
read the document yes my understanding
was that it is it is describing your
track terminology and then we have a
terminology with path this is describing
what you wanted to have with with that
and and also also uh regarding
the flows we have defined in that net
the member flow and the compound flow
which is of course on flow level but
something very much related to that
root just not to use track or path but
root to take over the network for the
packets belonging to a flow
I can answer the second one first if you
don't mind I think there is a bug in
that net I try to raised it a number of
times
and the bug in that net is that there is
a huge confusion between the water and
the pipe
the flow is the water that's what goes
from A to B the pipe is quote unquote of
this by path discussion it's where it's
gonna go what's gonna happen to the
packets on on the flight Etc
um the the flow
is in that net typically not the
compound flow the base flow is is
identified by the five tuples meaning it
is a application layer construct the
application decides what goes in the
flow
at some point there is and it's written
like this in the architecture I know
because I wrote it
um that says at some point the flow is
mapped to a path
and that's intentional
the intention is to say there is a
function somewhere that we decide that
this water goes in that pipe
and the cool thing about separating the
water and the pipe is that you can for
instance decide that this oam goes in
the same pipe will have the same
treatment as this water so all of a
sudden the OEM can absorb the water
if we do things based on application
signaling like the five tuples we are
screwed because of a sudden we have all
those plants hey how shall we put my OEM
on the same falling operation you can't
because you made that mistake of
signaling stuff with the application I
mean it's not your stuff that belongs to
the application
that's a bug
so I I went to the mic several times
tried to to say hey hey we confused the
water and the pipe I wrote this uh IPv6
that Network IPv6 document which I'm not
maintaining but when when the group is
finding interested in doing that I will
be happy to revive it
where I write this down in words and I
show how IPv6 can signal not the flow
because that's already what the
application did in the packet but
how you process it in the network which
is the pipe
so so don't tell me don't do what you do
because we have this bug and we want you
I want you to emulate this back it is a
bug
I I don't see it in that way because at
the age node at the age uh of the that
net domain you are just doing uh the
death net flow identification so it is
not an application related signaling
this is something but but you are
deciding at the age of the.net node and
within the.net domain you are using
those credentials to identify the flow
you fix my back
as long as we relate what that net does
I'm not talking about the Ingress
function that puts the data in I mean
that exists but once we have decided
that this thing goes in that pipe we
should not be looking at the application
information anymore we should signal our
home pipes and if we put multiple pipes
in a bigger pipe we just seen all that
it's our one domain we can decide that
we signal it and now the compound flow
is just a pipe inside another pipe
right so there is this first function
first function that assigns the
application layer stream to a pipe and
then we are in our world and and that's
what we need that's how we need to build
that's that's an architecture and that
net architecture is worded like this
but but this is exactly about the flow
identification functionality do at the
age node yes the flow identification
will record will have some mapping table
of sort which will do several things
um recognize the application flow if
it's not if it's stacked by five double
stacked by five double it will assign a
path it will do some shaping if the flow
doesn't respect you know the shape of
the pipe because we insert that flow in
that pipe the shaping must be correct so
there are all those things which happen
at the Ingress Edge and once that is
done we should not see look observe
think about any application layer
signaling we are in our world and I
don't think that that net specifications
are clear and uh enough on that
but at least my IPv6 hot by Hub document
is very clear on that
okay let's have further discussion on
that uh maybe just one final comment is
that uh in that net we have two data
plane
not only IPv6 we have also mpls data
plan
so
but in mpls I'm sure that naturally you
fix this bug because you label it's a
label inside label so very soon you're
in your own labels exactly and so by
Nature even without thinking about it or
wording it you kind of solve that
problem
but still a lot of the discussion I'm
hearing and the all these things about
five top also know
lead to the impression that we have this
back and I want to be very very clear in
everything I write that I'm I'm not
writing for that
okay
John Scutter Juniper Networks
um
so I
somewhat regretfully want to return to
the the previous conversation you are
having with Lou
where which you know made me think a
little bit of Alice in Wonderland and
you know a word is exactly what I mean
it you know use it to mean neither more
nor less
um and I I also I still feel like a new
guy in this group and like I kind of
walked into the living room when the
conversation is well underway
um
so you know forgive me as I continue to
come up to speed but it it's sounded to
me listening to you guys
Converse like
you're saying I really want to not reuse
your words when they have a different
shade of meaning from what I mean
I already have a terminology set it
means just what I want it to mean
and um it's much easier for me to write
a precise description of my architecture
using the terminology that is precisely
tailored for that purpose fair enough
um I think what I heard Lou saying among
other things was
um
we have a a terminology set that's
really pretty close to what you mean and
you if you use that it will make the
document a lot more accessible to a
wider audience
um so Lou is doing his email so he can't
say whether that's a
a good description or not
um anyway
um
and it seems to me like those are both
good goals
um it's obviously good for an
architecture to be precise and
unambiguous it's obviously good for an
architecture to be accessible to a new
reader
um
and it
furthermore seems to me that with
anything complicated the first time a
new reader reads through it no matter
how precise you have been in your
choice of terms
they're going to misunderstand something
because that's human nature
so it seems to me like one way of
squaring the circle is
and I'm sure that this has been part of
the discussion maybe even right now
um is to have a
careful exhaustive and precise set of
definitions
and to say look you can't really
understand the document unless you have
understood and internalized all the
definitions
and applied them as you're reading the
document right so you know you you got
to expand all the pound defines sorry to
date myself
um
trying to do that but I know I'm wrong
already so I have some changes to make
so but but at least I tried right no no
and in fact there are big terminology
sections explaining what they are how
they differ in my view yeah but I I was
wrong on something that luto told us so
I know I have to fix it already right so
so actually I I don't mean this as a as
a criticism of the document as it stands
I'm just sort of trying to set up
one more thought which is once you've
accepted that the only way that your
document is really going to be properly
understood is by somebody who has
carefully read your definitions and is
carefully applying them then you can use
either terminology set right you can use
your native terminology set
that you have been thinking in you can
use you know what is claimed to be the
more common ietf terminology set which
sort of the colloquial uses of it are
let's just accept for discussion that
those colloquial uses are subtly wrong
but as long as that subtle wrongness
doesn't like lead the the Casual reader
down like a path to like deep
misunderstanding I think it's okay
because the Casual reader is just coming
in and trying to get the big picture
and you know sort of one in 50 casual
readers are going to come back and read
it four more times on their way to
becoming experts
um so it seems to me that you know if
you're going to bias towards one thing
or another
um it's maybe more valuable
to bias towards making the document
accessible and towards really focusing
on as you've done towards focusing on
using definitions to make sure that your
your meeting is completely clear
um and I should have said up front that
I'm you know don't intend to be in
imposing any ads opinion here or
anything this is just me sitting in the
room listening
thank you
yeah so why I'm I am so sensitive to not
giving that wrong impression to the
Casual reader the big big thing with the
way I see it works right because I it's
not just the architecture I have my mind
image of what's exactly going to happen
what's going to happen is you've got
this probably this PC I mean the
distributed is in the architecture slow
pointed but I don't I don't have any
clue of how to make that work
distributedly so so say you have this
controller and the controller will
observe the links every hub
through a periodic statistical knowledge
so every hour what's the ratio of
delivery on that Hub so so it's going to
get statistical values because it cannot
get so many full pictures of exactly
what's going on so it will have
statistical views of all those links
right and it will be asked to build
something which allows every packet from
a to Rich B like 2.5 times every packet
should reach should arrive 2.5 times
average something like that and you will
say Okay 2.5 if I just build three
parallel paths with all the laws and the
statistics I get 1.1 which means that
some packets would be lost
not good enough so let me build more of
those
things now if I build too much yeah
Spectrum energy blood that's why we're
here
okay but the PSC cannot be that smart as
to decide if exactly on each packet
which hops are going to be followed so I
need to hint
and that's that's the Orient thing in
UDA I need to hint the PSC if you see
this you do that
and each of those that is a sub topology
of the overall thing so the overall
thing is all those extra links that the
PC has decided may be used from A to B
the PSC doesn't just give that it gives
a set
of T path
each one mapping a certain condition of
the network
and I'm willing to call this thing
t-path and I'm sorry I called that sub
truck
and so now I have a clear usage of the
term t-path it is this subset now oam
doesn't care only on that subset because
we are doing out of Bando am as well to
see if there is another path in that
bigger thing that we could use better
than what we are using currently
Okay so
we need to observe the big thing that I
call the truck and use the sub thing
which I call the t-path
you see and so if I call the two of them
the same thing how can I say what I
observe versus what I use
now back to lose point about yes it's
just a service the service actually when
I'm going to receive from the pce all
those different cases I will instantiate
a service for each of them because in
runtime I will just use one of those
services but in my code I will have one
instance I will just say flip that one
on flip that one off as the immediate
reaction so each of the service the blue
the red the green the whatever they will
they will be activated and deactivated
dynamically based on OEM that's exactly
what's going to happen so for each of
those Services I will have a t path so
what I'm gonna do is activate the t-path
deactivate that t-path that's exactly
what's going to happen
and then again I need to represent the
set of all those T path and what I call
coalitions is When You observe all of
them from above and if you have twice
the same link it looks like one but at
the end you observe the set of all that
that's the track that's the big thing on
which the PSC is operating from this A
to B
and HTE path is what one of the servers
gives me and I select which one I'm
using
confusing the two makes makes it very
very hard for me to explain exactly what
I told you
thank you
foreign
[Music]
ER since today the first time I came
over
because uh and then the first time I saw
your terminology track it immediately
comes to my mind in the tracking area
that being used since this is the raw
the radio the world is hard
so that has a different uh meaning to
tracking area okay probably are talking
about some set of sales I use the
switching routing but in the wireless
part
okay and then I continue reading through
and you talk about the six Pi SCI
Channel
and then okay so probably your and then
you say okay well not introduce anything
new
and then oh yeah okay so probably for
some base station and then on that side
for the channel you're talking about the
drv
and then I continue reading and you say
okay you statistically and combinational
comment uh combinatory aggregation of
the blah blah everything
and then at that moment okay well you
are talking about the PSE and going to
determine a path
so with for me I have both background
when I read it it's the first impression
I got is a little bit confused
yeah can you help I mean and then
basically my problem is that if you go
explanation I fully understand but uh
you know for I have background both and
then the first time I got coffee that's
wonderful because we are lacking this
feedback because everybody here kind of
understands what we've been working on
for a long time and when I said that
they made a rework to to try to make the
new reader's life easier
seems that I'm not through yet so if
could you write down what you just said
and maybe suggest you know how things
could be reordered or where where you
you add those times of confusion yeah
well I try to um ask you one particular
question we're gonna talk about the end
to end are you only talk about up to the
base station and Beyond on the layer 3
part oh you're talking things you're
talking this at the raw the radio the
well the wireless part are you also
mentioning from the UE all the way to
the server the whole path
okay so so there are two things here
yeah one of them is there are two use
cases in a row because that's the use
cases that were presented to us in life
and there might be a lot more to
wireless than those two use cases and
and you talk about UE and then base
station so that's use case one when row
protects the access only the access but
it observes the end-to-end path so
basically you get feedback from the
other hand whether the packet was
received but the only thing you really
act on is the first top so if if the
server doesn't get your data over
Wireless Wi-Fi you'll go to 5G
regardless if the problem is really with
the Wi-Fi or if it is somewhere else
right so that's when the oam is layer
three and and the selection the action
that you can take is just on the first
half because the rest you don't control
anyway
um so so that's that's half of of the
discussion
um and so the other Alpha is what I lost
myself
what was the core of your question
please I need to cover the thing here
got the the PSE okay so from the IP and
uh side I understand it's like uh like
some place to calculate on the layer
three the tunnel but the thing here if
you look at the radio architecture
especially 5G the layer 3 is uh you can
consider you can consider under the
genob side
and then so for your internal pass yes
the PS the PC discussion only applies to
the second case in the architecture
where you do the mesh
so I told you that those two big use
cases one of them is we protect the
access only and even if the fault is not
on the access we'll switch the access
and the Second Use case is we have this
mesh and we are looking at a multi-hop
Wireless truck
and that's when that's when all this
discussion that we had happens where the
PC will look at statistically blah and
say use that well even on the
the first use case the PC will tell you
about the statistics of the links
but
it does not compute the end-to-end
path that we are talking about it just
says you switch this interface or that
interface or that interface based on
observable qualities or whatever so if
you if you see for instance that your
Wi-Fi reports that the speed is this or
whatever you switch to 5G just an
example that's the kind of reaction that
the PC could tell to the end user the
user equipment
um let me just to make it very very
clear here for your statistic
terminology used to the track suppose
this is the radio the 5G uh scenario on
the down link from The genome B
here when the Downing traffic come onto
the genome B it's going to select based
on the sum of 5qi it's going to select
even the drbs the data radio barrier
okay so that one is going to be well
depending on the qls perform without
being start
that'll be uh the selection okay well
it's not random it's not statistic but
it's in the gr if the guarantee bit rate
obviously non-gbr is credible something
it might not yeah so for your statistic
and then my understanding is like the
track is some sort of like statistic
combination such that you flip the coin
and then you do something
the statistics in the access case the
statistics are obtained through the
end-to-end oam
and whatever did those two layer 2 does
is not observed normally it's not
observable we don't really have access
to what layer 2 does so the the that is
the use case where the oam is layer
three from the client to the server and
if that goes bad we just switch the
radio okay but we don't know what better
we don't even care if it's Wi-Fi or 5G
okay sure thank you okay the first align
just gave me the impression because this
one use the similar like the 60i sh and
we are not introducing anything new so
okay I try to associate this too
together
but please keep in touch Clips please
keep in touch I mean it's I mean
anything that that creates
an issue for the reader needs to be
addressed
so uh I'm in the Q next Rick Taylor uh
with chair hat off really and Lou it's
kind of a follow-up question to a
statement you made earlier and I'm glad
you're in the queue behind me
going back to the track versus path
question
um
this is we've got to get to the bottom
of this so uh actually quick comment to
concerning John's statement I'm I'm in
complete agreement that
um and this goes back to my idea that
that we are a sibling group of debt Nets
so making sure that
if you come from a debt net background
you can immediately
understand because there is commonality
of terminology but if specifics need to
be pulled out in order to make a
coherent argument
that's absolutely fine
and should be front and center so that
it those differences can be noted so my
question to Lou actually was
given you have layers of service
protection functions
and effectively a service protection
function
does something to paths or hops you know
you've earned it's going to be Parts I
think where a service protection
function which does some sort of
duplication and and eliminate
replication and elimination pairing
so that service function is creating
what do you call a link of service
functions from end to end
if a service function does something to
makes choices between paths what what is
what is that chain of service functions
is that a service path
and I think that does not exist in that
not that I know of and I think that
might be the Crux of the problem because
we've got layers and we use the same
word path right every slice through all
the individual layers some which may or
may not appear at different points
across the thing
yeah so we have a recursive architecture
not an overlapping architecture okay
it's a one layer can receive service
from a lower layer and it can provide
service to an upper layer each of those
are services and you go to end to end if
you look at the architecture document it
says the n10 service
it's really simple yeah and it's
independent of how many services it
traverses it's still the end-to-end
service because when you're operating at
a layer
you see what layer you're operating at
so switching you know the across the
horizontal providing service up to the
vertical where you know when you're
going up vertically that's to the
application and when you're going down
you're going to get receiving service
from the network
usually represented as interface but you
know there's lots of ways to implement
that it's not standardized
so if you're talking about the
collection of services that's used to
deliver traffic to a net application end
to end
n10 service it's in the architecture
document yeah no that is fine
sorry that's absolutely fine and I
understand that but what I'm saying is
as you start to talk about that from a
technical perspective and you start to
delaminate across these these
recursively applied Services the layers
if you're talking about a particular
service function which says oh there may
be a service above me there's almost
definitely a service below me it may
just be forwarding I have a pairing with
you know a replication and elimination
you have a pair one replicates one
Eliminator protection domain yeah you
have a protection domain
so the the relationship between those
two they exist within a protection
domain but the the
the transit of packets from the
replicator to The Eliminator function
yes does that have a name or is it it's
the end and service at that layer
it's a recursive architecture so these
are so a particular layer
if you were providing a service it's
your end-to-end service to your
application it's not their intent so if
I understand your argument correctly and
I I think I think I understand what
you're saying but I'm trying to see if
we can apply it could we just replace
the word Trek
we then to end service because we're
talking about I believe I really believe
so and to John's characterization of
what I was saying
there's one additional point that I
think is really the Crux of where I'm
coming from is if we can figure out the
aligned terminology we can figure out
what technology we can reuse I think
that's understandable and then what
technology what new mechanisms we have
to Define because I think there is
something new here
that's that's that's the thing to do so
what we want to do is tease down to
what's new and then reuse as much as we
can and that's the whole concept that
you know in bot is embodied in Internet
te and T's and c-camp and and all that
prior work
and there's one additional point I'd
like to make this is a separate point
well actually you're the one in queue
and I'm responding yeah yeah sorry when
you're done I'll make my point okay so
oh God you just interrupted me so and
this is kind of a question to Pascal now
if you call it a end-to-end service at a
particular layer is that a pipe or is
that still a flow because I agree with
you on pipes I actually do agree with
you on pipes and it's I know that's a
TechNet consideration not particularly a
raw one I think there's a big difference
look at this picture okay
we we spent some time yesterday on that
picture I'm sorry for the rest of the
group uh
but I I presented it at the last iatf
I'm it's very hard to build it's a very
simple picture but it's very hard to
build
what it's trying to say is that the PSC
operates outside of the flow of the
packets remember it's something which
will switch from Service Blue to service
Red because the radio conditions
somewhere have changed
and you could see it as a fork of packet
but no because it's not in the data
plane that's my answer to you and Lou
that's why I say no it's because this
thing happens asynchronously to the
traffic this happens in this oam plane
if we really want to to have an oem
plane where we will switch the service
but the next packet will only see one
service on the path of the packet there
won't be a service selection that will
and then a sub service selection so the
package will just see blue service if
you don't even know there was a red
surface sorry Rick yes I completely
agree with you go on so when you're
switching between services in the detnet
architecture you're actually switching
between forwarding paths because
remember it's recursive yeah exactly so
if
if I'm an application
operating at whatever layer I have below
me yes different services
but then if I go below that layer below
those each one of those is its own
service
so it you really I think you're saying
you're not switching between Services
you're switching between forwarding
paths in the recursive architecture
I I think it would be super helpful
to draw the same picture for a wired
Network
we have a protection switching function
in uh defined for
detnet we have one the architecture
allows any
so we could have a one for n service
defined in bednet we don't we only have
a one one plus one
but that is a type of switching function
that's a type of PSE
now it's a very sorry no I don't believe
that is what Pascal is saying I don't
believe that's a PSE I think a PSE is a
purely control plane mechanism that
decides what switching function should
be applied you switch the service
applicator and the function that is
being
popped in line and I hear you yeah so in
detnet it's a very rigidly controlled
PSE controlled by a Yang model and it's
expected to be driven by a provisioning
system but there's no reason that
couldn't be driven by you know take your
AIML system that automatically changes
it based on what it sees is you know the
weather pattern of the network if you
reach Roland when you do that or a thing
called a piece I'm sorry I didn't hear
what he said no I'm saying yeah and
that's that's this could be included in
what we discussed that's when you reach
Roland that the extension we want to
provide or the most additional
refinement we want to bring to that net
all you're discussing it's it's so I
think all of what I've just said is in
that net today
does not discuss it does not prevent it
we want to I think model fully supports
what we've talked about I think that the
architecture defines different ill
allows for different protection
mechanisms we've only defied one we've
always talked about we may be doing
others we identify Network coding as
maybe the second but it's a maybe second
we're contribution driven so if someone
came with something new you know we
could talk about that but I think from
an architectural standpoint you're not
adding something fundamentally new
you're adding a new protection switching
which already fits into the demo we are
switching the protection switching under
the carpet that's what that's great I'm
just saying
in the same plane because we are doing
it
that's that's why that picture is
important what you're saying is all true
but at the end of the day how can we
Express in this document
that we are not
folding plane we are not doing steps in
the lay going through layers for the
packet operation there is only one layer
or this is a service well and then and
then going down to Fourth but we never
go through the control layer for the
packet processing right and we need to
expose that to the reader yeah so I
don't think we're arguing about
the net effect and the behavior on The
Wire right we're talking about we're
arguing about how to represent it on
paper so it's more accessible to the
reader as well as
allows us to reuse existing mechanisms
documentation so we can reference rather
than have to define a whole new set of
things that's what we're really talking
about right
I'm suggesting take this picture draw it
for Wired
however you see to do it draw it for
Wired and then next to it say here's how
it how it's modified for raw and I agree
that we don't actually have this picture
drawn for detnet now I did drop and chat
something from a long time ago which was
mplstp talking about how to do it for
Wired networks and mpls and remember
that net inherits all of that because
that's much more refined so
the point is is that or my point is that
that type of thing exists for Wired
already it doesn't matter I mean yes it
does and that proves that we are doing
the right thing right but at the same
time we still need to to show our
readers what we are doing even if it
already exists that's exactly but let's
show it first for.net so people can
understand what is there already can I
connect and then add into it what is
different can I just interrupt for a
second just I think we've started to
move on to
a PSE discussion rather than getting to
the bottom of the track issue or do you
believe that they are so intertwined
that they that we need to continue this
time
I was responding to the slide that was
brought up and so you know I bought it
because I thought it was intertwined
sorry okay that's fine I'm sorry there
was chair hat on there just trying to
because I I think they're separable uh
but you know I I
he's the one driving slides he's the one
showing a slide so I'm responding to the
slide the reason why I think and it's
it's me right I mean we have a room so
is that for me all the T discussion
works
also all the existing terminology we
have in that net and that relates to
draw it for that net if I was to draw it
for that net I would basically say hey
we have
but the service access point exists in
that net it's in the model Etc and
that's neat that's perfect now this we
have this new user which is effectively
not the one we expected when we wrote
initially the architecture but the
architecture is open to having it and
now row is introducing that new consumer
to this uh providers app
so you're actually taking me to the
point that I wanted to come up and
actually make my point which is
um we have an art it's true we have an
architecture document you wrote A lot of
it but what came through the working
group is what the ietf agreed to
and I've had this set to me by the way
for documents that I've written is it
doesn't matter what I wanted it to say
it says what it says yeah so we have to
accept that that's what the ietf
standardized yeah so you know I I've
heard you say a couple of times I know I
wrote that and this is what it should
say
doesn't matter it says it and again I'm
saying something to you that was said to
me previously as an author I take it
nicely I mean no issues with that it's
just a matter of that steals the weather
right wrong
that's what was standardized or agreed
upon because it's not a standard it's an
inferential document exactly I close
right yeah
I still understand the words in a
slightly different fashion so we might
both think we agree with the
architecture and we might still have a
different image of what it is I I agree
with you completely and that goes to the
next point which is
different protection functions from my
my perspective as a reader I don't think
I was an author on that I did comment a
lot but I don't think I was an author
um I saw the ability to do any number of
protection functions you should take it
very abstractly we understand how I read
it
and that's you know I and I saw that
there was even multiple examples listed
in the document
so the fact that you have another one
which is interesting and tailored to a
wireless network that's great it fits
right in the architecture
okay so where we seem to converge at
least I can
agree with what you said is this is a
protection function I agree with that
I don't agree that it is a service layer
function because the way we Define the
service layer it's a forwarding plane
activity that's why I brought this slide
that's service when you could it's a
control domain service if you like but
it's not the services that we have today
because the only service that we Define
and where we placed it we placed it in
the forwarding plate
and because this thing is in the control
oam or whatever plane you want
then it doesn't fit unless we take our
definition of service and extend it to
control plane activity so it's that's
that's that's the thing but it is it is
uh what you said it is a Protection
Service it just doesn't live in this the
forwarding plane like the services do
go ahead Don all right
um
I
I think that like you've spent a lot of
time on this and and
but you've you've you've taken a Step
Beyond what what uh
some of us can keep up with with a new
terminology I would suggest like lose
the term track and describe it in like
you like you have the definition in
terms of a path you know whether it's an
aggregated path or a collection of paths
or whatever
and let the working group decide if
there's a term that we need to describe
that in the end and and for a couple of
the new terminologies do the same thing
and that would add Clarity to the
document for me because
a conceptually I'm not driving with it
when I see a track and I'm sure a few
others have the same problem but if we
use all the same terminology that we've
used before and maybe it's a big bunch
of words that we have to use for this
version of the draft and we would decide
that we want a term that just describes
that then I think we would we would
reach uh a consensus on this faster
uh that's very wise advice thank you
um I'm next in the queue so I'm I'm
gonna sort of go back to the argument
not the the polite discussion between
Lou and Pascal here
the splitting of the document I think
was uh made to separate
the pario service function
from the pse's role in the architecture
because I agree with Pascal here they
are two separate things and I think
where I disagree with Lou is I believe
he's telling me that they're just one
thing
I that's what I'm picking up Lou I I if
that's not what you're trying to say
as you said it
that has their service Control Function
Yang
modelsburger I
you ask me are they the same I said I
think they're separate and I just
switched to it because he switched to it
on his slide
right okay fine in which in which case I
I withdraw my previous comment about my
understanding of what you were saying so
again I should say that's what I meant
to say I actually have no idea what I
said
welcome to my world
yeah we'll consult the minutes
um
fundamentally there's there's the uh
beautifully young modeled uh detnet
service a Control Function or service
control model
and as I understand it the PSE
can be a user of that in order to change
service function based on some
management and monitoring information
that flows across the control plane
policy whatever
that is a unique decision or a unique
part of the raw architecture because
Pascal and the working group by
extension this is a working group
document proposed that that fast
feedback loop is important in order to
supply deterministic Services across
Wireless links
that is different from
by the way we think we can produce a
service function which will give you
better reliability
across whether we call it a path to
track a stream of flow I don't care
um
within the debt net service sub layers
and splitting those two documents may
help clarify that does anyone disagree
with me on that Pascal are my miles off
here
if I understand you well like I'm not
sure I understand
but if if I understand you well I'm with
you
Burger sorry I'm not in queue I just
want fast enough with the app
um your words just maybe remember that
we spent a huge amount of time
um going over these drawings of
protection models as we were developing
the Yang model to make sure we were
appropriately modeling what the data
plane could do
and
um Don was involved in that I was seeing
if Don had a pointer to any of those but
maybe we can grab those and uh give it
to the working group here and then we
can start extending them to draw the
pictures of what we mean and then we can
say we're pointing right here and this
is the new thing or we're pointing here
and this is the existing thing I think
that would be very welcome because both
Pascal and I had a corridor conversation
where we admitted neither of us like
drawing ASCII art and we both struggled
no these are PowerPoint they're not
asking but we I bet we can find a tool
that will turn them into ASCII but
anything to help with clarifying
diagrams I think we're so in the realm
of a picture is worth a thousand words
here so yeah I'll see if I can dig it up
or Donald dig it up and we'll send it to
the list since since Lou you brought up
the young model first things down for
the ug front and you know that that's
huge I mean if that contributed on the
meaning list but that's that's a huge
thing now a model gives you
what you can use and not how you can use
it that is the architecture which will
tell you what you can do and what you
cannot do for instance the model of a
car will tell you that if you press the
pedal it's going to go faster it doesn't
tell you whether or not you go when the
light is red or green that's the
architecture
and so because the young model could be
is wide enough to do stuff doesn't mean
that we we do all those stuff that the
young model allows but we wanted the
young model to allow everything you want
to do
but it cannot necessarily be limitating
to the to to to what we allow so so did
there is a role of the young model and
there is the role of the architecture
and the thing that tells you that if the
red is lie is the light is red you stop
that's the architecture so Pascal can I
reply to that um I I think you're
slightly meshing two concepts together
there what I meant to say was in an
architecture document you can say there
is this well-defined control path
between the uh service control functions
down to the services themselves we are
very lucky that there is a good quality
Yang model that can describe that and in
the architecture we can say we are going
to use this it exists and people
familiar with the prior work will go aha
that is perfect that I was not
responding to that because I agreed with
that oh okay fine I was responding to
Lou saying the way the service is
modeled in Yang although the service to
be kind of a maybe a control plane thing
I don't know if that's exactly if he
does that because I've not been enough
detail this document study
so so for me
it's fine that if the model allows that
it doesn't mean that we use that what
what we use is what the architecture
says we use right even if the model is I
mean the model has to represent
everything we could do and and the
architecture says everything we do
hopefully the young model is a superset
of of that yeah and not a subset so Don
are you still in the queue or have you
uh okay I'll bring you out of the queue
Stu you're in the queue
yeah Stu card and I'm not sure which of
my affiliations I want to tag on this
um so I'd just like to give a
perspective of a noob
um I have attempted to parse the net
documents and I have attempted to parse
the raw documents
and despite what is obviously an
enormous amount of work by both groups
and an enormous amount of intelligence
underneath that work
I find neither of them particularly
accessible to a newbie such as myself
okay
they appear to be
things that probably can be read easily
by someone who is involved in the work
from the first and can trace its
Evolution and not so easily read by
someone who was not involved in the work
from the first and is coming in late and
trying to wrap his head around this okay
so from that perspective I have some
sympathy for uh what Lou is saying about
trying to make them more accessible
on the other hand
um
I I do like precision
um and by the way we already in ietf and
even in irtf abuse the word path okay if
you go to the mathematical graph Theory
we have walks Trails traces circuits
Etc et cetera Etc right it'll be a long
time to find track
I went through the dictionary right so
um so to draw an example from a
different area with an ietf locator
identifier split you know there's hip
there's ilnp there's lisp and there's
probably others okay and each introduces
its own set of nomenclature which on the
one hand is annoying but on the other
hand uh not only are they potentially
attempting to address a different set of
requirements even to the extent that
they address the same set of
requirements they may partition and
allocate those requirements to different
subsystems within the overall system
architecture and the use of the same
term to refer to a box that over here on
the left includes a b and c and over
here on the right includes b c and d I
think ultimately can be more confusing
than attempting to reuse terminology
thus I come down on the side of
introduce terms that will be very
precise in their definitions but you
know there's a sentence that could go
early on that could it could make this a
lot easier you could literally say in
the Raw document
this is what we really mean by track
but if it makes it easier for you on a
first read to think path every time you
see the word track that's fine on a
first read but on a second read it will
be very important that you distinguish a
track from a path
thank you stu that's good advice I try
to do that
and actually this discussion today
clarified my own mind a lot
even from what I'm I don't even know I'm
thinking right because having to express
it to you guys helped me sort out my own
thoughts
but the reason why I brought this Slide
the reason why I think it's santankold
it's because in my view what we call
service and service layer is forwarding
play
since PSE is control plane I didn't see
that as a service stacked over another
service
and
I completely agree with what Lou said
about recursive for instance what we
call compound flows and for me it's just
tunnels within tunnels kind of if you
want to visualize it just a bigger pipe
where you have smaller pipes in it
this is service between service because
the bigger pipe has its own service
layer so certainly you you Nest service
layers when you do compound flows you do
that
um but
the operation the packet sees that
operation the packet fails every of
those operations the packet doesn't fill
the PSE
the PSC has been done under the carpet
while the packet was not looking
okay and and that's the reason why it's
not falling plane and that's the reason
why I don't call it service now if we
decide that we have control planes
um
reliability Services as well as data
plane reliability Services all of us
then we agree right so so my question is
really what we Define service layers oh
it's all right but but I want to be
honest to this drawing and then again it
looks simple I mean loose drawing on
nprs was very very complicated but
making simple is hard
actually and I spent a lot of time
making that simple thing out of the much
bigger thing with a lot more stuff in it
which looked so intelligent by the way
but
I think sorry I'm terrible with
pronunciation you're in the queue go
ahead
um hi this is joseon Pascal thank you
for your uh explanation just uh because
as the quarter of the uh then the yellow
mode or I just want to uh ask some
clarification questions to make me more
uh clear what do you try to describe
about the PSE uh I just read through the
document about the concept and the
description does it mean that is a
control Loop it does it mean that uh the
PSE itself includes the uh oam process
and the controller plan process and also
the uh maybe something like forward
implant or service layer often that no
it's the combination no the PSC is this
little box on the top left
of that screen
and the PSC talks to somebody who
represents what who I am finds which I
call the oam supervisor or something
just that thing which sits in the
control plane that observes the oim
activity and get reports from OEM
activities so it knows something
happened on the other side of the
network now PSC needs to take action so
PSE is just this and it's written you
know if you look at the uh again that's
why I like this UDA reference model it's
because the PSC is the one that does the
D the decide the PSC decides
right but the u o o uh and a
are are done by other uh other nodes
other components on this of this control
Loop the control Loop globally is
abstracted as these four letters
and and the PC is the d i if it helps I
like to think of the PSE as a small
stupid local pce
it's an extension it may not be small or
stupid but it's probably quite local I'm
working on a on a fast loop in in the
initial view we'll make it very stupid
I have Rogers on how to make it more
distributed in which case it could
become a bit more intelligent but for
now see it as a source routed multipath
type of activity
um it seems to me like PSE is part of
the control Loop and it is kind of the
connection between the OEM and the
forwarding plan yes OEM is the observe
the O in UDA yeah uh-huh and it does the
decision kind of like uh pce yes okay I
I try to understand the PC is the Orient
and Orient is the only letter that is
intelligent in the UDA Loop Orient is
the one that has some historical
understanding for instance the
statistics that we bring to the PC so it
knows this link is feeble this link is
solid so when I construct those
alternate paths I will rely more on this
one than on that one and expect that
this one fails in which case I've
prepared discipline B for you which is
service Red
okay thank you for the explanation I
think I understand it more but I think I
I should take more time to think about
how to connect the the concept in rule
with the existing terminologies or
concept internet can I ask when you do
that thinking can you after this meeting
no no no no no not now but over over
time if you find areas that you find
difficult to to make that thinking
coherent and understandable for yourself
in the document please record the pieces
and get them on the mailing list because
a document that isn't as easy as
possible given the technology to help
people do that thinking and get correct
needs to be better so you are a perfect
reviewer because you are trying to
understand it for a reason rather than
just for interest so okay pretty helpful
thank you I think I will try it and she
saw many thanks for undone and True song
for the hard work on the young data
model I know it's very hard to do right
and
thank you thank you also thank you for
your work here
just try to get it clear I think the
Rick said this like Workshop discussion
so just yeah keep asking
uh not the more I listened the more I
got confused sorry about that
no no and now try to downplay but they
try to just
because uh I I do both work on the uh
awareness and the Wireline especially
here you're talking about like the past
the track
and then PSE here so for and also you
mentioned for your awareness or I you I
think you mentioned about something uh
like some Wi-Fi switch over to 5G you
and one moment you mentioned but I tried
to uh map the 5G architecture through
the three GPB access and the non-3 GPU
access including the Wi-Fi
and so here your path let me make the
clear is your path
the the DNA the data network has beyond
the n6
it all it will pass
uh including the the back hall path
between the genome B and the UPF
or if your path end to end from UE up
through the uh through the back hole
through the 5gc and then all the way
beyond the n6 including DNN so just try
to get it clear thank you can you
on Slide the one which shows the two use
cases I want to be well
no no we're close so go down go down go
down
uh up I think it's no oops
I think that's the one
um
okay
so what you see here
is
probably the drawing that corresponds
the best in the document to to the
situation we we are talking about so the
situation we're talking about is we
don't have an end-to-end service we
don't have end-to-end visibility on the
path the only thing we see is what we
see at layer 2 and what we see at layer
3.
and
in the case of 5G because now you're
modeling
the 5G Network as a
deterministic TSN type of network we
could say that the debt net forwarding
extend
to the
G note B basically Unit B whatever it is
so so this this relay node would be the
end of TSN quote-unquote the the the we
the 5G Network
Pascal can you come back to the mic and
see what I think was amazing yeah uh the
little red one so
the point I was making with the two use
cases is this is part of the use case a
where we only protect the access we
don't know how you build the network
behind it and even TSN doesn't see it
because TSN
um at least talks to to to
[Music]
your whole 5G Network as one switch but
we don't see what's what's inside we
don't have visibility so the bottom line
is we have layer three
oam so we can observe when we send
something whether it's received but we
don't know what's going on here because
it's completely opaque
is the internet it can be anything
and so we we cannot take actions that
happen here like inside your core we
don't see it the only thing we see is
when we send a packet
uh we send away um packets over this
interface whether they are received or
not so cdoam activity in my phone as
being oh I've got those two or three
interface and my phone one can be 3gpp
that can be one or two Wi-Fi that can be
Bluetooth whatever I'll get those
interfaces and I'm sending away in
packets on all of those out of band
oh I am packet and all of those
interfaces and I'm trying to measure if
some of them reach my server reach the
other hand and based on that I can make
decision of whether I'm using 5G Wi-Fi
or whatever else from the abstraction
that we live on we don't even care what
type of radio that is it's just access a
accessb access C and if I send a packet
on an xsa xsb access C I'm getting this
sort of reliability should I use two of
them which two should I use three that's
what the PSC will decide that's all it
will do it doesn't have any control
visibility of the type of radio or
anything
so sorry can you take it to the
microphone yeah no it's so when we know
the track is the other use case where
it's a mesh okay so Sim to me you try to
make the 5G system as a black box yeah
you do not care about the back card
without running on the IP yes we we see
end-to-end IP and one hop radio like the
if my 5G goes down that I know but but
the the rest I have no visibility on it
so I I don't ask I don't act on it yeah
so all this discussion is kind of photo
scope of the are you asking
chair hat on
later once we get the architecture and
these core documents done
having uh there are linked layer
protocols for for some types of radio
having an ability to understand better
to get better oam
from those lower black boxes so to make
them gray boxes in some way that would
be very interesting and can make can
provide more information on the OEM
flow so that we can make smarter
decisions that's a good thing so they
they don't have to be black but in
general you have to assume they are
black boxes until we can find some way
to get information out up first and then
maybe later down but that's a part two
part three of the problem sure thank you
Rick and now you know the more dileep
type of stuff we get the the best our
life yeah we're genuinely trying to do
step one then step two then step three
is
completely politics
so
yeah
thank you uh Lou you're up
the queue is too long I forgot what I
was gonna say sorry
in which case done
well we still have 10 minutes yeah
um when you met when you were talking
about the PSC uh did I hear you say that
the PSE is deciding like locally to
optimize for for each
uh service is that is that what it's
doing yes it is it is
switching which service is being used
for that for that so and what makes that
stable when everybody's trying to decide
optimally for themselves like what what
coordination function makes that stable
okay so in in the current model there is
only one place where that this decision
is made it's the Ingress
but it's every service making its
decision for itself right
Oh you mean I have multiple services
that are running parallel that's what
you well they're all over the network
right because we uh all over the
networks are nested so you don't they
will all depend on what's going on below
um yeah
so so the the the intelligence behind
all this is the pce
um but if you do this recursively
I mean each each of the nested levels
will have to offer an abstract
reliability level between Ingress and
egress and if that's used as one hub for
the uh
inner flow well
the goal the goal is basically this
right you've got in and out
and for one end you want 2.5 out
something like that just to ensure that
your loss is 10 minus five or ten minus
whatever so you you should average
to the drive it's just the number I'm
giving now you should say a I'm going to
do compound flow and between here and
here I have yet another track
well this other track will be abstracted
as something which gives me 2.5 and one
so that's a PC doing this right it would
build this new inner track get to 2.5
out of it and compute that this is a
virtual link now that has 2.5 and make
the bigger end-to-end service for the
for the inner flow using that 2.5 link
that's that's how I visualize it
when you say 2.5 that's like an average
five copies of the packet which yeah
but there are multiple things that are
trying to arrive at their whatever their
optimal number is independently yeah
yeah I I mean that that can be a problem
the PC is supposed to orchestrate all
this if it has more than one service
right
directions that could be a meta uh you
can see playing with all the plcs well
then they're not independent there's
hysteresis and there's a global
coordination then right
I I did not visualize it with multiple
services like this it's just blue is a
set of things but then you select blue
as a whole I did not sell I don't think
you would select some some little bit of
blue and some little bit of yellow I
thought that blue would be a consistent
set of activities and and that you know
it's not like you have multiple of them
which operate independently it's just a
set it's the parameters the parameters
of your pre-off in that node is is in
blue and there is another set of
parameters of that node that is red but
I did not expect that would be
parallel sets doing different things
which are talking to one another it
could get crazy
I think if you were going to do that
you'd use the layered service model and
to either put that as a leveler or a
layer above to do that multiplexed stuff
um I I agree I agree with you get crazy
I never figured you could run two things
in parallel on the same packet without
knowing what you're doing on each side
that looks crazy to me even if we don't
switch services
but
okay because if they all have if you
can't do two control loop on the same
physical system
right I mean even in the real world if
you have something that decides if your
rating system goes up and down another
thing that makes another decision for
the same meeting system you have a
problem no no but even even if you just
have parallel ones each with their own
PSE
they're going to compete on two
different flows right nothing yeah on
two different oh so you mean physical
resources somewhere in the network yes
okay okay that that's that's
classical.net you must ensure that the
physical resources are available to your
flows
so I've locked the queue because we have
six minutes left uh Lou you have just
squeezed in can you keep it short please
just uh
yeah this is a question to the chairs
can we ask to get a sense of the room of
whether or not we want to
um want uh going back to what Stu was
saying do we want to focus on new
terminology that may be more precise or
to try to leverage existing terminology
um and then refine that
and if I may
tweak the question a little bit remember
that on the table there is the the third
in between thing where
more of the existing terminology as will
be anyway injected in document
for everything which is a thumbs up
truck will go away basically it's going
to become anyway a path
the question is for the big track itself
right for the rest you want
already
so yes that's a good suggestion I'm just
trying to work out some way of asking
that question using the show of hands
tool I'm clear I'm clear that I asked it
very badly so
I couldn't come up with anything better
off the top of my head while you were
um
so I would like to point out that this
week I've seen um
various things that went poorly because
the show of hands tool is a blunt
instrument unless you think it through
beforehand you end up getting bad data
out of it yeah
and really we want to censor the room
um does anybody object
to the
to what I think my understanding of the
room is I think I heard
strong consensus that people wanted a
terminology section which unified
familiar topics for people from the two
re the two main inputs from the wireless
world and from the debt net world
and added some richness to say in this
document when we talk about this thing
and I liked Stu's words here we mean
something like this something like that
from the other world with some
qualifiers
and getting that in early you know
section three in that document just to
Aid the reader does anyone think that is
a fundamentally bad idea
I I thought that might that one is a
consensus so my following question is
given Pascal is not a native English
speaker
and this is very much about and I'm
going to say us English because British
English doesn't help sometimes
is there a is there is there a U.S
English speaker who would like to
contribute text to this and I'm not
saying that people where there are great
people who speak English with a second
language and so I'm not going to
discount them but given we are spending
a lot of effort on the news and I'm
using a French word for of of this
terminology
I think we need help on this is anyone
willing to step forwards and do this
I see Don FedEx hand I'm saying that for
the record
uh yes and I I will absolutely underline
that point you're correct you are
correct
that was two cards saying he'd be
thrilled to review and help tweak but
he's he's the wrong man to draft
right uh thank you Pascal you can
oh and balash as well has has uh raised
his hands which is a fantastic great
thank you Pascal do you want to add any
last points otherwise I I just have one
last point is because you said something
at some point though I did not want to
interrupt the discussion on that but he
traced
the image that people might
misunderstand something
and that's something is some Protocols
are based on sessions there is one
endpoint which does something the other
end points that has to be aware of it
and that's you know the matching thing
the pre-off doesn't work like that
for instance you might have one
replication point that makes two copy
and later on the right that may be
another replication point that makes two
copies
somewhere in the end there will be a
single elimination point which will
eliminate all the copies that single
elimination point doesn't talk to either
of the other two
they are independent and it doesn't care
whether
those replication nodes succeeded there
is no session
so at some point there was this image
like oh if I make a decision on my hand
I have to tell somebody on the other
hand of the network because that impacts
him no they must be independent
because there is no time to talk to him
anyway whatever we do he needs to absorb
we can never negotiate
and and to design different the design
is is distributed the operations can
happen anywhere and the nodes which
absorb the copies don't have to know who
made those copies perfect thank you
Pascal so uh we are very very close on
time
um first I want to apologize for the
fact that we missed the two-minute
silence because we were too excitedly
talking about things I can only
apologize to those who wanted to hold
that I'm so sorry
um
any other business does anyone have
anything that they wished they had
um talked about not concerning the raw
architecture draft
so well there's our there's our silence
um in which case it really even I say
thank you very much that was a
productive conversation a good Workshop
in quotes I think we have a clear way
forwards
um thank you all for your contributions
can you please maintain the momentum on
the list so we can just get on and get
this raw draft of this raw architecture
done because I'm very sick of it I'd
also like to thank those of us who've
been heads down on the the note taking
because it was a really Dynamic and
nuanced discussion we will no doubt have
to consult the recording multiple times
but uh thank you for the group of people
who've been note taking and please put
your name into the notes that you that
you were part of this
and one last thing thank you very much
to everyone involved with getting ldax
out of the door that was surprisingly
painful and behind the scenes a lot of
work happened so congratulations for
getting it kind of out of our hands and
thank you for everyone who helped make
that happen and that's it thanks guys
end of the last session go have your
exercise meetings and
check out of your hotel room which is on
my to-do list otherwise thanks guys
thank you Eve
thank you
for granted
foreign
to be honest I don't care if you call
them variables