thank you
it's a high last year
yeah
I guess
quite a few people surprising yeah
that's too positive
really yes oh it was fun sometime
Massachusetts
you must
be lost
open source God
hi everyone Seth uh
[Music]
welcome to the second the routing
working group meeting uh please make it
so familiar with not well so your
participation in the ATF
by participating in ITF you adhere to
the policies that are in effect
so the agenda for today we've got a
invite talk so it got best paper award
at sitcom this year we'll talk about uh
Network Define Network simulation and uh
thanks Moon Chen to come and talking to
us our first ATF please support her then
we'll have 15 30 minutes on new routing
architectural proposals
so first of all detection stuff will
also have David
thank you David for being here to talk
about Envy me and what should and should
not be done so we'll have
semi-formal five minute David
presentation our talking topic
and then there are some
spring stuff as usual so uh again the
fact that you see it here doesn't mean
that building routing we offer sometimes
people place to present and then
dispatch them in the right place
foreign
for the first presentation we are very
happy to have the uh author who received
this year's ACMC comes past paper award
to give us a talk
um so a quick introduction
um Dr Huang Shin Chen is a researcher at
Huawei Hong Kong research center before
joining Huawei she received her PhD
degree in computer science and
engineering from the Hong Kong
University of science and technology in
2020 her research interests include
network configuration management
intelligent sensing several physical
security and their intersection with
machine learning so with that that let's
welcome Dr chat
okay uh could you hear me
if I can hear you
okay thank you uh thanks for
introduction and good afternoon this is
a function a researcher from Hawaii Hong
Kong Research Center uh actually this is
my first time to attend iitf conference
I'm so glad and honored to be invited
here to share our recent work on network
configuration management uh this world
is accepted by this year's sitcom and
our work is titled self-defined Network
assimilation breaching The Last Mile
towards Enterprise network configuration
management with nursing
this is the corroborated work with Dr
yukanya dot Legion uh professor hyphoon
professor hongshu daughter Libby Leo
daughter gonjang and Professor Wei Wang
and now let me begin my presentation
and as one of the most important
infrastructure that will support
numerous applications in a perfect world
all network devices should have
homogeneous device models uh which means
that if given the same configuration
they should execute the same action and
in this way the network operator will be
very happy
unfortunately the real Network contains
a heterogeneous device models because
large Enterprise will operate Network
device from multiple vendors
and because they want to avoid relying
on single vendor to maintain sort of
bugging power and risk control and in
the meanwhile they will gradually
introduce a new device model into the
network resulting co-existing of legacy
and related devices
and it is a pen for the network operator
to manage such a multi-vendor network
so uh in common practice we will have a
soft defined controller situated between
the app layer Network functions and the
heterogeneous network devices
it's desired that the network the
controller can present a logically
centralized control plan to config
multivendor devices as if they are the
same
uh does the network operator will Define
a unified model at the controller it's
often stored as three hierarchy nodes of
the tree denotes some configuration
attributes such as IP address of an
interface named of a SEO policies and
Etc
subtrees will generally denote a group
of relevant attributes for example some
attribute for specific Network protocol
and the network operator will construct
this unified model and annotate some
brief context for attributes and then
after that they will go to understand
the menus the vendor menus and file
correct commands and
draft and validate the template and
provide the mapping rule from the
parameter of a specific vendor command
to the attributes in the unified device
models and then they should repeat the
same process again for a new device
model
it would be a very tedious and
error-prone process
so we found that this is the process of
introducing heterogeneous Network device
into a century controlled existing
self-defined Network and we Define it as
a soft defined Network or simulation
sna in short and we identify that the
key problem here is the mismatch between
two configuration models uh the
heterogeneous device model and the
unified model in the controller and we
found that the current SMA process will
require significant human efforts to
bridge them
and in this work we seek a more
automatic and efficient way to
accelerate it and liberate Network
operator from most tedious tasks
and our basic insight to tackle this
program is to design a system to
understand the menus as Network
operators and with especially automatic
system could first extract a validated
device model from its menu and then
infer mapping between vendor device
model and the unified model based on
thematic information from the menus
however realizing this idea in practice
will encounter three challenges
the first is the menu formal
heterogeneity
a device menu are usually the most
trustworthy sources to obtain
configuration model however there is no
standardization for menus they are
organized and format uniquely for
different vendors let's make it hard to
enable automatic menu comprehension
the Second Challenge is the error and
ambiguity in the menus after all all
menus are human written documents it's
inevitable to have mistakes and typos
and is also impractical to audit menu
from the first page to the last and
actually some problems are hard to catch
by human eyes
so we are handling this issue
automatically invest is very critical to
extract a reliable device configuration
models
and the third challenge is to bridge the
heterogeneity between configuration
models actually the configuration
language is designed by each vendor to
be visibly different with each other
for the same concept or intent different
vendors could use different wordings or
syntax but due to the sheer number of
CRI commands and parameters handcrafting
mapping is very tedious and error-prone
automating this process will require a
powerful semantic comprehension model to
understand and match similar network
configuration context
uh therefore we propose nothing uh we
design a partial framework to address
the first challenge uh it mainly
features a vendor independent device
model Corpus format and also the test
driven development procedure for
Reliable passing
and we then design validator to adjust
the Second Challenge
we conduct validation on three levels
the command level the intercommand level
and snippy level and we finally
identified more than 230 errors in the
menus of mainstream vendors
thank you
and we further designed the method to
adjust the third challenge
we change the network
semantic similarity inference model for
network configuration domain to Output
the mapping between parameters of
different models we also release a
validate executory data set of past menu
copers for future research
and this is the overview of Nasim uh in
the following let us take a closer look
at three key components
and the first component is parser
the key inside of the parcel is from
investigating the major attribute of
multiple menus
uh despite direct Styles or menu serve
the same purpose showing us how to
configure the devices
uh sorry enjoy I could not see the
screen now
you see the screen
I can
flip the slides but oh yeah see it's
very slow response
oh let me let me begin here
the key instead of the password actually
is this despite diverse styles of menus
all menus should serve the stem purpose
showing us how to config the devices
they should cover the CR commands
supported by the devices and the
function descriptions the working views
and the parameter description and some
representative examples
therefore we design a unified format
additionally with keys and value type
constraints as shown in this table
right now
uh
uh sorry engine and could you hear the
screen now uh but because I cannot see
this screen I cannot determine you don't
see the slides
yeah yeah yeah uh it's very slow uh
response uh I cannot tell you you can
see which size
okay
you want me to try to present the slides
uh but I think maybe it's it's better to
let me control but just the the spawns
are response this mouse here is very
it's a little bit delayed
okay let me try it okay
uh oh just let me continue sorry and uh
and so we designed a unified format here
additionally with keys and value type
constraints as showing the these tables
and for mainstream vendor we build a
password to cast this menu into this
vendor independent format So to avoid
this here we will show the sample uh
Corpus generated by our passing
framework and actually to avoid the
potential bugs in the developed process
we will adopt some test driven
methodology to ensure the quality so
here I will skip this part please refers
to our paper for more technical details
so in this way we actually can extract
all essential informations from the
menus and meanwhile normalize diverse
menu style into a unified format to
facilitate the following processing
so the second part is the validator so
uh
here the key inside is that we want to
extract a reliable device model but the
key inside here is that the menus are
not fully reliable so we identify two
main type of Arrow on ambiguities and
the first type is a synthetic
ambiguities for example this is the CI
command from a vendor menus and it has
unpaired left bracket before the remote
As symbol and actually there are
multiple potential valid facing options
we can remove the left brain key or
adding a red blending after the remote
as simple or adding a right bracket at
the end of the call command and choosing
which require judgment from the experts
and the second is the hierarchy
ambiguities for example these two views
in a vendor menu share the same example
snippy so that we cannot tell which
where there is msdp command enable the
first view of the second or both
so quick question
AC lindum so you're saying that you just
take a PDF goes into the parser and it
comes out with this Json that you showed
the example of is that is that what the
input is
it's like yeah
HTML document we use HTML documents
the input the initial input is the
manual and HTML format that you took off
the web is that what what that image is
yeah okay yeah okay thanks
so and our continued uh so despite all
the potential errors ambiguity I
mentioned uh previous we still want to
derive the reliable device model from
menus so here we design a multi-level
validation schemes and the first Parts
actually work on the command level we
want to fully audit the syntax of CR
commands so we just find out the command
convention in menu Preamble and express
them into the equivalent backwards
normal form and in this way we can use
the password generation tool to generate
the to generate the
a seal command syntax puzzle and call
them to identify all synthetic arrows
and then the expert can only the
incorrect one in more targeted and
efficient way
and the second part to work on the
intercommand level
in order to derive this tree base
hierarchy which is implicit in menus we
actually exploit the example Snippets
uh in the menus uh it actually is
example generally demonstrate an
instance of the current command and its
Parent Command so we will construct one
model to get their relationship on CRI
template level
and here we we use to construct a graph
from this template energy with the CR
instance and so I will skip the
algorithm details so in this example we
can infer that the CR command template
bgps number actually enters the bgp view
so the other commands with the same
parallel view can also reuse this
derivation and in order to handle the
hierarchy ambiguities we will quantify
the certainty of each derivation and so
that to facilitate the expert audit
later
and the third part of the design to work
on the snippy levels here we will
leverage the configuration configuration
file collected from the running devices
because they are collected from the
running devices they have the
correctness current here to uh to to to
be used for validations so for each CRI
instance single configuration file we
uh oh for each configuration uh lies in
the configuration files uh we can derive
it uh we can check whether they are
matched CLI templates from the correct
parent trial relationship on our derived
hierarchy and we can record all the
image one for the expert to audit later
to correct our derived model
so let's take a quick look at the
results of our Auto vendor device model
construction phase and our password plus
validator successfully constructs refine
and validated vendor device model from
four menus of popular vendors and we
also identify more than 200 synthetic
arrow and ambiguity in the menus so
please refers to our GitHub report for
more details
and the third designs component is the
mapper
by applying the existing
Let Me Wait I cannot see my screen
uh this
the side component is
the
existing tedious handcraft mappings we
found that the key of the sna is to pair
somatic similar configuration items so
since uh the path validator has obtained
the device model with abundant somatic
information from the menus and and those
parameters from the unify model is also
enriched with contact information
assigned by the network or operating
experts so we want to design the mapper
that can understand the contextual
information
by applying recent advance in natural
language processing so our resultant
model is the our resultant semantic
comprehension model is collaborate so
let's take a look at how it works so for
a uh for a given uh configuration item
actually we want the model to find out
its thematic similar ones in the counter
bottom part models so we will run the
following process for each pair of them
first we will uh
we will locate and extract their
contacts information actually depend on
amount of available information of each
model we can we can select different
number of contact sequence for the
vendor device model we found that the
parameter names and the description and
its corresponding CR commands and
function description and the working
views are very valuable for mapping
tasks and for the unified device model
we just directly retrieve is this
description information of each
parameter and secondly We Will We Will
leverage the
most popular natural language processing
pre-train model and we Channel domain
adaptive version to encode the
contention information into the vectors
so for one pair of parameters the encode
encoder will produce a pair of contacts
uh embedding letters and thirdly we will
evaluate
the similarity of embedding better using
cosine similarity and to Quantified the
semantic mechanisms so actually we will
repeat this process to multiple times to
get a ranked list
about multiple parameter pairs
and so therefore for a configuration
parameter our model Network can
recommend top case similar mappings
so the power of the network comes from
two sources and the first is the
pre-channel model expert this model is
preacher on a large natural language
inference data set with the same time
matching objectives so it's capable of
encoding two semantic similar test
sequence into two embedding vectors that
are closed in the embedding space
however this preacher model may have
limited performance in a domain that is
never seen in the pre-trained Corpus so
we will introduce the Second Source a
domain copers of network configuration
so to generate it we will leverage a few
a few map parameter pairs labeled by the
experts but these are only positive
pairs so we do random sampling to
generate negative Pairs and combine them
to focus domain data and we then use
this data to do the domain adaptation
fine tuning to get the network model
so uh
now let's have a look at the result of a
mapping performance of the mapper
actually map is recommended to generate
the
most likely mappings so here we adopt
the record at top k for evaluation
metrics which denotes the percentage of
test case where the correct matching
parameter are in top care recommendation
by mapper so higher recall as small okay
implies that the mapper is more helpful
to assist Network operators we use cross
vendor tuning and validation to evaluate
the effectives of fine tuning and as
shown in this figure fighter Network out
for the other models because we adapt
this model to the domain of network
configuration and regarding the save of
human effort we can take an example for
the Huawei case we can find correct
matching within top 10 recommendation
with 89 accuracy
so that's if mapper is allowed to
provide 10 suggestions the network
operator only need to reverse the man
menu eleven percent of the time during
the mapping phase resulting acceleration
by nine times
so who conclude we list some key
takeaways first the soft Define Network
assimilation is very essential for
mapping multi-vendor Network for
managing multi-vendor Network and our
solution Nasim C2 transform the original
TDS and error from process to
automatically an efficient manner and
configuration menus as human written
documents are not fully reliable
including inevitable errors and
ambiguities so nursing feature a
universe password framework a routerless
validator and a mapper using the domain
adaptable model to produce
recommendation mapping between
heterogeneous configuration models and
we also release a validate and executed
data set for future research and and
this is all of my today's presentations
thanks for all your listening and any
question is welcome
thanks so much for the presentation
we've got four minutes for questions
answers
I've got one comment as someone who's
been working on
for a very long time so you're trying to
do Brute Force attack on inconsistent
configuration with inconsistent cli's
across different vendors it's a noble
task really
CLI is really wrong obstruction to work
with and you know we wish it would have
been consistent within single vendor
single release it's not
there's usually some product manager who
would put some
something in it and hope it's working
configuration has errors to any degree
so
I mean running it through neural Nets
and trying to figure out what's right
and reinforce it it's a noble task but
trying to use other
abstractions
look at young it's not complete but
it gives you a very healthy base to at
least get consistent Behavior
doing the CLI again it's really Noble
just but being involved in this for 20
years I don't think it's even possible
yeah and actually if you mentioned young
I think Young is a very evident Trend
and because um I think we at least what
we focus on the command line interface
it's a very entry-level way to configure
network devices we we choose it as the
research Target because it's almost
supported by all network devices both
the Legacy and new but we think that
yeah young is a evident trend is a more
advanced way to config network devices
and
a young young but young still don't do
not fully adjust the difficulty of
managing multi-vendor Network I think
because uh although young is a standard
but each vendor seems to have their
vendor specific young so actually we are
also currently working on some topics
related to somehow
uh try to address the heterogeneous
between the different young models
between different vendors yeah but I
think yeah yeah I agreed uh that this is
a this field still need much efforts
uh to to address this uh heterogeneity
thank you so much for representation
yeah thank you
from
somehow I lost for lost network
connection from my laptop
so it's just very second
it's coming up on the front
loading
you might want his slope yeah
so show me
for the first time
let's try tradition again
on the
right way to do it
yeah Network right now too but it's been
spinning yeah you lost completely
effective
the strength of the city
should not be here
try to see other networks yeah
let me see
something neglected
I Research Foundation
foreign
someone
Gold Line uh lending me on laptop you
see
we'll take a letter
in confiscation but yeah this um
thank you
it's really slow
whoever is watching Netflix please
connect
connected
oh no it is
foreign
sorry for the technical difficulties I
couldn't connect to the ITF Network
somehow
I tried a couple anyway go ahead
are you controlling or shall I try to
control
you should be able to control it
okay it doesn't tell me anything though
okay
mm-hmm
okay so let's hope this works
um this is about routing on service
addresses is a newly submitted draft
together with Louise from telefonica
who's somewhere else over there I think
um
I mean it does work
um the goal of the draft that but as the
name suggests is to propose an approach
to transition from locator-based
addressing to an addressing scheme
where the atlas represents Services
being invoked for computation processes
and their generated information requests
and responses
we have um there's a structure that we
we've done so far I realized after the
submission I forgot the last two
sections and they're already updated
they were still empty
um so we go through a number of use
cases I will very briefly go through
them uh formulate a number of
requirements and then outline the
initial design that we've been working
with
um
we also provide the terminology and I
want to highlight a couple of things I'm
not going through all of them I'm not
going to read them but it gives you an
idea what we are describing as a service
we have the notion of the service
instance which is a realization of the
service and possibly uh several Network
locations across a network
um we we well the definition of a
service address that we're using
um was also important in the in the
description is the notion of the service
transaction which is a sequence of an
initial request which we call the
service request and the so-called
Affinity requests which are subsequent
requests being maintained because of
ephemeral state so the idea is that if I
if I have been directed to a certain
Network location to a certain service
instance I'm sticking with that instance
because of femoral State once my
transaction is over I can be assigned to
another service instance so that's
important in our model of service
interactions to to incorporate in the
design we have different architectural
roles of the Rosa provider the domain
the endpoint that are being explained in
the actual text but we put this into the
terminology section up front
um
as I mentioned we we uh outlined a
number of use case and we're working on
elaborating and adding a few more
uh section 3.1 talks about CD and
interconnect and distribution so here
the main key aspects that we're
highlighting is the multi-site
replication you have more than one CDN
most most possibly you have a dynamic
decision making as to where to assign a
client to to which of the sites and we
also have the ability to actually do
multi-site retrieval for Content um to
reduce latent civilians we presented
yesterday some work in a site meeting
where we showed the impact on the
latency variants if you do such thing so
instead of sticking to one side for the
duration of a let's say a long-term
video you're actually pulling content
from all the different sites and that
reduces your variance
um quite nicely
um Second Use case subscribers
distribute user Appliance for mobile and
fixed access
um so here the idea is to take the
so-called user blend functions which is
the the data plane in in in a in a 45g
system and distribute them uh the the
the selection of the UPF that handles
your request may be service and
therefore policy specific uh and and
also some of the use cases there uh are
specifically aiming at Edge compute
capabilities which you've probably heard
enough in in in in 5G type of scenarios
the third one is multi-homed and
multi-domain services so services that
are deployed across administrative
domains so for instance for Enterprise
scenarios and again in multi-side but in
this case multi-site Enterprise
facilities uh multi-homing is very often
used both at the client and its server
side
and the the consideration here is to
pick the best
um service instance where the definition
of best may be very very service
specific that's hence it's written in
quotes so the question really about
trying to answer based on those use
cases we're working on adding more use
cases to the document in the next
revision
um that's meant to come out after this
ITF as to how efficiently steer traffic
across these but with possibly
significant distributed networks
um and enabling also a dynamicity in
selecting the best service instance so
not doing this for relatively long
periods but doing this maybe for
relatively short service transactions as
well
the main idea that we are outlining in
the draft as the name suggests maybe
routing in service addresses is to
replace the typical DNS resolution plus
IP
data transfer meaning the off-pass
discovery of the service name onto an IP
locator with an on-pass discovery
uh to a suitable service instance
location so for that and you'll see this
later in a bit more detail we sent an
initial IP packet it's directed and
again this is an air quotes even though
we're using the standard IP semantics we
are putting the service oh
no don't know what happened sorry for
that um they're putting the actual
service actress in the extension header
uh and it's directed to a special to a
shim overlay which you've seen in the in
the next slide and well and the shim
overlay routes the packet on path uh
based on the service name not based on
the locator right
um it uses mapping which is a bit
similar in in role but not in in
implementation uh to the DNS records it
uses uh these mappings between the
service name and the the possible
service instance locations to do that
once it arrives at the server's instance
location it responds back the initial
packet to the client which then uses for
the subsequent so-called Affinity
request the direct IPv6
address of the service instance so only
the initial packets one and two go
through the shim overlay and after that
you're shooting down the IPv6 part
um I know you do that as long as the
service Direction lasts if you finish
the service transaction you go back to
step number one you initiate a new
service uh Discovery and you may
potentially be assigned to a different
instance
um right if you have stateless Services
you may only ask a good step one and two
so you never send an affinity request
because you have exactly one request in
your Rover what so the key point is that
the in band Disco recovery is performed
at the IP packet level and not at the
application Level that's the
characteristic of the design
so how do we do this we this shows uh
the gray part in the in the figure
there's the slightly nicer figure than
the draft
um is a so-called Rosa domain which is
identified in the terminology which may
connect via a traditional locator based
IP to other Rosa domains on for instance
the right hand side which have other
services deployed
um the the rectangular boxes are the
so-called service address routers while
the round boxes are traditional IB
Physics readers so you have the normal
ib6 tools as well as the actual saw
Roots in there it's located that we call
this layer 3.5 it uses Rosa specific
IPv6 destination extension headers it's
deployed either in the network as you
can see here or like Star phones so five
for instance are increased nodes into
Edge side so they may also be deployed
at the edge site it's non-path shim
overlay routing for the initial service
request and it doesn't do the dedicated
off path in Direction like in the
various methods like DNS gsrb Etc
it is also described in the draft the
traffic steering uses server-specific
policies you can either do an increased
base based selection and I'll show later
how this works and how this is
differentiated
um which selects the service instant
location at the increase directly or you
use intersile routing meaning you're
rooting the request between the
individual SAS until it ends ends up at
an increase to a data center for
instance as I mentioned before the
instance Affinity is done over native
IPv6 so the the the the the overlay is
not involved in that one anymore
and routing table sizes are limited
given that we introduced a Rosa domain
and a Rosa provider the routing table
size is limited to the contractual
relations you're having right only the
services that are being announced to the
Rosa provider are in the Rosa routing
table you're not hosting if you see a
certain a certain Affinity here to
information something networking the
routing table does not include all the
services available in the Internet it's
only the Rosa announced service in the
routing table that keeps the routing
tables as large as you want right
there's no client awareness needed so we
describe in the draft how a rose enabled
client can issue requests to a Rosa
service but also to a non-roller service
this is handled by the so-called service
address Gateway which then gateways to
the locator-based IP internet hence you
can access anything really it's weird
and now my control went away
um no
this was the right one sorry
um we have three different messages so
we have a service announcement which is
which is used by a servers instance to
announce its own IP address in relation
to a service address with certain
constraints the constraints are being
used for the traffic steering
I mean after the initial service request
which is is being sent to the inquist
saw to your to the client specific
interests are which hosts the client IP
the increase IP as well as the service
ID the reason they are you'll see this
in a moment in the message you can start
there in the extension header is to
avoid client-specific state in the
increase so we we want to avoid that we
you need to carry any particular
client-specific state which is why we're
carrying this in the extension header
the service response has the same
entries but it attaches the or it it
amends its own instance IP in the
response so that's how the client learns
where it needs to go for the following
requests
um the the positioning and the
implementation we're currently working
on which we haven't brought to this ITF
because we're not entirely finished
um but we plan on bringing this to the
next one it sits under the transport
protocol right it sits on top of IPv6 um
and it uses ipf6 as well for the
affinities uh and it's it's realized
under the transport
hence the layer 3.5 as we call this the
message flow is shown in this graph
again looks a bit nicer than the ASCII
version in the draft
the client sends an initial service
request and the the first brackets are
the source destination address the
second brackets are the extension
headers as an explanation of the syntax
that we're using it's it sends to the
increaser
um a service request which carries its
own IP the SAR IP and the service ID the
service ID is being used to determine
the next top and I come in a second
there are two different methods that you
can use which then sends the uh uh uh
the service request eventually to the
service instance where derives which
generates the response according to
whatever the semantic is sent generates
the best the service response back which
includes its own IP address which is
then used in the following request in
What's called the Affinity request by
the client directly so choose it
straight to the um to The Chosen service
instance once the transaction is over
which is the dotted line
um you restart the whole process so in
the next iteration the service request
may be sent to a different instance that
depends on your policy see right so the
key point is really that the service
only as a service requests are being
sent by the by the by the shim overlay
the infinitive requests follow the
direct IPv6 part
my Implement is at the moment through a
socket interface
um which specifies a different address
family rather than IP address you use
the address address family for a service
address and the entire mapping of the IP
address is being hidden from the client
you're sending to a socket and if you
keep sending it automatically switches
to the IPv6 address in the subsequent
requests the forwarding engine I show
this here the difference is we describe
two modes in in the draft one is what's
called request scheduling where the
increase directly decides what is the
destination of the request that allows
you to do runtime scheduling or you may
use for instance multi-optimality
routing this is was actually meant to be
a link if you click on the actual
underline text you find one of the
really nice papers you can use for
multi-optimality routing and service
specific environments published in
sitcom in 2020
and which means in this case you
actually forward it to a Next Top saw
instead of forwarding it straight to the
instance the the difference comes really
in the forwarding information base if
you look at service.org and this is only
written as a URL not to suggest it is a
URL if you read the draft you'll realize
they are binary encoded names but just
for for readability I I wrote the actual
domain name there service.org has three
Next Tops and if you read in the next
hub information based they Point
directly to an instance right while the
other ones actually point to the next
top and that indicates that for
service.org you have a a secondary
forwarding step that needs to select one
of the three possible choices and this
is the runtime scheduling that I
mentioned before you also can use a
special wild card this is the last NV
and the phone information basis which is
a white card which means if you're
asking for anything that the Rosa
provider doesn't know it is by default
forwarded to the spa to the service
address Gateway which interconnects
either to a different Row the domain or
to the public internet that's how they
um client unawareness is being realized
so what are the plans moving forward
with this job this is the first version
I'm quite detailed we worked a bit on it
but we want to provide more details on
the design realization of this larger
section five and incorporate any
feedback that we that we received so far
proper header descriptions there's all
still a little bit schematic
um Jens suggested to support to to add
support for multi-home service device
instances we had that already but we
didn't want to have it in the first
draft so four for different naming
schemes we're reusing the naming scheme
that's used in the Isn Community which
allows you to actually use naming
schemes that are not tied necessarily
into phones into domain name name spaces
um we can do this so that allows you to
also do other service scenarios where
you not necessarily use the classical
domain name system
more use case insights I already spoke
of different use cases involvement and
implementation insights we've
implemented this through ebpf
um in a standard Linux router and we
will uh combat more performance results
in the next ITF we didn't manage to do
this in time for the first draft um but
there is more and we also plan a demo
um
thanks what we see feedback on is is the
problem space the motivation are we
approaching this all from the different
and from the wrong angle
um comments on the architectural
approach on the realization anybody
who's interested to contribute or fiddle
with a draft please send us an email are
very happy to do this and the way
forward thank you sorry for the few
seconds more Daniel
please
can you hear me
yeah uh from ZTE um trust me I'm
um I appreciate it for the wonderful
presentation of dark and uh I have two
comments and the first one is about the
service address or um I I can understand
as the uh service identification
um my primary understand is that the
right here from your terminology the
service address or service
identification is globally you leaked
across terminal and network and the
cloud side where the service resides so
um here's here's the quite
um important issue well
um the service address or or in any
coordinate the service identification
um has has to be managed and published
by a a quite higher entity which could
coordinate and management the manage and
all of the entities from terminal
Network and and Cloud site so
um it's not simply about
um
from my personal understanding the
network Lord could not alone
this kind of service address because
it's it's there's a lot of multiple
parties and get involved the second
question is
um
um actually uh
um what I can say is the first benefit
is from from
from your proposer the service location
Discovery is a processed is removed from
the off pass such as the DNS to the
on-pass routing so the benefit is the
the latency
um saving something like that but
actually we here is the quite heavy
price involved because this is probably
we really don't have time for this
please cut to the cheese
so the first part is we're not rely we
are reusing namespace governance in the
application space in which you which you
work we do this very similar to the ICN
Community you utilize the domain name
you're obviously relying on the domains
governance that exist in the internet
and that means if you do a service
announcement I cannot announce
facebook.com
that's not possible I mean it's possible
to announce what the announcement will
be rejected obviously because I'm not
Facebook
um so that's that's the only place where
this happens where you may of course
fake a server's announcement but we are
tying into the actual governance that
exist and we utilize a certification
authorization of the announcement which
you can do if you use your namespace I
don't care and this is the nice thing
about the use of RFC 8609 in in the
draft you can use your own namespace
um the the the the RFC allows that and
then you can do your own stuff right
which which I don't particularly care
the second part is about is about
performance um now the point about the
performance is that we are putting this
onto the on path and it's distributed
which means in the even in the early
performance evaluations
um we are getting hundreds of thousands
of service because we're able to root
this is significantly faster than any
DNS resolution you can do and that's in
a distributed manner which means the
increase is only dealing with the actual
requests that are coming from the
clients it's attached to so it's way
faster than doing an edns resolution at
high rate so so um I don't think they're
that's one of the reasons we did this
because the performance could
potentially be so much better
thank you Robin
uh just brief
um
so while putting application Level
things down to the network
which provides speed uh drawback could
be that the application Level semantics
are causing complexity inside the
network so what about the ideas what
kind of application semantics you can
put down into your service Gateway
well the only the only applications I'm
putting in is is the the description or
the identifier of the entity you want to
talk to uh and and that's something we
we can relatively easily deal with so
we're using a hash based lookup which is
much faster it's relatively fast uh um
and that's the only thing we're really
doing at the announcement level you need
to do the additional uh verification of
the service announcement that's okay but
that's not done at data speed right okay
thanks thank you
thank you please do take your questions
to the list and I think would be
interesting also to look into what
didn't work in the cncc and have some
comparison yeah thank you
hello so my name is Roland Bliss kit so
um I have the pleasure to introduce Kira
to you which is a scalable ID based
routing architecture specifically
designed for control planes
um
and this is Joint work with martinez
over on Archer
so controllability is really important
uh you may have heard last year's major
service disruptions at large providers
mainly caused by configuration mistakes
they took a large set of services down
for a considerable amount of time so
Services depend on resilient
connectivity
and the control plane connectivity is
inherently important I in The Meta case
for example the guy is misconfigured bgp
routing and they cut off themselves from
their control Network and it was hard to
regain control over their routers again
just to SSH to them or whatever in order
to to get the whole thing running again
so Kira is aimed to provide a
self-organized robust control plane
connectivity actually
so it is designed to interconnect a
large pool of network resources uh build
compute storage network coverage what
have you
um and it also
should design uh should provide this
resilient connectivity for the control
entities that try to control the various
resources you have furthermore since
it's ID based it provides stable
addresses for moving resources via the
virtual machine what have you or your
own
um and so
uh it tries to provide uh all-in-one
features namely uh massive scalability
so it scales up to 100 thousands of
nodes uh in a single domain so to say it
is zero touch doesn't require
configuration so we cannot be broken by
configuration mistakes
um it has a really fast conversion it's
Loop free even under convergence or
during conversions
um it works well in many different
topologies which we call topological
versatility
um so we don't need any special variants
of routing protocol in in denser
topologies like data center topologies
also and last but not least we try to
also provide efficient routes
there are some related works that um
yeah do some things in a related manner
but um either dialect Dynamics or
um we have a non-id-based not ID based
approaches which work in specific
topologies only
uh so uh Kira is a routing architecture
which comprises two tiers one is the
routing tier where the r2k routing
protocol sits in and it is the 90 based
routing protocol uses Source routing and
works on top of any link layer while the
forwarding tier is some kind of
optimization where we use path ID based
forwarding which eliminates The Source
routing that we use for the source
running for the running protocol itself
um and it is can be seen as basically
similar to your label switching approach
and it aims to reduce overhead since we
get rid of source routing
uh for the control time packets so I
briefly introduced what the routing
protocol does and how it works
um so
the first thing that we need to to have
is uh to to learn uh the path in our
Network and so here we have a very small
uh just uh
small topology from a larger topology
maybe
um so the white nodes are basically or
white circle nodes are basically a
layered link layer nodes and the
uh every every node then creates a node
ID uh randomly basically and these are
the the large letters uh uppercase
letters in the in the blue dots
um so in the beginning every node
discovers it's super physical vicinity
uh so X for example learns the context a
y b m so we call them contacts
and so now is the question uh if x want
to reach z uh how does it work and so
the idea is here to construct the
underlay routes by using the node ID
based overlay and we use cademia for
that that's why we have K in the name or
the cat
um
and so the idea is that we use Source
roads
um to the contact that is closest to the
destination node ID
um I have an example on the next slide
and so what is closest if you talk
things are closer to each other you need
some kind of distance metric and we use
the EXO metric from cardamia for that
which roughly uh boils down to
um if if two node IDs have a longer
share prefix the closer they are in the
ID space
um so now
uh let's assume that um X Knows Why
um as discouraged in the first step and
here also we assume that letter is
closer and the alphabet are also closer
than the node ID
um
space just for this example uh so the
next overlay Hub would be y for example
so
um exynosa sorcerer to Y so it's routes
via a to y
and let's assume that y has known or
knows Z Already and so it also knows the
source routes you see so X Y will
forward the package to Z using that
Source route so the complete route
um what we call that find note requests
in order to discover a path will then
um also contain that that small cycle
here
and naturally uh that could incur some
path Bridge uh so the checking routes
longer than a shortest path but we can
do some optimization so first uh when
respond Z responds to X it can shorten
the recorded route uh just cutting out
the cycles and later pickets actually
can use a shorter route because X knows
a routes to M which is shorter and then
it can use net route for later pickets
so the initial stretch that we have can
reduce for later packets in case you can
um spend some state for that
furthermore archicad offers a flexible
memory stretch trade-off
and this comes from the fact that we are
using cademia based routing table which
arranges its routing table as tree of
buckets where each bucket has a size of
up to K contacts
K is usually a small number like 20 or
40. and they are arranged by xor
distance
um
so here in this example we have one
bucket that covers all contacts that
have the different first bit uh in the
in the whole other space so so one one
bucket also only 20 contacts for example
for the the half of the ID space
um while uh the closer you get to your
own ID
um the more information you have so
um context in the lower buckets are
usually in your on ID wise vicinity
um what we now do is store
in addition to the uh to to the the node
ID we also store the the path Vector so
the the path that we learned uh are just
attached to these contacts
um and so we can do that also uh in a in
a way that we prefer shorter routes uh
and this actually leads to the fact that
we learn shortest path to all the
contexts that we know
um and yeah the size of the buckets can
be chosen so we can have here a flexible
memory straight off and basically we
have logarithmically large or depending
on the number of nodes we have only
um algorithmically
um dependency on the number of nodes in
the network
so what about Dynamics so if in case
links and my routing is about
also covering with Dynamics so
uh we assume that once you detect
failure in the underlay so let's assume
the let's assume the the link between X
and B breaks uh then we have a two-step
strategy how to deal with that and one
is that your first inform your ID wise
Neighbors about the faith link
and then after that
basically uh you try to ReDiscover an
alternative path by the overlay route
um and we included not via information
so that note on the path didn't heard
about the broken links that so they can
know then they cannot reuse routes that
that also include that broken link
um we also periodically probe context
for broken path and you also have to
apparently look up your own node ID
um
in order to detect any network
partitioning and so on and the route
information validity is ensured by using
State sequence numbers in the concept
for path information agents
hey
sorry that was an animation
um yeah so uh briefly about the the path
ID based forwarding uh so the the
forwarding tier
um so the the main idea is to get rid of
the source routes and so we simply
replace the source routes by using a
hash of of this Source route
um so the path ID is basically just the
hash of the source route and we use the
path ID as label for the source routes
and basically we use then label
switching between the nodes
and uh the reason for discovering the
two of vicinity in the first place is
that we can actually pre-calculate path
IDs on your true and natural vicinity uh
so we only need explicit path set up for
path that are longer than four Ops
so uh we also implemented the thing and
showed that
um basically we use the IPv6 packet
format we can embed the node ID into
IPv6 addresses and so the idea is that
the forwarding tier then has the node ID
and a path ID forwarding table and we
use in order to use the path IDs we use
GRE encapsulation so you have GAE
encapsulation header in case you're
using path IDs if you don't use or don't
need path ID you can just use plain IPv6
header and so any control application
that is able to send IPv6 packets um may
use keyword connectivity
and also the autocup messages are
sent by using IPv6 so we simulated that
thing on
in topologies up to 200 000 nodes
various typologies uh just to briefly
show that this works not so badly
um so for example uh here we have
various topologies and a size of 10 000
nodes along the x-axis and shown is here
the average multiplicative stretch along
the y-axis and so the green dots are the
first packet
stretch that the first packet C and
later practice are the the blue
triangular triangles
um and we compared here with a ripple
and a soaring mode single double deck
single direct version and so on and you
can see that we can even achieve for the
first packets a better stretch values in
average and what is really nice is that
the stretch to the context so all the
contacts that you have in your routing
table
um you have effectively shortest path
routes
so
you've got two and a half minutes and 14
slides
one
go ahead you've got too many slides to
finish yeah no no don't they're backup
slides don't don't worry uh that's just
showing uh the Dynamics part
um so in case you have a hundred
thousand nodes 15 of the links very
randomly at uh 20 seconds
uh then we are able to converge within
roughly 10 seconds until we have nearly
full connectivity again with uh scalable
overheads so uh the the packet rate is
is quite quite low in in that case
so uh to conclude
Cura provides self-organized robust
control tank connectivity it is not
meant to be a replacement for ospf Isis
or bgp because it's not data plane
routing right so it puts connectivity
first and efficiency second
is designed for large provider domains
as we expect them to have in in 5G or 6G
networks and could be used also even
across multiple providers we're
currently developing our domain concept
where you can keep the routing inside
your domain more local so you're not
depending on other domains security can
be easily added in that sense that we
can have safe server defined node IDs
and that stuff it is a path Vector
protocol so we can also um
I have uh hash values or a Max for for
path and so on uh we also designed a
special end system mode that reduced the
overhead even more so in case you're not
the router you can still use the node
IDs but you don't have to actually send
router updates and stuff
um it also supports multipath routing
also the forwarding scheme the path IDs
do that and we can also easily integrate
a DHT for a simple name resolution
service Discovery and recently we had
developed a new scheme that enables also
very efficient topology Discovery so you
can discover within seconds 100 now a
thousand nodes topology with most of the
links
so um having said that um we have a side
meeting for today uh starting at 7 00 pm
and it's a small room as a 912. I have
to leave for the animal working group
because I'm supposed to be a give a
presentation also there but Paul uh
sitting here next to the the mic will be
happy to answer questions in case you
have some after the session so thanks
thank you Alan
any questions
foreign
so to do the initial Discovery if you
get a node you don't recognize a node ID
if these are randomly selected it's how
do you it's like a
how do you find know who you want to
talk to the thing is that that you wrote
simply to the closest node you know I
closest in the ID space and the Excel
metric is very nice and because it's
Unique so you always can tell whether
you're making progress in ID space and
in case you don't know a node that is
closed so then you choose the target
then there's some inconsistency in the
routing table or the node doesn't exist
anymore
okay okay so that's that comes you know
you know you want to talk to this guy
through some outside mechanism now so
when you start this out if you see if
you're trying to talk to someone you've
never talked to before you just send the
discovery out all your interfaces yeah
okay
not not through all interfaces just
through through one
right so so what if you send it the
wrong way what if it's it's partitioned
if you send it if you send it uh right
and the and the guys to the left yeah
right
um we do not see so much stretched so
that the the progress is usually very
localized in that sense so so if you
don't make progress then you go the
other way no I mean it's yeah if the ID
way is overlay is consistent then we
always make progress
that's for sure so the ID tells you
which way to go and that maybe exactly
yeah oh okay okay exactly yeah I think I
saw something like this years ago where
the IDS were you go right or left or up
or down yeah sure I said there's prior
work but we have it a bit differently
and yeah okay one things in different
ways
thanks
you have 15 minutes
okay
hello this is hibo from Huawei uh this
time I'll present tour jobs the
requirement of three faster for
detection under the framework of us for
detection for IP based Network
next please
who have control of the slides oh
how can I control it
bottom of your screen
can you help me don't find how I can
control those lines
just sure
it seems ready yeah
just go ahead I'll flip it for you okay
okay uh this is a motivation of our jobs
uh today for most database applications
always use a long time out to identify
Network failures this will cause the uh
ZIP codes but with the also they are
very much designed to the faster really
detection is especially for high
performance applications such as IP
based mme and the class computing
they can hardly tolerance the long
duration of failures included from the
tunnel scheme for example for the ones
when the failure occurs on IP based on
ume the iops will reduce to zero until
the equation can identify the failure
it's through the key level timeout and
also for cloud computing it is similar
where IP connection for the server is
done the correspond respondent Computing
in a phase will be blocked under the
whole Computing progress may be affected
uh this pillar detection there are also
there are there are some resist the
failure detection mechanic mechanisms
such as BRB
also we can deploy the multiplied The
BFG to accelerate the fourth tension but
this mechanism will typically consume
the system resource heavily especially
for the host and servers so from IP
network Point uh we need an economism to
help the host accelerate the 40 passion
and provide a better experience for the
high performance applications
uh such a high performance applications
are really wrong in controlled domain
such as a data center Network and this
should be considered when designing a
solution and deployment
next please
this is the ID based memory use case
here show a small activation I mean
Network
the horse the the all the horse and the
storage connected to two switches and
the host one creates a mme connection to
the storage you want the ip1 but when
the ip1 link is failed
the host one will not detect it until it
keeps time keep live timeouts the
failure May last for more than 10 tens
of a minute seconds before being handled
during this time the connection between
the host storage is disrupt the store
service storage service is completed
stopped
next please
this is another class Computing use case
there are there are now there are many
distributed computing algorithm for some
for some kind of the Computing algorithm
uh the server the servers will be
divided to several Pairs and each pair
will connect communicate with each other
Network about the Computing model uh the
server one server three are paired and
the server two and the server for
another pair they are they are they are
both to the class Computing but the
servers uh when the server series the
link to the leaf three is fair uh the
connect the communication the
communication between the server one and
server three we all will not work this
video will block the step of the
commuting and the whatever it is further
will will block the whole cluster
Computing the job scheduler cannot
reschedule the Computing task until the
detecting the server series failure this
thought it may be lasted for one or more
minutes
next please
uh
this is this is our requirements and
first we we want the network device that
can detect the link or network failure
second we want the network device can
synchronously synchronize the failure to
the other network devices because some
because there are many there are many
many network devices in network uh so
the network device can notify local or
remote failure information to the local
access endpoints and then after the
network device they send the
notifications to the endpoints one is
the test or be notified of the detection
over any of any of the endpoints
subscribing failure
so next please
this is a framework of our web reference
model uh
in this model it will using a controlled
domain both the client component Imports
and the server endpoints are allowed to
register with their IP information and
some other information with its access
switch Services the third one points
must reaches is register its information
to that network but the registration is
opting optional for einclined endpoints
uh each client unemployes subscribe to
the network for the reachability of the
IPS to its E2 where it where it is
interesting
the registration and the substitution
information is synchronized and
propagated through the network
when a network device such as switch one
or switches to detects is a scheduling
failure or awesome on on
Commercial Network failure the switch
will quickly notify the fault to those
client endpoints through subscribing
subscribing is the app information
when the client endpoint receive the
notification it can immediately include
the recovery by switching to the backup
path
next slide please
here is an example of a procedure
example this is a also a IP based mme
and Network
in this network the all host and a
storage devices register their
information to the IP network such as
its raw where is the where is the host
or storage under correct correspondence
PHS or host and client endpoints create
mme connection to special specific
storage device here is show the host one
it creates a mme connection to store the
one the ip1 and also he may create a
backup connection to story through one
the ip2
wants to know if your status and the
Subscribe is a request to the app
network
with me submit the request to the switch
one
one ip1 link Fields switch one can
quickly detect it and notify the failure
to host one host one when receive the
notification uh then he can to quickly
start the reset or recovery progress how
to do it it may be defined by the mme
scheme
that's that's like this
this is another particular example it's
for cloud computing okay in this in this
particular the job scheduler uh he
wanted to can also at the four servers
are connected to the network the job
scheduler here to a tasks and divide the
four servers two into two pairs so we
want to so on with the server three is a
pair under server two with a service to
work for so four is another pair uh all
the correct connection to to for each
other then job schedule wants to know
all the servers the IP status so it can
it subscribe to all the
subscribers to us every servers IP at
least one one ip3 is the link fails if
three can quickly detect the failure at
least one count so if three will
synchronize the status the change to
other leaves level one
receive the synchronized single
synchronize the information like it
notifies the job scheduler based on on
its subscription
job scheduler identifies the fourth path
and then he can reassign the Computing
task to other good servers so the then
the then the Computing will maybe
continue to go on
next slide please
so this is uh before is our two jobs so
next steps we welcome more comments and
discussions and also we revise the jobs
accordingly thank you
foreign
presentation or
I think it's both already
yeah okay
Greg yes uh Greg mirsky Erickson uh can
you kindly bring the uh requirements uh
slide
um in the meantime I just wonder so
what your goal uh what you are planning
to achieve with this work
uh our our goal is to the network help
the client endpoint calendar to quickly
detect the network failure such as the
link IP Access Link value on the app on
uncovered just a network failure
so the whole network to detect failure
or a device to detect failure
Network the network will detect the
failure and notify its a failure to the
access endpoints
so uh okay regardless of their size of
the network
so you you you you plan to do it as a
distributed system or you you look at
centralized uh system that can needs to
know about the failure
okay well we are just a tool do it by
the network device I mean distributed
system we don't have a centralized
system to detect detect the failure
so each device in the network
must learn about the failure
yeah this is a this is the first step
later maybe maybe do some optimize about
how to reduce some information and to
the network
well uh I I think that that's already
can be achieved through the igp protocol
uh yeah you mean that how to
implementation the network information
signalization this is this is not
described in our framework now
let's take it to the list again this is
so uh I'll let David talk about nvme and
uh I'll take a second as a working group
participant talk about clusters machine
learning classes specifically the goal
is to converge with a number of
attitudes not number of seconds
the infrastructure is highly parallel
massively parallel so there's no single
point of failure the goal is in
requirement is to detect failure as soon
as possible and Route around it if
you're an accurate Network this is
commonly implemented on the host today
you could you could flow Bender or
variety of other techniques to change
entropy to your out round failure if you
need to notify a controller you're in
seconds your machine learning job is
dead you lost hundreds of millions of
dollars potentially so the requirements
aren't suitable for machine learning
clusters in any possible way
that's my personal
trainer okay so uh my name is David
black I work for uh dell EMC and I sort
of feel like there's one wonderful
British phrase for the opposition party
in Parliament uh it's now with Charles's
King is his Majesty's loyal opposition
and I would lay emphasis on the loyal in
that please and Frank would like to make
a pause contribution here I'm one of the
original designers of MV mirror fabrics
and the Envy uh me over TCP transport
that is of primary interest to the
authors I guess the first thing I should
say is that I'm surprised the storage
networking configuration shown in the uh
slides are unrealistic uh it's an active
passive uh configuration storage
networking is typically moved to active
active these days which means as opposed
to Second path being backup the second
path is active so if you've got a
failure on the first path There's an
opportunity to immediately use a second
path to get that failure and information
uh communicated without having to go
sort of indirected through all the
switches
um and that that's probably the the
better place to start uh for nvme
because uh you're not relying on on the
uh the level of switch interactions now
turn to those interactions I can't quite
figure out what's going on here but it
looks like
um the failure detection mechanism is
building a model of the topology and in
particular of Ip accessibility for the
cases in which Link in the network fails
that's not a good idea to do on doing
their own routing system is the
authority of what network topology is
what the connectivity is and what IP
addresses are reachable from where
please don't reinvent that and I guess
uh one of the major point of minor point
the drafts labeled security
considerations as n a which I presume
stood for not applicable uh
unfortunately also stands for not
acceptable this class of it's broken
gone mechanism is a great Vector for a
denial of service attack and and uh
that's going to take some serious
security thought uh minor point is that
um real when we talk about link failures
we try to talk about as binary the link
is either working or it's not real links
fail in really interesting ways the uh
draft office said that they don't want
to use BFD okay but need to do something
so if the switches aside the link has
failed turn the link off the other end
of the link generally tends to notice
pretty quickly that lack of light means
means a dead link and then you don't you
don't have a problem with the two ends
uh disagreeing on link failure
okay thanks for the opportunity be happy
to take any questions uh including from
uh uh hi Beau if he's still on yeah
okay thanks for your comments
um
thank you dude
and Versace is coming just to let you
know All Storage protocols as well as
your Gmail like product calls do
Implement their own livability
mechanisms at much lower layers than AP
and it it's very fast it's actually rtt
Mach 2 rtts so we are talking Nano
seconds definitely not seven can you
please uh show this slide with the
storage a network architecture
from the previous presentation if
possible
yeah next
there is a
the next one
uh
yes this one
uh I just would like to say that in this
configuration if switch one and switch
two were connected and if access of
hosts to storage One turns three two
stars three were not uh my IP addresses
of these devices on the links connecting
them to the switches but on some kind of
say Lubeck addresses switch the switches
that in Fairfax can detect very quickly
the link failures could simply rear out
whatever uh our exchange happens between
host one and host any specific host and
any specific storage without involving
any interaction in the hosts whether the
host itself the host was remain
completely ignorant of what happens in
the network which most probably is what
most Network operators would prefer
uh
if the switches are not connected uh
this looks indeed like I think
[Music]
David has said a somewhat problematic
Network architecture but I did not think
that we have to uh I'm not sure where we
here should try to address the what
personalized see as a poor Network
design by propagating some new
functionality to hosts
okay thanks for your comments okay
okay
so um
thank you for the presentation and all
the comments are great so let's go to
the next one
um
oh by the way if you are on site please
make sure you scan the QR code and sign
into the meeting so
yeah
just a certain room
of course
like this no I I passed you the
commercial
you don't share this life
okay everyone and I will give uh uh as a
physics deployment use case so you can
have this time and
okay
and about this uh this document is a
Services deployment Constitution and
this is the zero sixth version so at the
first I will give our simple instruction
to the document now and uh as rb6 has a
significance
and other
uh what you cause to use Asics and have
and as so far one thousand and each
controller
networks have deployed the SMS sr6 V6
and so and also the SM Sr V6 policy have
also been deployed to money
networks and also use like as FD and TFA
and a filter and like this future also
have deployed to improve improve the SOA
of the network and uh and currently
money
um money networker was thinking about
the smooth migration to as a Basics and
countries so this document will give
some design and network design and the
migration guidance about about this
okay and this as a ZO6
we add a new use case about the
agriculture Bank of general diploma in
the case and this the agriculture Bank
channel is the top top five biggest bank
in Channel and the deployment is the
deploy the SR srv6 policy and controller
in the backbone Network and so first of
all we can
introduce the all the network status
in all the network uh the the ABC they
deploy osb2 and it is very six to asset
background and to to get the network and
to cut the C and P and to save here to
connect here and I always through VPN is
deployed at the local network to carry
the service like the financial services
and office service and internet service
industration
[Music]
VPN and the SRT is used but it is hard
to attention to the branch and to
implement and to end as a traffic
management
and the traffic between the branches and
these centers uh has
ability
[Music]
all right
okay so for the new networker the ABC
have deployed the network controller and
as a Basics policy over its backbone so
to automatically optimize the link
traffic and the SR policy is used to
implement the
and the calculated in centralized and
about
one 100
are deployed in the internet worker and
password
since the least launch uh mostly is less
than six so use uh use the IPv6 IPv6
original and only Japan so and the
compression is not used and the VPN are
divided by the service and the based the
company of eviction and the tsap
okay so and also a service and the VX
line are deployed as a DCP and to
implement the tunnel in working between
the DC and the and Backbone in the
worker and spfd is deployed to detect
the
service policy and connected when the
password fails and the traffic will
quickly switch to another normal path
and also a feature is used to to deploy
the two
implementing the service level I would
say detection so in the ABC
networks the future is deployed and the
next maybe is we the the is planning to
deploy the new future and in the future
okay that's all thank you
may ask you a question as a working
group participant which of the services
presented cannot be implemented over the
southern PLS you said the service has
advantages from your presentation it's
unclear
you could go to the okay Services
[Music]
countries is not used in the in the
campus in the campus so we just used as
a bone but for the campuses they can use
them so they use asafix country use they
use the sr6 from the this complexity to
the the remote and the
um look
we'll take it to the list but looking
through the list of features implemented
there's nothing that prevents
implementation of these teachers there's
any other technologies that exist today
you mean the advanced
I'll comment on the list
here from the TCP to another disappear
so looking at the list here
you said that it requires srv6 in order
to implement new services
I don't see in single Services cannot be
implemented with other Technologies I
think you you really need to clarify
what are the unique and distinct
advantages that would require
significant investment into new
technology in order to benefit from it
once again what you see here doesn't
just maybe I can instantly use a
detailed department
yeah thank you okay thank you
yes
can you hear me yes yes yeah I just said
just a quick question uh you know your
SRV says are you but are you using uh is
there an inner working that you're using
between the data center and the core so
the core is srv6 and the data center is
VX slave
I don't think anyone can understand the
word of what you're saying if you cannot
get your mind quality better probably
would be better if you send it to the
list
okay okay
all right
thank you
okay thank you
hello hello can you hear me
chair can help me
yeah so this is a for young from China
mobile this proposal is a
by a joint effort of the China mobile
and the h3c
you have control of this life yeah yeah
I I I guess
yeah the background is that you know we
have a good definition on the srv6
hierarchy uh the first level is policy
as then come to the path and the bottom
is a sid list so uh that this is good if
we when we got a failure we think and Sr
policy as our policy
so it's a good protection
but in case of about
if we consider if the one policy run out
of the resources or the policy got some
failure in for example some of the
sincerely field so the bandwidth
got impacted so not not all of the
services can be uh can be can be assured
with a good quality so we want to what
we what we want to do
in case of there are still some of other
parties that can carry those those
uh over traffic
so that's a that's a question that's a
problem we are we are we are thinking
so uh
so for example when there are 100
service and voice traffic has have
different as our current that means they
have they got different of the uh as a
policy because each Sr policy has
can be mapped to one color
so they are carried by different
policies
part of failure happened with with uh as
a policy carried
the OE traffic or the voice traffic so
uh we we should have some way to
uh to to keep our services running
so the idea is what we what what we
think is first is which we should
maximize
the failure or the degradation
protection in case of there's still some
resources we can use
the second one is we should minimum the
impact
after after taking the repair repairing
action that means when the general
failures happened we need to uh not not
not
switch over all of the traffic to the
other policy but just pick up some of
the some of the prefixes
from the impacted policy to the the the
the the other the other policy
so the last one is is that way we can
maximize the band-based efficiency
because uh in case of there's still some
uh bandwidth available we can reuse them
to
keep our services
running
so the then uh the best idea is that we
need to set some rule on which policy
could protect what policy
so the idea is to uh to to group the
policies together
uh and then have some some some some
some some priority mechanism to uh to
give
the order of the uh traffic uh
switch over
so the uh so this is the basic idea so
the zero there will be
uh flow classification which will
identify the service class and then
third class does does map to the color
of the as a policy and then we got the
flow steering to Stair not uh
individual policy but uh policy group
and then
there is a new uh new new unit or
component which is intelligence logging
which takes the
takes takes the traffic and makes the
decision on which which the policy that
it should forward the traffic
so uh the intelligent blocking unit also
takes some input of the network called
environment for example the BFD or some
of kind of uh latency or loss
passing off as an input
so first one is uh is a simple just a
flu classification and just take a take
some some of the uh some of the of
tuples or something they are to uh
information out and
again and to identify the first class
and the first Theory unit is also a
very straightforward
it's just a mapped the search cast to us
as a pass group
so the the
thing is so we come to the Intensive
intelligence login unit so this part we
takes the as a pulse group as input and
also some of the measurement
result as input so here is a policy
decision decision
function which which can just just
decide which which policy the traffic
should be go so we have the
several policies with each with the
priority set so prior to just represent
a
represents the highest
so so so the priority is a uh is is
defines the manner what's what's the
highest
uh
priority that's the parts policy should
take take a spill over traffic from the
Imp from the failure impact either
policy
yeah
yeah so uh there is a level called
measurement units that takes some some
to marry some latency or Twitter or loss
so uh last one is a flow foreign unit
that is normal so we have the example
here is first we Define the some policy
policies and with colors and then we
combine those the second step we combine
some of the houses together with with
the color
the third step we just mapping the
traffic to those
those past group
so that's that's the idea of what we
want to do but uh maybe it's not not
perfect
but we can improve it so that's all
thank you
we are not taking questions here present
to the list
thank you for the presentation we'll go
to the next presenter
okay
um so probably I can already start so
um my name is David Rowe from Huawei
Technologies this is a work actually um
together with my colleaguers Luigi uh
Eugene and um training talk about the
um signaling in network computing
operation
um
so
sorry
ah okay okay sorry
foreign maybe you can just
scan the phone oh okay should work now
it works yeah so
um things I only have a few minutes left
I will be just speed up
um so the motivation basically is we
already observed a lot of network device
on taking some communication tasks to
improve the overall Network perform
overall system performance and typically
they are done in the program switches
right
um but we are lack of kind of generic
and general way to define what to do how
to do where I get the data and where to
how to
process it so that's the purpose of this
draft
if you look at the use case one of the
use case here is happening a lot AI
artificial intelligence machine learning
happened in the data center where you
try to distribute the tasks to different
hosts
those hosts will take part of the
calculation and the send without the
back and there's a APS server called
parameter server try to aggregate those
data and punch back the results so
traditionally the way is you build a
tree or start topology
where the PS server will react to all
the results from those hosts but
apparently you have an in-cast problem
number one secondly the PS server
becomes a bottleneck right although
there's other Solutions like all reduce
try to design the ring topology to
distribute the tasks to different
servers but still this is not really
ideal so
we uh we find that let's switch to do
that task in the wrong line rates will
be the up to uh will be the best option
so this is one of the actually
um use case there are two other use
cases happening in the data storage
Network where you want to store some
data you just trying to get the right
right so you have to really check the
lock and then um once you have this you
can do that but I will not really dive
deep deep into those use cases those are
the real use cases
um they really need the network switch
to help it's not like with networks
which you can do better no no they
really need the network to do something
for them
um so the idea basically is to offload
those leading coordination Mark and
bottleneck Computing uh operations to
the network device in order to improve
the system uh performance
of course we don't want to affect the
forwarding performance right
um
so two things we need one is generic and
simple operators are designed to to
execute those scenarios you need to know
what to do where the data comes from and
how do you process it secondly you need
to have a expected way to Route the
package to the right place so that they
can be
operate at all executed so a quick
overview about that is we have the uh
hosts which should tell uh what to do so
there's a async header created on top of
UDP to say that okay I want to do this
aggregation and the data are coming from
those resources and how many of them so
this can be information this is the
first part the second part actually is
you have to have a mechanism to look
back to the right place because you
probably don't know which switch has
that capability right so for that we can
use a lot of
um kind of mechanism to root back to the
right place
in this draft we use the example of
surface function training we can also
use as our signal routing or mpls or
even others right but in this particular
example we use sfc so you will you will
see that we have a sfc Ingress proxy try
to create Eternal and then to Route the
package to the right place
um
okay so
um so
first of all the sync header itself this
header is used to tell the switch what
to do so you will see that
um we have a group ID we have date of
resources data resource ID sequence
number they are all combined to tell the
the switch where the data is which data
I need to operate on then you you need
to specify what kind of operation right
is a it's a sum it's a maximum mean or
it's uh
um CNS FNA or others
um of course you have the data offset to
indicate where the data is in this
package right
um particularly there's a loopback flag
indicates that after this data operation
you need to send the data kind of uh
back to the source or you need to
continue forward to the destination
um so
the second part actually is creates a
kind of a tunneling in this case we use
sfc as I indicated so in the Ingress you
just wrap up with the next service
header until the egress and then send to
the destination of course in the middle
there's some nodes with the sync
capability to do the data operation
um so this is actually encapsulation uh
by using sfc
um we use the base header pass header
and the context header
um the context header is the sync header
we I just explained
um the service pass header uh are
defined in RFC 8300
and of course in the base header we have
to specify
um the a few things like lens TTL or
others for the metadata type by quiz
coincidence means our sync header is
only 16 bytes so we can use MD type 1
that fits very well
okay so these are the last slides so
basically this is the first trying and
there we know that
um
it's not very clear for us where is the
home for this kind of drafts because uh
um this is working on the kind of uh
data by leveraging the program switch we
use the sfc as a carrier but as I said
it might be other
um kind of uh
routing mechanism could be better suited
for for this case so we welcome any kind
of discussion
um and we are going to update the the
draft based on that of course and this
is only the data playing and Next Step
probably we will do the control plane
and others yeah
thank you thank you for the presentation
so with regards to home to the draft sfc
doesn't accept any new work and we are
looking for guidance from alvare and our
ideas to
okay yeah okay so we will let you know
yep okay thank you and thank you this is
very timely interesting work with
prolification Transformer models it
becomes business I do my best
thank you everyone and we are done in
London and hope to see you in Japan soon
thank you yes
I'm just gonna switch
so in network computers it's an existing
technology it's not new right there are
use cases