uh confirm that you are hearing RS it
would be appreciated thank you
I don't know we can hear you
oh we can hear you no problem
thank you
actually yeah
I can run this night because I've
already started go ahead
you know
okay good morning everyone or good
afternoon you're in Spring rocking Rupa
uh we're a full station today so we're
going to start now
remember that the session is being
recorded on including a video if you are
in the room
this is the is he not well you need to
read it if you haven't read it
especially if you are contributed
foreign
for ITF uh 115
so if you are in-person participant
you need to to sign in using mythical
multicolite this is being used as blue
sheet
and also this thing is being used to uh
to queue on the bike
so you have to enable queue on
meticulite before going to the mic
so that we can under a single queue for
both Olo code and remote attendees
uh but obviously keep your audio and
video off
if you are not using the light version
I saw something very important
um everyone need to wear a mask anytime
except if you are actively drinking
eating or speaking at the mic
this is uh very important this is going
to be checked
including during the meeting so please
uh please make sure you have a mask
if you're a remote make sure your audio
and video are off unless you are
actually presenting
on the usually your headset is a is a
better audio quality
in terms of minutes we're going to use a
collaborative tools which is available
at the following URL
uh you're welcome to help to take notes
at least please check and correct your
name and comments you can do so
IHF is moving to a new Wiki system
so spring working up has moved to the
new Wiki it's available at the following
URL
the week has been slightly reorganized
uh it has also been updated so thank you
for being about that uh you're welcome
to to check uh whether the content is uh
correct during the migration
especially you can check whether your
request for last call or adoption code
is still there and still correct
okay so since July uh we have adopted a
new policy in the working group
so we now among data an implementation
section in the draft
at least before working up last caller
this section is based on
the b205
which is about improving awareness of
running code
with implementation status section
we're a bit more specific items we
request all items either identified in
section 2 of the BCP
to be a to be filled
you can put not known it's fine but just
to check that uh
is not lost it's not blocking for
progressing to ASG but we do request the
best effort
so you can feel non-reporter does not
apply but something needs to be written
we also
um
ask for a statement that the
implementation
um is compliant with all mercen should
in the specification and if not which
one are not followed
on as per PCP 205 the section will be
removed before RC publication
so you can check the full policy on the
wiki
but it's just a reminder it has been
discussed on the list
in terms of a document
so my mistake in the slide the working
group Plus Code has not been started
actually we started but we
we stopped it because the implementation
section wasn't there
but we are about to start again the
working plus code on SR education
segments
so please review and comment it's
important for specification to be uh to
be supported by the group and to be
reviewed from a technical standpoint
so it's very important
otherwise the graph will not progress
in terms of classical we have an ITF
last call just started on a MPS pass
segment
with nsh integration with um with
segment protein
so that's all for document status this
is the agenda for today we have a full
agenda
so please stick to your allocated time
which include time to present on time to
to discuss
is there any any comments or bashing on
the internet
anyone removed no so if not we're going
to to start
with the first being a Rakesh
for MPS Network action
uh good morning everyone my name is
Rakesh Gandhi from Cisco Systems I'm
presenting the mpls network action
header and coding Solutions uh draft on
behalf of the co-authors listed um many
thanks to all the authors for um working
together collaborating and producing
this converge unified Solutions I really
appreciate it okay next slide please
that's right next slide there
yeah many thanks to all the contributors
they've been co-authors as well but with
the limit of five authors um so many
many thanks for all your inputs and
contributions next slide please
and next slide please
so uh in agenda we have this being
presented in past tomorrow there is more
time allocated for this presentation in
past there will be good discussion on it
as well
um and we're just presenting uh in
spring because of some Sr mpls um
implications on it the scope is
we look at the scope the solution that's
presented in the draft uh some we have
reserved our codes uh there is some
ordering there's some good discussions
happening on the action ordering
backwards compatibility and the next
steps next slide please
so the scope of this draft is uh for the
mpls encoding Solution that's uh in the
label stack there is a another draft for
the Post stack highest draft so the both
of them together form the complete mne
solution and the scope is to meet them
in the requirements and uh framework
that's already adopted by the mpls a
working group next slide please
so there are two parts to the solution
one is the network action the sub stack
header and the second is the action
encoding the header is basically a bspl
label indicate indicating that there is
a substance there which is encoding
parameters like the scope the ordering
length and whatnot and the action is
basically a TLP so opcode length and the
ancillary data is the value next slide
please
so the header test mentioned there's a
bspl uh there is a length of the header
for the so a lot of work has been gone
in defining this encoding for easier
parsing especially in Asic so there is a
land uh that the scope is there if you
want to do on the end points or hop by
hop or on select nodes
um there is some discussion ordering
there's a beat this is it must be
executed or the order is specified or
it's an optional next slide please
and the second part is the X and
encoding part which is a tlv so you have
uh op code the data and the length of it
so it's uh not recognized using the land
it can be skipped uh there is a known
awkward handling uh so if you don't
recognize it uh there is a way to
specify either a Skip and go to the next
one based on the land or drop the packet
or just forget about M A and just
forward the packet so uh this is
basically uh if you can see this as a
toolkit and how application will use
this toolkit it will be up to the
applications uh so the the programming
aspects of it and all the parameters are
in the solution
next slide please
so uh for there is a substack per scope
uh so for the hubby Hopper selector a2n
uh scope uh there's a sub stack uh this
is uh defined to make the parsing and
processing easier on the midpoint nodes
next slide please
so we have reserved some of course uh uh
there are four or five of them first one
is uh to say where the offset is for the
Post Tech data so this is to allow the
uh the gsch kind of uh existing
um data or header to be carried another
one is an OP code to just if you just
want to carry the flag based accents
there is a third one is for the flag
based Excellence with data and then
there is a another one to carry uh the
post stack network access as well so
that was that's on the next slide um
yeah so we can skip this as well
yeah and there are two uh special uh of
course one is the upper 127 so it's a
seven bit of course in case we run out
of it unlikely but there is a way to
extend it and 126 is if there is no uh
aim stack action and there is only a
post-tech accents uh 126 is a reserved
for it next slide please
so there is some discussions about
ordering how it should be executed so
there's an OB Define if it's set then it
must be executed in the order that's
encoded if not then it's based on how
the application Define it there is some
discussions about what should be done in
stack or post stack uh so uh there are
some flag base so how that should be uh
uh executed as well so there are some
examples in the draft on what the
authors think can be done uh welcome
your comments on that next slide please
so this is about ordering between instac
and post stack as well so next slide
please
so there is a lot of uh brainstorming
and thinking went in to make sure the
solution is backwards compatible
especially if you're only going to do
the end-to-end processing uh or
end-to-end m a uh we don't want to
upgrade the penultimate node or midpoint
nodes it should be transparent to it
make sure the ecmp is not adverse
affected uh make sure that it doesn't
Alias when existing reserve bspl it can
coexist with gsh so a lot of the uh
thinking has gone in but there could be
something so if you have feedback on on
this aspects please let us know
and next slide please
we'll skip the advantages
so at this point I welcome your review
comments and feedbacks as mentioned this
is a converge uh unified solution among
all the authors
um uh we receive lots of good review
comments uh and we are addressing these
comments uh some cleanup is required
there's some discussions on the scope at
ordering um so on all the aspects that
we presented today uh let us know if you
have feedback comments
and that's all I had
uh Grand whiskey Erickson so you
mentioned that uh the offers paid uh
special attention to uh
end to end
uh operation of MMA so basically when uh
anime is expected to be operated only at
egress
uh but my understanding is that uh there
are other uh options there is a hubby
Hub and there is what's called select
um given uh it's currently indicated in
very high level
of encoding
uh do you see that uh different
modes can be combined
together for example so some functions
are like iom
being requested to do hubby Hub while
uh for example uh generic uh
Pro indicator
is clearly end to end
yes definitely so uh there is a sub
stack for hubby hop and that is a
substack for end-to-end only requirement
for backwards compatibility is that the
m a bspl if it's exposed or under
received packet at the no receiving it
and that does not understand the bspl it
may drop the packet
um so that's the only constraint for the
backwards compatibility so the Ingress
and cap node needs to make sure that
along the path is never received vspl is
not at the top on the received node that
you cannot understand
um well that was not really my question
uh let me rephrase so for example
imagine that uh because of uh maximum
stack that
along the path
um we can put
um Hub by heart and end to end at the
bottom of the stack
so
to do hard by hop and end to end Network
actions with the current encapsulation
do you see it's possible to do it on the
one special purpose label or that will
require two special purpose labels so
two Network action sub stacks so the the
one special purpose label we can have
multiple copies of the sub stack and we
can have copies with different scope so
you would have one sub stack with hop by
hopscope and another sub stack with I2
Esco and hubby Hops uh substack will
contain the iom and the second sub stack
with the same bspl will have the flow
identifier for I2 okay thank you
okay thank you any no that's uh many
thanks
thank you
and now we'll we'll move to um next
presentation
for interlayer Network programming
um presented being uh U1
is my voice okay
I can hear you I'm going to share your
slime yes
good morning everyone uh this chapter is
on the topic of slv6 foreign Network
programming and the authors are from
Huawei and China mobile next slide
please
uh first I will introduce the background
operator usually have a multi-layered
network the layer 3 is normally IP based
technology where different technology
could be used for the underlying layers
for example there are two another one
the closed layer Network programming and
the optimization is expected it is
considered more efficient compared with
the independent planning for each layer
but it's also considered more
complicated as the way 6 enabled Network
programming by encoding Network
instructions in IP Handler but currently
only the network instructions related to
ipd are defined
so we come to user srv6 for the network
layers under IP
so we think slv6 can be further extended
to achieve the same needs internal
Network integration between IP and the
under layer layers
so this document describes the use cases
for the internal Network programming and
we propose a new srv6 function for this
purpose next slide please
foreign
use cases for the inter-layer
programming these three scenarios are
very common and widely used in The
Operators Network first case is IP and
Optical Network integration
in many scenarios in the network the
underlay of IP network is the optical
network but in some cases Optical parts
and IP parts may not be one by one
mapping so the reduction to Optical
process may not be fully used by IP
layer secondly the optical process may
exist between adjacent to IP nodes so
it's not too reasonable in the layers
rate polity
the second case is the IP and MTN
integration the MTN is Metro transport
Network it's a new technology and has
been divided in itog.8310
the m-team parts layer uses TDM
switching the intermediate nodes to
avoid Hub to hope I hope IP packet
display team so mq nodes can support
both per hope ip40 and it also supports
MTM Parts cross connect
the traffic can be carried using IP
parts and team parts or the combination
of the two but currently srv6 only can
be used for the IP pass programming for
the MTN Network the MTN Parts is not
included
the third use case is traffic steering
to a layer 2 random member link each
member link is a layer 2 connection
without layer 3 and this
um
and decency so if we want to choose one
specific Layer Two member link we need a
new function
next slide please
[Music]
also we propose a new slv6 which called
end XU in order to solve the inter-layer
program in the use cases this endpoint
with underlying
cross connect is a variance of the and X
Behavior it may propose it for the
interlayer programming and traffic
engineering uh the end actually is
associated with an underlay interface
which connects to one or more
underlyings or connections and the light
and 15 from the slv6 and progressing in
the current RFC
8986 is replaced by the following
forward the package through the
underlying interface associate with
seeds
next slide please
in this slide we give application
example to use the index using IP
Optical integration in this figure we
can see there is a IP networks only the
optical Network the node P1 to pH is IP
nodes and the node 01206 is Optical
nodes if we want to set up a package
transmission connection from p7 to the
right pH with normal segment routine
solution we can find the seedless in IP
network is p7 P1 P2 P3 p8
but assume there is Optical parts of 102
203 if there is taking the optical
Network we can use the NX usage to
P1 to steal traffic to this underlay
Parts under the optical parts so maybe
we can provide a lower literacy compared
with the normal IP parts
therefore the IP Optical interlayer path
can be created Created with a seedless
the new set listed p7 P1 and XU from O2
to O3 then go to the P3 pH
next slide please
we give another example in this slide
it's a application of NX during ipmq
integration uh we can see in the figure
in the figure the operator earns both
the MTN Network in the metro area and
also IP network in the backbone area but
for the empty nodes it builds two
separate Network layers the layer 3
function in the topology and the MTN
Parts topology
connect so we can use and X usage
to be allocated for each MTM parts
so we can correct a zip list with nxu to
end to end parts with layer 3 and I'm
two segments
in this solution we can flexible select
empty parts and layer 3 in all the
networks
next slide please
also inclusion we think the income layer
Network programming is a significant
requirements and stress to study and
divide the endpoint function for this
application and any comments and famous
feedbacks are welcome thank you very
much that's all
okay Sasha you're up first
hi uh I'm social Einstein from ribbon
can you please uh show again the the
slide with the no one uh one little bit
yes this one
uh I have a question
uh as explained
the optical path between P1 and P3 is
not an IP uh an iPad
my question is when P3 receives an IP
packet from
p7 I think uh how does it know uh which
layer two encapsulation should be pushed
on this packet before it is sent by the
optical path
because without this uh encapsulation P3
most probably wouldn't recognize the
packet as an IP packet and wouldn't be
able to forward it
via the IP pass to p8
[Music]
uh we normally we ate if the parts were
an IP interface P1 would try to resolve
uh
battery IP address or something like
that using our Pro uh Naval Discovery
but since the Optical path is not an
hyper pass such resolution seems
impossible
hurryan do you have any comment on that
[Music]
how well uh ran ran Chen you're next
yeah
okay uh
hi uh we agree with the useless
it's a lion Network programming at the
requirements and thank you very much for
your visitors to work and we also have
similar proposals uh by the way things
but new as always six and the bxc we
have here for interlier Network
programming
the srv6 and the pxc function mechanism
has been implemented by the key and the
China mobile has successfully completed
the basic verification of this function
hope it can catch you and the working
group attention thank you
thank you
Katan go ahead
go uh kind of follow on to snasha's
comment uh that
uh the whether the optical path is IP or
not is I think not clear uh but uh n dot
X said uh which is in RFC 8986 Network
programming
does can be used for layer to bundle
member states and therefore I mean I
don't see any reason why we need a new
uh Behavior it can be used for this
Optical link as well
for steering into Optical path
n dot X existing one
okay thank you ketan Chetan your turn
from Huawei and firstly I'd like to
respond to Sasha's comments on the
uh whether a P3 can correctly receive
the packet and forward it I think it is
a good question rather how to resolve
the like the IRP all the layer tool
information
uh since this draft currently does not
cover that details but perhaps we can
consider to uh
distribute some kind of information
through some control plane that is a
reply and the truth comes from Curtin
uh our understanding is uh the current
and Dot X behavior is very is correct
explicitly defined for the layer 3
adjacency and that kind of information
are used for the to build the leadership
topology and the forwarding pass in the
leadership network uh we Define this
node.xu to separate it from the
leadership apologies so that we for some
Network behaviors we don't want to mix
the literacy adjacency with the entirely
links so that we can have different fast
computation with four different kind of
service so this is the purpose to
distinguish these two food behaviors
okay
okay we'll move on to that
somebody was trying to say something I
couldn't tell who
okay we'll move on to the next
presentation thank you
hello can you hear me
yes we do
yes thank you uh I'm using Leo from
China mobile and today I will present
the encapsulation of BFD for The
Advocate policy
this is the first presentation of this
draft
next slide please
okay
we when we use the BFD session to
monitor the srs6 policy and as we know
uh sos6 policy has three levels and the
brt session runs associated with the
second list level and when we have
decision done the set the associated a
second list fail and the traffic will
stop forwarding and with this uh
specific segment list while all of the
signals the failed of the active
candidate parts and
the traffic will switch over to the
backup candidate pass and all of the
candid paths fail and the policy field
uh
why we uh the second is that uh uh what
the choice of the address for the BFD
and here we uh give the two types of the
BFD as DMV and the upfd ubfd means that
we use the bfpi code function and you
turn on the reflector and when we use
the spfd the head and address we can use
the iv6 address of the head end and the
and the two and the address we use the
endpoint of the SV rv6 policy or
specified by the local configuration
and for the ubft the head and adjust we
use the x36 address of the head and
we'll use the root ball or non-root ball
uh
for the tail end we must use the root
Pro ip6 address of the head end next
slide please
and uh we have the uh two modes of the
encapsulation of the BFD packet and the
uh the the difference between the the
SRH how to uh in Captivate the SRH and
uh for the track mode transport mode the
SRH is inserted after the ip6 header and
the tunnel mode we have the outer ip6
header with the SRH and the inner it's
uh for the BFD packet like the plan IPv6
pack package still into the srv6 policy
let's start sleep please
and next slides we uh I will uh
give the details of this uh
two modes for both the fbd and ubfd and
when the spit in chess mode transport
mode we are encapsulated only one IPv6
header and the SRH and for the sl0
position should be the athletic feed or
the ip6 address of the tail end node
but uh
sometimes the last segment of the second
list in the sr6 policy does not belong
to the tail end it can be a n dot X
segment of the parliament
Hub or a bunny seed so in such cases we
will add
a ip6 address or s36 seed of the tail
and node and the last segment will put
in the SL1 position in the SRH
and that's the slide please
when the sap internal mode we are
encapsulated the inner IPv6
header with the
ability packet and the author with the
IPv6 header with the SRH and
at the same
so
zero position should be the s36 seed or
the ip6 address of the tail and node
and
if the last segment of the second
listing sr6 policy does not belong the
tail end and maybe a n dot X but did
this I know that without the USD flavor
if if he he has if it has a USD flavor
it can decapitulate one in at the
punishment hub
so if we
that have the USD flavor or it's in it
is a burning feeder we should add ipv 6
address or a seed of the tail end load
in the sl0 position and put the last
segment of the segmentalist in sr6
policy in the SL1 position
so that's the slide please
the next is two slides about the ubfd
when the ubfd in transport mode that it
is uh that is a simple thing and only
one optimistic header is used to
encapsulate the echo packet
and for the SL
zero partition we use the SRA 6 seed or
the ip6 suggests of the head end and the
one the echo package arrived the tail
end
it it will use the destination address
at the SL 0 petition that is the head
and node address
uh one the usbsp in the tunnel mode we
encapsulate the inner Acoustics header
and the outer s36
encapsulation and
the destination of the inner
fps6 is the address of the head and the
node and the the
Outer Outer ip6 header we use the SL
zero partition should be the isab is six
seed or the IPv6 address of the tail end
and that is the same scenario that if
the last segment of the srv6 policy
without the USD flavor or upon your seat
it we we will add the fb6 address or
seed of the tail and in the SL steel
zero partition
so next slide please
so that's all thank you uh welcome for
the questions and comments
okay Greg
um Greg nurse Erickson
um a couple questions but um probably
there
uh first question is uh what's special
on encapsulation
so special for DFD
because I think that you explain uh
different modes of a certain
encapsulation in the SAR modes
but I don't see that it's different from
encapsulating payload uh and services
that to be monitored using uh BFD and I
I cannot find anything that is specific
to BFD being used over this a service 6
modes
we just work on the how to encapsulate
uh the BFD packet in the atheristics
policy and it may be uh have a major
difference from uh for the normal date
package
but if you uh okay if you suggest that
DFD should be encapsulated differently
from the payload then how you guarantee
that PFD will follow the same path and
will be treated the same as a uh service
that you're trying to monitor
uh I see that there is some
contradiction so you believe uh that BFD
has to be encapsulated differently into
a service six policy uh compared to
their payload
but then the question is if that's the
case then what are you monitoring
because if you encapsulate differently
on a service six level then uh the
packets would not follow the same path
okay I think this probably needs to go
to the list right a little short time
I mean I think Greg you've got a good
question but we need to take it to the
list Trotta you're next
yes go ahead
yeah so another question that you want
to know if it's not clear why you're
defining two different modes like
transport modern tunnel mode
it seems like all the scenarios can be
satisfied with just one word for example
transport more and it can detect the
liveness of the segment list
uh so can you explain why you define two
different modes
uh so I cut here very clearly
okay I will post my question on the chat
thank you
hi can you hear me
go ahead
yes can you hear me
yes
I yes my question is
um
the the uh why can't uh the sspfd
packets can take the uh use the standard
srv6 programming or is there anything
special that's being done in this graph
other than using the standard srv6
programming
uh we we just use the the standard sl6
programming we do the uh change anything
of debt
okay so what what is uh what would be
the benefit I guess of this graph what
is this graph adding outside of srv6
programming
um that's uh
that would need to be standardized I
guess good special outside of normal
behavior of a packet I guess it's being
um
either to be monitored from the ahead
and you know to the tail end
um
okay Jeff go ahead
Jeff Hardy speaking is with the bft
chair
uh your presentation was clear thank you
this comment is primarily addressed to
the spring chairs
we're currently tracking five distinct
documents for BFD out of spring one is
adopted four have not been
the documents are substantially the same
in many respects this is part of what's
been commented on in the last several
speakers
my suggestion would be to the working
group that rather than having five
distinct documents since you know
majority of this stuff is overlapping
Technologies with specific examples for
specific technology that's our v6s or V6
tunneling
please consider taking one of the
documents and simply having an
individual encapsulation example for
each of them since the procedures are
largely the same
this will probably save yourselves a lot
of grief and when things come around to
being reviewed by BFD you know for your
last call Process we'll simplify things
I can certainly understand why you'd
prefer not to have to review five and
we'd certainly prefer to see the various
authors pull together so that there's
one set of review in Spring as well
thank you Jeff
so next is a segment routine based
solution for hierarchical igf Network
slices
lion
hello everyone this is Liang from
Channel mobile
I'm going to talk about the topic of
segment routine that's the solution for
hierarchical ITF Network license
uh on behalf of all the co-authors
this draft has been completed in this
disability on 114 meeting
and is the suggested to presenter to
Spring also
because the solution is based on the
segment routine
so we also look forward to 12 months and
want to get your opinions on whether it
can be moved forward
so next place
for the concept of the hierarchical item
networks like this is based on the itfl
terminologies
Network slicing iqf Network slides and
the network resource partition
the hierarchical HF Network slices
described the networks like this which
can be further sliced or convent
hierarchically
uh for example one of the possible
scenarios is that an industry slides
needs to be divided into multi-customers
like this
so generally the idea of the draft is to
propose a true level hierarchical item
networks like this solution based on the
statement routine level one network
slides
is associated with the flexed alcohol
with the dedicated sub interfaces and
the level 2 Network slides is realized
by using the as a policy with additional
nappy ID on data plane
uh next place
and this slide shows the topology and
the traffic folding of the true level
hierarchical slices
it's a level one is associated with a
flex alcohol and the traffic is still
into the flex elbow passes
using the prefixed seeds or as a value
located a statistics locators
and the level 2 Network slides is
associated with one of a group of as a
policies under the level 1 NRP and the
traffic is geared into the SR policies
next please
uh the network resources is also
partitioned in a hierarchical manner
kicking bandwidth resources as an
example
the level one and wise is guaranteed by
a little series sub interface with
dedicated bandwidth and the prefix state
or srv6 locators is used as a datably
identifier
um the level 2 bandwidth is guaranteed
by kills with dedicated bandwidths under
the little three step interface and the
NRP ID is used as the data plan
identifier
next please
about the relationship between the NRP
and the slides actually
each NRP either level one or level 2
boost can be used to support one or a
group of network slides so it is
compliant with the ITF definition
but here for the example when we
actually
deployment theater it's much more
complicated for low to NRP to be mapped
to multi slices
so in actors in ISO and we think it
makes little sense is the resource is
already finally divided as
previously described so here for the
example the level 2 NRP to slice is
shown as one-to-one
if the multi multiple to multiple
scenario that to exist we think that the
solution also it can meet the
requirements
next please
this is one example for the whole
solution
from the bottom up to the physical
network is divided into two inner pieces
through the flex elbow and the hnrp is
mapped to two one slice one is for
education and the other is for the
healthcare and the corresponding black
alcohol ID is
128 and 129
uh fold the education slides there are
two customers
University one University two they have
different exercise points and
interactions
for Health Care slices literally there
is only one customers so for the second
level
slice there is only one slice
yourself
so next please
um based on the topology
previous the resource partition is like
this
slide shows for pe1 the physical
interface one there will be two sub
interfaces
and the under which there will be two or
one kill respectively
this is for the second the level slice
for physical interface two there will be
only one sub interface and one queue
under the sub interfaces
from this picture all the sub interfaces
and the kills are associated with the
dedicated bandwidth which can guarantee
the slice resource
uh okay masterpiece
and this is the last picture which
illustrates the traffic forwarding uh
the final result is that for the normal
education traffic
it's it is
encapsulated
with the understated and also associated
with the specific flux alcohol and it's
to forward data through the layer series
of interfaces and photos specific
traffic from University one and the
university to
accept the activistics either
SRH
the encapsulation also includes the
additional NRP ID
and with the traffic is folded through
the queue under the sub interfaces
and okay that's all
next is
okay just just a moment before we go on
I just I was looking at the room and I
saw a couple of people who don't have
masks on masks on over your nose and
mouth please unless you're eating thank
you
you may continue
okay okay since it has been presented in
this and there is no objection we still
just so we also look forward to your
commands from Spring and also want to
know if we can move forward for this
draft
thank you
okay Ted Hardy
Cisco thank you very much for this very
interesting draft I I have three fairly
quick questions
uh the first in in terms of
[Music]
just to confirm my understanding this is
an informational draft that requires no
protocol changes as far as I could see
so I'm I'm not sure what work you're
asking spring to to take up a
clarification of that would be useful
uh second looking through the draft it
looked like the hierarchical nature of
it would normally allow you to have one
level of the hierarchy managed by Sr and
another level of the hierarchy managed
by something else in your University
example you might have the overall set
of universities
um those resources in a slice that was
being managed by Sr and some but not all
of the slices for specific universities
being in either Sr or mpls or something
else and I wanted to confirm whether you
thought that that was possible in in the
approach you're taking or whether the
linkage to the underlying nrps made that
impractical
and the last question was uh this is
obviously very early work a zero zero I
didn't see any uh IPR disclosures for it
but I wondered if the authors knew of
any that were in preparation
uh thank you again for the interesting
draft
hi okay thank you for your comments I
will try to answer your question if I
cannot answer it clearly
um welcome to move it to the main list
uh first of all
about the solution I think it's an
informational solution yes you are right
and there is no other extensions on
practicals
session again I think your mic is on and
we're getting some weird Effects by that
the end could you go on
okay uh it's okay now
yeah the problem is fixed thank you
okay okay okay uh sorry uh so I'll
continue all
um because there is no other extension
on this uh solution so we just propose
this to uh check whether the solution if
there is any conflictions with the
spring
spring opinions uh so we think it's
informational document
the second one about the true level
hierarchical slides I think the first
level we use the flex algo is for the
control plan and because of the
limitation of the control plan
um it's very difficult to realize the
multiple
um slice so we proposed that the second
level slice which is
from the forwarding data plate data plan
so the second level I think they are
also based on the srv6 segment routine
because we combined it with the SR
policy of the services package folding
an rpid such as
so I think the total solution is related
with the s36
oh the second one I'm so sorry I can't
repeat it
again it was just a quick question of
whether you knew of any IPR uh
disclosures in process
oh no no I am not aware of any NPR
disclosure
again for both your answers on the
interesting draft
okay
yes can you hear me
yes we can hear you
um yeah I just had a question
is there um in your examples you had two
layers of hierarchy is it possible to
have
more than two layers hierarchy
um
as well
um I guess with with the uh
the semantics of the draft is there is
there anything special that's being done
other than what's uh defined and um you
know that's part of segment where I
think the standard
um is there are there any um
a special
um
Diana
requirements related
thank you thank you thank you very much
it's a good question we also have
thought about it later from now on
um the full Channel mobile it's a real
natural it it's just the true level
slice for example I think a different
business units with the operator
government Affairs departments or
Enterprises of Affairs Department
under this there will be different users
and another example for the operator we
think for China mobile there are several
sub operators several sub operators
located at different provinces they also
want to manage their own provinces with
business independently so I think this
financial is very special
for China mobile operator
we also
need the true level hierarchical slices
thank you thank you okay we need to keep
moving we're starting to fall behind
schedule folks
so next is a SRA sm2 for Sr policy again
speaking if you could try to pick closer
to the mic I am we're not hearing you
very well every every time thank you
okay
um give me one second I'm just going to
try to make an adjustment to my Nick
and just if you could let me know if it
sounds any better
does that sound better
no but that's okay thank you
it doesn't it doesn't sound any better
okay all right let me just I'll just try
to speak a little bit closer to the mic
thank you
hi my name is Leon Mishra I'm with
Verizon and I'm presenting the draft of
SRP MTU for Sr policy on behalf of
co-authors
next slide
so a recap some ministry as to how this
draft came to spring so during the
adoption of draft uh PCP set pmtu a need
for a document and spring was requested
and confirmed that both the pce and
spring working groups so an IDR document
was adopted in April 2020 a discussion
was brought up by Caitlin that the
concept of path MTU assess our policy
and its applicability applicability
should be first defined in the spring
working year before we introduce
signaling aspects in bgp as a result of
the PC PMG extension adoption called the
draft piece of pmtu was maintained only
protocol specific extensions of details
while the SR policy path M2 definition
framework was to be developed in the
spring working group as a standards
track document to ensure vendor
interoperability related to srpmtu
Concepts and computation details
this topic came up is a critical issue
to be addressed during the IDR working
group 2020 to GPS our policy to MTU
adoption call and now again during PC
workload 2022 pm2 adoption call as
mentioned above and due to the
criticality of solving this issue
related to handling fragmentation and
fragmentation avoidance procedures using
SRP MTU next slide
updates from revision zero to revision
one so mostly cleanup there was an
update as well on the Securities
consideration section so the addition of
the SRP MCU constraint information can
be sensitive in some defined and can be
used to influence the SR path setup and
selection results in it and which
results in an adverse effect
the protocol extension that includes the
SRP MTU must be take must take this into
consideration this document does not
define any new protocol extension and
test does not introduce any further
security considerations and then as well
another update was the section section
three the SRP empty enforcement
reference to separate extension to
handle pm2 draft result was also
obtained
next slide
so next steps we would like to get some
feedback on some critical aspects of
this graph from the working group
experts
um one one of the questions that we have
as far from from us authors is sfpm2 TI
LFA computation and fragmentation
caveats so if anyone can think of after
reading through the draft of any caveats
related to tilfa
um
a computation at the plr node to the uh
to the merge point in any any um any uh
any of that bypass Loop and any
fragmentation crappy outside related
there
um another question that we have and we
want to get feedback from them from the
working group as well as srpmq srv60
encapsulation and any fragmentation
caveats there when that happened and
then the last question is The srpmt
Binding Sid path computation caveat so
on the source node where the uh
as our policy candidate Panthers
bouncing forwarding plate then The
Binding sit is popped and then the
labels are pushed onto the label stack
or in the srv6 case the SRH header and
the srv6 package is pushed onto the
label stack
um are there any computation caveats
that were missing we just want to make
sure that we we recover all our bases in
the draft and any any questions or
comments we really appreciate any
feedback on the graph next slide
and so this traffic is fairly
straightforward
um what would like to take any comments
to the mailing list uh but we would like
to ask for work group adoption on this
job thank you
any any comment on questions
is
don't know what's happening
yes thank you very much again
okay thank you
so we are now moving to 7600ps
interworking uh from Square
hello everyone I am swadesh Agarwal from
Cisco Systems uh this document describes
the srv6 and mpls interworking
procedures
and I present this on the behalf of all
my co-authors next slide please
yeah this is slides shows the simple
view of the interworking scenarios in
the green we are showing the srv6 domain
in the orange we are showing mpls domain
and the tasked overall is for the
interworking functions has to be
executed
the document
divides the problem into two set of
things one is a transport interworking
and the service interworking in the
transport interworking what happens is
and from the end to end from the service
point of view it's running either srv6
vpns or the mpls vpns and since
end-to-end is an srv6 VPN we need to
provide a transport reachability to
locators and that's what we call srv6
over mpls we we do interworking
functions for the locators on these Dash
oval boxes and for the when we have a
mpls vpn's edge service is running end
to end we need to provide a interworking
procedures on those test boxes ovals on
whenever the data plate changes and that
happens for mpls or an srv6 domain and
the and the last case we cover is
service intervoking in this case we have
to provide connectivity between srv6 VPN
and mpls VPN and you need to do a
intervoking function on some data
working box next slide please
so for interworking functions the
document describes new behaviors one is
the n dot DTM what this Behavior does is
it's decapsulates an slv6 pack-in and
look up the UN it's carrying an
underlying label below it and it lookups
the label in the mpls table and we will
see how this is used in as you go in the
procedures and you can see the sudo code
in the draft next slide please
and the DPM behavior is it's a
decapsulation and push the label
associated with the Sid and again it is
used here we can see how it will be used
in our slides as we go through this and
the pseudo code could be referred again
can be checked in the draft next slide
please
so these are the and hidden behaviors we
have defined so what happens is when the
H dot encaps is applied to an mpls label
stack that's what we call H Dot and caps
dot m and there is both the regular
Behavior and the reduced behavior for it
next slide please
so Sr policy is bound to an binding set
so in the procedures if the SRM pillars
label can be bound to an srv6 policy as
well as sr66 can be bound to an Sr mpls
policy so we call these in the draft as
interconnecting binding set and we'll
we'll see this concept is used to
provide those interworking functions
in the next slide next next slide please
as already mentioned when the services
are of the same type end to end and we
need to provide a reachability either to
her if it's srv6 VP into a locator or if
it is a mpls VPN services to a p
loopback so what it is draft does is it
extends the two well-known transport
procedures to provide this interworking
to create this interworking control
plane one is a srpc base which can
provide both the best effort as well as
the intend away another one is the bgp
interdomain routing which is right now
described for best effort but we will
Define it for the intent aware based on
bgp also in the future versions next
slide please
so just to go over the procedures the
Legends used are the green boxes are
sizes capable and it shows how the
locators have been referred in that and
the orange boxes are mpls capable boxes
and then the orange and green bar the
are capable of both mpls and srv6 next
slide please
so we see these are srpc based
procedures so let's say between 1 and 10
we are running the srv6 VPN Services
it's been advertised by the 10 learned
by the one a VPN service and what the
endpoint or locator we want to reach is
of a node 10 B10 is a locator we want to
reach it's a multi-domain network one
doesn't know how to reach one request an
srpc for the a certain objective or a
constraint for a path to 10 srpcs look
at the constraint it figures out the
let's say node 2 Note 5 and node 8 are
in the path to provide that objective or
a constraint but since srpc is having
the bgp ls feed from each other domain
srpc sees there's an inconsistent data
plane happening on node four and seven
so what it does is whatever
interconnecting sets we use the the
procedures we Define of interconnecting
sets it use that behavior what it does
is on the Note 4 since we have to take
the policy 200 fabulous domain it
creates an mpls policy but the The
Binding said it's bound to is an srb6
Beast SRB behavior of the BM type and
that's and that uh srb6 BC is being once
srpc creates that policy on the four and
it and that's the one which is
programmed at the one with one of the
segments which takes to the node 4 and
which will get uh expanded on node 4 to
the policy MPS policy and that's where
the packet would Transit
transition through the mpls domain so if
you see on the Note 4 what packet
received is is received with the
destination with the BM Behavior we will
apply the BM behavior on it and then the
packet would be put into an amplus
labels stack which will take us to the
again the objective was to reach node 4
node 5 from 4 and that's what the prefix
it we have put in the packet and then
the last segment we have put is a note 7
where on the Note 7 and it would be a
regular sr6 domain and it will go to the
next segment which is node 8 and of
course the VPN segment which will take
to the note 10. so that's the way
interconnecting by index it is used to
provide that
6 over M reachability through srpc next
slide please
so it is similar Behavior it's a similar
operations that I have already explained
for 6 over M the only difference is here
the edge services are mpls VPN services
so we need to create this srpc request
is for the P loop back it's it's called
for a certain C comma e which is an mpls
in the mpls case here on the Note 4 what
we are doing is we are putting an srb6
policy because middle domain is an srb6
domain that policy but it is bound to an
mpls B said and that mpls BC that is
programmed for the policy on node 4 is
programmed as one of the segments on the
Node one so now what happens is when the
packet leaves one it is going through
the segments in the left domain on the
Note 4 it is expanded to a srv6 policy
with the the next header being 137
because getting an MPS payload below it
and then the packet will be reaching the
Note 7 and the regular mpls operations
will happen from there onwards next
slide please
so these are we have covered the srbc PC
based procedures where PC was aware of
this interworking procedures and was
creating those using the enter
connecting sets to create those uh pass
through to the different type of data
plane but similarly bgp interdomain
procedures can be used so in this again
it's over it's a scenario of 6 over M
where the services are Sr V6 VPN
services so now what we need to do is
when 10 advertise the service to node
one then we'll also advertise the
locator through a locator to node 7 from
Note 7 to Note 4 to node one when it's
advertised between 7 to 4 what you need
to do is it's a it's a regular IPv6
prefix over an elude mpls transport so
we can use the 6p procedures between
four and between seven and four and
that's that's the way traffic will flow
from one to ten next slide please
so this is the case of uh mplus being in
the edge and that means it's an mpls VPN
services so we need to provide a
reachability to node 10 that has to be
learned by the node one which is
learning the services uh from the 10. to
provide that reachability today we know
bgp3107 procedures seamless mpls is used
where what will happen is on on the 7 we
will allocate a regular vtp Lu label but
along with that we will advertise an
srv6 set of the behavior DTM which was
defined earlier right and that would be
learned by the Note 4 and Note 4 will
advertise this bgplu further to node one
so for node one it's a regular mpls VPN
put into bgplu LSP but on the Note 4
yeah we will do swap operation for bgplu
LSP but along with that we will tunnel
the traffic to node 7 with the DTM
Behavior but it will cause is we are
carrying a bgplu label below uh below
that srv68 so on the the Note 7 we will
decapsulate the packet to the lookup of
the bgplu label and send to node 10. so
that's the way we'll provide end-to-end
reachability over the SR V6 domain next
slide please
so these are the cases of Transport
interworking where we were trying to
provide a reachability towards the
service endpoint but in this case what
we want to in this this is a service
interworking where we want to provide a
connectivity between mpls VPN and srv6
VPN running on the Node 1 and node 7. so
what happens in this case is there are
these are
these are working on the existing
Gateway procedures what happens is on
node 4 we have a service awareness
because we want to terminate both the
services as the as well as the underlay
so since we want to terminate both the
what we can do is we can have a service
Awareness on node four so whatever is
destinations VPN destinations are
learned from the sr6 domain they are put
into the work on the service on the
service box Note 4 and then reordered it
towards the mpls side so there is MPS
VPN and s56 VPN and on the service box
there is a verb IP forwarding which is
uh when you receive a traffic from one
side you Decap you look at you do an
iplooker and then you get the
encapsulation for the other side and
that's the way as we provide the
interworking solution for this scenario
next slide please
so this is the last case where instead
of having a service Awareness on the
Note 4 what we can do is on the
interworking box we can do a translation
that means a VPN label could be
translated to an uh
vpn's srv6 service set or the SR physics
service set can be translated to a VPN
label using a procedure similar to
interest option b
uh doing the next 12 cell phone dot box
next slide please
yeah somebody is the staff was presented
uh first published in 2018 and it has
the data plane and the associated
control plane procedures it defines a
new Behavior DTM and DPM as well as use
the introduce the concept of
interconnecting binding sits and it uses
how to pass through a data plane which
is not consistent
it relies both on the srpc and bgp based
Solutions next slide please
next slide please yeah so one thing we
have done is from the last ITF we have
moved the bgp protocol extensions that
we have to a separate draft so it can be
reviewed in the best working group and
this is done for both it for the
independent review as well as future
application applicability for the other
use cases as well as we have expanded on
the uh interest option b like procedures
for the service interworking
next slide please
yeah uh we would like uh the working
group to review as well as adopt this
draft also one thing more uh there's
another transport interworking draft pin
there in the spring we are working with
the co-authors of those of that draft
because there's a similar one similar
Behavior being defined to see how to
move forward on that
thanks
okay truth
oh
Jeff you got to put yourself on the list
uh hi a Swedish very good presentation
thank you one quick question about the
PC part uh currently in the document you
are focusing only on a single PC case in
peace up working group we have one more
document called stateful interdomain
where how the PCS can cooperate with
each other to set up this kind of path
so just have a look at it I hope that
the solution can work for inter-domain
cases like where multi multiple PC
managing multiple domain cases as well
sure I I've been looking at that and
probably we can get back on thank you
what we can do
just Japanese or Microsoft so the drop
notably means a separational part how do
you deploy the stuff how do you operate
it end to end and I mean amount of Buffs
when you're going to deploy this it's
just scary right so it would be really
good to see sections that identifies how
do I trace when it Traverse different
calculation different domains when I
replace
seats by labels and so forth right it's
completely missing in the draft so if
you're saying the operational aspects
absolutely uh sure we can we can look
into it thank you update thanks
uh you should put yourself on using the
tool but just state your name at the
microphone please
um to the point which Jeff was making I
think there should be a separate
operational draft yeah we can look into
it that's one thing let's
looking at that part covered okay sure
hey
um
so you said that there is another
drafting base for the uh pure bgp
procedures for the for the signaling
aspect to because we are extending to
carry these new behaviors in the bgp in
the bgp transport layer like pgplu or in
bgp IPv6 so we have put a earlier that
was in this draft but uh to have a
future applicability as well as to a
category Group by the best we have put
in the those signaling aspects we have
put in sector draft and the architecture
and the procedures are still keptical in
this draft but also for the option b uh
section because at the moment it's only
covering the uh ldu part right no no
option b is for the services right we
can do next stop self on the
interworking box where our srv6 service
it can be mapped to a VPN label and the
outgoing LSP and same on the reverse
direction right so it's using a DPM
Behavior to achieve it
right so it's a next stop sell for the
services not for the transport so you're
saying there is there's no need for
extended procedures in the best draft
for the option b uh we can look into it
but it's just because option b is
already defined in certain aspects this
is more of using those procedures to
create this but the behavior is a new
Behavior DPM that's the reason we have
put it out so that everybody knows we
have to use a DPM Behavior we have to
push our labels that stack of labels
when I receive a subjected that's the
reason we have put it out otherwise from
control plane I still feel existing
procedures should work it's just some
data plane and update to that we can
discuss thank you
thanks a lot
thank you
next is a Sr policy group from lion
well okay okay thank you
hi and this is Leah again uh I'm talking
about the other topic as our policy
group next up please
foreign
flows of the simulator have different
requirements on the folding quality of
the network
so different traffic is expected to be
forwarded through different passes and
use different network resources
taking the left picture as an example
there are two completely isolated VPN
tenants within one and vaping 2 they are
both multipoint to multi-pond excise and
the whipping one has three different
types of sources within two has two
different types of sources each sources
has different quality requirements first
from the picture you can see that all
the traffic belongs to the same VPN
is expected to be managed in a unified
manner so here
we still the the traffic into one is a
policy group
so the traffic
belongs to the SR policy group who have
different sources and the different
destination addresses
and the next different type of sources
the traffic under the VPN can be steered
into different policies
which is based on the parent policy the
traffic
has a specific source and destination
address
next please
foreign
this is the terminology which is defined
here first the SR policy and the parent
is a policy are defined in RFC
9256 already and the New Concept of the
as a policy group is newly proposed here
and
generally speaking it is an
instantiation of a cyto apparent as a
policies this as a policies have
different destination and points and
the same service for the module and it
represents a set of passes with
different folding requirements and
computed by different parents as a
policies
which have the same color but different
destination and points
also the mapping relationship between
the flow characteristics and the color
value of the as a policy path should be
established in the policy group and it
can get the flows with different SLA
requirements to the as a policy with
different colors
next please
this is the identification of the ISR
policy group who an Israel policy group
must be identified through a colored
tribute
this color is an unsigned non-dural
32-bit integer value and it corresponds
to the color of the building of the bgp
root published by the endpoint
uh and this is third one second
different stories qualities use
different color values
the next sentence is also uh talking
about the mapping relationship between
the flow characteristics and the color
value
the same with the previous three slides
so next please
the relationship of the policy group
parent policy and the as our policy is
shown as the pictures
first
in simple terms and as a policy group
contains one or more parents as our
policies which have different
destinations on the point
and the color of the policy group should
be seen with the parent as a policy but
different with the SR policy
thank you
next please
this slides detailed the process of the
traffic steering using the SR policy
group for for the egg rice nodes which
published The btp Root it will
associate the b2p route with the color
extended Community attribute and the
photo increase node first
it will match an Sr policy group
using the color extended Community
attribute in the BP route and the next
it will match apparent as a policy under
the previous policy group
using the next hope in BCP root and then
it will match as a policy using the flow
characteristics
through the three steps finally the flow
is still into one specific as a policy
next please
this is an informational module of the
Apple Logic
from this picture you can see that there
is
one ISR policy group for pt1
which is with the color one and it
contains the two parents as a policy
uh pp1 and pp2 and they have the same
color one with the policy group pt1 but
different endpoint
U1 and E2 and each parent as a policy
contains three threes
corresponding to three different
policies which is with the color 100 to
this picture shows the basic logical of
the relationship
uh okay
uh next place
uh that's all and this is the the real
version of the draft so welcome any
question or comments
thank you very much
if you could go back to the slide uh
uh Bruno
uh yeah so one question uh Sr policy
Group which is a new uh new thing that
has been introduced here
does this belong on the head end or is
this something that's on the controller
uh
assuming that
the SR policy group who
that's how any height on the point
so it's at the head end okay so I am not
able to see uh what is the benefit that
this group uh brings uh it would be good
if the draft could be updated to clarify
what cannot be done or achieved with
what we have today uh before uh and so
therefore we know why we need this new
construct
yeah so the child
also the cause of this draft I would
like you to answer the question so
firstly I think the here the uh policy
group will not introduce any new uh
Hider or new change to the data plan and
the the second one
we use that based on maybe a controller
or some
other network management system
so that that is logically
uh module to organize
the
hierarchical services so we just talked
talked about the hierarchical network
slides so when we use the uh a services
policy to implement the
hierarchical uh slicing uh Zuca
solution can be uh used at that
application scenario
foreign
ER so maybe uh some clarity more uh more
clarity in the draft
um yeah I think the important value is
that it's a high up to organize just
different uh
uh policies uh for such as the same user
or the same kind of service
so if you can use those uh concept
then you can very easy to set up the
hierarchical uh
Services based on a services policy
a very very last bit uh
for taking the time but we have all
kinds of template and hierarchies in you
know of all the vendors uh config models
right uh the question is here why
standardize it uh you know you can do
whatever you want in your controller or
ahead and implementation
uh if we are standardizing it should
bring some functional value and that's
not clear to me uh thank you I'll end
here now
okay Boris
describe
a very short question because I missed
we have two colors here one color Fair
Sr policy group and second color for Sr
policy inside this group so how these
two colors resolution will be done it's
not quite clear
uh I think I added the same Library we
just use a one color so such as at the
isopers group we just use uh the same uh
color uh for uh one parent uh
policy
but
within the ASAP parent as a policy the
different Services may have a different
color so that it's similar to the
hierarchical cues
thank you
thanks
okay we'll move on to the next
presentation
hello
can you hear me
yes we can hear you go ahead
oh okay thanks
good morning everyone this is William
from China mobile I will present the
draft networking Network resource
programming with srv6
next slides please
uh they uh the consent of network
resource petition is introduced in
draft ITF test iitf Network slices
as this script in section
6.1 of that chart
NRP is a collection of resource in the
underlying Network
NLP consent consents of a subset of the
buffer queuing scheduling resources on
each of the connected set of links in
the underlay Network
and RFC
8986 has defined a set of well-known
srv6 and point behaviors
but those behaviors are not associated
with the set of NRP of the links for
slices
or slice aggregate
so this document defines a new slv6 and
point Behavior which can be used to
associate with a set of NRP
for example the dedicated skills
resources or layer 2 logical sub
interfaces uh we record and Dot NRP
next slide please
the uses of the end
of the seed
uh this end touch and now PC is mainly
used to steer traffic forwarding through
the associated NRP
by using the end.chana PC to build a
segment list the srv6 policy have the
capability to program network resources
and restricted
strict test SLA guarantees
for one HP link multiple and Dot Channel
BC should be allocated Each of which is
associated with a subset of Link
resources
in such as dedicated queues layer 2
logical sub interfaces and so on
let's see an example as shown in the
picture one at
the for the P1 node the link resource
from P1 to P1 has two and nrps one is
gg100.q1 and another is g100.q2
which are two dedicated cues on P1
physical interface g100
also uh two and Dot NRP seat
s are allocated to those two nrps
this means that for P1 note the
end.netic a column one colon colon 11 is
associated with an RP
g100.q1 and indicates to forward traffic
to neighbor P1 where this NRP and the
enter Channel visit a column one column
column 22 is associated
associated with NRP
g100.q2 and indicates to forward traffic
to enable P1 where this NRP
V6 policy uses the end.net PC to
construct its path
such an srv6 policy can provide strict
SLA guarantees to customers
next slide please
this is the price processing of and
started nappy Behavior
the end thought behavior is a variable
variant of Android X Behavior defined in
IFC 8986
any state instance of earned.nrp
behavior is associated with two sets
J1 and J2 G1 is one or more Elson
adjacencies G2 is NRP of J1
when
and receives a packet that's that's
changed to S and the S is a local and
dotted nappy seed the line is 15 of the
enter text processing
defined in FC 8986 is replaced by the
following
by the following
submits the package to the IPv6 module
for transmission to the new destination
where a member of J1
using the NLP identified by J2
okay next slide please
this is a use case of the end of the
nappy behavior in the srv6 list line
celero
uh in this use case there are two
customers with different list line
requirements from P1 to P2
one is a list line with 1G benchwise
with strict as our guarantee and the
other is this this line with two G
bandwidth restrict as our guarantee
so the controller will build two SRV 6
policies to meet the least line needs of
those two customers
first it calculates srv6 policy paths
based on SLA
assuming that both paths are calculated
as X1 X2 X3
secondly the controller cooperates with
the network nodes to complete NRP
reservation and the end.net PC
allocation along the SRV 6 policy paths
um also now take note P1 as an example
the two different tender piece such as
two dedicated cues are partitioned from
the network resources of the physical
link X1
and corresponding and Dot nappy seat is
also assigned to each of those
two and a piece
the results as shown in the table one
uh the seat a column one column column
11 is associated to an RPG one zero zero
Dot q1 and the seat the column column a
column one color 22 is associated with
lrpg one
zero zero dot Q2
next slide please please
similarly the NRP reservation at the end
odd and IPC allocation are completed on
X1 X2 and X3 links
uh finally the controller uses the
corresponding and Totten rpsc's on link
X1 X2 and X3 to build the seed list of
srv6 policy paths
as shown in the picture too the pass for
SRV 6 policy 1 is
a colon 1 colon colon 11.
and and a column two column color 11 and
a column three column color 11. which
satisfies the requirements of the
customer one
and the path of
srv6 policy 2 satisfies the requirements
of car customers to customers too
oh okay next slide
next slide please okay
in this use case the traffic from
customer one will be forwarded to P2
while the NRP previously resolved for
the per hoplink on the srv6 policy one
pass
and the the pie providing customer one
with and and head to end
1gbenchwise resource for list line
services with strict SLA guarantee
next slide
please
okay that's all for my presentation any
question or comments
thank you any any question of comment
from the room
just
obviously I was wondering how do you how
are you napping the uh it seems like
there's a mapping between the uh NRP I
guess when the when the controller is
provisioning the uh flow I guess to qos
because you mentioned queuing so I was
just
mapping that's happening as well as if
you have if you have that let's say on
the box you probably have your standard
queuing set up but now there's a another
layer of queuing that's set up with the
uh with this programming and I just how
that works because Ian are working today
thank you
okay that um I I try to answer your
question so uh
[Music]
uh I would like to answer the question I
I think it as you just mentioned the NRP
maybe uh
existing uh in the controller uh for the
provisioning uh as well as
how to attach the NRP to the forwarding
leader is a question
and uh it's very hard for controller to
manage the dedicated
resource in the forwarding leader so uh
combine the NRP in controller uh
modeling and the the and the NRP
Behavior
it will uh to set up
some good solution very simple uh you
can use such as a service 6 policy and
as well uh the dedicated
resources in the uh forwarding leader
can be attached
it will help operators to support the
high quality
uh
list the line uh something like that
thank you thank you maybe it sounds like
would it be like a layer of uh like a
hierarchical qos almost I guess like you
have a layer of key OS per per NRP
similar to like hierarchical qos thank
you
thank you yeah
thank you
next present next on last presentation
is a segment concouring procedures for
Magical VPN service in Native IPv6
Network
okay uh hello everyone from China
Telecom and I will introduce our draft
on behalf of the co-authors and next
slide please
uh yes we proposed this draft to define
a new segment we call it endpoint and
VPN to contain the VPN custom
informations and this segment can be
used to distinguish traffic from
different customers and
it can
unleash this segment of the
VPN multi-group multicast Group address
allocation can align with the unicast
ipvpn address allocation and this the
the implementation of the solution is
similar to realtor and VPN and it can
also come compatible always a beer and
other Technologies and next slide please
uh yes uh one uh a customer wants to
join the multicast group uh the ecosp uh
is connected to uh will generate an
endpoint and VPN according to the VPN
custom information and send the segment
to Ingress PE and increase P it will
maintain a mapping table of endpoint and
VPN and the European custom informations
and the generated endpoint and VPN will
be inserted into the table
and when uh CE sends a multicast packet
to Ingress P the Ingress P will
encapsulate the package with a header
according to the endpoint NYPD mapping
table and the destination address will
be set to the endpoint I'm VPN but then
the packet will be sent to the the
responding request piece and the
behavior on P routers depends on the
generation method of the multicast tree
and finally the egress P will
decapsulate the package and transmit it
to the corresponding C is a Nestle at
least
[Music]
oh yes this is the encoding of uh
endpoint mopn and it will come first to
the IP wave 6 multicast address and the
way defined uh an away bit uh
over it defines a highest speed in ff1
as the way bit which means the VPN
multicast bit and when the speed is set
it means the multicast group address is
uh and a VPN segment
otherwise it is a common multicast
address and the network network prefix
field will carry the customer's Rd value
when the web it is Set uh addressed the
information carried in this field should
be determined by the other base in ff1
and the group ID
carries the information of customer
group Nestle please
[Music]
oh yes this is the generous generation
procedure of uh endpoint type mypn when
an Ingress P generates the uh endpoint
and VPN segment it will firstly extract
Rd and multicast Group address of the
customer and set the value of vb21 and
set the value of a net Network prefix to
the customer's Rd and
attend the Ingress P will set the value
of group ID field according to the
customers
multicast Group address if the address
is iPhone 6
ipv4 the the value of group ID will be
set to the ipu for a multicast group
address and if the
customers multi-group address is an ipoa
6 address
the egress P will check the P bit in the
address and if the p is equal to one
the group ID will be set to the group ID
in the customers
multi-group address and otherwise the
value of group ID will be set to and
32-bit value that is hashed from the
customers multicast Group address a NASA
please
oh yes this is a
the behavior on the increase P when it
received uh an happy way 6 package waste
the destination address D and the D is
associated with an uh endpoint of mvpn
segment on the egress PE
so the englishp will check the way bit
in endpoint and VPN if we beat is equal
to one it will look at the endpoint MP
mopn mapping table according to
the and and point and VPN value and find
out the associated Rd and the related
unfield table T then it will remove the
outer ipa6 header with all its extension
headers and set the packets Associated
and flip table 2T finally it will submit
the package to the egress MVP lookup for
transmission to the new multicast
Downstream and if the wave a bit is
equal to zero the Ingress P will set the
is associated I've made table to Global
fmib and submit the package to the
egress MF me lookup for transmission to
the new multicast Downstream and next
slide please
oh yes and since since this is the first
time for us to uh give the presentation
of this draft Subway
uh we hope we can
uh get some comments and or suggestions
about it and we will reverse this draft
accordingly thank you
thank you one question did you ask a
scrot that the best baseball team up did
you ask for slot at the best working
group to present it uh
uh at this time we don't apply the third
time maybe it would be good to ask for
to present for next meeting because it's
heavy on VPN on multiplication
uh yes uh maybe we will uh presentation
it in next uh ITF meeting thank you
hi uh I'm Sasha Weinstein from riba uh
I had looked at the draft before the
president sure before the presentation
and send an email to the authors and the
work group
it seems that the solution proposed in
the draft only can work with Ingress
replication as the provider tunneling
technology for mvpn because they
provide the structure of the end dot
nvpn Sid includes the route
distinguisher of the multicast where if
in the airspe
rail distinguishers
uh in menu if not most cases are
specific to each address P for instance
if you use type 1 route distinguishers
they would include the uh
something like the router idea of the
recipe is part of it and therefore in
order to work this proposal would
require the Ingress fee to send a
dedicated packet uh to each address fee
where the specific mvpn service is
instantiated
uh
at the very least I think that this
should be expressed if my understanding
is correct I think that at the very
least this should be explicitly
specified in the draft
if I have missed something I would
really appreciate explanations
yeah I I I think your uh
actually for for a podcast
scenario the Rd
of an artist value for all of the Eagles
okay
then the you know our job just uh
described
for for matter of the engineer VPN for
the multicast services and my customers
the marketplace audition must be the
same for the market Services okay
the text is definitely not what the uh
normal uh mvpn Behavior suggests and
uh in any case if you started from the
unicast uh
a VPN service that you wish to upgrade
to
multicast VPN you don't change the route
around around distinguishers but in any
case if this is the Assumption of the
draft it should be stated explicitly uh
because uh I maybe I have missed it but
I have not seen anything like that in
the text
normally in layer 3 in uh and that
that's why I think that if you present
is drafted at the best worker it
definitely should be presented because
it includes the bgp parts uh this the
same question would be raised
the Rd can be set differently or in your
uniquely so I think we saw the Express
in our draft or in our next practitioner
expressed as the Rd value of so to be
same for the all the equality
if you can have a short question please
I sure I did just a quick question does
this uh draft does it follow like uh the
mvpn procedures RFC 6513 and 6514 uh
using like Leaf ad to discover the
endpoints like the auto Discovery piece
or this is completely separate from any
uh nvpn procedures also I I do agree
that this seems like it's more in line
with like Ingress replication and uh not
uh and not any other ptas thank you
you can comment briefly
hey John uh I think the kind of solution
for the foreign
[Music]
foreign
so thank you folks for all the
presentations and for all the discussion
which is more important than the
presentation in many regards so thank
you very much for your time we'll see
you on the mailing list