thank you
Taro will you do it may you take notes
no come on man no okay
I'm trying to open the ether ad and it's
giving me this proxy server encrypt
failure
so Dave are you gonna do it remotely
I'm trying to but um I can't access it
for some reason
yes it would be nice can somebody please
watch it to take anything that Dave
misses
I I can't access it so I won't be able
to take notes you can't access it all
right
got it
um
please
I mean honestly everyone I mean we're
active in this working group we can't
have this meeting without minute taking
please I mean there'll be multiple folks
in The Ether chat it's about key
decisions and Milestones
thank you thank you
for the recording thank you Michael
Richardson
I should have done that
okay
um
remind you of the note well
please uh if you're going to contribute
know your rights Privileges and
responsibilities
and please uh treat each other with
respect
and uh
we'll we'll make better technical
decisions that way
we just did the administrative tasks
and here is the first part of the agenda
um
and the second part of the agenda are
there any agenda bashes
um day favor um I have to present in the
room next door for 10 minutes about 45
minutes in and since our usual rule of
thumb you don't see times up here and
that's because the things that are the
most well Advanced documents we let them
run until we actually get them done
because we want to ship them or whatever
so that's why you don't see times on
here so that means we reserve the right
to do Dynamic swapping towards the end
so that the things that uh teep does not
directly reference
are the ones that might be done during
the 10 to 15 minutes here so for example
I have to be in the room for the
firmware updates because Russ is an
author
um whereas things like uh mud and MTI to
might actually move up depending on
where we are after 45 minutes or so so
that we'll do that uh real time
any other agenda bashes
okay
we're gonna start with suit Manifesto
we did not get any slides for hackathon
does anyone want to share
um the results
yeah I think for an interested time uh
any of the hackathon stuff can be done
in tip and any of the uh actual outcomes
I've already think been rolled into
these slides on the various documents
and stuff so we did have several people
working on suit there but there's a
hackathon report in teap which a cure is
going to cover in teeth which kind of
covers the relationship between deep and
suit and so on so we'll cover any of
that stuff and so we can just focus on
the time here for the getting our docs
done all right awesome
great
Dash 20. yeah that's 20. I did not
expect it to hit 20. uh right so
um there have been sorry
eat the mic or eat the mic oh I don't
need all right
okay now you should be able to hear me
um right so they're mostly editorial
changes in this version there's not a
lot of technical uh churn uh primarily
these are uh coming from feedback from
the the well I I guess it was the list
from feedback from the list
um there were some things on uh naming
Clarity so what we've gone for here is
to rename run to invoke because there
was already a run sequence and the idea
here is that we want to make it clear
what's happening so that was just a
minor editorial naming convention there
the same thing in
um common sequence versus shared
sequence the idea was that common and
command get a little bit too close
together so by separating that out
um it becomes a little bit clearer that
we're saying comments or shared Suite
sequence versus Command sequence you can
see how there might be a little bit of
overlap
um
I've added some uh clarifying text in a
number of places uh and the uh those are
around run sequence when strict order is
false which is more applicable on uh
large systems than small systems so this
is not a microcontroller consideration
in general this is more of an A-Class
system kind of consideration
the entry for suit invoke there it
wasn't clear that it contained could
contain image verification so there's
some text to explain that that's
possible and the try each which is used
for some decision making purposes uh
doesn't didn't have a clear explanation
of what its stop conditions were so the
stop condition explanation has been
added there was a minor technical change
um I even actually asked for a way to
write a small payload directly without
needing to have a separate payload
argument
and the idea behind this is if you've
got something that requires I don't know
32 bytes you don't necessarily want to
have an entire separate hash and
everything to make that work you
probably just want to be able to put
that small payload directly into flash
now that required the addition of two
commands one for a direct write and one
to do a direct content check since there
won't be a digest to compare against
uh next slide please
so we had an Ayanna early review and
obviously we've had a previous
Ayanna early review uh this one is
pretty minimal there was one comment and
that was
uh since we have standards track ranges
do those also require uh expert review
as is the norm in the cozy style hybrid
approach and for that I will take that
to the working group how do you think we
should handle this
so my thought is that if there's a
standard track document it's gotten
plenty of expert review
okay so I uh if that's the consensus of
the working group then we need to put
some text in there to give Ayanna that
guidance
does anyone see it differently
I guess someone does
State explicitly which register you're
talking about
the one this document creations
the ones defined in this story right
yeah customer the problem is that
over the life of this document
the people who will do uh
standard strike
the documents that are based on this
will not be limited to the people who
know what they are doing
and I say that as a designated expert
with several registers
uh so I actually prefer
the expert to be involved okay I mean
the the response of the expert can be
very short
sorry I didn't put myself in the queue
Roman denilio uh as the kind of AD to
share similar field experience with
Diana on other documents they have
previously in collaboratively identified
some issues where it was uh just in the
standards track range and there was no
de and it would have been really helpful
to have remembered and had some of that
knowledge as Carson was saying when the
registry was created Boy you really
should kind of think about this kind of
as a as a gut check and so thinking
about that the registry will endure
after the working group is closed
all right so you good point
okay I guess so that reaction is counter
to my original reaction so that being
the case
um should we adopt the cozy style hybrid
standards plus expert review model
sounds like
and I should comment one of those places
where I was talking with Ayanna and they
pointed out to me was on the Cozy
okay so we'll need to add some text to
the document that explains that
there's a standards plus expert review
model moving forward
well will we have to recommend uh
you know some individuals to um to be
those experts
Roman denili again kind of by process it
would be the isg that would choose those
designated experts but uh I would
certainly welcome recommendations
be great
I think someone just pointed at me uh
seems plausible
okay quick uh this is your last slide
yeah
uh quick reminder please uh if you're
not
currently drinking something from your
soda put a mask on
and this this is the last one I have for
this draft so
um unless there's any more questions or
comments I think we can continue
right so this is uh suit must multiple
trust domains this is primarily
um in support of tip at the moment there
are a couple of other use cases that are
important but they haven't gotten quite
as much exercise as the team specific
ones have
uh next slide please
so just in summary what we've got in
here is three key Parts
um we've got
um or three key needed features rather
um key delegation being the first one
um we want to support explicitly and
then there's the use case for mutually
distrustful signers this is where two
different parties own two different
pieces of the system image and they
don't trust each other to see uh to
authorize their code and we need a way
to deliver those packages while still
expressing software dependencies between
them
next slide please
so summary of features we have we have
cwts for key delegation that part is is
defined currently but I'm not sure how
accurate it is so cwt experts please
have a look if you're a cwt expert
please check that out for me
um in we have the unlink command which
is a specific requirement of teep as
well as the uninstall sequence and then
we have dependencies which are a way of
expressing these multiple signature
scenarios
next slide please
so there's been a number of updates so
we're no longer indexing dependencies
separately from components the Indus
index lists have been merged this is
intended to make uh the whole thing
simpler to handle it does have some
significant implications so
digest of manifests are over the
Manifest content itself not the envelope
but this treats the Manifest Envelope as
a component which means that doing an
image check will digest the wrong thing
so the current implementation or the
current definition in the spec rather
just says that the way that this works
is that there is uh a test done in the
image check command the feedback from
the hackathon was that perhaps it would
be better to implement a separate
command for this I see Ira in the queue
Brandon
you're using a highly directional mic
unsuccessfully and up to this point your
your audio will not work in the
recording is this better
much better thank you for myself yeah
okay you know I mean I can substantially
hear myself more is that better all
right
is this okay is this working okay okay
this is okay challenge accepted
[Laughter]
okay
so uh right as a better solution to the
the approach that we've had so far with
uh with joining the two lists of
components and uh dependencies is to
um
have a separate command for verifying
the
uh the digest of the Manifest and we
also needed a test to determine whether
or not the the currently processing uh
component was a manifest or whether it
was a uh dependency or a a an image and
the the idea behind this is for handling
batch processing so this is where you
have a
um
you're using the true variant of the
index and this is so that you can go
through everything at once giving it the
same commands uh the problem is we used
to have a way to say handle all the
dependencies handle all the components
but now components are depend our
dependencies are components so now we
need a way to split them apart and so
that's what this uh this test is for
then finally there is the process
dependency command and that is of course
the the thing that allows you to say go
and execute the command sequence that
lives in the dependency
um
we don't currently specify or I think I
do specify that it needs to check
whether it's processing a manifest and
fail if it's not
um it's possible that we could just not
do that and have it just fail on a parse
error I'm I'm not sure I like that I
think I'd prefer it checks but I will be
happy to take feedback if anyone has a
specific preference
um the uninstall command sequence
is the mechanism that tip is going to
use from what I understand to say that
it is time to remove all of the things
that were installed by this manifest and
so that has been added in here in
support of team
uh next slide please
I can comment on that one Dave Taylor
um so not only is it usable by teep but
uh the other scenario and this is much
less for constrained devices than it is
for say uh devices that a a human can uh
you know type things into for example
the other scenario is we're a local
administrator wants to uh physically on
the box go on and uninstall something
and so you can do that if you've already
have the stuff that's in there and just
follow the uninstall command sequence so
that's the first scenario would not be
for constrained devices but it's for a
larger thing so there's a deep scenario
was done remotely and there's a local
install scenario the two
um okay so for open issues what we've
got other than what's already been
talked about and the security
consideration section is not
particularly specific to this document
it's the one that was originally in the
suit manifest draft so that definitely
needs to be updated
um so there's a bit of work left to do
there
um the component another issue raised in
the hackathon was the component ID for
the root manifest now this is an
interesting problem because
um in a constrained system this is
irrelevant if you receive a manifest you
know where to put it you have one space
to put it in you put it there
um
in a dependency enabled constrained
device this is still the case there if
you receive an unsolicited manifest
there is one place for it to go however
once you're starting to deal with
devices that have multiple independent
manifest trees that Define individual
applications
probably this is most common when they
involve trusted applications that are
signed by someone else but when we have
that scenario then there needs to be a
defined place to put it
um and that's where the question of a
component ID for the root manifest comes
in because that tells a device that's
receiving it where it goes
um there's a slight challenge with that
which is that if we have that there's
going to be an interaction between it
and the component ID that's specified
for that for a dependency so if you have
a a root manifest but it doesn't matter
what's in it for the current moment but
it defines component IDs for its
components now if one of those
components is a dependency manifest
which contains a component ID there's a
contention between these two uh the the
best idea
for the the thing that I've come to for
the moment which may or may not be the
right answer uh is that anything defined
in a dependency component list should
override whatever's in the Manifest and
that's just not going to happen and
there are other arguments we could make
but I think that's so far I that's the
one I found the least arguments against
uh thank you so this is actually one of
the long discussions we had at the
hackathon and Brennan summarized three
choices which aren't on the slide and so
one is where so this is where I think
they actually
following slot okay then I'll wait then
um right so I believe I put those on a
following slide we'll come back to it um
oh there okay yes so there we are where
should a dependent manifest be stored ah
okay and so there there are in single
image devices as I said this is clear in
single system configuration devices
still clear
um but when you have a system with
multiple independent independent
manifests not clear
um
so if we give dependent manifests a
component ID that solves one of our
problems but the question is do
dependencies also get to declare their
own component ID
um
I think I just ran through these choices
the three the third one was actually a
hybrid of two of the others so I left it
out
um so the dependent component list would
this is the what I'm saying I think is
probably the right answer the dependence
component list overrides any declared
component IDs and the other option of
course is that the uh designated element
of the dependence component list is
concatenated with any dependency
self-declared component ID I'm a little
bit worried about some of the security
considerations around that one whereas
the other seems clear to me
um yeah so to this day favor uh so to
make it clear the uh thing that is the
in the override case right the outer one
gets to override where the inner one
goes correct and so the scenario is you
can have one inner one and it couldn't
talk about some of the things that Fran
and I talked about at hackathon
um the uh the same dependency could
actually need to be installed in
multiple places on the same overall
device okay and so for example if a
device has say multiple tees in it right
then it would be exactly the same suit
digest exactly the same dependency or
whatever but you may need to install it
separately in two different tees and so
where would you say that you'd say that
in the outer one with different
component IDs with one prefix going to
one te one prefix going to their tee
right so that's an example where the
person that authors the Manifest of the
of the component that's the dependency
doesn't know where it's going to be
installed these creates a default list
right but then you have to be able to
override that to say it go is open this
one it goes over in that one okay and so
the concatenation aspect could have done
that but it means you have less control
over the full path right and so the
override means you have full control
over exactly where you want it and so it
can be installed multiple times in more
complex devices and so that's why you
know I agree with that as the uh as the
proposal and but I just want to explain
why
okay yeah uh thank you Dave next slide
please
it says six of seven there should be one
more one more
oh this is the rest of it yeah okay I
think we just talked about that
yes okay I think we're done
uh the the optical part you haven't
mentioned that oh yeah the the point is
that declaring your own component ID is
optional that's not a mandatory field in
the Manifest and the idea there is that
um dependencies just omit it
does uh anyone
no we're on this is this is trust
management this is multiple trust
domains trust domains right
so
does anyone disagree with the conclusion
that
uh was just made here between Brunson
and uh Dave just so that if there's any
disagreement it's it's aired now
I'm not seeing any online and I'm not
seeing any in the room yeah this is the
conclusion we came to with the hackathon
but 100 at the working group to see if
we could get working for consensus right
your examples because
it's two sleeves up your suit
before you go on to the next one Brandon
did ask for somebody that is um a cwt
expert to be a reviewer of this one so I
just asked is there anybody who
considers themselves to be proficient in
cwts it would be willing to do a review
for uh for that aspect of the document
um how about Carson
[Laughter]
thank you
so let it be noted in the minutes
just to be clear for the notes which
document or are we referring to that was
multiple trust domains and uh everybody
pointed at Kirsten after Hank raised his
hand first in case you're taking notes
thank you
all right so this is our viewers
reviewers for the cwt aspect of the
multiple trust domains document
all right okay uh so now we're into uh
update management
so it just as a summary there are
several extensions to suit in this
document the first is uh it currently
contains a coast wood
um I would prefer it to contain a co-rim
uh it has uh mechanisms for version
comparison for uh Loosely coupled
dependencies rather than ones that are
coupled by Digest
uh it's got some things on deployment
constraints like timing priority and
authorization and a couple of commands
to enable more compact encoding for
setting parameters
next slide please
so the primary changes since v0 are
adding the override multiple command the
point of this is that if you've got a
lot of components this saves you two
bytes each
uh then there's the copy parameters
command which uh when more than one
component uses the same value for a
parameter cuts down on the encoding this
is primarily important for hashes
because if you copy a hash in the in the
current version of the suit manifest
draft if you copy a component from one
place to another you have to declare the
hash for it more than once and that is
uh not great for something that's
supposed to be encoded small so this is
to resolve that problem and it allows
copying from one component to another
with a relatively minimal encoding
next slide please
oh that's it no is that it one more
just waiting for it to advance okay
um so there's this is definitely not a
full list of update management actions
if there's something missing that you
need for a use case please uh let us
know
let me know let someone know
um if they're uh for sorry uh version
comparisons
um there was an open question from the
previous uh meeting about whether it
should be possible to use a manifest
sequence number as a version comparison
in a manifest
my instinct is no because we already
have a way to check however I have had
the request for that
um and then that request Dave went
strangely silent so
um I'm not sure where we go from there
okay uh sorry then
um are there any other uh open issues
that anyone's aware of
it's the first time I've ever witnessed
Dave have a cash Miss
cash overflow
in that case I think that is it we we do
have I'd be interested if anyone has
review uh or is interested in reviewing
the uh this document I'd appreciate
reviews in general but also specifically
on those two introduced new commands
okay this one didn't come up with the
heck though this one didn't come up at
the hackathon but I I have the Instinct
that it will at some point if I don't do
it
foreign
so are you able to are you able to uh
say more about what the actual issue was
or should we just take that offline
okay perfect okay
I don't see harness in the room no I
believe that Ken is gonna do the
firmware encryption live okay yep
thank you
okay uh Kentucky
of this document the next slide please
yeah uh we are still uh improving our
document uh yeah and David Brown uh
joined of course as
and uh we have some dependency on other
documents uh we are
still
discussing in quasi working group like
causing hpk and also called the AES and
ASC CBC mode uh
and as you can notice the title is
changed uh the software encryption with
suit manifest into encrypted payloads in
suit manifest
and we are still improving the text uh
in the document and we have new uh
example approach to uh
delivery the integrated firmware into to
device next slide please
uh simple uh this is old approach and I
don't want to explain it so next slide
please
yeah this is new idea uh the
uh
the Manifest is uh signed by the
Manifest Creator you know so the and now
the encryption aim for is inside the
Manifest so it is signed by
someone
and uh it requires uh if they also
create the Manifest
nobody can not change the Manifest so it
requires distribution system to create a
second manifest
uh with a dependency resolution
mechanism
and so this is another story but so I I
explained it later and
yeah in this draft we do not uh
exemplify the dependency solution so
just simple one the author creates uh
encrypted firmware and its manifest and
deliver it to the device so next price
please this is the example
up could you tilt the microphone okay
yeah that helps perfect yeah next right
please
uh okay at next slide please okay hello
yeah
uh with this case as you notice the
the uh
oh it's so so tiny
oh
yeah so the as I said the encryption
info is inside install uh command so
this is signed by author
so the device can decrypt it with this
parameter next side please
and now we are trying to export in this
example to multiple trust domains draft
so this is a little bit complicated uh
that they also create a go firmware and
it's manifest and then deliver it to the
distribution system the distribution
system creates uh encrypted firmware
and it's manifest so there there are two
manifests and encrypted firmware to be
sent to the device
so first of all the distance systems
manifest contains a command to fetch or
such manifest and encrypted firmware and
how to decrypt it
and lastly that it triggers also's
manifest
the osis manifest is quite simple so
just check the validity of the decrypted
firmware
maybe that's all right uh we are still
tackling to create it and also improve
our example manifest because uh with
this scenario the the author have to uh
Trust on the distribution system because
uh the they also have to disclose the
raw firmware to this to the distribution
system and also the device must trust
the distribution system because to
process the uh the Manifest which is
created by this distribution system uh
it requires to depend
trust the uh the Distribution Systems
public key so it is uh it introduces uh
more new uh security considerations so
maybe we we have to improve these
Solutions
yeah that's all
and any comments and advices are welcome
uh this is a day favor
um case there's any way that wasn't
following this what are the reasons for
the rename that Ken mentioned at the
beginning is that uh teep uses this not
just for code but also for what type
calls personalization data so in other
words the code itself isn't necessarily
secret but the config file or the config
data around that may need to be
encrypted and so this abstracts it
because it's just a payload it's a file
that could be placed or something that
could be stored in storage whether it's
code or data doesn't matter for the
purpose of this is that was why the
rename because T needs it for both code
and for data
yeah this is so complicated I don't want
to explain this that's your last life
yeah you can check this one but uh yeah
uh any questions or any concerns with
the shift in Direction which is a
significant one in this draft
all right thank you Ken
foreign
at the mic I guess the the only thing
I'd note is that we probably could
revisit a more distributable version if
that's something that's uh that's
demanded from the working group I'm not
saying that we would change this draft
I'm saying there's the possibility that
we could look at a
um compatible or the one that doesn't
use dependencies but uses a key
distribution mechanism instead
Independence
we're going to change the order now
because Dave just got his five minute
warning to go uh
next door so we're gonna do
um
mud and then we're going to do uh MTI
while Dave's gone
[Music]
yes are you commenting on the last one
no no no I'm doing the time machine
thing again
uh sorry
I really forgot and there was this
comment about when you have close with
that you wanted program instead that
would be perfect that would be a blocker
because it would take way longer yes
accommodating for that is fine
um but don't expect as of course what is
basically done so maybe if you want this
done and if we want this done maybe not
wait for Quorum but you know
yeah that that's the reason that it
still contains a coastwind today
okay uh wait a minute how does that
affect the working group last call this
was for the uh update management so
sorry when he jumps way back on the
agenda I've got to follow the gotta snap
the pointer
okay
um
you you could go in the YouTube pad and
fix it
[Laughter]
we're jumping to the integration between
suit and mud
uh next slide please
so the just to give a summary of what
this is for anyone who hasn't looked at
it before the idea is essentially this
uh mud files are a mechanism that allows
devices to point to a URL which contains
a document that tells Network
infrastructure what they should and
shouldn't access over their intranet and
possibly over the internet
um
what this does is provides a new
reporting mechanism for those URLs the
argument here is that uh it would be
nice if your network infrastructure knew
what this was and had those files
available before it ever sees that
device
and if you're receiving firmware updates
those
access requirements can change so having
those two things coupled together again
makes sense further to that some of the
reporting mechanisms that were defined
for mud originally are unsecured and
leaving an unsecured way of reporting
security information doesn't make a lot
of sense to me at least there was one
mechanism defined that was secured but
that mechanism was done through device
certificates and while that is a one way
to get the job done there are other ways
to do it as well and particularly the
interesting thing about this approach is
that it allows us to link it in with
attestation as well so you can attest
the software that a device is running
and using that information about the
software you can then determine what
network access requirements it has I've
lost the slides yes we have okay I'm
trying to figure out why so so this is
the the idea behind it
um I I can talk probably off of part of
that first slide from memory so I'll do
my best uh the
the what we've defined in this draft is
mostly just
um a mechanism to report either a URI
and a signer key
or a full copy of the mud file
um and that's it this that is the draft
in summary there is precious little else
that's there so it's got similar
benefits to certificate bindings but it
doesn't mean you need device specific
certificates
um it does require device fingerprinting
or attestation in your network so it's
just different ways to solve the same
problem
um I with different trade-offs uh next
slide please
last slide and also last slide there's
been very little activity on this I
don't know if just no one is interested
in it in which case maybe we don't need
it
um there is an open issue about how we
handle updating mud files
um specifically if you deliver the full
text of a mud file does that imply it
never changes or is there a way to
override it so that's that's essentially
the one open issue around this
foreign
Richardson um
I I did read the document some
ihfs to go
um so you just I was going to say
something positive and then you just
said well you just said we're delivering
the full text of the mud file I didn't
don't remember that ever being the case
I thought it was only the URL there was
an option to do it that way well I think
that's probably a silly thing okay
um so that probably solves your problem
um don't do that
um but
um so there's a document in opto AWG
which which uh I think will finally get
to where can we last call this morning
um on once you have one securely how do
you update and what are our reasonable
update path and you can do it relatively
securely
um so I think that actually solves most
of the problem but I think that you can
deliver a unique URL per firmware I
think that's the right way to do it
even if the I would say it's the right
way to do it even if there's no
functional changes in the firmware okay
just you just say this is the new
version and this also lets you do
because as you may know you can also now
Point there's multiple ways of doing
this now you can point to an s-bomb from
the mud file and so while that might not
be
like we could do that through suit as
well there's multiple ways of doing this
I don't think it's a terrible thing to
have a variety of ways of being able to
tell the owner operator Network
this device may be vulnerable to this
dve right that's what we want to do
yeah I actually just go I think you're
done you're getting the reviews because
I think you're done okay cool
sounds good
does that mean it should go to working
group last call
I'll ask that when people are through
common things so hi this is Hank I was
just
um I was writing modifieds for rats back
in the day so mighty rats there will be
Paul postponed them because uh
um the implementations were not there a
year ago were there now so that we're
returning to that so you are not
explicitly fire defining a mod file here
no yeah so um
um isn't there a need for that why is
that a no just as a nutshell why do I
need to define a mud file if I'm just
pointing a URI at it
because maybe there are some suit
specific cards no that's not what this
is for this is for uh giving your
network infrastructure
infrastructure so it's the native okay
that's fine thank you
so it sounds like the action item that
that Michael is suggesting is to remove
the the encapsulated mud file and stick
with just a URI and signer
that's what I heard okay
so I think we need to implement that
before we do uh working group last call
what I'm hearing is
get that update done then do working
group last call should this be blocked
on the the last call of the Manifest
it shouldn't complete before manifest
completely understood
okay
student report no now we're doing MTI
last one
oh and I've got the wrong date on or
oops next slide quick before anyone
notices I was just gonna say on the last
Point um if if um the timing is right we
could submit them as a bundle
it'll get bundled whether we do or not
okay
okay so the point of this draft is to
ensure on interoperability with a
minimal crypto Suite now I want to
prefix this I think I'm going to say
this again multiple times but the
important thing here is that this is
specifically for constrained node
firmware update I'm not saying anything
about uh mandatory to implement
algorithms for tape I'm sure Dave has
ephemerally heard me somewhere
um so that's that's an important
consideration in this discussion that
this is specifically for constrained
node update that we're talking about
these crypto Suites
um
so it's an asymmetric problem unlike
many of the interop algorithm
discussions we have
mandatory to implement means something
different for the author than it does
for the constraint node the important
thing here is that your manifest author
should be able to make a manifest for
any device
sorry
the Manifest author should be able to
make a manifest for any device an
intermediary that processes a manifest
should be able to process a manifest for
any device but a device does not need to
be able to process any manifest it only
needs to be able to process the Manifest
that's aimed at it and if the Manifest
author can't work out which crypto
algorithm to use for that there are
bigger problems problems that we can
solve with suit report
um so the that's the the fundamental
consideration here in that this is an
asymmetric MTI it means something
different for the author than it does
for the recipient
and if we don't have appropriate choices
for constrained nodes they're just going
to ignore this document
that's one reason that it's been
separated out of the suit manifest the
other reason is that it's likely to
change over time and be obsolete a bunch
of times
next slide please
so the current status is we're defining
four MTI algorithms
they're all mandatory to implement for
manifest authors and intermediaries but
manifest processors are simply required
to implement at least one it's scoped
specifically as I said to iot Firmware
deployment use cases and constrained
nodes at that
uh one of the questions I have for the
working group is whether we should
require all authors and intermediaries
to implement the symmetric algorithm
Suite that's defined I'm not sure that's
a good idea so if there's any feedback
on that maybe that's an option and that
one's not mandatory then
next slide please uh unless there's
events I was thinking that if a cipher
Suite is implemented we probably want it
to be one the one in firmware encryption
it's since it's already bundled there
why I say anything here
I think the point was that the firmware
encryption draft won't need to be
obsoleted each time we change algorithms
it won't
it's got the algorithm identifiers there
you can do anything from cozy
but
confused
I think I'm I'm misunderstanding
something here okay
um ask your question okay so are you
saying that we're defining an algorithm
Suite in the firmware encryption draft
and therefore we don't need this yes
but what happens when we decide that
that algorithm Suite is wrong
then there'll be another document that
comes and replaces it or it just you
pick something else from the Cozy
libraries uh the algorithm registry
and as long as the code points are there
it just works
but how is that mandatory to implement
right if you're going to mandator if
you're going to change the mandatory to
implement you're going to have somebody
at the dock
yes the update which document the
firmware encryption document I think
that Brendan's point is that it that he
would rather just rev this document and
have all the things in one place like
we've done an ipsec
I see okay so um where we've had to
define a new mode you're still gonna
expect the new say block Cipher with the
same mode as a future yeah that's the
idea okay I don't have a problem with
that
okay
um
welcome back
um so you've defined four profiles yes
uh one of them is has HSS LSM yes right
um which I'm very enthusiastic up Russ
and I had a back and forth about LMS
excuse me I'll never get if I could have
you know simple syllables instead of
lots of letters to say I'll remember it
um Lucy in the Sky with Diamonds
whatever something like that right
um
um so Russ and I said so who actually
implements hsms with
LS
HSS LMS see I can't do it now right too
many letters there's at least two so you
told me to open source okay you told me
to
um one of them is defunct I had a long
conversation with Randy and and um
Rob okay it's really defunct you really
can't get the hardware uh okay that was
a third one the the cryptek is the third
one
okay so the third so there's a Cisco
implementation and there's the pi uh
HSS LMS
okay well okay so let me tell you what I
I know okay all right
um the cryptek one is at this point
sadly defunct yep okay the hardware is
unobtainable the the revision to it uh
got killed by pandemic and now Russian
sanctions yep okay because the guy who
did the work is there so and they're not
likely to ever get new hardware out is
what I got if their spares you could use
it there another company was one in
Ottawa correct who uh surprisingly has
an office Three Doors Down from mine
there you go you should be able to find
them yeah so a of course no one's been
to that office in three years
um
uh but actually I suspect no one's been
to that office ever that was a a tax uh
uh office registration for r d credits
uh so I don't know any of the people
involved right maybe you do
um so you know that's interesting okay
they exist and you say there's a third
one a Cisco implementation I think that
that I think that just the community
needs Assurance a feeling of of safety
that there's stuff that we can go and
get that are going to be useful
otherwise we're going to get a lot of
push a lot more pushback and I think
we've got that already and I would just
like to see people relax and go okay
it's all right we can handle this okay
that's the point so would you prefer to
see this document revved when a more
available pqc signature algorithm comes
out
don't I don't want to wait for that to
publish it okay I'm happy to to rev it
in whatever that period is 18 months two
years six years whatever okay
um yeah of course we should do that
right and and if and if we obsolete one
of our profiles that's okay too because
we the purpose was to get an upgrade
path that was the whole point was to get
the upgrade path and I'm very very
concerned that people are not going to
implement the the PQ safely one if they
feel at all uh anxious about you know
what they're gonna do they're just like
oh it's too hard and throw up their
hands right
yep I I agree with everything you said
is there an action item from that yeah I
have to introduce something okay
and he wants an introduction next slide
please
so these are the algorithms that are
defined
um
we've got one symmetric one post Quantum
asymmetric that's only kind of post
Quantum it's post Quantum hybrid because
there are no standardized key exchange
algorithms yet
um the classical asymmetric uh we've got
es-256 and eddsa uh both of them with
hpke because uh that seems to be where
things are headed I think uh they're
currently listing
aesgcm but it sounds like AES CTR or AES
CBC should be coming so I'm not totally
sure CTR seems to be the direction at
the moment
okay uh so there you are
um so those are what we have on the
plate at the moment next slide please
there were two that were obviously
missing
um those there might be a need for a
specialized version of eddsa there I
don't think there's a Code point for
ed25519 and cozy
um but that's kind of an important
consideration because on a constrained
node you can handle it differently
uh day Fair can we go back one slide
I have a question not a request but it's
a question yeah
um all of the MTI ones actually require
encryption
uh that's a sweet that's so sweet yeah
if encryption then that's what you use
okay so you're not actually requiring
all constrained devices to have
encryption if all you're doing is
Distributing public firmware and things
right no no okay I think right now the
security consideration section says to
do I think it would be useful to
elaborate on that point fair enough
to do
well it is to do next slide please I
mean you can at least fill in the entire
document is about security I mean that's
what most people do but yeah I think I
probably will
um
I like that even better
so here's you know there are a couple
obvious things that uh get used a lot in
iot that are missing from that
um maybe they shouldn't be I I've seen
at least one argument that if we're
going to have eddsa we might as well put
Chacha poly with it and that's an option
those that set seems to get used
together quite a lot which is the
argument for that
um so maybe that would be a good change
I don't know oh I've got a thumbs up
from at least one person
okay so uh that that might be one change
to make
um and that's it if you have any
feedback please let me know I'd be
welcome co-authors as well if someone
wants to do some of this write security
considerations Maybe
so should we do a uh Poll for adoption
how do you want to do that because I
think he needs to do and an update to
address that point you made before we
adopted
uh
it's adopted before we last call it
um no I'm saying right now it's an
individual estimation it's not a working
group document the MTI MTI I think
you're right I think that's right it is
and so um uh I think we have the action
item to call adoption so I'm asking can
we do that right now and say can this
it's not done right can we at least
rename it from uh individual to working
the question is does anyone object to
adopting it
we'll take it to the list but does
anyone object to it in its current form
I've heard several people saying just
just adopt is the next step right
just making sure okay so uh technically
it's within our race to just adopt it
without asking the list but we like to
ask the list so or ask the people so the
assumption is it will be adopted and the
next version of it will actually be a
draft ietf suit
um so when you grab it post it as a new
one unless we tell you otherwise okay
we'll do
that sounds fun okay
I just wanted that minute
okay I think this is the one Dave wanted
to be back for so this is a suit report
next slide please
so a summary of what it is the idea
behind this is that you want to know
what your device did when you attempted
to install something or try to secure
boot uh so what it contains is a
reference to the root manifest so that
you know exactly what it was working on
then you've got a record of each
decision it takes there are relatively
few decisions in a suit manifest so this
is a small list uh there is also a
record of any critical information
that's identified in that process this
is done through the uh the reporting
mode hint that goes with each suit
command that feeds into the construction
of the suit report but it is a hint suit
manifest processors are welcome to
override that behavior however they see
fit uh the result of this is this so
what it gives you is the result of an a
procedure there are were two procedures
but since the changes to the uh
suit multiple trust domains there is now
a third procedure which is uninstall
uh invoke in case it's not clear is
equivalent to either secure boot or
running the code that's in your tee
next slide please
uh so this has a relationship to rats
and uh we didn't quite have time to talk
about it at rats but the idea here is
that a verifier in rats could take all
of this information and construct your
device State out of it and by using that
they're able to uh discern information
they might need to determine the uh the
trustworthiness of the device
they can also extract the system
property claims and by extracting the
system property claims they can
construct the information that would
normally have gone into an attestation
report so this can be used in appraisal
and the the one important consideration
here is that this is not the kind of
information that a relying party wants
to get so there is an onus that gets
placed on the verifier to translate this
information into more conventional eat
values
um it is and so what I'm saying is it's
attestation evidence but it's probably
not attestation results
next slide please
so there were a couple of changes
um I noted in the original version of
this uh draft that it's very convenient
on a constrained device to do reporting
through a single append-only log and if
you have multiple places that you have
to put data mistakes get made
serialization is hard what this does is
it allows you to just keep a pending and
serializing to a log all in one go so
you don't have to do a post-processing
step before you can cons before you can
send or store your report
uh what I have done in this one is
merged the system property claims and
the suit manifest records to try and
join that together to go from two logs
down to one and the mechanism for this
which is not entirely clear here but the
idea behind it is that one of these
elements is a list or an array element
and the other is a map element and by
doing this a verifier that wants to
extract only system property claims just
takes all of the maps out of that list
and it has the system property claims
without having to worry about parsing
anything else
next slide please
I've added suit capability reports we
talked about capability reports a number
of times in this working group and we
never quite got to doing it but I
thought that a report draft might be the
place to put a report so I've added a
suit capability reports in here and it
essentially breaks it down to the things
that a an author needs to know about a
suit manifest processor and it's just a
list of lists of integers it's fairly
simple in that respect so oh and
component identifiers which are not
integers so so that's that's the overall
structure on the rough idea of what's in
there between these things you know what
a suit manifest processor can do
modulo any ACLS that are applied by it
which you won't know from this
next slide please
your last one oh that's my last one okay
well then that's it
um
so uh that if there's any feedback on
that I'd appreciate it if you want to do
a review I'd appreciate it
um
go ahead any questions comments
yeah
you want me to go first yeah go first
okay
um so two what one question one comment
I'll give the comment one first um that
I think uh some place we need to write
down how you might carry a suit report
in an eat
yes so that is a big to do on this yeah
and I think that what it boils down to
is that we need to Define an eat claim
yeah just eat one yeah
manifest which would not be this right
there's an e-claim for measurements
which maybe you can squint and say it
goes there or maybe it's a new claim
that's specific to suit manifest my
preference would be to Define this as a
single new eat claim which is just a
suit report right that that would be my
preference as well and Russ is also
nodding
um as part of where that wherever that
gets written down whether it's in this
document which would probably be my
preference but it doesn't have to be
um should also consider answering the
question of okay assume that your suit
report has sensitive information
do you encrypt the suit report or do you
put it in and eat and encrypt to eat
I suspect it's easier to say the latter
because the eat may contain other
sensitive information from that device
besides the suit report in which case
not having a mechanism to say encrypt
the suit report for use and eat is
probably not necessary but that's what
the security consideration should
actually discuss that so I think there's
a response coming to the mic okay I do
have a separate question but I'm happy
to go after Michael so this is all my
first one so okay but if Hank wants to
respond to this we can cover this one
so I would this is Hank I would not
assume that we offload the
responsibility of encrypting something
to eat
because but that would imply that we
always send suit reports and eat
that looks weird to me yeah yeah
I was not making that assumption I was
saying when sending a suit report and
eat
right but the implementation then is
that what do you do when you don't know
how do you encrypt it when yeah I I
agree that you need a different
mechanism when not covering it well you
need to also answer the question of what
if it's not an eat I agree with that
yeah okay if that's fine then yeah
on the eat one if you imagine that there
are uh five different claims of which
you preferred as one
and all of them have sensitive
information do you encrypt five things
separately and then put them in an eat
or do you put them all in and eat to
encrypt this whole thing that I'm saying
that's the discussion that should be put
into the security considerations right
last question
and possibly yes okay so if you didn't
hear that remotely Russ said uh that's a
discussion I should go in the eat
document
or yeah
so uh Michael Richardson here so I'm
really happy to let you go first
um because because
um now I can ask my my question in a
much uh more interesting way
um so
um
up to this point we are the whole status
tracker has been sort of out of scope
for the working group
so
my question is how do we get suit
reports back in the first place given
that we haven't even told people how to
get you know manifests and stuff to the
device that's of all a device specific
thing so how do we get any of this back
and it actually answers part of the
question huh and that's the same way the
same magic way but but you see at that
point if you say it's the same magic way
then the the privacy considerations for
that thing are also the same magic way
okay so that actually is my bigger
question is that I think that this
document has pushed us very close to
saying it's time to for a small
recharger to have an ietf standard
status tracker with encryption that can
collect this information okay I have a
counter proposal that's fine I don't
care how we do it but as long as we do
it okay because otherwise I think that
that well there's some places some
verticals like teep where they have the
problem solved I think there's a whole
bunch of other places where people are
just uh okay and they're going to wind
up in some very proprietary uh vertical
at that point
so so I have a counter proposal can I
tell you about it in an hour in an hour
yes at some other place okay so but I'll
sorry I'm just joking uh the
what we've realized that this is that
there really isn't anything in tape
that restricts it to Tes
there's nothing in the T protocol draft
that would prevent you from using it
outside of a te
and when you squint at it just hard
enough it looks an awful lot like that
status tracker
so I think that's really cool and I
think that for a bunch of things
um that are of the you know Raspberry Pi
and larger devices I think that's
probably the right answer
um and then the question is whether
that's usable below that and that may be
the case that it is right and the reason
I I think that tees don't have that
problem is that they also have a
typically a rich execution environment
that can do all of the heavy networking
stuff you know that is you know no
longer possible on 16-bit CPUs for some
reason but anyway I'm just kidding right
obviously it is right there you go so
what I'm what I'm saying is I think that
it's worth exploring that but I think
that it would make sense if we already
have a protocol and and so on that does
roughly what we're talking about to
evaluate it first
okay
um if it's a follow-up let karaoke first
well just to Russ's Point um
about where encryption discussion should
go I think it should go on and eat
profile which is where ER says things
should go now absolutely agree
okay so Dave Taylor now my other
question
um
uh on the slide here it says they're
broken down into supported component
identifiers and and you uh pointed out
that you know they're not integers and
stuff so what does supported component
identifiers mean for a non-constrained
device is my question so there is a wild
card
thank you
does that answer your question so you
could say here's a path and then
everything after that is a wild card
record support arbitrary components if
you choose to install them as long as it
goes under this path that's correct okay
that answered my question thank you
are we done
let's just make sure
[Music]
no we didn't uh we need to talk around
okay I don't remember what the charter
question was
oh yeah yeah
you're right
um uh on uh so Brendan's answer here
about an hour I was referring to like
the tape meeting
um and uh I will observe that earlier in
the suit working group right we had a
discussion of can you use suit
for so I can use a suit manifest for
things that are not iot devices okay
because you know software update for
internet of things and we said yes for a
chartered to make sure that it works for
iot but we actually put language in this
manifest that said it is not restricted
for that purpose okay you can imagine a
similar discussion go that might happen
in deep
fair enough
all right so we've covered you cover the
hard case because otherwise you wouldn't
right and then if it happens to be
useful for the easy case go for it right
all right so just making sure since we
jumped around the agenda
this page we covered all of them
[Music]
this page we covered all of them so we
arced out to the any other business that
would anyone like to raise some foreign
thank you we're done already
they're probably not out yet
thank you
I'm surprised
but we definitely needed more than 60
minutes right so it means you know we
picked the right number at 90. the fact
that we used
71 effectively yep
I don't think we had any
unless something happened there was no
non-essentials
interesting things while you were next
door
foreign
I hope it went well next door
um
my part of it did since I'm just
advertising a side meeting so
apologize
called a generic prospector API
okay generic
and everything yet another layer because
there's so many they're just a
bit
you know
so there's there's so much
or root of trust which is
similar but nice
definitions document I'm pretty sure
that actually means busaker and so they
want to manage that for validation
procedures of course and uh and the uh I
will propagate the TA profile for Quorum
Edo platform because I have a
relationships
that concise da stories again they can
slice CA stores documents they have uh
they have a common size yeah I'm saying
make sure they know about our
consolidation
they have also a
cozy key store
they built a CE
implemented
and they use cozy Keys as the interface
messages and then the score is 88.
[Music]
they don't why so wait a minute
I don't know
if they want to be capable of supporting
a lot of this I'm worried that you they
made a vodka oh