or didn't
all right we're gonna have to pick on
victims
thank you
behind the masks
okay
so we still need a note taker most
immature got the news cap the point next
capture also need somebody to watch the
chat just in case questions come up and
chat
um uh from people who aren't able to
join the micq for some reason
also speaking of the Mike Q This is a
hybrid meeting therefore the mic Q is
what's up there on the screen if you are
standing in front of the mic and your
name's not up there you don't actually
exist despite the fact that someone
looks an awful lot like you is standing
in the mic line
so make sure you join the meeting uh
because that's where the micues Run
I mean it's also saying that unless you
join the meeting you haven't signed the
blue sheet so you should join the
meeting anyway even if you have no
intention of saying anything
foreign
so please join the app
use the QR code do the blue sheets
please volunteer somebody to be a note
taker
or else we'll have an even less time
than we currently have which
we are planning to use to the full
thank you for your assistance we will we
will try and make them good so don't
worry about the details we will help but
very much appreciated
so note taker
okay please record your name in the
notes as a note taker
okay
this is t t s v w g as far as I know the
only working group with WG in the
acronym
uh and we're here to look at the
transport area topics uh I'm gory first
I'm one of the working group chairs this
is
I'm David black and
I'm Martin ziman
okay
so welcome Martin
uh good one we'll
um yep let's go through the note well
not well is the standard ietf note well
if you haven't read it on day one then
you should uh this covers the rules for
IPR disclosure among other things
next slide
we do need help in tsbw dupe we will be
pursuing people to help them help with
note taking and we have a note taken for
this session thank you very much
if you if you're intending to produce a
document in tsvwg then please add the
acronym tsvwg to your draft
and if you'd like that to proceed
then please offer to review drafts we
need reviewers for working group drafts
okay and I need a volunteer to watch the
chat and bring to the room's attention
to anything and chat from somebody who's
unable to join the mic line for some
reason so
looking for a volunteer who's going to
be in the chat anyhow
anybody
okay Richard can you pay attention to
the chat for us
[Laughter]
we'll just k on it okay a quick reminder
uh please join the meeting of the blue
sheets also the mic line is running
entirely in meat Echo you have to join
the my line and meet Echo standing in
front of the mic does not put you in the
mic line we run the mic line uh automate
Echo it's shown on the smaller screen in
the center of the room
all right
um as gory's noted uh Dr quality relies
on reviews if you like documents you
care viewed please in the effort to
review other documents some upcoming
documents that could use some careful
review are multi-path uh dccp and the
UDP options drafts
all right time for a review of our
greatest hits nrc's published since ietf
114 but there are three drafts at the
art all three l4s drafts are at the RFC
editor they are being actively worked on
they will appear in the very near future
I think we're closing in on uh what's
needed to get them published no drafts
at iesu after IHF last call
we have two drafts with regular chairs
and authors after work last call this is
yours truly uh as as the responsible or
irresponsible group chair uh the issue
encapsulation for the lower layer
protocols and ECM for tunnels that use
shim headers uh we're working through
the revised reframing interaction text
for that first draft using captivation
for lower layer protocols with luck that
will con that will close fairly soon and
the Arts publication request will be
coming
one draft just completed a second
working group last call is signing a new
recommended dscp that will be discussed
in this meeting we have a draft in
working with last call uh the nqb phb uh
Greg is going to discuss uh where we are
on that one
um here are the remaining six drafts the
first five drafts are on the agenda the
sixth one use reports for experiments is
a fairly small mostly processed draft uh
the draft itself is complete it's going
to be working group last called fairly
shortly after this meeting and uh we'll
do them there
if you've been paying very close
attention what we do you'll notice sctp
Nat is missing from a list above uh we
decided the right thing to do was remove
it from our plan of work because we
could not get uh convergence and
agreement on what that what that draft
ought to do
okay bunch of related drafts these are
all on the meeting agenda we have uh
three uh sctp drafts a couple of updates
uh and a proposal of zero checksum we
have a general uh internet condition
control guidance draft uh Martin Duke
has found a case that we appear to have
missed in uh ecn interaction with
tunnels so there's an indoor draft on
that and careful resumption of
congestion control are you going to talk
about those are going to talk about that
Glory
I think Nicholas will try and join us
remotely if not I'll cover it okay
sounds good
um wait to see here
um here okay uh some related IDs that
are not on the agenda please uh post
list or talk to the authors if they're
interested uh Jason livinggood has a
Comcast uh uh draft on uh deployment
design uh hpcc plus plus well this is
sort of on the agenda sort of not
there's a there's one slide coming up if
uh we get through the agenda quickly
they'll be timed out the end to go into
it much more detail but we'll have to
see we're trying to run what would
normally be a three hour meeting in two
hours and so uh things are tight and
John has a draft on media headache
extension for wireless networks which
has been uh discussed some on the list
and if you're on that list of people
then please be ready to come to the mic
when we show yours one slide you have
two minutes to present your topic as and
encourage people to read those drafts uh
just two minutes in total and that will
happen after slide 17 you're on slide 10
so we're getting there
okay Milestone reviews we have two
record Milestones it says still about to
be achieved because I thought these were
almost done in Philadelphia I still
think they're almost done we're closer
now uh we're well into the second we're
well into the last 10 that takes the
other ninety percent of the time
um uh additional uh 2022 uh working
group uh Milestones uh we're going to
move uh the UDP options drafts to March
uh 2023 as the new date for them
um nqb well we're not too far off it's
in working group last call so we'll
leave the milestone in September uh
moving forward we have uh considerations
for a shining new recommended uh dscp
coming uh which has been working with
last called uh and then if we go into
next year
um use reports for experiment needs a
new Milestone that looks like January
and then the March uh details sctp and
July milestones for the dccp extensions
and lfers operational guidance uh remain
intact uh Magnus you were in and out of
the Mike queue I hope we covered
whatever it was you were concerned about
okay
uh agenda so we start with these slides
including Milestones view which you've
just seen uh chairs update so I've we've
reviewed the Asian encapsulation draft
status we've reviewed the uh status
shelf first drafts at the RFC editor
expect to actually be rfcs very soon
it's been a long strange trip but we got
there
uh and the status active working group
drafts
we then have a couple of group drafts on
uh uh on uh diff serving an aqm
um DHCP assignment considerations which
it has gone through our group last call
we have some comments resolve the lfs
operational guidance which Greg White's
going to talk about a little bit uh that
one's going to stick around for a while
moving on transport drafts uh two
sessions on multi-path dccp there's been
some interop testing and I hear the
results a bit have been pretty good uh
and then Marcus will talk about the base
multi-path DCC D CCP draft
John Matson has taken over SCP
authentication and found let's see I
think we could politely call it some
opportunities for improvement uh Michael
tookson is going to talk about what to
do about those opportunities
Magnus has our latest details of sctp
draft and then we have the two uh UDP
options drafts uh I think gory you're
going to try to impersonate Joe touch
good luck
thank you
uh and then the deal uh the DPL pmtud no
don't don't actually pronounce that uh
uh uh supporting UDP options uh gory is
that yours at Tom Jones
um they're both going to be dealt with
the same way all right
okay uh individual drafts
um sctp UDP uh update
um proposed by ctps or checksum
um Nicholas is going to talk about
uh Carefree junk careful resumption
congestion control gory is going to talk
about a general draft on guidelines and
recognition control and as I mentioned
earlier uh Martin Duke has found a case
that we a case of EC internal
interaction that appears not to be
addressed as an angel draft to address
it then down at the end of the meeting
at the end of item five is normally two
hours of gender time if we get through
this more quickly we'll have time down
at the end to do uh hpcc plus plus
Michael has uh at least one other sctp
draft John has a metadata draft uh on
meditative media packets and finally
ingomar has a 5G radio scheduling l4s no
draft he's also going to talk about that
in iccrg so it's not essential that we
get to it but it's certainly usually
have a heads up here
okay we need to get through some cherish
topics administ trivia time uh liaison
Communications so I'll start the third
liaison came a while ago uh it's been
dealt with
um and nothing has been heard from wa
since we sent the reply back in essence
what had happened is a an interest
individual draft to come here saying hey
let's go to find phbs and dscps for
every 5qi we can think of
uh to which our response was uh that's a
lot of dhcps not sure we're going to be
using that many and oh by the way 3gpp
really does not like what you're doing
uh a liaison came from WBA said hey
would you please do this once a response
went back was uh that consumed a whole
lot of dscps how about something fewer
and would you please get along with 3gpp
and get back to us nothing has been
heard from wwba since I think we can
retire this uh this liaison
so we have a liaison with 3gpp relating
to a CTP and dtls
and this will come up in the liaison
discussion uh tomorrow where we do the
coordination and it may be updated if we
need to after this meeting we will see
how all this goes and gsma liaison has
your name against the world as well
yeah gsma are aware of the multi-path
dccp work and this touches with a 3gpp
and gsma work on
uh on the multi-path dccp work really
and keep going next one's yours too
all right um
this is uh iepg presentation on dscp
measurement is where Anna presented her
data if you didn't see it you missed it
put it still in the archive so you can
go and look at it or speak to Anna at
this meeting
um yeah we have an eye on a registry for
phb IDs what do you believe it
yeah well it's really interesting
um Ayanna was going around checking
whether they had uh active uh uh
designated experts reach registry and
ran across this one yours truly want
Disney experts Brian Carpenter is the
other we looked at the registry it's
over a decade old it's still empty
that's a real strong suggestion that
whatever it was trying to use the
registry isn't particularly useful
um so the path forward is I'm going to
write a draft that obsoletes the stuff
that uses the registry which is I under
registered uh per hop Behavior dinner I
own a relationship identification codes
for perhap behaviors that aren't
standards track and don't have and
therefore don't have a default
recommended dscp
the only thing we're going to do is
obsolete those things that we never use
because nobody ever registered one
um get uh update our 340 get rid of that
leave the existing format which is
essentially an encapsulated dscp
um and uh close-handed registry so no
effect in use of DSC fees are signaling
no effect on PHP IDs and embedded dscp
nobody's used this thing we're going to
get rid of it
Martin
um I propose nothing uh the um secret
isg back handle says the zoo lip is back
up so if we can monitor the zulip the
chat is back up so if we could please
monitor the chat Channel thank you
and there will be a phbid registry
internet draft appearing is that right
at some point soon don't hold your
breath because somewhere between the
change in XML format for rfcs my
external based tool chain collapse I'm
not going to have to rebuild and mark
down tool chain that comes first 14 is a
small draft it's a good test case
okay at which point we will look more
closely at that register and decide what
to do yeah
okay and next slide
welcome Martin
welcome Martin Martin would you like to
say something on behalf of Martin well I
was going to say this is Martin I mean
we said the name Martin several times
he's our new working group chair he's
acclimatizing to being up here in front
of everybody and um it's really good to
have him here thank you
I will be continuing as a working group
chair for the foreseeable future and
David black
I will be stepping down his working
group chair after a uh long uh and uh
interest interesting experience up here
I'm going to continue to separate drafts
not quite true the exact timing of this
but it will happen some sometime the
next few months Mr Duke sir yeah I would
just take a moment I would like to take
a moment to recognize David
um he has been the tsvw chair since
before I started coming to iitf meetings
I've never known a tsvwg that he was not
sharing and and like obviously being a
very present and active leader of
an expert on just a wide swath of the
kindness oh first of all tscw said you
know a very
robust group with like a wide swath of
technology that it covers and David has
done covered it quite adeptly and been
really an expert on a whole lot of stuff
um and uh I mean hopefully you're not
gonna you're gonna be around
to to continue to um provide your
expertise for the group just maybe from
from the floor where you can you know
take the gloves off which should be
quite entertaining and aside from the
technical you know obviously this is
this group has had um its share of
strife to be quite Frank about it and
um that's always
um
a uh a demanding thing for our chair to
handle and he has been um instrumental
in doing that so thank you for
everything you've done for the transport
area and the ITF and um like I said I
hope we hope to we hope to continue to
see you around
thank you very much
thank you very much I intend to stick
around perhaps more virtually and
physically but uh I'm not going anytime
soon and as Martin has reminds me
occasionally I still have some drafts
and responsible for Shepard
plus when I just volunteered to write
okay
so the next slides will be the
individual documents which are just
brought up here for a heads up this is a
new experiment you get two minutes to
pitch up on your draft if you want to so
come up now if you wish to give it a
talk
um for two minutes on your draft if not
then we will we will introduce it for
you
so who's first Jason Jason
while Jess is coming to the mic I'll
clarify that Wes Eddie will remain a
Shepherd for the l4s Ops work uh wise
has kindly agreed just to continue with
this so very grateful for that right
Albert Jason for his magic two minutes
right no pressure two minutes my
goodness well this one's pretty simple
um so in the process of getting ready
for deployment of all Forest types of
Technologies I've been talking to a
number of folks not just um folks on you
know sort of business positions but
policy makers
um you know researchers those kind of
folks that really influence the
technical environment in which isps
operate day to day
um and the key questions that they often
ask which this uh draft attempts to
address are what this means in relation
to prioritization sort of Fast Lanes and
slow Lanes in the American Regulatory
parlance and capacity or speed
um because those are very very common
points of confusion and then of course
how does this relate to the concept of
net neutrality and a fair treatment of
all applications without regard to the
protocol being used or or something
along those lines and so those are the
key two things that it speaks to and
then as a result it suggests sort of
four key things there might be a few
more bits and Bobs in there but
um really suggests this orientation
towards applications marking the traffic
rather than the network and I put that
one in particular because as soon as we
started talking about this we had sort
of DPI style vendors coming out of the
woodwork telling us that because apps
won't be marking anytime soon we should
put this magic you know inspection thing
in the network and it will magically
infer what applications which by the way
are encrypted you know need what type of
um you know queuing and that's a
nightmare and always results in improper
treatment and potentially starvation or
other negative effects and we've done
that before with TCP resets uh oops so
um you know I put that in there
application or Edge providers being able
to use it
um really on a sort of open base us
multiple you know sort of Edge Equipment
types should be supported okay you need
to wrap up quickly
so that's that I'm happy to take any
changes and uh there's a GitHub
repository thank you
Jeff are you doing hpcc
hi everyone so hpcc uh what is it it's I
novel congestion control mechanism
leveraging in bent Telemetry so each
node in the possible population data and
Center based on the data can either
adjust the sending rate or change
entropy why should you care
if you are building
IP address infrastructure for either
storage or machine learning especially
if you combine learning and inference
the same network
you'll figure out Hardware the tcmp
doesn't work due to collisions or you'll
have to keep your network 30 loading
uh you need to build lossless networks
because this is how we do machine
learning in general
you would need to spend a lot of time
and effort to build Network and
if you try to build it lossless fashion
without better congestion control the
cost just run out of control so
practically what we are doing here
we are gathering all the data as we
travel the network send it back to the
sender sender adjust the rate and allows
you to adjust the rate Within rtt
so if you would deploy something that
today you would probably run gcqcn which
works pretty well for long flows and you
know large environments however as you
try to put it into machine learning
clusters it stops working
uh we spent a year working on different
encodics you know there's a zoo of
indent limiting population unfortunately
in ibpm so we got to support all of this
recordings and metadata most importantly
we got all four
data center silicon vendors to support
it so you see Sisk broadcom melanox
sorry Nvidia and Intel supporting it's
coming in Silicon that's going to be
shipping starting now
so please do read the drafts uh we
expect a lot of people to be interested
in this technology it's much better than
what we have today most importantly
there are implementations in deployment
Alibaba runs this hpcc yeah
and Alibaba deployed hpcc with TCP just
three months ago so uh there is a larger
deck published and hopefully we'll get
them next ITF to present yeah thank you
John go ahead yeah the the uh the larger
deck is um is in the meeting materials
and we may get to it if we get get to it
if we have coming into session John go
ahead
so this is a draft that identifies some
media header extensions in terms of
metadata that is uh specific to wireless
networks I think for now uh because the
media I mean the the motivation is that
media applications demand low latency
and high bandwidth and handling this
kind of wireless link capacity variation
along with network utilization and the
demands of media applications is quite
challenging in the wireless networks
along with that we have HTTP 3 or quick
based media that's going to be
encrypting packets so multi-streaming
needs to be considered in 3gpp the xrm
working group has cons I mean sorry
study has considered some solutions but
we think that the ietf is a good place
to look at these options and avoid I
mean it have a common solution to the
problems that exist for all kinds of
Wireless I mean Wi-Fi and 3gp Networks
and we've identified a minimum set of
things which we think should be secured
and sent only between trusted parties uh
but at this point we're thinking of the
priority or importance of packets for
example an iframe should not even if
it's past a budget it should be sent
because otherwise it causes further
damage a scheduler in the radio network
can get use of packet bursts so that's
going to be a useful amount of
information and then delay budgets and
last the third part is that you know how
do we transport it and there are
multiple options at this point possibly
and each have different trade-offs so
there's media over quick with just HTTP
UDP options which is more General but
we've got to consider the API mask and
encapsulation which is more flexible but
then we're going to consider the
overhead and uh so you know that's
that's where we are at this point
um if you would read the draft and give
comments and suggestions that would be
very very nice almost exactly two
minutes well done
yeah for those three drops please look
at them please discuss on the list
um
likely at the next meeting every
question we will ask people to see if
they've read them or what they think of
them
oh it's me
I can actually be me
um
I'm one of the co-authors of the
considerations for assigning a new
recommended dscp this has been through a
working group last call so I'll try and
be relatively quick on this there were
changes in zero three and zero four
we added various clarifications
um
we had a request to mention 3086 so we
did
um we noted
um more explicitly that there are
different ways in which packets can be
remarked from the original marking that
they were sent with and we just tried to
highlight that a little bit more clearly
so that um nobody got confused about
implying what it meant to see a remark
packet
we changed the word pathology which
seems to be a relatively common
measurement term but has other
connotations used outside of the
measurement community so we can change
it to Observatory marking behavior and
we made various editorial Updates this
was the version last called
um we had some issues in working group
last call we had a number of different
topics raised and we put those in the
issue trackers the first set here are
all things that we think required better
text it's amazing how many times you can
improve your text we found yet more
places where the text could be better
maybe as other people reviewed this
higher levels I was hoping that it
passes out of this working group we'll
find yet more
corrections but we think all these are
solved in our editor's copy and we plan
to push this after this meeting as soon
as the meeting closes we'll push the new
version with a also an introduction to
all the behaviors in section 6.
David yes well
um we didn't include one of the requests
made in the working group must call yet
in our editor's version and it was to
discuss an issue
that happens when you have a
remarking behavior that
comes from a TOS precedence bleach
and where basically the first three bits
of the dscp are reset and
rudiger gave us this example as part of
his uh offering on comment and we didn't
include this text but we could still do
it if people think it's really important
it described example a and example B
example B being something that is kind
of like diff surf compliant because it
uses six bits to classify a set of rules
into another set of six bit rules each
individual dscp is remarked to a new
dscp
if you were to use some bleaching
mechanisms you would simply zero some
part of it as in example a
that anyone who knows anything about any
way in which coding happens you'd
realize these actually have the same
result so there are multiple ways to
represent the same thing and this is
part of the whole confusion about what
it means to bleach something I think the
real issue that we were trying to convey
in the draft was the intent behind the
remarking not the remarking itself
so if that confused you you can look at
the slide puzzle on it and password past
comments
um if anyone would like to ask a
question about this and feels really
passionate that something should arise
from this
um then please let us know otherwise
we'll go with the text written here
which I think also includes David's
comment on a similar subject
which is a very long explanation to say
um please read the draft and list text
if you care David let's slide number
three was
um somebody helpfully asked us about
their owner PHP ID and um
it was going to be a nice slide but
David already stole my thunder and we're
not going to say anything about this
on the last slide
there you go I think we're done anybody
any questions or any other issues that
they'd like to raise
good then I can go and put my mask on
again
Greg operational guidance
all right thank you
um actually before I get into
operational guidance I will say one
thing about the nqb draft since you
mentioned I would talk about it um I
don't have a slot on the agenda for it
so um it isn't working group last call
there already have been a few uh
comments have come in on the mailing
list but please do review the draft uh
and contribute to that discussion I
believe it has two more weeks until
um the work group last call ends so
again please review and provide comments
thank you all right hang on all right
just a minute need to go get your slides
back
um
there we go
all right
um the l4s Ops draft you can go on to
the next slide
[Music]
if you've not been aware of this
document before it talks about
deployment of l4s on the internet as it
is today which potentially could include
some RFC 3168 or classic
ecn aqm bottlenecks
and if those do exist on the internet
and classic traffic shares that
bottleneck with l4s traffic
there can be a rate imbalance where l4s
traffic gets more throughput than
classic does anyway the draft talks
about how to manage that situation
guidance for and hosts and network
operators and researchers as the l4s
graphs have gone through the working
class caller now in the editor's queue
we as a working group agreed to keep
this document open as a living document
as the experiments and deployment of l4s
begins to capture any learnings that
that that come along with that initial
deployment so I just posted a new
version of the document today
um and uh just to keep it alive and
again if anyone has any contributions
for that document please bring them up
on the mailing list and uh and we'll get
them added so I'm quite sure you and
Jason know each other
yeah
yeah we do
all right another topic I want to
mention which wasn't explicitly on the
agenda but since I'm up here I asked to
mention it a little bit on the next
slide some interoperability events that
have been going on around l4s we had our
first ietf l4s interop at ietf 114 in
Philadelphia I was pretty well attended
and got a lot of work done around
multiple implementations of l4s
congestion control and network
bottlenecks and congestion feedback bugs
were found bugs were fixed different
test cases will run
and uh after Philadelphia cable Labs
hosted another interop event at our
facility near Denver
again nicely attended and uh and and
those include
results from that and then currently
downstairs in the other Tower the main
the building we are running our second
ietf l4s interop
the link on the slide there is the
presentation that we did at the
conclusion of hackathon yesterday
afternoon but the testing still
continues some of it will will run
probably all week we've got two 5G
networks that are implementing l4s as
well as Wi-Fi gear and a fixed Network
emulator and then a number of different
endpoint implementations congestion
control implementations that are running
across those networks so
that's going on currently and after this
meeting down in the the room where the
hackathon was taking place there is a
happy hour please stop by you can see
the demos of the
real-time streaming media applications
that are running over l4s bottlenecks
some nice uh nice graphical demos for
that so please stop by with that and
then upcoming opportunity communities
cable apps is planning on hosting
another interop at our facility in
January end of January
the next ITF in Yokohama is a
possibility to host a third ietf interop
for l4s that will depend on interest and
availability and so if you're interested
in participating in that please let me
know
and I think that's it so our our
milestone for this is completion in July
2023 does that sound reasonable still
I
I wouldn't change it today
um but as we get closer to that date
that might be a good question to ask
whether we're far enough along in the
deployment to have further guidance to
add but we can always revise if it's
better Bob
are you I just wanted to
um clarify when Greg said it's in where
the hackathon was
um it's Admiral sweet which is the low
gram third floor right at the bottom of
the East Tower
yeah thank you and Bob will forgive you
if you're not joining my queue this time
[Laughter]
any other questions or comments
thank you for your talk
next topic will be the working Group
Transport drafts with MP dccp okay
um
no sorry yes please go ahead
oh I am majoring and I'm from xiaomi
located in Beijing here is our brief
introduction of the mptccp
interoperability test SBT
next
uh here is what we did we have ported
the mptcp to Android 13 based on Android
T version phones with 5.10 Kona world
right running and we verified the
policy and the interoperability of mptcp
OC Land one environment
here here is what we have done uh we
read the specification reported the
mptcp internal module and also the udccp
commanders and also we sold many
problems and finally we approved
performed as a high Prof interability
test next
uh before the test we made some
Gravitation
we actually follow the reference
implementation and we prepared
uh one mobile phone with dual WLAN
capability and we modify the kernel
with 5.101 version
and
thanks to dtz provided the server side
implementation why is there for virtual
machine and another is
one remote server located in Germany
uh
then we set up the
layer and the one test environment
of all the IQ addresses are listed here
uh especially especially for the one
environment we you we are using the
udccp header convention application
to to avoid the problems with middle
boxes between
uh China and Germany internet transfer
or the next one
uh
here are the functions
verified in the uh in our inability test
uh
we configure the
all necessary options
uh first one we we import the mptcp
capability capability on every physical
interfaces and also we enable the
transfer options we also configure the
routine rules and we set the translation
port
finally we
we perform the right test
the right side is the functions here
and the next page
uh
in the first step we verified the first
subflow handshake process and along with
the MP capable and the MP key functions
uh you can see from the
TCP dump and the Y shark uh
files here the next one
the next one is the second subflow
handshake and also the MP joint and MPH
Mac capabilities here
the next
[Music]
uh
the next day this is a
this is for the sequence and the rtt
measurement
the next
uh this is for the MP close function
verified
the next one please
uh this is for the priority the address
add function and also the confirm
function
the next one
this is a uh address remove remove
function and the fallback machine
uh functions
so next one
here I will plan to push the mptcp
further
uh right now we have test the basic
function and the next step we will
put the tomb prox
to Android kernel under deploy the
encapsulation framework to allow the
multi-pass transfer transport of any IP
traffic
uh
finally we will test the real-time
service
such as Skype uip sources
so the next one
uh here I will conclusion for the mptcp
interoperability test
uh the functions of mpdcp works well
from our opinion and
we actually
use different combinations of mptcp in
4.14 and 5 on 10 Linux reference
in meditation and
the reporting on the Android searching
also we
we run the test in both slide and one
environment
which proves the complaintenance and
maturity of anti-dccp draft 206
and
uh
its usage and the function operations
are very similar to the mptcp protocol
okay that's all
any questions
foreign
code is always very very good to see for
a new protocol so thank you very much
look looks like a solid piece of work
okay thank you
so on to Marcus I think
there we go
hi everyone Marcus from Dr Telecom
giving some overview on the multiples
dccp progress next slide please
yeah starting with the draft maturity
State how we as authors see it so it's
all already outlined in Philadelphia the
freeze feature state birds version four
so no further updates from our site
we're added to the draft and we mainly
focused on getting external reviewers to
providing us feedback that accumulated
in
the current version 6 of the draft I
will get more into detail on the next
slide remaining minor work we see at the
moment so there's
some feedback from uh see monophel in
writer
um and also some Ayana review
um here we still have to dig into and to
close all the existing issues in our
GitHub repository next slide please
yeah you see a number of changes since
last iitf uh where we presented version
five now we are at six as I outlined I
will not go in in all the details here
but just to give you a brief overview on
the on the number of issues we solved
together with the reviewers have in mind
all the issues we solved when accordance
with the with reviewers so they gave out
the okay
uh that we solved the issue in the draft
we had some editorial
issues we solved and all the other
things I really helped to
um
yeah all the other issues are mentioned
here
helps to give some clarity to the whole
to the whole draft and make it better
readable to externals not just to the
authors
a full change log is available did you
see it on the bottom right
so we maintained this with GitHub which
gives you a nice overview
yeah oh that doesn't look complete this
light some check marks are missing but
maybe I can outline it without having
all the symbols presented here
um so last time in Philadelphia
we mentioned that all the
functionalities and multipass options we
Define in the draft
in the in the left table were completed
and this time we focused on completing
all the things in the right table so we
can State implementation is completed
now we fixed the last things and
improved them mainly about multi-pass
confirm functionality which gives a
reliability to some of the multi-pass
options like the editors remove address
and the prior
we verify the fallback mechanisms also
together with xiaomi as you have seen in
the previous
a presentation and we implemented the
two different closing procedures based
on multi-path close and multi-pass Fast
close you also find here
um right to the table uh the pull
requests
in which we added those functionalities
to the public GitHub repository of our
Linux reference implementation
um yeah and with that we started the
interoperability test as Tommy has
outlined next slide please
Okay so
ending with a summary here
um yeah
we did together with some me some or not
some we did the interoperability test
which confirmed that multi-pass dccp as
it is specified so far works and
um all the different functionalities we
have specified
um worked with between two different
entities uh a server hosted by Deutsche
Telecom in in Germany and the UE a
smartphone implementation running in
China
they ported the multi-pass dccp to
Android 13.
um based on a 5.10 kernel
and they solved multiple issues compared
to the Linux reference implementation
they verified that the code matched the
mpdccp specification
and yeah last but not least as I already
said so we run the successful successful
interoperability test
um there's also or what supported us in
that was also a new Wireshark detector
um thanks to a PhD student from City
University London
who made this public available
and we improved this dissector also
during the hackathon on Saturday
so saying here the wire Factory sector
is available which is in line with the
mpdcp trust version 6.
yeah now coming to the interesting
questions or discussions probably
um you have maybe have also already seen
on the mailing list also thanks to Gary
um that we approach to
working group last call and there's also
a discussion to move
um the mpdczp draft from experimental
track to proposed standard so I'm
supported that let me go try to show the
slide Mark is meant to show I'm gonna
require a little bit of uh Meade Echo
magic okay
um
so there there are no further
remarks from my side um I think it would
be no good to get some some feedback on
this working group last call and propose
standard track question okay hang on a
minute okay right
yeah probably maybe
also there I just cannot get that slide
up on the screen sorry so I think the
first question I've got to the group is
not this question but first of all uh
could I have a show of hands for people
who have read
this or a
maybe the previous version so I want to
know how many people have been reading
this work as it's been developed and are
we going to use a tool to do this David
oh yeah you're showing the ticks okay
there's there's a few ticks here
um that's what you wanted to show isn't
it right okay uh I'm going I'm going to
try using the tool and then maybe as a
calibration device I'm going to try
using the room and people's real hands
and see if they cut if the results
calibrate
so can I use this tool here we go
and of course the next question will be
um
do you have input to help us work with
our ad to decide upon the appropriate um
position in the RFC series to publish
this so I'm going to ask people to come
to the mic to comment on that we've seen
some comments on the list
and
I will be the next question
do you want to try the test in the real
room or does that is that a sufficient
test David
we have 13 people who've read this I
think 13 I think over address people
who've read this read this is excellent
so uh
let's go ahead to the next one
okay so the next question is does
anybody want to provide any additional
comments on whether they think this
document should progress
to a working group last call as PS
rather than the current status which is
experimental so does anybody have any
comments that might help us make this
judgment for instance why wouldn't it be
a PS
PS here means standards track
does anyone think it should be EXP
okay um this is actually not the working
group's call but it's the ad working
with the chairs to decide but we need
input and Martin's the man who's going
to have to yeah ask questions I
definitely would like to add the input
um or rather have some input and I
wanted to wait for somebody but nobody
stood up so I'll talk some more
um uh
so I think Marcus was okay so number one
um
I'm always concerned about real world
deployment for this Beyond like proofs
of concept and so on uh I think there's
an excellent point that we also have an
MP quick thing going on and it makes
sense for that to align and I don't
think my co-ad oh my co-80 is here I
couldn't see him a second ago he and I
need to get together on this
um my original thinking when we started
all this multi-path work
was that a lot of the scheduling
problems were very researchy problems
and that what we were doing here was
creating lots of platforms for the
research community
to be able to run those experiments in a
way they can't necessarily do with mptcp
very well
um
I don't know that if in your particular
use case Marcus you think you have the
the scheduling problem solved
or
not but so you talk about multiple
scheduling
um yeah right yeah okay so
um
multiple scheduling I think it's it's
for all of the protocols which are
currently discussed in IDF mptcp MPD CCP
and multi-pass quick that is very
implementation specific and uh we just
provide the protocol with that from our
experience we more or less adopted the
scheduler already existing for the
multicast TCP implementation that was
quite simple because the multiple dccp
protocol as such provide the same
information to the schedulers at the
multi-pass TCP does and I assume uh that
it's also similar to multipass quick so
um yeah
at the end we had not to solve something
so we just adopted what what is what
already exists
yeah I think that's a reasonable
approach and and like I I do think this
work is certainly ready to progress as a
document um or certainly go to working
with last call it seems like we have
solid implementations and whatnot so
like I don't want to cast any shade on
that at all but I am I think when we put
out a document as proposed standard
that uh it kind of communicates to
non-experts that this is kind of
safe to use
um in a way that I don't know that the
multi-path community is I think there
are a lot of people who unfortunately
are not in this room to speak for
themselves in in the kind of the
research Community say this is the own
research problem like multi-pass stuff
in general
um
oh good there are lots of people now so
I'll sit down and be quiet
hang on a minute
you're not an accused you don't exist
Lars you're next
foreign
that was very harsh he does exist so
I've seen him standing in front of me
um large accurate so I haven't followed
the multi-path research space a while
ago so I might not be up to date on this
and then somebody please correct me so I
think the the scheduling problem is
still sort of hard
um and I don't have I haven't seen
any claims that somebody has a general
solution I know we have solutions that
work for certain kinds of path
combinations like you know Wi-Fi and
through G and so on
um but it's
you know it's an it's an efficiency
problem in the sense that if you have a
scheduler that isn't working very well
you don't get the throughput or the
latency you you might get with a better
one but it's not a safety concern
it it might generate a bit more traffic
because there might be some
retransmissions happening while the
scheduler is doing like stupid stuff
but it's not like driving us to
congestion collapse right so
from a safety perspective I think uh
this should be fine to go as proposed
but we still actually do need some
scheduler for more General multi-pass
scenarios which is the research question
thanks Lars I think we would have
serious concerns if the group said that
there were congestion control issues or
stability issues with this
um but that was a really useful input
would you like to come to the mic um
sorry sorry to make an advantage sorry
to make the examples
yeah I just saw a general question I
have not read this draft honestly but I
in now if you remember the mobile IP
work we did quite a bit of work on
multiple care of addresses multiple
tunnels and all of that there the
underlying tunnel is a GRE tunnel which
can GRS or IP but gr is now extended
over gr UDP so the question is two
questions I think what are the key
technical differences is that in the
scheduling the way we use both the links
that's question number one question
number two as you know in Mobile AP we
failed you know I think you know 3gb
system we had references but we didn't
have any deployments right overall we
spend a lot of time if you look at the
mobile AP community
but we didn't find any traction so
what's the where is it heading how do
you see who is going to deploy this I
think the previous reviewer commenter
had the same question are the same
comment
so the the acoustic is quite bad here so
I'm not sure if I've really got here two
two questions but maybe I try to
rephrase it though the first question
was about how the encapsulation works
yeah I think I'm trying to compare it
with the mobile AP system where
where we support multipath
essentially you know you can a mobile
node can establish
two tunnels from two different access
Technologies
right now I have the option to do flow
level distribution or a packet level
distribution so
I hope I get your question right but
first of all it's required that
multiplies dccp is implemented in both
endpoints
and then the exit and then we take the
multiple axis which are available to to
run the multiples dctp protocol across
it
um the relevance of a mobile system or
5G system I don't understand to be
honest
okay so you may want to look at some of
the work that happened in the mobile AP
working groups
Mobility yeah
um
so we think with the multipass gcp we
support the mobility aspect
so we don't see any issue with that but
we don't follow this
okay maybe I'll take it off let's take
it off yeah because
so I just wanted to respond to Lars but
I was sure to get in the queue
um so I I I I do feel pretty comfortable
this is not going to lead to the
collapse of the internet
um under any circumstances but we also
don't have a standards track approach to
multi-path congestion control to address
shared bottlenecks and the like so I do
have some concerns about fairness issues
um which should not necessarily block
everything but um there's that and then
people will generally adopt this to
improve their performance because I
think intuitively it makes sense
uh you know multiple house will improve
performance and if the if like the fine
print is that if you really don't know
what you're doing
um with the scheduling like you may not
get better performance or get much worse
performance that strikes abusing may be
not something to stamp with proposed
state and it applies to all multipasses
not a specific critique of mpdccp
um uh like maybe that's not something to
stand put standards track at this point
like use with care use the feeling if
you know what you're doing if you're
networking professional that's to me
that's experimental RSC but I mean you
obviously know a lot about RC states too
so like I'm we can talk about this and
we're going to talk offline tonight
anyway so we can go but I just wanted to
respond for the good of the uh community
yeah that's actually a good point right
so so because we actually did never
publish a couple of congestion control
so so this is the old original
um you know um what's the guy's name
from Cambridge
now Frank Kelly did the math and and
custom and Mark Hamley did the
implementation right which is sort of
this the couple contesting control stuff
that came with part of the original
Damon right sorry costing him later
um
the couple connection control has sort
of this property that is probably uh
safe in the sense that you don't inject
more traffic into the network than a
single flow would and that might be
actually something that we could pick up
um as a baseline congestion controller
because it's mathematically proven that
it's you know pretty good and then you
could normatively depend on it and if
people wanted to do different things
then they could but
yeah good point right um we would have a
before standard
um without a congestion controller which
we can recommend which feels sort of
dissatisfying so I don't want to derail
the discussion but I think it's sort of
we should probably figure out
if this is if we feel comfortable doing
that
um
what are you using for congestion
control at the moment the story what are
you using for congestion control at the
moment
um we use a PBR implementation
are you coupling the bbrs or are they
independent okay so you are injecting
two or multiple but but we see no issues
with adopting the uh couple congestion
code control which was specified for
multiple TCP for example so that this
could happen
right so that would be sort of I think
the way but that was was that
experimental informational I can't
remember it was not standards track
and you know what you do in your
implementation is obviously separate
from what you would recommend in a
specification
um and if we could point to the coupled
in the specification that would be
a solution at least we have a remark in
our draft that we mentioned that couple
combustion control is available and and
can be used but my question is do we
really need the work to adopt to our
prototype coupled congestion control or
can we take the evidence from the
multi-pass TCP that it works so for your
code right we're not standardizing the
code we're standardizing works exactly
and so the words would need to explain
how you do it
because you know otherwise everybody
needs to figure this out by themselves
and that sort of also ends with
dissatisfying
do you have words about bbr at the
moment in the document or
I struggle now a little bit because I
know that there are rfcs for for the
couple congression control for Lira at
least I think
um and that we mentioned in the in our
craft that this can be used
but do you say how to use it anyway
maybe we're going too deep at nearest
and yeah so
um
yes so thank you for this I mean I think
this is what we can investigate offline
I just want to bring the big issues out
um and and ask for Community you know
reaction to them if I'm completely crazy
about these concerns thanks yeah this is
this discussion is really helpful Meera
is still in line if you wish to say
something and I think the coupled
congestion control for multi-path
transports was published as exp in 6356.
right and it's basically just um
explaining how to cut the congestion
control without kind of like you could
apply different congestion controls to
it and I think it only applies Reno but
anyway
um that's not what my comment was
um I'm I'm usually like we have the
discussion very often that the transport
area has been very conservative about
going for experimental force and like
I'm actually been arguing many times
that we should more often go for
proposed standard but I'm actually a
little bit uneasy about this one because
it's a quite big change like multi
multi-pass TCP was experimental at the
beginning as well and then we got a lot
of implementation experience and the one
advantage we have here is that you can
actually borrow from that experience and
you've taken over many mechanisms
directly from multipass um TCP but you
still had to add a lot of extra stuff to
dccp anything about protection
reordering and so on so there's there's
a lot of stuff that I think is is an
addition so this is for me not a small
change
and so for such a change I would like I
would like to have like a slightly
higher barrier and it's great that you
now have like a second implementation
there but porting a Linux implementation
to Android is kind of I'm not sure if
that actually comes as an independent
implementation like I would I would be
much happier if somebody would actually
from the draft
not from your code but from the draft be
able to produce an independent
implementation for example
okay the last point I understood uh yeah
I'll clarify that last Point mirror is
actually a requirement for progression
on the standards track rather than to
propose standard but it's a way of
judging maturity for sure and I think
what we're asking here is what's the
maturity of this spec are the risks
um if you want to think wider are the
same risks in mptcp are the same risks
in mp quick please talk to either the
chairs or the ad but please do it
quickly rapidly because we will have to
make some sort of determination
and I don't think we can say more at
this time and we won't we won't make a
decision until we're ready however we
can ask about working group last call
and I'd just like to ask how many people
in the room would be happy to review
this document if it were submitted to a
working group last call
um
maybe I could try the tool again if you
like there you go
would you be happy to review the next
version and say no if you don't think
this is anywhere near ready or say yes
if you'd be happy to review it and then
you can just make your own comments
well we we see people if you're review
offering to review we saw 14 people say
they'd read this or a recent version
we've heard some discussion at the mic
you already have a lot of feedback we
can't give you the answers to your
question but we'll work on them with our
ad and then provide feedback to the list
thank you very much Marcus thank you
foreign
CTP
we're currently running roughly two
agenda times so we're good we're going
to talk about sctp
oh you've got the analysis yeah yep so
this is about some recent issues or
opportunities found in sdp root
recently is a joint work with minus
vestalon and Claudio perfori
um we're not talking about history I
will not talk about to solve the
problems that would be in other
presentations
so the security requirement requirement
properties for security protocols or
systems have increased incredibly since
sadp what was was written for the use
and for the use cases there uh modern
systems typically require strong
confidentiality strong Integrity strong
replay protection and high availability
at least these are the things that 5G
require for the the use cases it has for
dtls over satp and with strong it was
meant that it should be computationally
infeasible as hard as breaking is
data here refers to has to do with
external user messages not internal
things like scdp chunks availability is
a bit harder to Define but given an
attacker should not be I mean easy than
expected to affect the availability like
Center a single packet and tearing down
their Association Next slide
uh so these are the issues we have found
uh as satp would use this um the keys
are not directional you can
reflect uh authenticated chunks for
example data sets
and to do this and you need to be in on
path attacker with read capabilities you
don't need to have right capabilities
for the reflected chunks to be accepted
you need to match t7 stream identifier
and stream sequence number stream
identifier is probably quite easy
if you have very large messages in the
worst case then the stream sequence
number wouldn't change at all and the
thing you need to what match is TSM so
after 0 to 2 to the power of 31 chunks
average total power of 30 in the worst
case it's trivial to do this
um
and what's happened is that you might
reflect the whole message you might
reflect part of the message corrupt the
use message or it might be some error
leading to a termination of the
association
uh uh next
uh then as the replay protection
duplication relies on TSN and TSN is
only has 2 to the power of 32 values uh
when this wraps of the if you have a
very long Association then you can do
replay of data what you have to match is
the same as in the reflection attack
still worst use case is worst case is
that you have very large messages then
they only then you just have to wait and
it's trivial of the two to 32 messages
uh this is very similar to the other the
reflection is a little bit easier to do
uh than the replay the break slightly
different properties
um next
slide uh three more issues should three
is a very theoretical issue as as and
all of these are analysis of the
specifications not any implementation
this is a theoretical issue the
specification allows you to use the same
key with different algorithms and this
is typically should not not or must not
in modern RBC but I don't see any
practical problems with the current
algorithms uh number four is reflection
but of authenticated control chunks
instead of data
and this is easier because you don't
have to match a TSM uh for example the
error message can be trivially reflected
back to the sender
if you reflect the sac control chunk
this might or would or might lead to
packet loss missing data any consistent
State probably tearing down the
association at some point and then
heartbeat act might also be an attack
availability if you reflect that uh so
these four is different and another this
is an attack on availability only not on
integrity and so on uh and five is that
you can do replay of control chunks
um very similar analysis
um probably worse with reflected stuff
like ever like
this is what the different overseas and
drops says about what they offer
uh
uh what is clear is that 3dp when
reading when specifying this thought
that they basically got dtls same
property as dtls over UDP they
definitely thought they got replay
protection for example
in the last version of satp over details
over satp because five we have made a
very thorough list of exact properties
that are provided I think that's a
general recommendation it should be easy
to see what is provided and what is not
provided even if you're not an expert in
sctp next
uh yeah and this is analysis of the what
is broken
um
satp was all definitely does not offer
shank origin authentication for example
uh like it it promises uh then it all
the other most other things whether it
promises or not otherwise you can say it
doesn't offer them or it offer them in a
weak way
detail RFC 6083
is a better dtls uses directional keys
and it uses single Mac to use the
message so you don't break integrity and
you don't weaken confidentiality
these issues had a worse effect on
details over satp piece in the version 4
because it uses several records per user
message in zero five
issue one to four should be sold as but
in general all the attacks on the
availability is probably remaining this
is also a bit harder to analyze a lot of
the handling is implementation specific
and not really mandated by the
specifications
yeah
okay Michael
Jackson can you go back to the the list
of issues
right at the beginning which which side
we reactors
come on we can start with that we know
the next one
yeah so the first one the reflect the
reflection stuff that is an issue in
HTTP auth we we missed putting in a
directional specific information in the
in the computation however
um for dtls over HTTP that shouldn't be
an issue because the dtls keys are
directional specific so in attacker
should not be able to
in to reflect user data and it's being
delivered so that's not an issue I think
for details over HTTP yeah it could be
an availability issue I'm asking about
inserting data which looks like it's
coming from the peer and it's not and
that is not working it would not be
accepted exactly the next slide
which is the replay stuff and the replay
stuff sap authentication does not
provide any better replay protection as
the base protocol does that's stated in
the document and dtls does this by doing
renegotiations at least in the the old
one where dtls 1.0 was used and you
could do renegotiations that's the whole
reason why we did add
support for renegotiation and it is a
dance with sequence numbers and and kind
of stuff but we do not have text in
there when you do this because you can
do this because sequence numbers are
wrapping you can do this because you're
using an extension at that point or
Define we just didn't specify that next
slide
the third one is something we just
didn't know
so and yeah it's just there I don't know
if it's usable but we just didn't know
um four and five is this I don't think
you can do anything except availability
things
however and it's in my view an attacker
which can take a packet
and uh send it in in in a wrong in the
other direction might also be able to
just drop packets so it's your host then
anyway at least this was
at the point of time we did satp auth
there was not
a huge difference between an attacker
who could read packets and who could
send packets compared to one who can
take out packets
but that might have changed I don't know
but availability might be an issue yes
but can be in other ways
and most of the stuff we can fix in a
simple way which I will cover in the
next you'll be up to next I wanted to
get in here more as individual make one
quick comment the word replay is being
tossed around a little bit cavalierly
insecurity replay attacks usually refer
to tax where the attacker can replay the
attacking data at the time and place of
her choosing these replay attacks here
they're they are replay attack they are
much more specific because they the
replay can only happen exactly when the
when the sequence number rolls over and
comes back around so it's much more
limited than we usually see for replay
attack and security context it is
nonetheless uh an actual attack it's a
nice piece analysis thank you thank you
yeah I just wanted to briefly say thank
you for breaking our stuff
[Laughter]
valuable things that that we can hear is
that our security has got problems and I
look forward to the revisions that will
come from this it's a huge huge
contribution thank you
oh okay and I think Now for Something
Completely Different
we have Michael do we find it it's this
one right yes
so we're on sttp security this time
Michael yeah um I just forgot that yeah
thank you for the analysis so it's it's
uh it wasn't up to
whatever our our view that we should
need to put in some directional stuff
because when we did satp authentication
we did it
in the framework of
protecting certain control chunks which
we didn't even foresee that they will
see there will be
a lot of them
okay so what's I'm talking about a Biz
document
um
um I started on working on this this
document way before not way before but
before
um I got aware of the security
um issues so
um
years ago there was a document sap auth
based someone from submitted by someone
I don't know
um basically covering some
textual improvements where some of the
wording was not clear enough for the
author and he should and he wanted to
improve that so that's definitely
something one should we should we we we
would include
um the motivation of this was based on
the discussion
um I had with the authors of the dtls
document
basically
um the mandatory to implement algorithm
is Shao one hmaker using Shawan and
there is the wish to
um have other ones deal with this stuff
uh and in particular so defined are
actually two so the dtls over HTTP
wanted to use uh the other one and make
sure from the API perspective that they
can do this so this is also something
um we would
um uh add there that you have a way to
control this and I think to cover most
of the stuff uh John has brought up is
one is to include a direction specific
data in the computation of the of the
mac and basically this can be
um this is part numbers and the
verification tag from the from the
common header so this is not equal and
and you can just do that and this third
theoretical one I think could be solved
by
um doing a key derivation
um
a directional specific one
um and and then algorithm specific one
so the status of the document is
um
I submitted the zero zero version as
similar as possible to the existing RFC
um going through formatting it as an
internet draft but using the same XML
sources I got from the RFC editor I
updated it to XML V3 because it was
written earlier and I did some
wordsmithing and updating the reference
about the old ionic in considerations
are there no technical content has been
changed because next slide
um
is that one yeah because
um the question is whether this should
be adopted as a working group item and
if yes then it might be better to to
change to a working group document and
then do any substantial changes there so
you can easily see them in the issue in
the data tracker there
of course when we do this work any
additional input will be incorporated
but you see the scope of the the changes
we wanted to make also Magnus I think
brought up going away from the hmac
staff generalizing to a Mac allowing
more algorithms
that's it for my side
questions
but actually not a question I think it's
we need to do do something with sap auth
it's it needs to be improved here so
it's just I mean we need to fix the
issues brought up by John yeah
and I guess the polls giving you the
answers about working group adoption
and people haven't yet read it okay
um and given the motivational speech is
going on today it may be a good thing to
read so we will we will not make any
determination about the working group
adoption at this moment please read this
okay
thank you
okay next
now for something not completely
different
they are different
not completely though no
so um my name is Westland talk about the
details over satp uh
so the latest version is o5
um talk a little bit status we have
three issues here on the list uh and a
little bit dealing with those what you
just talked about uh so but let's take
the next slide
so
um
the current status is where we've been
working through with Martin Thompson's
review we mostly addressed the issues
there
uh next slide is it yeah um
there are a few that's dependent on the
issues uh especially on the detailers
versioning Etc which will wait what to
do resolve before going ahead and do
those text changes
um but yeah I think a big big relation
is to regards to this SD of security
issues so but uh let's go forward to
that issue then
so uh detail is over HTTP in this
version
has this very higher than a dependency
on SD Western 683 has because it's what
ensures that the detailers record as a
part of the user message protected user
message fragments are in the right order
therefore any replays Etc is really bad
for us because that means that you could
actually affect the resulting message
message Integrity if you actually get
through a data record
that's verifies so a straight Replay
that actually fits correctly could mean
that you actually get corrupted message
through that would be really bad there
are mitigations here and I think we
could go on to that next slide
um
for the reflection attacks Etc uh and
for the reflection attacks
we could I mean fix the sap auth
that takes care of this would fix that
and I think uh re-keying is is
a requirement from detailer so sdp is a
fairly straightforward making it very
clear that you need to retire the any
sap auth Keys before you wrapped so
um
the fact that this is that I'm going to
have implementation impact on sdb worth
and the stack which means that some of
our baselines they go into this is
affected but I think it's the other
question going forward here is is if
these mitigations are sufficient
implementable to reaching those security
goals we see as being sufficient for for
example 3D PPS and 5D deployments there
in very long in sessions uh so go to
next slide
um I really would like to encourage
people to guess about these two I'll
have some insight and need for this to
actually do a security analysis in terms
of what what their stands are
um the other aspect we see is that the
details of sdp is complex there's a lot
of corner cases Etc to avoid the CTP
implementation impact
we have some ideas how we could actually
do detail as more in satp
which would be simpler enable a less
complex detail less
details implementation requirements will
be simple Etc and and we are actually
proposing here to actually
uh that we would actually quote write an
individual draft for an alternative to
just present as as we will have a delay
at this stage until satp watch is fixed
if you stay on the current path
and and that might be that that
alternative path is is equally fast or
faster to basically it's as fast as to
complete and provides Better Properties
but uh you know we want to investigate
that a bit
um
so um next slide
so if anyone has any comments about the
sap host aspects it's now is a good time
the next issue we have is is about which
detailers Stacks we should support
ing only detail as 1.3 would make our
life easier from a spec perspective it
will also improve I think
the potential for an interoperability
failure if one side supports only
details 1.3 and the other only 1.2
um so
um
but what was raised in the discussion on
the main list when I brought this up
earlier was that yeah the availability
detail is 1.3 Stacks is currently not
great
it is much more limited details 1.2
we know that false SSL is in beta it's
announced I talked to
Summit Mozilla and yeah the NSS is
coming there but they will not have
connection ID
and then important aspects of this is
that we did details over STP that's
currently in the draft
we do have requirements on connection
IDs
turning off replay and we need
large record sizes and or
you couldn't need to support negotiation
to smaller maximum record size for
detailers these are feature we are kind
of you need to have for implementation
to work so
um so
Michael
a question comment
uh
yeah I have a question
um is it relevant what open source
implementation open source details
implementations
provide since there are API issues so
I mean I I are the iprs outside of
what you need in a dtls implementation
and
no I think it's uh so I I
let's see how I should answer that
question uh
I think it brought talk about open
source details implementation here is
about
uh
if how you
get an implementation of details of satp
in place and and that
uh I mean details taxes is not trivial
there's some lead time if you would if
you would go order one and want to have
it tested secure Etc it's going to take
quite a while and these extra features
you're probably gonna have to order
that's that's I think is the concern
here
uh but my point was can I use for so can
I use an open source
details implementation to implement
details over scdp since it has some
some patents part of that is patent
protected so I'm I'm just not sure what
can I
what why okay so if if the IPR claims we
have for example have is not covering
details as it is I mean if it's okay I'm
just asking can I yeah can I suggest
that this uh uh discussion be taken
offline the usability of Open Source
libraries in non-open Source has a long
track record but what you can do depends
on the exact licensing condition of the
specific Library which is not a real
good topic to discuss here I was just
asking because both SSL is given there
so it's um I I said I think I think
you've opened up a rat hole um I suggest
you find legal counsel to to work
through the license details yeah
yeah now yeah yes I mean my point to
bring this up we're just saying what's
what's looks appears to be the current
situation of public known
implementations that's the only thing I
wanted to State here
so and next next slides uh
ah okay but is there anyone having any
more input I mean otherwise what was
raised on the list was saying uh no we
don't want to go to 1.3 and I guess if
no one has more input that might be
where we'll be stuck here Martin
now
uh yeah Martin dude Google um no hats uh
like the future's bigger than the past
if if this is a much shorter document
and you're not like desperate to ship it
tomorrow
as long as we feel reasonably confident
that
dtls13 is on road maps of major
implementations
um you know if we could eliminate a lot
of stuff like that's good
so yeah and I think it's especially
dependent on if we can take this
alternative road that might reduce this
list of features needed
which makes it even easier um so I think
yeah I've it might be just best to delay
this question a bit and see where how
long it takes to fix the rest of the
aspects here
um
so uh on this last issue there's one
important aspect has to do with uh some
Marty brought this up and
background here is really that yeah you
have those things that are detailed as
message between the stacks between the
endpoints the handshake the errors and
errors or close notify which is
terminated
um
we have 63 did stream zero in order
delivery of these we changed this to any
stream Etc what Martin wrote up was
saying well it might be hard to optimize
this to ensure that you send the records
to the fast path and only take these
messages to your slower path
um so next slide
uh
one interesting question in this is the
identification of these messages
and that's actually I want to hopefully
get some feedback on that eventually
It's like because 1.3 Heights is what
they are the content type is internal
it's encrypted and
Etc so the stack when it's processed you
will know if it was oh this is a
allergic message
um not so
but if you can actually be able to sort
this out
before you send them to the details
implementation
we need to have an identifier on them
being details message already being
details records we protected user
messages
and and that ends up in a question is we
are we okay to expose this it leads to I
think some potentials for trying to
Target these measures specifically in a
low volume or something to to affect the
session affecting availability
I would say here and not really other
things
so and but one way of identifying was to
do stick your ppid on this particular
message that's headed for the the end
stack not records but um if someone has
an input on this it would be great
so
um yeah come talk to me or send an email
or whatever
um the timeline of this will be delayed
I was hoping that we would actually have
a chance of meeting the March deadline
it doesn't look feasible now we need to
fix this to be worth fixed or not use
another version alternate detailer
solution
um
but I hope that we will be able to move
forward in reasonable Pace here and we
do try to update the drafts uh in not
two extents but yeah and I think we
might have to notify 3D people about
these delays and the Securities should
be listed both here so they are aware of
it because
so
so therefore I would like to send an
Ellis from this group to
so
yeah
um
any questions
okay thank you clearly we need to gather
some momentum around the sctp and the
authentication problems
text and new techniques so we'll look
forward to inputs on that
we have next
this okay uh
I'm going to cut the announcements about
Joe touche's UDP options and the related
DPL pmtud for UDP options uh we're
awaiting a revised ID from Joe touch
which we intend to work in group last
call
so what
if you're interested in an update that's
the situation revised ID expected
shortly after this ITF so we'll move
straight on to Michael Tucson on scdp
UDP this is the individual draft go
ahead Michael yeah this is an individual
draft on next slide and
um it basically
um
deals with satp over UDP encapsulation
so this is one of the possible ways to
transfer sap over UDP through Legacy
nuts and
[Music]
um
there's an RFC for it it's 69.51 it does
not describe how to handle
um in its packets containing an inner
chunk because you have no verification
tag you have no way to verify that this
packet is really coming from your peers
so is that it has an impact on whether
you should update your port numbers or
not and
um this issue is covered in the draft
given there and uh I think when Magnus
was already it was still
transport ID
we asked how to progress and the
argument was well maybe you just do a
business document instead of having two
small documents describing one thing
and I asked um Martin got the same
response so this is basically
um uh
the the the the first
document trying to join these both next
slide
um and I did what I did with the other
documents submit zero zero as the
original RFC changed the XML V3 and do
some updates of the documents which were
outdated
um
there are two implementations oh there
are two open source implementations in
corner sticks right now which is FreeBSD
and Linux and both are covered on
the RFC and the draft so both are
um
doing the right thing
um but it's not documented in a single
document right now in the idea is to
um
get this cleaned up
which is I think the next slide right
yep
and of course we would incorporate any
additional feedback coming up through
any kind of discussion
could ask the first question
yeah the question is
is the work can go better so at what
point is if the working group is not
adopting it it doesn't make sense to
progress the document so
it's an offer
foreign
do you think this has to be done by
whenever there's time and resources sure
so there I mean the implementations are
there the draft describing the issue is
there I can keep it updated it's just
that
um
if if you're just looking based on the
experience from the Linux people they
they find the RFC but they don't find
the draft describing what they also have
to do so
that's it
okay any questions from anyone else I
would say less pressure than Earth
I I'd encourage feedback on this one um
it's something we've talked about a
number of times please read it please
progress it please come and present
again and let's ask those questions when
we got more people reading this because
I I think it's something that should be
of interest to this group given the
previous work okay
uh Michael not so fast
okay so this is a document about
um zero checksum next slide
um SUV uses as a checksum CSC 32c which
is a 32-bit checksum which needs some
CPU Cycles to be computed and there are
use cases which is webrtc in particular
where you run HTTP over dtls so you have
a much better protection of your packet
from your lower layer than you get from
your CRC so
um and there are people using webrtc on
CPU constrained devices
which just don't compute the CRC on the
receive side because they can do this
without breaking interoperability but
they can do it they can't do it on the
sender side so the idea is to add to the
handshake a parameter stating I'm
willing to accept zero as a check sum
and then you can do this in the
handshake you can do it backwards
compatible and then you don't have to
compute the checksums anymore when you
do the data transfer
there are co-authors from Google trying
willing to implement this into the
what's the name Google webrtc
implementation used in Chrome there is
a quarter from Mozilla I'm willing to
integrate this into
um the
um
Firefox browser and
so there is there is support from
implementers uh next slide
[Music]
um
and we have support in Wireshark we have
support and packet tool for doing tests
um I'm working on a
um on an implementation
um and it's a very simple document but
we need this document to get the
assignment of this parameter so it's
specification required
that's why it's here and that is a
document I would say which is very
simple
could be progressed very fast and people
would like to deploy this
so same question as again
and we would integrate I mean we would
integrate comments and we got comments
from gory
from Mike and from Ayana basically about
we know we normally do in the INX
section write the specific number
so question two the document author do
you want me to ask who's Reddit or do
you want to give them a time to chew it
over and get a better answer
up to you
I guess we get the same answer yeah all
right okay let's go um here we go who's
who has read this document
um coming in
no who has
zero
I'll come to the mic if you have any
question
you do exist
we have
a poll going on on questions
concurrently a higher last record so for
specimens for specification required you
actually don't need an RFC
you need a stable specification that's
around
right but it doesn't need to be done in
a working group just saying
and the stable specification is
a draft which has not changed any time
or something that the uh Ayana will
accept when they get the request
there should be a expert reviewer which
might be even you
I'm just pointing it out right so it's
specification required is not RFC
required
um and and so there is the option
right I'm going to ask an additional
question
um Lars is correct
um but let's ask this question
um who thinks this is a useful piece of
work which is abbreviating wrk to doing
this working group
for the next group
you for fun in the question to try and
stimulate a response at this moment
because people might think this is a
useful thing to do here even though
um they haven't read it because it's
pretty clear what it's meant to do and I
will keep talking I'll come to the mic
ask any questions because we're seeing a
response in the chat and we have Mike
and Martin
uh very quickly if you have
specification required it could be
published as a uh outside the working
group uh I suppose is an option
thank you yeah possible yeah Martin Duke
Google
um
you know I asked the question about SCP
working group a couple months ago and
you told me there was no need now we
have five drafts up for adoption
um
like so yeah I to be clear I've read
zero of these drafts but I think the
presentations have made a pretty
convincing case for all of them you know
addressed at some point and I I guess
the real question is working group
bandwidth for the from the chairs like
how many of these can we swallow at once
um and do we need to like have some do
we need this set up very quick working
group to clear through this backlog if
these things are Urgent or not
um okay we we will triage that question
because we also see the same Community
uh making the responses for each of
these drafts and we will check the work
Cycles Etc yeah this particular draft is
is simple
an additional comment yeah sort of I
mean I got flashbacks to win Magnus and
I were transporting these and we talked
about Dynasty people working group and
the reason we didn't at the time was
that we felt that the sdb community was
too small and it did it wouldn't get
enough review and that might as well
might have all changed but it doesn't
quite appear that way and so it's
probably the best home is unfortunately
still here
we will look at that part of the problem
space uh the answer to my poll is
clearly people think this is a useful
piece of work to do in this working
group and so I'd encourage you to keep
revising and come for an adoption call
in the future okay
right uh
did you want to say something
I guess I need to pull my and to get
vigorous about the discussion about once
uh just ensuring that I I think this
document makes sense in the context this
it just needs to be very clear on on its
very limited applicability or is saying
the requirement that I think it's
decently clear already so it's not a
problem but uh yeah so yeah because
running without checksums verifying
ports Etc over the internet and having
no additional mechanisms would be a bad
idea
from my perspective exactly the ietf has
been through this process in a much more
torturous way and I think we can make
good recommendations on the
applicability for this
and we should keep moving because we are
a little time left but we have a couple
of talks so we should is Nicholas online
she is Nicholas your slide deck is ready
please present
can you hear me
yes please go ahead thank you so next
slide please
uh so this draft is uh activities you
have been presenting in ITF uh in
different working groups and in
particular in a quick working group The
Main Idea here on this description is
so these first slides are how to quickly
catch up with the activity about
catching up and on the boundaries so in
the satellite industry there are some
cases where it takes a lot of time for
the condition control to quickly ramp up
to the high bdb that is available so
this is an experiment we have been we
have done where we have been downloading
and made with quick and we could have
seen that basically on red and the
bottom right part of the slide it took a
while for quick to actually converge to
what was the bandwidth uh the bottleneck
that I read
um so we have been thinking that storing
the idea of knowing what was the best
characteristics uh and using it to New
connections could be very interesting
um
the thing is you should not do that uh
without any care so you have to be
careful about how to do that and and
stop doing it if you find that anything
has changed in network
um next slide please
so we have been proposing different type
of uh documents to cover this issue uh
in the last summer we there had been a
adoption core in the Creek Coffee group
for two drafts so basically the first
one is careful regime is how you can
store computed constant control
parameters
um
to actually modify the Construction
Control behavior of subsequent
connections let's say and the first
connection I understood I was using a
satellite link and on the next
connection to the same peer I just want
to use and
previously computed control parameters
um we also had another draft which was a
specific implementation of that issue so
we have basically the bdb frame
extension for quick that has been
implemented in Pico quick and tested
over a real satellite Networks
this is how to store and exchange the
completed values uh between peers
so we have been populating that to Quick
working group and
um
basically the discussion the conclusion
of the a different call was that
supportment space is more broadly to do
with consistent control and not really
quick specific
um indeed uh we need to must we this
solution must to effectively share the
capacity with all the transports and
um maybe there is a way to do that with
all the transports so that's why we are
here and to see if there are any
discussions here that are related to and
relevant for the tsv WG
um basically this what are the
Construction Control items that we think
could be interesting for the group
um so if we assume that we have had a
first connection that I finished and the
information has been stored
um
we think a question an open question
that we have is
um what what event information you
you can obtain to change that the path
has not changed that much so we're
seeing that for example if you lose back
if you lose packets after sending the
first ADW uh there should be some
problem in the network so you may not uh
resume to the previous construction
parameters you can use a minimum entity
values you can also use the interpack
enter packets time the interpacking time
on other activities we have measured
that this metric was very useful to
detect conception in the network
so we think there is this discussion
here uh we have discussed some
algorithms in the draft that we have
been we have posted recently
um then when you know that the path has
been checked how do you carefully jump
uh you may not want to use to go
directly to what was the previously
measured bandwidth so you may want to be
careful in that and some sort of
specific slow sort algorithm
um let's say uh you just did the jump
how did you react if you see any
Collision
um in the network
and also Implement when Christiano
implemented that in uh Pico quick we saw
that there are some aspects that are
very specific on the construction
control that you have been using if you
use cubic or Reno it's different
um you may have I start or I start plus
plus uh making your Construction Control
going out of the slow starts so you this
is something that we think is very
interesting to discuss and these items
are currently discussed in the in the
current version of the draft uh next
slide please
that's what I'm saying that are related
to transports but not maybe third
relevant 40s vwg
um it's basically how do the clean tasks
for this jump because in the quick
implementation we have been using the
Sierra TT and the TLs certificate
signaling or we at least we use a
specific frame that is protected by TLs
but the problem is that when you use
um you may you may end up being very
specific on
both Construction Control and the series
visions that you have you are using
basically to know what do you send and
when do you send it and how protected
this information is
and also another aspect is really the
real system performances of that
and that is not covered in the draft for
the moment but in the end
um
we have been pushing out for this
working quick cooking group we've been
said that maybe this should be
addressed with a more wider view so we
were wondering if there is any interest
in the csgwg to is there any appetite
for this work and if you would want to
to join us as we seek to define the
appropriate details of such solution
thank you Nicholas any questions to
Nicholas
okay we'll take peers you have peers
please come to the mic
uh hi yeah um I was just wondering
uh this has been going this has been
used
um by TCP in um Linux kernel for some
time like TCP metrics or whether you've
looked at the uh how that works
um with in comparison to the approaches
you've been considering because it
caches like a sea wind rtt
and then it obviously
um reuses those for
the different congestion control
algorithms that are kicking off
yeah um so these thank you we there we
have been looking at that uh and also we
wanted to have this kind of TCP metrics
save for quick and in a way that is
interoperable in a way that the client
can participate in the decision on
whether this Matrix is used or not
okay yeah so I guess it was just useful
to look at how that that's been working
to inform
how you might kind of start do the same
thing it obviously works reasonably well
yeah
indeed
so they have timeouts and stuff like
that in the in the TCP metrics
um so they they don't last forever and I
don't know I'm not quite sure about the
some algorithms around that but anyway
okay that's good you're looking at it
Pierce could you send a email to the
list please can I add an email to the
list with what you just said that would
be so helpful okay yeah I think I did
very briefly I think it was mentioned on
the Quick List
and I mentioned it yeah but then it kind
of went over here so then okay I can do
that yeah and that'll be so helpful and
while we're talking about where it might
be going uh I think it's the queue for
Martin to come to the mic for one minute
yeah uh I just want to announce to
people uh many of you probably remember
from tsv area 114 a discussion about now
could you ask control working group
possibility
um that chartering work is still going
along in the background and for those of
you who might be interested it will be a
side meeting at 5 p.m on Thursday uh
please come by if this is up your alley
thank you
so thank you Nicholas as a chair and we
will encourage discussion of that item
on the list I think we've had feedback
for that particular document in various
places in the ietf so I'd encourage you
to carry on working on it and we will
try and find a home working with our ID
obviously Thursday is an interestingly
to attend if you possibly can and I'll
take my mask off to stand here to put
yet another flavor on the whole story
um which is a draft that I produced a
little while ago which may or may not be
related to all the story so next slide
please
um okay this slide kind of captures what
I was trying to do the ITF has said
about much about congestion control in
the past much of it has prevented a
meltdown congestion collapse on
starvation of the internet
does Our advice still apply hmm we
should perhaps check this there's more
than 40 references which are informative
on this and about 10 which are normative
descriptions of congestion control
things you need to do next
in 2019 and I decided to write a
four-page document on the core things
that would encourage a cc to play well
what happens if you make a new
congestion controller what would you be
needed and next
it took more than four pages next
so um I wrote a draft I presented in
Singapore you might go what happened
well what happened is we failed to meet
as a community face to face and this
actually is more I think of a design
team type activity than it is of a
design activity so I wanted to resurrect
it now we are starting to meet face to
face and I would encourage you to come
around talk about whether the ITF has
made the right recommendations in the
BCP series for its congestion control
and maybe we can add another RFC or
update one or maybe we'll just conclude
with a bit of guidance this is actually
okay I don't have an opinion but I've
tried to write a draft and this is the
draft story and we're now at draft seven
please go quickly next please
um there's a principles of congestion
control and the key thing that I'm
motivating is that things have changed
we absolutely must be preventing
persistent congestion that's things like
starvation congestion collapse and lots
of other horrible things which would
result out of work
but we I also have to react to incipient
congestion by adjusting the rate of
particular flaws to nicely play with one
another and I think these exist at
different levels of importance and we've
kind of recognized that over the years
but it's not really reflecting the RFC
series to the same extent so I've tried
to group the recommendations on these
two topics separately next slide
um yeah I rewrote um I changed a lot and
it's like
um there's a table of contents just to
encourage you it's not actually as long
as it looks because some of this is um
motherhood and apple pie and some of it
is the new stuff well the new stuff just
grouping the old stuff so actually it's
an easy read so please read it next
slide
and is anyone willing to play with me on
trying to get this right and that's the
reason for standing here
um I've had one or two offers at this
meeting of people who've worked in
congestion control previously and would
be really great people to have on my
side to try and get this right if you're
willing to join me please do if you've
got different opinions to me even better
I don't mind I don't mind what the
recommendation is I just mind that we
get a new one that is appropriate or we
established that the current ones are
quite right so anyone will help me
please come and speak to me after this
meeting
foreign
very quick pitch from Martin if you want
to do it do you want to talk or do you
want to just assure the slide
so Martin's talking as an individual and
this is on the ecn story go ahead Martin
yeah all right I'm not going to go all
the way through this but um there's a
bunch of ecn drafts out there
um uh I don't think they cover all the
cases specifically I did a review of a
ipsec draft that like matches a bunch of
packets together
uh if you match together different ecn
markings given that CE is now sort of
ambiguous uh there's trouble next slide
and so after a lot of thinking and a lot
of assumptions which are probably wrong
and ought to be challenged like I came
up with this big truth table please take
a look uh if there's something we want
to do we can do it if we want to somehow
Munch documents together it's getting
late in the day but we could do that too
um let me know thanks
so uh David black speaking individual I
took a look at I took a look at this and
the existing drafts this is a standalone
piece of work uh Mark we would Martin's
take that it's not covered in 60 40. it
looks like it would be a useful update
and as individualized support just just
taking this forward and doing this as an
add-on to 60 40.
foreign
people here the meeting's not over uh
we're carrying on the IHF meeting for a
while so please continue to talk about
transport things this particular
session's finished uh thank you for
attending see you online or in person if
you're here
thank you everybody
things listed so I don't know if you
didn't realize that when you requested
your sessions
we should ask but there's the evidence
yeah so um yes that's fine so next time
uh answer two because um there's another
hour material we can get