now welcome to the last session of FZ it
will be a session about new designs and
there will be free talks the first talk
is re on tone length preserving
encryption for entry-level processors by
Paul Crowley and Eric Biggers and Paul
will give the talk thank you very much
for the introduction I want to talk
about a problem I'm on the Android
platform security team and I want to
talk about a problem myself or my
colleague Eric faced and what we did
about it this is going to one of the
less technical talks you know it's the
last day we're all tired but also any
anthem is not a sort of deep technical
advance its combination of well
understood techniques and what I want to
talk about is the the practical problem
that we faced and why we chose adding
anthem as a way of solving it if you any
of you who have Android devices in this
room undoubtedly those devices will be
encrypted and those devices will have
something like arm cryptographic
extensions or perhaps even an inline
crypto engine that makes AES super fast
and so those devices will be encrypted
using AES but for a lot of devices not
in this room devices being for example
being used in developing countries or
IOT devices or something like that they
have processes like the cortex a7
processor which lack the ASCE extensions
and on those devices
AES is just not only acceptable
performance and so this affects storage
encryption which is my area but it
affects all sorts of things like for
example TLS connections and in TLS the
solution to this was RFC 75 39 which
uses down bernstein's primitives chacha
only one 305 to build a fairly
straightforward a EAD mode that you can
use for these kinds of applications and
it is I don't have benchmarks but
there's similar benchmarks I'll show you
later Friday anthem is way faster
than a us on these devices and that
gives you an acceptable performance and
so for an internet connection for
network connections
RFC seventy five three nine solves this
problem trouble is because it's an AED
mode the cipher text has to be larger
than their plaintext there has to be
room for a Mac and there has to be an on
switch is not reused the storage
encryption we have to have a cipher text
which is the same size as the plaintext
and I'll get on to why that is so you're
probably that the most familiar example
of storage encryption is the full disk
encryption for every physical sector on
the device we have a virtual sector and
the read/write to the virtual sector
which is has to be exactly four
kilobytes because that's what the
software expects is encrypted and is
sent of the hardware as exactly four
kilobytes because that's what the
hardware supports if we had flash
storage that gave us a little bit more
room we had to have a few extra bytes in
our sectors then we could use an ad mode
store these extra bytes that would that
would change the picture they're a
little bit I've been saying this since
about 2000 I've been having this
conversation with like if there's
storage manufacturers could just give us
a bit of extra room here we could really
do something different even if they were
to turn around tomorrow and say ok we're
gonna do it we take a long time for that
hardware to become available and to me
this problem is urgent
there are devices out there that are not
using encryption because we don't have a
solution to face now on a lot of more
recent Android devices we don't use full
disk encryption we use file based
encryption and at first I hoped that
this would give us another way to
address the problem it would allow us to
the file based encryption could mean we
could be a little flexibility in our
store format and maybe we could make
room for a little bit of extra storage
for a nonce on a Mac sadly it doesn't
really work that way first of all that
would be a major engineering effort bias
to write a file system that could make
room for this it would be a pretty deep
change but even given those deep changes
there will be certain circumstances
where you would see a major hit
so databases for example they expect
that if they have a multi gigabyte
database file they can go to some four
kilobyte align sector and make a change
and see a single write if we have to
update an alts and a Mac for that sector
making a little bit larger that means
it's got to be at least two writes and
when they read from it at least two
reads that has the speed it breaks
atomicity it makes it much it's a major
challenge to update this in a way that
is atomic but worse than that it's
really bad for the flash devices the
lifetime of a flash device is measured
in writes if under these circumstances
we're doubling the number of writes it
will have the lifetime of the flash
device which would be a serious
inconvenience for users so even in the
file based encryption scenario we can't
get away from this problem that we have
to have the cipher text the same size as
the plaintext in order to call itself an
Android device advice has to pass what
we call the the compatibility definition
document and that for many years now the
CDD has required that Android devices be
encrypted but there's a carve out and
there's a carve out so that people in
developing world countries can have a
full-fledged smartphone operating system
on the hardware that people that can
afford that carve out says that if you
encrypt AES at below 50 megabytes a
second you may ship an unencrypted
device now that's that's sad and that
lots of people have unencrypted devices
but it also provides some pretty weird
incentives if you can just slow down ASN
your device to 49 megabytes of seconds
bingo you can ship that device
unencrypted and now your device is
faster than the device that one's 51
megabytes a second which is unencrypted
so oh I was pretty unsatisfied with this
and III wanted to fix that so here's
what we did so given that the ciphertext
has to be the same size of the plaintext
we can't achieve formal property
of an a EAD mode it has to be
deterministic because it's a bijection
we rewrite new content to all sectors so
there's no way to store a and a nonce
that isn't reused and the best we can
achieve is a tweakable super
pseudo-random permutation we want for
every sector we want there to be a
ejection between the plaintext and
ciphertext which is indistinguishable
from a random permutation and for all of
those sectors we want it to be a family
of random family of permutations
indistinguishable from a family of
random permutations and that's assuming
the attacker has access to the
encryption and decryption functions so
an example of a tweakable
super pseudo-random permutation is a sx
TS and this is what we use on modern
file based encrypted devices to encrypt
a 4 kilobyte sector we simply apply a sx
d s 256 times in parallel units and so
the tweet comes in two parts there's a
part for the offset in to the sector and
there's a part within the sector for the
offset within the sector however on the
devices to be target we see performance
of around 59 cycles per byte which is
like 20 mega second which is way too
slow for our users experience if they're
loading an app or something it takes
really visibly too long and so we can't
expect about our users won't accept it
better than we can achieve a better
security guarantee fast super
pseudo-random permutation is applied to
the entire four kilobyte sector so a
change to any bit of the plaintext in
that sector it affects the entire cipher
text and vice versa and for every tweak
it should appear to be a completely new
permutation not only does this give us
better security properties it gives us
an opportunity to be faster because
we're operating in much larger bulk on
the data we can use primitives that work
in bulk and give us greater speed in
bulk NS PRP has to read every byte of
the plaintext
before they write anything so you have
to have at least two passes because we
will
it to be super pseudo-random we need the
same property in the during decryption
direction which means a minimum of three
files passes so we've gone for a hash so
hash structure simply because the hash
is faster than desorb and so doubling up
the hashes is faster than doubling is
all wrong
and we're inspired by examples like I
mean there's a lot of interesting work
in this area which is cited in the paper
we are inspired by examples like a each
counter in h CH which that you like the
other work that we looked at is based on
the assumption that you're going to use
AES and you're going to use multipliers
and GF 1 2 8h counter initiate have this
this hash door hash structure they have
a narrow 16 byte block on the left and
they use that they hash the wide block
on the right to combine with a block on
the left they use that to generate the
notes that goes into the counter mode
encryption and then they hash can on the
other side and there's a single block
cipher call on the thin block on the
left to defeat the Looby drag off attack
on the three round feistel structure but
because like the other things I looked
at this is based on a es and Jia GF 2 to
the ones who ate it doesn't form except
its eaves better security properties but
it doesn't perform better on our
hardware so the work we did was simply
to take these ideas in H counter and H
th and combine them with the ideas from
RFC 75 39 with their like high
performance primitives we have and so we
that means we change the the hash
combiner on the left to a addition more
two to the one to eight because that's
the combiner that works well with our
hash and but the structure is basically
very similar
we also because to char is very well
behaved
compared to AES in counter mode we can
achieve a slight optimization where we
don't have to we can see the slight
optimization where to char and AES can
run in parallel in the decryption
interactions that we sacrifice the
asymmetry of encryption and decryption
but it can give us an opportunity for a
slight speed up in decryption and so
that if that gives us a massive
performance boost 17.8 cycles were quite
well over twice as fast as a sx TS and
that was a big win but we needed it to
be if we were going to the discussion we
were going to have with OEMs trying to
make sure this feature was mandatory was
going to be a lot easier for every cycle
of a byte I could shave off this mode so
the first change we made was we switched
from chassis r22 cha-cha r12 the
currently the best attacks on ChaCha
break7 rounds and that's been the case
for over a decade now and it's seen a
lot of crypt analysis in that time so
every round of cha-cha adds a lot of
strength and so we felt good about
choosing choosing that mode that gave us
thirteen point six cycles byte which is
a significant improvement but there was
room for one other improvement which is
that while poly one three or five is
very fast there are still faster epsilon
with Delta Universal functions on on
this hardware and so we looked at NH for
hashing the bulk of the data NH is
blindingly fast around 1.5 cycles a byte
and they just output is variable length
the long the more you hash the larger
larger its output so we use NH
essentially as a as a compression
function to reduce the amount of data we
feed to probably 1 3 or 5 and then poly
one 3 or 5 handles the final hashing
stage and that's then combined combined
with the tweak and that gives us our
mode @e anthem at ten point six cycles
per byte and so this is the overall
performance where so because the because
of the single IES encryption we get
faster the wider the block we're
encrypting but we still fairly
acceptable evil on the 512-byte sectors
that you used to get on all devices and
with wear faster than normal in fosston
aes fast
other block ciphers such as noachian and
speck and there's a there's a larger
performance table in the paper I think
I've got time to talk a little bit about
the proof it's fairly straightforward so
this is the main step in the proof where
the adversary is trying to distinguish
between two worlds world X and world by
they can make plaintext and ciphertext
queries of any length and tweak so so
world X is essentially a tea anton
except we replace the block cipher aes
with a random permutation pi and we
replaced a char with a random function f
in world Y for every query the attacker
makes they get a random reply of the
appropriate length and we're going to
use the H Co efficient technique which
is thanks to one of my reviews for
pointing that suggesting that and so
after the final query we're gonna make
the attackers life a little bit easier
we're going to give them the hash key
which can't hurt and can only help them
once the attacker has the hash key one
thing they can do is calculate all of
the intermediate hashes inside of a
mountain so you've got this this diagram
where you've got these hashes being
either side of AES and we're going to
allow the attacker to calculate those so
they can put in the plaintext at the top
tweak it aside and get the plaintext
hash and the same thing for the
ciphertext of the other out having done
that they can look for collisions either
in the plaintext hash or the ciphertext
hash it doesn't matter of a plaintext
have collides of the ciphertext hash
only matters that if there's a collision
in a specific layer and the if they find
such a collision they're going they're
going to win what's the probability for
whatever queries they do we can bound
the probability of finding such a
collision and because the wonderful
thing about the H coefficient technique
is we only have to consider the
probability in world wide this is this
is the effort that it saves us so the
for the result it's pretty simple the
result is totally random so the
right-hand side is totally random
and it's combined with whatever the hash
value is but the result is totally
random so the probability of collide
with any specific previous query is 2 to
the minus 1 to 8 for the this is
assuming a plaintext query at all the
exact opposite for a cipher text query
for a plaintext query the it's the
epsilon we were blind the epsilon almost
or universal property of the hash
function the we forbid pointless queries
so given its claimed its query either
plain text or the tweet or both must for
any given previous query they have to
one of those two has to be different and
so the result is the probability that
the hash will differ by any given amount
is at most Epsilon
meaning the probability there'll be a
collision in the plaintext is at most
Epsilon and so across all pairs of
queries the probability that we'll see
such a collision is the most epsilon
plus 2 to the minus 1 to 8 times Q
choose 2 if that happens we call that a
bad transcript and so supposing we get a
good transcript what's the probability
given the queries the attacker for a
given deterministic attacker what's the
probability we'll see a particular set
of responses and well why it's pretty
simple for a given response the
probability is 2 to the minus P all the
filters are equally likely the length of
the response is the length of P and 2 to
the minus the length of P in world X
it's almost the same we'll see a
particular response first of all if F
has exactly the correct output des or
into the content on the left-hand side
to convert it to the expected content in
the ciphertext probability of that is 2
to the minus the length of P minus 1 to
8 on the right hand side pi has to
encrypt in just the right way for the
first query the probability of that is 2
to the minus 1 to 8 as the queries go on
because this is a good transcript it's
always producing a value that it's a
never produced before it's always
guaranteed
deucey Valley has never produced before
and so the it's a probability of getting
it right goes up by a tiny bit every
time and so that's 1 over 2 to the 1 - 8
- I where I is the number of queries
before this one and I should mention
that the reason why we can say make the
assertion I did where F is because the
notes is being fed to F is unique every
time and so its output is always
independent from all previous outputs
and these two probabilities are also
independent so overall the probability
we'll see this well it's this formula
here it's the product of the two but the
important thing is this is always either
the same and if it's one query or just a
little bit bigger
the worldA Probert than the probability
in world wide and these sum across all
queries so now we can play the H
coefficient technique every good
transcript is at least as likely in
world X well why we've bounded the
probability of a bad transcript and that
bound it bounds the distinguishing
advantage which is that most epsilon
plus 2 to the minus 1/2 8 times Q choose
2 so epsilon depends on the sum bound on
the length of the message in the tweak
the attacker sounds we're using
polynomial hashing so the longer the
message gets longer the tweak gets the
the larger epsilon gets but we plug that
into our formula and we add terms for RP
RP RP PRF bounds and for to chart and a
s and we get this rather large
expression but the key thing is that it
is linear in the message to tweet length
and it's quadratic and a number of
queries and it's small
the good news is adiantum is already
part of the league's 5.0 so I don't
really think in terms of years I don't
call these 2017 and 2018 you know I call
years things like Oreo and pie because
those the names of the Android dessert
releases to come out in each year so
this year's release was Android pie and
we have added and at the end time to
enjoy pie and some devices will be using
that and in android q which we don't
know what it'll be called yet if you
know of a dessert with that's called
after the letter Q please let me know
the there will be no carve out we will
require encryption on all devices and
wear AAS is too slow those devices will
use adiantum thank you very much any
questions from the audience
so then I will ask a question I was
wondering sir you said it has some
favorable properties compared to X yes
so could it be also interesting to use
it on the devices which have aes support
and then replace the cha-cha call with a
yes in counter mode or something is that
something you looked at where you used
to like ASC instructions that are very
appealing a lot of these devices so all
these devices have inline encryption
engines and they're it's hard to make
changes but also an S PRP mode is a
terrible fit for an in-line encryption
engine they want to be able to stream
the data path they want to be able to
stream the data past and decrypt it as
it goes an SPF p mode totally rules that
out you have to read everything before
you get to write anything and so maybe
that's possible but I think that will be
that will take a little bit longer to to
land okay and maybe another question
that was interested just maybe could you
give some ballpark figures like how many
percent of Android devices this would be
deployed in the many millions but I we
take this question often but it's a lot
I mean you know it's a next billion
users were aiming this at it's a lot of
people okay any questions from the
audience
then let's finish speak again
[Applause]