the next talk is entitled constructing
low-latency inventory and the as
matricies
with lightweight circuits its joint work
between showing you a only story see why
soon shy only see our way in line who
and surely will give a talk senator
Allah introduction it's a joint work
with waste one timely to where the
highway and they who arrange introduce
our work for from five part first is the
diffusion matrices that diffusion
players are typically realized with
linear operations expressed as matrices
and internal dependencies as much as
possible the diffusion property of the
diffusion matrix is up to its branch
number he has read carrier definition
it's a measurement of a minimal number
of nonzero words of input and output and
there is a it has a upper bound called
single atom bound the matrix achieve
lasting wladim single atom bound is
called MDS matrix regularly lighter
weights perimeter we have following
types of diffusion layers the first in
the bit level permutations such as
present gift the second is the bitwise
xor and the rotations such as skinny
craft under stirred in the maximum
distance separable
MDS matrices such as a yes and almost
MDS matrices that had victory and comer
he
definition of MDS matrices and
inevitable NK by a binary matrix is a
MDS over k ambit worse if and only if
the branch number of a equals K past one
here is a example of MDS matrix in a yes
besides its circulant la vie de charity
is an approach used to desire around
transformations that combined efficiency
and resistance against differential and
linear analysis amnio's matrices are in
accordance with flood strategy have
advantages as diffusion layers in AI
traits block cipher one is its
relatively small number of runs
contribute to low latency device here is
a comparison we have three cipher or
they are all 128-bit block size and
128-bit to key or key size for skinny of
bitwise XOR constructions the number of
his is around it's 40 y4 Natori almost
MDS it's number of rounds it's 20 and a
yes the MDS construction is number of
brawn is only 10 the other advantage of
it is simple and clear security proofs
followed by AES we have some
construction strategies the first is EXO
and rotation based such as height a
second is the iteration based such as
font on hash functions the third is a
special type based such as succulent of
sake no admah tablets Kochi in rotary at
a and the stock is search based to talk
by 200 and ruined for amore matrices
here is the definition the square matrix
Larry its own inverse well it's a means
M squared equals to identity matrix in
rotary matrices are preferable in terms
of hardware implementation things the
same circuit can be used when the
inverse is required
advantage of MDS and the Amala Tory
makes the military matrices more
preferable involute or MDS matrices
applied in some ciphers such as a
newbies iceberg and prince now we go to
a conjunction of lightweights in
military MDS matrices firstly we need to
give the introduction of metrics we
asked estimated where cost of a linear
operation and the number of actual case
required in its implementation but it's
mb hard to obtain the minimal minimal
numbers of actual codes required by
Boyer's theorem that is for any field
shortest linear program is mb ha so only
metrics determine our bounds are
available one here we only give to our
bounds one is direct actual count of the
oxy it's the it equals the Hamming
weight of matrix - the number - it's low
number and the other is the global
optimization it corresponds to a good
linear straight line program which is
based on certain SLP heuristics such as
bias and we denote this as the SLP here
is a comparison for multiplication by
this matrix is direct its directed axle
count is for y it's a CLP actual case
it's three that's following the SLP
actual cases last line acts deoxy cousin
because the intermedia where variables T
1 is used twice
we introduced some previous work
relative to relative to our works Sakai
terrified lightweight 16 by 16 very I
mean the as matrix of less form
LST is equals to the companion matrix of
X to the 4 plus X 2 plus X plus 1
and it's SAR px4 case it's 42 and crowns
at a obtained by the weight 32 by 32 a
moratorium diaz matrix by applying
subfield construction to their formula
we all have stop feared construction is
just a double each sub matrix of some
matrices of the the matrix now it's and
it's SAR P XOR gates it's double here
the Crown's matrix is has a extra count
of 8284 so like we extracting the
structure left for me because of the
former two matrices are forms of it this
well the difference is real choice of a
the matrix a let me generalize Ahn try
to fight right away the Amir literary I
mean these matrices of fallen forms it
can be divided in four parts the left
top two by two matrices right top left
button and the right button there we can
see that all always four part is Samet
somatic so to keep G a military that is
G square equals to identity matrix the
four parameters have to satisfy these
two equations and this let's calibrate
caution will decrease the number of
parameters from four to three and
furthermore we our goal is to find new
military I mean the estimate metrics
such as lat it's Derek
directx to account is small and by some
the to deduction we get a solution which
minimize it at least four and we apply
FOIAs algorithm to it and its SLP xor
gate is eighty battlin crowns the
previous result motivates us to consider
a more generalized form of list we only
fix the time diagonal some matrix to
identity matrix while the others are to
be selected and we also fix the matrices
matrix of a to be a companion matrix of
opponent polynomial x - 8 + x - 2 + 1
drop list form we choose it because its
type is XO account is just 1 and without
loss of generality we can do some
operations on kilometers well the
cooperation won't change the number of
parameters is still chaff but in next
step we use in military property and
reduce it to the list form and the
number of parameters is 6 that is
epsilon 1 2 epsilon 1 epsilon 1 4 and
rst under this limitation we inspect all
the parameters in engineering of
dimension 6 satisfying the following
conditions after
ah Steve search we identify 5550 in
military emergencies whose Hamming
weight are within a range from 148 to
172 that is Tax Director actual account
within a range of 116 to 114 and now we
consider the depths of the
implementation circuits here is a easy
example to list two implementations of
is all the same summation y 1 plus y 2
plus y 3 y 1 it will first is a
summation of first four variables y y 3
equals the last four variables some a
summation and left the depth of left
circuit is 4 while the right is 5 so so
it's the importance of the sequence
easing so it was sequence is important
as we said we get 5550 M Lea's matrix in
the third section and we apply all we
apply boyss SLPs heuristic algorithm to
all matrices and we found the
implementation depth is or is all not
all no not last landfall so but a yes
mix columns can be implemented with
depth of three so we wonder if our
matrices can be implemented with depth
know that no bigger than three and we
have lists or theorem let's rocket taps
often MDS majestic matrix a in 32 past
32 which brand number 5 is at least 3
it's it's ritual
detection but we just counting the
number of one in matrix so we try to
enhance voice algorithm with depth
awareness the difference is in the
choice of distance function basically we
modify boyss algorithm by only picking
signals which are not going to exceed a
specified depth of taps bound and
defining a new notion of distance which
takes the socket the socket depth into
account we are giving some examples
first we denote as as the sequence of
signals F as linear predicate and third
hsf as our new distance function there
is SF as FOIAs distant function if third
edge s F equals K F not only can be
obtained obtained by K additions but
also have implementation of K additions
with in-depth strength it's indexed edge
the first thing example we have the
input signal of five variables and the
linear predicate is estimation of how
variables then the third edge the third
3sf equals Delta s F equals four because
it can be implemented as first x2 plus
x3 x4 plus x5 and the x6 + X X Devon now
we get the estimation of x2 x3 x4 and x5
the last step is x8 + x1 this
contributes to depths 3 y if is that the
depth lamentation - too nice it has no
solution that means all more all
operations contribute to F have
no not less than three and the second
second example we have more two more
where variables X 6 and X 7 X 6 has
depth it tab stack 6 is 1 and the depth
of X 7 is 2 now we we have to compute to
the summation of X 2 plus X 2 X 3 X 4
and X 5 by Boyer's algorithm the dirt SF
in this step it equals 1 because it can
be implemented at X 5 plus X 7 now
equals x 3 plus X 5 plus X 6 equals x2
plus x3 plus x4 plus x5 equals 2f well
if we start at the apps limitation the
to nightkin can be also implemented
within implemented we as we first in
computer x 8 equals x 3 plus x5 then x 8
+ x6 this is the F so we apply our new
algorithm to all matrices with
generating such in second story and the
lightest one with depth 3 is restful
Yola a is still companion matrix of
exponent Gnomeo X X tulip 8 + X - 2 + 1
and it's XOR gates is 88 now we are give
our main results we use our new
algorithm to the AES mix column matrix
and get the XOR gate of 105 105 and the
depth limitation of 3 and we also can't
construct it too
in military MDS matrix one is one has
actual gate of 78
we steps four and one the other with XOR
gate 88 and depth three of our code and
the results are available at our github
website
in conclusion we constructed a large
number of imagery MDS matrices apply boy
SLP heuristic algorithm to our matrices
and we get to the lightest military MDS
matrix
at last we modify bias the algorithm and
apply the new algorithm to all matrices
we get largest in rotary and B as matrix
with depth of three it's all and thank
you thank you very much any questions
okay so maybe I ask a first question do
you think your results can be further
improved or this is best possible
constructed more new structures because
we already limited our structure to
torus forms but it can be made me have
more structures not left aligned
maybe it's another question I have a
step may be difficult to answer but the
previous talk was also about MDS
matrices with lightweight circuits but
they're not involute or e yes so how big
is the price to pay to get involute or e
did you get a chance to compare your
results with the ones in the previous
paper I mean how much more or Xers do I
need to get an involute or a matrix it's
a difference very big or is it water
small yes
[Music]
we think the military's better for
metaphor ciphers binder for division
layers okay there any more questions
so if not thank you very much Jen
[Applause]