so hello back everyone
this is novelist's session of today
before the REM session and this session
is about new exciting results on the AES
new cryptanalytic results so the first
paper is called new yoyo tricks with AES
based permutation by demons are
moustaches are Hammond on Gutenberg and
mr. Fischer will give the dog chance for
the introduction what I had to page in
today is a joint work with diamond saw
and goes on pal it's new your tricks
with a is based permutations and in this
work we have tried to device
distinguishes first a is best
transferable permutations for this
purpose we have chosen to a is best
reputation AAS in the known key setting
and a is best permutation ask these are
typical distinguishing setting where a
distinguished arty tries to distinguish
between random uniform random
permutation and given permutation so our
distinguished will work in the adaptive
chosen plaintext and cipher test sitting
and attacks will look similar quite
similar to the boomerang attacks there
the plaintiffs there we will give some
difference to the plaintext and we'll
get in the return pair some defense so
these are we choose the to plain text
with some defense alpha there there are
some special ways to choose the Alpha
which we will discuss later and in the
slides and we used round radius ciphers
to encrypt then and get new pair of text
c1 c2 with given with defense beta and
now we use the function s M soif on c1
and c2 to obtain new pair of ciphertext
C 1 des and C 2 days and the relation
between c1 and c2 s is that c1 des in
the defense of c1 and c2 des is equal to
the defense of c1 and c2 and we and this
UN and s and C 2 days are decrypted
using the round energy Stefan and new
pair of plaintext are obtained now we
look into the matter where actually this
work is done by Andre rajim at all in
and this showed that there is a special
relation between this alpha and Delta
and there is they they found out that
the the zero difference pattern between
alpha and the Delta is equal for two
jennxpenn rounds so for the round
reduced ciphers they used it to to
Jenica spin-offs and this showed this
result that for two JSP announced the
new defense pattern of the P 1 and P 2
is equal to the difference pattern of P
R and s and P 2 - these are and they
generalize this work and use this result
to find the first key independent your
distinguisher of AES and also they they
implemented this error to find the five
round key recovery attack so how does
the aims walk walk we have defined two
things there the aims of function and
the Geo defense pattern aims of work
there's the typical AES superest walks
so
so in the upper part of the superest box
these the diagonals and the diagonals of
that super as books parts so if we want
to implement that implement the sub
function on the upper parts so what we
will do we will swap according to the
diagonals so there are four diagonals
and in total there are fourteen
combinations of the swapping functions
and if we want to swap according to the
in the last layer of the superest box
will swap according to the inverse
diagonals and here also there are 14
combinations abner of the swap functions
and these the example of the swap how
the swap was there are two aes states
and after the swap these only one
diagnosis were swap between them and
this the new states became these are the
swap function works and the giro
difference pattern is we just draw two
plain text and see whether some of the
superest boxes are active or not if the
service was easy active we do not eat y0
and otherwise it is one so prepared for
this particular case the zeb becomes 0 1
1 1 1 and the weight is a weight is the
number of inactive superest boxes in the
in the difference so the the UM your
game basically works with choosing new
pairs on plane airplane takes and
ciphertext and these are made adaptively
and when making this new pairs of texts
a certain property gift in invariant and
at the end of the game which we see that
whether we verify that whether the that
property is satisfied or not so this
work is basically done by Chandra no
matter we we exploited their work and
further extended the results so our
target is here ask-ask permutation which
is based permutation and the AES in the
non key setting this is the ask
permutation to round there you can say
there there are 4 es States each of
these tests goes through two rounds of
AES rounds and after that there is a
permutation and in the original ask
these steps are repeated 10 times so
there are 20 rounds in total
and to penetrate to implement the
insolence design is less work of the
yo-yo game we have to first identify the
superest boxes or some other nonlinear
nonlinear construction in these results
in this works so first we have
identified the superest box in the ass
we can see that this is the similar to
the AES superest box and there are 16
superest boxes in this result so now we
can use the SLS yogam on the is less
work in this result directly and these
the makings most of a is asked which was
given by the design as themselves it
covers three point five rounds and the
superest was also starts from the even
rounds like and and the mega X was also
starts from the even round and in the
last count the mix column is omitted now
there the first result which is the
direct implementation of the yo-yo
result so first with the four in the
four mega is boxes it starts from the
round two so there are three point five
rounds the mixcolumns
completes the fourth round and after
that against the three point five rounds
Omega X boxes so in total there are
eight rounds and it starts from the
event now that is that's why it is the
two two two nine two two nine and in
this we can directly implement the
result of the yo-yo paper so for
extending those results which are which
are already implemented in you again we
look into the into the into the further
into the Super S boxes itself so like
far like previous where only the
superest boxes are denoted whether they
are active or inactive we further look
into the super cassettes and denote that
whether each of the bytes in the super
expose are active or not active so for
the first of Super S box it's all whites
are active so so nu square alpha 0 is 0
and see the last Super S box that is
alpha 3 only one white is active so they
are the so
its value is 0 1 1 1 so our first
strategy to extend the yoga Mitch
prepend happen strategy so what we have
done this is the classical euro game and
this entry domestic distinguisher and
because new or beta goes to new of ETA
with probability 1 now to a prepend we
have added one round to it which have
some round prepend someone will probably
stick with probability P and and same
rounds are added at the end of the game
with probabilities with some probability
so alpha to Delta and now will not be a
deterministic distinguisher it will come
with some probability and we have
implemented this for the we have
implemented this for the oz9 round is
starting from round one so what we have
down what we have down here we have two
for the first part we have chosen for
where activate only one superest box and
there are only four bytes and after the
one round because there are the shift
rows and mix column with poverty to the
minus 22 it will become 4 to 4 to 1
property will come and only one super
response will be only one byte will be
active in in beta that means on one mega
has was get active in beta so in ETA and
it there will be one mega is both active
and that means there are 16 bytes in
each mega xbox one with some probability
one of the spies will get and in act
will be inactive in ETA and which in
turn in Delta make four bytes in active
this is a example of this result there
are 4 bytes which are we in alpha which
are active after 4 - after our first
round those due to the property of mix
column the one byte gets active with 42
to the minus 22 and due to the euro game
there are 16 the one mega is most active
here and with some probability we get
one byte in active in the active may
Xbox which in turn
in the Delta gives us for bite free
bites so next our strategy is composing
impossible differential with the yo-yo
game for this we have used the you know
we have used the inverted u like the
previous yo-yo we can play the yoga mean
both direction here we will use the
inverted one so in this we have first
used the inverted u opium and then we
have append linear layer and after that
we have a tendon is offended ah is des
layer here is desk in be a sub purse
were is box super as box or mega exposed
anything it can be and after that we get
beta and we try to impose impossibility
condition of beta based on alpha and we
have applied this result on we have
applied this result to found the six
round a yes in distinguisher and asked
distinguisher four nine ten and twelve
rounds this is the impossible
differential for six round AES
so here the SLS in the SLS constraint s
means on supers box so SLS compose the
3.5 rounds in the left side so 3.5
rounds and ale means the head the mix
column and after then again 1.5 rounds
in total it makes six rounds without the
last mix column so it starts in alpha
we'd make one superest was active so in
gamma there will be one superest was
active so that means that in each column
there are one byte active at least and
one there will be one byte active
so after mix column all the four bytes
will get active in the in one column
which in turn will activate all the
supers boxes so in Delta in for the AES
case will have never the never the case
that will get in active superest box
this is the impossibility condition and
this is how the as6 round distinguisher
is devised for ask the same thing is
done we have used the previous editor
asked
and after appending the linear layer
that is the MMC megamix column layer for
in-ground we have offended as simply the
S box to extend one round for the 11th
round we have a extend we have appended
the superest boxes to extend two rounds
and for the 13 rounds we have appended
makes boxes to have to extend four more
rounds and these are all the same
conditions like impossibility conditions
now the last one that is the bad
external euro came here we have used to
yo-yo game and those are those are added
by the linear layer so this is the first
you inverted yogam and then we have
offended a linear layer and after that
we have used another in another yogam
now we start from alpha we took we start
from alpha get the Delta and try to
impose impossible condition on Delta
based on alpha 4 we have ich to use the
strategy to find the first we have used
the strategy find distinguisher for
eight round AES and 16 down ask so these
are distinguishes so what I mean here in
the AES case again we start with one
superest was active and in in alpha in
ETA we get one superest was active so
there will be one one active bytes in
each column so after mix column all the
four whites will be active in each
column which in turn makes all the
superest boxes active so in Delta all
the superest box will be active for the
AES so in a will never have the will
never get inactive Super's box in the
ask case we want to get we are using
instead of super his bosses we are using
mega X boxes so in alpha we are
activating one only one mega Xbox which
in turn you know in ETA will activate
only one mega is first due to the yoyo
game so in Delta due to the mix column
all the four bytes of a column will be
active so this activates all the form ax
boxes so in Delta all the Maya four mega
X versus will be active
and these the impossible the impossible
condition is that in Delta will never
have a inactive mega Xbox
these are the distinguishes on us and
our work report the first nine noun
distinguish a studying from round one we
have also reported the eighth round its
and deterministic distinguishes and all
others our all other distinguishes using
a negligible memory very these are the
eighth round Naoki distinguishes and
again due to the by decks in your game
we are using very negligible memory and
these are the distinguish which are
reported in this work in total we have
we have reported eight distinguishes of
way success related to ask and toward
related to AES and all of the
distinguishes are using Englishman
memory so we have so new ways to
exchange the Euro game we have compost
classical differentials and impossible
differentials with the euro game and
also we have compost to your games to
sort the by adaxel yogam and our our
technique can be used for the public
computations and using this techniques
we have so far achieve the best results
were asked and we have also so known a
new non key distinguisher for AES and
all the practical distinguishes that
have been reported however have been
practically verified thank you so we
have time for some questions okay I have
a question so when you look at a yes q
do you think you could improve its
security by modifying the mixing layer
where you for while you're mixing in
between the AES rounds is it a weakness
which you exploit in your attack or is
it optimal I mean could you make a esq
stronger by changing this mixing layer
now we have not looked into that till
now okay okay
thank you let's find a speaker go
[Applause]