[Music]
all right thanks everybody for joining
today
uh my name is mayuresh gayathande and
i'm a network reliability engineer
at roblox uh today's talk is gonna be
about network automation
and roblox but i'm gonna try and keep it
a little bit different
uh quite often we hear people coming in
especially on this platform and
showcasing all the awesome tools and
technologies that they've implemented
in order to solve their automation
problems however i feel that there is
generally a lack of conversation around
uh some of the real world problems and
challenges
that one may face in today's production
network environments
and also discussions around some of the
solutions to those problems
so today's talk is not so much a deep
dive into any specific
technology or automation stack that
we've implemented
but it's more of an attempt to highlight
how we and roblox have built
and evolved our automation stack over
the past few years
uh hopefully giving you an understanding
of how that has helped scale
the roblox production network
infrastructure as well
so we will start off by looking at some
of the background on the roblox
infrastructure
from a few years ago and some of our
initial approaches towards getting some
basic automation in place
we will then discuss the problems and
challenges that we faced
with our automation stack
over time as the network grew and the
user demands increase
so this increase in demands it caused us
to rethink our approach
in several key areas and to evolve the
automation stack with the focus
on improving reliability and scalability
as well
along the way we also learned several
key things related to building and
operating
a robust and scalable network automation
stack
and some of these takeaways i'll try and
share towards the end as well
so let's start a little bit of
introduction on what roblox is
for those who don't know uh roblox is a
massively multiplayer online game
creation platform
uh we're not so much a game as we are a
platform
uh and one that allows users to play a
wide variety of
games created by developers as well as
other users
as well the platform also has a a huge
social aspect to it
where friends can get together and host
virtual parties and hangouts and stuff
like that
we have millions of monthly active
players so it's imperative for us
to design uh implement and optimize our
infrastructure systems
including our networks and the
associated automation
uh with scale in mind so
just to start off with a little bit of
background on where we where we started
a few years ago
back in late 2017
2018 we basically operated out of a
single data center in chicago
the network there was built using legacy
hardware
and featured really outdated network
designs
they had one large flat layer 2 network
and this network was really difficult to
troubleshoot
operate on day-to-day basis was hard to
scale and grow this kind of network as
well
so the infrastructure team which was
mainly comprised of just a handful of
folks at that time
was faced with the growing challenge of
overhauling the existing network
and building a more modern cost
effective
and scalable replacement to meet
increased player demands
so a decision was made to build
the roblox cloud this cloud would
initially be comprised of a new data
center
in chicago as well that would have
in-house compute
as well as all the supporting network
infrastructure
as you can see in the picture here
initially we would be starting off with
just a single data center in chicago
and that would later expand out to
multiple data centers
in the u.s as well as several smaller
data centers known as points of presence
or pops
all over the world by the end of
december 2018.
these paths would help us accommodate
future growth and as well as improve
player performance over time
now in order to build and scale this new
network it was
imperative that we took an automation
first approach
the reasons for taking an automation
first approach should be pretty apparent
to most people here
uh and this is because all of our data
centers are going to be built with scale
in mind as well as our pops as well
so that's where the nre team was first
established and our main goal
was to build a scalable robust and
reliable network automation stack
that would facilitate network deployment
as well as help with day-to-day
operations and monitoring
the primary focus was going to be
reliability
as the name suggests and building high
fidelity monitoring and alerting systems
was going to be our number one priority
we also took a very customer-centric
approach
in which we would be working very
closely with other teams inside of our
network engineering organization
in order to gather requirements and to
implement the right solutions
so let's uh discuss a little bit uh on
our initial approach to network
automation
whenever we set out to build a network
automation stack the first thing that
usually needs to be implemented is
what's called a source of truth
it's not a must-have but over time the
advantages of the source of truth
become really apparent and pays off over
time
the source of truth as you most people
already know is essentially a database
that serves as the authority for what
the network needs to look like
the network is usually modeled into this
database and the rest of the tooling
and the framework plugs into this source
of truth in some fashion
so with that in mind we decided to
implement a popular open source solution
called netbox that would serve as a
source of truth
once netbox was stood up we needed a way
for network engineers to express
their network design in a user-friendly
manner
and also a way to translate that intent
into objects inside of networks so with
that in mind we wrote
a tool called the net box builder
it's this is a python tool that provides
a declarative way or used to provide a
declarative way
to translate intent into netbox objects
it also included a resource allocation
engine
that would be able to allocate different
resources required to operate a given
network element
examples of these resources include
autonomous system numbers interfaces ip
addresses and so on
like i mentioned before monitoring and
alerting was the number one priority for
us
and we all know that network devices
will typically expose a large number of
metrics that
need to be collected stored as well as
visualize in a centralized fashion
so we wrote a custom data collection
script that would talk to
network devices using whatever protocols
they would support
the base underlying code base was based
out of
or depend or derived from open source
vendor libraries that were available to
us at that time
we leveraged the telemetry stack
that was already being managed by our
site reliability team uh in our
organization
and that was a big stack which which
basically uh
has different components that you can
use to set up your telemetry pipeline
influx database influx db was the one
that was used for storage
for alerting we generally used
the tick stack as well and alerting was
accomplished by writing text scripts
using
capacitor and dashboards were built
using grafana
the expertise of the sre team at that
time greatly helped us in setting this
up
so besides this there were several other
sources of network
information that needed to be collected
and
stored as well and we used whatever
stack was available to us at that time
which the rest of the organization is
also leveraging
an example of that would be using the
elk stack which is the elastic search
stack for
things like syslog now the second most
important task for us was to implement
a config management and device
provisioning framework that would allow
teams to rapidly deploy
new networking gear as well as to manage
their network device configurations on
day-to-day basis
so the first version of this framework
use ansible which is another popular
open source tool for net remote
network device management network device
properties were stored uh not only
netbox but
also in git this is because
not all of the properties required to
generate a device config would
necessarily fit inside of netbox so as a
result of that
we organize these variables in the form
of group and host variables
for those familiar with ansible inside
of a great repository
and then these variables were used to
create our templates that would be
pushed to network devices for just for
the config management
we tried to use vendor provided and
simple models wherever possible
and we also stood up a open source awx
which is a ui framework for running
ansible jobs
the second part of it was device
provisioning and this was mainly
accomplished at that time by also
running ansible playbooks that would
connect to devices or
console terminals and push out conflicts
that way
the provisioning process also involved
code upgrades or firmware upgrades but
at that time these were mostly performed
manually
we also used a bunch of mostly older
vendor source
console modules to write some of these
playbooks as well
so the above stack it kind of served us
well for the first eight to ten months
in the beginning but as the network grew
some challenges started to surface the
biggest challenge at that time for us
was the limited
resources we had not just in our own
team
but also in some of the other parts
inside of netensch such as the
operations team for example
so this meant that not only did we need
to maintain our own code
but also helps streamline the workflows
of some of these other teams by making
them more
resource efficient so majority of our
time
was spent in keeping the lights on which
meant
fixing bugs and fighting other
scalability issues
in order to ensure that automation was
not the blocker for scaling the network
so at that point we decided to get
together and to rethink the entire
network automation stack
which was to overcome the existing
challenges some of which i'll be
outlining next as well as to enable
other teams
to self-serve some of their basic needs
as much as possible
so let's look at some of the issues we
face with our with our beginning
stack at that time the first challenge
we faced was with netbox itself
so all of our monitoring and config
management tooling was extracting info
from netball using its basic rest apis
the api itself has limited capabilities
and we often found ourselves making
multiple
different api calls post processing and
unifying all the data together inside of
our tooling
and then passing it over to our
templating engine in order to generate
device complaints
secondly uh as the network grew the
network builder that we wrote also
started to show its age
it lacked a proper schema based
validation for expressing network intent
and the code base also lacked any kind
of unit tests
also as the network grew and several new
design revisions
were needed to be maintained at that
time for a given device role
it led to a large number of different
yaml templates and their variations
which made the entire
framework really error prone and very
hard to manage
so uh what did we do to overcome some of
these problems
to overcome the net box api limitations
we built custom unified apis that would
encompass
all of the business logic that was
required to generate the appropriate
config template
this was initially maintained as a
plug-in inside of netbox itself
but as the number of dependencies grew
we quickly realized that the right
approach
was to abstract away some of this
business logic into its own service
that would then talk to networks and
potentially other backends as well
in one direction and on the southbound
side would expose
other pertinent apis for clients and
applications to consume
so this led to the creation of what we
call the network api
which is basically an overarching grpc
based
service that acts as the gateway into
the network
going forward we are hoping to make the
network api the primary way of consuming
any and all data about the roblox
production network
on the other hand we completely reload
the net box builder to release
version 2.0 this version includes a
schema based templating engine
which relies on the same prototype of
schema that the network api service
actually uses
is a lot more simpler and scalable and
manageable than the old one
we also rewrote the resource manager
completely and we added a bunch of
different unit tests to cover the entire
code base
this network builder 2.0 has been
instrumental in helping us build out
some of our newer data centers
and that has helped in our explosive
growth especially last year with the
pandemic
so uh the next problem we had was with
our config management framework
over time we started encountering a lot
of problems with our ansible-based
mod uh models we routinely found
ourselves having to push out configs
to hundreds of devices at once and at
that point ansible just would not scale
for us
especially during times of network
outages when
network engineers need to push out a fix
as soon as possible to all of these
problematic devices perhaps the biggest
problem
was that with just like any other
framework things would break
and ansibles cryptic internals and error
messages
such as the one you see pictured here it
made it really hard for us to debug
problems in production
and this ended up slowing us down
considerably
the awx ui was also struggling to keep
pace
with our some of our more complicated
workflows and job runs
many of these workflows have become
strategically crucial for us at this
point
secondly the console based device
provisioning workflows
which are mostly put together as a quick
hack
but also very bug written in error flow
and they would only work about half of
the times
the code that was following the console
playbooks was also written using
the old like pxpect style shell
interactions with the device as you can
see pictured here
which made it even more error-prone
the device provisioning process it also
lacked any kind of checks
and validations and this ultimately
started impacting the rate at which we
could
turn off new pops and new data center
parts inside inside of a production
network
so to solve the ansible problem we moved
to a pure python based framework called
non-layer
this provided us with basic inventory
management capabilities
the base functionality for us was not
enough so we expanded on this base
and built an entire operational tooling
framework on top
this would be a modular system that
would be a collection of different
python scripts
that would help us with various
operational needs including config
management and device provisioning
in order to maintain some of the
familiar workflows as before
we retain some of the good parts of
ansible
namely the same filtering and variable
management capabilities that ansible
provides
for device provisioning we move to zero
touch provisioning
which is very similar to pixi booting it
uses a dhcp-based bootstrapping
mechanism for network devices
we leveraged the non-new framework to
build an
entire end-to-end workflow for device
provisioning
that would stop that was complete with
both pre and post validation checks
and finally because the ui based push
button workflows have become
so crucial for us in enabling us to move
fast
we wrote a job runner system complete
with the web ui that
allowed running any of the non-new
scripts using a web interface
so this framework has also again helped
us
grow our scalar networks in a rapid
place to accommodate
their growth throughout the globe so as
as you may have noticed the common theme
so far has been that
we regularly challenge the status quo
we solicited regular customer feedback
from all the stakeholders and consumers
of our tooling
and wherever necessary we came out with
improved versions of these tools and
frameworks
that incorporated the best of the old by
trimming out the worst of the old and
adding new features as well
now let's talk a little bit about
monitoring and alerting
our initial approach to alerting was
simply sending
everything down to a single slack
channel all of our alerts would be
dumped into a slack channel
so needless to say as the network grew
and the volume of alerts increased it
became really hard for us to distinguish
the noise from the legitimate alerts
given that we had a very small team and
a single person on call at any given
time
this quickly led to alert fatigue
we also lack unified view of all of our
alerts coming in from our different
sources
and we also lack the ability to take
specific actions on alerts
examples of these actions include
acknowledging an alert clearing an alert
suppressing an alert stuff like that
at any given time the network also
generates a very high volume of
repetitive alerts
that can easily be managed by using
software
so the need of the hour for us was a
comprehensive alert management framework
that would help make the on-call more
manageable
so with that in mind we created an
in-house tool called alert manager
the reason for going in-house at that
time was because
there was nothing out there in the wild
that
would uh satisfy all of our requirements
that we had for this system
so this alert manager it acts as a
single pane of glass for all of our
alerting needs
users can visualize and interact with
different alerts it provides features
such as alert aggregation
it's also able to automatically plug
into our source of proof which is an
inbox
and automatically suppress alerts by
fetching the operational state of
devices and other network elements
finally it also allows more advanced
workflows such as auto remediation
wherein we are able to offload trivial
high volume alerts
to a robot for initial triage and for
possible remediation as well
we recently wrote a tech blog about this
entire framework
and if you're interested i would
encourage you to go out to the
provided link here so you can read more
about it offline
the last piece i wanted to highlight is
the challenge that we face with our
monitoring stack
so the data that we had collected it had
to have a long retention time
in order to comply with network
analytics and forecasting requirements
the version of influx vp we were using
at that time it had a rather inefficient
storage engine
which meant that we had to constantly
keep a track of
storage and migrate to larger disks
over time secondly writing alerts
meant writing tick scripts these big
scripts
had really steep learning curves
and were rather cumbersome to maintain
and debug on a day-to-day basis
our capacitor instances had also started
hitting scaling issues as a number of
increased alerts had increased and the
network actually expanded as well
finally the sql-like language that
influx db used at that time
also meant that the burden of creating
dashboards it fell entirely on the nre
team
even for us complex dashboarding
required some degree of trial and error
before we could get it right
so all of this meant that we could not
safely transition to the self enablement
model
of empowering other teams to control the
features that they wanted
so the solution to this thankfully
turned out to be pretty straightforward
uh we migrated all of our monitoring
over to prometheus which is another
very popular time series database
prometheus has been
proven to be generally more efficient
than influx db based on real world usage
and personally we observed over a five
time
increase in disk efficiency for all of
our metrics
of course this differs based on
cardinality and other things
it is also orders of magnitude easier to
learn and write
prometheus query language or promql and
this meant that with a little bit of
guidance
we could enable other engineers to write
their own dashboards as well as queries
finally prometheus also has a built-in
alerting system
that utilizes the same from ql query
language
to generate alerts which meant that we
had one less component to manage and to
take care of
so uh with because we wrote much of our
automation stack in-house
this has allowed us to control our own
destiny and to move
fast while iterating over time this has
allowed us to build
what we call our self-service model
one of our guiding principles for
writing our tools has been to take the
long view
which meant that we've always tried to
build extensible
frameworks and not just ad hoc scripts
this meant making software like alert
manager non-near
plug-in driven where new features and
scripts can easily be added
network engineers are able to write
their own scripts audits
as well as to create their own
dashboards all of the heavy lifting
is usually taken care of by us as owners
of the framework
and the network and operational
engineers can then simply focus on the
business logic when writing their
scripts
this also meant that we could extend
some of our tools to
more easily fit the use case of teams
even
outside of network engineering
organization
and finally incorporating a user
interface has
allowed teams uh that
are outside of neteng to also assist in
growing the network as needed
and examples of these include people who
actually work out of the data centers in
chicago and
some of the other locations around the
world so these folks can actually help
us in growing the network by
running these workflows by simply
pushing a button on a web ui
and all this without requiring any
knowledge of how the network works or
what the software systems are that power
the underlying network
so finally i'd like to highlight some of
the key takeaways
for us from this journey so far
first off network automation is
definitely no longer nice to have
especially in a fast-paced growing
production network environment that
needs to scale rapidly
because network automation adds
strategic value to your overall
business plans it's really important to
hire the right people to get the job
done
i would even go so far as to say that
network automation needs
to fit within the core business strategy
of the organization as a whole
secondly don't strive for perfection on
the first attempt right the old adage of
done is better than for perfect has
proven to be true time and again
as some of the real world examples in
prominent companies
across the world and even even at roblox
has shown
try to standardize some network designs
wherever possible
uh clean and robust network automation
usually goes hand in hand with clean and
standardized network designs
however also be prepared to maintain and
support multiple revisions of those
designs
in your tooling and all of your
frameworks as well
it also helps to carefully evaluate the
functionality that comes
out of the box with open source tools
and frameworks
chances are that as you grow these
functionalities may not be enough for
you and
most likely you will need to add other
features and functionality on top
and as such it is imperative and
important to choose solutions and
products that allow for a seamless way
to extend
their base functionality
also remember that open source is not
always the right answer
open source has its place but just
because the repository has
10 000 stars on github and serves the
needs of others
does not necessarily mean that it's
going to serve you equally well
like i mentioned before it is important
to realize what tools and frameworks
will add strategic value to the
organization especially over the long
run
long run this means even though your
team
might run thin on resources dedicating
whatever time is available to those
strategic initiatives will
definitely pay off in the long run
there are also several different
one-stop shop automation solutions that
you might come across
that may be tempting to avoid attempting
to
adopt in my personal experience over the
years
this is a pitfall that needs to be
avoided as much as possible
not only does this introduce vendor
lock-in but a majority of your time
would be spent focusing on what i call
adapting your automation needs to fit
the tool
rather than adapting your tooling to fit
your automation needs
if you see if you see the difference
there
of course if you're really out of
options it's fine to use something off
the shelf
until such time as when you can grow
your team to be able to handle
the problem on your own and finally
it definitely pays to think of network
automation as something that
enables the production network to grow
and scale
which usually means empowering other
engineers with
tools and frameworks that they need to
assist you in that mission of growing
and scaling the network
so things like auto remediation and ui
based workflows they help lighten the
operational burden on other engineers
which means that they can now spend more
time in helping you grow and scale the
network
which is ultimately a win-win for the
organization
and that's all i have for today and i'll
be open to questions now with there any
thank you
thank you my rush so we have a few
questions that have just come in
um so let's uh let's let's go through
them first question
does the addition of graphql to netbox
and next major release help you
or do you just steam forward with the
network api and current api stitching
yeah great thanks for that question uh
so for us the graphql edition is
definitely
a great feature to have uh because it
expands the query capabilities of netbox
but for us
the overarching external api it allows
us to abstract
the business logic and decouple the
business logic entirely from the
underlying source of truth
so our philosophy generally has been
that the source of truth
should be nothing but a plane monitor
database with
extensible query capabilities and all of
the business logic should totally be
abstracted out into its own service
uh the leaner the database is kept the
better it is
the external api also allows us to plug
into
other organizational engines for
authentication authorization and stuff
like that
without actually maintaining two
separate you know components for for
that specific use case
so for us it is definitely going to be
the external api which will be the way
to move forward
all right so next question
is uh which metrics just for example um
were stored in
influx db and now move to prometheus
so pretty much all of our uh network
device metrics which includes like
uh interface statistics bgp metrics uh
you know uh other utilization issue uh
counters and stuff like that we pretty
much move
entirely uh away from influx jb into
prometheus
okay um how is
how does your existing automation deal
with new device or new vendor
intros into the network
so whenever possible uh we try to
leverage uh
we got our core way of interacting with
devices today is via nepal
which uh fortunately brings in a lot of
multi-vendor capabilities out of the box
uh there have been devices for example
uh
we're building our own optical network
so they've been like some optical
devices which don't necessarily
uh you know fit into the napalm
framework so for that we've
managed to because the architecture is
so modular and plug-in driven we're
easily able to
uh you know use whatever libraries the
vendors provide whatever apis they
provide
and to create modules that talk to these
new networking vendors over time as well
okay totally so um
um so another question so
and this is something that we all deal
with when you have network engineers who
write their own tools
um like you or or me for that matter
um how do you define what the ongoing
support
structure looks like because you have
these tools and dashboards that
you know are written and if the original
engineer
network engineer leaves what happens how
do they get supported
um you know how do you end up avoiding
you know building up just another
version of tech just another version of
tech debt
yeah that's a great question and to be
honest uh we have struggled
with that uh especially because our team
has been
uh you know kind of small uh and we
haven't had a chance to grow the team as
much as we would have liked
but generally we try to uh you know
provide
a contract uh meaning that as long as
network engineers adhere to the
core underlying framework and how
the core needs to be structured in a
specific way and as long as they inherit
certain libraries
uh that bring in you know
instrumentation capabilities
uh centralized logging those kind of
things it makes maintaining the code
base and those scripts a lot easier
uh pretty much for anybody else taking
over the framework or after the awesome
author leads as well
so the trick for us has been to you know
centralize things as much as possible to
provide a common observability and
monitoring framework not just for our
network but also for our tooling and
scripts as well
all right um so uh last question here
um actually no we got a couple of
questions
we get your questions um so
context-aware learning context-aware
alerting
is huge and missing from nearly all
traditional monitoring
um at a previous firm we did some sort
of consolidation
related alerts are there any thoughts on
contributing or open sourcing your
approach unlock though
definitely yes uh context of alerting is
one of the
core features of our alert manager
framework uh it plugs directly into
netbox it can also plug into any other
source of truth
to fetch metadata about alerting
entities
uh right now the system is kind of
coupled into
uh kind of tightly into the uh some
other
internal roblox systems so there is some
work in progress to you know uh
abstract out some of the uh logic into
its own
code base that we can eventually open
source so yeah we definitely have plans
of doing that in the near future
great all right um this looks to be the
last question
um following up slightly on the
prometheus question above
do you store significant model driven
streaming telemetry there
and if so what's the retention period
good question so we are not uh currently
using streaming telemetry we are still
using
uh the pull model where we use uh
either the json or netcon to pull data
from the devices
uh but yeah everything goes into
prometheus our retention is mostly
driven by
uh forecasting and analytics
requirements uh
we have a high availability cluster
setup we also have
a long term storage engine uh that
connects into
our short-term prometheus instance so
just we can horizontally scale that
engine
and we can add more machines into that
cluster and
grow the scaling and retention
capabilities as we need
okay great so thank you for your
presentation and your time today