[Music]
welcome to the nanak 82
virtual hackathon i'm really excited to
be here i'm sitting
with participants and organizers michael
costello is a
nano committee chair as well as netflix
director of engineering
michael go ahead and tell me what you're
most impressed by with this year's
hackathon
thanks elizabeth like most hackathons
i'm
continue to be impressed by a number of
people
show up and they spend their weekend
working on on hard problems when they
could be spending their weekend doing
anything else uh they come in here they
they show vulnerability
and that they don't know everything that
are willing to learn they're willing to
meet other people and rise to the
challenge to learn something new
what did you find most challenging
during this process
jeff i'm going to throw this question to
you and go ahead and introduce yourself
to everyone hi i'm jeff barteg i'm a
network architect for internet2
and i'm a member of the program
committee and the hackathon subcommittee
uh i think the for the
organizers i think a big challenge was
that
we looked at a completely new way of
offering
virtual labs this time uh we're using
container lab
and so leading up to the hackathon
members of the the team put a lot of
effort into making sure that worked well
uh steve tell me what is most different
as jeff had mentioned we're now we're
doing this remotely as opposed to being
in a large room together
uh due to the pandemic what other in
what other ways
has hackathon changed over the years
over the past few years past many years
perhaps struggled with trying to define
what we want the hackathon to be
we've gone back and forth between it
being very free form
we just invite people into a room give
them some power
and network and tell them to go build
something to
having a very prescribed uh almost a
training course type of event
the pendulum has swung back more toward
do it on your own but here's a set of
tools and a theme you can use to
organize around if you want to
i personally really enjoyed this the way
it was done this time because i
let me sort of develop on the fly what i
wanted to do and go ahead and do it at
my own pace
um changing from in person in a single
room to virtual
has brought a whole new set of
challenges and we spent a good part of
last year trying to figure out
how to deal with it and i think we've
settled on something pretty good here
biggest surprise to me but also the
greatest thing
is that by going virtual we have a lot
of people from all over the world to
come in and
contribute and collaborate i mean just
look at the tony and barry team
this is their third hackathon in a row
um where
they're sitting pretty much at opposite
ends of the world and working on
something together i think that's great
prior to this we're just an organizer so
this one is kind of an
extra special event because you
participated for the first time is that
correct
yeah it is um and it was great for me
because i got to see
the other side finally um and i found a
way to do something fun
at the same time uh i did to get to talk
to michael about how this is such a
passion sport can you talk more about
that
i mentioned during my presentation
earlier that i love to learn new things
um and this gives me a way of doing that
in bite-sized chunks where i can pick up
some new technologies play with them and
see where things lead um the fact that
everybody here was willing to give up
most of their weekend to do this
like as michael said is an amazing thing
um it means that we're
all passionate about um
what we do the technology the
educational aspects of it
and uh and to be honest with social
aspects as well
so my project ended up being to install
an autobot container um use that to
create some sort of truth data
and then write a screen script that
would use that data to
uh use gnmi to update router configs
this is what i had to do in container
lab to get it running
i added exactly these lines to the
container lab config and it came up and
it ran
the only little bit of magic here is
this bind
statement which let me create a
directory
on the host system which was shared
amongst all of the containers i added
this to the uh
excuse me to the linux containers as
well um so i made
sharing code amongst them very easy so
this here is the
autobot main screen um so i created
two whole devices which i will show you
here so these the ceos device and the
srl nokia device so here's the four
interfaces on the device
descriptions and ip addresses what i
ended up
being able to automate in the time i had
was updating the interface descriptions
on the devices from what not about
claims there's a source of truth here
so if i go to well first i'll go to this
window um
all i'm doing is show interfaces
descriptions so you can see the
descriptions here
should match uh what's here in the
autobot
um i'll go to this window which is one
of the centos containers on the uh
in the lab and i'll run dot slash
update descriptions and it's going to
read through
uh notobot um looking at all the devices
looking at the
configurations on the devices so it says
that the descriptions don't need to be
changed because they match what's on the
device so i'm going to go here
and i am going to change let's see i
will edit the loopback interface
and change it to
demo demo time
and update so you can see that it's
updated here um so i'm going to go here
run my script again
takes a little bit of a moment okay so
here you can see that it had to
update the description loop x0 now if i
go to
the actual device and do show interfaces
description
again you can see that it was set to
demo time
the big thing that i came out of this
with is that there are so many tools
that let you put together
bits and pieces of things in useful ways
and play with them
um it's just a matter of learning the
tools and finding the time to dig when
you want to
what are you most excited about for
future hackathons i'm really impressed
with the pace
at which we've seen the the lab
environments improve
um you know pretend you know i've been
i've been
networking for 20 some years now and
you know you know starting with you know
here is your here's your hardware to
play with go in and connect to things
to to uh to a system where you can
more or less spin up any topology you
want
run whatever tools grab them and you
know and
the ease of which tools can be spun up
and deployed
topologies can be deployed i'm i'm only
looking to see that improving
and with that i'm seeing i'm seeing a
lot of opportunities for
teams to maybe maybe not so much
develop a lot of their own code but just
figure out interesting ways of putting
tools together
in different tool chains and different
combinations
uh to make to make some interesting uh
systems happen
you know we've seen that a few times
where you know and a lot a lot of the
hacks we see you know yeah we took we
took this project
and and made a plug-in to make it talk
to this one
and just putting the glue between a lot
of existing stuff um
and and and then and
the nice thing about that is that you
know you can say all right you know
i'm not going to build everything from
scratch there's a lot of technology out
there
maybe not all of it is intended for
network engineers a lot of it is
a lot of it um is geared towards systems
but
the the law between network systems
and services um and
running running software as web services
apis
um that's starting to get fuzzy enough
that a lot of things can apply to both
and that's really exciting to see
what what people are gonna do with that
next as
you know as those uh as that those lines
continue to blur even further um so
coming into this
hackathon you basically have shared a
whole
new evolution of tools starting with
continued labs
so this is the um this is the topology
that is running off
of my uh
sort of um virtual
lab you can see that it's
it it all comes alive on a very
bare minimum resources so this is a four
gig
um virtual instance
uh off to a main host of windows
and you can see that it is hardly using
half of it
the lab itself the way it gets
constructed
is pretty much all these demands that i
was able to run in
of course you need docker support uh you
would need to have
the right docker ce uh
instance for the kind of ubuntu that
you're running the guide was talking
about focal length using
pursuit so and then um
of that once we are done with docker c
implementation
then f of r fr lab
instances they were you know they were
pretty easy to
spin up because it does provide you with
pcs uh
uh with a login to uh ehl
as well as to a router login to vty sh
all right tony who is all the way
in south africa thank you so much for
joining us
how are you doing today tony hi um i'm
doing good thank you how are you
i'm very well uh so has it been a long
weekend for you
um not so much um but it's been it's
been good
it's been it's been a great experience
as
the last few have been why should
someone participate in the future
um well i think
for me um i think
coming from south africa for instance um
you know
like we a lot of people would
uh would like always be fascinated by
what's happening in the us
uh closer to silicon valley um and
what's always fascinating to me is that
the access to knowledge to information
to the internet is all the same
so you know working with people from
different organizations
uh well-known organizations that we get
to collaborate
on the same problems and solve the same
problems um
kind of highlights uh the fact that we
are
a whole lot more unified and there isn't
a lot that separates us
so for me that is is
enough for anyone else to just come and
participate
and see what other people are working on
and you find out that
we kind of are all working on solving
the same things
is this your first hackathon no it is
not
um i have been participating since
october of 2020 that was my first
hackathon and there i met tony and we
started to work together
and have been working together for three
hackathons now if you count this one
wow that's amazing so what drew you to a
specific topic
you chose well i've been wanting to
focus more on network automation and
uh network scaling as well as network
management
so um i was drawn to the idea of
being able to take the streaming
telemetry
uh the the stream of data and
do something useful with it you do seem
to learn a lot in a small
span of time yeah it was a
fun 48 hours like yeah like a ton tony
said i
i went to bed at six in the morning
today um
i'm learning bus so i i just wanted to
to get that working out of the way
most of the hackathons that i've
participated in have
always been successful so um
for me um it was just that in my
previous roles
um i'd never had the chance to come to
nanak
so um i think that the first
time that i attended it was a good
opportunity one because it was
uh i could join online and
also uh having been in the midst of
lockdowns and restrictions it was a good
way to travel without leaving my
my home oh definitely
yeah and socialize yeah yeah
yeah so yeah so i think it
one thing about you know the pandemic
was that
we we kind of have been able to actually
reach
each other uh even more seamlessly
uh ironically enough um uh from from the
comfort of our home and i don't
and for me that um if if
things were as normal i probably would
have had something else more important
to do
so so um that that was a good
opportunity for me
that's really interesting that the
pandemic opened up this door for
you guys to respond and find camaraderie
yeah well uh javier what would you
what kind of advice would you give to
future participants
um don't be afraid to join um
and again come with an open mind if you
don't have a project you don't know what
to do
there is an amazing staff of mentors
with chris
michael jeff that they're gonna help you
all the way
all the way in um and you're gonna meet
people like tony
and barry and steven john that are open
to you to help you with anything you you
have questions about um and
just yeah don't be afraid um
if you want to learn if you want to meet
new people and share experiences
it's it's the right place to do it well
thank you so much for talking to me and
all the rest of you
i enjoyed it thoroughly so cool to
connect
to so many different kinds of people all
over the world
um michael do you have any closing
thoughts
well i guess uh i guess yes i wanted to
uh to thank everybody here who
participated and i wanted to
thank um everybody who helped organize
it uh and i want to
thank the um the kind sponsors uh
uh nokia arista and deft for
uh providing the virtualized lab
infrastructure
so thanks again everybody thank you
michael
thank you all for helping and mentoring