[Music]
thanks for having me and i hope you'll
like this session
where we'll focus on networking in
public clouds but from the
end user perspective so i will not tell
you how to build one
i will tell you how to use one
some of you may know me i am a really
old networking engineer i've seen
everything from
apple talk and decnet onwards which
makes me a little bit sad
and sarcastic at times as you will
notice
throughout the presentation so for
example
and this is i promise the only marketing
slide in the whole talk
clouds need no networking and
you know they might even be right they
might even be right about this unicorn
stuff
depending on how you define cloud
because you know when you talk to
industry analysts and they tell you that
90 percent of
everyone is using cloud services they
forget to tell you
that they're using office 365 or so
called
software as a service which honestly is
just a website so
why bother you just need some internet
connection or whatever
and you're there and we know how to do
that and let's move on
then you have platform as a service
which was known as
web hosting before it was called
serverless because serverless
sounds so much better than you know web
hosting because everyone understood what
web hosting is and now with serverless
you can you know
do wonders uh there the plumbing is
implemented by the cloud provider and
you honestly don't care about that
unless you want to connect platform as a
service
with your existing workload when the fun
starts
but what if you want to do the classical
infrastructure as a service
where do you think you will connect your
vms to and how will they connect to the
outside world
and we'll go through those details and
finally
lately all the public cloud providers
started offering container as a service
mostly running on kubernetes and that
thing
is really just abstracted ned madness
and we'll forget about that for today
otherwise we'll never
end so today we'll talk about public
cloud networking from the end user
perspective
we'll figure out how different it is
we'll also figure out that it's on one
hand
nothing special but on the other hand
it's crazily complex
so starting with the bare minimum for
in every public cloud these days you can
create your own tenant network and then
you have to create one or more subnets
and then you create the virtual machines
and the virtual machine
has an ethernet interface everything is
running on ethernet these days so
of course the virtual machine has an
internet interface even though
everything is running on virtual
networks and then you
connect that ethernet interface to the
virtual subnet
and someone magically gives an ip
address to that
interface it's all done through dhcp
there's no other way
and then you start a vm and everything
works until it doesn't
as you know there are still people who
don't understand that
one cannot simply connect servers to the
internet and
hope that nothing bad will happen and
some of those people are running
men cache d on their servers and running
memcache d
on udp and so some other people are
using those people
as a great amplification tool for ddos
attacks
and you know what's the best thing about
that the person
who left his memcache d server wide open
to the world
is paying egress fees for his omissions
anyway we have to add security so you
have to protect the vms and there
the first question is will you use
security groups
which is really a fancy name for access
control lists
usually stateful or will you use
firewalls
and is the cloud provided firewall good
enough
or do you want to bring your own
firewall
and honestly don't don't even think
about bringing your own firewall
it's a total disaster
firewall vendors are doing great job
trying to
document how to do it properly and as
simply as possible but
once you start digging into that stuff
you go insane so
don't but that's not all
the next minute someone figures out that
oh we might need more than one server so
let's add load balancing and it can be
either on the network level
on tcp or udp ports or it can be an http
load balancer
then someone figures out that oh my what
if this cloud thingy goes down
and then you start thinking about
availability zones which
are really failure domains in one
geographical location
or regions because i've heard that there
are some parts of us for example
where there might be floods coming in
and you don't want to have your workload
just in that region
and then of course you need to connect
the workloads that are running in the
cloud back to the workloads that are
running on premises unless of course
you're a unicorn startup and everything
is in the cloud
at which point you will be dealing with
ipsec
and you will be dealing with virtual
tunnel interfaces and you will be
dealing with
bgp and if you want to have direct
connection to the cloud
every single cloud provider is working
with vlans
and subnets and ebgp running on top of
that
and then you have people who are telling
you how
much better it is if you deploy your
workloads in multiple clouds
please don't as you'll see in a few
minutes
every single public cloud provider does
things a little bit different
and why exactly would you want to learn
three different ways of doing the same
thing
just don't obviously it makes perfect
sense to run
office 365 and have your
compute workload on amazon and use
google dots
but remember those are just two websites
and your infrastructure as a service in
the third cloud that's perfectly fine
but having compute spread across
multiple public clouds
maybe not and now that i
briefly mentioned all those complexities
who do you think will make that work
developers
cloud experts or someone who understands
networking who knows how to make things
work and so
yes it is different and yes everyone
believes that
there is no need for networking
engineers but in the end
even though you are using api and
terraform and
ansible and who knows what else it's
still networking and someone must still
understand
how for example a load balancer works
on top of that networking in public
clouds is
different from what you're used to
there is no layer 2 in any sane
public cloud there is at least one
not so small cloud provider that is now
offering layer two
that's why i'm saying sane public cloud
and i'm not counting people who are
running vmware and calling that a public
cloud
because we are talking about stuff that
scales beyond
approximately thousand hosts which is
the scalability limit of
any vmware solution i've seen so far
so if there is no layer 2 in a public
cloud how am i supposed to move virtual
machines
well guess what you won't
how will i implement high availability
clusters well
it's great fun and will touch on that
how will i deploy
firewall clusters maybe you shouldn't
because after all we're not dealing with
uh physical boxes where the power supply
can burn
if your firewall crashes just restart
the vm
maybe it's better to have a little bit
of downtime
unless of course you have mission
critical applications and you're losing
millions per second
and wait for the firewall to restart and
trying to rebuild your firewall cluster
in a public cloud
and finally there's the
eternal question of how will i migrate
my workflows from on-premises data
center
into the public cloud one by one while
retaining the
ip addresses and of course the
networking vendors have their answers
for example
lisp is the answer regardless of what
the question is
and of course there are people doing
this with lisp
please don't if someone wants to move to
the cloud
they should re-architect stuff they
shouldn't
try to stretch existing subnets into the
public cloud
because remember public cloud is the
same environment
based on ip routing not crazy
layer 2 tricks now
comparing aws versus azure they have
some common concepts like
they both have isolated routing domains
uh aws calls them bpc
azure calls them vnet and they are like
device context
on a nexus switch both of them
have multiple subnets within that
routing domain
in both of them and any other
public cloud large public cloud that
i've seen
the ip and the mac addresses are
assigned by the orchestration system
yes you can change the ip address
usually you can change the mac address
or you can specify what ip address you
want to use but it is done
through the orchestration system api
there is no
ip address snooping there is no dhcp
snooping there is no arp snooping
there is no crazy layer two tricks that
we are so used to
from the crazy enterprise world
everything has to be done through the
orchestration system including routing
routing is controlled by the
orchestration system
and yes you can disable strict ip source
ip and source mac checks
but they are enabled by default
so what does that mean you cannot use
any first hop redundancy protocols
hsrp vrrp glbp
they don't work because you cannot just
grab a mac address and pull it over to a
different vm
you cannot just grab an ip address and
say it's mine
with a gratuitous arp that doesn't work
the only way to change or move an ip
address
is through an orchestration system api
call now with aws that's a viable
solution
with azure sometimes their restoration
system becomes
glacially slow and so the worst i've
heard
was it took 17 minutes to install a
static route
now if you have two routers two sd-wan
devices let's say
and you use static crowd static default
route pointing to one
or the other of them because you can't
have two default routes
that's cloud for you and then that
device crashes and you want to
move the static route to the other
device perfectly easy
a bit of python and you're done
17 minutes later you can reach your
network
maybe not a good idea uh
also you just you cannot just run a
routing protocol
within the cloud for example from your
vms running bgp
with the cloud that doesn't work there
are a few exceptions like
azure route server or aws
transit gateway connect peers these are
brand new things azure route server is
still in preview
aws doesn't believe in previews when
they launch something
it works but you know be careful these
are
new thingies in
aws they focused on availability so
each subnet is limited to one single
availability zone remember availability
zone is a failure domain
which means that it's extremely easy
to build resilient applications you
deploy a few servers in one subnet
you deploy a few servers in the other
subnet and you know
that if one failure domain goes down the
other subnet will stay alive
they do unicast ipv4 and ipv6 forwarding
they have
some approximation of ipv4 multicast
statically configured through the api
calls
interestingly they don't do layer 2
flooding and all that stuff
but within the subnet they are not
looking at
ip addresses they're looking at mac
addresses and that allows you to do
crazy tricks like static routes between
a and b for example but only
within the subnet interestingly the same
thing for aws and azure
each subnet can have a different route
table so except that could be
almost like a vrf but
in aws there is absolutely no way
to influence intra vpc packet forwarding
so if you want to insert a firewall
between a and c
it's totally impossible
if a sends a packet to c there is
absolutely no way that you can intercept
that packet
and send it somewhere else for
inspection if you want to do that then
a and c in this case must be in two
different vpcs because between dpcs you
can do all sorts of crazy stuff
speaking about crazy stuff in aws all
the crazy stuff
is done with static routes so if you
want to
build a complex scenario with many vpcs
it's perfectly possible
you'll also enjoy a gazillion static
routes configured through the
orchestration system
so we are back to 1960s
so intravpc service insertion is really
really hard
and yes you can get some things done
usually with a lot of net involved
as i said you can do routing tricks
within a subnet because
between a and b they look at mac
addresses so you can use static routes
but not
across subnets azure is totally
different
subnets span availability zones which
means that it's really
harder to build highly available
applications because
you can't just put two servers in one
subnet and two servers in another subnet
you have to work with availability sets
and you have to work with zonal
resources
so you have to be careful they also do
unicast ipv4 and ipv6
they don't look at mac addresses at all
it
looks like every instance would be
connected
directly to a router you look at the arp
table
all the mac addresses on your vm are the
same
so whenever you arb for anything what
you get back is the mac address
of azure router like with aws
every subnet could have a different
route table and
the route table can contain prefixes
that belong to the v-net
so it's perfectly fine to say well
if a wants to send the packets to b i'll
intercept that
send it to the firewall and then send it
to bn the same thing
on the way back so service insertion
in azure is easy to do but it's messy
because you're dealing with multiple
routes tables and static routes
and all that building proper
high availability architectures with
swim lanes where you have two
totally different application stacks is
harder because these subnets are not
tied to availability zones
so looking at that and these are just
two you look at google
you look at oracle you look at rackspace
they're all different
so you say well why couldn't just they
be why couldn't they just be the same
and the problem is that you know they
all started from different places
they all had different audiences so
microsoft is obviously more enterprise
focused
aws is more developer focused
they probably have different scalability
goals
azure has like 130 different regions
uh aws has a few dozen regions and they
must be
an order of magnitude bigger than some
of the azure regions
they were fixing different problems
probably
uh azure is running
at some variant of hyper-v we know that
aws
was running on zen if i remember
correctly so they were dealing with
different things
and so they were solving the same
problem in different ways because
you know how the id industry works when
you have a hammer
everything starts looking like a nail
and you use the hammer until someone
points out that now you're doing damage
to yourself
and then you start looking for the
screwdriver
now why does that matter the problem is
that the moment you start thinking about
multi-cloud you have to decide
will i be limited to the least common
denominator of all the clouds
i want to work with or will i use
cloud specific features and of course if
you start using cloud specific features
the portability is
gone the next microsecond it's like you
know
i'm buying cisco boxes and should i use
eigrp
or not or i'm buying juniper boxes
and should i rely on the automatic gre
tunnels between pe
routers or not
even real life tools that some
so-called thought leaders try to sell
you
as preventing the cloud lock-in
really have cloud-specific plugins or
modules so terraform has
cloud specific plugins for aws azure
gcp you name it the same thing with
ansible only they're called modules
so you can't just take an infrastructure
definition that you deployed
on azure and deploy it on aws
so multi-cloud really works best
in powerpoint and yeah i am using
powerpoint at this point so let's move
on
uh on the other hand networking in
public cloud
apart from a few differences that i
explained
is nothing special for example
you want to build a vpn connectivity and
it's almost the same for aws
and azure you will have to use an
ipsec tunnel so you will have to
configure ipsec in a tunnel mode
and you will have to configure ipsec
with a virtual tunnel interface
and these are unnumbered interfaces and
you have to run ebgp over it so what do
you do
well you create a static crowd to the
next hop pointing to the tunnel
interface
and they do the same thing on their end
automatically is through your
orchestration system
and then you run ebgp multi-hop session
and similarly for direct connection uh
you create a
vlan trunk then for every connection
into the public cloud you take a vlan
you provision the vlan in the
orchestration system so that
they provision their router and then
you're running ebgp
over it so wherever you look it's bgp
everywhere and it's always ip routing
no public cloud provider worth
their name will allow you to extend your
vlan
into a public cloud because why should
they they would just be exposed to
all the spanning tree loops you would
have in your network
now their bgp implementation
let's try to be diplomatic sucks
so they don't have the gazillion bgp
nerd knobs you're familiar with
aws is much better than azure by the way
so usually the only thing you can do to
influence as path
selection because you know you might
want the direct connection to be
preferred over the vpn connection
is asp prepending aws
does understand communities and they do
use communities to mark their
routes so you can use the communities to
select routes coming from a certain
region or global routes or
what have you
and finally even though you know it's a
bit different
and yeah it's all the same
it can get crazily complex
so aws for example launched
something called gateway load balancer
gateway load balancer is a thingy where
you create
a separate subnet sorry a separate vpc
and then in that vpc you deploy your
appliances like firewalls in my case
and then they do load balancing across
all those firewalls so that you have a
scale out solution
by the way they're using geneve because
they need
metadata in the tunnel so
you need a firewall that supports geneve
not many of them out there even though
everyone is claiming to have one
but let's forget about that that's the
easy part
somehow you have to intercept internet
traffic
send it to that gateway load balancer
which will send it to the firewalls
and then it has to come back and
get to the application server and the
same on the way back
so to intercept the traffic coming from
the internet
you have to use a trick called ingress
routing
and that is attached to the internet
gateway and you use a static route
for your vpc cider prefix
and you point that to the orange
interface here on the picture
so that you push the traffic into that
interface
whatever lens at that interface is
load balanced across the firewall
instances
and then the packet comes back through
the same interface
so it's like a firewall on a stick
and now the traffic needs to go to the
application servers
which means that you need a different
route table right
that's why we have the two routes tables
on the top the red boxes are the routes
tables
but you also have to filter the outgoing
traffic so the default route
in the application subnet must point to
the orange interface so that the
outgoing traffic will go
through the uh firewall
and then as the traffic is returned the
default route
on the gateway load balancer subnet must
point to the internet gateway so the
traffic
really goes out so you see you need
three different route tables two subnets
and a ton of static routes to make
something
as simple as a firewall cluster
work well want to have more complexity
let's add net gateway together with
the network firewall which is really the
same thing as gateway load balancer
only it's a managed service of sturikata
ids boxes so you need the default route
in the application gateway pointing to
the
net gateway the net gateway has its own
route table where the default route is
pointing to the firewall interface
the firewall interface is connected to a
subnet where the default route is
pointing to the internet gateway
so we have this sequence of three
default routes pointing in different
directions so that we control the
traffic flow
and then on the ingress side you need
the ingress route table pointing to the
firewall interface
and then we are in the vpc and remember
you cannot control the traffic inside
the vpc but what you do is
because there is not involved remember
we were talking about that gateway
all the traffic is really arriving with
the destination ip address of the
netgate where it's all the traffic lanes
at the net gateway
and so now net gateway is in the
forwarding path and it does the reverse
that translation and sends the traffic
to the
vm instances
um interesting spaghetti mess
and this is just one vpc
now imagine that you have multiple vpcs
in the region
and they have to communicate and you
want the
traffic between different departments
sent through the firewall
and then you have to add multiple
regions and so you need transit gateways
with static crowds between the regions
and then you have the
ingress vpc with load balancers for the
incoming internet traffic and you have
the egress vpcs
with uh net gateways for all the
outbound traffic to the internet and
then you have the local egress
for vpcs in other regions because you
don't want to push
everything through the central region
and pay for the
interregion fees and so on and so on and
it's all driven by static routes
so it's great fun managing and
troubleshooting all this
and by the way you don't have the same
troubleshooting tools you have
in your enterprise network and
traceroute
doesn't work just saying
so what can you do how can you survive
this madness
well first forget powerpoint
including mine uh it's time to
take the cloud seriously it's time
to start playing with it because in the
end we will all
have to work with it one way or the
other
so if you don't want to be like a kobold
programmer
you have to understand what the cloud
does
and the only way to understand that is
dream up the scenarios like i want to
deploy a simple web server i
want to have a bunch of servers with ssh
bastion host
i want to have servers in two
availability zones
i want to have i don't know
load balancer in front of three web
servers so build
those simple scenarios and it's really
easy because all cloud providers give
you some
free level of service so
not a problem you just create a cloud
account
and off you go and you start exploring
don't believe in powerpoints don't
believe in blog posts including mine
read the documentation and start with
the fundamentals
do something extremely simple
deploy one vm see how that works
deploy two vms in the same subnet
ping between them explore the arp tables
explore the ip routing tables
try to change the ip addresses create
two subnets
deploy two vms in two subnets ping
between them
and so slowly build the understanding of
how is this different
and it's really you know if you had
geometry in high school math you might
remember that we have the
traditional geometry and then we have
geometry on a sphere
and then we have the geometry in
hyperbolic space
and they're all the same only in one
case you can't draw a parallel in the
other case you can draw
three different parts well infinitely
many parallels to any single line
and it's the same thing here it's the
same it's just slightly different but ip
routing is ip routing arp is arp
there is no layer 2 and
you'll master it you just have to focus
on the fundamentals
so i'm pretty positive that you will
master the cloud
and if you get stuck you can send me an
email you can reach me on twitter
yes i do blog and i told you
not to rely on blog post but you might
find something useful