good morning everyone
first of all thanks to the organizers
of bait for hosting us
the goal of this talk is to
try to give some visibility to
the ios operating system the
mobile operating system based on the android open
source project
in particular it is a fork of lines joyce
and  to give even a little visibility to
the fondation project because because in
our opinion it
represents a real alternative
to the mobile solutions
on the market today, i.e. the
distribution of android distributed by
anyhow and ios is obviously an ongoing
project it is certainly not  something
that can be proposed as a competitor
but today it is a waste that reflects but a real
alternative as you have heard the first
introductory part will be done by marco
calamari cassandra I think that here, in short,
people my age have certainly had the opportunity
to read it for years  on the pages of
punto informatico he
is a person who has always been active on
what  it's civil rights
on the internet and with projects like
privacy or the winston smith project
it's so i'm my leandro anyway of
computer science die upon completion
different work mainly that
small medium business but i've always been a
supporter of free software
which i send in  mind I use
in my work so now I don't know if
you want to start your
marco starting
system with
good morning everyone well all I
'm sorry not to be there with you or
the 2014 shirt establish at least
disenchanted and
perhaps thanks to documentation that I
add some unpublished is a  onesie for
years precisely that I have been dealing with privacy and
I have also had my
information
large companies
[Music]
[Applause] I
have always been involved in information technology that
I had to large
professional training systems or start
a lansing business that made
me  naturally led to dealing with the
phone in use
already more than that profile I wonder about the world
says
one  parable on privacy that precisely
from plumbing was a more detail
this year we will have one and
taurasi 1 and 2 october which will never be
tamed yes of relationships not only refereed
smi testimonials tell me about memories
in which you are all invited to participate
at home what  it happened to me in
these 30 years in a nutshell
what is a state of security
evolution the biscione a breakfast the
scenarios because the 90s whoever has
it will remember it was played on a par with
the great great strategists where
one could have a  and they come back born
absolute with a bit of self-discipline
in the following decade
2010 what they started to
change therefore mounted bis time and
therefore a lot of services were born
in
2010 2020 and smartphones have
become useless therefore from
everyone's pockets and mary only show  have increased
adopted
household habits hours 20 in
my opinion minute 20 all and have
produced the two great evils of
society order is  a disability from aids can
no longer be fought
on a par with the big brains it is
necessary to pass a strategy of
imitation of the damage that is to play
this lesser animal here on a personal level
and to draw lots for the two
great evils threats
serious problems in progress that concern us
more or less all i.e. social
smartphones are two great things to
talk about there are different strategies so
let's talk about social but the strategy
the imitation we have now let's
get out of it
in a smart and
social way theoretically could not decide
there are those who have it  done I did it too
for a certain period of pendulum
smartphones big pot raiola yes but half
from budan phone those who still come for
20 euros and who make phone calls and I
received a text message and always without
operating systems they can't do any more
damage
and started at that it is clear that if
i can only call and i lose my age it is
social that we talk do not call
so on the chat it is incredibly  you
too lucky limited
human developed and therefore approved mobile phones
immediately touch what it meant
in terms of interaction with others
interesting the mafias with others
what it meant is that I
put it a big damage that on the other
side of the  balance respect respect
and it occurred to me to
promptly go back to the relative mobile from a
new mobile one often to the new and
began to implement on the smartphone
harm reduction is completely the
milans that
developed me
been in the past a movie with me so
past that  mini froome still burn
and so i had to study a
bit i did the cue of the beginning of
activity as with tutor france
the computer process i don't know more
just the influence because the relationship
only actress to the computer smartphone and
of 9 the  90 percent of the time what
I had to do something and analyze
a smartphone that I did a crash
practical course even if v  seen from
a somewhat peculiar perspective on
smartphones I realized a few
things that are not maybe become not
only fact that
much wittier colleague spoke about
it he will lose in the future of those from us he
will certainly be an adult interested
but coming to us that  thing what you
can finally start installing the
possible applications
dinho can apply the
installed possibly that they
should be he did it look
and you have to give him minutes
and mission possible that not only those
are not what is
good
my
need always
now they tell me
talking about history there is always the lume
feedback so I would say that
could 3 mine
problems that can further
lower enough in fact di milic not even
a veil better but I'm still
hair better even
before you hear me I can lower then
maybe
arched personal data more perfect
very well  I apologize then
radiation donated to makeshift accommodation
is  we were saying that the normal normal
ways to reduce damage
i.e. few applications remove as much
permissions as possible from
bonds are certainly a way to reduce
damage but it is not a very effective way
because it requires continuous no
continuous application a lot of time
in the summer under what phone  with all
indeed this obviously nobody's
and above all it does not eliminate the damage given
to the non-applications that
android phones is my case they are on
about eighty percent of the
existing phones in the world and they have a lot of
unusual things from the minute that  they stay in the
background and do things without there
being an application installed they are almost
all in the play service which in fact are
absolutely impossible to install
and in the 28 google applications that
we use without but all announced by
google maps the cfc voice assistant is
that therefore it is also necessary to make another
gas and there are other steps
here too, I do a bit of drug dealing  a flashback
and I'll go back
there are phones that don't have
android and they don't have indeed they are very
old the progenitor
that the free runner of open moto was a
linux phone on which they downloaded a
customized linux distribution and they
tried to make things work and make them
work  things mean that if he were
able to call with both of
us hearing and if he knows how to send us an sms
and this is already difficult for the well-known
reasons of complete closure of the bees
and chipsets that telephones make and
continue to be even now so
after having bought a randomly
known tool and having wasted a
considerable amount of time trying to use it
at least to make calls, promised it is only
in the scarcity of things too beautiful
to be thrown away and he still
succeeds with a lot of paul c  'there's been
a lot of activity a lot of companies have been
producing since we're talking about
the late 90's since then they've been
producing
show phones for the most part
limits inside but they have always been weather
and commercial initiatives and have
never had a minimum of diffusion
lately the two phones referred to
are
the file with the phone problem which are
two
implementations the second in free
of the first of a mobile phone answer
distributions that begin to do
what they have to for the
main performance call sms little else but
they are not usable as a replacement for the
phone we if we want to limit the
damage we have to move in the real world
a world voice bottle that i with
limited space these are
delimited where to put  in
most people's pockets a phone
that does at least the essential things
today we are used to not making calls and
sending text messages but seeing total maps
this is possible because in reality
various folks and androids are satisfied that
derivative linux created by google and then
leaves  I have to leave it if I don't know if it is
open in pure form without services
add-ons without strings installed
programmatically sure that
this whole process is put into producing a
binary distribution let's believe
there have been several before the last one
we'll talk about
someone defines software distributions
to save on the phone
if we talk about software for  the
phone we talk about rome we are talking about the
same rope from the point of view of a
software to reverse view but the object
is the same so try to make
this interchange
let's get back to us and
if the bull must be this an
initiative like that of limes  and
precisely produces a clean stop android
without anything concerning google play
serve only it is an excellent initiative
that stalls in a single hit
any phone of the many supported by me
that have where the
complete environment and I immediately have an
operational phone that the  phone texting
also does a few other extremely
simple things that i can install
apps on  no
applications without a market without a
store
I can install them on from thinking about it by
uploading them by titling them by
uploading them to mine it's not something it's
easy but it's not a very simple thing
to manage between joyfully and
whatever else has been mentioned nor step
forward because actually  a
functioning smartphone could be
bought at prices quite similar to
that of a smartphone hunt start
work however they are not enough because in the
absence of studies in the absence of a
comfortable rob installed that would make the
smartphone at least similar to an
animal smartphone did not exist
and on this  sublime joe s building on
garages the
e foundation of turin initiative was created le not an
operating system those giardinese but a
complete distribution
will be a small software ecosystem that
starting from the beginning s
builds something that from the point
of view of services  of functioning
as a normal profession was a
cell phone smartphone and how  this was
achieved by creating a story from
everything because he knows things but said
in terms he really is documentaries and
I hope I don't trivialize too much with
the cars he corrected not you his
disposition
a micro service was created it's
called mythology and it does  essentially
ended up with the applications being
google places
and then
providing the application with a service
similar to google free or e ak
excuses like no right now we're
off i can't give it to you etc
etc in order to still
make the protections work  this event
possible to install
android applications not much of the ways
the android application and to make them
work with limited efforts
especially if one goes the law what has
not been the reception successfully
but not enough a store is also provided
and it is not the  usual est
that we all know that allows you to
install free applications from
a real market brands from t  utor
say free and obviously
but he installed another one derived from
another market on which he will tell
that he had the road that to all
intents and purposes appears as a market like the
google play store in the second then
install the applications you will find a
good part of the
commercial and functioning applications and you can
download the most varied things from it I
easily found
sites to use the identity card as a
token there I found my bank's
for they were able to use
my bank's types it was given the
most normal applications
if functioning installed in the middle of a
stop that this is a big step forward
for selling the phone actually
insertable in the pocket of the enemy's aunt
with that dealing with the computer or
even the med who would have time to
deal with
badly want to spend the tricolor fish
I must say that  basically I managed to
finally create reason for the dream of
having a well used object a
ragi object  honestly leader
probably respectful of my privacy
not concretely the which reduces a
lot and damage without spending
too much time and without spending too much money
this difficult goal and foundation
has among its many merits on which
apologies at length to that of having
been the first to put them in  able me and
I hope with many other people to
carry out this operation with a few
hundred euros and a couple of days
of work that could have been done
better sergio the funds that
are there understood
this to tell you that my intervention
which was only intended to
illustrate a  personal perspective on
what are huge privacy today 10
to 20 not thirty years ago fully
studied and tackled a sauce of
industries because here you see
even if it looks like a brick just
like other bricks
this is a phone that contains
a dozen applications
upload and by the way a film so if
you are sensitive to
ecol issues  logic more materials is a phone
that costs a little more for the same
performance than a normal phone is
repairable made with
materials mostly obtained from sources respectful
of people's pros is more than anything
can be fixed with a single
screwdriver disassembles completely  you
can change the pieces with large
pieces they cost him you can
upgrade the walls when they come out then
later electric you can change the
camera the previous model as
there is the camera of the
current model which is more three soldiers they are not
all of them are flowers and clear that not
all sims and applications that then
turned around but there were for
example the boscolo of e foundation
allows you to request if an application is missing
to request it I
did it twice and within a few
days these applications are
buying
the  operation of the e
foundation store a complex topic
was detected channel wind i believe
it had oc  the time wasted for me code
their base I just wanted to get
this message across it can be done
it can't be done without particular
android development skills on
tim mobiles in fact I didn't have
and I'm glad I did and if you
use meters I'm in this situation  the
old cellphone on my desk
without sim turned on so many times i had to
find a demo netti
application but it happened once
luca nemoli signs like the realm of
security on the desk without
portable behind
so many times i had to do
something i forgot puts us at  chin
partivo's sim unusual
polluted environment of google this happened to me
once in a month and i could have done
without it it wasn't an
emergency this is another
important story because it's important how
to exit initialize a phone but
get  in your pocket affect that you are
substantially more
class-friendly you can obviously do by quoting in
que  this news and thanks to marco for the
introduction
I wanted to start first with a short
survey since in short we are
not even a few today to understand how many of
you have used so I didn't try to
install I played but used a
mobile phone as an aroma
I bet leandro  now
it goes
ok I don't see hands raised so it means
that here at
12 ok 3 well
ok anyway here we will be
three people
we feel like marco you know
yes we feel like him too you know about cristiano
ok the other question was how many of those
who used a custom rom
they used as their
main phone i.e. the phone they
answer when he called from his number
horca myseria ok those of four out of
four good let's say that to date but
in principle
even if we use a custom rom it
is difficult for this to be
our first phone  the one where we
save our contacts where maybe
we have our calendar etc. I'll
add a question I didn't have before
this since I didn't expect that
all used as your first phone do
you have google applications or that are
based on google
ok ok ok ok 4 out of 4 we didn't get
the good one, in short, we are desks, in short,
ok, this
is where this talk comes from, so I'm
precise and not  just an
android developer i'm not even particularly
fond of telephony no
confirming what marco said that you don't
need to be an
android geek to approach ios however i am
a person who has always had
the issues of free software and
privacy at heart  and if on these fronts,
in short, the best minds have kept the results over the years
the fact that
many public administrations
have also adopted
free software is certainly because
administrations like this like
google dei a lot of work has been done in
other situations we will perhaps never see
get results so maybe the have
of linux on desktop is destined not to
arrive but the cos  what I think we can
see is that for some time now
most of the interactions with the web
have moved to the mobile so
most people use the
mobile phone to connect to the internet
and if in the future it is possible that we can
meet a person without a  pc very
difficult we will find a person who
does not know that he does not have a smartphone
and the question is that on linux and school
on mobile linux is already present it
has always been present therefore linux
mobile is actually also open source because the
basis of the open operating system  source
but how is it that this thing is not done
we are not pleased because obviously we know
very well that inside these
mobile phones there is a large layer of
closed software of google software in
particular the google play services which
we say is the basis  indispensable not
only for
google applications but also for a whole series
of apps that count on this
software to be able to work
here
now of the custom roms here I
also caught four of those who
use it well but in short I think I'm not
wrong and linux on the desktop
we have not yet reached but
we all normally use linux on the
desktop
the custom roms on the mobile or a
completely open mobile still the
most of us don't have it
even though maybe we are in a context
where the skills to be able to do it
should be there let alone if
we can think that a normal user
can choose to get a
mobile phone that is not with android
with google installed as his first
phone  then we have these which
could be the characteristics that
a device must have in order to
be our main device
we have identified fat and functioning among the factors
which may seem
a bit paradoxical but in reality who has
had to deal with the  rom custom knows
that this one is not a foregone conclusion to
make the gps work some time ago
also i  wireless it is clear that if one
wants to think of adopting a mobile phone
as the first mobile phone the hardware
must work everything must work
let's say first the availability of the
most popular apps in the sense that maybe even
we who are a little more sensitive to
privacy issues or  work or
because in any case we have to know
applications such as whatsapp
facebook instagram we find ourselves
having installed in the question I
asked earlier all four of those who in
any case have their first mobile phone or
a custom rom use applications
that rely on the
google
pd software we must expect  that the mobile phone
allows us to do this with a certain
ease
and the other part is the integration with a
cloud platform in the sense that by now we
are used to that when we buy a
new mobile phone we
install and configure our
account because it is essential if
we want to install  applications and
in fact very generously  google
gives us an e-mail box
it allows us to copy
our contacts on their platform it's
like this for the calendar it's like this for
photos then if we take the mobile phone
we have a backup and we can
restore it if we change mobile
we take a new one  we enter the account
and we find everything
synchronized, that condition is created
which is commonly
called the garden role where
basically we are so used
to some comforts that even if
we know that perhaps the operating system
is
quite intrusive we make it
go well because it is  hard to
give up these services here so
the fact that there may be a
cloud platform that allows us to
have the same community that
google or apple gives us is definitely one of
those features that we require a
phone to be our main phone
because they are interesting  fondation
something I also told you marco to say
add  meanwhile it is a
foundation it is not a company it is
a non-profit association founded by the
creator of mandrake and the linux distro
obviously he is not a wizard and therefore a
person who has already had the opportunity
to demonstrate that he knows how to manage with
complex companies have also been successful and
another thing that I think is quite
interesting is that it is
openly privacy-centric
if we look at the homepages the
company's claim your data is your data
this is a clear
market positioning and we know that when a reality
is positioned on a particular object
in this case privacy going to
incriminate or make a mistake on that thing
means making the project fail therefore
in our opinion the fact that they are
openly intertwined with the
fact of guaranteeing privacy is a
positive side of the project and  then the other thing
provides those three things we were saying
before, i.e. the possibility of having a
telephone that saves me from having to give myself
e-mails.  being capable of installing a rom I go
to the site and it is the purchase
it gives me an app store that allows me to
ask for the installation of an app and
have the most installed and it provides me with
a cloud infrastructure for which I
enter my cloud account
myself  my pickled data also on their
servers
we can say that the user experience
within a fondation mobile phone
is substantially the same as the
one we have with smartphones
google wiphone
obviously I repeat now here we are
going to highlight the parts and good
we know very well in short  that these
projects
may not work one hundred
percent there are still some things that
need to be fixed but the reason that
also prompted us to give visibility is that
we see when we try you and what
we can see how it works is
really really easy and linear
we have some  on the slightly more
technical part what does it mean I have to use
a
smartphone we know well that on top of
android open source  that is, the layer of
software that we identify with the
google play service all
google apps make use of this software
but also a good part
of third-party applications
include in the sources the client library
that interfaces with google play
service for just to name one  above
all and signal despite the fact that
the application is one of the applications
that makes security its
focal point includes the client library
three-sided well igoogle play service basically does it
only to solve
push notifications because otherwise if
you choose to install the version that
does not include  the library to receive
notifications you have to open signal or in
any case keep it always open but in
fact also the applications that we
are used to framing as
secure applications
make use of the software layer that
derives from google so I have to use
a smartphone basically
means to replace that layer  of
google software  and play service of with
another software
in this case the software in question
is micro jim mickle g basically it
is able in a nutshell
to respond to all the api requests and/
or all the interactions that the
software can do anyway like this layer
of  google software like google for
services
how the ac does it in this case it's the
secret spoofing what happens to the
applications
before interfacing with the google
play services and not all but
most do the verification of the
digital signature to ensure originality
of the google play service
the problem is that obviously micro g doesn't
have the google private key and therefore
can't generate a certificate
that is either original
how can you get around this well the
verification is definitely not done
by the application it's
not that  each application has in
its sources the code to
verify the digital signature makes a
call to the operating system
obviously the underlying operating system
implements the
green light signature spoofing and says don't worry,
talk to him interact with the software
because it's google play service
this is
we'll leave it there but obviously if
you go to inform yourself around
not everyone is
favorable favors  to the implementation
of signature spoofing in the operating system
because because in theory
when any app is present it
could pass itself off as
another app and this would obviously be
a security exposure
in reality ineos which obviously already
comes out is already distributed with  mike it
is understood there is nothing to do the
sigma to school finger is active only at the
level of some and some applications
at the operating system level therefore
there is no userspace it is not possible to do
the secret spoofing there is no way for
an application to succeed  to install
expecting that in another so it's
all caged at an operating system level
o and checked cir built
only those parts that
allowed the book to use the phone
then we talked about the apps of the apps that
work here try to show him the
phone
this is jos
this is the app store you are
facing
ok
let's try to search  some applications
let's go with those of google
and youtube it is ready to install
whatsapp
and it is ready to install
you will see that all the applications that
we are used to using are already
here, ready to be installed and
used, which I had already prepared for
the municipality there  it's facebook etc.
ok and this is definitely not something
that takes for granted for those who, as I said before,
have used custom roms
what's the question how that has a bit of
a
dull point in this system
josé's app store
declares to
download applications from the service
that tassels that the dot org
genetics the dot organ
interesting service because in any case it says that
in the applications that it approves
a checks the digital certificate and
then verifies that they are original the
bluff a check a check with the
exodus privacy service to
verify that there are no trackers if
we take a moment off the phone and
open an application
you see here that in addition to the
user rating  there is also a privacy rating of
8 out of 10 which means that the application
contains something that sends data to
someone else android layer applications
normally have a rating of
ten out of ten
obviously this is already a useful thing
because it also allows us  without going to
look for information on the application
to get an idea of ​​how intrusive it can be
is the rank of
open source applications boys 13 out of 10 to 9 out of 10
because in short they are
included when open applications are
developed with platforms that
have the possibility  to report
any errors and the developers
have inserted three cards but only three
carbons but it is right for d  give you
the information in the extreme case to
look for an application that you consider
safe and you don't find now even ten
out of ten
let's go back to the clean up x.org speech
so let's say it provides an excellent service
because we said it provides us with
all the applications we
need there are  additional services because it
checks that they are original because it
checks that there are no trackers
as marco said it is even
possible to request an application from the mobile phone
if we cannot find it times
also seem to be quick enough
to find it present in the app store
however it also tells us that the
open applications it takes from ex droid it does not tell us
where the other applications and other apis arrive, however,
which of
course when a company presents itself
as a supporter
of privacy it is easy for the
forums to be populated by people who are
particularly sensitive to issues
of  privacy
in fact if you take a look you will
find above all a thread where they are
quite harsh on this point
against fondation
, in the end after long
discussions a faq was generated where basically
the bunds and shawn says that she
periodically receives
collaboration proposals that it seemed to him that the
picai dot org climate proposal was
the valid proposal  who have been
using it for several years who are
also inviting users to report
any problems and that to date
there are no problems so this is
what we have to stop at of the
conjectures that have obviously been made it
is that behind
the cloud applications there are  other
app stores such as
aurora who mentioned marco or ap chi
although
it is another store that basically
sums up gateways to google play and
aurora sine install it open ask
just connect to google play with your
account or anonymously if you choose
anonymous way they use a  their account and all
they do is tell you what application
you want they fish it from google  plate they
return it and then in the
operating system you do what you want so it
is easy to understand that behind
the clean up cloud applications
there may be one of
these stores with the problem of these
stores that there are those who raise  doubts
that they are
legal on the fact that they can do this
thing
and here one could make a huge conjecture
that therefore clean up and point org could
be a ploy made to
protect themselves in the event that tomorrow morning
google wakes up and wants to be a
propose boxes from the  legal point of view
repeats it these are conjectures to date
we stop at the fact that we have the
availability of all the applications
that in most of the
applications we need that are
installed with a click and that the
open ones come from freud and this is
all we can say
so then the problem arises
of saying or an application and klose let's
install whatsapp I made a
phone  or some bugs and now
an application that in any case does its
good job of profiling sends to
my contacts sends to my photos it's a
pity because it would be nice to be able to
limit this annoyance a bit it is
also possible to do this because
when companies have had  the need
to deliver to your employees with
a mobile phone just to prevent them
from forgetting their home when they were out and about
fatality that of the company
was developed what is called
work profile and essentially it
is a sandbox within the
operating system where  the company can install
the company applications
the data the contacts in the company address book the
company files and keep
completely separate from the personal ones
therefore basically a user can
have his contacts his family members
his vacation photos on his
personal profile and instead have those  which
are company data company documents
and company contacts on work profile
shelte  r is a software that takes advantage of
this feature I don't know if it
can be seen here no
we are on the phone
I have already installed it for convenience and
for even times
we can see it from here
basically shelter shows the apps
installed in the main profile and then
tells you that you can  clone them on shelter
essentially in workgroups what
you can do in fact is to
select an application and click
on ready shelter to find yourself with
the application installed in the work
profile one thing I didn't tell you
sorry for a moment
when we go up shelter we see that
by default
we already have
the contacts file and micro g installed in the work profile
if we go to see the applications on
the desktop of the mobile phone we see that
we have a contact icon with a
padlock and it does not remember a file with a
padlock while we have another one that
i'm who are the ones by default
proving they are separate moments
i had created contacts in my
profile when installing  to shelter the
contacts on the web profile are empty
so when on this it means that
even if they access the
contacts, all the applications installed in the work profiles will access the contacts that we
decide to insert here
the standard modus operandi for those who
use shelter is to insert
on the contacts  that he needs and
possibly obviously cleaning up additional data by
leaving the
telephone number and perhaps a nickname so
that even if the data is sent,
the use that can be made is
substantially limited
the last suggestion I give you in
relation to shelter
is that  not to clone the applications
as I showed before
ok but to clone the app store directly on shelter
and then
possibly install applications
from the cloned app store on shelter so
if I want to install whatsapp
this is their success and this instance of
whatsapp
will have access  only to the work
profile boxes and the applications and data
that are installed there  there are
that this already represents the
possibility of saying
either a phone where or
the applications I need but the
applications I need I have had the
possibility of relegating them to a context
where I have more control over the data they
can read
ok let's see what comes  after the part of the
cloud that came first as an
important part
to have a phone a smartphone
as the main phone
the foundation makes its own
infrastructure available and if we go to
the account section of the phone
we have the option of entering a
google account this  it means that if
we already have a google account on our
current phone we can
configure the
username and password profile of our google account here
and see our
contacts, our files and our photos synchronized on the
foundation mobile obviously
this is not the optimal result and
therefore a  alternative solutions to
that, for example, of registering an
acc  ount on the fondation cloud and
keep the data on this cloud
obviously the functions are the
same when I enter an account
in the address book this venera tuned
to the fondation cloud so for the photos
for the calendar etc. another thing
that is very interesting  that I
can do this since
standard protocols of card
hard caldav are used use a web account
from I personally use a
zimbra platform in my mobile phone
so we will always have used both as
e-mail but also for
calendar management etc.
the zimbra platform I have  entered my
account as soon as possible and I
found myself with the mobile phone that was already in
place ready for use
marco earlier spoke of maybe two days
to fix the mobile phone
I must say that my experience
was that of a couple of  hours to have
the mobile phone up and running
and I don't know how we are with the times
I'll show you
a little v  elocemente oh well
the cloud registration procedure is the classic one
insert an e-
mail address you receive the confirmation e-mail
you choose an account that
will become the left side of an
e-mail at the dot email that is
provided by the foundation
obviously there is  the confirmation and on the cloud side
we discover that there is
a fork of next cloud
it is a fort where the server side has
been implemented
end to end creepshow so in short, as
you know very well it is a question that not even
the system administrators of the
funds cannot access the ai
our data
we obviously also have the other areas
the other data the contacts the calendar
the photos and the e-mail
obviously for those who want to have
their own personal cloud they have the
possibility of integrating on their
next cloud server or as I said
before any other server that supports
the  standard protocols of Caldav card
or and the ddv desh platform itself is made available
aun
is
deprived quite understandably also
of e-mail servers but there is
the image that allows you to
install it on your server
I would stop here possibly for
some questions if there are any or otherwise
I don't know how we are with the time
sebastiano ok contempo  we're good
let's say yes you have questions can you make
the hand and get the deal
come here to me
question from one of those who already has a
phone why should i choose i s
rather somewhere in the middle s with micro g
then i don't  I'm here to
promote sponsoring us in fondation I
'm clarifying because I don't know
maybe I'm too enthusiastic but
my idea is to present an
alternative project
I think your question arises from an
evaluation of the capabilities of the operating system
what I  I find it interesting
this case is that we have a
complete ecosystem so maybe even
though we got to this point here and or
it was born to fight role
google garden at this point they are not
introducing me to their walled garden
ok they give me the possibility
of self hosting but still
email preferably if
they win
it which at this point is practically
going from the frying pan to the grill
also because I anyway  I'm using a
service of which I don't know where the
servers are because in any case it is not
specified anywhere on the e
foundation site where are these machines if
they comply with the gd pr and above all
I don't know what they are doing on the
machines because as one knows very well the
cloud is not actually cloud computing it has
someone else's computer sure sure
then
you know what the servers are like you also know that they
are powered by renewable energies and
information in this sense
I repeat I am not sponsoring new
re I'll give you the answers because what
they read I'm sponsoring in any
way
so he pulled the answers also because
I made these doubts about his
s  tesse questions and tito the answers
I found ok it
was the part of you were telling
me where the servers are then what it was remind me where
the servers are they are in European territory and they
are gtp areas with briand what
they report is there  a part that
says that we divert cobian so from
this point of view the information is
there then also here it is a bit of the usual
speech that can be done for many other
realities it is the objection that sometimes makes me
say ah ok you install software for me
free you tell me that you can say the
sources spot that will never see and
sources not it's always the same
objection is rightly 1 both these
doubts can preferably use
continue to use google and
google servers if you feel more
protected on this side I  I believe
that running open source software on my mobile,
basing it on my servers
where I installed my data,
gives me personally more
capital guarantees than google, in short, the
dis  course is more than anything since that
anyway and or s is a direct fork of line
and gs with micro g if I still take
line i.e. if with micro g that there is the
unofficial project as the parts
I find practically the same
solution without  be bound by both the
release cycles which are
slower than those of line and gs and
above all I also release myself from the
o s code and therefore I release myself from the whole
part of the pre-integrated cloud services I
release you from their app store which in any case
as from the slides  the source
of certain applications is not known so I
don't have the faintest idea of ​​where
they got these apks
when I can still install the ngs
with micro g install aurora store and
get the evaluation anyway if to pull them with
exodus of the privacy risk of the
applications  down directly from
google and do the verification with
google certificates are due
ok if no more questions
but there are more questions so
thanks to  there is a question I'm coming
more than a question perhaps an answer
to the topic in my opinion from what I understand
the elementary os project I think it's an
intermediate step perhaps compared to fool
self hosted I do everything myself I
compile the apk I do everything I
want  I'm a less
experienced user who perhaps wants to
use their phone in a
simple way without necessarily being
tied to a because to all
intents and purposes this is an intermediate step being
able to move the back end is in any case an
intermediate step between google and apple and me
I buy a vps remi stall
the former cloud everything else no indeed
thank you also because I agree
with this position what I see I
have my opinion because I repeat I
find it absolutely legitimate and I like
that there is the possibility of being able to
choose  between several solutions and therefore
also for those who risk doing so to
adopt that solution but I find that
this is a specific approach that
is pragmatic pragmatic  i.e. the idea
is to say
I want to try to get out of the niche
I want to try to make a proposal that
also that's
why I said in the introduction look I don't
understand almost anything about mobile telephony
because it's not necessary to be scaled
to  succeed while to do what
you say a little something you need to know here
I buy the phone in stallone upload
I use I'm done and if I have to compare the
two solutions
I prefer one it's an approach that can
but pragmatic I see it in my
personal experience as I said
in  'introduction I've been
disseminating open source software
for companies for about fifteen years but the only thing I've
done is that when windows told me
ok let's use windows it's because the field
is hot but the management software we use
management software and I went  leenstra windows now
there's a lot of open source software
going around so the approach
that is a little more rigorous is right because
there needs to be  or in any case chiti years full
stop who goes to annoy the boxes
but not despair less the approaches
that are more pragmatic because they make us
take a step ahead of my parents from my point of view
between a
classic mobile phone and a given group mobile phone
where maybe  I'll sort it out with two apps I'll
buy illegal roma lario
mobile phone of this type
here questions then wait for it to come this way
second second careers
I was a little distracted so I hope I'm
not asking a question has
the all types of
connections that occur from the  of the
mobile phone to understand if there are
strange things going around
look I don't know how to answer with certainty it's
not a mandate that I can give you with
certainty I know that if you go around
the community you will see that they hit
enough because it is clear and you propose yourself
as a sensitive project  to privacy and
those who arrive are all
sensitive to privacy I know that there are
many checks done on the data
you have  ngo transmitted there are
comparisons for example between
what a mobile phone does with google is what it
does beyond a custom rom but I would tell you
a lie it is not a Syrian fact that it
is certain
I don't see any other questions
so thanks to underwater and marco
calamari  who spoke earlier for
this interesting cable thanks
for sharing your experience
your knowledge with aler summer camp