all right good morning everybody thank
you for joining me today my name is Mike
Ryan and I have been researching
Bluetooth and bluetooth security for
about seven years now and I wanted to
bring together everything I learned over
the time doing that into a learning talk
about how to look into bluetooth and how
to start learning how to hack it I will
say this talk is not going to be like
here's a bunch of awesome Bluetooth
vulnerabilities and like we hacked all
the things this is really going to be
more focused on learning how to do
Bluetooth reverse engineering and
Bluetooth hacking but some people in the
audience might be asking yourself why
bluetooth it's not necessarily the most
headline-grabbing technology there were
some vulnerabilities recently that came
out like blue googles tighten security
key and all that sort of thing but it's
on average not the most exciting topic I
will point out though that the growth
has been pretty impressive twelve
percent year-over-year these numbers
come from the Bluetooth people the
Bluetooth SIG so take them with a grain
of salt but it's definitely a growing
technology if not the most exciting
technology however when it comes to the
security of Bluetooth it's a little bit
of the Wild West and I was asking myself
why is this why is there a relatively
low movement in the Bluetooth security
space relative to other wireless
technologies or web technologies I think
it's partially due to the fact that
Bluetooth is somewhat inscrutable it's a
little bit weird of a protocol if you're
familiar with others and I think it's
partly because people think it requires
super specialized tools you can't just
pop open Wireshark
and sniff Bluetooth the way you can with
Wi-Fi or Ethernet so I want to I want to
dispel the notion that Bluetooth is
mysterious or unreachable it's actually
very possible to get into Bluetooth
right now with tools that you already
have and that's what we're gonna be
focusing on today who is this talk for
Bluetooth device developers if you're
developing a Bluetooth device you
probably want to keep security in mind
and you want to have an understanding of
what security risks are out there for
your device if you're
tration tester and you come across a
Bluetooth device where do you even begin
we're gonna get into that
and finally if you're a manager if
you're a product manager or you're
managing a team of engineers do you have
the skill set on your team are you doing
taking the right steps to ensure that
your device is secure so the structure
of the talk I'm gonna give you an
overview of Bluetooth I promise I will
keep it pretty brief then we're going to
talk about the reverse engineering
process and tools and finally we're
going to go over a case studies I'm
gonna walk through actual devices that I
did security analysis on reverse
engineered and show you the exact steps
I took so hopefully you can learn how to
do that and do it yourself
so to start let's talk about Bluetooth
in the reverse engineering process we're
gonna start with a very very high level
model of a Bluetooth device and it
doesn't really matter what kind of a
device we're talking about in this case
we're going to be focusing on Bluetooth
Bluetooth wristband like a fitness
wristband something that that tracks how
many steps you take and normally those
devices have a smartphone app that they
communicate with and the way it works is
sometimes you do something in the
smartphone app sometimes you might press
a button or tap the device and those two
devices will establish a connection via
bluetooth and communicate and that's the
part that we're really interested in
right we don't care about anything else
we just care about what kind of
Bluetooth is happening and I will know
the same is true if your Bluetooth
device communicates with a laptop simple
enough right
so how do we actually begin reverse
engineering it where do we start the
first step you do something with a
device in the app and you make a note of
what you do
for instance if it's a fitness wristband
you might take a bunch of steps you
might tap the synchronize button and
then the number of steps could
synchronize back to the app you'll say
oh I took five steps the second thing
you do capture the data sent via
bluetooth once you have that data you
analyze it you can really understand how
the device works super high level makes
sense right but we get stuck here on
step two how do you capture the device
how do you capture the data sent via
bluetooth that was what I was alluding
to earlier in the talk
you can't just pop open Wireshark right
so can I get a show of hands who here
thinks that we should sniff the
Bluetooth oh okay yeah all right people
are people are waking up I have bad news
sniffing Bluetooth is hard it's it's
hard but it's not impossible
this device is made by a company called
alysus and there's another company
called front line who make a really
similar device this is a commercial
professional Bluetooth sniffer these
devices are supposedly really excellent
I haven't used one but they're 100%
reliable if you want to sniff Bluetooth
this device will do it unfortunately it
comes at a small cost the starting price
on this and the competitor from front
lines around 20,000 bucks that's out of
most people's budgets I will again make
a disclaimer I haven't used this this is
not an endorsement of this product but
from all accounts if you want to if you
want to sniff Bluetooth this thing was
the business on the other end of the
spectrum you might be familiar with an
uber tooth one this is a much more
affordable tool it's in the hundred
dollar price range so within most
hobbyist budgets unfortunately it is not
reliable or I wouldn't say unreliable
but it's nowhere near as reliable or its
useful it's the commercial Bluetooth
sniffer and it is limited to ble and we
won't get into it now but there are
different Bluetooth protocols and if you
want to sniff something with classic
Bluetooth this device won't do anything
for you at all unlike the Ellis's
bluetooth sniffer this is an endorsement
I wrote most of the ble sniffing firmer
for this device and it's actually pretty
good at that I also will say I don't
make this device and I don't get any
kickbacks I just think it's pretty cool
but what if I told you there is a better
way we don't have to spend 20 grand we
don't have to fuss around with kind of
dodgy open-source software and in fact
you might already have a device that
already does this if you have an Android
phone in your pocket right now if you
have a laptop running OSX or if you're a
Linux nerd running Linux on your laptop
you can actually get the Bluetooth data
that you need to perform this kind of
analysis how does that work well let's
go back to our mod
the Bluetooth of ice you've got your two
devices there communicating via
bluetooth and the sniffing approach is
that we want to capture the data here as
it's going over the air well the data
already exists on our smart phone and
this is a smart phone that's running an
operating system we have a lot of
control over that device so wouldn't it
be great if we could sniff the data on
the smart phone before it even goes over
the air and that's exactly what we're
going to do before I go into into the
mechanics of how that that works I'm
gonna give you a little bit more theory
because this is going to be relevant to
when we're looking at the data I know
some people went cross-eyed when they
just looked at this this is a simplified
version of a Bluetooth stack and don't
worry too much about what the various
layers mean I'm gonna put up this rough
equivalence here if you you might be
more familiar with the tcp/ip stack and
if you squint really hard the layers of
a Bluetooth stack match up with the
layers of the IP stack so at the top
you've got the a player that's think of
it like HTTP this is where the actual
data that you care about lives and then
below that you have layers that are more
or less responsible for just
transporting the data back and forth
getting data over from an RF RF
converting it from RF energy into an
encapsulated packet so on and so forth
until you get up to the a player so if
you're ever looking at a Bluetooth
protocol dump that we're going to look
at in a few minutes and you're getting
lost looking at all these layers
remember this slide so with that behind
us let's look at how the the protocol is
actually implemented in practice you're
gonna have to learn a little bit of
terminology and I promise I'm not going
to get super deep into this but any
Bluetooth device has is called a host
and that's not my terminology that's the
Bluetooth SIG's terminology it's a
little bit confusing and every Bluetooth
host has some kind of a controller this
is a chip that is on the device that
speaks bluetooth so in the case of your
smart phone there's a dedicated
Bluetooth chip on the device and then
the upper layers of the stack from the
bleurgh down to l to cap are implemented
in software in the Bluetooth stack on
the device the lower two layers the link
layer are implemented in hardware on the
controller the way the host communicates
with the controller is via an internal
bus and on that internal bus they
communicate using a language called HCI
the host controller interface this is
where we're going to sniff and the power
of this is that we're sniffing the data
while it's still on the device meaning
we're going to capture 100% of the
packets and as a bonus the encryption
the protocol level encryption happens
down here since we're capturing at the
HCI layer if the device is using
protocol level encryption we get the
data before it is encrypted this is
really powerful and really useful as
we'll see you later that's all the
theory and when I bore you with we'll
get into the interesting part now how
does this actually work well Android
Linux and OS X have this feature and
they produce logs that can be loaded by
Wireshark super awesome I learned
everything I know about tcp/ip and
Wireshark and if you load up Bluetooth
captures in Marsh Ark you can learn
everything you need to know in there -
you don't need to spend time reading the
protocol manual nothing like that just
start dropping down menus in Wireshark
which is awesome so on Android if you go
into the developer options menu there is
this little checkbox here enable
bluetooth hcis new blog the Android
phone running in your pocket right now
not rooted nothing fancy
if you go into your developer options
menu and and check this box here you can
start logging Bluetooth from an Android
app and you can pull the data off using
whatever technique you prefer I usually
use ADB because that's what I have lying
around if you're running Mac OS 10 you
have to have Xcode installed and you
install a package called the Xcode
hardware developer tools inside the
Xcode hardware developer tools there is
a piece of software called packet logger
it's not blue tooth packet logger
it's called packet logger if you run
this software on your device you can log
all the Bluetooth data exactly
as you can and Android it has its own UI
for doing some of that analysis
I prefer Wireshark so you can just save
the log into a Wireshark compatible
format and finally for the Linux nerds
you guys should all be comfortable
running command line commands to log
this this will output a log file in a
format that bar shark can handle so back
to the reverse engineering process we
were stuck at step two but now we're
unstuck we have a mechanism to capture
data via bluetooth that means we can
move on to actually doing some analysis
that brings us to our case studies in
each of these case studies I will
introduce a device and walk through the
process of reverse engineering it I'm
gonna start with really basic devices
and I'm gonna gradually get more
advanced now the goal of this is to give
you some real concrete devices some
devices that I actually did reverse
engineering and security review on I've
anonymized them a little bit but there
this is otherwise completely
unadulterated this is the exact the
exact data that I was looking at with
these devices so our first case study is
a ble heart rate monitor this is a
device that might be worn by fitness
enthusiasts they wear it on a chest
strap and a strap that goes around the
chest and there's an app that runs on
your smartphone and you can log what
kind of fitness exercise your type of
doing so like if you're running or if
you're riding a bike it'll log bad data
and it'll log your heart rate up here
so how are we going to approach this
device how do we go about reverse
engineering it we look back at our
reverse engineering process step one do
something in the device do something in
the app and make a note of what we're
doing so in this case we're going to put
on the heart rate monitor and we're
going to tell it that we're running
something like that and we're gonna make
a note of this heart rate value here in
this screenshot the heart rate is around
76 we're going to have the Android
Android OS logging the Bluetooth HCI
data in the background then we pull that
data off of the device and we load it up
in Wireshark and I can actually give you
a really quick demo of what that looks
like when you actually load it
boom Wireshark if I can pop this over to
the other screen yeah all right oh that
fun is a lot smaller than I thought it
would be on this screen okay perfect
so if you look at at this here this is
what so the very first thing that you're
going to see when you load up the wire
the file in the Wireshark is a bunch of
stuff that makes no sense whatsoever so
when I say that we're logging the
Bluetooth on the device we're logging
every message that the host sends to the
controller this not only includes the
data that eventually gets sent over the
air but it also includes really basic
stuff that we don't care about stuff
like setting the device name or setting
scan parameters tons of highfalutin
Bluetooth stuff not interested in that
so the first thing we're going to do is
we're going to use a filter in Wireshark
and you can't see that text there I have
it on another slide it's bt ATT BP ad
and I'll have it on the slide you don't
have to write it down now this filters
out everything and only shows you the
data that is going to ultimately be sent
over the air so there were like hundreds
of packets before now they're still like
quite a number of packets but they're a
manageable number and as we scroll down
the list here I don't know if you can
read that in the back but there's a
heart rate measurement Wireshark did all
the work for us like it already knows
that this is a heart rate monitor and if
we go down here into the packet
dissection click this drop down there's
our value the heart rate was 89 so maybe
I was running or something when we took
this heart rate measurement what's more
even more interesting down here is the
heart rate monitor gives us the RR
interval this is the interval between
individual pulses of the heartbeat so
even though the app is only showing us
the real-time heart rate information the
data being sent back by the device is
even richer than we possibly imagined so
going back over here to our slides this
is the the same information in case that
demo failed that's our first filter
right there BT ATT write this down
you're going to use this if you
ever look at any ble device using this
technique in Wireshark and you can see
mark shark figured out the heart rate
measurement showed us that data and the
heart rate in this case was 80 tube that
more or less guys with what we're seeing
in the app there's some internal
consistency here yes question yes so the
the question was where did this log file
come from this is the log file that was
produced by Android that we have pulled
off of the phone and opened in Wireshark
on our laptop here so the next thing the
next Wireshark filter that you're also
probably going to want to write down is
this be th CI command dot le long term
key if you see this command that means
that the host is setting an encryption
key for the controller in other words
the device is probably using Billy's
built-in encryption if you're a device
developer and you see this there you go
you know that you're using ble
encryption if you're reverse engineering
something now you know this if you don't
see this this message being sent there
is the device is not using the ble
encryption now that doesn't necessarily
mean that it's not using any encryption
whatsoever but if they are using
encryption they've developed something
of their own you'll actually have to dig
into the pack and sit take a look for
this device they were not using
encryption so there are it's not a
medical device per se but it is medical
adjacent at least and that means that
the device is more or less broadcasting
your heart rate to anybody in the room
who has the capability to sniff it and
furthermore the encryption here provides
some authentication to if you were if
this device we're being used in a
medical setting it would be possible to
impersonate the heart rate sensor and
inject malicious heart rate values and
this could have pretty serious
consequences if it was being used as
part of a diagnostic treatment what are
our conclusions from this case study
first of all Wireshark is incredible it
did all the work for us it has a really
great filtering interface and for this
particular device it already
how to interpret the data the second
thing getting Bluetooth logs is
practical if you have an Android phone
in your pocket right now and it has
Bluetooth capability it can do this and
using Wireshark which is free and runs
on every platform you can interpret the
data so right now there are practically
no barriers for you to try this as soon
as this talk is over this is only a 45
minute talk I don't have a lot of time
to dig into how to actually talk to
these devices I'm gonna focus a little
bit more on reverse engineering them but
if you want to talk to the device on
Linux I usually use Linux to do this
because it has a really rich set of
tools for talking to Bluetooth the Gaetz
tool command is the one that I usually
use that's three T's in a row G a TTT
ool and this device lets you do really
basic rudimentary communication with
Bluetooth you'll see a list of uu IDs
here and most of these UUID values to
find services that are standardized by
the Bluetooth SIG and you know in one
case there's a device information
service and there's a heartrate service
and I'll tell you about how to find that
information in a moment so these are
these are standard services and that
makes sense you would expect to see a
heartrate service on a heartrate monitor
you would expect to see a device
information service but if you look down
here at the bottom there's this 128-bit
UUID that doesn't fit in with a rest it
looks like a long random value this is
not standardized by the Bluetooth SIG
this is something custom for this from
this manufacturer and there are a couple
of ways that you can go about trying to
interpret that and trying to talk to
this device and figure out the protocol
you can start sending messages to it and
you can see you know what do you UID the
actual UID of the characteristic is the
approach that I actually recommend is
take that value plug it in to Google and
see if somebody else has already looked
at this device in at least 25% of the
cases that I've looked at I've either
found a thread of people somewhere who
have done some reverse engineering of
the device or I found github
repositories they have some of the the
white label source code that the Chinese
manufacturer used so you find some
interesting stuff this way our second
case study is a ble blood pressure
and I was actually talking to somebody
before this talk they have this exact
blood pressure monitor at home this
device you might be surprised to hear
that a ble blood pressure monitor exists
they're really common actually and this
is the first case of what I like to call
a Bluetooth Madlib if anybody is
familiar with Mad Libs from like middle
school you have to insert like they say
to select it now and select a verb that
uh well Bluetooth Mad Libs the way it
works is you select a noun and then you
add Bluetooth to the beginning and
somebody in Silicon Valley is working on
a product that does just that so in this
case our noun is blood pressure monitor
this one is a ble blood pressure monitor
you put on a blood pressure cuff you
take a measurement and then it connects
to an app on your smart phone that logs
that and logs it over time I guess
there's a market for this it's not
intended to be used in a medical setting
but I know at least in one case
somebody's doctor recommended that they
they purchase it how are we going to
reverse engineer this device similar to
how we did the last one we're going to
do something with the device and we're
going to log that data we're gonna make
a note of what we did so in this case
we're taking a blood pressure
measurement so you'd probably write down
what blood pressure values were recorded
by the app and then when we look at the
data we're gonna look for that
information I will also point out on
this particular device the only way to
get it to generate data via bluetooth
was to take a blood pressure measurement
so when I was testing it I ended up
having to take my blood pressure like 20
times in a row it's just somewhat
uncomfortable so just know that like if
you're gonna be doing Bluetooth testing
things might get physical fast for you
so yes Bluetooth in this case I can pop
up wireshark again why not let's open
another file
okay we're gonna open our blood pressure
monitor here and again we're using the
BT @ filter and when we look at our data
here nothing jumps out at us I will say
the first thing that to notice is that
there not a lot of packets in this file
so even knowing nothing about bluetooth
you can start to look at this and try to
get some kind of sense of what's going
on here so if we if we look at the you
know just pick a random right request
here right
you can look here's the data that was
sent in that right request and if you
see a handle value indication here
here's some data that was sent so even
though we don't necessarily I haven't
gotten super deep into the Bluetooth
packet structure or anything but you can
start to make sense of this in Wireshark
you can start to really experiment with
it and in fact Wireshark s-- filtering
I'll probably on the next device I'll
probably take a look at that more you
can really powerfully filter the devices
so when we look this look at this in
Wireshark the first thing I'm noticing
is that Wireshark hasn't done the work
for us it hasn't already told us that
this is a blood pressure monitor so in
that case that means that we're we're
gonna have to do a little bit of legwork
on our own excuse me for a second here
and if we look at this value here we see
something that could feasibly maybe be a
blood pressure measurement it's the only
packet in the capture that's kind of
long and if you look at the Bluetooth
SIG's website you'll see that there is a
blood pressure service however this
device is not using that and this is
actually extremely common
this is our first instance of what I'm
going to call a hidden serial port and
for those young gamers in the crowd who
aren't familiar with the serial port it
is bi-directional communication
mechanism you send data one way you get
data back the other day why do people
implement things this way when there's
perfectly well standardized profiles for
doing this my thinking on it is that
Bluetooth is complicated and weird and
if you're a hardware developer you just
want to get on with your day you want to
get data wirelessly you don't really
care about the detail so you'll want to
get into the deep fancy Bluetooth stuff
this is the first time we've seen this
it's not the last time it's in ble it's
implemented using our
right characteristic and a notify or an
indicate characteristic and this is
handy because you can always tell which
direction the data is flowing the right
characteristic is data that goes from
the phone to the device the notify
characteristic is data that's coming
back from the device to the phone going
back in here you can see handle value
indication that's a notify
characteristic that's data coming from
the blood pressure monitor back to our
smartphone app that makes sense now this
is probably a blood pressure measurement
in here and if you look inside those
values these this these are like the 2nd
3rd 4th and 5th bytes of the packets to
my eyeballs this looks like a little
endian 16-bit value and this looks like
another one and if you turn those into
regular decimal integers you see it's
117 and 81 that exactly matches with a
value that we saw and at this point you
can start to make sense of the data the
structure of this data here and one
thing that's interesting is that there
are quite a few more bytes that go on
past that if you're reverse engineering
this and trying to hack it and all you
care about is the blood pressure
measurement you're done however if you
want to actually learn about more about
what some of these other bytes do where
I normally start looking at this point
is the app Android app reverse
engineering is definitely out of scope
for this talk but it's super easy to get
into it just google it long story short
you can get back something that more or
less resembles Java and in this case
even some of the the value the string
values were preserved so taking the UUID
values that you might get out of gat
tool searching for those inside the app
you can see oh there's a blood pressure
measurement characteristic and you can
actually see a bunch of other stuff like
firmware update service for instance
that might be interesting and if you
look at the code that references this
data you start to see really useful log
messages like received blood pressure
receive timestamp motion detected and
irregular heartbeat this one was really
interesting because I could send I could
simulate motion detected I could
simulate different blood pressure values
I don't have an irregular heartbeat I
couldn't possibly simulate that so the
only way for me to get this information
is to look in the app security-wise what
did I find on this device well there's
no
encryption so that's already a concern
so you're already leaking what could
potentially be patient medical data
depending on the context in which this
is used furthermore on this particular
device I found that there was another
characteristic or another service that
was a firmware update service anybody
who figured out how to communicate with
this device for instance by looking at
the app would be able to send malicious
firmware updates to the device once
again not actually a medical device but
who knows if it's being used in a
medical setting or not the consequences
of setting incorrect blood pressure data
could be massive what are our
conclusions here the hidden serial port
again this is not the last time we're
gonna see this it's extremely common
once you get past the weird Bluetooth
stuff it's just normal binary reverse
engineering and finally when in doubt
look in the app security-wise no
encryption and there's a firmware update
service exposed imagine you are the
Bluetooth device developer you want to
know this yourself before somebody else
figures out about it and writes a mean
blog post about you alright I'm gonna
pick up the pace a little bit
ble padlock somewhat self-explanatory
it's a fitness it's another device kind
of aimed at the fitness market you go to
the gym you put this on your lock on
your locker it has an app that runs on
your smart phone if you want you lock
your locker you walk away at the end of
your workout you you pop open your
smartphone you click unlock how do we
reverse engineer this step one unlock
the lock step two look at the data that
that comes off the device when you
unlock that lock and you'll never guess
what we find on this device it is
another hidden serial part so if you
look at this data this one starts is
where things start to depart from the
previous ones we see something that's
happening over this hidden serial port
but it's looking a lot more opaque this
is just a bunch of long random binary
data and going through these packets
there are like lots of these weird
binary messages and this is where you
start to hit the limits of Wireshark as
a tool it's not really great for doing a
lot of comparative
messages that are sequential and
fortunately Wireshark provides a really
powerful feature that allows us to get
at the data a separate way if you go
into the file menu export packet
dissections as JSON you get a complete
JSON dump of all the totally decoded
packet information this is awesome
any modern programming language ships
with a JSON parser and you can load this
data in that way or if you're like me
you'll write some super Gro t-rex based
parser in Perl
don't judge me only god can judge me and
by god I course mean Larry wall and his
glorious mustache this is what the
output of that tool looks like and this
is a custom tool that I wrote but it's
really only it like a few dozen lines of
code it's super all it does is take in
JSON and prints it out now what we're
seeing here at least makes a little bit
more sense in terms of like our ability
to look at it do you see a bunch of like
binary strings then you see this value
here this is actually 128 bits long now
we're starting to get into seeing stuff
that looks like well maybe this is an
encryption key or an encrypted block and
it's really hard just looking at this
data to make any sense about it
whatsoever
in this case you really have to go into
the app look back and see how it works
what I found in this particular app is
that they were using encryption that was
so you trace through the Java and you
end up getting bumped out to a native
encryption library that's shipped with
the app written in C++ this is where I
gave up and I said it might be secure it
might not be secure but I don't
personally have the time to go in
reverse engineering this this custom
encryption algorithm and that's actually
one of the takeaways I would give to you
is custom encryption is really common
and implementing custom encryption is
fraught with peril it is not something
to be taken lightly and a lot of
companies do take it pretty lightly you
can't just slap together AES and a
couple of keys and say you're done like
if you're gonna if you're really
thinking about doing some custom
encryption please hire a cryptographer
don't let your programmers do it they
know just enough about crypto to be
dangerous what are our conclusions on
this the developers were at least
security minded they tried they're using
and
option but is the homegrown encryption
good or not I don't know I didn't take
the time to look it's not as bad as some
of the other ble padlocks I've seen out
there there was a Def Con talk a few
years back destroying a bunch of these
but who knows I'm gonna pause here and
take a brief intermission because I need
to grab a sip of water but are there any
questions before I move on
no questions okay awkwardly grab a cup
of water here what have we seen so far
first reading data going to and from
Bluetooth is straightforward really it's
it's simple you you turn on the HDI
logging in Android you do stuff in your
app you pull the data in and Wireshark
and interpret the data for you and if
you run up into limits on Wireshark you
can export the data and parts in your
favorite programming language number two
no encryption on the first two devices
huge target and given the context in
which they used privacy implications and
possibly patient health implications
furthermore firmware updates it's like I
said at the beginning security and
Bluetooth is kind of the Wild West forth
case study a classic Bluetooth headset
it's not exactly a headset it's a
industry specific device that works more
or less like a headset and just think of
it in your mind as a Bluetooth headset
there are standard profiles that most
Bluetooth headsets would use one is
called a2dp
this is the profile that your if you've
ever used a Bluetooth speaker or
bluetooth headphones to listen to music
you're using a2dp
the other is hfp hands-free profile if
you're making a Bluetooth phone phone
calls via Bluetooth in your car or on a
headset using hands-free profile once
again they're not using these there is
another custom serial port why is there
another custom serial port
well reasons some they're actually
somewhat pretty good in this case in
this is a classic Bluetooth device this
is not a ble device and that helps us to
a certain extent because there's already
a profile in classic Bluetooth for
speaking as a serial port the serial
port profile meaning when we pull the
data
into Wireshark now all we need to do is
filter on it's called RF comm here but
that means serial port profile so that
saves us at least some of the trouble of
having to look at the data and do fancy
Wireshark filters fun fact the best
Wireshark filter to use if you ever have
a serial port profile device is the word
data dat a data it's just it just worked
out well in this case and again we can
page through this data in Wireshark and
if you pay attention to the bottom of
the slide here you can see the data
changing between these between these
values and Wireshark is not the best for
doing this type of analysis but in this
case we actually can do some rudimentary
analysis in Wireshark and we see a
structure emerging every packet starts
with this magic number followed by an
opcode a sequence number a 16-bit
little-endian length and data and a
checksum and this is enough to kind of
get as a broad sense of how the device
is communicating with a companion app
but it's not enough for us to really
make a lot of sense about it again in
this case we're going to export the data
to JSON using a homeopathic application
of perl or your favorite programming
language you can build a tool that looks
something like this in this case I've
got a little Direction indicator and an
opcode and you can start to see these
big data patterns emerge
knowing the nature of this device when I
see it's a headset right there's going
to be audio data I'm seeing these big
blobs of binary data here this is
probably audio data so I hacked together
the tool a little bit to export these
big blobs of data into raw files and
then turned over to audacity an open
source tool for processing audio you
import the audio you have to specify all
these values so in this case it was
signed 16-bit PCM big-endian one channel
mono and 4000 kilohertz four kilohertz
sampling rate how did I know these
values let's call it an educated guess
but in reality when it comes to audio
they're only if you just play around
with these values a little bit you'll
eventually end up with something that
looks like this this is an audio file
and in fact when I played it back it was
a very low sample
a recording of my voice saying this is
the test what do we take away from this
first that the techniques that we use
for ble devices work equally well for
classic Bluetooth devices as long as you
have a companion app in this case
I neglected to mention it the companion
app runs on Linux but you if you just
run the b-team on command you can log
that data and load that into Wireshark
how much of what we were talking about
was actually Bluetooth related almost
none of it right ultimately this really
boils down to basic reverse-engineering
finally because it's classic Bluetooth
the device is essentially required to
use encryption so in this case there
were no flaws with the actual encryption
of the device however I didn't dig into
it it might be possible to do some sort
of a buffer overflow attack on the
device by messing with length data
memory corrupt and that sort of thing or
for that matter in the companion app
that runs on the system know is when
things start to get a little bit more
interesting I'm gonna be talking about a
ble credit card absolutely a case of a
Bluetooth Madlib what is a Bluetooth
credit card pretty simple you have a
credit card you slap Bluetooth on it and
it's supposed to replace your big fat
wallet this particular device the way it
works is that you load data into you
load your credit-card number into a
smartphone app it sends your credit card
over bluetooth to this the credit card
is send your credit card number over
Bluetooth to the physical credit card
and then you use buttons and a screen on
the device to select which Bluetooth
credit card or which credit card you
want to use when you make your next
payment I hope most of you your toes
were curling when I said you send the
credit card over Bluetooth because that
was immediately what brought me my
interest on device not really apropos to
reverse engineering the Bluetooth part
but I I went and talked to my pal John
McMaster and I said how the hell do you
fit a bluetooth into something that's
the size shape and thickness of a credit
card and he said well let's look at our
let's look at it on an x-ray machine
because I have one of those in my garage
and this is what we came up with I don't
have time to dig into all the details of
it but it
if nothing else it is an extremely
impressive technical achievement that
they were able to fit all this
technology into something the size and
shape of a credit card and what is even
more shocking to me is that not only one
company does this there are actually a
total of three companies that are
currently or previously made a
bluetooth-enabled credit card this is
the only one I've seen that has a
rechargeable battery which again blew my
mind that you can make them that VIN
anyhow same reverse engineering applies
load credit cards into the app send them
via Bluetooth and look at the data in
Wireshark the first thing Bravo to this
company they are using Bailey's built-in
encryption you can see they've got we've
got the le long-term key command here
start encryption and this is our actual
encryption key right here now this is
don't don't freak out that you can see
the encryption key this was logged on
the device that we control however this
is the actual encryption that's being
this is the key that's being used to
encrypt the data the data itself as
mentioned before is logged before the
encryption is applied to it so now even
though if we tried to log this data over
the air using a Bluetooth sniffer of
some sort it would just look like
encrypted garbage to us but we can
analyze the protocol here in Wireshark
because the encryption hasn't happened
yet and we can see something that
amounts to another hidden serial port
surprise surprise and if you start to
look in the the decoded protocol here
there's actually some ASCII data so
that's good that that this is not really
even binary reverse engineering at this
point this is a protocol that we can
really make sense of so exporting the
data into JSON and writing another basic
Wireshark parser exporting the data into
JSON and more creating another parser
you can see you get a bunch of messages
and they all have a really predictable
structure and you can even start to see
some unencrypted data or some well it's
not encrypted yet some ASCII data here
that this one of these is a fake credit
card number that I inject it into the
app so now you can actually see the
credit card data that's being sent over
Bluetooth and start to make sense of
this protocol this byte is always fixed
despite is high entropy and it's at the
very end that's probably a checksum we
see a single byte here probably
something like an opcode
something that looks like sequence
numbers and a bunch of data well guess
what this is what the message format
ultimately ends up being and I think
what really surprised me was seeing
these ASCII lengths encoded in the these
lengths encoded as ASCII values inside
the protocol that tells me that some
parser somewhere is looking at that
length and any time I see a length value
embedded in a string I'm immediately
wondering what kind of mischief you can
cause with that in this case I didn't
find any sort of mischief like that you
might be thinking well they used
encryption they were safe right they
were not safe because they were making
assumptions about how ble encryption
works and how it could how it kept them
safe in this particular case if you gain
physical control of the credit card for
instance if you're a waiter at a
restaurant and they hand it to you to
pay a bill you could unlock the device
and you could actually extract credit
card numbers from the device so I think
the biggest takeaway I want you to take
from this is that encryption is not a
silver bullet you need to fully
understand your threat model and
understand all the possible ways your
device can be abused our conclusions
here though
HCI logging allows us to see encrypted
data even if the data is encrypted via
ble encryption we can get the data here
the encryption is not a silver bullet
finally our last case study I only have
a few minutes left a ble electric
skateboard this is 100% a Bluetooth
Madlib and I 100% support it these
things are awesome there's one wrench in
the gears here there's no app or at
least at the time that I tested this and
this is actually some joint work that I
did a few years ago with rich o'healey
there is no app so the only way that you
can get any data via bluetooth is using
this handheld remote controller this is
just a hardware device that you hold in
your hand and there's a little wheel
here when you adjust the wheel it
adjusts the speed of the motors on the
skateboard in this case since we don't
have an app the technique that we use
for the previous five case studies won't
work
you have to use a sniffer in this case
we're going to look at an uber to using
an uber tooth and here's where the
process the reverse and
hearing process deviates a little bit
and mainly due to limitations of the
uber tooth the first thing we're going
to do is launch the uber tooth as a
sniffer we're going to connect the
remote control to the skateboard and if
the connection is not captured by the
Bluebird tooth you go back to one you
just keep doing this in a row and it can
take like a couple tries like maybe
sometimes a couple dozen tries to
actually get it but once you finally
capture that connection you do stuff
with the board like you adjust the speed
you let go the Deadman switch and see
what kind of data gets generated finally
pull that into Wireshark just to give
you forewarning if you're going to try
to do this you're gonna need at least
three uber teeth to reliably capture
every connection you can do it with one
it just means you're gonna spend three
times as much effort and in my
experience more uber teeth is better so
just go ahead and go out and buy a bunch
when you load the data in the Wireshark
we again see our hidden serial port and
what's interesting here is that we can
see some ASCII protocol data in fact it
is almost literally a serial port it
even ends with a carriage return
character which is a little bit bizarre
for a hardware device one other thing
that might shock and terrify you is that
there is no encryption on this data this
is captured raw over-the-air if there
were encryption we would have seen it by
now
so protocol reverse engineering here is
a sample of some of the messages that
were sent and if you correlate them back
to what was happening during the capture
at the time that the messages were
captured this is what happens when it
just connects and it's idle as soon as
you press the dead man's trigger this
value here changes and as you increase
the throttle the the speed goes up the
only thing that really kind of gets in
the way of of just injecting whatever
speed you want is that this value here
at the very end turns out to be a really
simple checksum it's a life like and
together all the nibbler XOR together
all the nibbles of the speed command for
some reason I don't know why they did
that because there were already checksum
was built into ble however there
no encryption which also means that
there's no authentication the protocol
is very simple in this case it's only a
small matter of programming to write a
tool that impersonates the Bluetooth
remote controller and injects whatever
speed command you want into the
skateboard rich oh and I actually got a
CV for this and as far as I know is the
only Bluetooth only skateboard related
CBE that's out there and it's one of the
few CV descriptions that result that
includes the wording this uses the CBE
may result in harm to the rider of the
skateboard so I'm saying it a little bit
light of a tone but there are real
actual consequences to this until they
fixed the problem somebody could have
hijacked skateboards and caused people
to fly off this this is a thing that
actually happened because the developer
we spoke to the developer after we
reported this vulnerability and they
said well we were following the hardware
manufacturers guidelines we set the flag
that said to use encryption but they
never verified it all they would have
needed to do is spend a few minutes with
an uber tooth and would have immediately
found out there was no encryption and
they were at risk conclusions here uber
tooth much harder to use than HDI
logging if you have an uber tooth or
you're thinking about using an uber
tooth see if you can use the HDI logging
feature first if the device was using
encryption in this case we would have to
crack the encryption and I've released
some tools in the past in order to do
that and I should have added a bullet
point for this but if you're developing
a device and you think you're using a
encryption make sure you validate that
end-to-end testing is the only way that
you can possibly validate it parting
thoughts wrapping things up what are the
most common security problems that I've
encountered devices using no encryption
we saw it in three of our six use cases
and fifty percent of devices pretty much
reflects what I've seen out on the
market there are problems with homemade
encryption we didn't really see it so
much here but many of the times that
I've seen devices they use custom
encryption there's some kind of
encryption flaw be it reuse of a key
improper use of algorithms all sorts of
stuff be very very very very very
careful if you're implementing custom
encryption there were some debug
interfaces on some devices that I've
encountered and incomplete threat
modeling this is what would tanked the
the Bluetooth credit-card they were
using encryption the app and the design
were reasonably well thought out there
were just a few quarter in edge cases
that they didn't consider so you really
security you have to be holistic about
it you can't just think oh I'm using
encryption done you have to have a big
picture conclusions doing this is
affordable you don't need to drop
$20,000 or convince your purchasing
department to approve the invoice you
can use hardware that you already have
and the reverse engineering process and
tools are very straightforward you can
use an Android device you can use
Wireshark you can even export data from
Wireshark and finally by studying these
case studies
I hope you've gotten a sense of how to
actually approach them in concrete terms
any device that you encounter it's
probably going to be at least
rudimentary rudin the rudiments of the
reverse engineering are at least going
to be very similar to the ones we've
already discussed I'm going to leave you
with a call to action
go forth and hack some Bluetooth you
probably have an Android device or have
access to one go try this out there's
there in the Bluetooth CTF the hardware
CTF right now there are Bluetooth
devices that you can use these
techniques on I'm gonna be hanging
around there this afternoon come try it
come ask me if you have problems and
that's it are there any questions these
have questions what up here the
Bluetooth credit card was there anything
that could be captured by Bluetooth that
couldn't be captured otherwise by the
mag stripe or the smart card chip was
there like there was a string or
something but I don't know if that was
on the other interfaces yes so the
actual data that was sent via bluetooth
I think it was the track one data and a
few other pieces of information but it
was essentially equivalent to what you
would have gotten off of a magstripe
card or swipe or whatever they call
those things this device had a smart
card built into the PCB but it was not
exposed to the outside world so I think
it was a something that was on the rebbe
2 board that was up
to come out and I don't know if that
ever came out is that into your question
other questions thank you so the idea of
you know using Android and you know your
phone and going above their layers that
link there that is when you are the
device that paired with a Bluetooth
device yes what if there's a device that
paired with another phone and your
device vendor in that case you have to
go to a sniffer what's there so you're
asking if you want to sniff somebody
else's Bluetooth no you have to use the
sniffer yeah and in the case of ble you
can try your luck with an uber tooth I
found in practice if you're not
controlling one of the vices it's pretty
hard to actually successfully sniff you
have to capture the initial part of the
connection and if you miss that
yeah it's troublesome have you found
that that initial handshake for the
pairing to be vulnerable if you were
there to sniff so if you're referring to
the built in ble encryption the LE
legacy pairing which is what most
devices still use if they're using bila
encryption is in fact vulnerable to to
an encryption attack a few years ago I
gave some talks on that and there's a
tool called crackle that you can look up
it's linked from it should be linked
from my website here I will say that at
the time I think I overstated the danger
of using built-in encryption the pairing
process is weak only at the time of
pairing so let's say you paired your
devices at home then you go out to a
coffee shop and use the encryption there
there's no real risk to the encryption
the only time you're vulnerable is at
that moment when you initially pair the
devices other questions
and you're the questions okay thank you
Thanks all right - uh we'll break for
lunch and we'll be back at 2:00 the
lunches