[Music]
[Applause]
welcome my name is Steve Chang senior
director I can policy development
support here with me today Ron and Julie
from the SS leadership Rob the first
question what is a SAG well s sac stands
for the security and stability Advisory
Committee it was originally created back
in 2001 right after the 9/11 attacks was
originally the Presidential Committee on
security and stability it later got
converted into and I can advisory
committee today we have over 37
independent technical experts that make
up our membership and we advise ICANN of
the board and the community on issues
regarding the stability and security and
integrity of the internet naming systems
thank you what role does a sac play in
the ICANN policy development support so
esic is an advisory committee and such
we give technical advice around those
SSR security stability resiliency issues
that advice is then turned used by
various processes to turn that into
policy over the last 17 years we
produced over a hundred publications
major publications and then other
documents to advise the community on
these issues ranging from a wide variety
of topics ranging from address
protection main domain system abuse
domain system security various forms of
abuse issues regarding who is routing
issues a whole host of different
security issues that affect the the
naming systems and parts of the the
ecosystem that supports them those
reports are then used by given to the
board and then used in various various
ways either through policy of
development processes or adopt adopted
through the board and the ICANN
organization and turn
depending on what they are turned into
various end policies operation changes
etc great how does the SS conduct its
work so it's it's a three-step process
first we select topics that would be of
interest to the community or maybe
something that gets asked of us by where
the board or one of the SOS or ACS that
pertain to to SSR issues there's a wide
variety of them and we try and
prioritize those based on our
capabilities our memberships
qualifications interest in the topic etc
we then form a work party and that work
party consists of the technical experts
that are in that area have an interest
in whatever the topic is they get they
form a work team really that goes
through over a course of weeks or months
sometimes longer depending on the how
complex the issue is on we're using
things like week the meetings
face-to-face meetings that I can
meetings and of course our staff to help
support creation of a document a report
one of those 100 reports I was talking
about and then that report is taken to
the full a stack for a for a review and
through that process we come to a
consensus on the whatever they have
issue happens to be include any
withdrawals or consents or withdrawals
or our objections to do the issues and
then publish that for the community to
use as it will and the subsequent policy
work how do members of the essay
participate in the world
members participate as subject matter
experts and as rod has just said they
participate in work parties in topics
that they are knowledgeable in and they
can either research or write the subject
matter of the report others might review
the reports and the homeless sack
subsequently gets involved in reviewing
reports but they can participate in
other ways in the community we have
ESSEC members who serve as liaisons on
the Nominating Committee we have ASEC
members who get involved as individuals
in other activities across ICANN and for
some of the cross community groups we
will provide ESIC members as
representatives to those groups their
participation needs to be active to
remain a member of ESSEC we actually
require that people do participate it's
a privilege to be on ESIC and it's a
privilege to have many of the members
that we do on ESSEC and every three
years a members participation is
reviewed by the membership committee
members are appointed for three year
terms by the board and in the third year
of their membership they will be
reviewed and their level of
participation looked at and because most
members do participate very actively
many will be reviewed for a further term
of course participation can depend on
other commitments in people's lives and
that's always taken into account
thank you how does one apply for a sec
membership well individuals who are
interested in joining the isaque can
reach out to our director of sacs
support and ask for the skill survey and
the application procedure will be
advised to them so normally we would
seek information about the people the
reason why they're interested their CV
and the particular details that we
request in our skill survey all of that
information is then reviewed by the
membership committee and sometimes an
interview will be conducted with the
member to probe more deeply into their
area of expertise and the membership
committee will then come to a decision
about whether that individual should be
recommended to the esseker as a whole
and their details will be shared with
the S econd the whole membership of the
SI gets involved in bringing onboard new
members thank you very much rod and
Julie for sitting down with us this is
very helpful thank you
[Music]