[Music]
greetings to you all when it's BSF off
as Chris said I'm here representing the
numbers community ii and i can and as i
said about three years ago at I came 49
in in Singapore I think I can is about
99% names and 1% numbers maybe that's
changing I was I was impressed by the
chorus that followed the question just
now but at that time back in back in
Singapore there was a conversation going
on about how the name side of this
community could get to know more about
the numbers and one idea was that we
have a speaking slot here at the opening
sessions of these meetings which is a
very generous allocation by ICANN and by
you all and it's one that we appreciate
as an effective way we hope to to reach
out to all with a few updates which
which I hope you'll find interesting I
speak about the one percent in I can but
it doesn't mean that the number
community is small we actually can we
actually comprise over 50,000 different
autonomous networks around the world
that comprise the internet and most of
these are members of one or other of the
five regional internet registries the
the RI arts and like the DNS community
here the numbers community has got a lot
of work that we need to do but the thing
is that that work happens mostly outside
of ICANN so we have our own meetings we
have two meetings per our AR per year
that's ten meetings around the world
each year attracting probably the same
participation in total as as ICANN does
roughly and those those meetings involve
networking capacity building information
sharing and also policy development so
in a normal year of our AR meetings we
have I'd say between 20 and 40 different
policy proposals which pass through the
bottom up consensus based PDP's policy
development processes of the our ARS in
each region so that's a fair amount of
work that passes through those meetings
in which most of you I think don't get
to hear about
unless you come along you're always
welcome of course at the global level
it's the NRO the number resource
organization which coordinates the
registry side of IP numbering that's the
five RA arts we have an MoU with ICANN
that was signed in 2004 and that
established the that the NRO would serve
as the ASO defined under the icon bylaws
so that's how it's been for 15 years
last year we completed the five-year the
latest five-year review of the ASO
and that was one of the normal review
processes that goes on with ICANN
supporting organizations that review
have flagged a kind of ongoing confusion
between the ASO and the NRO and its
components executive council dress
council etc etc so if you haven't
noticed that we certainly have and it
record the review recommended among
other things that the rars should hold
community consultations across our
regions on how to improve the structure
of the ASO in in the first place to help
to resolve the confusion in the
structure so that's one update for you
that the implementation of the ASO
review has started with these
consultations which will continue during
this year at the RA our meetings and
after that I expect I hope we'll come
back to you to I can to report on any
agreed improvements that have been
agreed for the ASO the second subject I
wanted to update you about is the I thi
and identifier technology health
indicators project which we're working
on in coordination with ICANN and this
actually relates to the comments we just
heard from from David read all about who
is because the rars do provide registry
information services via who is the
familiar who is service I think we all
are aware of it and also adapt the
registration data access protocol and
that information that we provide through
those services is critical to the health
of the internet because it allows IP
address holders to be identified for the
purpose of tracking technical problems
and network abuse and so on that might
be that might be going on the AR AR IP
who is is really the first point of call
in that attribution and diagnostic
process
so like many in the ICANN community the
RA hours are also working together with
each other to ensure that our
registration services are comprehensive
and correct and current and we'll be
reporting on that both this week and and
ongoing now I'm sure you all know that
the point of a domain name is to resolve
to a public IP address a number where
some internet service can be found and
these IP addresses come in two flavors
ipv4 and ipv6 we probably also know that
there are not very many ipv4 addresses
left today we have rationing policies
more or less in place across all our ARS
and there's also an active transfer
market in most parts of the world that
ensures an ongoing access to the
remaining supply of ipv4 but those are
stopgap measures because ipv4 is is
almost exhausted and the next generation
is ipv6 so to update you about ipv6 the
good news is that v6 is accelerating
very rapidly around the world now at the
beginning of this year we reached around
18% of total Internet users having ipv6
capability on their computers on their
devices and that's a huge number and it
also importantly that increased from
around 7% just a year before that so
that's that's great news and it should
give confidence to you to the names
community that it's really is now time
for DNS registries and registrar's to be
providing ipv6 resolution services in
the near future if you don't already and
I think if you don't make that that move
then in a competitive environment you do
list risk being left behind just to
conclude then I'd like to echo what
Chris Mundy nee said about the
resilience of the internet and efforts
to keep it running during emergencies
such as when the Hurricanes and Omer and
Maria hit the Caribbean last year the RA
ARS work in our regions on the specific
needs of our communities but all over
the world our members are the ones who
actually build the Internet
and who are directly affected by the
disasters that happen so our communities
are very aware of the need to be
prepared and also to recover quickly
when disasters happen and I could say
that all our ARS have needed at
different times in recent years to
respond to emergencies in our regions
we've contributed local technical
capacity we've given financial
consideration to members who are under
distress we've supported the operational
communities the network operator groups
who share really critical information
about how the Internet can be maintained
according to today's best practices and
that includes within the resiliency and
recovery of course and also we we
collaborate with public safety
communities where we can so like I can
the rars will continue to support the
cooperation and the coordination that
characterized the internet ecosystem and
that occurs never more so than in times
of need as Shirin said no one is the
center of this universe we all need to
work together so thanks again to I came
for the chance to give you this very
brief update thanks to all your
attention
[Music]