so my name is Hong Kong I come from
Alabama group as a security researcher
today is great honor to be on stage to
share some of my my thoughts and my
ideas during my research work my
research focusing on IOT b2x and several
physics systems so I want to share some
of the effective approaches from the
open source communities so that we can
build up some interesting in fact you
productive communities in our cyber
physics cyber security community so
basically what I think a researcher
should be a sniper as well as a as an
observer because if you look so hard on
something you can miss a lot of other
parties but we cannot afford to observe
for the whole day so if there is a
friendly productive and helpful cyber
security community watch your back there
will be very good so the core value of
community I think according to mr. order
from MIT it's productive and helpful so
what are our problems now basically we
are facing the Internet
of bankruptcy the IOT so we have already
seen the bankruptcy of email right back
in the year 20 2004 some some guys are
using the technique of bankruptcy of
email that ignoring all of the emails
later on and just to send every other
email that I am bankrupted please send
me another email if you rather need and
furthermore we are facing the bankruptcy
of instant messages and we cannot
handling so much of messages now
and we are facing the bankruptcy of
ready never remember the last time you
want to save an article for later use
and you never read it actually and the
bankruptcy of news even RSS the worst
part of it is bankruptcy of focus we
cannot focus on nothing for longer than
eight or nine seconds it's basically the
intelligence or sublime because our
human beings cannot handle so much of
information during the past decades and
I am failed and will fail again because
we need to be forever online and there
are a lot of distractions and push
notifications and there are a lots of
clients with proprietary protocols and
even versus they are flooding stickers
and flatterers that there is no serious
and helpful discussions and even worse
days centralized system all of your data
is stored on the I am servers and not
ready no mark Ives according to the
communication technology is Nyquist
theorem if you want to get the whole
picture or an accurate something of a
signal you have to separate at least
should be double of the signal rate
right as for our information handling it
can be learned that if we want to get
the whole picture of the research area
you need to be read as much of the
information as you can and as fast as
you can and there's another interesting
thing that there are more and more
popular high catalyzer that can filter
messages for you but in my opinion we
should not trust it we should not trust
a I characterize err because take this
picture if the vertical axis is good
news and the this is a bad news and the
AI categorize our will
definitely reported the good news for
you so you just think I am the best keep
on and ignore the chance of improvement
for yourself so this is basically why we
shouldn't trust AI categorize in my
opinion and according to Dan bars number
which is a very simple theory that a
human being can and only maintain an
active connections with at most 148
human beings at the same time so
basically 140 148 raised to the power of
4.55 is roughly the whole population of
the globe so basically this is that is
why there are a lot of hierarchy of
reporting by level but you know the
reporting by level model has some
serious disturb on DJ's because the is
information asymmetry which is a source
of the power right and furthermore there
are a lot of distractions and we are
facing we are in último ultimate war
between our users and product managers
and remember we have the keyboards a
hundred years ago the typewriter the qwt
buckyballs right and now we are losing
its way now are having touchscreens we
have once we had very very fancy very
useful shortcuts but now that give us
gestures and we lose HTML that everyone
can easily deploy an application but now
we have application store and sing I
think a male and now we have push
notification and we have to be online
for error and we lose some serious news
and productive discussion and they give
us stickers right the sum up stickers
and cats so they are basically now are
the products
I call according to Time magazine we now
have a shorter actually I I know have a
shorter attention span than goldfish
the goldfish has nine seconds of memory
and internet-connected human beings only
have eight seconds so this is our
problem and this is a very interesting
research that one one guy use a
high-speed camera to record your typing
and your characters on screen so they
mirror the input lag you can see this
some modern computers are not responsive
than the sentir are old ones and so
according to Andy and Bill's law we our
pro users experience are not improved
for the past decades we are still asleep
still waiting for the machines install
itself instead of the machines waiting
for ours serving us so this is basically
the summary of the challenges we are
facing okay eight minutes nice
so before we want to share the further
ideas I want to give us the conclusions
first so you can take this in mind and
see the following stories basically I
want to categorize our members into
senior members regular members new
members public and random members and
they have a lot of different behaviors
and they have different user agents and
all of them should be respective
accordingly and we have to use trusted
calculator and some board to bridge the
clients together and I have a three
parts of each basically the first is and
leave no one behind
bridge everything and keep everyone
raise everything and to achieve this we
need to build something very fast and we
wait for everyone no need to no need for
them to show up for every every time and
we have to build a helpful and
productive community and we have to rule
out some toxic behavior I met by
speaking of toxic I mean these once
these behavior appears it will never
come back
so let's first we want to learn from
some of the big names they are facing
the same but the bigger problems and we
want to see their solutions so
Lanie's aligners oh sorry I should
pronounce the edge leanest or walls
he is a founder of he's a father of
Linux right he said only wimps use take
a backup realm and just upload their
important stuff on FTP and let the rest
of the world mirror it and the other
part of his coat is he he raised he
talked to organize his emails it just
keep everything in one big folder and I
have done some research of his emails in
Linux kernel my mailing list and I found
that about half of their emails for the
past of 20 years they are written with
pine or Alpine the modern version of
pine according to the hacker ethics
written by Chaos Computer Club
there is a code says make public data
available and protect private data and
this one is the email from the birth of
Linux trolls the Linux kernel you can
see this the date is 90 91 and the
publish
places newsgroup comp dot org dot MINIX
and this one is the modern the the year
2006 he was discussing his email clients
you can see these from the year 2007 and
he is using alpine it's murder immersion
blah blah blah and learn expose is a
facing the categorize of failure in the
year of 2015 that are around the 20% of
the emails is filtered as a spam so he's
very angry about this because there are
a lot of useful pages a lot of
interesting discussions cannot be marked
as spam so rudely Marissa Mayer she's
the former CEO of Yahoo I remember she
said who he/she kept as many as 700 to
800 dame of emails and he/she needs
something very fast so she use a
application called pion and to marathon
email catch-up sessions up to 14 hours
ever wake early at saturday or sunday so
what is pi mine is a very old-school but
very effective email client according to
my opinion back in the year of 1989 and
the pine was the de facto email client
according to this guy from hacker news
for many universities and the pine is
short for program for internet news and
email and remember you if you once used
the nano the best editor ever none of
new now no it's basically evolved from
the pico pico is the beauty editor of
pine and this picture is from slack dot
stanford.edu slack is short for Stanford
Linear Accelerator Center is for for the
physicists so a lot of the
servers provide alpine and of for the
CERN the MIT they also provide a pine or
Alpine Greg KH he's one of the active
maintainer of Linux kernel during a he
once said he trying to swear off of IRC
because he thought he's a great
distraction so this is gkh and our hero
Richard Mathias torment of a new moment
he's read web page said I'm he's
abandoning cellular phones and the way
he's using Internet is quite interesting
because he he want to read some web page
it just to send an URL link to the
server and the server will fetch it and
send it back by email to him who quite
old school ha and Lambie the former
former leader of TBN project and he even
used email as a cat things Chan style of
to the list what he's using is he wrote
sup some stripes scripts that if you
want to put this email and show up after
some days of for example week how awake
after you can just put this email to a
folder named delight thought seven days
and the script will rotate by each day
and after seven days the email will show
up against and you will you will have a
more mature thoughts on it maybe and
guido van rossum he's the father of
Python program and he said I read
everything sent to his mailbox so he
just reads everything so it's very
interesting and Donald Knuth the author
of tag right and he
a professor of MIT and she is the author
of the book ti LCP the art of computer
programming and he has been a happy man
ever since 1990 because he no longer
with emails he has a very good circuit
or a wonderful secretary and filter
every incoming emails and print the
important stuff for him to read so this
is basically our heroes I'd like to show
a brief demonstration of the good old
days
[Music]
so this okay let me show from the start
so this is a server a public access poll
UNIX server called SDF dot org and I
will log into it yes and we have Alpine
sorry there is a lot of mmm this is some
sort of like the BBS style of the
message handling for example this one is
the N NTP server provided by Linux
kernel code or you can read all of the
emails discussions without subscribing
to the email mailing list and and the
best part of it you can read from the
very beginning of the discussion instead
of the losing some before you subscribe
it for example this is a wild card and
this one is if you want to read
something from ext4 right so yesterday
is mailing list and imagine if you
subscribe to such a can of the mailing
list you are you are definitely will be
bankrupt
of email but I think this is a new the
future of the community because the
amount of buildup something some sort of
poll model instead of the push model
actually this is the old school way of
messaging handling and security model
right you get a lot of messages and even
like the FGX the padres yesterday and
the next thing I want to show you is
this is a Jemaine which is a bridge
between an NTP and RSS and mailing list
if you want to for example to read
something from DB on there is some nouns
from here for example they are they are
selecting the new project leader and
this is after the news / thought oh
three okay and the next thing is the IOA
this is some sort of the Usenet so we're
still serving for example you can find
some discussions oh it's not very active
quite and Mozilla Mozilla is still using
like yeah and remember this platform
they are discussing the development of
yeah you can just a reply to it you can
follow up to the Usenet server or you
can just reply it by email yeah next up
is I can see the IETF IETF who was a
public accessible I am MP server which
is very useful for example
I have subscribed actually it's not
subscribed I can I just added as a short
card and if you want to read some
internet draft announce again just to
access the anonymous I am 80 servers you
can see yesterday's message and you can
you can read something very fast you can
forward to your friend and you can okay
the permission is mark it as answered so
the anonymous one is not support this
one okay confirm and the best part of
Alpine is you can learn by exploring
because all of the help will appears at
the bottom bar the other commands you
can explore it so and there are some
interesting emails during my exploration
for example this one is the linux perth
mail yeah this one i can see the headers
right form helsinki taught fi and is
saying a lot of ok progress and another
interesting thing is tim berners-lee the
purse of the first of web browser as he
is published at hypertext and this is
his signature interestingly after 19
days the linux is burst right this is
like 91 and this it is this one
yeah after 19 days Linux is birthed okay
this is basically the demo a brief tour
of the good old days
so where is my pointer so the UM this is
the SDF torg and it's a public server
since 1987 and remember it's very
interesting
maybe you should register one is free as
long as you have published a email to
the administrators to confirm that you
are a human being and you will get it
very interesting and this is some of the
discussions although they are not very
active but you can still see the some
100 school men are living there and the
next up I want to show what we can learn
from the designs of Internet according
to the first chairman of IETF David's
the clerk he said our best success was
not computing but who can people
together David is now a professor of MIT
now the designs of the internet the
inventor of it is Vint Cerf he has three
calls that I personally love very much
the first one is the Internet is a
reflection of our society if that mirror
has a problem we should not fix a mirror
we have to fix the society and the
second one is the more we can organize
and find and manage information the more
effectively we can function in our
mark and this third one is information
sharing is power if you do not share
your ideas smart people cannot do
anything about them and you will remain
anonymous and powerless so this is
basically what the designers of the
internet they are thinking and the
internet design principles Tim
berners-lee he said he's a father of www
decentralization and tolerance and they
recruit he published a talk and 1919 to
and after 20 years he delivered the same
token with the same slice and a lot of
the citizens he said in that talk is
still working after 20 years quite
awesome
he said we reject Kings printed
presidents and voting and Bolivian rough
concerns an attorney code this is this
is basically the motto of internet
Engineering Task Force and speaking of
Internet the underlying protocol
basically is a PGP supporting a border
gateway protocol the Internet is all
about the addressing and routing so the
BGP simply advanced advertise network
reachability with and for forms neighbor
relationships and use metrics to rank
them so what we can learn from the
designs of BGP that each member of the
communities he comments with questions
come up with answers and if you were
cast your skills and your needs to each
other
and the questions answers in
inspirations will be pasta until you and
remember the software Mathematica and
the CEO of it is Stefan boyfriend
recently is publishing a blog post about
his effective approaches during being a
remote
CEO of
warfarin company they even built up a
database called who knows what database
on each profile picture of the employees
that once one finds some problems you
can search through the categories the
directory of the company and find the
right person to ask
and so imagine this is your you in a
community and this is a Dumbo's number
and 148 rows and you don't need so many
active users in our community imagine
there are only 12 active users and each
of them has an ability to remember all
of his friends needs and skills this
community could be a very effective one
so actually this is like the designs of
our network the access layer application
layer and backbone they are right and
speaking of the information handling
model according to later speaking
natural language processing there is
speak retail and listen and according to
book of Elements of Style
there is writers radar and communicator
and according to the new video and
open-source framework for signal signal
processing the source filter and sync
and according to email designs that are
except for the liver and store and for
the IP tables they are input/output and
forward and for the MQTT the IOT
protocols the publisher broker and
subscriber and they have tags called
topics and for the twitter there is
trait retreat and knock actually we can
learn from the common part of this is we
often has a source a filter and a sink
take cheddar for example the the like is
basically the sink because the message
will end after you press the like button
actually Twitter this the CEO of Twitter
wants to get rid of the like button note
we can get from these major E's appears
in case not very helpful for the
community this should be avoided and
instead instead of private accessible
technique notes we should encourage our
members to publish their ideas their
write-ups and their to some like
independent blogs or search for archives
and each of the discussions should be
accessible by afforded 800 members and
this is an code excerpt from the year of
1998 mark Crispin is the author of ima P
which is used in email system this is
very interesting because this part is
his actually address and this part is
his email address but he thinks the
email is the internet this is the ideas
or thoughts from the father of I am 80
and so Tim berners-lee on the Left he
invented the web and the windsurf
invented invented the internet but who
invented the email actually according to
my research this is a quote and emails
was never invented it evolved from very
simple beginnings and the concept of it
communicating by email from organization
to organization is the impetus for the
advent of Internet itself and it's often
called the killer application of the
Internet so
this one we have already shown the email
from Tim berners-lee and so why do
people love emails a lot of the
open-source communities chose email to
collaborate like the Debian actually a
lot of the operating the the whole
office procedure of Debian is running on
email and Linux kernel and in my opinion
people love email because the the old
akuto are good all haskell headers
because they can choose your own client
as long as he speaks of same particles
and according to this link the emails
wait for you and is pushed technology
and has a power of 1/2 men and and he
said it has a very successful but very
simple model we have the subject
actually the subject the magnetic needs
the abstract
likewise in scientific papers and except
for the network store messages and
threading this is the public access
behalf of IETF emails you can just type
into your interesting interested group
you can get up to all of the accessible
emails by I'm ap and for the NCP or you
said the actually it is the satellite a
lot of satellites services the users
will choose the narrowest and fastest
servers to do the news and the servers
will be synced later on I think this is
sort of decentralized to some accent but
I think this is very fast for messaging
handling because
users don't need to wait for the message
machines he says instead of actually the
message is waiting for you
this man is a hero of Internet and he
just rescued all of the you said
archives by the tapes on his wall and
later these archives off you said was
imported to conquer groups so he can
search back the Usenet archives because
thanks to mr. David Weisman Jim Jim
ain't Ozark is bridge for polite
indicate why he beaten and on TV our
essence and medalist
you can this is roughly about thirty
thousands of channels that are serving
by Juventus world but I think the German
dark hour facing some problems that
basically the this site was maintained
by a single man before he's an active
user of news in Emacs and so on the
Linux kernel materials are worrying
about this so a few years ago they
developed a new project called public
inbox stored so you can use it as a
email receiver the MTA and all of the
emails will be received by this some
poor but very strong hold and and the
best part of it is public inbox reward
you can simply mirror all of the email
archive spike in pool because each of
the messages is a git commit so you
clone the rebel you can hold a mirror of
email archives and according to them
they are doing the push model is
of the instead of push model they are
building the pool model because sometime
you don't have to read all of the
messages you just a sort for let me show
you this I fire up a sovery okay and
Laura dot Colonel sorry it's a bit of
small wait a minute that's okay ml if
you want to do some research about some
for example you want to read all of my
email published by tours you can just
search it and you can download it I as a
mbox archive and for example you can
search my some of my name and a few
years ago threesome I think I easily
find all of the discussions and patches
from this project and you can clone the
whole rebel is quite useful the best
part of it it is now served with an NTP
for example that you can remember if you
used up a 3m you just type into sorry
too fast you tap into this command you
can get access to the email archives of
Linux or Linux kernel discussions
so McGinn box.org can be deployed for
for your own communities I think this is
very promising project and for the
newbies the kernel newbies Dorothy
provides some very useful links
documentary documented documents for the
newbies and for the persons that cannot
afford reading all of the messages they
provide editorial digest remember we
shouldn't trust the commercial
categorize but instead of the commercial
categorize err we should use editorial
digest for example this is a news from
the source the alto en dotnet they
provide a lot of the write-ups
of news by the human reporters they read
every emails from the open source
discussions they publish some of the
interesting things I call this the
editorial digest actually internet
Engineering Task Force they provide a
daily dose actually this is generated by
a robot each day you can find different
activities for the IETF and our way em
they provide of weekly right up from the
editors on the mailing list and commits
commits and news and articles
interesting articles from around the
world and there is even some interesting
robots that automatically summarize for
you but I haven't tried tried this also
our practice final part I was a founder
of an open source community called tuna
desperately basically tiller runs an
open source mirror site in our country
basically is one of the largest open
source camera site and a part of them
we also roughly we are wanting to
like the CCC in the Germany so our
practiced the first one is we want to
keep everyone raise everything so we
want to decrease the latency of each
operation we want to keep machines waits
for human beings it's just instead of
human waste for machines and the best
part of it we want to our members to do
database leak style news reading so that
you can get the whole picture so the
members just like for example like the
SDF that org we log into a gateway and
the information sources some of them are
RSS so we use free to xec to pull them
as a mailbox because if everything is
put rev for the route times and that the
human will be waiting for the machine
for our so we fetch the news async by
the machines and the gwa e is some of
the public RSS like in the 30 thousands
of the Tim are served in gwe using an
NTP service protocol to fetch to alpine
and some of our members prefer the RSS
readers so but this part is very
important because the RSS RSS readers we
have to feed back to as a new RSS feed
that everyone pick up the interesting
things to publish to a new collection so
that everyone is a filter instead of a
signal sink right for the mailing list
there are providers from the email
services and Gmail and pop begin box and
news groups all of them are
pre-configured by the system
administrator so we just open new
account for the members then all things
are set up the next up is leave no one
behind and bridge everything remember
there are a lot of different senior
member rayj remember new and random
members they have different news agents
so we build up boat to like a switcher
to preach the messages through them and
we also provide editorial digest some of
them are for the public some of them are
for the random members to catch up and
the most part of the interesting part of
it we the boat can be used as a
administrators that execute some
friendly roles like the sticker remover
and some sort of the serious filter of
the community discussions so for example
a lot of thumbs up they basically are no
it's very toxic for a service community
is a proof of no work and people will
just push the fam'ly button and no one
will see there are interesting things
and the worst part of it is different
from the emoji it's very large stickers
so it will flood the screen it's not
very good for protective and very good
not good for the helpful so a port is
better because we can simply we cannot
trust our administrators we only trust
the roles that can be enforced
automatically so basically we want to
make human beings speak the language of
human in real world if you want to push
this kind of things rose to a commercial
products if you cannot push the product
manager you can like me be like a hacker
file a patent and push again actually
this is a real patent
and speaking of the blogroll
and this is a surprisingly work method
of our members each of them are
publishing their thoughts on a is
independent blog and we provide at least
actually is you know just a a markdown
file served in github and this is a full
list everyone can submit a pull request
and we have a robot to actually Travis
no Travis is yeah Travis daughter say
guy to build up compiled the list into a
single opml file that you can just
subscribe to the single opml side then
everything is subscribed it surprisingly
works very interesting and we have
organized some weekly up meet up evens
actually we are not getting any fans but
remember everyone is a filter not the
sink so the speaker local audiences
remote audiences and async audiences we
want to keep everyone heads a outgoing
line and incoming line so for the
speaker they can be yelled by the local
audiences and they can also be yelled or
remotely by the demo this is a floating
comment coming software written by our
members of tuna actually we run the
software on the speaker's computer then
the the comments will be floating on the
slides so the remote audiences will be
connected and we use obvious and to
provide the fees by unjinx rtmp to
remote audiences and for the local
audiences all the sound must be heard so
the poll will build up some thing called
actually it's not build up just a
combination of some very
very inexpensive microphones that we
call it's a poor man's mica array so in
the in the discussion room everyone's
sound can be heard by the poor man's mic
re and provide to the remote speaker and
I sing audiences actually there is no
feedback line for the async audiences if
you we want to we have to build some
sort of time machine to for them to
discuss okay some of my contributions
the last page I have been providing some
of the patches for alpine some of my
this is my name some of my name and some
of the public in box.org and some of the
fee to XE project so key takeaways the
first is no keep keep
leave no one behind and we should bridge
everything respect each of the user
agents and consider all members and
newbies friendly we and we keep our
senior members won't get support and we
connect remote members and I think he's
a new thing we don't have to keep our
members to stay online
7:24 and they made her payments so we
bridge local remote icing and speaker
together and everyone reads
everything to achieve this we the first
one is we provide accessible archive so
the message will wait for you and this
part I called is high for the high
throughput in for handling the basically
needs low latency and large volume of
message handling and we have to speed up
and let machines wait for human and no
information cemetery avoid report by
level two and provide large volume of
them and trustee the categorize errs do
not trust the commercial categorize errs
and
from the even for the same group of
people like we should build up more
channels or more discussion groups for
them and we provide a datura digester
for those who cannot afford to read read
every messages for them and helpful and
productive we rule out toxic behaviors
with support and no black hole everyone
should provide feedback and human
Rossing we should encourage our members
to broadcast us the skills and needs so
that help will find you and you will
find the helps okay thank you so any
questions will be welcomed over this
information handling this looks to me
more like for the techs talking North
Texas informations that renews our email
so you know nowadays and in order to
share more
your question was if we can take
advantage of the YouTube and my opinion
maybe we can grab the automatic
generated a caption from it and to some
data mining no not the remaining I want
to so that people members can grab the
keywords from it so if I will find the
right YouTube and for the tools we are
using is OBS is open source code
actually you can break we can set up a
lot of the microphones and the webcams
and you can be a director of your own
using OBS to put and push the stream to
YouTube or your self hosted rtmp server
I think thank you okay thank you for
your time have a good lunch
[Applause]
[Music]