people in the audience are really very
little idea about what goes on in the
booth we have a total of thirty-two
interpreters come on when Cyrus tomato
has a high-pressure job by all means
what goes on the booth is very intense
it's exhausting catheters do not just
translate words otherwise it would have
been automated a long time ago we only
ran their ideas which means that in
order for us to interpret we need to
first understand what is being said and
that requires a great deal of
preparation and really focusing on the
task at hand it is one of the most
amazing things that the brain can do and
you have to practice to do it somehow it
becomes very natural after a little bit
because you automatically don't think
anymore you know it comes in shifts in
goes out from the other way right away
in the other language without having to
stop and think all the technical terms
that you have to learn for I can all the
acronyms and oftentimes icon is an
alphabet soup all that makes our job
significantly and more difficult because
we need to prepare so much for every
event
yes it does take some studying some
rehearsal some sitting at home and going
through them practicing them trying them
in front of the mirror in front of
somebody who helps you until you start
getting used to them we have two people
in most of the language is however
there's certain languages they require
three persons in the booth what we do
requires a great deal of focus and
concentration like I said earlier and so
human mind can't really do that for an
extended period of time we work in 20 to
30-minute shifts depending on the
complexity of the assignment and so we
switch every half hour
I do love my job I think it is one of
the most interesting things in the world
and it is definitely the most
interesting thing that I could have
found myself you're traveling the world
you're meeting fascinating people you're
learning fascinating subjects you are
interacting with the most wonderful
human beings around the globe in every
aspect it's just it has all the
ingredients and you get paid for it so
what more do you want this vid Anya a
beer 200
you