my name is 108 aku putra so I'm the
deputy director of electronic
transaction development agency is the
newly developed public organization just
only three and a half years and we take
care of the infrastructures like
security standardizations and legal
frameworks to ensure the electronic
transaction in Thailand currently am one
of the why share one of the five in a
kak leadership teams so I responsible
for to represent the AP which comprised
of 75 country one of the largest groups
of the country and interval population
is also maybe one third of the whole
internet user groups all together
because we from Middle East or the way
to Australia and China and Japan and
complexities and diversification of the
profile is its marvelous than to say the
challenge we have since the day one
since the beginning of I can but like I
said the early times of the gap is
mainly in the hand of academia and
because we just start off with the
infrastructure but lately since the
internet become part of everything
business and almost like electricity i
should say but then on the other hand we
try to look on how thailand has a
country that have our own culture
language could respond to the one
internet the new technologies new new
initiative of i can like new gtld idn
the universal acceptance that you can
use your local language in the email
email address in the nationalisation all
these is in able to reduce the digit 0
dy that we normally call because we have
70 million people and maybe only 20
million people could use the English or
which you say ascii types of the
characters
some people don't even know how to spell
that name in asking but when you open up
all these international eyes I think
that that the most important positions
when we get into the gas we have to
learn on how the other country develop
the public policy end up to promote it
and we like to learn from the other like
like the Arabic countries or the Chinese
and Korea that verify hit in this
utilization of ID n so this is my eighth
again meeting I do see the big change in
the CAC how we work together one is the
cat try to be in the early engagement we
have several working group working
stream that we appoint the gang who will
take who will follow up that and make a
brief that one of the things that I do
see that is changing quite a lot and I
think the second Lee is the
participation as a shattering
organization in Cebu GCC beauties and
the participation from the CAC is
something that that I do see is knew
that the CAC try to to involve and
understand what is changing what is
coming internally there is a lot of
change we we used to have like a monthly
meeting among the CAC or intersessional
e maybe only one or two time between the
meeting now is every second week only
only for the gap leadership teams and
then every month or almost like two or
three times for the whole gap and we
have to do the briefing and to
accommodate the time zones or some
meeting need to have to conduct at two
so it's become more than a full-time job
because you wake up at two o'clock in
the morning for a meeting and then next
morning you go to work one of the key
important no matter is CW G's or gTLD ID
and the key point is that people spend
maybe a thousand of men are working
there I think that other things I always
respect the multi-stakeholder approach
like
and we also have a local Thai community
almost like a multi-stakeholder in the
beginning we call Thailand internet
multi-stakeholder it's comprised mainly
on the technical because in the early
stage when when I step in since Beijing
most of the issue is very complex the
NSX ipv6 and all this you cannot talk to
the public general so in the first two
years I establish a strong foundation
for multi stakeholder in technology
aspect Academy ccTLDs or these people
now we evolved with just setting up and
we agree on the Charter we change to be
a tie I GF so we bring in the Civil we
bring in other government will being in
the student we try to be very proactive
on on how we laid an infrastructure and
we communicate to the people i think
first of all when i discuss with a new
country then i try to approach to bring
them as a gang the first thing is that
the difference from my hand to the other
fora we also participate like I tu apex
essence and this is a working floor
people are come here to work we not the
dialogue floor so I just tell them that
then you have to understand the fact
that it's difficult in that sense to get
in the problem is it's become I always
call people is become like Hotel
California you can check out anytime you
like but you never leave because they
become a communities we work together
the first group I met is a lag GNA saws
and we just talk among each other's I
think this is the community is not the
community that work and that's what I
telling them it difficult to get in and
difficult to get out because you get
attached to the communities and I've
said even if you are not a government
that still are other charter
organization that you can still working
that what I tell them