technical difficulties on the
presentation more from a perspective but
the connection in the colors such as
soon as it comes back to the proper
cabling will be able to get you to call
it going but I thought it's not go ahead
and talk to you
civically cloud workloads security and
the six critical criteria that we
believe are important when you deploy in
a cloud environment so called passage we
are a startup based on at the San
Francisco Bay Area cloud infrastructure
security and compliance focused company
we have 150 customers enterprise
customers today about a large number of
them in the fortune 500 and what we are
seeing is a huge transformation from
respected you leery about tea and
security using new methods like that
right and those methods are not
controlled by ITV controlled by your
business goes into utility
orchestration types of things that
happen and with that comes a huge amount
of challenges related to stop at
acquiring data centers challenges
related to how you deliver new
applications orchestration tools and the
existing environment you have today with
your security controls and security
doors do not necessarily crashed into a
cloud-based season just because they
have said and cloud-based appliances
doesn't mean they crashed into the cloud
that easily and security and compliance
you have the biggest challenge really
loud crash mansion and that's what's
going on today so we're not obvious
security and I think this is a slide
that marketing created to be funny so
yes it's funny but a lot so what's
happening today from a data sent back to
the existing data that
you living in isolated infrastructure
mom and focus on your perimeter networks
and stations would you like to help
patients would you like to restructure
or hardware bare metal casing and you
have a pressing need be and such
behind you protected by your tools and
in an approach internal to your dad is
coming up so moving on will be seeing in
the when you have this kind of
infrastructure
so going from that internal data center
you have with those applications you
control with instruction you can call
with the perimeter and network-centric
what you can and with your clients you
have today through your power all power
finance your ideas ideas your web
application firewalls and protecting
this application was a traditional dad
and mom and what you've been doing today
and then from there he moved on to this
is regular internal
cloud-based application sought an
eternally infrastructure that but this
is using things like so provisioning
direct involvement with VMware vCloud
OpenStack infrastructure now this
applications that were around the
reading the data center behind a
firewall Mukesh ad posted and shared a
pitcher and now the applications running
routes in your firewall behind your file
structure internally so tied up but
still a private hosted model when you
are behind the pilot and you build that
and I what you're trying to do is to
move higher as computer amounts increase
in the utility model you get some
efficiencies from moving to the cloud
that's what you see right through you
not want to move some infrastructure to
the cloud because you see the efficiency
agility and moving the clock from that
internally hosts it until she go ahead
and build a BBC you still have a permit
to build a BBC of what your private
cloud and Amazon Google compute
environments
this all the challenge but
so you building that and then put city
we want to be secure so we're gonna go
ahead and do the end of watch a private
network to that BBC right so what you
want to do is use that existing
you have already built spending millions
of dollars and network-centric tools and
security tools and while you want a fact
you trying to back calls all that work
to a private cloud information through
your traditional
so this problem going to use and your
back calling all unit but crappy
latency right huge issue from a band
with perspective and availability and it
creates a lot of issues for deploying
applications with the agility and speed
you're required to do so the Mex
approach was to find visibility into
that infrastructure that's running in
the cloud which you don't get with this
point you to the next step was to move
all those security prices you have in a
hot with one pack it into a bushel
iPhone packed into the cloud environment
the problem days this particular
hardware we talk about exploration with
high-density Lee chips like they were
built specifically to those how kitchen
to do security into a specific Agra domu
very easy to do and Amazon EMI and
provide the same kind of missions as
you're looking very expensive to run in
a cloud computing model so that doesn't
help you as for securing and providing
visibility and providing concludes you
want in your cloud-based
so we are proposing is that when you
move to a cloud based architecture
whether it's a private cloud public
cloud and hybrid environment
structure using utility computing
internally what you must do six things
and what those things up is one the
security must be at the workload right
which means that the security must be at
the compute level
computing with the structure in going to
the cloud right where they'd see in
total base
hard right you have an infrastructure
for moving to a cloud based on mom or a
hybrid the next thing you need to cover
a broad set of controls within the
security of implies so popular is
virtually in a bit more important thing
aspect of moving to the club and
providing the Julian the speed and the
deployment capacity Yuyuan Garden mom is
your position and this is an area that
you get to hear more and more as
companies move to a week almost to a
mighty moving from the existing
infrastructure to a cloud-based
automation becomes extremely important
you can hear these again and again as
you get the other aspect it as you move
to the cloud infrastructure you still
want to be able to mind the gap between
the two you go from the internal data
center into a cloud environment you want
to be able to use tools to what platform
you're using to would we do you have
with security and controls and
compliance as well as a cloud involved
and scaling would clean horizontally the
ability to go not only skill up in a
cloud infrastructure back in the cloud
model you want to be able to scale down
most of these security tools have a
great amount of difficulty that existing
today moving scaling down good there is
huge you know
hardware that's a high density and very
focused on large amount of capacity they
can scale down to my car service like Dr
B's contain it out and then horizontally
just kill thousands of soldiers and
hundreds of thousands of containers as
you move into a container the reality of
I T today price on this europe brand-new
Stata is that you're gonna have a
combination up existing to existing
infrastructure and some moving to the
cloud using automation so you need to
get these two together and the platform
needs that while it secure what quotes
sayings
if you look at security of the world but
what does that mean it's like you know
somebody asked you know what you up the
bank and that's where the money's right
so same goes here this is where the
computer is happening it's not a
monolith happening at a computer level
in a cloud-based architecture where they
take contain amicus a survey that you
sign up in Amazon actual computer or
even your internal it's a layer of
abstraction he has no specific network
boundary it doesn't have any primitive
hypervisor nothing's gonna always
abstract about it then it's a workload
its cute and it needs to be a policy
driven because you need to apply as you
compute as you see the cloud
infrastructure you need to apply to
securing controls stats you need to be
policy and logically group what we mean
by that is why law it is all good
network-centric reported assault from my
perspective need to be able to group
these were closed up antennas or any
type of so being sucky moving to the
cloud in a way that makes sense for your
support separation of duties your
compliance requirements and security and
then be able to apply automatically
enjoying right so those are critical
aspect what you want to do of course
portability scalability all the good
ones are cross was out the clock is a
critical aspects of what you want to do
security at the workbook a different way
of thinking because you're so used to
getting your network appliances getting
your firewall is blocking intersection
that you can touch when you can't just
sayin structure when you moving to an
environment that's boosting
thousands of surveys every other day or
every month however you want to avoid an
automated fashion the workload specific
compute will quote specific security and
control so we talked about what we mean
by that is
operating instructions that you want on
the operating environment with Windows
operating secular and then application
stack it so so a compute instance or
what we call it what boat isn't just
happened just because you don't instance
or a my Linux instance Amazon it happens
because you have a specific book a cutie
that happens throughout the book goes
abroad said this is nothing new this is
like the basic important blocking and
tackling you today every day right
visit you have that all the control you
need in your internal medicine but using
some of that when the perimeter
dissolves in the network model is off
and segmentation you want strong access
control module into your cloud
infrastructure as you move to manage the
ability to do an on-demand scan whether
through a GUI di he was 99% of most
egregious recent past year had been
through normal abilities were reported
as a CBE
so the bad guys how is appreciated you
think they are they using basic
existing and it's nothing and nothing
more nothing less than using and hacking
into what you haven't hatched century
data protection that a compromise
managed centrally looking at any type of
malicious activity indicators compromise
and take necessary immediate action so
all these things I talked to none of
this is new it's what you do today and
what you have an existing policies was
seen the automation aspect so when you
deploy through rapid deployment
technologies or a job
orchestrate that deployments with you I
cause that's what gets into a cloud
environment with the controls abroad
said it could cause you're looking at
putting so what are those broad set of
controls it could be as I talked to
software configuration security
management very important to make sure
you get so instances you can get into a
cloud environment rarely has the
necessary configuration settings are
hardened configuration settings
according to ISO you when things like
this out which is the government
standard for internal Department of
Social Security and applications
discovery you want to check east-west
traffic ingress egress points in your
infrastructure when you deploy the cloud
even if the cloud instance instance like
a docket contain it
you want to make sure you discovered a
crappy keep it locked to look for those
anonymous activities
look for compromise traffic tied you
applications internal process these
numbers and use it is very important to
understand that traffic was backed
viable management orchestration the
entire Microsoft around this every
borough instances very important ability
to provide separation duties when you
don't have that you know were close to
compute instance that changes constantly
problem in 2009 mama doing so in going
from different provided managing
accounts
place and you provide service security
on many occasion detecting intrusions
through blogging whining anomalous
activist shot by integrity monetary
checking you operating structure files
registry again
combination these controls it right at
securing funds you look so this I talked
to has considered to be the most
important aspect of what we do from a
work perspective and different level of
thinking from what you're used to
in the traditional mode wanna fight you
might even put employment scenario so
I'll get to that in a bit so automated
orchestrated by what that means is that
today when you provision and in my name
is on a new provision 8,000 continues on
a doctors over the DevOps folks it's a
culture as well as a operational
deployment methodology they just want to
be bothered by the security folks be
controlled like this one and deploy as
many releases as they can't and the
deployment of being challenged us to the
security folks and compliance both
always want control so there's a
constant challenge chasing of the day
bopd release cycle from the security
folks and compliance books to understand
how we can secure this instance you
really see how it is comprised of this
is usually when we come across my heart
he saw his prob what we need to do is
provided policy orchestrated using them
up with using Chapman property and
provide that security at the moment
provision right so when you deploy a
bowl game engine you want to spin up
thousands of so what you want to do is
apply to security policies the server
hardening policies while integrity
policy at the moment deployment at the
moment provision so then it becomes
working together she complies and
working together and it becomes it def
second-story your sector and gonna get
those two more and more as we progress
through the cycle of moving from the
traditional like whatever so you had a
situation where I T control its
deployment cycle
the release as well maybe 10 20 year
traditional waterfall based
methodologies were used and had a system
analysis and deployment cycle everybody
knows what's happening today that you're
getting at least psycho done every month
and that some companies one of the
customers o'clock passage is Netflix
support a child not only AM is are you
there
thousands of workloads running an Amazon
did bring them up and down every day but
also put their bus so when you combine
all of this release like that happen
very frequently has become very
challenging to deploy security writes
this story and what better way to those
cycles through multiple death teams you
multiple releases every month until nine
o'clock passage we release about every
six weeks we have a new incremental
release coming up
reality about shop us and and the
methodologies and kind of limit cycles
very different from what you use
traditional so what you need to do it
with that caused security controls and
policy in place as you deploy and
provision your instances whether they be
in the private cloud infrastructure
using utility computing public or hybrid
type you want to do your code testing
unit testing all the things we've done
when you deploy that at that compute
level and all this information
collecting from Michael segmentation to
ingress egress traffic as you deploying
cloud infrastructure spending to
internal reporting dashboard with its
gyasi compliance simple continuous
monitoring and expand internally to know
those things so you have a RESTful API
that sends out information directly so
what does that mean that supports this
type of cloud infrastructure needs
support not only the cloud-based
deployments but internal data center
right
so you looking at supporting your data
center hosted service today they could
be badly they could be what you like
supporting a colo Saudi that controls
just the physical infrastructure and
then moving on multiple public provided
by the Amazon today as you tomorrow
IBM Software Rackspace will you will you
run it will be a provide that security
controls and compliance control across
this full appeal is whether using Intel
XO and again
bridge the gap between type of
instruction with a single single pane of
glass of security and plus I think this
is an extremely important aspect of what
cloud infrastructure would look right
this situation where I internally sucks
day be a medal says 6428 gig of memory
or 2012 good memory and asking for
instance avoid showing stands between
megabyte memory in desktop
infrastructure is not a big deal but you
have a lot of you when you go to the
cloud and for example an Amazon a
migraine since are now known as small as
you can ask what that type of you power
in those instances could be 10 megatons
so what is hunter systems in your
computer from a local data center
virtualization voices thousands of
computing says you're looking for in a
cloud environment could be tens of
thousands of 60,000 you go to microsoft
office you looking hundreds of thousands
of containers that go away every every
half an hour later it would happen it so
we're moving away from the model of the
Soviet Union factory that built
everything to a smallest level to
compute the world is moving away from
this instance
smaller and smaller compute instances so
if you look at in the past
the deal would have taken several
minutes to load up if you look at it
since you're looking at about a minute
to get container so Mike services we're
looking at about milliseconds instantly
up as you want because they were
stripped down version Connell and also
so you need to be able to support
visibility and Micah segmentation the
controls from scripts backed it into
that small computer with its going from
a lot service you deploy Microsoft
tennis so black support this level the
smallest ever has posted the biggest
that was a scalability is going moving
down and most of the existing tools
today
unable to support at that level to
compute the security and control you
looking for that's the challenge of
improving existing permit a netbook or
into tools into the clock and then there
were designed for him I could never
designed for it now knowing since
compute and that's what it seems that
using to deploy line utility find a
speech to the reality light eats not
Greenfield
they'll be fantastic if it's a reality
right so we can easily do it you know
destroy the trees and build some new
factories out there but that's not be
out looking at reality is this which is
positive existing infrastructure and
some that might move to the cloud some
might say it's into that green up soon
you're looking at so we need to be able
to deal with this reality with a
platform that's both both ends of the
story is nobody is heated to the right
unless your brand new side of just
knowing for sure and no no BC I will
give you money to buy infrastructure
today this is going to be everybody's
starting probably but the enterprise
that existing today under percent not in
meet existing infrastructure maybe not
in person on the green Prince talk about
you in a combination of both
so let me try to explain this one this
is something that got more to do more
but I T is additional now you are using
existing technologies waterfall methods
and you're releasing outpatients every
couple of times and you have a very long
kid and so oriented meetings and you
have been a traditional a soft analysis
going on before you put the proper and
getting less and less as time moves on
the upper the green light year the Queen
Margaret talk about MOTU of I T
we're looking at a Sprint show-business
demanded the speed you looking for and
folks are moving there may be there in
20 that patients initially low risk
applications into that day off a psycho
we talked about before but as you move
companies are so many here right now as
you move on that deployment cycle
accelerates and eventually all organized
social mood to give up its I don't know
when that will happen but they'll have
more applications I'm 02 of IP the
spending methodology deployment because
of the competition that you gonna face
from other businesses that are pointing
at Dollar Tree and then this could be
something in between so the tools you a
platform you choose for security
controls and compliance moved to the pot
need to support bookmarks that support
so reality today what you like
infrastructure service maybe you have to
compute model until we have some
customers who do that until they made
using continues into custody papers so
delivery but they may be using their bob
stewart's like sharpen and Jenkins type
of Engineers integration using be cloudy
but then you may be moving to the cloud
you testing set now because of the
options you gonna get the outdoor
business will be mad at you because of
the same you get probably running under
met you and this is a challenge comes
out if mikey is something that the tool
you choose to use our reply so recovered
six things working at the workload a
broad set of controls to talk to and
used to add to that automation
rest will continue syndication hyper it
works any any structure at any scale and
I talked about how the scaly to go now
level is what's more important than the
high school we talked to reality if I T
Mobile now my team working with more to
bridge the gap with this we have issues
around these deployments binding
Security and you want to move from chaos
to a platform that's orchestrated that
provides a kind of securing controls you
looking for and integration was you need
to isolate PIAA
in real time on your real time to the
existing tools and technology questions
are ok you have any questions I'll be
happy to answer those who does make any
sense
okay thank you very much