on on cybersecurity but what makes me
really nervous is like standing in front
of my peers trying to talk to you guys
about stuff we already know about so
forgive me if my voice is a little is a
little shaky I guess let's start off
with an icebreaker here right so I made
this joke last week for my four-year-old
son and I want to try it out on you guys
we're seeing is utopia so what do you
call a sheep that the cop anyone sheet
that the cup of police officer at work I
mean I worked for my four-year-old so so
I'm Justin hardy I've been doing cyber
security for 22 years I got started in
1994 when I worked for the first
national ISP and if you remember company
called netcom anyone anyone there you go
old old ISP they get gave out UNIX shell
accounts back and center was for 13 days
and had a like a little slip PPP product
they had for Windows and one day this
japanese guy came in and said you guys
have been owned course he didn't say oh
and that's like what the last 10 years
that we've figured out what underpins
means and he's like this guy came in
I've been tracking them seem credit card
from you guys we had to put up the first
firewalls that way before Cisco you had
a fire also like 94 livingstone firewall
he goes remember though the Livingston
company will that guy turned out to be
tsutomo shimumora the guy who hacked our
company was kevin mitnick so that's
really how and why I got into security
and since then I worked big breaches
like Sony in 2011 my team was on the
ground that Sony Playstation they want
done in to respond to mainland China I'm
probably the only American ever do set
foot on China doing actual incident
response was out there for a couple of
months
and so what I want to talk to you today
about is the Apple vs DOD case and just
seems like every day we hear new stuff
happening and kind of how it affects us
in the commercial world so in in the
ordering of events you know first off I
did say that a lot of this is is my
opinion so it's not that it's not
necessarily shared by the company said
Ellis we make network analytic security
products have an endpoint product that
does detector response in the end point
we have a consulting team but response
to breaches so the first thing here is
my labor work or the the thing that not
ever lose sight of his number one
fourteen people died in a lot of people
were injured so my heart I think all of
our hearts go out to the victims of this
senseless domestic crime and this guy
and his wife murdered all of these
people and he had a work iPhone in
January 2016 the FBI requested the
iCloud password to be changed and this
is really what created what started the
big who + so just an informal poll just
an informal poll who here is an Apple
user or I iPhone Wow jeans I'd say I'm
wrong but that's like 80% 85% maybe
eighty six and a half percent
and when you when you change your iCloud
password you gotta do it in two places
right you gotta
if you do on the web you get a change it
on the web and then you go to go to your
device and change it on your phone and
when you change your iCloud password in
this manner meeting on the web or Apple
did it it created this problem so that
Saeed Farooq's iPhone couldn't have been
backed up right because when you it will
automatically back up to the cloud by
default if you have a power source and
you're connected to a trusted wifi so if
if the FBI had not requested that of
Apple we probably still couldn't plug in
his phone he could have taken it to the
what was cited for employers San
Bernardino County of mental health right
with the health department so they maybe
I could have just taken in his phone and
plug it in and it was an older phone it
was a five see so there was no
fingerprints so you couldn't take his
corpse and put his thumb on the on the
unlock because it was an older from the
feisty doesn't have it so they created
this problem and they realize that the
last iCloud backup with six weeks old so
before the attacks or six weeks ago he
backed up you must be in the office and
backed up and then nothing happened
between them so the FBI naturally wants
and I believe they are correct in their
investigation procedures they need to
unlock that phone and see that six-week
period I part of my role at Fidelis is
also to work with the media which I do
about 90% the time and I we all know
this I think I hope all of you know this
but the media kept asking me like I got
it received increased three weeks ago
from political there like what the FBI
hope to gain in a six-week period am i
mean
you never know who he's who's texting
who he's i messaging who he's doing any
of this to and political came back with
wall what the carrier args what about he
was probably with Verizon Sprint or AT&T
right for the most part what about their
Kerry likes kids they collect many data
they collect who you're calling they
collect SMS numbers they don't know the
content percent maybe they do
SMS is not encrypted or maybe Apple
could have said that I message recipient
was this e-mail address or this or this
phone number but they want to see the
content they just don't want to see the
metadata around the transaction may also
want to see if Saeed was downloading
something like Skype or whatsapp
something that that the carrier really
wouldn't have disability into and in
that respect so I believe they had
absolutely Cinemark West comey told the
senate and 2009 we're still trying to
unlock yet and they started to go to
Apple and ask them for help
also in February a couple more things
happened once it became public that the
FBI requested Apple unlock it
the there is a big public outcry just do
this one found just unlocked this and
the government will go away right just a
terrorism case well the fact of the
matter is had Apple unlocked at the new
york district attorney and a state
attorney had over a hundred and
seventy-five iPhones ready to go
ready to subpoena Apple thing used that
same tool that you made to unlock it and
I believe the next speaker's ahead and
Christopher great lawyers and attorneys
are going to be there in this room or in
another room I highly recommend you go
there to hear about this but they're
going to talk about the All Rights Act
of 1789 which was which is really darn
cold
two hundred and twenty or thirty years
old that said the government can compel
individuals or organizations to comply
or assist them in a time of need an
investigation or situations so without
that the the government had no right and
no legal ability to ask Apple perform
some development now what's one thing
that to subpoena a vendor and saying
push this button we know you have the
capability today
unlock this phone or change this
password for instance that's easy or
hand over documents that you have is not
easy to say develop sit down with your
developers and spend year on resources
to develop what i do to be a weapon and
I'll get more to that and then hours
before the scheduled court appearance
this last Monday it was funny right but
30th or was it happened around the 21st
it was Monday right so hours before the
scheduled court appearance FBI postpone
the hearing in this Monday the same day
that Apple released 93 they said they
drop the case so I'm gonna get my next
flight ok sorry this is this is another
reason it makes me nervous is like I can
belt out and talk for probably 24 hours
on my normal routine you wanna hear
about incident response and all the
stuff what we're saying and how to
combat advanced threat defense but this
is makes me nervous to the content I
don't normally do so I'm a little bit
shooting from the hip but to analyze a
few of these things i wanna if there's a
little bit of advice I want to give you
today to use this as a as an example if
anyone has an iPhone today and you're
not using multi-factor authentication
highly recommended and if you're as well
if you are backing up to the iCloud for
convenience I recommend not doing that
as well
and I'll tell you I'll show you why so
this exact thing the FBI request the
iCloud password when you are in
possession of someone's iCloud password
and they back up to the cloud which is
both default ok not having a password
but clear text password or just a normal
password not using multi-factor
authentication which Apple supports you
can do things like this and this is
exactly what the FBI did there is a
Python script called I loot and when you
run by loon to you supply and iCloud
username and password and it goes out
and programmatically uses
iCloud CPI to active you and it lists
all of the devices that you have this is
not me by the way so don't think that I
own a 3G yes you select the device and
then it goes out and normally when you I
didn't think it was possible I kinda
understand how it how they do this what
they do is to impersonate you and an
apple gives you the ability to any
programmers in the room one dude come on
there's gotta be some other people have
a right to in programming this there's a
function called and says go to this part
of the files so if you've got a eight
gig file you know that something is in
the middle you can say seek to the
middle of the file so what Apple does is
they give you the capability to keep
certain parts of your huge backup I mean
if you get a hundred twenty eight gig
and you're uploading photos and stuff
your backup is pretty huge so what
they're able to do this script can do is
say go like what you have and then you
can download someone to address book SMS
and photos and it's worrisome for us as
consumers not using multi-factor if we
use multi-factor he whoever had your
password when people do
this is they wouldn't have the
capability to put in the code it's also
worrisome to extend that and I should
have told you this in the beginning I'm
a bit of a 10 40 hat where but I think I
think it's justified given a lot of the
stuff and I'll go over why I think some
of this is warranted but the reason why
this is doable because people back into
the cloud to be they're not using
multi-factor authentication see i think
thats create the condition where
combined with the Apple's refusal and
I'm gonna have to say this Google and
other providers have stood behind Apple
said you know we're not gonna I'm not
devices but hoping entrust them Google
Microsoft those guys that if vendors
won't unlock phones and if the
encryption and if they don't outlaw
strong encryption which I'll get to that
it creates a condition where the
government in order to order to run drug
cases anti-terror cases or whatever are
gonna start developing malware to attack
citizens and attention to grab their
passwords and do things like this that
they can't get your SMS or criminal or
suspected criminals text history they're
gonna figure out a way to do it and you
think I'm a 10 40 where we'll go Google
a company called the hacking team the
hacking team was Italy Italian based
firm that did for profit hacking they
develop malware for nation state they
themselves got hacked by an Eastern
European crime syndicate and all of
their malware got released but they also
released purchase orders and guess who
was guess who two of those entities that
were purchasing now where we're partners
Justice Federal Bureau of Investigation
and the NSA why are they doing that well
the FBI according to the press if they
were doing it because there are other
malware as a backup to the other malware
why is this not front-page news why is
this not so do we have a right to
privacy hope there are no lawyers in
their room because I'm gonna use a
Slashdot / ready term I and what does
that stand for I am NOT a lawyer think
users and get some here
personal statement I believe that it is
an inalienable human right to have a
private conversation but digitally and
in the real world unfortunately our
current current unfortunately our
Constitution doesn't specifically allow
for that this is the the amendment to
the constitution before that says that
we can be secure in their persons houses
papers and effects now this is several
hundred years old toy right but so it
doesn't say digital communication and
says papers and effects so that leaves a
little bit there against unreasonable
searches and seizures and I'll come back
to that in a sec and this is Bradley
being interpreted two different ways the
first is the one that I support which is
humans have a fundamental right to
privacy
affected one is what is being taken by
the government spying that allowed when
there's a probable cause and judiciary
oversight the check-and-balance to this
through the legislative branch but this
guy changed at all now personal
statement here
number one I don't agree with what he
did the method I in your little homework
thing right and giving his homework go
out and watch the movie citizen for very
good in one scene citizen for not enough
of you
125 people 67 come on
please I implore you watch the movie
citizen for because it start issues you
from start to finish the release of the
top secret files of snow it's an actual
factual account so it shows the camera
starts rolling
well first off I can spoil it we all
know what happens behind but essentially
showed you the build up all of the
congressional testimony people like an
associate director saying we're not in
front of Congress were not collecting
metadata we're not doing that
surveillance we're not doing all of
these things then you go to snow D
flights to Hong Kong gives all the doc
the top secret documents to Glenn
Greenwald the Guardian shows all the
Guardian guys my friend Julian border at
The Guardian is in possession of all
those but the point is he he he promised
he made a note he swore to uphold the
Constitution and to keep things secret
and so he broke his word and it's it's
the situation where he did something
really horrible but he also expose
something horrible as well so it's like
in my mind I'm compartmentalize things
i'm saying yeah the guy and he should
have done this but what he did disclose
cannot be ignored
right I guess one more but now it's
there can be arguments made on both
sides on whether or not people's lives
were at risk I think that one way to
look at would have been if he would have
been may be justifiable people would
have been dying because of this but
Americans like what if it was to expose
murders or torture or something like
that but on the other hand what he did
also probably could have put soldiers
lives and dangers but then again there's
also the drone strikes that he was he
was talking about how it was operating
so on so but what he changed was I think
before snow I I was very much
a trusting government never been there
been too trusting of members and open to
things in my life that it really just
resonated with me that changed my view
the first thing is the Iraq war when we
didn't find weapons of mass destruction
that made me really mad and the second
thing was when the government the NSA
was testifying said we're not doing
these things and then they were and it
wasn't just it wasn't just yeah we're
collecting metadata defined threats it
was were collecting meditated and did
you know about all these abuses people
like anything co-workers were spying on
their spouses or spouse spying on their
neighbors and pulling their phone
records looking at their messages in
their tax and i know im gonna bungle
this but the the the quote that I love
is its by the barren and time from
England it was go something like this
you know power power corrupts but
absolute power corrupts absolutely right
and that is as politicians and as
governments get bigger you can't trust
them to compartmentalize what what they
have access to but the more and more
they have access to and and and and in
essence the government or the anything
had followed this power there were quite
a few abuses so he changed a lot of our
perception because I'm not sure that I
would have really had a problem with
apple and locking up a bit like that
people are deal breaking stuff is
happening so how about you do that and
I'm here
ok the things that I would say is I my
personal opinion is Apple do the right
thing I think they did the right thing
because it's not that I didn't believe
that the San Bernardino Bernardino
attackers
didn't deserve the truth or what could
be another six weeks I felt like Apple
would be developing a weapon they would
be developing a weapon because if they
were to develop a code to unlock any
firm but then what happened to that code
they can then be subpoenaed by the
government that can be taken by the
government or they could give it to the
government and then you've essentially
created this weapon that is into hands
at an Apple fans and send the the
government's hands and and you at this
point it's still kinda be like ok I'm
kind of with you but then when you see
things like opium or the Joint Chiefs
emails being fished and secrets going
out the door if we can't keep our own
top-secret files top-secret instead of
getting a nation states hands what
possible hope that we have for not
letting this thing
escape because even if it escapes there
will be lives in our customers and our
livelihood in danger because there's
already documented cases where
executives will go to another nation
state to negotiate a merger and
acquisition to do a business deal and
the chinese will grab their phones and
laptops in customs and they'll pick them
into a back room and not come out what
happened they were probably imaging and
shame on anyone who goes to a different
country doesn't use a burn laptop or a
or heavily encrypted devices small
personal care if you type in Fidelis
welcome to the jungle I do a whole
webinar on this talks about operational
security there is cases of executives
going over to that wasn't homework that
would be really self-serving but if you
want to
there's cases of executives going to
other countries and their their hotel
rooms were bugged my hotel room was
bugged when I was working the breach for
42 months in Shenzhen China the phones
were bugs so there's if this is out and
of course every nation state on earth
would want this here is a piece of
homework go out and rent a movie called
me
sneakers and sneakers is filled with
Robert Redford and Ben Kingsley and I'll
boil it down for you essentially Ben
Kingsley invents this magical box that
can decrypt anything right they plug
into the modem in a double doj they can
see everything they dial the FAA and
they can see and then there's openings
flying around over phoenix was in there
too and the quote that I love in there
there's two quotes in that is number one
no government on earth would ever
government on earth would kill for this
capability and that box that he made is
the same as that unlocking iPhone if
Apple were to develop that the second
thing is that the Kings equipment
arrived for quote thanks Ben Kingsley
said the battlefield today the way they
that nation states are running battles
its 2011 that's not with a gun anymore
so we have to really make sure that
there are no back doors and whatever we
do because we can't trust me it's like a
mathematical fact we can't trust that
whatever backdoor whatever we create
will not fall into enemy hands and we
there's a long pressing that this let's
look at the past few breaches target and
Home Depot 10 p.m. and Sony and
all of these big companies they spend
tens if not hundreds of millions of
dollars and they still get hit they
still get hit by that one guy or gal who
clicks on the FedEx rewrote package
phishing email and then there is right
and this has created this sort of
juxtaposition between spying for
legitimate to to find the thread and
spying on on the citizens is really a
macro version of what I feel like we're
struggling with in in the industry
full disclosure I work for services and
product company and we make products
that do surveillance on the network but
then again satisfy arises lol so it is
cisco and sort of all the beating so I'm
not saying it were unique I'm saying
that as vendors we're running we are in
a in a pickle right now if my PR team
were here they'd kick my butt if I am
going to open this up a little bit they
kick my butt because there was a case
where currently going through some of
this right now in california the
University of California went through a
bunch of breaches with nation states and
Berkeley who do you know who the
University of California Chancellor is
trivia question anyone Janet Napolitano
Sochi
she understands how serious it can be
when when information gets out and
universities are a treasure trove for
nation states because of things like
health care information and stats and
research so why should a nation state
develop their own capabilities in their
own people to perform research when they
can just get it from these universities
so the University California last year
have agreed with public they brought us
in and we were collecting network
metadata on threats looking we weren't
decrypting the thing we weren't doing
all of these things that the government
is doing but we were still caught up in
a student backlash saying you guys are
conducting surveillance you guys meeting
university-california president's office
of the president and so it's kind of an
ongoing thing we're not we're not at
fault for not really were personally
involved cuz were brought in to find
nations to a threat or not we weren't
being brought into that but it's a it's
a really fine line I think we're running
and corporations today and I think this
as information security professionals
it's up to us to do a lot of Education I
guess I should have put that message at
the beginning of September to whether or
not you agree with me on any or all of
these subjects up to us to educate our
family and friends in the press and the
government and helped influence it I
don't know about you guys but in a
furious me to see congress people
talking about key escrow or 13 or hoping
that they can just tell Silicon Valley
to develop some new crap you know some
new software that'll fix all this there
it's a temp fix map you also can't fix
stupid but but I'm just really concerns
me that I was going to be a surprise but
it did it just concerns me that our
legislators don't get it you know
another piece of homework go watch if
you're if you're ok with obscenities
watch John Oliver's thing on DOJ vs
apple from a couple weeks it was pretty
funny
and I do have a tremendous amount of
respect for the senator who said
something to the effective if Apple
won't do it or can't do it they're
stupid and then he came back later on
after that he was educated actually
stood up and he didn't stand up one of
his subcommittee meetings he said I was
wrong so I don't remember yes Republican
right I'm not a republican but I respect
that guy for his views and and be able
to come out like him and say ok I was
wrong i mean that's a lot of 422 yeah
yeah yeah that's so it's up to us as an
industry to really educate people on as
the city's that could attract but we're
not all executives here pretty telling
me I'm just talking head it's up to us
to educate I guess here is one of the
things is to educate the board in the
c-suite that it's not just a simple as
putting devices on its not as simple as
supporting or being against an issue
there's a lot more it's really
complicated to be able to go to wade
through a lot of this and I feel like
the polls are are sweet in a direction
because it's so complicated that the
american people just aren't keeping up
with it like I looked at a Washington
Post poll that was like 63 or 60%
sixty-seven percent of Americans said
that Apple should unlock the phone but
that's because they don't have all of
this extra information so what I think
in drawing a parallel between the
anything during wholesale surveillance
on the populace in collecting metadata
in and abusing that reverses
for the for the public explanation of
finding or monitoring for threats and
and the microcosm of that which is in
our corporations what's the difference
between the NSA spying and because we we
essentially do that right I mean we put
these Palo Alto devices down health
devices misfire I devices and it does
things and it sends information source
right orator log management orator
dashboards and we look at it we can see
where people are browsing the I don't
have any answers for you but what I will
say is I personally think it comes down
to communicating what is going on to
your boys and it comes down to
and and I haven't seen this very very
often when you join a company saying or
you go to school you find all these
documents and we don't read half of them
but i dont the fine print like those
apps that have always been termed the
terms of agreement like us
but it it's critical to be transparent
and clearly communicate to the employee
that if you are on the corporate network
then you will be subject to two
surveillance and surveillance is a dirty
word thats word right I don't know if
I'm not politically correct but if I
were to see so I'd probably say
something like monitoring for threats vs
surveillance but let's call a spade a
spade acceptable use policies and really
clearly defined the usage of personal
versus corporate assets and think
through the the the mess that the San
Bernardino County Health can send
Bernardino County Health Department must
be going through with a lot of this I
mean it wasn't their device that he had
and that that is embroiled in all of
this and maybe it sheds new light on
BYOD as an old school security guy I
hate DoD int but I know I know it's
necessary but but you know my my two
senses don't ever allow personal devices
but that also an Energex some problems
MDM mobile device management there's a
couple of them like iron watching
MobileIron and we're recruiting as
quagmire by doing bio BYOD because on
one hand the lazy way I should be doing
this room hates the in the the the less
risk more risky way is to do BYOD you
are you sign a document say ok now
testing can bring his iPad to work in
use it to do work you can use Outlook
and he can join the protected wifi right
without doing anything that's really the
the most risky way because then you have
to trust that whoever brings their iPad
or their Fire tablet or their laptop
that it is properly secured they're not
doing some crazy things like I don't
know it doesn't have like four digit
passcode with no 10 attempt white things
like that
and then of course you the next level
are at the top level that is BYOD but
you gotta sign something and we're going
to learn why I was so tired MobileIron
and air watch so that you if the company
can monitor that device but then that I
think we're going to start seeing more
legal cases of companies abusing that
and it's your personal rabbis and those
MDM can be really sneaky peek can record
all the URL to go to so what if your
employee you love your iPad you want to
use it in meetings because everyone's
schedules meetings and you're in there
and you can play Angry Birds what people
are talking and you have your little by
little innocuous MobileIron icon there
and MobileIron is great because you can
do things like I did ministration
provision your email account just like
that on your device you don't even have
to know the exchange or any of that
stuff but what did you go home and new
Browns pornography near into certain
things and you're going to those sites
well what happens when the administrator
looks at your browser history or look at
some of that information and exposes it
or the company uses it against you that
you have an illness there this sort of
juxtaposition
i think im just waiting on this to
happen and when it hits the court it's
going to be really a difficult case to
try because it's a personal device in
the personal house but he got your MDM
on there
and and forget the USS first SEC did you
guys know and Europe that you have to
get special privileges to do incident
response on an endpoint like you have to
there's a little asterisks all companies
are all countries are different right
but the the strict one like Germany and
Luxembourg Brussels boy they will kick
your butt if you're an instant responder
and you can't even really do
threat scanning on these endpoints you
you really have to get the employees
permission to do something proactive at
the stuff does hit the fan you can do I
R but the lot there's a lot there's a
lot more employee privacy rights and by
the way my just speaking to an audience
anyone to international business
anyone couple people could write a few
there's a thing called the GDP art I
think the UN should have this to GDP R
stands for general data protection
regulation it's this new European Union
thing that says companies have to tell
their to inform the public what they
collect what is considered private how
they can use it how they can analyze and
and then all of the citizens of Europe
had the right to be forgotten so they
can say Google forget about me and
Google will erase you from from search
histories that there's a little bit of a
crappy that's what the going back and
forth as you you can essentially use it
to abuse it to take out search results
were your less than favor in news but
that's a different and you know that the
us- doesn't have any of those laws we
don't
we don't have any law that characterized
what is considered private data I i
testified in front of senate on data
brokers in November and these big data
brokers like axiom and experience and
all these others we had no idea what
they have on it they they have what's
the next level up from terabytes
from that its 180 alright let's just say
they have a massive amount of data on
all of us think that we didn't even know
it's possible they that's a really big
data right when we call are you know are
five terror by Sports Club cluster big
data
yeah they operate on a totally different
skills such as Google and Facebook and I
kind of feel like the EU is way ahead of
us here in the states because they
actually classified what is what is
personal data but what is what's really
gonna be funny is you guys know this
term brags it who knows what brings it
means what exactly so if you doing very
smart check out the big brain on Brad
pulp fiction right ok just making sure
if Britain leave the EU that gonna leave
all of this in disarray for the United
Kingdom so if you're doing business over
there good luck it's gonna be an
interesting case I have no idea what I
meant by Romanian case involving a
messenger and we think here there was a
I think it was the law
disk i/o remember this remaining I was
using instant messenger at the office
and they were legally able to spy on him
it was against company policy to use the
instant instant messenger and so the
company spied on him and saw him using
it in the suit thing you know have the
right to to spy on me even though I was
breaking the Acceptable Use Policy
actually lost so it's actually an
interesting victory but you know I guess
to to bring in around two to the topic
and which was privacy in today's
enterprise I guess hopefully you guys
are walking away a little more
knowledgeable but also I hope that you
are you guys are able to understand it's
it's never as simple as we're going to
keep your private data private it's a
deal with all of these devices with all
of this monitoring for threats in
network here that there's quite a room
for abused and not only at the corporate
level but at at the macro level at the
government level and we're seeing that
today with the gym so with that opened
in cash and tell me what you guys think
disagree with me something completely or
parking or different tell me any
questions or anyone want to make a
statement
yes sir thank you thank you where I was
going with this is I don't ever wanna
hear the word key escrow or third-party
key ever because as soon as you have
that capability you guys know what I
mean by that right
personae if talking in person behind
talking to my coach Guy back to its Mike
Sherman runs our central division here
at the company if i'm having a private
conversation with Mike if he gives me
his key I gave him my kids were having
complications two keys the third key
would be giving
you the government so I have to create a
third key to give to you so it in time
in the past you can go back and look at
our thirty
escora 13 and the problem with this and
the government trying to do this in the
nineties trivia question what was it
called clipper to ya like one clapper
talks about the clipper to thats funny
admiral clapper
he had clapper that intelligence
disarray but yeah so the IAEA DNI and
the problem with this is that you have
to trust the government they want the
view that third key and currently
congress and help feinstein said that
she was going to introduce this bill if
no one else did this would just simply
weekend our our our security and it
would weaken it because just like the
weaponization the iPhone back door if
anyone were to get ahold of these
third-party keys that would essentially
mean they could like that box from
sneakers they can plug in the box and
see in encrypted traffic ticket CI
messages they could see all this stuff
so let's play it out
suppose feinstein gets her way and and
they're able to ram rod this through
congress to say all the major
manufacturers let's start there all the
major manufacturers Google Facebook
Microsoft anyone who makes the device
has to do
key escrow so
and by the way I'm gonna say this in the
smartest manner if they do it in a way
that they got the the Cyber Security
Information Sharing act through at the
end of the year which was kind of dirty
they put it into a big appropriations
bill to end of the year and it just
slipped through even though a lot of us
were lobbying against it
don't get me started on information
security cheering so if they get through
then the biggies will have to comply
right Microsoft Apple all these people
will complain or start to give the
government their third party teens you
can kind of monitor and audit that but
what will happen is the terrorists
criminals
us cybersecurity professionals we're not
going to use iMessage anymore what are
we gonna use no not carrier pigeons
you're right we're gonna we're going to
use a third-party ad were gonna use
whatsapp and Skype and my daughter uses
it and I have a big problem
the two but I hate when things just
disappear you know why the kids you
think those pictures disappear yeah so
we're gonna go one level down we're
going to third party apps let's say
congress comes back again and says if
there's a threshold that began across
outlaw at any app developer would be
required to give a third party to be
government I think they're crossing a
line I think they're crossing a line
because that would be the first time in
history that a developer cannot develop
what they wanted his right now in the
you s right now I can sit down and I can
program the worst matter where in human
history i mean nothing I have a
capability probably don't let's just say
I did it could overwhelm a nuclear
reactor could crash finds you do
whatever as long as I didn't infect
anyone that I can have it safely on my
laptop but I didn't have my pictures of
something it with illegal but the minute
that congress says that for the third
partyies crew don't do it they have
introduced two problems number one is
its it impinges upon my freedom of
speech to be able to write whatever I
want whatever code I want and not have
to give any of it to the government
the second thing is it's unenforceable
because they can't what is the way that
the government would audit this if they
want to ensure everyone is in compliance
yes right and what you gotta do the
carrier like some stuff into the network
news since we gotta go do survey of mass
surveillance again
under the purposes of auditing the
people are in compliance so those are
mine that's my things about the end in
plus it's mathematically there's no
mathematical model that will support
building a back door there's just not
the problem is the government had that
has that back door there was one dude
who posted an encryption algorithm that
said in order to decrypt something
personal person could communicate but in
order to decrypt that communication
there wasn't a third-party keen there
was like a third party that was built up
in New six yards and six people had to
come together in order to decrypt that
traffic then you're just sitting there
fishing going to every nation state or
every person who has that short in
assembling it together so we're almost
out of time here any other questions or
comments I guess I'm lying on the open
discussion thing
questions comments concerns flames
constructive criticism ok I'm ending
with 30 seconds to go thank you guys SO
much for laughing at my jokes like to
thank you