somewhat entertaining and interesting
and informative came up with the idea of
calling us presentation seesaw for an
hour having been a sea so I thought it
might be a good idea to share some of my
experiences as a seesaw for a larger
organization hoping that most of you in
the audience may be aspiring to move
into a row like that someday and for
some of you that may already be seasoned
veterans hopefully you'll pick up a
couple of tips along the way I just by
way of a bit of background have been an
information technology about thirty
years I started really young 16 of thats
been an information security and 16 of
its been in health care I've got a
couple of certifications my last role I
was the chief information security
officer for Mercy Health which is the
largest not-for-profit hospital system
in the state of Ohio 24 hospitals 35,000
employees pretty decent size
organization I also managed the security
program for the Cleveland Clinic's nine
community hospitals and board member of
the Cleveland InfraGard
the summer learning objectives I want to
achieve today is helping you understand
some tips and getting that job as well
as some of the actions to take when you
first step into that role you know
because depending upon how deep things
are you'll need to know whether you
should be wearing galoshes or hip waders
and then become familiar with some non
technical tasks in the role frequently
people that move into a row like that
maybe somebody that came up through the
technical ranks and you'll quickly learn
that there are a lot of non-technical
aspects to the job that I think are
important to be aware of and lastly have
some words of wisdom along the way as I
mentioned the primary intended audience
is for people that are technical or
managerial level people looking to move
into a sea so roll and information
security officer or director security
role you know and everything that I'm
going to talk about doesn't give you any
guarantees it's mostly just for insights
I think one of the most important things
in getting the job is focusing on two
aspects of your experience in the
interview that has little to do with
your technical abilities and more about
how you can lead people at the end of
the day for getting hired into a
leadership role the person that you're
reporting to wants to know can you lead
a team of people and also can you manage
projects because an awful lot of what
you'll find you have to do in any
organization despite the level of their
security programs maturity is knowing
that you can deliver on projects because
there will always be new projects that
have to be implemented there will be
upgrades that you have to do
and the whole assessment process for
filling in the gaps in the program
because those were things that weren't
on the road map perhaps for any of your
predecessors I think that you should
make the opportunity to interview the
company that you're looking to secure a
job with as much as they're interviewing
you you really want to make sure it's a
good fit it's it's unforgiving job and
it comes with a lot of stress and so I
think what you should be asking are
these questions in particular understand
what their corporate initiatives are and
that's really a wide-open question and
it covers a lot of ground you'd like to
know a little bit more about what where
have they been where they at where they
heading and that could be anything from
what acquisitions maybe they'll be
looking at they may not be able to tell
you specifically that they're looking to
acquire other companies but it may be
good to know that least they're looking
to grow because that could add a whole
dimension to your responsibilities in
terms of assessing any acquisitions or
mergers and who knows it could affect
your job both positively or negatively
and you would like to know if if that's
something on the near horizon you know
why
ok I'm getting hired tomorrow and we're
starting that next week or is that
something that maybe 12 to 18 months
down the road beyond acquisitions I
think it's a good idea to understand
maybe a little bit about what sorts of
products and services they not all
already have but which ones of those may
be new or which ones are they looking at
launching because I would hope that you
would be involved in participating in
some of those activities because many of
us have been in a situation where
security gets bogged down at the end
instead of beit din along the way
security initiatives in flight now on
the books would be more specific to what
you'd be working on its good to know
coming into that role may be what's
already been achieved what sorts of
things
they aspiring to accomplish and to what
extent are they aware of those things
they may be looking to you to come in
and tell them what they need to do
depends on the level of maturity of the
organization asked what's expected of
you in the first 90 days there's a
couple of reasons for that obviously the
most important one is that usually your
evaluation period and you want to do
well but also it is good to know what
they're going to expect of you so that
you get off on the right start
you don't want to be heading down the
wrong path and find out that you should
have been doing something differently
based on what they were expecting I
think it's really important to
understand the management style of your
boss every interview that I've ever been
on I asked the person that would be my
boss that very question I don't like to
be micro-managed I like a boss to do the
two fundamental things that I think all
bosses should do provide direction and
remove obstacles if I micro-managed I
won't last long and I like to know what
their management style is now they could
say one thing and be completely
different but I think it's better to ask
the question to ask it at all and lastly
I think it's important to know where
security sits in the organization there
there's a different dynamic if you
report up through the CEO and I T vs
reporting to risk management sometimes
she sews report directly to the board
sometimes they report to finance
sometimes they report to risk management
are legal it's a completely different
dynamic based on where you are in the
food chain and it helps to understand
that context when you're stepping into
that role
assume that you get hired I would
suggest that you confirm the
expectations that were set during your
interview because things may change we
all know that the AHR cycle doesn't
happen right away you may interview for
a position that you actually don't start
for a couple of months
well that's two-thirds of a quarter that
that could really impact what the
priorities are and maybe they've changed
so it's a good idea not to walk in
assuming that the expectations that were
set are still the ones that exist so
just ask the question is what we talked
about in the interview still how you'd
like me to prioritize my focus it
depends too and if you're taking over an
existing program are building a new one
when I got hired at Mercy we were
building an enterprise security
department from the ground up we had
some markets that had a pretty decent
security program with people that did
security full time and then we had other
markets where the network engineer where
the security hat when necessary so
understanding what you're getting into
is important because it will help you
create the strategy and vision necessary
to realize whatever those expectations
are if on the other hand it's a rather
mature program you probably want to be
asking questions about well where are
they in a maturity scale is there some
sort of framework in place where they
are measuring their level of maturity
and if not you want to get your arms
around now because then you can figure
out what we need to do to help take the
program to the next level
risk assessments would be key seeing if
they have any done taking a look at the
results I would hope that if any risk
assessments word on that there'd be some
action plans and what's the the track
record of of completing those things you
may find that you've inherited quite a
number of audit findings that need to be
addressed and are those tied to risk
assessments at all and also if they
haven't done any risk assessments you
should be prepared to recommend
and some risk assessment framework and
get started and obviously you'd wanna
help them help you identify where the
the most important information is and
start with those systems first
identifying budget is important do you
have one what's it look like from a
capital and operating expense
perspective and we'll talk about that
when I first was hired the line items
for security we're actually part of the
data center budget because they were
looking to build an enterprise security
program there was no cost center for
security in and of itself so part of the
work that you would need to do in a
situation like that includes figuring
out what your budget needs to look like
and work with the appropriate people to
move existing budget in two different
structure
the other thing I mention is it's a good
idea to ask questions about the history
of the budget I found out I get hired
the middle of November of that year and
I found out that there was a line item
for identity and access management that
was about two years old
the capital had rolled over one fiscal
year and then a second fiscal year and
so one of the things that was said as an
expectation is we need to get started
next year which was about six weeks in
building and identity and access
management program and making some
investments because if we go a
third-year that capital may not be
available anymore so that became
something that I had to prioritize so
you want to dig a little bit deeper into
questions about the history the budget
and not just know how much money you
have to spend it is critically important
early on to build strategic
relationships it was sort of ironic that
one of the first to people that I met
when I went to my orientation at the
home office where internal audit I
bumped into the two ladies in the
hallway and we struck up a conversation
and
and that was the start of a great
relationship and I'll tell you a couple
of stories about that along the way I i
think what else is key is something that
will talk about near the end of this
discussion which is incident response
and building those relationships early
is very important because security will
have to work with marketing human
resources legal risk management all of
those key areas that are often needed to
be pulled together if you have some sort
of a crisis or an incident to deal with
and the sooner you build those
relationships to better another thing
that I'll recommend to you is after I
started I gotten myself involved in
reviewing contracts from a security
perspective and you can build some
political capital with the legal team
because I always turn their contracts
around very quickly because invariably
something came across my desk that
require quick response sometimes I had
to rely on the legal department for a
quick turnaround 15 established a
reputation with them as somebody that
turns their work around quickly if I
pick up the phone and call them and ask
them to return the favor they're most
likely going to do that for me because
you scratch my back I'll scratch yours I
think that you want to ask this last
question you want to be diplomatic about
it but what you're what you're looking
at
looking for is you know the locus of
power are the people that make decisions
maybe they're the people at the
corporate office and what you want to
ask is you know what do I need to know
about interacting with this you know
certain person whether it's the head of
legal or the head of a char because
maybe there are certain
unwritten rules about how you interact
with those people and early in your
career at this organization you don't
want to put your foot in your mouth by
doing something that you wish you had
known about and maybe by asking some
people maybe even your boss just say you
know based on your experience working
with these lists of people are there any
things I should know about their
management style the do's and don'ts in
interacting with them and that goes a
long way in helping you have a smooth
road and transition into this new job if
you're building a new program a couple
of things you should consider you'll
probably be asked to define an org chart
like I did I had about fourteen people
reporting to me either directly or
indirectly and I came up with this idea
of creating a services catalog if you're
building a new program it's a good idea
to have people understand what your
services are so initially I think we
broke our department up into three areas
of focus security engineering security
compliance and user provisioning and
that helped us focus on where we needed
to place people remember I had some
people that had been doing security as a
full-time job and other people that kind
of wear that hat when necessary unless
you're building your church need to
figure out what am I gonna move people
around what opportunities will people be
interested in working for and in that
will help try to solidify what that or
church needs to look like also referring
back to risk assessments and the
methodology that was used as a good
place to start to if this is a new
program and there isn't much history
there it's an opportunity for you to put
your finger prints on that program make
it your own and help shape the way it
needs to be you also want to inventory
the security technology you want to find
out you know what investments there are
when I started at Mercy they had a
centralized logging system that was
defunct it was running an old hardware
it had old software and that this were
floor nobody was using it so one of the
quick wins that I strove to accomplish
was I needed some visibility and I
thought it might be a good idea to
outsource that and we were able to do
that so I got some visibility scored two
quick win but it's also a good idea to
understand what the technology inventory
is not just from a functionality
perspective but from an age perspective
because remember I started in November
so in the first quarter of the following
year I was already expecting to have to
do budget forecasting for the year after
that we'll understanding what the state
of the technology was would help me make
recommendations about the investments
that needed to be made not only in may
be replacing technology but even just
doing up greats sometimes upgrades are
more than just the software you get to
the end of life of hardware and you're
not necessarily interested in moving to
a different vendor but you want to
refresh the hardware that takes money
and lastly when I understand the
operational ownership of security
technology and this widely varies from
organization to organization around the
room and asked people to share with
their organization look like we probably
get a lot of different answers sometimes
the security department manages the
firewalls sometimes it's the network
team you know you could run down the
list of Technology understanding who
owns what is important especially when
you tie it back to that earlier slide
about building relationships
communications is the big one this is
where some technical people that come up
through the ranks struggle because you
have to be good at communicating
technical ideas and issues in a
non-technical way and when you're
interacting with people at your level or
higher
you know these emails meetings phone
conversations and text messages are all
different methods of communicating
they all have their own etiquette but at
the end of the day they have one thing
in common we need to try to boil down
the issue or the communication in
simplest terms and as you move into a
sea level role you'll find this for
yourself it's very difficult to keep up
on all the expectations of you and so
you appreciate when people communicate
with you in a concise manner you
probably want to ask some people that
you interact with frequently at that
higher-level what kind of information
they prefer to get from you and how
they'd like it because then you can
tailor your communications based on what
they're looking for some people like
more detail than others and you want to
err on the side of caution and keep
things concise but if they're interested
in more information over time you can
kind of develop that expectation and
rapport because what you want to avoid
is striving to be concise and then find
out that they'd like more details so you
wind up getting emails back from them
asking questions will can you go into
this or can you go into this and
sometimes it's easier just to pick up
the phone and one rule of thumb that I'd
like to try to follow if possible is if
it's going to take more than three email
exchanges why not just have a
conversation cuz it's a lot more
efficient so again learning how much
detail as a novel based on a
communication medium obviously you can't
communicate as effectively in an email
as you can on the phone and texting is
even more limited
want to come back to building
relationships for a minute especially in
the context of communication rather
interesting thing happened when I was at
Mercy I mentioned that I started
building a relationship with the
internal audit folks what the time I
wanted to look at bringing in some sort
of a risk assessment tool that was
quantitated based and we wound up
selecting fair I had jack jones come in
for those of you that know him and run a
two or three day training course for me
and my team I invited risk management
and internal audit to that training I
paid for their seats and I said to them
the only expectation and I have of you
is that you sit through the training if
you can afford the time and just learn
about the tool that we're planning on
using if you find that it may be
beneficial in the work that you do I'll
budget for licensing and pay for it but
if you've already got something that you
want to use thats fine and that was well
received and Internal Audit and Risk
Management did attend both of them
declined to use the tool not because
they didn't like it but because they had
other things that they were already
using well unbeknownst to me at the time
I laid the groundwork for something
really important internal audit did an
audit of the data center and they
brought in a pretty high-end tool that
spit out one of these big reports and it
ranked something finding as high for all
the servers that had this obscure I'm
not gonna go into the detail of it but
it has a somewhat obscure vulnerability
well I wasn't sure I agreed with that in
fact I knew I didn't agree with that so
I did research I wrote a report I used
fair to prove that if we fixed what they
asked us to we would actually cause more
problems in the environment
and I think what helped was not only
having a solid argument against fixing
it but because I used fair and they sit
in on the training they understood the
story I was trying to tell them and they
change the audit finding the low that's
a good day so I called Jack and told
them about that success story I think
it's important as a new leader that you
establish regular communications with
your team I remember shortly after I
first started I called a phone call
meeting with everybody because we were
all spread across the state of Ohio and
we actually had somebody in Tennessee
and just you know kind of introduced
myself and talked a little bit about my
vision and some of the things that I
thought we needed to address an
accomplished you'll find and for me
especially having come from the
Cleveland Clinic where everything was
about an hour within each other all of
our meetings were in person and this was
a completely different dynamic because
my team was spread so far across
geographic region all of our meetings
not just security but I T and general
we're done on the phone so much
different dynamic to get used to and so
it's even more important to keep that
line of communication open where
possible I had weekly meetings with my
direct reports and I tried to get
involved in some committees and it may
be a good idea to start some committees
when I was at the Cleveland Clinic we
created something called the information
security technical advisory forum called
that I staff for short and we held that
monthly and we invited people from the
security department keep people from my
tea and some of you especially if you've
been in health care you know that
oftentimes these shadow I T groups exist
where a department has its own funding
and enough clout in the organization
that they hire their own I T staff so we
wanted to try to get those people coming
to our meetings and we also had physical
security com
what was interesting about the Cleveland
Clinic and it's still true is that their
physical security force has legal
jurisdiction in the entire state of Ohio
because they get people you know we get
at the time when I was working there you
know they'd get foreign dignitaries
coming for open-heart surgeries and
things like that I'm so they needed a
police force that had that extension it
was good to have them on our meetings
because we get to share information
about what each other was doing so
starting those committees is another way
to build communications and
relationships so for some of you this
might be very boring because it's old
hat but I didn't want to make any
assumptions so just talking about
budgeting for a minute
you know you need to know your fiscal
year allowing the calendar year or is it
one of those situations where the the
budget cycle runs from July 1st to June
30th you know that can make a difference
you know the definition of capital
expenditure vs operational expense
capital is typically an asset and you
want to work with your finance
department understand what their rules
are for what can be capitalized and what
can't I T side you'll often find that
they identify certain value of the
equipment or software that you by where
it goes from being an expense to be
capital
the other thing that's important to know
is that in some organizations they may
allow capital to roll over to the
following year
other ones may not operational expense
never rolls over its always
incurred at during the fiscal year so
that becomes a forecasting gotcha you
want to make sure that you know that if
you're forecasting some sort of let's
say you're gonna buy next-generation
firewall and you're buying a three-year
maintenance contract you want to be able
to forecast out three years what your
capital and operating expenses will look
like because the operating doesn't roll
over and if you don't budget for that
and yours 2013 you will have a budget
deficiency and that's not good
the same topic in a cruel is something
that can catch you if you're not aware
of it so it say that that
next-generation firewall has a
three-year subscription and three-year
maintenance those are operating expenses
every month over 36 months the finance
department will take 136th of that
against your budget but if you pay for
all up front that's cash flow but on the
accrual side you need to make sure that
when you're doing your budget
forecasting for the following fiscal
year that you put one third of the cost
of that in your budget because when the
finance department takes that out of
your budget each month that will hit
your budget's bottom line one
interesting thing is traditionally
labour is considered operating expense
but some organizations will allow your
workforce to be capitalized if their
labor is being applied to a project so
you need to make sure that you
understand that so that your capital
budget for projects includes labor is
your capitalizing it and you'll also see
some reduction on your operating expense
because the salaries of those people
that work for you
that are being funded as capital for a
project will reduce the impact of that
on your budget and then managing a cost
center
you know you you'll work with your I T
department and your finance department
understand what all of the numeric codes
are for your budget so that you know
which things get charged which budget
because you'll likely be approving
purchase orders and invoices and things
like that and then I think it's
important to know the style of budget
accountability at the Cleveland Clinic
they manage things to the penny but the
CIO at Mercy liked to manage things more
a slush way so that overall there was
responsibility for the budget and
meeting it but there were some
flexibility
in how much money one part of I T was
spending versus another because if there
was an overage on one side it may be
irreconcilable because you could
identify that there was some slush
somewhere else because there was under
spending there and then some things to
think about in the first second fourth
quarter of your fiscal cycle it's not
uncommon for in the first quarter
finance want released capital until near
the end of the first quarter so if
you've got project plans you wanna make
sure you understand it because if you're
forecasting that you're going to start
some project shortly after the new year
assuming that you are fiscal year aligns
with the calendar year but funding isn't
available on the capital side until
three months into it
your project may wind up being three
months late right out the gate Q-two is
interesting because in that same
scenario the flood gates open at the
beginning of Q-two so there's this
flurry of spending and then finance will
typically look at the financial health
of the organization at the end of the
second quarter and depending upon how
spending is going and how revenue is
they may start cutting back allowing you
to spend more money so you get this
three-month window to try to get some
things done and then the last thing I
mention is it's a good idea to have a
plan in your back pocket about things
that you'd like to do if you had extra
money because sometimes in the fourth
quarter that's what happens somebody
makes an announcement we had this money
that we need to spend the first person
that can step forward with a project
that we can review and approve gets the
money so if you've got a couple of
things in your back pocket that you can
respond to an opportunity like that you
may be able to spend some money this
year on something that you had
forecasted next year because you were
prepared to talk about that
department meetings building
relationships again is important what we
eventually did in my department was we
met four times a year
typically in the first quarter and third
quarter we did a team
phone call that lasted a couple of hours
and then the other two times of the year
second quarter fourth quarter we had a
big team meeting we got together and it
was typically a full day but the night
before we all went out to dinner and you
can build some great relationships that
way the meeting agenda was really the
same for me you know your team is going
to be heads down every day fighting
fires and keeping up on project demands
and they will forget over the course of
three months or six months just how much
they accomplished and my team always
appreciated it when we reviewed all of
the things that we had accomplished
either since the last meeting or in the
past six months and they're like wow no
wonder we're so tired we really got a
lot done and I forgot about doing that
and then the other thing is looking
ahead so it helped set the stage for you
know they've got them excited about what
we accomplished so that we can talk
about more work that was coming up I
think it's really important as a leader
to know how to run a good meeting how
many of us get invited to a meeting by a
person that we just we roll our eyes are
like we're never gonna get anything done
in this meeting so here are some of my
tips you want to send an agenda out in
advance because there are some people
that are introverts and they would like
some time to digest what you're planning
on talking about instead of being
surprised when they show up the format
that I like to follow at times is here's
the list of topics we're going to talk
about and here's the times that I've got
allocated to it people respect you when
you manage a meeting to a schedule and I
would say that you know skipping the
minutes for a moment talking about the
parking lot
this is a really good idea because if
you're trying to be a good leader and
run a good meeting and you want to stick
to your agenda there may be some great
dialogue going on and there may be some
ideas that get thrown out that are
important but aren't necessarily germane
to the topic if you create a parking lot
and make a note of that it lets people
know that you value their input their
ideas are important and that this is a
topic that should have its own meeting
you'll find that people are more willing
to share in a meeting when you ask them
to come up with ideas if you're making a
parking lot it's a good idea to take
minutes
whenever I was running minutes our
meetings I took my own minutes and I
always put action items at the end of
the minutes and then for the next
meeting
action item review was always the first
agenda item because it fosters
accountability you can ask people what
their statuses and after a couple of
times of heading meetings and people
give you the same answer why haven't
gotten to that yet you can rely on those
relationships you been building and go
back to that person if they're on your
project team but they don't report to
you directly and ask for some assistance
from their boss and how to help them get
the work done that you need them to
gaining consensus here's a tip that I
have found to be effective
it's rather subtle but it makes a big
difference if at the end of a meeting
you're trying to get some consensus and
you ask the question is there anybody
that does everybody agree with this
decision
people will tend to feel silent peer
pressure if they disagree and so they
may raise their hand and say I agree but
then they walk out the door saying
there's no way in hell I'm agree to that
if you ask the question is there anyone
they can't agree with this you're giving
them permission to disagree and it opens
the door to discussion because then the
follow-up question is what will it take
for you to reach consensus so it's a
subtle way to open the door to
communication and that will help make
your meeting more effective because you
least have some confidence knowing that
when people walk out the door what they
said is what they meant performance
reviews is a part of your
responsibilities and you'll have to set
goals that align with the company with
the department and what the individual
you heard Darrell talk this morning
about the importance of training and I
agree with that to the extent that the
organization will be willing to fund
training take advantage of it I think
the only thing worse than training
people and having them leave is not
training people and having them stay
there can be a detriment to your program
we don't have time you may find that
there are formal employee engagement
surveys that take place in your
organization and some of your department
goals may be tied to the outcomes of
most things and they will typically ask
you to identify two or three things that
are areas for improvement and maybe
there would be one thing that you see is
a strength and what can you do to
sustain that so those are some goals
documentation is very critical
have to be very careful how I share this
story with you but i i think it's
definitely worth telling
documentation is very important on the
positive side of performance reviews its
good to capture emails and other things
along the way throughout the year that
reflect positively on some of the people
that report to you because you're going
to forget about some of those things and
if you document that you can pull them
out at the time of performance review
and it not only helps you formulate your
answers to their review but those are
good things for you to share with those
employees during that performance review
and it lets them know that you thought
that the things that they did were
noteworthy were important enough to save
so that you could you know talk about
them however it's also important to
document conversations that you have
with problematic employees because you
never know what's going to happen I
guarantee you that nobody's gonna pull
you aside and say hey guess what this
one person that's underperforming in
your department has been getting meets
expectations for the last five years
because their previous boss rank them
that way and so when you start to
document conversations about that person
and for two years in a row that person
gets a needs improvement and doesn't get
a raise and pick your poison
whether they file a complaint with H are
based on age race or gender you're gonna
be in the hot seat to show that it's
none of those in fact this person wasn't
a good performing employee and you have
to hope in my case that when this
problematic employee met with leadership
within the first five minutes that
person put their foot in their mouth and
it was very clear that there was a chip
on the shoulder and had nothing to do
with whether I had an issue with that
person's age gender or race documenting
is very important and if you've not been
through something like that before you
don't want to have to turn that
conversation into a he said she said if
you've got documentation that shows here
are all the issues that we talked about
here are the actions that we agreed upon
you've got a very solid foundation to
stand on to defend yourself if something
like that happens and lastly you want to
provide some sort of career path for
your team to the extent that you can
talk about projects for a minute I think
it's very important to know how to do
project management I'm forecasting if
you're not familiar with the
methodologies where you're doing
personnel ASUS or even doing things like
the standard deviation of a critical
path of a project it will serve you well
the quick story we were one of the
projects that we had was a rip in
replacing the friction my predecessor
purchased an encryption product and
threw it out to each market to implement
and we really needed it to be
implemented in an enterprise fashion so
we sat down and we did a time
forecasting analysis and we estimated
that it was going to take us about see
fifteen months and after we applied some
of the the mathematical analysis to the
project we extended the project by 11
weeks because we had underestimated how
long
it was going to take and what was
interesting was when I said that what my
boss and went over the length of the
project he said why didn't think it was
going to take this long and I said well
that's because as humans we tend to
underestimate how long it takes to get
things done
night in say this to him but I'll share
it with you why is it that in
organizations we don't have time to do
things right but we have time to do them
over and I would rather build that into
my project plan up front and as fortune
would habit halfway through that project
we had a reduction in force and a number
of the resources allocated to the
project were gone so over the next
several months we started falling behind
because this was a compliance project we
had to pull resources in from the
outside to help us get it finished and
it took about an extra two months so
despite the fact that the project came
in late think about if I had not done
that forecasting analysis with the
scientific methods we had added three
months to the original and now we were
two months late behind that so otherwise
that project would have been close to
six months later the two most difficult
security projects in my opinion are a
rip and replace of encryption and
building an identity and access
management system
expect project to take time I mentioned
that there was a line item in the budget
for an identity and access management
system we spent four years working on
getting that up and running and we were
successful we integrate it with our help
desk software and IT automated a fair
number of things for us
you want to expect security program
maturity to take time it in a five and a
half years I was a sea so we
accomplished a significant number of
things we closed a hundred and twenty
audit findings we built a pretty robust
security program but those things take
time they're not going to happen
overnight
you shouldn't expect that of yourself
and hopefully the
organization you're working for doesn't
have that unrealistic expectation as
well and also you know reduction in
force
affecting project schedules I already
mentioned an example where that's a risk
that you always want to cite in your
project charter and you know I put trip
it's up here again because you'll find
that there may be some people on your
team that are really good at projects
versus the operational stuff so maybe
you want to lead them towards doing
project implementation for security work
couple of tips they have for you i think
is security people sometimes we missed
the boat when it comes to opportunity we
always want to strike while the iron is
hot after something bad happens but let
me tell you a story that was in the
other direction so we had an incident
that required an internal investigation
and we had a good outcome there was no
issue but one of the reasons we had a
good outcome was because I had
visibility into activity on the network
based on our login system when I sit
down with my boss to be briefed him on
what happened I said to him you know you
know if this same situation had unfolded
this way we wouldn't have the kind of
outcome we might have here because we
don't have visibility in these areas and
he said well what do you need so I put
together an analysis to get budget
funding to increase our Splunk licensing
so that wasn't a case where something
bad happened but I told the story in a
way that helped me get more funding
despite the fact that something bad had
happened
innovative thinking can sometimes pay
you back handsomely so it was about ten
years ago this month when I was at the
Cleveland Clinic that I i realized a
major success in my career I was
thinking we spent time rehearsing
disaster recovery and we would send
teams of people out to some third party
company and we would rebuild our systems
why don't we do hands-on incident
response testing so I came up with the
idea I partnered with
net curtain from Inter hack and we
created a laboratory environment where
we had real equipment staged and we
staged a live hack and we had management
there and technology people there and
you will learn things in a hands on test
that will never come to light in a
tabletop well the following year we
cooked up this scenario where we had a
person working in a lab department
selling patient information to a private
investigator and just for fun we had the
lab person on the incident response team
so they were an insider that knew what
was happening as the investigation was
going underway so five years later I'm
at Mercy how and we had a real insider
incident fortunately it all turned out
good
the person that was the bad actor was a
third party vendor who only had access
to test information so there was no
patient data exposed but having
rehearsed something like that in the
past it sort of felt familiar and I
think it helped me better lead my team
through that investigation now it's easy
for me to stand up here and tell you
what happened in three sentences that
investigation took every day of six
weeks before we figured out what
happened now might might point to you is
it's just like disaster recovery we put
it off and put it off until it's in our
face and then nothing else matters
make the time to rehearse incident
response because it's going to happen in
some way shape or form and you want to
be prepared for it
building a peer network is helpful
especially when you get into a position
like this upper management last few
questions like what's everybody else
doing if you've got a network that you
can reach out to you can make that
happen within the first year I was at
Mercy I found out that mercy is
religious-based organizations as you
might suspect the CIOs across the united
states formed a Catholic hospitals a CIO
network and one year they invited all
their sea so stay calm and so while I'm
there I'm talking to a couple of other
people and I'm like what spin off our
own group so we wound up having a
monthly phone call and we just talked
about you know what are you concerned
about what you working on so you know
you may even use a conference like this
to start building some relationships
where you start to have a phone call
like that periodically and I think one
of the most important aspects to
developing your security program is
incident response as I mentioned you
want to have plans we have in both at
the Cleveland Clinic and mercy we built
playbooks for specific scenarios there's
a different type of response for a
denial of service attack then there is a
phishing attack and even you can get
granular when it comes to malware some
malware will flood your network like
back in the day when sequel slammer did
that's a completely different response
than somebody discovering that there's
malware on a workstation extol trading
data versus ransomware having a playbook
helps you make decisions under duress
and give you guidance that helps keep
you focused and test those plans when
you can you want to tap into expertise
where and when you need it unless you're
a large organization that can afford to
have a forensics team I think it's a
good idea to outsource that only because
if if you present evidence in court by
people on your team that collected
information a sad be opposing counsel
we'll ask you or ask your team is this
something that you do every day and if
the answer is no they can shoot holes in
the credibility of the information that
you collected strengthening those
relationships mentioned earlier so
here's another interesting tip that was
another hands-on exercise I did I was
teaching my team
the value of how to document an incident
because you never know if that
information is going to appear in court
later because maybe the incident starts
to unfold in a way that you quickly
realize that you've been breached so
what I did is I i set up a scenario
again I work within her hair done this I
left the room for most of the day and
left the team do some acquisition and
collection and then the following day we
staged a mock deposition and I was the
one being deposed by a real attorney who
had he discovery experience and shot
holes in all of their documentation and
the lesson learned there wasn'ta give my
team a black eye but the problem that I
see is that the technical people will
collect evidence that doesn't get used
in court for six months or a year maybe
and so if you've got good documentation
practices it helps you recall what you
did that further down the road and plus
if you're being questioned about things
that you did not necessarily collecting
information but even just the decisions
that you made it goes a long way and one
of the other things that I'll share with
you in terms of the documentation when I
mentioned to you that we had that
six-week investigation I made a note
every time a conference call started
with a vendor and when it ended and that
really helped me out because when it
came time to pay all the bills and they
were sending me invoices listing all of
the times that other people spent I
could go back and look at my notes and
because I had remembered to write down
when the call ended I knew how long they
were actually on the phone
those are things that you don't always
think about any questions
had some takeaways from this discussion
thanks for letting me share my
experience with him