yes there are people selling it but
let's talk
there's still some seats up front so why
don't we go ahead and get started so
today we're going to talk about the
cloud Britain talk about how clouds a
bill is gonna be a lot of a tutorial
will dive deep into some things and
we'll talk about how to secure the cloud
which is very important as well so
before start time
my name's Lisa guess I'm with juniper
Networks and I vice president for the
systems engineering team there but also
want all of you know since we have a
large group of I T folks I started my
career back in the late eighties at
Shell Oil Company and I was in there I T
department then so a lot of the
challenges that you may have now you
know I'm not always been on the vendor
side I spent about ten years on the
customer side so I am well aware of the
challenges and decisions and and the
different tradeoffs you have to make
every day as a nightie professional so i
just want to get that brief intro so
before we jump into the cloud and talk
about that I I think about cloud we hear
cloud everywhere just the other day I
was at my moms and she goes what is the
cloud and I thought why is my eighty
three-year-old mother worrying about
what the cloud is you know and that's
how ubiquitous it's become and I was
thinking where did that term really come
from so I'm also a trivia buff and I'm
going to give you a few tidbits so you
can entertain and amuse your colleagues
at your next cocktail party so it's it's
somewhat nebulous origin but the first
known reference to a cloud related to
networking in an official capacity was
in 1977 when there was an ARPANET
diagram and instead of showing the
actual network elements it actually was
a cloud so that was the first known use
of it they did not use the word yet but
it was a symbol in 1994 Wired magazine
used the term cloud in a reference to
general general computing that was
available the time that's really the
first known reference in an official
document to cloud and then it wasn't
until 2006 Amazon actually launched
their enabled and elastic computing
cloud and so this is all of fairly
relative term relatively new term and
it's amazing to me how quickly things
have evolved over time and how important
and ubiquitous the cloud is now even in
our own personalized tee shots so try to
remember that and use it next time and
people will really enjoy it I'm sure
just like you guys did so the promise
the cloud is is it an important one
its on demand computing its pay as you
go
its elastic computing you know it's it's
rainbows and unicorns it's everything
you could want but we really get to what
the cloud is like this you know it's a
pile of spaghetti it's hard to manage
its hard to secure its hard to automate
and that's what we're talking about
today how do we simplify secure and
automate a real cloud and all the
elements that go into it so what are the
business challenges that might even make
you want to embrace the cloud you know
how do you secure it how do you innovate
without disrupting your business it's
really hard to go from what I would term
a legacy data center very monolithic
into a virtualized data center that you
may be on your own premises and then
even harder to leverage public public
clouds and to hybridize it so if you
look at where I T is now it must be
pretty important because 57% of
respondents and is actually slightly
dated this is from 2014
over half of all the respondents from a
fairly major survey had I T shops moving
toward the cloud and you'll see but
you'll also see as many people that want
to deploy it you still have more than
half of infrastructures don't have any
cloud infrastructure whatsoever yet and
that's because there are several
challenges that we're talking about so
why why go to all these challenges
what's driving it first floor
applications are changing things used to
be what we called ourselves so you have
a very monolithic environment might be
your finance department and they want to
use an ERP system or your sales
department might have wanted their own
isolated CRM system now we have social
networking we've got all kinds of
applications like PeopleSoft or
different CRM programs now a lot of your
traffic is east west and this is
fundamentally changing your traffic
patterns in your data center and driving
a lot of the need for the change to
cloud your needing flattered apologies
and we're gonna go into a lot of detail
about what exactly beings we also have
some elements network virtualization
available to us that we didn't have
before we should be lands for quite a
while probably season's early nineties
or so but we really haven't gotten to a
point where we can start to virtualized
network and run virtualized network
functions on bare metal ware and talk
about that as well as we talk about
apologies and then we get into
everything as a service at Juniper we're
starting to see more and more of our
customers either leasing I T as a
service from a large provider or maybe
even large companies that are using a
multi-tenant setup where they're
providing everything as a service to
their different business units so those
are playing in more and more
environments not really just you just
care about it if your Amazon or if your
Google you really care about it even in
every day every day I T shops so today
you're here you know how do we get where
we need to be and so by that I mean here
being you got it
customer and user they want a service so
days or weeks later you provision head
and then suddenly it comes up and it's
running and that's really not fast
enough to satisfy them and I remember
when I started back at Shell all these
years ago
I was working on their infrastructure
and it took minimal one month to
provision of service and we were using
3270 terminal someplace showing my age
to view some of you probably haven't
even heard of this nearly cried as she
talking about you know we'd have a and
user in all they would want to do is go
from ok I'm really gonna see if anybody
knows this region
3278 mod 2 230 2785 and that took a
month to provision that all that was
just changing out of terminal in the end
of a coax cable did anybody know that
term I see if you think you so that's
where we used to be what we really
really really wanna be is where that end
user clicks its provision and they're
getting used to that today and everyday
environment you know it won't be long
until they have a Comcast service or att
service at home all they have to do is
click on not only do I get provisioned
also can add firewall services or
content acceleration services on the fly
by myself using a portal without even
calling anyone and and that's where the
world is going in a very ubiquitous
fashion even in our own I T shops what
goes into all that all of these
different buzzwords John Harris TN
orchestration you get all the protocols
you've got automation so those things
are important to understand and to
factor into where you are and here is
where many many networks are today we
think about your datacenter or even your
campus your resources are in silos you
know you talked earlier about your
finance department needed a specific
application and you put that in and then
sales needed specific thing and you put
that in but everything is siloed and
it's not working well together or you
have to go multiple hops for the network
to get to it where you need to be aware
you have a physical infrastructure that
is a very high utilization because
you're able to virtually overlay
networking elements on top of it and
utilizing much like what you're probably
already very familiar with doing today
on your high-end servers running several
virtual machines on them or maybe you
got Fibre Channel storage and you got a
storage area now
work that's where networking is going as
well when we get to this ubiquitous
ability to have virtualized networking
is it easy to get there
know there's a lot of impediments to it
you got a complex network you know you
got sub optimal topologies when your
traffic was going only in a north-south
direction and not be stressed you don't
really care if you have multiple hops it
had to go through when you're going
application to application directly all
the sudden multiple hops not turn into
two times multiple hops and then you
start out performance issues so we have
problems there we have manual processes
everybody still used to using CLI to
configure their routers switches you
know we're not we may have some good
things on our sonar firewalls but you're
going to Vice by device that's another
impediment and then let's talk about
security what a challenge that can be
then you got this complex network and
now you're trying to overlay security on
top of it and figure out where do I put
the firewall do I care if I need a
firewall between a virtual server and
another virtual server on the same
physical hardware what do i do or you
know is it like the old days and all I
cared about was just the pipe coming
into my data center
things things have changed quite a bit
in the past few years we use some a real
example to talk about this so this is
the application silos I talked about
primarily in North Salt traffic then we
evolve over time and you evolve you
separate your database are starting to
get better structured data so you have a
datasource you have an application
front-end it still siloed and you still
are able to share the data but all of a
sudden one day your customers figure out
hey be really cool if I can just
directly access your order management
database or H R figures out oh I'm not
the only one who needs to see your
PeopleSoft application maybe every
employee could directly interact with my
people management application to all of
sudden you got this
any to any traffic and this is where I
was talking about earlier in today's
typical data center and network greater
than 75% of your data is taking this
east-west pattern
which is fine because it's got
connectivity but the performance is not
gonna be what you want it to be so you
sit down one day and you have a nightie
planning session you say okay here's
where we are
here's where we wanna go here's our next
step is we want to have a virtual data
center so we want to virtualize our data
center are absurd quite resilient yes
you know they still made five nines
reliability out of the data center so
i'm gona designed for that but I'm gonna
bring in virtual machines have high and
x86 servers I'm gonna bring in virtual
machines I'm gonna put an ass and have
shared storage and then I'm gonna have
layer 2 switching in my fabric so that's
a much better choice but you still have
challenges with that and you also want
to incorporate let's hear cloud data
center where you're absurd more
resilient to think to some of the
applications that sit in the cloud today
like PeopleSoft sitting in the cloud
salesforce.com is much more resilient
than it used to be able to sit in the
cloud and if you're especially for
leasing cloud services from a larger
provider as part of your overall
solution now you're only gonna really be
able to count on three nines of
reliability because now we're going over
that I P public network so you need the
resiliency but you also get the
virtualization you're able to use
network attached storage and have a lot
more flexibility
let's talk about some of the decisions
you make their applications so let's say
you got a partner at you know we talked
about your partners might want access to
it and that's maybe not as
mission-critical tu as maybe your
inventory management or your order
management and maybe you might even
decide I'm gonna save cycles and I'm
even going to put the partner
application into the cloud so that I can
free up my own resources in my own
management overhead so that I can manage
my own mission critical critical
applications
you looking for processing now you put
that into the data center and it's much
more efficient now you still own all the
infrastructure yourself and you think do
I want to put that in the cloud no I
don't because that's where my revenue
comes from and i really can't afford for
my order processing to be down for some
of you it might be customer management
whatever it is that your core business
and you want to maintain that control of
it
common examples are in our financial
industry they put everything they can to
the cloud but things that are really the
crown jewels they leave in their
virtualized datacenter and move as much
as I can't now maybe you got this very
ancient inventory database that you
don't have an ability to move it into
the virtualized data center but you find
other applications that you can move in
there like mail is a great example in
our personalized we all use mail in the
cloud we all use CRM and the cloud
that's the PeopleSoft think of a char
sorry that's the PeopleSoft
salesforce.com is in the cloud so my
point is as you're thinking about this
you're not gonna one day wake up and say
everything's gonna go into the public's
out you're gonna have to think carefully
through all of your applications and
which ones can migrate in which ones are
unable to and the network is gonna be
key to that and it's going to be more
important than ever that your network
has when I'm going to define him it's
called coherency meaning I don't care
where I sit in the network it was my
legacy data center my my newer upgraded
virtualized section of my data center or
my public cloud I've got a coherent
network provisioning has always been a
big challenge with braised networking
with servers and storage and I don't you
tell you that you know I told I
illustrated with this is my story
earlier so in the old days back when you
had to bring up a physical server it
might have taken two months you had to
order it
provision it find a rack space for it I
remember those days to this is like in
the mid nineties and we're using NetBIOS
and enterprise LAN server from IBM
anybody remember that so it took a
couple months to really provision that
server so it didn't matter if it took me
two weeks to bring up the network or the
storage guys took two weeks to bring it
up but now the advent and prevalence of
the virtual machines in server world you
can actually bring it up in two minutes
in fact one of our customers very very
large online retailer they actually
bring up servers on the fly in may be
less than five seconds to accommodate
for high workloads during the Christmas
season it's fascinating some of the
automation that that our customers have
him play but what sticks out like a sore
thumb now is his two weeks time to
provision your network and storage so
what do we do about that and that's what
we talked about a lot later in the
presentation we need to orchestrated and
we need to automate it there are those
two terms equivalent they're actually
not so I hear them used interchangeably
quite often think of automation as I
think of wine grapes he will put the
grades and then stop the grapes you know
you got think of Lucy from that old show
I automate that and all the sudden now I
am crushing grapes in an automated way
it's still a single function and it's
not really related to other functions
but I'm doing a lot faster so that's
automation orchestration think of that
is making wine so there's different
automated things that happen like I've
got my bottler I've got thing that much
the cork in the great pressure but think
about a true bottle of fine wine that is
what orchestration is it brings all of
those things together it has
intelligence across the processes you
know how long those crushed grapes of
SATA near Barrow you know when it's time
to bottle and then you know when it's
time to ship it out and that's really
where orchestration comes into play and
that's where the master winemaker comes
into play
so that's that's a way to look at these
two things differently and they're both
critically important so we've talked a
lot about the path to the cloud just
gonna summarize the dive into three main
elements of how we're gonna get to the
cloud so we consolidate we got our
legacy data sooner you start to
virtualized servers a lot of you're
probably passed that phase in your into
the optimization phase where you're
looking at automating your network
automating your provisioning automating
your storage provisioning and then we
really want to get you is where you have
a soft provision cloud where your end
user can go click on a service and your
network provision itself and that gives
you a lot of time to do a lot of your
for planning do more efficient things
with your time rather than sit in front
of a sea lion type commands what does
that look like in reality physically I
like I'm an engineer I like to look at
where these boxes really look like you
know these are all pretty conceptual
things I'm talking about so if you look
you got an on-premises data center we
talked about the legacy which should be
physical and in the virtualized
datacenter you might have a managed
service provider that's gotta element of
both and then you might have a cloud
service provider as well today all those
things don't necessarily talk to each
other in an in a very seamless way but
where you really want to get is this
coherent network this network that
doesn't perform differently depending on
where you are this network that is a
provision differently depending on where
you are is something that works both
within all of your data centers and
within your public cloud and enables you
to have a hybrid cloud getting back to
that point I made where your application
system should sit where they need to be
male and H are apps fit really well in a
public cloud order management probably
fits well in your private cloud
so what are the three steps that you
need to go through to get there the
first step you need to do is to simplify
your network you need to secure your
network and you need to automate your
operations
let's talk about simplifying your
network so in your old model you got a
rotary switch and see their RCL I am
bringing things provisioning the server
and doing everything on its own but in
the new model you got the network where
it can do self provisioning and part of
the way you get to that is you start to
simplify it I talked earlier about the
challenge you have in the way we build
networks fifteen years ago even in five
years ago so again
think about that traffic going in north
and south she went from an end user up
to a server you don't have server to
server communication you don't care how
many layers you had necessarily you get
your router layer you got an edge you
can access you got aggregation but then
when you look at the way a server to
server has to communicate its not
performing very well so the very first
thing you want to do is to get into
something known as a spiny leaf
architecture where you're taking out one
of those layers were your spine reef
you're already in a better performance
because one of your layers is gone but
the next thing that's really important
that starts you down this path to
getting to the coherent network is you
start deploying protocols like something
known as multi chastity link aggregation
so in this scenario think of your your
access layer you got your end users out
there
your spine layer acts as one switch
because you're doing a multi chassis
link aggregation so your your network
access doesn't care which of those two
it goes across already you then
eliminate that need to do manual
provisioning the next thing you can do
is start to build what's known as a
virtual chassis fabric for your home
network looks like one ethernet switch
and all of a sudden now you don't have
to worry about where are my view
lands where does this provision as
houses port talk to the other one its
all Cutler to connectivity to itself and
its managed as one ethernet switch the
next step is to start to deploy an IPO
opens fabric in the scenario and so your
your network now has all managed as a
whole
within your own entity but what this
enables you to do is then when she got
this platform set up now you can do
coherence were called beyond the edge
and start to exchange data with an
Amazon or whether Google and related
link state to them or response times and
start to choose the best best pads for
your traffic so this is this is the
simplify the network part there's a lot
of details behind it but this is the
conceptual notion of it and where do you
use these different pieces you know when
should you worry about what
so if you're if you're any legacy or
private data center and it's not a large
datacenter you're probably fine with the
most HSE leg and that's a standard
protocol standard Lee used in your
common Ethernet switches you're not
sitting here pitching proprietary thing
we do then you have the notion Ethernet
fabric so that fits in both as you get
into private cloud data centers and
larger data centers and then you get
special into the public cloud all the
sudden your IP connectivity becomes
critical because now you're going over
distance you're connecting your
datacenter as you're trying to do
backups over distance and you need to
have the right foundation do that what's
the next challenge that you have so we
talked about simplify your next
challenges how do I secure this network
if if you look at all the elements and
house built it can be really tough to
figure out where does that firewall go
or where where do I need to worry about
security will answer is unfortunately a
lot of it I know this is a crowd in
particular is very focused on it
if you look if you go back a few years
there's a call the castle model of a
castle and it's got a moat around it and
you inherently assume everything inside
the castle is safe and there are no
threats inside the castle and its
enemies come with the drawbridge put
some alligators in the moat and there
you go
what we have to think about today those
are threats from everywhere there's even
threats from non-human entities that are
just coming through bots and and
programs that clone themselves and so
think about it like the hotel model
thing about this hotel here so it's it's
your room now has a room key cuz you
can't assume the halls are safe so
that's that's one element of it but the
other element and all other things for
me this idea in your presentation
earlier today but the other element is I
have specific points were in for
security but also have an overall threat
intelligence that a coordinate so
imagine if there is a threat
entering the hotel there's a security
room in this hotel has security cameras
everywhere and they can see ok there's a
problem here there's a problem here
there's a problem here not just relying
on you to have an access key to your
room for your safety they're looking at
the whole hotel and their correlating
threats around the hotel it's much like
that in networking so where does all
that fit so this is a breakdown of the
same thing I've been showing you so this
is that data center topology you can act
as well you get the spine and I'll leave
and the router so typical firewall in
the castle would sit in this box one and
this is still critical to stateful
firewall keeps things from outs you know
bad things outside coming in but you
have a lot of other places that you need
to do enforcement along the way you got
now virtualized servers running on a
physical server what if one of your
virtualized server and it never
exercised the server it goes in
threatens another virtualized server and
it's lacking in that way so you need the
ability to have virtual firewall running
between your virtual machines in your
server
you may also have a need to do filters
or access control lists and that can
take a lot of load off of this main
fireball lit the fire on number one and
what really helps all this work is if
you have a and my clickers are going to
have an orchestrated central policy
engines of think of that as the hotel
security staff sitting in their room
watching for where the threats are and
enforcing security where it makes the
most sense you got your room key at your
door you may have doors that lock after
hours at night so it's not relying on
just one layer of securities relying on
multiple layers of security and it gives
you the threat intelligence that you
need so you can so you can send off
unwanted attacks so we've talked about
simplify and secure so the final thing
is let's let's say you got all that in
place now what's left for you to do is
to automate operations so that you can
get to this nirvana
of the end user be held revision or even
yourself provisional things very quickly
within seconds what goes into place so
again we talked a lot about where we
were gonna go quick little story when I
was really early in my career at Shell
and it was a really new I T apartment
you know things were kinda knew about
them and sometimes things didn't work
that well we're doing source route
bridging and we had some groups network
I get called up to the CIO and to
present to talk about why was a network
down and my model was worried you know
where we've been where we are now where
we going so I think learning all those
lessons of how to get a hot water back
in my twenties helps me design my
presentation so I liked about we're
worried and now where we want to go so
no bond on managing your network devices
using a CLI or something pretty brutal
wars
rather than automating but what we want
to do is get to the point where we have
an automation stack and we can
orchestrate from there now I'm 0
hardware engineer so I'm not a
programmer and I'm learning all this
probably along with a lot of folks in
the room but if you look at the stack
this is this is where we used to be
we would have arch St you be running
some kind of a proprietary operating
system on this in this case or cases
juneau's other router vendors have their
own operating systems however we're
starting to get to World War II got your
XML so I can start to run pretty
primitive scripts but I can start to
program and saucer programming interface
interface now I can write a script for
this one device oh and now there's other
things are improving all the protocols
and adding more ease of use to you got
netcom you've got Python Ruby
just goes on and on the buzz word of the
day that you can have these are all very
important they're all very useful I hold
as a team is going through class to
learn about answerable so now you get a
lot more richness in your scripting
language and chef aid those things are
providing you know they're they're
amazingly simple to use even for someone
who is a software developer and you can
look at that and say here's what I wanna
do and then tools like puppet in shelf
enable you to very easily script and
automate your network so they're very
valuable and in those are all again
those are not something our company
makes us something widely available in
the market and something many many
companies use so that its 21 bucks
though now what do I do when I get ahold
networks each of those boxes is running
that whole thing she got a couple ways
you can approach the problem of your
network coherence and your automation
you can look at a network management
system such as ours or there's a lot of
third-party systems and you can you talk
about some of the puppet type on the
world is really becoming a much more
open world these days and it's important
to understand where to leverage is
different
bodies that bottoms-up approach is
Israel for the day I called the do it
yourself Thurs they may either write
their own scripts or they may use some
things off the shelf there's also a
wealth of of trolls now for folks that
want to buy more integrated solutions
and I just throwing up several examples
here these things from VMware IBM HP
there's OpenStack solutions that are an
open-source you know freeware that you
can use or you can even build your own
but what is happening that in here
that's the missing link so network
virtualization let me describe this
fairly simple example you can't get
where you need to be unless you can get
to a virtualized network also known as
Sdn or also known as overlays and under
lays whatever terminology used to using
what is that exactly mean so let's let's
go back to my simple example and we used
to think we had some element of network
virtualization with VLANs so that's
virtual local area networks so I've got
the green network and I said I V LAN and
on the exact same infrastructure I set
up a red network that's great I was
already there why do I needed Sdn or
anything else I can already do that
actually hear your problem let's say
you're a one service needs to migrate to
different port for whatever reason yuri
provisioning server you're bringing in
new capacity you're feelin didn't move
with it did it know now you gotta go in
and manually reconfigure that VLAN to
get that to now provide connectivity to
it so there goes your automation and
orchestration that was a weekly
interchange where we want to go next
so this is it I'm gonna see the promise
of overlays because St and it's still a
relatively new technology it's it's
picking up very very quickly though and
so here's here's the promise of it we're
already seeing come to bear so same
example agree network and now I have my
red network and by the way I'm using a
centralized controller to provision
now the centralized controller can
understand when that server instance has
to move to a new port and now be
centralized controller that is automated
is able to reap revision on the fly so I
no longer have to go to manual
intervention for it and when I get from
that is not only the ease of use for the
automation but now see what happens so
let's let's look at this in logical
fashion here's my red network of my
green network what if those two are talk
to each other now what I do so now I can
do what's called service Cheney who I
don't want them I don't want finances
talking to a chart deserves some serious
data breaches that might happen either
way so now I can have virtualized
firewalls virtualize intrusion
protection I can have a load-balancing
network address translation and those
also exist on virtual machines inside my
data sooner and so I can have the
overlay controller now say oh I want to
load balancer a firewall between the red
and green network and just from my
console or even just setting up a
template of a policy I now can have that
automatically provision and by the way
this is what large carriers like Verizon
AT&T Bill Self sorry that's my age again
you know like bTW that's what they're
doing as well as a provision in your
home services so you know we're all
gonna benefit from the automation that
is already in existence but even you
know being developed and simplified a
very very quick way so that's really the
Pats in the cloud
these are the parts of the cloud we
talked about how to simplify your
architecture we talked about different
ways to secure it and why it's important
and how overall threat intelligence is
important
and then we talked about all the pieces
that go into automating it and and why
that helps you provide the fast
provision for end users and make sure
whole department run much more official
internet work work work much better so I
had finished early because that was my
last side so I give you guys two minutes
back for breaking with any questions