met good afternoon thank you for those
of you who don't know be there still
time to go back and for those of you who
do I'm sorry my name is bad I am the
founder of inter hack and I'm gonna talk
a little bit about forensic computer
analysis and I'm gonna talk generally
about forensic analysis and the
presentation of scientific evidence I'm
going to look at it from the perspective
of somebody who's challenging that work
so I'm curious before we get going how
many of you in your day jobs or your
night jobs the case may be
are involved in the creation or the
collection for the analysis of
electronic evidence that may be used in
some kind of a proceeding
a bunch how many of you have been
ordered to testify in a deposition how
many of you at trial
how many have seen things like the court
documents that's a scary things like
motion in limine
talk about some stuff here
alright so if you have questions feel
free to pipe up you could throw things
at me that sort of stuff is all fair
game usually giving a talk I'll get
probably no more than 10 minutes into it
before people feel the need to start
hurling things at me for various reasons
if the kind of thing that I'm talking
about sounds very interesting to you and
you want to play at the grown-ups table
then we should talk because as I am
desperate for people who can survive
this crazy environment that I called my
office right
the kinds of things that we do are quite
remarkably serious this is an analyst at
my firm who was given an award and that
award is what we call the verified kill
the verified kill and the associated
skull pin you get to where that goes
along with it is the results of
encountering evidence that has been
presented by somebody else
the analysis of which you have knocked
out
so in this particular case we had an
expert on the other side who had some
things that he said and Matt here had a
look at it he said
problems here gave a line of questioning
to counsel filed some paperwork that
identified some problems and the judge
ruled in a pretrial hearing that one of
his four opinions his his big-money
opinion that this iPhone has been reset
at this particular date after the fire
the judge said you can't tell the jury
that that is not a scientifically
defensible opinion sucks to be you by
the way anybody know what happens if you
have that kind of thing happened to you
you lose the case
money back if a court rules that you are
offering an unreliable opinion your
career is over
nobody hires you anymore to give their
opinion in that area it's kind of a
continuum so it's not necessarily you
never ever worked as an expert again but
you may in fact have that kind of thing
happen to stakes are high not only for
the people who are involved in the
litigation but the people who are
involved in the delivery of the evidence
so the question arises what is an expert
witness it's important to understand
that because before we get to talk about
how we analyzed evidence and how we
present the data and all that kind of
stuff we understand the role that we
play in this process the role that we
play as an expert witness is a
relatively humble one we don't really
matter in the grand scheme of things
who matters in this will be the
plaintiff who has some kind of the beef
the defendant who has a right to defend
himself against this complaint
their lawyers matter because it is the
lawyers who are going to be making the
arguments the judge matters because the
judge has to ensure that this judicial
process is being administered fairly the
jurors matter because they're the ones
who had to take a couple of weeks out of
their lives to listen to all of this
pitiful and do their civic duty so that
we have an option besides killing each
other whenever there is a dispute that
we can't resolve my arm wrestling so our
job as experts is a humble one our job
is to help the people who matter do
their job that's all we do is we help
the people who matter in this process
do their job properly so we will apply
technical expertise experience things
that the lawyers say beyond the kin of
the jury that they have the ability to
understand what all of that junk means
to be able to offer that opinion there
are several things that you need to have
this is the Federal Rule of Evidence 702
there is also an Ohio ruling on their
own rules of evidence and whatnot but
they all boil down to basically this
four prong test and it's not get to
choose which one of these I'm gonna be
able to get in with option be
you have to do all of them that is that
you have to have that kind of technical
or scientific knowledge that is going to
help the trier of fact the jurors to
understand what's going on with all of
this stuff you're gonna have to base it
upon sufficient facts or data you can't
pick two data points call it a trend
testified to it and say what's going to
happen on your third data point that no
worky has the technical term
the other thing is that you have to have
your testimony be the product of
reliable principles this is not the time
to get experimental and innovative if
you're galileo and you're saying that
the Sun is actually the center of the
universe the time to present that is it
a technical conference at a scientific
research outlets not in a trial
finally you have to apply those
principles and methods reliably to the
facts of this case you don't get to go
take a look at what's happening in
general all the stuff that's generally
happening out there and somehow score
some kind of points in this particular
case you have talked about this case for
that too
to be admissible everybody with me so
far so good now I want
to emphasize again the point about what
we're doing
being very important is not just a
question of each other for getting
killed in that sort of stuff some of the
stuff we talked about his criminal we're
talking about the government's wanting
to deprive someone of life or liberty we
have a documents that defines how we are
going to operate and that includes a
provision in this document that
provision is amendment number six the
sixth amendment to the Constitution of
the United States requires that when
someone is accused that he is afforded
the right to be confronted by the
witnesses against him
to have compulsory process for obtaining
witnesses in his favor and to have the
assistance of counsel for his defense so
if you go back to your office you fire
up in case
print out a report
who is the witness testifying against
the accused and by what process is the
right of the accused as articulated in
the sixth amendment going to be afforded
it is ultimately the person the person
has to be able to meet that test if you
don't have the ability to meet that test
in the rule of evidence then you've got
no business doing this this is very very
serious stuff as seen by some of these
cases that were working on we see a lot
of development as things get very very
important and we have more and more
information becoming increasingly
sensitive coming under attack from
nation states and all that sort of stuff
and every sheriff's office in the
country wants to be SEAL Team six and
they want to be the equivalent when it
comes to the forensic stuff so they go
to their end
training 58 training and they get their
20 hours of boot camp and then they want
to do a report
well okay but we've got a process that
we need to go through that sixth
amendment thing what prosecutors have a
bit of an issue with ads on the way to
talk about why not a good idea and
remember the Casey Anthony trial Casey
Anthony trial we got to hear about
nonstop why because nancy grace for her
bully pulpit
CNN has decided that we've got somebody
who's guilty we've got ourselves a young
mother wants to be a party Carroll and
that daughter is kinda getting in her
way of her lifestyle so we're gonna try
her on TV and we're going to convict her
on TV and that's how this is gonna work
she was such a good prosecutor that he
cited a TV host
this guy
sergeant Kevin Stenger Orange County
Florida sheriff's office he was called
as a witness for the state he testified
that in his examination of Casey
Anthony's computer he found that the
term chloroform was searched for 84
times why is that important how's that
relate to the facts of the present case
how was it the little girl was killed
chloroform was involved
84 times if you're a juror and you have
this terrific set of circumstances put
in front of you and that guy sits on the
standards is 84 times her computer had a
search term chloroform is that powerful
to you that mean something to you this
is it just what's after the fact if not
random once before the fact eighty fair
times effect repeated over and over
again by the prosecutor eighty four
times the little problem with that the
guy who wrote the software the sergeants
tanker used to eighty four times as a
lot so he decided he'd better have a
look at a software found a bug in his
software he said holy moly we got
ourselves a problem so he calls his
client Orange County Sheriff's Office
hey guys there's a bug in my software
the areas in might want to fix it what
they do they ignore him so he calls the
prosecutor hey guys are seeking the
death penalty here before you kill a
citizen maybe wanna get your facts
straight what they do
ignored him
so he calls the defense attorney hey
guys guess what I'm real sorry but
there's a bug in my software I'm trying
to get the record cleared up after
having all this notice the prosecution
puts on sergeant Stanger 84 times they
say and what they don't realize is that
the defense had been in touch with the
guy who wrote the software found the bug
fixed it and got the right number
anyone want to get the right number one
that was important
anybody remember the result the verdicts
returned by the jury not guilty does
that mean that she didn't do the thing
necessarily the state failed to prove
its case doing stupid stuff like this to
try to get an advantage because you've
got somebody you're sure is guilty is
not just corruption of the process it
ultimately is not going to get you the
result that you're really looking for
anybody know this lady and a Dukan a
chemist's Massachusetts state crime lab
she was every prosecutor's favorite
focus on drug cases anytime they needed
somebody to come through they gave her a
call why because she was always able to
make the connection that they needed why
well because she did all the evidence
that's why and we now have thousands of
cases thousands of convictions which
have to be reopened and reanalyzed
because we've got somebody fooling
around with the evidence so we could get
the conclusion that we wanted that would
be bad
heard about this elite team of forensic
hair sample analysts at FBI between 1985
and 1999 268 criminal cases across the
country the elite hair sample analysts
at FBI came in to testify in 257 of the
268 testified wrongly in favor of the
defense I'm sorry in favor of the
prosecution favorite the state you got a
state agency going through this process
using hair samples to type people to the
location of a crime
32 defendants were sentenced to death 14
or either executed or died in prison
everybody alright with this is people
are dead and no on Friday that serious
the stuff is what does not about
computers well I do computer stuff I do
death penalty cases it is that serious
in one of the cases that we worked on we
were dealing with an iPhone iPhones are
all the rage now we're so fast that
right back to the iPhone so the deal is
anybody had to make an insurance claim
lately
car crash fire in a kind of the
insurance company ask your phone
wait for it they're coming after your
phone
the reason why they want to know where
you were they wanna know how fast you
were going they want to know you're
talking to your house is on fire because
insurance companies are there to deny
your claim for your convenience
like Incredibles you know the
bureaucracy so we've got a case where
we've got an insurer and they want to
deny somebody's claim
to have their house that has burned down
because they had some guy look at the
phone super duper forensic eight er 2015
open up reads the data out and this
report this god-awful report has
conclusions in at one of which was the
location services disabled before the
loss and never relabeled the phone was
reset after the loss the owners
selectively deleted data we've got some
stuff in here that has been chosen and
also there's an encrypted backup
somewhere maybe that might have more
information on it if only we could get
ahold of putative encrypted backup that
might exist now when we start taking a
look at this what are some of the
questions that come to your mind if
you're looking at this and you're
thinking about ok somebody is trying to
make a claim that their house has burnt
down and they want to be paid for that
ok well it seems a reasonable thing to
ask you by the way to just set the fire
yourself if you got evidence that
somebody has in fact set the fire that
might be important
if somebody has tried to cover up such
evidence that also might be important
and clearly this is the kind of thing
the insurance company wants fine now has
anybody ever contracted to provide a
service to an insurance company
insurance companies as you know are
always looking for the most optimal
solution to their problems whatever the
cost right but they are shaped as all
get out they will tell you if you have
told them it's gonna cost $10,000 could
do for a nickel copper nickel that's the
kind of thing that you get into which
means that the tires of experts that
have been lined up by the insurance
company are probably doing so based on a
low rate with the promise that yeah you
might lose money on every deal but will
make up for it in volume this is where a
lot of these guys get this thing so they
start getting a lot of hype around boom
boom boom boom
and you get stuff like this now if this
is something that you're interested in
understanding locations services has
been disabled before the fire never if
you're working for the other side if
you're working for the claimant how are
you going to address that kind of
assertion are you gonna take their word
for it
call me call me skeptical about what I
have a look at this riddle me this
Batman how come when I start looking at
the palest data around here I start
finding that there are apps that record
when they last looked at the location
services and why is it that there are
time stamps in there after the loss
could you answer that question for me
that would be really great
the fact is when you offer an opinion
within a reasonable degree of scientific
certainty that is the phrase that pays
you have to meet that standard if you
can identify a simple null hypothesis
and be sure that it's not linking then
you might have a little bit of a problem
because I'm good stuff and in fact we do
look for that in fact did find it
the question of whether the phone was
reset after the loss of 10 the
foundation that would be too if you
needed to establish that with an iPhone
how much you go about doing that
timestamps you could find on the phone
somewhere
ok white 3 o'clock 15 well there's no
log off there is however going to be a
timestamp associated with records the
import into the phone and in fact after
the loss we found out there were a whole
bunch of things and contacts that were
all the same time stamp so what we have
will soon be loaded a bunch of contacts
in the phone Africa loss and you want to
go from there to the phone was wiped
really the owner selectively deleted
data this might be my favorite so
difficult with this case with the iPhone
there is a notion of a serial number
right recorder with it with a picture
like a picture 106 107 108 109 114 117
we're missing a few so clearly if you
had a fire and you're missing a few
photos in sequence then you deleted
pictures that you took of your house
burning right that's the conclusion but
the owner selectively deleted data
selectively
does anybody use celebrate to do those
phone analysis I mean this is the great
new tool everybody loves their celebrate
right could you tell me which button on
their tells you will selectively what
what what what is the test used to
establish whether something was deleted
selectively or can you tell me why
somebody chose to delete one thing but
not another anybody ever taken up at
picture before might have been blurry I
got the thing up site was in the way and
that kind of stuff now if you do have
that problem of them because if ever one
day you need to make an insurance claim
you don't want that to say well clearly
you deleted the evidence that you set
your house on fire
that's what they were claiming this is
amazing
in this case
as you saw earlier we had somebody do
some work on this issue number two and
in a pretrial motion the judge tossed
that said that you can't say that to the
jury you're not allowed to ask the
question counsel and you mister expert
are not allowed to say that they read me
but the rest of these three things
they're still on the table were going to
allow the jury to hear that and then
they can decide whether they're gonna
believe that or whether they're going to
listen to bow tie boy that's ultimately
going to be a question for the jury what
are the things that we do in the process
of preparing for trials not only to help
counsel figure out the line question to
ask us about our story will get out
there but we also do work to figure out
who's on the other side what they're
gonna say what their approaches how
they've testified in previous cases
where they've gone to school all the
training they've taken everything that
they've bumped up in the entire history
of their existence and we're going to
put that into a machine
its way to spit out a line of questions
and these are not comfortable questions
the remaining three questions
conclusions that were put up here the
opposing expert was allowed to say
opposing counsel asked the questions he
the pontiff occasion and then it was
time for cross-examination and in the
cross-examination he started taking a
look at this business of location
services and he presented the defense
attorney so they played his attorney
who's suing the insurance company
presented an exhibit that showed the
location services table and all the time
stamps on it now mister expert can you
tell me what the date of the loss was
and can you tell me in light of your
opinion that location services was
disabled before the loss and never
reactivated how it is that the table
looks like this how does this get
updated well when text location services
and say that the table there you can see
it
ok fine now how many of them are after
the date of the loss can you count them
for us we can wait
that would be more than 0
so riddle me this Batman how is it that
we have these dates in here
well I guess location services had to be
reacted location services had to be
reactivated after the time of loss so in
fact your first opinion here would be
wrong is that correct so I try to stand
that correctly
yeah okay and he would make his day
you've also said selectively deleted the
data could you explain to me that you
use to establish what the data had been
selectively deleted and then what is the
significance of that well you'll notice
the gaps in the photos exist where we've
got the old photoset stops before the
loss and then there's some photo to
continue after the loss so there were
five photos taken in this period of time
between these these these two dates for
days apart
yes
and which date were those taken on or I
don't know who's between four days the
fire lasted for five hours and you're
saying that out of the out of the whole
thing with the significance is that it
might have been the five hours where
there's a fire is that right yeah ok now
did you look at the rest of all the
photos in here see the sequence there
was no alright well let me show you
exhibit so we show the entire list all
photos by number how many do we have as
part of the series how many are skipped
before the next series continues and so
on
would you say that this period they're
looking at is consistent with the rest
of the use of this phone over a period
of eight months that's consistent so
what is the significance of your
conclusion that these photos were
deleted when they were taken at this
period of time I guess it doesn't have
any significance
so anyone can make a mistake and anyone
can say something that has no
significance I understand what about
this encrypted backup if you see an
encrypted backup know any evidence that
encrypted backup actually exists no in
fact the probative value of this would
be nothing no further questions that
sounds great presentation but I gotta
tell you it is painful to watch but it's
really rough to watch somebody go
through that especially when I'm the one
drink in the screws down on him on the
other hand remember we don't matter so
much
who matters the woman's house burned
down
she headed insurance policy
and those knuckleheads use this to deny
payment so for the last year while this
litigation is going on she is living in
a motel 6 with her family that's who
matters in this thing and that's the
reason why as much as I hate to do it I
will turn the screws down when it is
necessary
don't do that any questions on that
would make good tampering obstruction
and false alibi in this case we had a
criminal case very very high profile
criminal case we had an elected official
holding a press conference we are going
to put this guy away for twenty years
why because we know that he was involved
in the cover-up of this crime
we don't have any evidence directly
showing that he was doing any cover-up
but it is necessary to know that over
two-thirds of the unallocated clusters
contain the hexadecimal value 00 the
forensic report says decibel 0000
encrypted so what does this in an
interview transcript we see one of the
investigators getting a little flustered
well we can't get anything that he's
touched has been white with the globe
elsewhere in one of the reports we see
the contents of
were not consistent with wiping at least
a third of you raise your hands when we
were asking who's involved the analysis
of data for this purpose can anybody
tell me in a nutshell what the test that
we would apply
to data to establish whether the
unallocated clusters had been wiped was
to test for that might it be possible 00
as interesting as a Mac you know what
happens on a Mac or any PSP system for
that matter
computer
if you use our aim with the dash capital
P on it they get it right zeros
but not at first
rights FFS and then it writes 00 and
then it right Steph and that's the state
that leaves it in anybody know
what happens if you use the the trash on
the Mac and do the secure delete that
way what what what what what what
remains of the clusters their leaves
behind 00
decimal 00 no less and now for the
kicker if you get a new hard drive and
you never ever write something to it you
know what's there there there
hexadecimal 00 that death you tell me
the fact that over two-thirds of the
disc unallocated clusters contain the
hexadecimal value 00 what difference
does that make
0 hexadecimal now let's revisit the
situation we have a guy who is being
tried in the press because we got an
elected official standing up in front of
the world and the whole world is
watching this case songs are being
written about this case the TV is on and
on about the case with Rolling Stone
everybody's going on about this case
worker to put this guy away for twenty
years what evidence do we have that he
did any of the stuff that covered up
nothing but how do we know they did it
two-thirds of that allocated spaces
hexadecimal 00 were gonna put them away
for twenty years because of that
sounds good to me this is a problem I'm
not okay with that
nevertheless this is the kind of thing
that can happen now does this mean that
the analyst is Ryan too far with the
data the analyst said only this another
analyst actually said this about the
unallocated clustered not consistent
with wiping but it is the prosecutor who
read that and use it for foundation for
what she wanted to see and was prepared
to tell that to a jury until I got my
report and then things got ugly long and
short of it is rather than trying the
case on the data are supposed to pick a
jury he said your honor we would like to
drop the charge as long as all quit his
job
he'd been on administrative leave a year
and a half to go back to that job he
doesn't have to plead guilty to anything
to give any licensee known and just
don't go back to that place okay twenty
years so that not good
alright last what real quick
we're building up to a crescendo here
once upon a time there were naughty
you could procure naughty bits
file-sharing networks the standard for
being convicted of child pornography of
your possessing a disturbing as you have
to do it knowingly with any criminal act
you must know what it is that you're
doing so you get something like this the
question becomes re we've got some
naughty bits on a computer here how do
we know that this was done
knowing what we have is a report that
came from investigator poking around out
there in a big scary internet big scary
internet says well we got some naughty
bits over here they go and they serve
warrants on the phone company phone
companies as well as where he lives so
because computer guys are scary they
come beat the door down before dawn they
grabbed the computer and they resent the
files in evidence
well we need to establish this guy knew
what he was doing how do we do that
let's look for the terms that we have
here
underage underage underage must be
searching for underage and upon that
foundation they go forward this guy's
gonna have to register as a sex offender
for thirty years because he's got
pictures of somebody underage
now it comes to us take a look at what's
going on here I want to complete said is
I want to see everything I want to
understand what you're talking about hey
look at underage sure enough it's their
underage sure enough it's there and it's
there we do in fact have three files
assay underage in them isn't that
interesting however if we take a look at
the rest of the files we see the word
porn porn porn porn porn porn porn porn
you tell me is the search term are
likely underage are more likely porn
in this case Perry County Ohio we've got
to explain to a jury there how
peer-to-peer file sharing works
28 count felony indictment 10 get tossed
by the judge before trial starts we've
got another nine that we're dealing with
as the state's putting on its evidence
and then after that the judge has look
at some of the stuff and says you you
you you you have not met the threshold
here it's outta here now we're down to
nine counts and there I am on the stand
using the state's own exhibit to apply
their own method to the complete set of
data instead of the small set that they
selected for themselves not guilty
I don't think I did it for this is a
computer that was in the middle of the
house the whole family lived there a
bunch of people would come over the
house regularly and in fact when we take
a look at the timestamps associated with
it all those downloads are at the same
time making the single session so what
we learn from all this when we are
putting together forensic evidence we
have to understand that it is imperative
for us to meet a proper standard for the
stuff to be used against somebody else
because the sixth amendment requires
that the stuff get confronted and there
is exposure that we have individually as
analysts our careers literally can be
over anytime we get up on the stand
common mistakes and things that you can
watch out for when you're doing your own
work number one is not accounting for
the alternative theory you have actually
thought about what else could explain
the data here and do we have a better
explanation
then you've not done your work your job
is not to listen to somebody else's idea
and then to go about proving it your
jobs develop a hypothesis and then what
do you do next
you develop knowledge hypotheses the
things that will disprove what your
hypothesis is a new test for that when
you have tried everything that you can
think of everything that the literature
articulates and that theory still holds
then you've got something that you can
go with the next is not applying any
kind of a test not bothering to
articulate how you tell the difference
between X&Y selectively selection bias
you choose the files that you want you
ignore everything else is cherry picking
the stuff and what happens when you're
looking for something you'll find it but
if you don't see all the other stuff
you're blind and as a consequence you
wind up getting confirmation bias to
play into it and I just knew it I just
knew he was a naughty boy and ultimately
that sloppy work
in that trial in Perry County the
defense attorney made me answer the
question when talking about the state's
experts was this confirmation bias was
the selection bias or was this just
careless I like the guys on the other
side of this thing
professional working relationship advice
they screwed up but they're good guys
well as careless I'm sorry I couldn't
hear you Mr Curtin could you say that
again
no joke careless not guilty that's all
that stuff happens so as you were going
about the process always remember
important always remember your role in
this process never forget the stakes
apply these five lessons from seeing
these mistakes and you should be able to
do well thank you