so is waging Valtteri these are my
television late involved in the earlier
you get so welcome wagons were more than
working in technology and some capacity
over 15 years when I was young
what I'd like to do is turn around and
go figure
cool Mary tax stuff to do was higher at
the open source and at the time most of
the information security was open source
told CNN dallas and enjoying offers me
things
nasa's with a trip wire was if it soars
ration it was before all these vendors
who are some of this stuff out with his
hands
technologies multiuser technologies ISPs
yes I i've been warranty as well
operations and security and rear tire
was fifty years ago as the culinary
thing to do pretty much these days it's
all paperwork so GRC is seems as my time
and
relative to find out what clothes and as
well I feel a couple of high-performing
season so that's really where my
background house from I help companies
kill their technology and teams I work
with my mess welfare and before that to
check out my presentation is going to be
broader as early as you kind of us that
much of you it's really not necessarily
close your eyes like this on the agenda
is far foundation executive for forty
percent exactly that they can give it to
a little more technical stuff like to
feel free to consider any questions
about that there was the tax is
something I makes us more than happy to
speak so the folks here still awake so
that's great year with an organization
will consider cell technology because
this or any technology fried
all I hear is expecting this information
security so many different question how
many of the folks here just do this
typology of this information security
things boss once you have okayed over he
wants to be more information security
and technology in technology business
and that's a big part of what I'm going
to be talking about as far as practices
approaches to information security so
however herschel
this is out against versus all of the
Scot
artists who is a little bit so how to
make things just me if you wear things
so I think secure with other ways we
keep things secure encryption encryption
huge fire in this general other things
we do techniques were used to keep
things secure 0 trust in 10 trust now
access control or physical artifacts
physical security separation into it he
is their education that's huge he said
the voice
one lawyer 23 ish so all these things
are true and security of them come down
to restricting access control in the
industry and there is always great
approach things is so so just close to
you please so I T years back
professional perspective pretty much
came out three years and even still in a
lot of his age I hear there's a lot of
security patrols as well a lot of
security controls came out of finance
and accounting and well separation of
duties and accounted for issuing checks
you had a set of other international
security patrols crossing the road is
down their reaction to find this is
still hasn't been roped into creative
places I can't take credit for having
the right of the stellar
so traditional security controls can
slowly organization that a little
some keys so couple stories first
security bill I didn't know what the
stuff was not not from the perspective
of having years of experience i
certainly we need access to draw change
control decks started really like of
course lightweight processes
organization grew over 10 years where is
widely
I love to tell the story so literally
used to get high tech forum basically
somebody to play something it literally
turned into a pile of papers this is a
new technology or the paper had a list
of files changed his initial test
engineer software engineer initialing
awful pages on it is so late on these
pages
various block as soon as you're so you
have to walk around this country person
or organisation is a test engineering
manager software engineering manager so
as you might expect in this
hundred-person organization even better
pile of paper it was candid then
submitted to it then somebody else has
risen organization someone else has
ticket it was a very quick to get some
changes in a while
that's really not the Christmas story
may care is that these processes grow
bill this whole winter their own
overtime I question the value I do
appreciate in value
trading records changes is seen that if
you look back and tied the actual change
may be here for the folks in the US who
eschewed a little bit to make it easier
for photographs in a pic to show there's
plenty of space in here right out front
organization being slow for technology
or this issue where technology is too
slow
pictures to your product it doesn't take
very light speed things up early this is
where I want us to most time with you
talking about ways we can keep it secure
really available and secure those are
two things I think things will secure
scalable to all operations there so
let's drill separation of duties 2012
after tax changes for the five percent
of you who work in technology
decisions you probably know this
heretics for the other 95% of an
organization school really smart
engineers who has a lot of fun playing
with their ecology and takes them we
make a simple change it
tell you whether you were very long and
silent all these things that things we
want information security practitioners
do the things we want to tax i dont want
two hundred and year's title log in our
room are really user long as we all know
and probably addition tools allow us
access the system is still in power
tools and create tractors so long my
favorite things to do change that person
or actually tell you what it's like a
signature sunglasses
signing off relay 200 application or the
details of what I love they were not
really in a position
so is a much more active review and
approval process and how you manage your
teacher teaching stop doing that
dimension to enforce our control
processes nobody has to change that
there's a sec
technology plus out there yes a lot of
their coat and a lot of the things
digital as well as good as crap so check
it out sometime there's all sorts of
this when people versus there's one but
the boys it's really easy to do any 12
they're not bridge is practices are more
cognizant technology so it's kind of a
buzzword right now that's really what
that does is brings together so these
are the kind of things that adopt its
information security people we have an
opportunity here to train more to the
table from our perspective to enable
better security
a little more details for systems with
figuration
not just application for its changing a
tempest rush all these practices can be
applied universally acknowledged system
configuration management applications to
pouring the whole area was integration
tenuous integration is often the
district St but actually make sure all
the security tests so it's likely just
as much doesn't it can be at St toys
even doing this a long time
technology that's not what they need
thing about source code management is a
source of a record for a change at the
height of the at me she told the police
that she ties to the source control
there's so much competition rules out a
little stronger true martin Fallin's
then
is there's a lot of others don't have
experience working with organizations
like this because it's homey more
recently where more regulated industry
has found itself in the position where
it needs to be and that's really where
the others swear a lot of folks and the
fact that I've been in a fitness company
now
healthcare industry is it so we're going
into 2016 14 the boys so if we're
talking value many tools like this not
only is their value from a security
perspective because we have way more all
over the consistency production there's
a lot of value to business as changes
and Australia have a much more effective
organization even as an organization you
are not using technology as a
competitive advantage
much more effective operation which has
a huge value but why take even if you're
not as her college your position
technologies used as an additive it back
and if you're not your company and your
industry
many years short years there's one
industry that is this going to be
challenging for those who are talking a
little marvelous so there's holes out of
here just listen quite catastrophic to
plane engines get up very bad out these
all serve different purposes of issues
tied to enable this process which I'd
expect me you know about this autonomy
the source code scanner really focus on
this source and if you preferred vendor
must have the most supportive so so
really this is a way for information
security to align itself and work with
more innovative sisters as an issue I
most certainly will be tied to drug test
the business enabling more effective and
more secure in these are ways to do this
I assist we can do this with this is a
white whale this is a really difficult
thing to do and that's all the more
reason why I think I've seen it done
nearly perfect
accesses want there was once as well
access data only and as the structure
must developers on the database side
many of them would like access to do
this and the reason I hear most common
issues course there's always an
opportunity there's always an
alternative solution there's an
automation solution for did a business
process
business intelligence and reporting
tools and then there's a business
developer areas there's an Operations
arson if there's a non-technical person
and you are as a nation in sacks as to
the date of his decision or change your
business
V-eight will enable that very well and
that's the way taxes without accessing
the database directly or you seen her
physical security controls are logical
also a way to obstruct access on a day
later it was if you're doing it sheler
structure and spoons and analytics
databases all these things you know all
this office is not here so that's the
business side effects production
troubleshooting side of things we see
that i truly think this is
just about every organization needs to
be the biggest challenge ever got
scrubbing
if you're telling what terrifies them
are challenging logistics of it all is
lost her longtime visit technology
solution for that suffered instance
scrubbed it all investors with Mr fishy
are obviously if you really gonna get
another business work out what your
credit card numbers table doesn't need
to be sure like to wake one relatively
speaking a separate instance development
innovate automation processes to enable
that that's the perfect solution
nice two separate stints has value
performance testing is one of just heard
the technology to have a four year old
hottie is certainly not what the
confidential information that I needed
only this year and it's small sees her
organization has been around for a long
time
well when any organizational change this
is true
big small pilot project this new product
much easier to do from the ground up I'm
not sure this year's talking about
things that are difficult to do or say
hi guys still big deal we've actually
done all of this recovery and publish
the tools to enable it one of the things
we do is open source technology and
stuff like that
one of the memories currency fill this
application and serious Chris quality
beautiful air which enables status
change control using automation and made
him a dataset and see how to production
from Dell pass the time so it's been
done you can even go with really
appreciated as you contribute back but
you don't have to it's an MIT license
you can do whatever you always get out
there were doing it right now so there's
always this is a big part of my back
PCI on time and work out there that is
pretty sure all things Davis level there
is a solution for every client's
landscape there is a control solution
for every environment
are you plan and all the different in
almost all cases there's a solution one
of my favorite dishes with you a talking
about for several years how it aligns
very boring if you have information in
your email you probably need to take a
closer look
but if I slid his license for your
corporate power have no access control
of technical issues babe ministry and
get a big pile also heard what he wants
to talk about and throw it out the
window is really that is that big of a
risk to your organization
lot of time on that you got some most
viewed you live here but I think that's
an example or something relates there's
examples for everything and everything
is just a matter of finding the best way
to do we talked about earlier
the twenty-eight rules and stuff like
that those are controls that empower
different parts of the organization
hurts way over here in the superscript
very low level encryption and again
there's a solution to everything well
most of the other organizations other
parts of the technology aren't going to
be affected by that story and what they
took your new school in isolation
extreme example is there any congress
where they sell some money and that's
what they do they waited her with a
choir even so far and so every other
position even PC Island hundreds of the
day two of the things that make them one
of the technology solutions so whenever
there is just need to step back next
florida was doing school and isolate or
do something like the Eiffel many of the
other examples earlier GRC for many
people drive shoppers compliance
in a regulated industry
care or any of the others where the
average company and the industry is
having challenges because of regulation
there's
with security control your information
security program lines of the regulation
in the industry
make an organization more competitive
than 95% of the other car hire retain
made a protein marks road network
practice a lot of
it is always one of those areas we're
pretty sure this is what you see in
those cases can say okay this role this
group of people in operations as a
business you build the controls around
this does this is unique in all the
personnel management such as background
checks such in the hiring process is
stronger and the organization said no
means is that they want to see those are
pretty strong and in cases where there's
an organization established more
traditional there are opportunities to
fall back on things that resemble a more
traditional controls that are enabled
with technology tools and things like
that last procedures where the
technology is still our people that is
building a little extra points in the
process so about places though so we
know
throat surgeon dr.
thinking I'll tell you what there is a
ton of the news that our love to talk
about this subject and so very oceans in
my experience it's just hard work he's
doing the exercises going through the
Organization of culture security takes
time because and the organization as we
are to do exactly that it can be done I
probably not are helpful but I'd be
happy to discuss in more detail outside
of this particular questions so whether
that on so what I found this that's
actually one of the more things that
happen when you accelerate is today I
shops are moving so slow business units
to shatter build these applications
drives talks by accelerating and doing
this very rapid cuts the need for the
shadow of bill and it drives the data
infrastructure and back off the desktops
so you know people go over too risky
viewers actually accelerated you mean
when you don't do it on their desktops
and that price it is really really
actually
various social
has a design that enables the production
and insistence way up to a lot of yummy
asian
we use your eyes as if equipped with her
as well while the environment for system
side of things is going to differ
between the environment and we are the
types of has some organizations to have
you on the issues in configuration
management and other systems management
why so so all is well enough he
religious states I love everything but
there's companies right at once just
building using first appointment process
enables very troubling you have for two
more questions there's nobody in the
room after
so we can go a little long but I
wouldn't want to take away from your
great presentation so 14 bill today I do
you go back and decipher which one of
the 14 may break something if it has a
trickle-down effect other enhancements
that are reported each vehicle bills
during a given time thank you
process automation which is great I
washed it we haven't told that I really
want to open source we will eventually
help W was her mission tools for the
process similar to that specific to a
seal so this whole enable process part
of it primarily because there's triggers
cross-functional operations get the
notice
understand the path to communicate with
certain
so great how to process this could work
through that's tied to our automation
tools from my perspective we're still
building honored and I think I have a
much better story and you're so I think
that answer your question
like to deduct where a
business-to-business company and we
operate very much behind the scenes with
prior so try other positions in central
or insurers haver medication so this
process involves pharmacies physicians
insurance company so it's very much
built modern technology what protocols
and what level of different countries
for the process
pharmacy dispensing systems are even a
user as a right so thanks so much for
the question is really good actually
give me some ideas for building on this
presentation so if you have is here so
any recommendations are you think there
was something
why leave my nose amor awesome or are
you back this presentation specifically
for you
plans get it again so your feedback will
help me make it better and i really
appreciate that a lot of the community's
cover my magic we're hiring them I'm
esta com in the communities chris-craft
technology blog I hope my mess we open
source all sorts of stop if it is not
the primary so the software and it's not
our primary product we are going to
sources if this that's what it's worth
more often than not one of the stores
and even if it's not in the Commission's
decision yourself like that script grab
we talk about the things we're doing
these articles that DVD deploy and other
things as well if you'd like to eat or
on the ionized Ohio Linux fest I am very
involved in the lesson of this chapter
and this will be our second year old
higher if you would like to learn more
about these concepts
out of upstairs Ohio or only a hundred
and fifty bucks
hurling under this year really great
speakers last year eg from Nordstrom we
had a manager
folks came from all over the country
a bunch of Columbus locals with
technology with its strong security
physicians presented
organizers sponsors as stickers
restricts up trying to help yourself
always happy to chat or 60