thank you thank you well we're a little
after after 150 sites that we get down
to business my name's Alex Han Wei Miami
product marketing manager at Gemalto am
responsible for our equipment portfolio
and as such I get the opportunity to
participate with customers on a wide
range of issues and so we're gonna talk
a little bit today about using a
holistic data-protection approach
primarily with encryption key management
to secure your sensitive data going to
talk about this basically through the
perspective the experiences we've had
become so before we get underway I'm
kinda curious I can get a show of hands
how many of you right now work with
encryption on a day-to-day basis one how
many of you would like to use encryption
on a day-to-day basis
got 2345 ok so this fantastic this helps
me understand what to focus on next 45
minutes so how to get started we're
going to find a just a brief history of
encryption through the agents Riverview
how enterprises are looking at
encryption right now perhaps this will
speak to you very much like to get your
feedback as well and then we'll delve a
little deeper into white encryption key
management best practices look like and
how you put all of that together to get
the framework that we will review at the
end so cryptography or at least the idea
of the simulating information through
through tricks goes back for millennia
and actually the first organized
approach that we see with this goes back
to the Spartans were there to take this
thing politically essentially it was a
long strip of leather that they would
wrap around a dowel of the specific
length and diameter and they were tapped
out their messages in the latter unwind
it all and then send the message off to
another battlefield commander or bank
account for letting people know that one
to run for the health and this was a
reasonably effective approach for for
the time now is simple the person on the
other end needed a dowel of the same
diameter same lane to be able to
preschool message to Dan reading this
approach evolved and the first real
organized approach her we see something
that we would consider encryption
actually started with the Romans and
Caesar cipher where you would have to
alphabet staggered so you would write
your message
longhand and then start to transpose the
characters against the second alphabet
so in this instance your DS would become
A's B's would become be irrational
become Steve you can send your message
job and secretly as long as the person
on the other end knew where in the
alphabet start they could work backwards
transpose the message back into their
tax so again you had this idea the
message and then to secret that the
algorithm the new piece of knowledge
that you had to keep safe today
reread that message meant for centuries
largely stayed longest active is
generally character-based it did become
more complex but as with everything
enter the 19th and early 20th century
and everything went mechanical things
started to get more complex and actually
in 1918 the germans painted this enigma
rotor started an invention a few years
earlier actually designed to secure
trade secrets and then turned into
military use during World War one and
then later on ww2 and effective leader
rotors within this machine all
correspondent to specific and like every
time you hit a letter certain late with
a separate letter would would pop up
menu right now not later transcribed
your your message and the new encrypted
taxes fended off on a telegram in the
person on the other end as long as they
had a matching rotor would be able to
decrypt message so
not unlike what Caesar cipher did but a
lot faster and it also presented the
opportunity to be far more random and so
I did everything in twentieth-century
innovations fed up and this lasted
through world war two actually when the
big sagas of ww2 was discovering the
ability to beat this machine understand
German movement the advent of the end of
world war two and the advent of the
postwar age we entered the information
age and become the digital encryption
moved from character-based debate base
and then we had a series of innovations
that went from 56 big keys to now
hundred and twenty eight and 256 cheese
or modes that I'm sure most of you are
familiar with today the reform ago I
want to start this way wasn't
necessarily just to give a history
lesson but to come back to this
fundamental idea that will revisit time
and again throughout the presentation
that the basis of the security is
actually quite simple
the idea of having your your information
that you're trying to secure and the
secret that you're need to protect to be
able to encrypt and decrypt that message
right so as complex as things will get
we return to the simple idea it keeps it
all into perspective and so today this
is no this is no secret forrester this
last year reported a 54 percent of
organizations are saying that they're
using encryption extensively within the
organization
the same report found that additional
20% were planning on implementing and
corruption within the next year so sound
like based on a show of hands that are
quite a few you fall in that 20% where
you're looking at encryption and
starting to dig into this little deeper
and for good reason I we all know the
numbers I'm not gonna beat you over the
head with all this but last year alone
seven hundred and seven million records
were
through security breach I here in the
united states there were nearly 1,300
breach incidents that conduct about
three and a half a day right and we all
know the stories there and use every day
this affects everyone whether or not
you're and governments the private
sector the local level of the federal
level
everyone's been dealing with with this
in some way shape before and it's
driving how this is only going to get to
be more relevant more complex and more
vital right so we all know the data is
growing by leaps and bounds the Internet
of Things is just going to blow this
wide-open IDC projects that by 2020 will
be producing 44 trillion gigabytes of
data every single year right and Sophie
think about this you know all the
concerns that you have her just going to
grow exponentially right storing the
stuff in your datacenter defenders are
going to get bigger they're gonna get
more complex the infrastructures be used
to collect this data are going to get
bigger and more complex so how do you
create security framework around that
when we're used to building walls that
are bigger and taller and longer with
tools that we used to do determine who
gets under or through over or around the
small things about this little
differently and it makes these simple
questions even more complex right so
where to encrypt your data will how do
you do that when stopped moving to the
cloud or being replicated three other
different sites reusing right how do you
manage all of that if you got 44
trillion gigabytes of data is corrupted
and that's a beast in and of itself and
how do you do this in a way to make
sense
collaboratively within your organization
so what we're seeing from customers and
this is backed up by by reports that
we're seeing at a
Gartner and Forrester result is that
most organizations are approaching the
security specifically encryption and a
very objective focused short-term
approach a very short time so it only
comes about you have a business unit has
a project because they realize they're
either not compliance for regulations
are changing com compliant someone in
their industry has suffered a security
breach or they themselves have suffered
a security breach and so the pressure to
get something done very quickly which is
not necessarily bad is totally
understandable I'm sure all of you face
pressures one way shape or another to do
something like this maybe think about an
organization that may have 1020 business
units all doing this thing start to get
a little more complicated and foremost
business units were finding the feedback
that we get that they start off down the
path building it himself that he could
DIY approach because that works on most
of their projects right why would you go
to a third party vendor by something and
then she turned it into your
infrastructure when you have the skills
and talent to be able to do yourself
the issue that thing that we've been
finding why people have actually come to
talk to us is that encryption one is
generally more complex than people start
out thinking it is right building it
into your applications is not
necessarily a straightforward approach
and to once you actually building there
becomes a whole administrative effort
that goes on after to see you complete
the project
you achieve security or certain level of
compliance but then you have to maintain
that infrastructure you have to rotate
the keys you have to report on the lodge
he had to do the audit and that in and
of itself becomes a beast that no one
really planned on at the outset and so
the idea though the reason I prevent
this isn't necessarily to take critique
that the way things are going are wrong
is very normal and natural and people
are responding to the stimuli in the
pressures that are being asked of him
but when we take a step back at the
macro level this leads us down to an end
point that is is more complex and really
grinds to a halt in operations within
your organization so I wanna walk
through how do we actually get to that
point the road to hell is paved with
good intentions will what are those
great intentions no-decision start here
effectively this is the calculus that we
find our customers are running through
the right so year you got your data flow
you know where it originates where it
ends up and then you have a certain idea
of security versus the amount of
resources you're willing to dedicate
generating that security and somewhere
in there you figure out where the flow
you're going to establish your option
right so straightforward easy enough
well as you start thinking about the
fact that you can use encryption for a
lot of different reasons so you'll have
one business unit that's focusing on
complains you'll have another whose
driver is moving their workloads to the
cloud
you'll have a third that's focusing on
consolidating the data center and then
another one that's where to buy internet
think the responsible for all of the
data that's coming from their stances
totally normal everyone's operating in
their own best interest trying to move
the project forward but it when you
think about all of the different use
cases it becomes very clear how many
encryption keys are out there how many
you need to store and how many need to
manage and all of a sudden you've got an
organization with 10 business units all
implementing encryption you've also got
10 units managing their own encryptions
and that starts to get numbers and so
you start finding slightly so you've got
people worried about you back at media
with encryption file servers with
encryption you've got all of these
business units with their own encryption
and that becomes costly and the
administration becomes complex it
becomes a security issue because you
can't guarantee that policies are being
managed evenly across all right what
happens if a chart encryption and
they're doing everything perfectly and
financial asset in need some
informations so somehow you get
financing a charge to start working
together and a chart pattern that
featured information to finance where
the person responsible for security
there is on the beach drinking a pina
colada everyday right how do you how do
you ensure that data stays secure as it
stays within your organization right all
threads are necessarily external to the
organization you eliminate the ability
of repeatable process if everyone's
reinventing the wheel that slows down
the runnings of the organization and not
to mention the fact that they're just
challenges when you have 10 different
parts of the company so this is where we
pitch an idea right and idea for best
practice and that's to understand that
there is a relationship between
encryption there is a relationship
between key management but even though
there's that relationship we need to
separate the two start my first
attaching security to the data by using
encryption tokenization so you know that
once that data security is always secure
right so if you see cheerier information
at the application level as it enters
your databases as it enters into files
as those files are then backed up and
moved offsite you know that for its
entire life cycle it safe
right it's safe as long as the Caesars
right so you start taking this cheese
and you implement secure and property
management strategies and make vote the
administration of those two things
separate but two separate individuals
then you're creating a fail-safe
redundancy that protects the other so we
like this a decoupled your keys from
your so it's natural it's pretty into it
if there's a three-step approach first
figure out where your day right what's
the weirdest shit reside what's the flow
from the point is created what are the
touch point where does it end up what
are you trying to achieve once you
understand that the solution the type of
encryption that you need is relatively
straightforward once you do that
implement a property management strategy
will get into the best practices of
command ransacking centralized archie
management that only one person or group
be responsible for it
access to your key as separate do decent
no single individual has control of both
data and key management hiring again
something we'll get back to us so you've
decided to go with encryption you are
trying to figure out how to manage your
cheese you've got a couple off so first
for agile organizations who have a lot
of flexibility you need to spin out then
down pretty quickly there are certain
things such as doctor based managers and
there are number of vendors the dude
that do this I don't want anyone to feel
like this is a multi-page we've got
competitors that do this as well and the
idea that virtual machine running on a
server somewhere so if you're benefiting
from the cloud workloads you can spend
these up an Amazon or a sure goal or IBM
to give you all the functions that you
need to property manager teased so
functions call keys generate keys wrote
E Cheese delete keys the benefit really
comes into flexibility and within a
virtual machine the downside is that you
generally will not be able to offload
the same extent of cryptographic
operations on to a virtual machine as
you would a political planes the upside
however is that users are cheaper to
give you more flexibility and you can
use them in tandem with hardware
security modules also rooted in the
cloud to give you the same storage and
root of trust that you would get on
promised meaning you can still guarantee
that your teeth are locked away and it's
not just a random software files located
somewhere on the software on a service
that's second option is a physical
appliance that you attached by a network
benefit to go into this approach
generally better performance you'll get
expanded no expanded range of the number
of keys are you can manage you'll get
better control also complained reasons
you may want to have the keys and
everything stored within your datacenter
we don't have to nestle for no doubt
that cloud and benefit from better load
balancing and high availability so these
are the options you can mix and match
depending on the level of security need
if you need something that's fully
tamper-proof UK the play on prime
minister and a network-attached key
manager if you were OK with your team
and your not being tamper-proof but
you're still want to root your keys and
hardware you can still see him out of
the cloud using a virtual machine so the
best practices writes the encryption is
the easy part it's the key management
start to get complicated the first and
foremost most important thing you should
do is get up to speed and comfortable
with property managers and this will
change by my industry
some extent certain regulations will
dictate how often you need to rotate
your keys how do you delete data from Dr
that you're going to retire so get
comfortable and up to speed with how
regulations affect key management in
your industry and put one person on this
at the very least one person generally
more rotate your cheese
the ideas that you don't just encrypt
data and put it away that's part of it
but you want to keep people on their
toes right you want to change the
encryption so what's so someone can copy
that gate in and try to brute force
overtime
trashing the goalpost movie the second
centralization for all of your season
one place so we returned back to that
idea of the ten business units all with
their own set of encryption you got ten
different people managing keys how do
you at the macro level and CIO level
guaranteed control across this
organization you can but you don't have
to so depends depends on how you want to
do it there are certain ways to to
rotate he's just by altering the header
header on on the data or on the key
itself or you can decrypt entry
encrypted so it comes down to the level
of security you want but most key
managers will give you the flexibility
and more stricter organizations well
will completely
encrypt and there are ways to do that
without decrypting itself most
organizations will will do I shall we
call it shallow key rotation
and they do that by by affecting better
question though many others before so
centralized her to end this is a return
to this and the second this really is
where you get the biggest benefit for
both control and cost savings so imagine
how this ten business units all
implementing encryption all managing
their employees what happens if you were
to take the key management off their
plates and put it in one central service
matter how much time energy and money to
freeze up across the organization right
and imagine if you are the Administrator
what kind of headache that takes off
your place if all this and you've got
one place within the organization that's
responsible for encryption key
management that's their expertise and
that's their day-to-day tasks to rotate
these keys to delete keys do all that
because he rotation doesn't sound like a
lot of work but imagine if you are
responsible for data center that has a
thousand file servers that's not
including the databases that's not
including virtual machines are workloads
move to the cloud or applications using
encryption that's just a to file servers
that's not even including petitions
within within different servers within
your organization you had to rotate all
of those keys every six months almost
becomes a real nightmare right and
especially as we go back and think about
44 trillion gigabytes that we're gonna
produced annually in the next four years
that's you know that becomes a challenge
that becomes a lot of time there could
be better spent on other parts providing
value elsewhere
once you centralize your keys you can
implement access controls to the data
you can govern that a charge and access
subset of foul play
finance get setup file R&D get set of
files be you can do that both at the
data level but also from the key measure
controlling who has access to those you
can separate duty among administrators
so the person responsible for storage
will never see the data include tax and
the environment they manage your team
manager can control all of the
encryption me he'll never have access to
the storage right thing goes for the
database imagine how important this
becomes if you're moving your data into
the cloud right how do you guarantee the
person responsible for storage in the
cloud isn't going to get into your day
encryption and managing the keys and
controlling the keys your cell is a
great way to think about it the other
day and encryption key is a file and
that files on the server somewhere who's
to say that someone can come along and
copy it move it somewhere else without
you knowing it so take your keys and
store them in harder whether it's from a
virtual manager or from a
network-attached a plan to make sure
that you've got a chance them available
to store the key because it also helps
you demonstrate complains right if you
can guarantee that your data is
encrypted and you're the only person
that picky and you have the logs to
prove that you're the only person who
seemed like she then you can demonstrate
the you're controlling your data
wherever it is whether it's in the cloud
whether it's offsite backup whether or
not you've got a geographically
dispersed environment and then the last
few are basically make sure there's
never just one set of the key most key
managers come with high availability
configuration for you can replicate from
one to the other
securely so that he take one offline for
maintenance one goes down your
maintaining access to today so if you do
this you move from the site leaders
central I sir this is starting to catch
on
gardener is projecting that centralized
management is going to be the root
encryption within the next few years and
that everything's going to build on that
and this will will significantly alter
the the way that your organization will
will work together for a number of
reasons one this approach helps you get
to better secured for the simple fact
never bring everything together and
putting one team in controlling your
eliminating
ensuring that instead of having nine of
your 10 business units doing encryption
appropriately you've got one
organization that's doing encryption
appropriately data security
appropriately for everyone this saves
money so if we come back and think about
key management 10 times versus chain
management ones I mean think of all of
the time money and effort that you're
saving
I got a case study at the end and the
case study at the end they did it under
information government governance but we
do have a couple customers off the top
of my head I know are doing it with a
ninety so I think it comes down to the
politics of the organization or just how
you want to do strategically and think
all of us have enough experience where
some organizations I T lead security
another is it legal to carry so I think
it comes down by we've seen boat that's
great question so consolidate commandant
will save money both by saving time and
effort but also think about it i mean
how many vendors that you work with
readers a volume discount
clothes and you're buying encryption
licenses once for the entire
organization you're also getting a
discount so from a macro level when
you're making the case to the c-suite
not only is this edition for you this is
good for the organization and this
relieves budget everywhere it improves
collaboration so going back to the
example of a char and finance if
everyone's on the same encryption
platform the barriers to working
together to share information is less
right now those barriers were smaller
you might have to work through the
central encryption service though people
had free access to cross functional data
but ultimately you're not getting the
silos that are keeping people from
collaborating not only does this lead to
faster innovation but the fact that
you're centralizing these services and
creating repeatable process he's also
drive innovation faster to get you to
value faster imagine if you're the
business unit and your need to
incorporate encryption into your
application that central service can
have sample code they can have the
encryption libraries already said they
can have a TI is there for you to call
and so instead of building this from the
ground up which is our natural
tendencies based on so many years of
success this approach actually takes
weeks or months off of your home your
cycles and gets you to value passed so
what this looks like the holistic data
protection frameworks starts with your
enterprise key measure sorry that it is
low cut off I started your teenager
that's the root of it all everything
else plugs once you do that you know
there are a number of vendors out there
is not just our portfolio you can find a
portfolio that works for you where the
solutions are the application the
database the file level
virtual machines tokenization it's all
there for you they all plug into the
same diamond ring once you do that
you've got protection for a broad set of
n points within your organization
whether its sequel database and no
sequel database had do these portfolios
will work together to cover this gas and
that's just from a single vendor then
from that portfolio most vendors with
their team manager also have a broad
ecosystem they build on top of that even
more so the idea is that there's no
single vendor that's going to solve all
of your problems and create world peace
but these vendors are working together
in a way that that lend their expertise
to cover gaps and to do so in a way that
lets you manage them all from one so
this is really that the trend that we're
seeing where things are going whether is
Gemalto Andover metric analysis but
their their acquisition or merger is
going down the status while so for you
as ninety professional you have actually
a lot more power and leverage when
you're going to these vendors looking
for encryption to say I have these
solutions in my environment how are you
going to help me centralized them in
this teenager that better for you in the
long term is better for the vendor in
the long term and just makes things
easier right i mean if you've got to do
if you've got mainframes you know moving
from legacy to new workloads to the
cloud databases in both places no single
vendor is going to do all that in and of
themselves but you start bringing in
court works and I aww us to do all of
this stuff behind a single key manager
that just makes things easier for you so
come back to the customer success story
took the name off
but we have a large payment processor
that came to us about a year and a half
ago they're coming run into problems
precisely because of the silo parts of
their organization weren't working
effectively together and corruption was
the root of the problem they got over
two billion credit and payment cards
around the world so PCI DSS was
significant challenge and they needed us
to secure both structure and
unstructured we worked with that come up
with this idea of centralizing key
management and then for me got
encryption we call it encryption as I T
service and started work amazingly they
were excited by the fact that I love for
coming down and certain business units
Rick just working together they were
starting to create products that they
were then turning around and monetize it
wasn't just an internal internal
efficiency actually helped drive their
business and now I mean we we talked
with them often defined increased
efficiencies we are part of our our
Customer Advisory Council D help us
understand how the business units are
responding to this in all came back to
the idea that the the silos within the
organization there was such expertise
and timelines are so short
building in themselves just meet but now
they're taking a step back they're
finding all of the benefits all the
benefits I just shared are actually two
things that they reported so you know
from at a high level thought perspective
there's a lot this intuitive here but we
actually arrived at this point because
this discreet challenge and the outcomes
that this payment processor found by
implementing a centralized service so I
would like to tie a tie it back up
we talk about encryption and the
inevitability of security breaches quite
often I think it's certainly important
to acknowledge that this trip was part
of a larger security scope right
everyone should have a perimeter
everyone should have intrusion detection
no one should rely on August single
approach to security but there are
certain fundamental things that have
worked for thousands of years and
there's a reason why those approaches
just propagated involved in got better
right they went from strip of leather to
now
digital bits and bytes but the
fundamentals are the same if you do
those are you're going to be successful
and they're going to help you gonna fill
those gaps so you know
think about securing your data through
encryption keeping that secret the
encryption key private locking it away
and she do that your data can travel
anywhere
99.999 99 99 percent of the time I'll
stay secure so I'm that I think you very
much for showing up around if anyone has
questions and I hope you have enjoyed
your show