rearm the co-founder and chief
technology officer for fish me what that
means is I'm in charge of our product
technology roadmap I'm in charge of our
R&D efforts and our engineering teams as
well as the operations teams needed to
pull off millions upon millions of
fishing simulations what you're in for a
lot of flights don't worry if you see
URLs or stats your statistics that you
want to capture the slides are going to
be on the portal for this event as well
as I'm going to be uploading them to
SlideShare I hate it when I go into a
presentation and the presenter doesn't
cock cover what's in the abstract
that's not this presentation at all I'm
pretty much going to cover the abstract
we're going to examine is fishing easy I
hear a lot of information security
practitioners claim that it is a weird
look at multiple data points highlights
from our enterprise security reports
we're gonna look at popular fishing
beings ones that our customers tend to
use and they like to use we're going to
look at some statistics on how much time
people spend on the education material
once they fall prey to a phishing attack
and then we're going to try to export
the topic of why do people continue to
fall for fishing so first we're gonna
start with a telework the Office of
Personnel Management this was probably
in my opinion one of the most impactful
data breaches that we had to deal with
last year and anytime I hear about a
breach I'm always curious to know was
officially involved was fishing involves
so I watched the C span testimony on the
hill and made him say anything about
fishing but chances are in this day and
age appears a breach fishing were
somehow our fault so I got my hands on
the search for a certain report it
didn't say this was the cert report for
the OPM breach but the opening of the
cert reports that hey here's a search
report about indicators about a breach
that caused a large data loss that's
that's all it said in the headers so the
idea behind a lot of research reports
and see if we can get indicators to
other business units other parts of the
government they can look at their
networks to find out if they were
compromised well like I said the report
didn't say this was about her p.m.
but inside of the indicators listeners
in the back one that was interesting to
me some of the domains listed OPM
security dot org and opium test learning
that or that the attackers registered
chances are this probably is the search
report related to that breach another
thing that was interesting as I was
going through the indicators that stood
out to me was one of the indicators was
a file an executable e-zpass Highland
ill when a number and then invoice fish
dash malicious that PDF so that analysts
when they put that in this may rename
that file probably just organize their
tasks so what that says to me is this is
probably the surf report about the
European breach these are indicators
probably related to that drinks and most
likely it was fishing that was the
initial attack vector that caused that
breach so the verbiage around this
breach wears these were advanced
attackers they got in it was a nation
state but when I C E ZPass as one of the
indicators one of the things that
immediately I think about is if you live
on the east coast are familiar with the
e-zpass toll system is it was this fish
this theme has been around and it's been
plaguing consumers for three to four
years so these advanced actors military
state sponsored actors they didn't
necessarily put a whole lot of effort
into the phishing email needed to
compromise those employees they went
with what works which was carrying those
employees that they think that they may
have received a Gold Pass violation so
the DA chance response to this was
interesting again there was no admission
publicly that this was a fishing
incident at all in fact the congressman
grill opium about not encrypting the
data but a few weeks later the DA says
started to put out a response to this
and basically one of the heads of the
DHS has said that we're gonna pull my
credentials of anyone that fails a
fishing test and another message from
the government was
what we're gonna do a security awareness
fishing campaign and it's going to
feature short videos and posters and
literature on the do's and don'ts for
better security hygiene and as a citizen
who had been his biggest win in this
breach in like 10 this this is really
not going to to help out and we're gonna
look at reasons why so the testimony on
this was frustrating to say the least
but yet we definitely got some more
information from the DoD I mean people
that run received copies about their
data being breached and what ways the
government plan to address this was a
thirty-minute fishing awareness video
and computer based training program so
I'm like the dude says down there you
have that's that's not going to work
jump back into my background I've been
doing information security for a long
time
want to write a most memorable positions
when I started as a consultant for found
stone in 2002 which was later acquired
by McAfee and I did a lot of incident
response and penetration testing in
there is here but also a thing that we
did as part of that found stone was
delivered this ultimate hacking class to
hundreds and hundreds of information
security professionals over damir and it
was based on methodologies we would
publish and are hacking exposed books
and the idea was you become a better
network the standard by learn how the
way that people break into networks so
throughout that time I met a lot of
information security engineer and I
begin to understand how they think about
network attack in the stands and most of
the time they're really thinking about
configuration management patch
management and that sort of thing in
their rarely thinking about the user's
impact on a security ecosystem one of
the classic debates and I get into with
my colleagues when I suggest that trying
to make our human were resilient against
phishing is actually worthwhile endeavor
is this little report but it only takes
one fish to compromise a network so why
even put any effort into making me so
that's something that I encounter quite
off
so I want to examine that thought is
fishing he is fishing easy for an
attacker
look at all the things that they need to
pull off in order to successfully
mission organization they have to start
with recon have to find email addresses
I have to find relationships inside of
that organization oftentimes remaining
social networks in order to get that you
get weaponization of some sort of
payload to work so they have to figure
out the operating systems but their
target victims have they have to tune
something that will get past filters and
firewalls in URL analysis sandbox so
they had quite a bit to do you usually
need to obfuscate that code so they can
bypass traditional wavy I'm so there are
a lot of their effort goes into the
Recon in the weaponization to prepare
for phishing attack but they're not done
yet
now we have to deliver it so that means
sending an email campaign to deliver the
work that they've prepared for that fish
so they have an entire infrastructure
ready to receive outbound connection
with their physician successful but now
they still have to get that email and
that is actually getting more difficult
for those attackers it used to be that
they would register random domains news
differently hosts in order to use and
phishing emails the trend that were
observing as many of them are choosing
to send phishing emails from gmail from
hotmail from Yahoo and the reason why is
they know that that smell infrastructure
that is difficult for you to block and
those mail providers are all have proper
spf they'll have property again so they
increase the chances of getting that
fishing to that organization so that's
something that they have to consider
another thing that Fisher Fisher has to
consider is the time of day the most
exploitable platform is a Windows
platform with tons of plugins installed
one of the most Brazilian platforms is a
mobile platform so if you're doing all
of that reconnaissance and preparing up
a road you need that phishing email to
hit an office worker when they're likely
sitting in front of your Windows
computer you don't want that fish
to hit them at night when they're more
likely to use a mobile phones are you ok
so now we have to get that exploit to
land so there's a number of different
defenses and things that an organization
might have to detect that stop that
breached survey have to worry now even
if they are successful in breaking in
now they have limited time to explain
expand influence on the network flat
black doors and hopefully begin to
export trade data out which is even
difficult for them know that they can
have their breach discovered if they're
not careful about the data exfiltration
so there's a lot that they need to
consider in order to be successful at a
fish so when they're put all of that
together they really put a lot of effort
into the phishing email for instance has
officially email that advance the
attackers are sending to your employees
at work here let employees know that hey
we had a problem during the Halloween
season was wearing inappropriate
costumes at work and so we want everyone
to have fun this Halloween and in order
to make sure that we're having fun is
still within the acceptable guidelines
click this gallery of acceptable
Halloween costumes at work something
that we would all want to click on right
wing but what is acceptable what's not
acceptable
here's another one that advanced actors
are using all the time we have a lunch
in the break room in order to combat
this we're doing is we put a webcam and
allow any employee to connect either
from a home office a remote office to
monitor the webcam to see if their
lunches are getting slaughtered what
employees Creek this yet maybe they're
the ones the languages may be the ones
having their lunches thought maybe
they're just voyeurs may want to see
someone's the Uni Watch maybe they're
connected to a remote office these two
examples they're actually not made by
advanced attackers at all these are
fishman simulations because we like to
have a little fun and try to think about
emotional triggers that would get an
office worker to click the reality is
what advanced attackers are really using
are examples like that OPM breach just
tired reuse content over and over again
or here's an example of a crime where
reaches an incoming fax report but your
to open up the attachment the reason why
not pretty wide effort into the content
of the emails is because their operation
is complexed they have a lot to do and
support they do it's kind of a numbers
game for them they just pulled fishing
template off the shelf and they give it
a go and they sendin and suspicions are
now following the emails so they get
somebody to click and this is this is
really the state of things that the
clever scenarios about refrigerator
webcams and Halloween costumes at work
that's that's what companies are doing
simulations or are worried about the
reality is most attackers are rooms and
content will look at a recent examples
of ransomware is hot again
lockheed we I thought trip to Wal Mart
where things are the past but there's
been a huge uptake in ransomware encrypt
crypto where over the past two to three
months and we've done a lot of analysis
and here's an example of a very recent
face March 10 that was distributing
locking and it's using some of the same
tired and true tried-and-true methods
again it's about an invoice overtaxed
increased 32 reviewed your pick up the
invoice you click it and unfortunately
it starts encrypting files on your
computer
one of the things that was interesting
to us as we were observing this campaign
is they are getting more sophistication
and randomized any portions and content
of the phishing emails so we're gonna
look at rocky briefly as well as a dire
campaign so this is an I know this is
impossible to read in the back so just
explain it quickly this is an example
where to fish is that we caught in a
while that was directed at us and our
employees reported and it was the same
exact campaign one of the things that
really stood out to us is it was highly
varied in the body
the file names were changed the sender
names were changed different numbers a
sport in which numbers customers order
dates they were all different or miss
trying to show that uptick in the
sophistication of crime where actors
that are sending station
Nelson mass they're doing this to avoid
different detection that you might have
and really to have a different antispam
technologies might have in place but
this one was a bit of a surprise to us
the same campaigned same day had so many
different variations embedded into the
fishing body itself so we looked at this
campaign we had twelve hundred different
samples and we noticed that all those
100 samples it came from seven hundred
different IP addresses the attackers to
deliver those 1,200 samples had six or
seven hundred VIPs under control he had
over 1,100 different domains to send
these from and they definitely did a lot
of randomization this really speaks to
wide waukee and ransomware is
particularly damaging right now the
network that these guys are using to
deliver beans n bass is impressed that
they have thousands of compromised hosts
in order to pull this off I will get
another campaign dire so most of these
are being delivered by its cyber crying
game out of ukraine dyer was a banking
Trojan that is installed it would
attempt to get credentials from your
your browser with man in the middle of
your browser what we've observed is that
same cyber gang is just moved to answer
we're so what they're doing what they're
doing is they're using the same network
and hosts that they have reduced
delivering a different attack right now
it was alarming about this is we looked
at 218 campaigns from dire we had 30,000
unique samples and elbows 30,000 unique
samples a single subject was used nor
more than a dozen times so they
definitely are rotating and random
rising their campaigns in order to
maximize efficiency for them
all right we're switching gears a little
bit here and we're getting out of crime
where and current fashion trends and I'm
gonna share with you some highlights
from our enterprise fishing
susceptibility report there is an entire
presentation about this on bright talk
it's free to view and you can you can
get this report from mars I just really
want to cover some of the highlights
because we get we have a lot of data and
we're getting a lot of questions about
this this might be useful to you if
you're in charge of doing fishing
simulation program at your job we've had
some some some somewhere questions or
want to learn from some reports that our
customers are doing so we we really
wanted to whittle down the sample size
we have a vast diversity into our
customers are if you dont know about
fish meal and fish me simulations it's a
platform in order to send simulated
efficient you know the people at work
seventy percent of our customers they do
this completely on their own so we just
kept them in the account and may have an
idea of how we're going to use
simulations in order to reduce the
official comment the organization about
30% of our customers use our Managed
Services in order to let us drive the
entire experience and prescribe their
next steps while they're using it so in
order to try to make this enterprising
reporter or enterprise broke is what we
did is we we limited our our analysis to
organizations that we're training at
least 3,000 employees are more we want a
larger enterprises and that have been
using fish me for for quite some time
I'm so weak that so we we focused on
after this study we asked several
questions we wanted to know if different
beings are levels of complexities more
difficult for some employees to
recognize what were some of the
motivational emotional motivators that
got people to click on a difference
people that are on the job as people
ride home and attacked officials might
interact with this time of day influence
that users vulnerabilities we wanted to
work at some of our customers that were
running simulations in the morning
versus the afternoon and so on and so on
this report has all of that data is one
of the key findings it's the store quite
a bit to cover
eighty-seven percent of employees open
the fishing simulation the same day and
this is what I snore murder our
customers reports there's a huge spike
in the first day but the first few hours
that fishing simulation going out which
makes sense you know a lot of people are
on the spot where their email me do try
to keep it clean
inbox most employees are responding to
emails during the morning hours so that
might mean when maybe when they're
little word rocky or they have a lot to
email to go through so they're trying to
do it and no more rapid fire that method
instead of mathematical method this next
step was interesting to me
sixty-seven percent of people who fall
prey to the fishing simulation are more
likely to fall for another efficient it
sounds so when we observe this and we
saw our customers like that makes sense
you know you tailor your program around
the people that have demonstrated that
they do have a vulnerability that they
need extra help here and increase the
frequency of simulations to that
population and export Co Inc wasn't
really surprised the most effective
efficient emails for our simulations
weird names that contain business
communication so you're at work trying
to get you got done getting a business
communication oriented fish you're more
likely to fall for that then one that's
trying to give you an Amazon gift card
or give you a discount to home keeper or
something to that effect in the last one
we observe is that population is
demonstrating susceptibility that it
took about four simulations for them to
follow along with the rest their their
peers so yes they were susceptible they
were 67 percent more likely to fall for
the next fish that metric kind of hang
on about that same level until they
received their third and fourth place
where there was a dramatic decrease in
that users except to go with what about
teams and complexities so we tried to
organize our things because there's
quite a different templates inside of me
that can use and we wanted to see which
ones people were more likely to fall for
so what we did is we organize them by
office communication type emails
things about computer updates employee
well lesson so on and then some of the
things that we consider we're trying to
evaluate our what is the contact person
or persons home what are the emotional
motivators to get someone to click she
reward curiosity entertainment
burdensome and then technical
difficulties are very erotic lose that
this was a fish in the body of the email
or just one or two so he averages and
benchmarks so like I mentioned office
communications had the highest
susceptibility ranked by average and if
we looked at a specific room the one
that was really giving people trouble
where's files sent from scanner on that
is something that might received when I
didn't scan something or maybe someone
is trying to send something to me it
feels right in the context of your work
day what probably is no surprises
fishing teams about computer updates
they had the recent African seen as far
as getting someone to fall for a fish
but if you look at the sample size and
demographics of the study we did try to
limited to organizations were more than
a thousand employees that's highly
unlikely and organization at that level
has their employees manually installing
patches were flash or Adobe Reader any
of those things are the databases we
show that too is that those employees
were more suspicious that type phishing
email than the standard office
communications one of the questions that
we wanted to do we have enough customers
that we can do this now is there anyone
market for vertical that's particularly
more vulnerable to another so we looked
at package delivery type of scenario our
customers like to send out lots of
packing delivery scenarios and there was
a wide variance we couldn't conclusively
say finances are more vulnerable to
package delivery or energy and probably
really has to do with the likelihood of
you to receive a package at work so
education is that out is one that was a
little bit more vulnerable to package
delivery some barriers and maybe it is
that the people on education they do
receive a lot of packages very exciting
to get a package whereas manufacturing
was pretty low is highly unlikely that
arrived workers someone is receiving a
package of work not sure on that lets
move into top emotional motivators so as
other data that we analyze what's
getting people to want to click a
connection is going to I know this
person is someone trying to make a
personal connection with me was your
name dropped in the body of the email
was one reward was another one curiosity
urgency and cheer against to trail off
so you know an email that's faking to
look like it's coming from your CEO your
boss and your VP that might be one of
the motivations that get people to click
on average another thing I did as I want
to our content and I said show me the
most popular scenarios are the ones
especially customers really like to use
that kind of does show us which threats
that they're worried about insider
organization and so what they did is
they organized for me the average
susceptibility
the percentage of people that are on
average were falling for this type of
simulation and then the popularity
amongst our customers so likewise like I
mentioned here
package delivery is very very popular
works and unauthorized access I want to
highlight that one will look at that it
has a high percentage of people clicking
on it and it's it is very popular
amongst our customers then I asked our
content team I said I want to look at
our most susceptible themes are not
necessarily the ones that our customers
are gravitating towards and they want to
do but the ones that have demonstrated a
high percentage of susceptibility but
also show me how popular they are
amongst our our customers manager
evaluation is the highest percentage as
far as susceptibility but it is not
popular more efficiently customers and
that's probably why there that might be
just too much of an emotional trigger
for someone to rescue the fishing
simulation of phishing email about a
performance evaluation even though it is
shown that it is
employees are susceptible to rate it
might be the people that are running
simulations they don't necessarily want
to risk your job making some sort of a
chart type of process
similarly though we're gonna look at two
different unauthorized access teams one
of them is unauthorized access or don't
care
oriented its 30% or people are falling
for that but it's a low popularity would
get why and then unauthorized access
just regular it's right up there it's
nearly 30% as well but it is slightly
more popular with our customers so
unauthorized access 29 percent of people
on average applying for this it is
popular
the way that this fish works is it
basically says hey we think your
computer when sites that wasn't supposed
to you but we understand that sometimes
these systems are incorrect if you want
to log in and review the logs we
captured granddaughter this portal and
login with your credentials and we can
see what triggered this alert another
one that is very popular and has a high
success rate is hard alerts you have a
secret admirer at work why does he
retired worker who is it I marry why
would someone be my secret admirer all
this is where I want to click this and
find out who this person is or yes I
have a secret admirer work I want to
click this and find out who is this one
is a popular scenario used by customers
and it does have a a significant impact
we do see this being sent out around
down times they another holiday inns the
one that I mentioned that is low popular
low popularity but high rate is manager
evaluation and if you look at this
temperature is a little hard to see a
lot of different mail merge type of
features and so dear in certain names or
personal connection here at our
companies in the field it's
automatically populated Department these
are all things that I
attacker could glean about your
organization just by browsing LinkedIn
your supervisor's name and company name
so it's no wonder why something like
this really does get someone's attention
it looks like official communication
and it's something that makes that
connection with someone who makes them
want to click and interact with that
email more unauthorized web use low
popularity so this one is kind of up in
the bar on the first one which is a we
went to some sites that were categorized
as adult material what we understand
that we can make some mistakes if you
want to review that's I go ahead and log
into this portal to check out the
reviews again not surprising that a lot
of our customers avoid this they don't
want to necessarily create a situation
inside of her organization I just want
people to be less vulnerable so shifting
gears here we're gonna get into creating
fishing awareness like I said I've done
a lot of information security
professionals and often times especially
in the engineering and technical sides
their battle that why why do people fall
for phishing emails obviously this isn't
correct and so we charge them with
trying to do an awareness type of
campaign and most of them take us down
this path well in order to figure out
phishing emails what you gotta do what
you gotta have your mouse over the lake
and then gotta read the rain from right
to left slow and then you're gonna have
one clue and that's a lot of Engineers
think that they're going to teach people
how to sing and this is what our
customers want us to build so we build
these templates and education templates
are we color coat them for them and we
say ok we'll make them for you and we go
to a rather different awareness type of
events and one of the things that I hear
a lot of awareness professionals is if
you just make the content more engaging
if you don't use Times New Roman and you
use word I don't use red and you hired
artist that's the key that is the key to
getting people to look at your awareness
material and stop overfishing so I see a
lot of security professionals just kind
of whipping themselves thinking up I was
just better at heart I would get people
to really look at my education and stop
calling for fishing so we get tons of
requests from our content team because
most of our customers have some sort of
security awareness rollins'
side of the organization our customers
want videos they want infographics that
one static HTML they want translated
content we do it all
that's what they want and then we get
feedback based on this content and were
spending quite a bit of money we
probably spent a million and a half
dollars a year on content creation
translation service and video animation
you name it we put a lot of effort into
this so our customers told us that the
bad guy in our training videos to
Chinese look so we had to go and we do
that and make him work less Chinese so
that was expensive but we got it not
have a super woman in our and our videos
they're like hey you did it you found
the fishing this is how you reported
Lori did you make her less alluring Mike
really means it was at the Cape is what
is it with just two alluring just toner
downright ok we're gonna go ahead
remaster that video and then get reach
translated into other languages to make
her West or worrying gold your scenarios
of two American cheese me what ya we
don't like the double room so you want
us to read all the narrations in our
videos with a British accent please do
that ok you think this is the key to
getting people to stop calling for
official we're gonna go ahead and do
that are short video was 27 seconds
our longest videos about three minutes
and these things are tailored to teach
during that just occurred so it was an
attachment base fish
videos about attachment issues and so on
time spent on education so we're on a
piece of JavaScript to count how many
seconds
people spend consuming this video this
content we spend a lot of money on its
not too sexy not to Chinese not tutoring
and not to american and mass majority of
people are spending less than nine
seconds so they just built for sin area
and they're spending between 0 and nine
seconds to review this content whereas
concerning especially if your job as a
security awareness but is it there so
one of the things that we observe across
our data is doesn't matter for
susceptibility to susceptibility rates
are going down doesn't matter nine
seconds on the video its evidence is
right there in that susceptibility
report but why why is it that it's going
down not only is a susceptibility rates
improving
berated user reporting accuracy and
speed of reporting simulations is going
up our customers really tend to focus on
the susceptibility data are not
necessarily they will be really want to
drive that down so there are little
disheartened when they're doing their
campaigns and things are driving down
and then also there's a spike in April
gonna happen when we look at their
content more like well you chose a more
advanced scenario you send it to a
population that hasn't had as much
exposure to it and you've been
traditionally doing clinical reason this
was an attachment
case scenario so that's that's to be
expected one of the trends our customers
don't always notice but we do try to
help pointed out to them is this is a
hard thing to measure you if you want to
be David Rabin you can just send the
same type of scenario over the course of
the year and you're gonna have a
beautiful general trend lying down we
recommend up in the sophistication every
single time in order to get them to
prepare to ward off early gains tax but
what even earlier scenarios are a little
bit old will replace the green trend
line is your rate of user reports so
these are people that have been
conditioned to spot suspicious email
that are reporting it to your writing
organizations is quick and a quicker
than they're falling for that so that is
absolutely a wintry
so what we want to do is show that hey
you you you you build an army of people
that are a rare fishing they've
demonstrated they can try it and they
can tell you about it quickly that is
gold that is a new source of
intelligence that we didn't have before
inside of your own network and the story
repeats itself over and over again if
you look at customers that have reporter
install their ratings user reports far
outpaces the people that are falling for
that so is officially awareness the
problem I have a hard time believing
that it is especially in the modern era
we're hearing about hospitals falling
victim to phishing attacks Home Depot
sorry it's just in the news constantly
but I live in a bubble i living reef
fishing so there's a possibility that
awareness isn't a problem so I said no
we're just gonna do a study we're gonna
commissioned a study and we're going to
targeted at people that work in email
days office workers who are not inside
the idea organization and are not in the
security department and we're going to
ask them one question are you where
fishing and depending on how they
respond we're gonna ask followup
questions to that so you know the study
goes on fishing is a term described to
describe this up to email designed to
infect your computer store your
passwords were you aware that poor
reading mister 15% 6.0% they said they
were not aware of that so you know we do
have some work to do
seventy-six percent said that they were
aware of repetition is at least 30
people are being honest I mean it's an
anonymous survey hopefully people were
able to admit when they don't do or
don't but this is just a small survey we
are going to a much larger warned it was
interesting to me is what I assumed to
be doing this was the vast majority of
office workers are aware of fishing
how could they not mean you're getting
so many communications about it not only
at work but it home from every credit
card vendor and bank that you work with
getting warnings about fishing right I
know we got started a little bit later
running up 11 ch there will be no time
for questions at the end of this
presentation but I will be at our booth
you want to talk to you later so we ask
followup questions and the results were
a little bit mixed phishing emails
contain attachments most believe that's
true they can take you to links to
websites again most believe that's true
phishing emails asking for information
on our website most believe that's true
this one was a bit of you know do we
have a real human on the end of this
phishing emails come from people my
company thirty percent of them said
that's true that's a bit of a
head-scratcher unless they actually
doing fishing simulations at work that
one was interesting to me we also got
some statistics on whether or not
employees are told how to report vision
mostar but the vast majority of
organizations are telling their
employers for 290 department or order to
the spam alias at the organization and
which which usually doesn't you human
eyes are so the key findings were
seventy percent of people were aware of
fishing and most employees have
instructions on how to report suspicious
e-mail this doesn't really add up with
the other statistic that we hear over
time which is nine percent of breaches
start with fishing so people are more
Jordi Roura where fishing what ninety
percent of beaches are starting with
fishing maybe awareness isn't the
problem this is where I get a lot of
size from my colleagues cause I'm
actually suggesting something to them
that is very hard to do which is change
human behavior is one of the most
difficult things to do in so when I
suggest that they should have put any
effort into it
it's like I don't even want to hear that
I don't even want to hear that and it is
difficult to change human behavior I
know I have a history of cardiovascular
disease my family yet I still want to
take us last night even though I
shouldn't have changing human behavior
is the rising data breach report came
out and there was some discussion about
it on read it so I got on reddit night I
joined in and because the rise of data
breach report basically said yeah
fishing the problem is gonna likely
remain the top problem and there were
some information security engineers
beatings like chimed in like a duck like
just a puppy just completely out of my
element my city if you think
conditioning humans to avoid fishin
shouldn't part of every organizations
hygiene overall braised beer and toast
year and this was what troops response
to me was I absolutely do not agree you
should be designing systems and networks
that cannot be compromised via phishing
attacks trying to train a bunch of
useless meet tubes to become to become
competent so I unfortunately I heard
this sentiment from a lot of information
security engineers and they desperately
want to engineer the fishing problem
away and a lot of them are just
frustrated angry that we're still have
fishing is a problem in 2006 and within
that you have to understand about
security engineers as they want to
engineer and they don't really care
about the human input into any system
they believe that this is an
intellectual challenge that they can
create something that can't be defeated
order seeing new official tactic in the
linear very specific solution to defend
against that really the fact that humans
interact with data system was the
complete inconvenience to their personal
security engineering model and topia
that they'd like to build put the genome
fortunate reality is data systems are
for us to use and it's not just an
intellectual exercise this evening
continued near Kirkuk system to keep bad
guys out there now I'm sorry look at
history
history shows that most the time when we
try to engineer a perfect system and we
ignore the human human is clever and
then figure out a way around the first
slot machines were defeated with a coin
and a strength
all right we're gonna fix that we're
gonna put optical sensors in the slot
machines and we're gonna start the way
these coins and this will be a
bulletproof system in a way that slot
machines actually payout is this
coins are going through a hopper and
depending on the amount of coins are
passed through knows what the panties
minutes tops out sounds like a pretty
foolproof system while this guy made a
device called might wander among keep
that was basically a LED on the
endeavour true but he would go up
through the coin dispenser hopper and it
would blind the optical sensor making it
say that it wasn't done risk the payout
to work this didn't happen then attend a
result of dumping all of the money out
of the system and if you look at
information security we are a road
littered with examples in our own domain
and its but it's not just our own domain
it's it's everywhere you look at email
has evolved it used to be able to say
and executables as attachments
well we figured out that was a bad idea
so what attackers do they sent screen
share files are files guess what thats
XQ by your computer
oh ok we're gonna walk that would
attackers do or innocence zip files
know what we're gonna blog zip files
what actors do next
they included password for the zip file
and they put the password in the body of
the email in order to to get past those
types of filters oh no what are we gonna
do about that when attackers started
sending cab files which is also an
archive system Windows know so there's
always this cat-and-mouse evolution I
wish that we can engineer the perfect
system but I accept the fact that we
can't show that guy on reddit he clearly
designed miss you didn't see any
problems with his his gate here in the
middle of the road from our sandboxes
the same thing
if you work at the evolution of the tax
and malware this work pretty good idea
is an attachment would analyze and it
reached out to something bad or did
something nefarious on the computer
reboots stopping however the attackers
figured out roll with your mouse for the
user to go to a website that the system
date how many cores are on that system
is a core i7 work only one core
processor to devote devoted to it maybe
it's a sandbox so there has been
constant evolution of sandbox evasion
techniques for people that would love to
solve the haitian problem with complete
automated analysis and I just accept the
fact from my information security
careers that the attacker were always
involves
around this so when I hear vendors
telling me that they stop fishing my
reaction is sure you do yesterday sesh
but what we gonna do about tomorrow /
here's one that really angered them to
business email compromise and basically
it's an email
impersonating executive management to a
finance lease in handy you to wire money
to this account please go do that and
increasing security where is the URL to
analyze where's the attachment there
isn't one but there's no domains that
could have been a whitelisted no
application whitelisting no sandbox and
would have helped here and this is
caused billions of dollars in losses in
fact one company Ubiquiti Networks wired
out forty million dollars because of
this I'm so the security sandbox isn't
going to stop this or how about this one
this one is very fresh
this one's hitting lots of a chart
apartments right now just an email to
PHR department saying hey I need your W
two's for compliance rooms and suites
Melbourne Sydney and what RHR
departments all across the United States
doing right now
copy and paste thing plz W two's and
sending them to the attacker again
there's this is very low tack and
there's really nothing that information
security engineering to stop this this
is playing multiple companies right now
I get a I get a lobster pritchard rates
are predictable response from the bottom
my colleagues lets the human it's the
dummy to there's nothing we could do to
fix that
so what do simulations do people say you
know sooner awareness but better this is
not a picture of our Bernie Sanders
this case and I credit the system for
Akamai kind of turning me on this he did
a lot of work in behavioral analysis
mostly to help marketing campaigns and
he was trying to figure out how humans
make decisions and what he did after
going through countless studies is he
realize you know what I'm going to
characterize the brain and how we make
decisions into two distinct ways system
one is defined as our intuitive brain
process and it operates automatically
and it's designed to help you avoid
decision to teach because every time you
use a congress function and have to do
in our asses it wears you out and so
your brain tries to protect you from
that it tries to help you identify
patterns and once it does identify a
pattern it tries to help you get through
that is quickly and painlessly as
possible the other part of our brain
that we used for a deliberate thinking
process he characterizes as system to me
and he said anytime that something
requires after a cognitive effort to
bring switching to another murder
process in order to deal with the
challenging task to get multiple
examples in his book
intuitive brain quick quick pattern
matching and then our system to
deliberate so how many emails do we
receive and have to deal with the day
radically did this study may do it every
year and unfortunately the amount of
emails that we have to cope with this
going up but on average we receive 171
rejecting emails a day we have to send
about 41 emails a day you must mentally
discard 14 emails Jonker is not
assuming that we have a lunch break in a
couple meetings that we have to attend
we performed 33 email related tasks per
hour that's a lot i mean how many of you
are supposed to be in a meeting painful
tension dial in but you're really
looking at email trying to make sure you
don't have much to deal with it at the
end of that meeting so we are distracted
we do have to do a lot of related tasks
during the day so I want you guys to
consider the following we're gonna do
some exercises in intuitive thinking and
then deliberate thinking the system one
vs system to so here we go out I can
deal with this paper supply as soon as
that member pumped up we had to make the
switch from system 12 system to a more
deliberate thinking process we're gonna
do it again
write your brain detector that pattern
knew what to do it went into full system
wondering that jolted out of system and
what we're gonna do is we're gonna
jolted into system to pop up on the
right side the grain to say wait a
minute this is not a pattern I can deal
with I need to use a different mode of
thinking in order to cope with this and
so that transition was the transition
that we needed to make to get into
system to process so our system ones and
twos are always active and this is how
we're trying to get through 33 email
related tasks per hour and we have to be
prepared to make the finals indicators
that jolt us out of system warning
system and that's really what
simulations do they expose people to
these concepts and these emotions and
these events that attackers are using to
get your employees to click on things
and to give them practice in making that
switch system one system to so this
image right here it should not trigger
system to nothing really out of the
ordinary met here there's nothing
dangerous this one should trigger system
to this guy is running with scissors
that is dangerous we should use a
different mode of thinking when
evaluating this picture is this picture
saying with emails that were interfacing
in her inbox so system 12 system to
success I was talking about that
business email copper mines and there
was something this went to our VP of
Finance impersonating our CEO is there a
couple things about this one row it
never is encouraging finance to send
money especially before bill is there a
number to the attacker would not have
known is our our CEO just hate site I
don't he's crazy he was an injury and
this was my from my iPhone so our VP of
Finance he has a Samsung phone to use
like something's not right
it was that thing that was not read
those two pieces of information that
change this murder thinking from system
to system to that report so what you're
saying is simulations create experiences
using tactics similar to real phishing
email to Joel repetitively easy
intuitive cognitive functions into a
deliberate thinking process that
requires after this is why they don't
allow me to do our marketing campaigns
because this is what I would put in the
banner in our booth but apparently that
just doesn't roll off the tongue so when
I tell you a quick story we're gonna and
let guys let's watch system warning
system to switch over it doesn't always
work that's why I think it's crazy to
the DHS actually suggested that they
fire people are falling frustration
simulation specially on smeeting on the
mountain of evidence that I have so I
was at the Derby Conn Louisville
Kentucky this past fall they're staying
in a modern hotel it was Embassy Suites
just built and it was very modern and
contemporary and i was just need to get
to the airport that morning I was
running a little bit behind and I was
run down the hallway and I decided that
I really should go to bathroom for a
head over and go through security so I'm
sitting there and I'm like wow very
clean bathrooms bathroom that's good for
them so I'm washing my hands and I am
rising know your nose in this bathroom
mats I guess that's just one of those
modern bathrooms and they're doing away
with urinals new design element and then
I started looking around that bathroom
and I saw this contraption on the wall
is bad and it was at that point when I
realized that I had made a critical
mistake that my system one was in effect
that warning and it didn't know
deliberate or cognitive higher cognitive
functions and then I was definitely in
the women's bathroom and I needed to
figure out a way to get out of there
quickly so yeah we we can't expect that
system run the system to transition to
happen
flawlessly every time but we definitely
need exercise the security curmudgeon
will say looking to get some people fail
summertime and I'm like it will work it
the reporting metric the vast majority
of your people are accurately
identifying and reporting phishing
emails and now you can do something
about that so that's it
if you guys want to talk about this more
lbs please go get some lunch good news
you go tell everyone out there that
fishing awareness assault as I promise
you your employees are where fishing I
can't promise you that they've been
conditioned to avoid it