good afternoon my name is Jeffrey sweet
I work at American Electric Power and
I'm gonna talk today about third-party
risk governance some of you may have
been a presentation I did a couple of
years ago I will tell you this is not
the same presentation it has been
matured greatly over the past couple of
years and I hope to help many people who
are struggling with dealing with
third-party vendors for party
relationships and help you find a way to
make your environment more secure by
having it secure relationship with your
third-party relationships your third
party vendors so let me see it at hand
how many of you think that commercial
off-the-shelf software provides a risk
to your company and how many of you
assess that commercial off-the-shelf
software by D compiling it in tearing
into the code and looking at it you know
kind of illegal so how do you deal with
that and about the commercially produced
hardware products you buy servers you
buy appliances you buy all kinds of
equipment but how many of you actually
assess those and look at them deeply and
look at the software that's running on
those to make sure they're not bringing
rescue organization not easy course what
about the security culture the company
you're dealing with you know what they
do how they do it to make sure that
they're providing a secure product you
know anything about them
typically we signed a contract with
somebody we bring our product and we
install it we go to work that's as far
as we go there's a great deal of
security risk out there that we're not
even looking at and then well what about
the fourth party relationships was a
fourth party relationship you've got a
third party vendor that has a third
party vendor that has a third party
vendor that has a third party vendor
how deeply are you looking at those and
making sure that those are bringing
riskier company where they located what
are they doing what kind of security
practices do they have in place so the
first
thing when when we're when we're doing
an assessment of a company we want to
look at the culture of security within
that organization what I mean by that
securities not a point in time point and
click get it done
type thing it's something that has to be
in bread into the organization that has
to be a part of their day-to-day lives
because if it's not there not been a
practicing consistently and they're not
going to provide the type of product
that you need you gotta look at the
culture security and I just put a couple
of definitions up here cultures of
quality in a person or society that
arises for a concern for what is
regarded as excellent in the arts
literature and so on and so forth so
it's not just it's not just to sing or
act as a way of life and culture
security drives the practices of our
organization it's deeper than antivirus
and I D S IPS we all talk about those
tools are what time we talked about the
tools not being good enough anymore
right for what about the organizations
that you're doing business where are
they doing the right things today have
something more than just tools products
service
every product or service that you bring
into your company introduces risk to
your company to some degree some of the
more than others
network interfaces do you know what
ports and services they're running what
network interfaces they have how they
how they communicate outside your
environment using secure coding
practices when the developing the code
that runs all the products you're
putting in your environment
vendor systems themselves when they come
in and plug into your environment to
help you install it had those been
secured property they have hips they
have any virus they have the right
products in place and even the personnel
sometimes we don't even have let them
plugin we just have people come in and
they work on our systems but they're
using our systems are they
rocking the desktop when they walk away
are they trying to access data that they
shouldn't be accessing in your
environment using your systems so what
are their practices what is the
knowledge they have and what the risk is
in your organization that they might
introduced by interacting with your
systems and then again for 30
participation in any contract that you
have with a vendor will talk a lot more
deeply about that dream once those 4:30
relationships where are they how many of
you have a policy that you don't allow
your data to leave the continental
United States for you control that data
very significantly when it does leave
the continental United States so you
might have that relationship with third
party and tell them that what are they
doing their cloud hosting service they
may be transported your date outside the
continental United States for backup
purposes have you assessed at if you
look at that you know what they're doing
that or not
that fourth party have the same culture
security that the third party has that
you're trying to assess and then do the
third party providers have a contractor
and understanding with their providers
that arise what you're trying to
accomplish and security contract
language or put in place in your in your
environment or in your relationships so
every like I said every relationship you
have with someone outside your
organization brings risk so how do you
go about trying to evaluate their risk
and determine and tried to reduce the
risk your organization or at least let
somebody know that the risk exists and
make let them make the decision whether
they want to accept it or not so you
gotta you gotta done a fire framework
methodology and we were just in a
session just a few moments ago with with
Helen pattern in here and one of the key
themes that kept coming up is there's
nothing common everybody does something
do everything differently
there's no standard and there's right
now that's right there is no standard
today that everybody subscribes to do
this there are some standards out there
that you can subscribe to
but unfortunately as I as I've gone
through and top two different companies
even those standards are being used
people are writing their own
questionnaires and doing their own thing
and they're not really looking at the
standards that are out there and I'll
talk about a couple things that we've
looked at some of the things that we're
doing as I go through the presentation
today
you have to determine whether it's even
worse the time to do the assessment what
is the relationship that they're
providing you and do you even need to
know or even need to worry about how
much risk of breaking word electric
utility if I guess somebody mowing the
grass outside of my substation how much
risk they gonna bring to me if they're
going to grass outside your building
they're not coming inside they're not
touching your I T environment how much
risk exposing you to very little you
probably don't need to assess them but I
got somebody comes into my substation
and started doing work inside now good
risk rises just like if you have
somebody walk into your building a new
business inside your facilities your
risk writers you have to determine
whether that risk level is sufficient
actually even have to do an assessment
then you have to write that risk and
determine what an acceptable level of
risk for your organization is and that
can also tell you the frequency and the
depth at which you're going to assess
these vendors you might say if it's a
low-risk offender all we're gonna do is
we're trying to get a contract
supplement in place we're not gonna do
anything further than that but if there
are critical vendor we're gonna go in
and we're gonna do a full in-depth
assessment we're gonna do on-site
evaluations on its whatever you want to
call them we're gonna make them sign a
contract supplement working to restrict
how they access to our environment what
they do stuff of that nature he had to
determine how deep how frequently you
want to do these things and then you
wanna put contract agreements in place
and there was a comment by a guess as a
provider vendor in here or in the
previous session so well we've had
contracts where they tried to make us
subscribe to their security policies
that's not the kind of contract
supplement you want to talk about that
little bit more as well so there's a lot
of different frameworks course you got
NIST SP 18 800 161 which supply chain
management designed for the federal
government it will not fit everybody's
knees but you can adapt it is a national
strategy for global supply chain scary
there's the Cloud Security Alliance
their shared assessments standard
information gathering and agreed upon
procedures there's a bunch of different
ones that you can use you can use a
combination of those that's all you have
asked loud relationships may be the
Cloud Security Alliance is all you need
but if you're doing hardware and
software you might want to look at the
shared assessments for the next eight
hundred 161 so talk about the German a
questionnaire termination question
you're not all relationships were
intense scrutiny you must determine
which doing what's known as short
questionnaire typically five to 10
questions is all you need to determine
the level of scrutiny so I guess that
high-level risk or were you might have
something like groundskeepers cleaning
teams different things you have to look
at him differently and figure out what
the risk level is some of the questions
that we use for that I used to determine
this doesn't vendor store process
transmitter access systems for data says
offender have logical or physical access
to your facilities
canada entered directly or indirectly
impact your business availability let me
stop on that when resetting how many of
you have a cleaning team that goes in
your data center cleans your datacenter
force and how many of you haven't hit
that little red button right outside the
doors overhead now thinking that was the
door recent was actually the emergency
power shut off probably most your data
centers now been adapted because that's
happened way too many times those little
red buttons but it used to be that the
cleaning crew would hit that little red
button under way up endorsing in there
are releasing the security lock on the
door and it was actually the emergency
power shut off the data center but even
worse maybe they come in here and I got
a bucket full of water and tomorrow they
splashed water on short-circuit
something in the dataset is that a risk
to your organization maybe you need to
assess them and maybe you need to put
special restrictions on how and what
they do with in your facility does the
engagement create modify or purchase
software hardware probably about 80% of
your relationships do
and then the last criteria that we look
at is are any of the above criteria met
before during or after before during or
after implementation of the products or
services don't look at just what they're
gonna do before don't just look what
they're going to do while they're
implementing it but look at this
relationship going to continue on after
work and does that increase your risk
level because it does go beyond the
scope the original implementation
because the longer the relationship the
higher the risk low then we have the
risk
here and I'm not gonna read all these
slides to you because there's there's 25
different questions that we go through
for the risk questionnaire but some of
the key things that you want to look at
when you go through a risk questionnaire
and you cannot have these slides 30
gonna be publicly posted so you can have
a slight but some of the things that you
want to look into your a trick question
here is what is the sensitivity of the
information that they're gonna have
access to and don't just look at what's
on that specific system that they're
working on but look at where that system
might allow them to reach within your
organization within your in with you in
your data center that they could
potentially access from that system how
frequently are they going to do the
service for you said once a year as it
once every five years as daily is it
weekly is at Markley are gonna be
sharing data with anybody I'm gonna be
taking data off your site into a cloud
service like AWS our Google or or or one
of the other cloud providers or any data
center might not even be a cloud
provider they might be just posting your
data for you
does the engagement include offshore
services some companies it doesn't
matter what your data does offshore but
how many have you ever heard of the
Export Administration regulation to
federal regulation that says that there
are certain data that cannot be
transported to certain countries outside
the united states and its pretty broad
and probably many companies are
violating it on a day-to-day basis
because most companies are not even
aware of these deregulation exists I
don't see any chance but how many of you
use a cryptographic communications
device secure communications SSH or ask
your phone and send those outside the
continental United States you realize
that that is restricted under the Export
Administration regulation
and that wow you can transport outside
the united states that has to be
licensed licensed by the federal
government
there's actually a theater process you
have to go through to export that
outside the country how many of you
travel outside the continental United
States and take an encrypted laptop with
you in some countries that's illegal and
can cause your laptop to be ceased and
Lee the process to get it back in some
countries it's not worth the effort so
many times it just ends up being
abandoned in that country and god knows
what they're doing to it after they've
got all of that because we know that
there is no encryption that is
unbreakable none it takes time but it's
all breakable
inbound outbound connectivity remote
access does the vendor have unrestricted
remote access to your environment where
somebody watching what they do or is
there a restriction to what they can get
to buy by specific IP address or port
and that's the only place they can go so
the things you gotta think of is your
risk ranking how many fourth party
vendors are going to be involved is it
just one is that multiple disaster
recovery we probably most of us have a
disaster recovery program within our
organizations but how many of us look at
the disaster recovery programs of our
third-party providers to ensure that
they are going to meet our needs when
when they go now especially in a closer
relationship did they do it
analysis see it as street vendors are
somebody's gonna do business with
repeatedly if it is then maybe you do a
high-level a deep dive assessment on
them making sure that they have all the
evaluation completed and then you only
do that assessment one time every three
or four years as opposed to repeating it
on an annual basis where you have just a
short-term or maybe a two-year through
three year relationship and you want to
look at it repeatedly and then what's
the how long does utilization what
what's the time period you're actually
we use this third party to provide the
services that you're looking to receive
because again the longer the
relationship more risk it introduces
environment the potential risk she got
three
thank you determine whether the
assessments needed the level of scrutiny
what you need to do an honest and the
frequency interview I mention that
critical if you have a critical risk
thank you might want to consider doing
an annual assessment and an on-site
assessment of that meander was mentioned
earlier in the previous presentation I
keep referencing back to that because
she said wait so nicely into what i was
gonna presented a but she talked about
the sSAE 16 and a sock Tues don't trust
a sock to explicitly to determine
whether a company has enough security
first of all it's a point in time
second of all is only a representative
set of systems and three half the time
the auditors that do those don't
understand cybersecurity to begin with
there are some there are some that are
very good but the vast majority of them
don't fully understand cybersecurity
especially in your environment because
this may be the very first time they
were touched your environment
late understand how you practice and so
they're going to collect evidence and oh
by the way every individual interprets
the evidence differently as well how
many of you had two artists by two
different orders come back with
different results will be almost every
one of you could raise your hand to say
that right how many of you have federal
requirements such as Singapore hip our
PCI and PCI quite a few retail people
are here had to PCI assessment come back
same environment same exact set of
systems but the interpretation was
different I wanted you met clients or
not
just depend on an essay 16 you know and
ISO certification ISO 27001
certification is great glad they got it
but that doesn't mean that they're
consistently practicing that way
throughout that time period between the
evaluation periods
making sure all kinds of evidence
they're doing it a point in time but
doesn't mean there continuously doing it
and even when you do your own it doesn't
necessarily mean they're gonna keep
practicing it every day but at least you
got a good sense was that they are not
because when you go in when you're
talking to the people ask questions find
out how easily they agree to certain
things go sometimes easily agreed to
something means that they're not doing
it they're just agreeing to get you out
the door and then you risk
was once you've done that you risk
ranking you going to the in-depth risk
assessments not talk about some of the
assessments that we use in a few moments
but use the framework you choose Create
a scoring model maintain maintain a
record of the results don't dispose of
the results as soon as you get done
during the assessment to maintain them
so that when you do the assessment the
next year you can compare them to the
previous year's assessment or the
previous two years whatever it is you're
doing better or worse
if they change their practices in
accordance with what you've asked them
to do or if they just kept doing the
same thing and not made any changes in
their environment because maybe they
just said well we're gonna do this one
time they're never gonna come back
doctors against when I gotta change
anything you come back into another
recession to find out that's exactly
what they did absolutely nothing to
reduce the risk your company and its
follow-up on the findings we have a
process where we document everything
that didn't meet our expectations and we
actually put that back to the business
that's making the engagement with a
vendor to follow up on those findings to
make sure that they're doing the things
that we've asked him to do where there
are gaps things like having
vulnerability assessments conducted of
error of their application code and the
reporting the assessment results back to
you might be something you put in your
your contract so they say well we can't
do that right now we'll do that next
quarter
follow up on that develop a remediation
plan if you need to always provide a
path for don't don't want something you
tell them you absolutely have to do this
without a Paris forward sometimes you
can be a little flexible work with your
business find out what the business is
willing to accept and then give up power
forward for the vendor especially for
the smaller vendors that have very small
shops don't have a lot of money to focus
on cybersecurity help them develop a
security program we spent a lot of time
talking to smaller vendors and helping
them develop their programs giving the
guides we don't tell them how to do it
we provide them guidance and what they
might want to consider in developing a
program that could be beneficial to you
and to their other customers in the long
run
the types
investments in some cases may be a
contract supplement is all you need
other cases you might want to do a light
assessment we use the standard
information gathering questionnaire for
the sig develop my shirt assessments
which actually came out of the financial
industry kalb it's something we heard
bits shared assessments as the ride from
bits and created a standardized
information gathering questionnaire now
what's next numbers gonna scare the crap
out of you guaranteed there's 2650
questions in the full assessment but it
is an adaptive assessment what happens
is that they answered yes to some
questions and expand and ask some
additional questions if they say no
collapse were even if they say yes it
might collapse the assessment as well
just depending on what the question is
typically a vendor does not have to
answer all 2650 questions on the floor
assessment the light assessments about a
hundred and twenty five questions it is
not adaptive 825 question but it gives
you a basic idea of the controls that
are a vendor says that they have in
place and that's what it is it's a
controlled assessment the only way to
validate what they're saying
they're doing what they're saying
they're doing is to do an on-site
assessment which is the deepest level
assessment because of course that
requires commitment here time and money
to go to the vendor site and evaluate
that they have a security policy
make them show it i didnt assessment a
number of years ago I walked into a
company and I asked him to see their
acceptable use policy and their
information security policy
you guys what I don't have it right here
he says I'll send it to you the next
couple days I said that's fine I'm gonna
be about a week in this all put together
anyway and the next day I get an
information security policy and
acceptable use policy and I mean the
investigator that I am I'd looked at the
properties of the documents and both are
created the day prior to be receiving
them so I took an extract out of the
document I popped it into a plagiarism
website and I'll be darned it was the
exact copy the policy was an exact copy
of a major university on the east coast
in fact in some places they did even
change the name of the organization in
the policy before they sent it to me in
the Acceptable Use Policy was a direct
copy from Wikipedia work
getting someone else US policy to help
guide you in creating a policy is great
copying someone else's policy and
putting it as your own just doesn't work
because that university is not same as
the struggling company it's just not the
same so when you do an on-site
assessment to validate the information
given you the evidence representing make
sure that they didn't just copy and
paste something from that from the
internet so typically we use the signal
light by what we do is when we send out
an RFP to a vendor would typically send
the signal a questionnaire out to get a
general assessment of their security
controls for more asking for vendors to
submit bids back for product and then
once we get that we evaluate that we
evaluate the risk of the product and
everything that we determine whether we
need to do a further assessment and we
also always and every art piece on a
copy of our security contracts are
security contracts supplement is 18
pages of negotiable document it does not
state that you will use our policy does
not state that you will use this
particular IPS for this particular ideas
for this particular firewall against
guides and says you must have a policy
you must evaluate your products and
assessment for vulnerability you must
use secure coding practices such as a
wasp where science and sore or whatever
the case might be
we give recommendations we give guidance
but we don't prescribe exactly what they
do in in the vast majority of the
document there are some restrictions
that we put very prescriptive language
in such as our information cannot leave
the continental United States for you
must have a strong password policy that
includes a minimum of this many
characters to level of complexity for
your remote administrative access you
must have a multi-factor authentication
methodology but even that we don't
prescribe what multi-factor
authentication methodology we just say
you must have a multi-factor
authentication and we used for on-site
assessments we use what's called the
standard mission gathering for shared
assessments agreed-upon procedures it's
actually a checklist of items that you
should look for when you do an on-site
assessment it's very very good program
yes it does cost some money it's not
expensive also say that it's probably
gonna be less than $10,000
to get the questionnaires and the
agreed-upon procedures and they come out
annually they update them we derive our
security contracts supplements from the
agreed-upon procedures checklist and we
just put language in there and according
to what's an agreed-upon procedures and
then there are some areas for example
the right to audit but we do put a right
to audit clause in our security so we do
have some special because we're a power
utility we have no except requirements
the sense that we have to have a certain
level of background investigation of
people have access to certain assets
within our environment so we put that I
would you never specifically above and
beyond what side of the agreed-upon
procedures so it's a depth of you can
change it to your environment to your
particular needs there is no framework
anywhere on the face of this earth
that's going to be 100% good for your
environment you're going to have to make
adaptations you may have to take
multiple frameworks and Adam together to
make them work for you every industry is
different every industry is different I
couldn't use my supplement for somebody
in the education industry because it
wouldn't be the same requirements but we
could adapt and use it to make it
modifies the one thing also with the
contracts supplement use we always
negotiate the document we give them the
vendor the opportunity to market up and
make recommendations because while we
might have certain language in there
that might give some guidance in a
certain area they may have better
practices the what we're recommending
and we will allow them to be accountable
for maintaining our practices
so the areas that we have in this the
single light a cig fall and also the
same categories for our supplement our
risk management security policy
organizational security asset management
human resource security physical
environmental security communications
operations management access control
information systems acquisition
development and that's very important
how they maintain their systems within
their environment
do they have an asset inventory today
maintain access controls do they
maintain antivirus host Intrusion
Prevention all that with their own
systems within their environment I don't
know how many times I gotta understand
what you're telling me how to run my
environment yes I am because everything
you do in your environment impacts my
environment but we're just selling your
software yes you are and your software
is going to be installed in my
environment and everyone ability every
risk that is part of that application is
at risk to me
incident Vantage communications
management what if they have a breaching
their environment how soon do you want
to know about it depends on what to
providing this is
time to disaster recovery compliance
mobile how they manage former
environment privacy software security
cloud security and then you can always
add Section there's a section and
actually in the same question here for
additional questions that you put in for
your cell
that might be something that wasn't
covered in any other sections that you
want to know about the vendor could be
financial information could be any
number of things that you might want to
know about the vendor and might be for a
specific engagement but rational human
being in every contract to some degree
there should be some security mine which
every contract you sign even if it's a
non-disclosure agreement NDA privacy
agreement for daily use agreement where
data destruction agreement there should
be some contract language that's
applicable to the engagement that you
have in nearly every contract again if
somebody's morning grass outside your
facility obviously you're not going to
necessarily need a contract offers deep
security contract supplements should be
negotiable don't try to 100% dictate to
a vendor led to do their business
because you're never gonna be successful
ever
hard to be soft and give them guidance
and guidelines and suggestions and make
them accountable for things let alone
try to prescribing be very explicit how
they should do their business should be
general enough to allow flexibility
specific enough to ensure security and
then of course always ensure
accountability and the way we do that he
is that we use shall statements and not
should statements should
allows them away out some areas you may
need to use a short statement but
generally if you want to be accountable
for it it's either shower or will that's
the only way you can make
accountable when I'm ready
yet but the other thing that that we
have as we have developed our program we
put a contract supplement and we use it
as a supplement to the contract we also
wrote it a point in time where it could
be a stand-alone document so that
require signatures from both parties
what we're doing today is because we're
adding it as a supplement to the master
agreements within our organization
there's an app rural section and it's
for cybersecurity to prove it and
basically what happens as it comes to my
desk after my people have looked at it
yet we're good with this and I'll sign
it and send it back up to procurement to
be added to the general contract you can
change that however you feel necessary
if you want to make it a stand-alone
document you want to add it into your
master services agreement we're actually
getting ready to take portions of our
security document because it applies in
every circumstance and put it in the
general services agreements and we'll
take it out of the security supplements
it'll be in every contract signed by
every person that provide services to us
one of the cab if you start a program
like this do not take on the world and
once we started this program we started
looking at our relationships and
realized that we have total count over
16,000 benders and 64,000 contracts
you will be amazed when you start
talking your procurement divisions and
how many contracts and vendors you have
in your environment especially for a
large corporation so
so what we have done initially as we
look at the new contracts and the
renewal that were in the process of
performing as well as starting to risk
rank all the rest of the contracts to
determine what our risk level is and it
will go back to the Chronicles and start
working our way down and going back on
the others don't try to boil the ocean
was it won't work was not flushing bring
the Sun to the earth you're never gonna
worry ocean and then there's the
consequences of that site so I won't
open it up for questions I think I've
got about 10 minutes or ten minutes so
many questions yes sir so that
determination questionnaire is done by
our business and the risk rankings
dunbar business and that we do the
actual the risk assessment so the
business actually helps us with the
determination questionnaire in the risk
rank so good question what we do is we
always let the business know that they
can contact our team we have a team to
specifically set up for third-party risk
governance then contact any member of
the team to ask any questions we had
additionally we've also trained our
procurement division and I did fail to
mention that we have a very tight
relationship with our division and we
train them and let them help help them
understand what those questions mean and
how they should be answered and so they
can help give guidance as well so it
doesn't for 100% back on us every time
but many times through after one or two
times doing it they understand that
they're able to answer without our
yessir
they have 100% on that is evidence that
their client we still do testing when we
can and ask them for evidence of testing
as well so while they may have a
certificate of compliance we want to see
the evidence of the testing performed as
well as see what the because no one not
necessarily looking to see that the test
was valid but also looking to see what
they tested and make sure they covered
all the areas that we would consider
security risk to us especially in for
example and operational technology very
new space a lot of assessment hasn't
been done on operational technology
because it wasn't networks in the past
it was always see realized and
internalized it really didn't
communicate across the network so the
risk is very low for now that stuff is
starting to be connected to the network
connected to the internet so we gotta do
a deeper assessment of those
technologies to make sure they're not in
adding additional rescue us know because
we won't sign a contract with them until
they give us the information for the
business chooses to accept the risk and
that's one thing that we make sure that
if we identify for example we had
vendors that have absolutely said we
will not sign your contract supplement
period there's no way we take that back
to the business we write it up as a risk
we write up is a critical risk
and they evaluate whether they were
willing to accept that risk we have had
businesses that have severed
relationships with vendors big vendors
because they were not willing to
negotiate a contract with us so we have
it it's not up to us at that point it's
up to the business whether they're
willing to accept the risk with one
stipulation our chief operating officer
has told the managing director
cybersecurity that if he feels that the
risk is too great for the business to
accept it he has allowed to escalate
that up to the risk Executive Committee
on a risk executive committee to review
that risk and determine whether they are
willing to accept it or not we treat our
vendor information is confidential
information or competence what we call
competition especially which is our
highest classification weekly class file
that confidential and maintain it where
we need to if we don't need to maintain
it then we destroyed it with a tarp our
secure our information classification
guidelines
so as I stated we work very closely with
our procurement vendor and we actually
extract every relationship that
determine holds with every vendor and
put it into our centralized system so
that we know what relationships we have
and we can go through and evaluate those
internal what level of scrutiny we need
we do is if if the vendor will not
respond to our questionnaire will not
sign our documents than what we do is is
we we basically give them a cannot be
evaluated was not evaluated ranking
which is the same as our critical
ranking said that the business itself
down this vendor was unwilling to answer
any of your questions we feel a great
degree of risk are you willing to accept
it or not and that's where I where we've
had some significant size benders much
bigger than us that we've severed
relationships with were playing every
bit of their product out of our
environment and replacing also we have
some general data retention requirements
in the contract supplement but we also
allow the business to dictate what the
retention requirements are because as we
all know different data has different
retention requirements we allow the
business to drive that we just reference
that as a part of this agreement that
it's within the compliance requirements
of that particular data classification
works with the business in in the
specific requirements for that business
we just drive the cyber security
requirements and if there is a specific
requirement for the business that is not
in our settlement we can have that added
either the general contractor the
supplement as necessary will not run
into that too much because we tried to
cover just about anything that we could
possibly think up i mean obviously we're
not going to cover everything but we try
to make it
broad enough to cover just about
everything we need to thank you
your time that's all I have for today