object to get home put in my mind she
has done that treated to a friends but
he obviously wanted to have a discussion
about ten years ago
games like World of Warcraft right
shoulder they went massively online as
it is folly still sold your quiet then
you had to talk to subscribe to be able
to access the servers this was
especially interesting business model
that I hope will be good for the first
time I can play not just the right form
some sheen to it as 2,000 people
simultaneously right now for big deal
the smartphone right the first time ever
who were all that is much more powerful
than desktops as did not grow
you ask most people was the very first
thing she studies of the no was the
first thing you people downloading and
going on into mobile and most of the
ones that are always at the top of the
top grossing
paradoxically free to play free download
but by giving by small things and it's
our lives not on just getting the game
on somebody's farm but looking people at
a game that they keep playing over time
as they introduce new features and new
ways to my house and these games last
year right you saw on the Superbowl like
the Holy Grail so that's how big these
games and desperate to attract players
because unfortunately just like
absolutely everything is getting harder
and harder to differentiate them from
the competition so giant counties like
these guys get a whole host of others
who are just hoping that the next and so
broad so this model is so profitable for
the online just online so it's just a
tough no duty to research published
there and we'll review as I like how
much you know he's made just on your
father your PlayStation Network codes
generator 63 billion dollars being 2013
and that is why take first hollywood
movies you know all these big movies 38
so you know just about twice as much a
lot of money is right but a lot smaller
and generated through 31 publisher parts
just online sales for their traditional
34 that last year so it's very probable
that it's easy for people it's fresh
unless you know from banking is that
fraudsters always follow the money they
don't care where it is there not being
rude or not wizards there just isn't
right and if you think about it this is
true you know about cancer versus banks
are there not regularly to report to the
FBI after by sea like banks do you know
a lot of times he's stealing things in
games not even private just in terms of
service
and so what that means is that a lot of
guys who are refined tools like stands
dealer for other industries like banking
just able to retire and how this is
happening
Indians in a big way and this is what a
lot of this is actually a screenshot
from customers credit is actually pretty
easy to virtualize that dropped out
random gaming Strike Global Select
Market so you'll get one of these will
sell it somebody party site for real
money trading system
traded over but now takeover is so rapid
this is why because people happy in
their house and for taking a special and
very strict about and it's just like a
slut and that's what are some of the
high-end very rare form of thousands but
there is more than a takeover going on
so there are scams like gold farming
where people will actually just gather
mundane virtual resources are you know
like charles Rangel right well yeah you
it's worth things trade for other
personal items in the game and so we've
got a lot of it is just like any other
virtual currency value 31 you know
hundreds of special customers just once
and we actually found it was worth
for some of these guys r straight so
that stored on your help with a lot of
people to purchase those items from the
store store sells them for a fraction of
the cost on a trademark why not losing
any money but I also notice that charge
they're gonna say no i didnt is the
publisher response clock back so what's
so when we first started the company
accelerator here in Columbus Aliant a
salary Columbus
one and we spend time building our own
time and we should I had the timing we
talking to some contacts in the industry
and so I talked about you know well what
are you doing now and what is not so
they were actually talking about their
incredibly opening the gate a lot of
really good information so they tried
all traditional stuff they tried to you
all those things and what's interesting
is a lot of solutions iraq to recognize
the original banking but they lost
because the banks stopped using them so
I am sells a chance and now actually
something worked for a while because
we're seeing and are fundamentally
thanks a lot of us so it but it still
works because there's not helping
matters in place and offline access
right because these are people that
buying things they don't want security
products a lot of folks at the tax so
they can get away with something that
never thought and other industries
this one somebody said this and try to
resolve the problem with using bank
tools to secure my games has turned into
that have two different types of games
have different problems as well so far
have a lot of other life late for work
at the Sheldon was playing games and it
takes a lot to build up a lot of
resources are reselling so that people
can actually loved account automatically
they just sell your with top-level a
loss for overtime for your time saving a
market stall generate been credibly just
gonna come right back
a new social casino games that you
cannot ship so surely played for final
more about those sheeting and collusion
so that's when players will together on
the plane together against the rules
going to try and win and that's a whole
different thing because in real money
and those guys huge issue not only
because they are trying to sell but
they're being used for money laundering
cybercrimes totally makes sense if you
think you're buying jewelry line casino
and then lose all your mind to another
player and I got a portrayal of that
money goes to get somebody to talk to
about what they're doing this said well
you must be so they don't have turned on
their teams they usually hurry turning
on and then they do for us 67 what's in
the past
create some rules this is and what's
right and this is actually making
company is is that exact same thing to
go about their own solutions but you may
ask our people and our customers we
should be able to do this problem though
is that expensive but we were some
reports for eleven years I you know that
they're probably expensive to own right
but over time especially when you got
people change and because a rule-based
system can be observed that does right
so what they were doing yesterday
suddenly stopped working so they know
they're on the subject to change their
behavior off until it starts working
another train delays on what the rule is
that stopping and so now they just it
over and over and over again
yeah I suggested changes to my rules
engine for the last month or two but it
was getting pushed the bottle there's
always other I T things that are more
important happening why these factors
are all over there constantly looking as
they always are not really sure how to
fix it and the most important thing is
really more than about the money because
the damage done to the game if they want
to play overtime games no longer fun for
you to stop her
satisfy something tell it to you later
and tell right that's true and expensive
for what a wired and you want to have a
bunch of china's coal for its just so
they are really worried about the
reputational damage to the reason why is
because even very large studios are
finding a lot of his underdog you know
reputation is all you got her employers
not remember that and you know this is a
focus point developers not for
publishers this article and he was a
studio remember your publisher and was
it your publisher doesn't help keep your
name security scanner do the right
things is going to hurt you know she is
your reputation and much much harder
especially in emerging market to get a
chance you got about her tuition with
the players
talked about in a specific case study
that we did for March over sure where we
actually got some interesting statistics
about what is actually costs was
actually going on so that we did we just
ended it was a social casino game I
can't seem to be able to understand why
if you plan on Facebook you're playing
games probably change how can we mark
that we actually study was a very large
name that was a social teams to play
poker in this was not a real money so
they could not cash out their chest but
really wonder selling it and see you
know I think you can in that case you
can buy $100 worth of virtual ship's
right over $200 million dollars chips
right so what they're selling the fans
here going all-in I don't know then that
in texas holdem poker table that's real
that you gave us on the line is great
when you lose the way that our customers
and chips through their story actually
is a great thing for that there are a
lot of fun had a thirteen and a half
million players and they were making
$100,000
now it's interesting is that they were
going through mobile Facebook this over
and get told that have multi-factor
authentication on vacation they also got
itself was in the App Store we were
relieved to be proved highly doubt that
the Nevada game we're not going to
happen so this was purely a straight up
you know commercial so there are no how
was it all on the fact that they had the
most expensive that transaction so they
think they had everything set right now
so we're very eccentric so it wasn't
like a lot of customers we have in our
lives turned on this is going to sound
so they decided that they had everything
just because they knew they had this
problem when you search for buy cheap
over chairs with your name on it
you actually see see their product page
7 everything else was some chips for a
fraction as so basically they responded
to this by having people manual he wanna
play
literally looking and playback of what
was going on
hoping something will trigger the
spiders they would know that playing
right around the world
cost them to this report
differences difficult part every day
they saw not only to decide to not go
away but their prices down a lot of
acquisition leading them to raise their
prices so they have to be 100 percent of
all our players for 90 days so we
stopped by rules be used pure when he
start fighting monitor everybody reading
was like normal good behavior and that
is our first pass bounced back after
2012 models that translate to when you
look at the sheer exhilaration so great
market they were losing about 40% of
$1.40 per number and you can tell you
know what it is like if you think about
trying to operate your profits or
revenue falling up a lot and was really
about this number is when I first
started talking to all publishers and I
asked them you know ok well let me know
for sure when I pressed the first time I
kept hearing the number really did enjoy
a large market got so I think these guys
really onto something I think it's the
kind of the problem know where you got
that right now there's tons of water
everybody's like getting into gaming
down on them like mad and so there's a
lot more water as everyone's happy but
it was actually that's going to change
and when that changes and change the
popularity so the whole lot smaller
players you know if you've no financial
gain investors and you took you to
nothing bucs
million bucks to market your language is
actually the ratio is expecting the
models that back her likeness a 24 to 36
months you can strip on my bad you know
good luck trying to get science and that
hurts everybody that's why I say that's
because it not only best games of all
teams are coming up behind them because
it's going to be hard especially for
smaller and mid-sized make them because
they won't have also made for you guys
to security professionals ever tasked
with protecting one of these types of
organizations with the get out because
that's what they are locked up there are
perfect for its ok there's no I know I
tried to talk to our keynote speaker
you know I every time that happens only
a tiny fraction so the guys you know
especially groups and companies
countries were visually this time so
what do they care so if you're a
security professional players
strong lots of studying what people who
is it passed by our defenses what are
they and what are they doing inside
today also measuring the right now
because just tells you on Friday that he
really that's true that might actually
be just like wow did not know that the
Jews are very careful skeptical look for
things that is strange and your study
authors were released early as possible
I recommend that you start measuring
things pakistan paid it right because we
see tons of guys filter tools in women
involved with a dose of pre-release
version became a lot of policies
marketing like it but it's really not
testing and so that I sign up and gave
us a table for tolls because on release
day that's what most people most excited
and they wanted to be part of something
and that's one out of 10 again that
already running just a soon
you know and and what they're doing now
analytics for your plans mostly from
corporate secretaries to try to figure
out how to monetize these games so a lot
of this stuff out
monetize Caldwell right out there all
right how long they go out and studying
the variable stars I can tell them what
happened just trying to find a house we
close our unusual differently from
suspects something that the industry is
is really bad because not all know if
you have to understand things on your
mind always tell you when something
hurts people yesterday I actually found
things that need to happen but they
never got a lot of $1.99 some support
tools used by workers are not support
developers
certain variables and so that they don't
want to get in the game which means that
if you put it cool and the client was
over your head on rival
glad you came in just eight games that
are healthy and making money are costly
changing the environment on purpose
all the time which means not under rules
harder and harder to anything that is
going to change for a challenge you know
obviously Election Commission then that
are unusual for the difference between
that and you know already making
something to a computer first tells the
day got the right people look at the
list of things hundreds and they don't
know which one this is much talk so much
everybody else informative to people
this is what will happen when the FBI
was doing better
said there was no question that has to
do with you know let's play this is just
plain wrong
just play us but you know I guarantee
you that make a living writing sessions
also questioned him on Twitter on and
off the water so thanks very much
everybody enjoy the rest of the show