or do we just use the mouse wait to see
what I see when I started my name is
Stephen Kyle presenting my presentation
I'll get started here I do wanna I guess
maybe apologized after I wrote this I
realize the title is somewhat misleading
because this is the problem not the
solution
goal is to present the solution so that
you guys have some control our
environment is very unique we're
currently on a project and I'll get to
that later but because of the
proliferation of vendor devices BYOD and
other things we felt like we needed to
get get things arranged in a little bit
and that's where we started this and
that's what we're gonna talk about here
is how to move forward with it so let's
go ahead that first of all give you the
introduction of Columbus Ohio area
currently live south of growth lucky if
anybody's from this area again
boarding reindeer have been doing the
game for a while
started way back when I'm old and gray I
get that and was blessed to work for IVF
and the rest of the credentials are up
there
the bottom line is the best because in
August I have another grandchild coming
so they'll be number five very happy for
that but get the kind of give you an
idea what's going on
this is the one thing Chuck Norris
cannot be because everything you know
Chuck Norris there's limitations believe
it or not he's not god but I felt like
this is one of these companies one of
these waves that weekend no offense to
Chuck Norris fans I realized that that
Rep
preparing for this I did look up some
Chuck Norris jokes just kind of wake up
I know it's in the morning time so I've
got my top three for now and more later
so the first thing Chuck Norris wise we
have to keep in mind
Chuck Norris's website has never had a
hit because nobody will ever touch
anything belonging to church right
second one
Chuck Norris's keyboard doesn't have a
control key because nothing control stop
Norris right we got that and the last
one is if you ever look at his keyboard
are only only has two keys 10 everything
else is optional
things up and get things move it
BYOD is here you guys have all seen the
numbers potential saving rides a lot of
numbers I was doing when I was
researching this wasn't about the $350
per person per year as far as
productivity gains and that type of
thing so that's why I say even Chuck
can't stop it
businesses like it because they save
money on some cases they are letting
things reimbursing and other cases an
art project
people are showing up with stuff on the
door so how do we deal with that how do
we make sure that we have the
appropriate controls in place and
frankly the users like to users love
this stuff because if they want us down
here they wanna Panasonic if they want
an off-brand somewhere if they can find
something that fits that might help
their productivity that should be
encouraged some people care I myself
carrying iPad 2 meetings and other
people too so we have a proliferation of
phones tablets and phablets all the
different flavors thinks so it is a good
thing but there's gotta be a way to rein
it in so that we have some control and
some consistency
by way of introduction also
so at the project that I'm currently
working with him and see some wonderful
co-workers here we knew we had a problem
we were seeing the inconsistencies we
were seeing people bring things in you
know sometimes it would be a very nice
design sometimes not so I started
studying this I just recently got my
master's degree in December and
information security so I made the
support of my project how do we make
life better for our project but also
used in that respect so very proud of
the graduation Western Governors
University has their graduation at
disney world in wintertime so I
apologize for the crane exit castle they
were like family and they were taking
down the Christmas lights on if you ever
been to Disney World and bottom left is
my favorite dessert they have those dole
whips outside the Tiki Room they also
have a shout later they have been to
places of the Polynesian hotel the
exercise so that was one of the things
we did down there was enjoy the
graduation but let's get back to the
topic at hand I recommend the college
while if anybody has questions about
Western Governors getting online degree
program for us back to the subject we r
project and again I'm working on a
project primarily deals with medical
data moment and so when it was designed
and set up to him at the management made
the decision they were going to use BYOD
for everything so we have a lot of
vendors come in we have a very small
component up maybe half a dozen
employees arrested as a horse and so we
have a variety of contractors we have a
scale of one to 10 we have some
corporate issues machines where they
have very good controls very good
documentation and also very good
patching schedules and things like that
we have some that are were at a lower
level organizationally supplied
sometimes ok folks admin access local
admin access type of pics like that in
some cases then we have a lot of people
just showing up with what they bought
the night before or worse yet picking
something up out of the basement and
bringing it to work because they find
out on Tuesday I got a job and they have
to show up on Wednesday and they're
supposed to bring her own stuff and so
again we have the whole range when I
would call very good all the way down to
very bad
and that's one was driving our car
headache myself and Bobby might
September 30 compadre at the track here
and Caroline found out that we were
seeing a variety of things we had the
whole scale we have stuff that showing
up there hasn't been patched and six
months or a date operating systems we
finally killed all the windows xp
finally got that under control but you
know we're making sure we're doing it
and I get the problem was the vendors
are being hired by functional people
that they there was no security vetting
so they would come with whatever they
were had so the goal was to take the
project was to find some level of
minimum security controls we don't have
anything so you gotta have a baseline to
start from you don't know how bad it is
until you identify the problem right
what's that saying the first thing to
knowing you have yet to identify the
problem we can start to study it so hard
out west to study it and then we
realized as a result of that we had this
long acronym that I came up with a good
pronunciation for it but the essence of
it is bring your own device and whatever
security controls you want that's what
that acronym is for because that's what
essentially what we had some very good
somewhere very bad and we all know from
the security world hit only takes a few
bad ones to ruin it for the rest of the
world so that's where we were starting
from somewhere this was very
operationally defined because we know we
have a problem and so how do you bottom
line is on the bottom how do you define
controls when you don't you have no
access to admin rights people are just
showing up on your door every day
first thing we went through and again
ready has questions feel free I'm happy
to take the middle some of the rest we
quickly identified and these are not new
risks everybody understands these are
fair on the environment so we have a
shared wifi wired network that we use so
we only need one more on who hasn't
patch to suddenly let something in and
then start proliferating one of the
unintended benefits is because we have
so many different organizations in so
many different owners is we don't have
one master admin password for all the
machines because they belong to
different organizations so in one
respect because we do have a radio
vendors
applying people we don't have that one
single point of contact they may take
out you know this group with this group
of patients take out everybody but
nonetheless a lot of new stuff coming
nowadays it only takes one click to run
it especially in the social engineering
field we do have something controls
likeliest multi-factor before we get
into the back and stuff so you're not
gonna just blatantly login on our end
user population whether they be the
folks doing the work or the people long
accustomed to request their benefits
they're coming in through a web browser
so we have controls on those parameters
my concern and what we drove this from
what we do about these insiders have a
lot of functional people especially
testers and I love testers they have a
hard job but many times that's all they
know is what's in the box they don't
know anything about it
for instance last week when the guys
walked up and was having trouble with
his wife I went click and turn the
switch on 70th wifi worked homogeneous I
love that but you know that's what
happens with some of the biggest thing I
started looking at what we have an
insider and he's bringing in a virus
that he's not patch we're gonna have a
potential for heading out on our
internal network if we don't know that
it now their risk of course is that
something stolen high times the users
have a business need to download stuff
from our project and documentation
functional design documents technical
design document the rest their courses
if they put on the laptop this walkout
laptops to walk out the door i mean how
many people had to deal with laptops
disappearing over organization and never
coming back a few hints so those are out
there
and because we don't want healthcare
data primarily some of the examples are
running into what i've seen
quickly and one group in indiana gets
fined three quarters of a million
dollars because they didn't have
encryption on their laptops to help out
the Alaska Department of Health and
Human Services got a 1.7 million dollar
fine started out just what those stolen
USB Drive and then they started coming
into the organization looking around
realizing they had very low policies no
controls no procedures and that's what
drove that fine then so get Alaska
Department of Health and Human Services
had to pay that price and as recently as
last month
Oregon State University their health and
science department and lost a laptop
containing information on nato ICU
patients so get through another
situation so encryption for us is very
important and so if nothing else from
the standpoint not only protecting the
data but if the device is lost or stolen
so that was one of the risk that we have
and I'm just going to hit a few the last
one is anybody's read their history
about Mary Mallon she was going to marry
that the thing and put in there she was
a cook
live from 1869 to 1938 she ended up
infecting 51 people and three of them
died she was cooking would work in
people's homes and in the process of
cooking she was asymptomatic she never
had a single symptom but she was a
carrier but typhoid and so she would go
and she would start working on a family
within a week or two people would get
sick so we had this hidden care and
that's my example I used for this
particular one if we have somebody on
the inside our internal network and we
played a minute they've been breached or
they have some kind of mower going on
they could be in that situation where
they're spreading at risk are spreading
the virus in attacking us I looked in
the latest data breach investigations
report the 2016 one just came out from
rights and also got hacked by the way
and they listed three scenarios of this
same trend the first one being the what
they called the flea flicker which was
just basically more we're breaking into
machines another one was what they
called the alleycat started out with a
phishing email and then people were able
to get in
backdoor access to that spread through
the organization and then the last one
was what they call the imperfect
stranger again a road connection to the
network they all resulted in most cases
from the last one especially was a BYOD
machine from a contractor was brought
into an organization plugged in and
started spreading so that's against some
of the sample rest I would say probably
everybody has seen these same risks at
one time or another I knew we were just
trying to figure out how to categorize
and quickly so that we could figure out
a way to put to understand the problem
in and deal with the problem so we went
ahead and put that together have had a
very good group to bed all this through
so we came up with and we recognize we
have to start with something we are
starting at zero and I'm trying we're
trying to work our way up the stack so
this is going from level 02 level one we
intend to go higher as we get more
mature but we gotta start somewhere so
we defined a list of minimum security
controls in order to enforce it we had
to have a policy so we've been working
with the management team to get that in
place and then defining the jurors so
we're gonna make sure that we get from a
starting point let's go with the most
common devices so we do
enduro Apple and Windows you folks with
your palm pilots can wait till later or
if you folks have an Atari or a
Commodore 64 the older people might
remember those guys can wait until later
to let's get the let's get the mass
market first and then we heard about
what's the best way to start to get
reduced the rest from those things I've
identified plus more so
baseline twice we have to figure out how
to do it because we're dealing with the
health care industry we started with
what the recommendations so there's an
anemone in this series that's just
really good I like it and it's a good
trade mark but we also use the same
critical mass and CSC to critical
control list because that to me it's a
more operational because we're dealing
in some cases with the feds I don't like
this my like what we're doing with this
much better because they're very much
operationally are in it I was real
disappointed in the last series that
came out that they took away the quick
wins but if you read through pretty
quickly which ones are too quick wins
and which ones are now
I think they took them out because
people are only doing that quick wins
and that going deeper but they're still
there you just have to help the last
thing that was important was we have
vendors and our organization so we had
to consult with their security teams we
didn't want to be slamming stuff in her
they wouldn't supporter couldn't support
for real big on relationships and trust
and working with our folks to make sure
that they are able to understand why
we're doing things before we up on that
so we did interviews to understand what
are your controls what can we push and
what can we get and actually worked out
better than we did that we did some work
against you gotta deal with tax data you
want to make sure you have that covered
the regulations and pub 1075 a good tip
of course is well-documented especially
the high tech stuff and then we already
had policies and many place so we went
to that's just a brief list of the point
being BYOD is a conglomeration of things
and so this when I played a little bit
here this one applying a little bit here
this when applied to a bit here and we
last saw all those who put them into one
place and give you a coherent thing that
somebody can read one documentary series
of documents and I have to go to I think
I counted example here
13 or 11 different policies where that
actually had some overlap in this arena
so that but part of the driver behind
this as far as the research and coming
up with the list again I mentioned
earlier we don't own this it's not a
good thing it's a starting point
Microsoft Word document called their
microsoft Device strategy framework
this was part of what I did with
research for my permit great so they
have a four-step series starting out at
level 10 which is basically bring
something in it who cares all the way up
to where you know corporate issue
corporate controlled corporate
administered
so what we after defining through and
looking for that we realized we were at
level one let's move to the next level
and we can take a pause and as we tune
it get people involved then we can start
working her way up higher we will never
get to the point where a shooting
laptops I don't feel like management
would support it and I don't think they
want to bear the cost of that but what
we can do is get a foothold establish an
insert winking at making it tighter so
that everybody's coming from the same
playbook and I think that's probably the
best way we could do it the other team
recognizes people want flexibility so
that's where the bottom line we are more
of a standards-based approach at this
point and I'll give you an example in a
minute so we have to find a list of 15
standards if you can demonstrate you
meet them have a purple shirt that's
great but I should hear my example here
is encryption and I just picked the for
devices that we were talking about
earlier Apple iPhones and iPads which we
of course after reading the press know
that maybe they're not as secure as we
thought using something called data
protection Android's use the typical and
write crypto unix script file for
poverty that Windows computers most of
them use about locker and some third
party and then Apple computers
themselves have file so the goal being
you can't we need encryption we there's
no two ways about it so if you're coming
to our project near walking in the door
can you demonstrate encryption and
doesn't meet our standards as far as
dealing that type of stop but odds are
it's going to be one of these four
layers of encryption same thing with
other tools and we'll talk about those
two depending on the type of device that
was involved and how it was actually
working any questions so far yes
were gonna get to that but I'll give it
two in a brief depending on the level so
we have individual contractors are
coming in her coming in straight off the
street
those guys know you're not getting into
a look have you come as part of our
onboarding process will take a look
people her recognized organizations that
demonstrate consistency in their
controls were going to allow them to
come in we figure at that point they've
got good responsible people and they can
demonstrate what the third their
sanitizing machines and stuff so it's a
hard date it has to be a hard date you
don't if you just kinda
validate don't trust quickly whereas
when I get out again
control that's not enforce is no control
people will understand that people say
yeah they'll do the check mark
compliance but they will never come back
and actually do it
good intentions are great but I also
understand the time pressure people are
under and how they are expected to
produce and to perform and its heart so
we did make it a hurry we made it a
discrete you when I get in until X so it
is fine so let's walk through the list
we're trying to make sure we knew what
it was and I can demonstrate some of
these little better case so first thing
is we gotta have your basics your mobile
games here
IMEI if you're playing an end to the
wifi to the other and I can supply
anybody with a list of these guys want
this case back to CSE number one and I
think 15
so you know what is that inventory
devices on the network that's just the
basics you'd be surprised that number
two would be necessary to actually tell
people but it does so you know again I
talked about XP we weren't finding as
much XP on the desktop as we were five
people finding people using it for a
virtual machine type situation where
they would fire because it's included in
many cases with free copy of XP know
that's an unsupported operates so we
have a look at the machines we also look
at they're trying to do something in the
back door catches patches are again he
and again we're doing a one-time look we
do reserve the right to come back later
to spot checks but 30 days to us seem
reasonable we don't want to push it too
fast and how many people have an order
iPad and just went through the debacle
Apple they issued the latest operating
system and it kept doing the spending
spending spending actually do it I know
papi ran into it and I specifically held
off so 30 days to us seem like a
reasonable point if not you know you
might be in the elements icon machine or
you may have some compelling reason but
at some point you have to true we we we
also not only the operating system but
how many people to applications that's
probably our biggest weakness in some
cases especially people who use flash
which I'm pretty sure is on its way out
I would want to be a stockholder for
Adobe anyway this again ties back in
critical security control eighty we got
a patch that's the cheapest easiest way
to fix things to be stable to make sure
that your that we're doing things you
asked a question I brought prices for
the people who asked questions
so here this is actually this is
something we gave our have to explain
but I'm happy to have you come so
there's RFC 2321 read other reliable
internet work troubleshooting agent that
we use as a motivational prize basically
a rubber chicken it is awesome in here
see instructions on how to use it is
mostly used to hit on the head with a
machine work you can smack it with your
rubber chicken so I brought a couple of
those to hand out to people if anybody
else wants a REIT reliable network
troubleshooting agent asked a question
and I'll give them out to my hand up and
once we ran out we run out a broader
view we also have a blunt or see so as a
Christmas gift but back to our control
patching is critical and it's the
cheapest insurance so the quicker we can
get people to patch the better off we
are but we're gonna make sure they do it
at both the applications based in
operating system doesn't do any good to
patch the OS if you still have a lot of
these are basics and I hate to covering
it with that type of a town I wanna come
off you know I realize people lot of
people debate the value of anti-virus
and anti-malware especially because of
the way signatures can change so quickly
I look at it for the really the diamond
stupid her more than anything else
there's always going to be some script
kiddie or something trying to take an
old exploit and diplomatic so it's not a
bad bank I don't see it as an end all
but at a reasonable thing to have out
there but we're only requiring a lot of
you notice some of these only apply
laptops some apply to multiple devices
again I tend to use Apple products I
like the walled garden I'm also not
enough to know that something can't
sleep in but again because we have to
start somewhere
let's start with what we can accomplish
in a reasonable fashion we're gonna go
with laptops an antivirus and
antimalware and again scanning to make
sure they're actually do it doesn't do
any good to have it if you don't use it
then jumping more onto the encryption
side we talked about that
storage must be encrypted we have a
policy about that already that defines
what it needs to be but we also wanted
to include the external devices it
doesn't do you any good to plug a USB
and we've gotten your desk and it
disappear it's not encrypted so
everything I don't need the hard drive
itself but also to the device itself any
external peripheral devices should be
updated numbers next one local firewall
again same thing it's just one of those
easy basic thanks it's not an end of
everything but the basic control and
then we did the password after hearing
the gentleman upstairs talk about spring
2006 he never really thought the best
control in the world but we gotta start
somewhere and I haven't you noticed when
I walked up to this laptop I just dump
it on but I'm not gonna plug any of my
stuff into it so I got another basic
critical control 16
screens how many people walk fine how
many of you I mean I tend to go over
into Windows now but I'm really tempted
get on email and send some love letters
to somebody but I resist that you
shouldn't let that they would like to do
the upside down 12 yes I know what
you're talking about here so that's a
good suggestion here you get a chicken
to have a very low bar
this is the last time it wasn't a
question or a comment but it went I have
one more or less than 10 timer yes it
drives me crazy so let's have a timer 15
minutes and that's too long in my mind
but again there are people who don't
like shorter time window so we had to
compromise on that one
number ten so basic I don't know what to
say if you want to use that at home
great if you an experiment I'm not here
to discourage innovation and I don't
want to do it I just don't want on my
network if you want to do it at home if
you want to explore please do set up a
lab break stuff that's how we test
things when I think that's what the
gentleman was talking about earlier we
have to be passionate we have to
understand and find things but don't do
it on my network when you're supposed to
be doing something else you're supposed
to be working on pics you know let's
figure out a way we can isolate that but
if you're coming in at a special
exemption or good countermeasure not
jailbroken stuff that's just me pretty
good run again for the phones let's do
the device wipe away the FBI can't get
into it after they mess up and change
the password on the storage but that's
another story is a you know we just pick
the Apple default that seemed to be
pretty good and the same thing with
number 12 all these heavy services let's
be able to find the stuff if you lose it
if you leave it in the restroom or
something like that happens but you
still be surprised how many people don't
have it turned on this is also are also
including devices that plug into the
network that are personal phones and
those type of things if you want to use
it to download your corporate email then
you're gonna be subject to
we were that point taken up as a
security group and then say okay to find
the countermeasure in effect as you know
I get some flexibility in there so these
are not absolute they are used this and
and unless you run into an exception
exception if you're doing something that
makes perfect sense how many people have
seen this stuff and I've seen it to
where you get a thing that says you're
out of compliance could you went to the
more secure version as opposed to less
secure but because it's not in the
signature you get the warning that stuff
happens we recognize that plus we don't
want to discourage innovation the points
from our security team standpoint is
talk to us reflect Peter we want to help
you we recognize that we're in business
and I always take the view from a
security standpoint of work overhead we
can't help contribute to the business
and make things go better for not a
profit center and never will be so I
need we need to be cognizant of how can
we be an enabler of technology people
getting more productive or we can
deliver better value to the people who
are using our system so that's why we
set up the exception process how you
develop a good catch and they said
instructions are included it goes into
much more detail it works at all seven
layers of the OSI model so the guy did a
real good job writing the artsy it is an
actual RFC it's wonderful and I if you
look at if you actually read it it was
put out on April 1st so you understand
why it out there which is also coming up
very soon
again i cant looted the earlier not only
the device itself with peripheral
devices need to be on there again that's
critical security control this is gonna
be the hard line and I'm quite sure how
we're going to do this yet because a lot
of people have their kids are iPad and
that type of thing we're trying to do is
get people to just reserve a device for
work purposes only
you don't need to have your corporate
email on every single device you own a
tablet and this will give parents an
excuse to change the password and not
give it to you know leave daddy's iPad
alone at the bad people at security are
making me do this and they can blame us
for staff and that way we can be the bad
guy I'm so used to being the bad guy now
it doesn't matter but we do not want
corporate data and I realized the
tablets are the best example don't do it
for free gonna do it don't let your kids
play with it that type of thing that's
where the biggest risk and that's why we
get into the sharing so we don't want
people accessing corporate data were not
on have been gone through the disclosure
process not been trained on this purity
training have not gone through the other
things and I'm a country that to a
five-year-old I realize there's times
where the kids gonna be screaming and
you want to hand it to him
ok you know email and delete that
account it'll go up from there so this
is the list we kind of left it at
fifteen you can do a lot more but again
I do you get a foot or how do you get
started so this is the basic start up
problem that exists it's not a better
solution and their answer question but I
have a chicken for you
that's right now we're just gonna be
collecting the data so that we can
switch as we can see who's in and who's
doing what we have a later enhancement
that is going to actually get us into
the switches and then we can start doing
I wanna do Mac filter in I want to start
flocking into the MAC address before you
get it I can't do that yet all I can do
right now with the current
implementation is control who gets to
pass work now we're gonna drive that way
but again I gotta get it started i've
got a project with like five hundred
people have got five or six corporate
staff people like Frank Sinatra song
after work since so first phase now it's
gonna be made no later phases were
looking at doing anything tonight people
don't answer is yes
because there are particular one we are
starting to receive federal tax
information and to use as part of the
process of whether or not we're going to
be granted somebody as part of our
things medical stuff we takin come into
account so are we going to be able to
use that if you're in the project we
have a you know you have the jump and we
have our multi-factor so if you're
getting on with your laptop that's why
it's on a tablet as you should not be
going in dealing with the federal tax
information while you're on one small
handheld devices so again part of its
IRS yeah we do receive data from the IRS
and act on it so yeah of course is the
federal tax we're just trying to keep
our requirements tight it really you
should meet you shouldn't get a lecture
appropriate to have a right roles and
right security I just don't wanna DBA
trying to tweak something from do it the
right way to try to do you should answer
your question
oh yeah this is unique to our project
that was probably the biggest thing that
why we did it and move on to their
status today we've reviewed and vetted
the control last frankly we have the
policies out there we haven't acted on
as far as I want to part of it is
because I graduated in December and I
took some time to relax you regenerate
and so now we're back to reorganize and
picking it back up I think I was just
having too much graduation after two
years in grad school and not see my
family not doing anything other than
studying it was a break we took a
potentially took a break so the other
thing I want to talk about a little bit
as we're implementing this and it's come
to light more than anything is we're
implementing this at the project level
it is very unique and specific unless
your organization using vendors
everywhere with a very small core staff
this really wouldn't work well at an
enterprise
so that's why we're taking it and doing
it at the project level week we know who
our people are we on boredom with that
and we're going to go ahead and just
started this is not a fix for everything
and in some respects it's unique to our
project because of the composition of it
but I think it will work well it where
it's appropriately sized and where you
have the similar situation but the
controls are still reasonable no matter
what you can take those adapter but as
far as our implementation plan we're
just gonna do it at our specific project
you are part of a larger enterprise yes
sir I would love to but I have no budget
so that's why we're starting with this
again future enhancement wise we'd like
to go down that road for that stuff I
gotta have something today that I can do
right away to at least get a good
baseline and then we would do when I do
more of a control control enforcement
type thing but we don't have the budget
for that right now so it's purely money
driven we were trying to find a way that
we could do it at low or no cost because
we had a problem it's do we wait until
we have a budget or do we wait or do we
try to act into something immediately
that will guide us toward getting better
as I said it's going from low level to
the next up will keep going with the
next step and once we demonstrate value
then hopefully we can get some
additional funding so that's why we're
in the particular status that we would
love to have more money
yes ma'am yes ma'am
one of the enterprise policies are
dealing with requires it to be us- based
so you don't have to be aware that type
of thing we're probably probably the
people we have I lean toward like
two-thirds of them are based are coming
to the project work we do have some
people who are not necessarily on there
but they usually come in through
multi-factor or through another networks
I will have to we're gonna get to them
later but most cases those are my people
with the better corporate controls the
ones who are just showing up on Tuesday
with a laptop they bought at Best Buy
the night before they went to work so we
do we have some people out but not the
country
the way the project is structured as
with the five think we have six machines
are actually provided by the
organization and the rest of them were
all walking in the door so again
leadership chose this so we had to get
some things done how do you do this this
is just a lot of the general stuff that
people are ready to be aware of the time
schedule we were able to get leadership
in early we've already built some of the
job dates I want people to be able to
get to these quickly and not only that I
want them to take them and go home with
them if they can do some things on their
home machines that not necessary I work
12 against shredder and make it better
for everybody we're going to you we have
a checklist to find and so we have one
particular person Carlo who's gonna be
the onboarding person has two people
come in we're going to do it and then I
talked earlier question we have a
pre-approval process review the vendors
are going to trust you but we're also
not verify the antenna is a couple of
times oh you know weekly basis start by
checking two or three machines at a time
and keeping inventory thats we can roll
thru everybody the people hurt him so
again like everything else its
communication understanding what it is
it's getting in front of people early
and telling him what is so there's no
surprises I want with us because I
learned a lot through the process not
only about the controls that were
available but how to work better with
people so that's why I put this one
included this particular the first one's
pretty pretty generic most of our staff
and our project want to comply they just
don't know what to do and I have found
that I've gotten good cooperation for
most of them and that's probably a good
thing so that's why we're publishing the
guys were trying to push the guidance as
much as we can tell the people quickly
because I and most people have these
wonderful machines and they have no clue
what's already available so if we can
get him to use the features are included
are embedded were probably seventy
eighty percent of the way there
especially the people who are just buy
the machines a pic on the example of my
testers and they're great they have a
hard job to do 'cause are also trying to
be deadlines that many cases I still get
the
I dunno if you do that ur type of
response to things we show them
something so a lot of this is education
and I go with the assumption that most
Afghan comply and that's why I put that
on the bottom if we can lead we can lead
by example we can demonstrate within
help people we don't have to use the
Hammers much bob and I still use the
hammer or we have to but I'd rather not
I'd rather you comply voluntarily and
not have to do that it's it's in the
process of being upfront with you on
that I took too much time to play after
graduation but now it's getting there
it's been a great thing to all things
around and bottom line is on the last
slide bullet there I feel like we're
gonna be in a much better position when
we're done because we're securing our
end points that's one of the major
things as how many points you haven't
had that since I can block them in a
pretty good position so to summarize
cause we're almost out of time and I
have two more Chuck Norris jokes save
some businesses gonna do this whether we
like it or not that's why I repeated the
slide we gotta find ways to help the
business we need to find ways to make
sure that were part of the equation we
keep saying over and pushed away from
the table and find out about things
after the facts of the more we can bring
value to the organization the better off
we are so maybe when you hear my last
two Chuck Norris jokes okay sure so I
like I like these two I say these are
the Chuck Norris can read all encrypted
data has nothing to hide from Chuck
Norris right and of course he doesn't
need pseudo either he just types Chuck
Norris before all of his commands and
automatically gets nothing stops Chuck
Norris right speaking of pseudo I was
doing when I was looking this up I
thought it was cool there's a Columbus
connection to suit and I'll drop this
this is my last nerve tribute for you
when I was looking it up in 2003
Nationwide Mutual Insurance just across
the street contributed code to storage
to data and held up so Columbus actually
made suit
we can actually use you may know what to
do me understand what it stands for
yes maybe now it's super user do you
have a question or answer it
you actually know UNIX I'm proud of you
that's okay that's just the references
here in case anybody cares any questions
we have a few minutes and then we need
to let you out of your next thing he
asked questions right why thank you for
coming I think you for your involvement
thank you