you think preferences yes wonder what
that's only as we look like there's
Wayne just funny let me try it is our
second just to see is not every spooky
hcp ocean are either okay then it works
so it's working there you go okay i
guess i just woke it up or something i'm
gonna use the clicker thing
bring say oh all right well this is the
DC working group meeting if you expect
to be somewhere else you're in the wrong
room and I'm Bernie volts one of the
co-chairs and I'm telling Podolski and
welcome to the working group I welcome
all eight of you here now that's
probably like 12 people in the room okay
let's get started so please note well if
you see this for the first time you are
doing it wrong okay so blue sheets
banging again they're both been
circulating your day please make sure
you sign them well with this amount of
attendance I suppose the next time we
are meeting in a closet anyway so okay
well as well as keep them okay guys we
need javascript in case like the chance
re going okay great and and it would be
appreciated if you could help with not
taking on the inner part so we already
introduced ourselves we used to have a
working group secretary but shank step
down so if you are interested in helping
a bit with the working group the
position is open okay so this is the
agenda for today Ian asked to go to the
second slide because he has a plane to
catch so we will go through the library
for over six dynamic provisioning then
we do the HP v6 update I will provide an
update regarding the forestry meal
extensions and finally Bernie will talk
about an old draft that possibly could
be resurrected okay so working group
status we had one Fc pub
topic on we also have two documents sent
to is G the HP v6 file over and DTV six
previous line taking issue with the two
to 315 beasts we are making progress
there's a separate presentation so i
won't go into the details and a young
draft it's progressing forward but my
kink it's slowly with the security HP v6
the work continues there were several
versions published and we had some
discussion on deep-sea mailing list and
also on sag so with the first new
extensions there was no progress outers
are not responsive Bernie and I tried to
contact them several times so we have an
agenda slot you know to discuss what to
do about it and there's there are two
drafts that were adopted Dixie rely part
and the Dixie realize server security
and there's technically there's the last
call on the second one is in progress
because i haven't summarize it up there
were very few responses actually only
bang you responded i think so if you
have some comments please do send them
to the list okay so we have several
individual draft one of them is the
software dhcp for over six and there
were there is a presentation about it
coming right after this one okay and the
last update regarding the working group
is about milestones so we recently
completed two milestones we still have
too much since opened the first one is
and that we should reach outer this
would probably make sense after we
finish our work on 2315 bitch and of
course we have the second milestone
so I have a question to the working
group so do you guys consider the
milestones useful at all have you looked
at them and follow them later them ok
that's a good feedbacks ok so Suresh are
we required to continue updating those
milestones Association I think it's
useful to update the milestones because
it helped me plan like you know when the
documents come through so I don't get
like a sudden I have like suddenly 14
documents in my queue in the last two
weeks and it's not it's very difficult
for me to plan to get them until it
shuts and everything so I I I want to
have an approximate idea when something
is going to be done so I think it's good
ok ok so in that case only one person is
using it but he's an important one so
yeah ok in that case we'll continue
updating them ok so that's it yeah good
morning in far from Georgia telecom
first slide please so second slide
technical so um I I think I presented
this a few meetings back in the HCHO
probably probably going on a couple of
years now but a quick refresher about
the we're just trying to get rid of that
ok there is the what and the wise so can
you go can you go to the first slide
just to sort in Greece what this is so
um for soft was we need to have fee for
configuration and we need to build a
tunnel in v6 so we've got a few
parameters that need to be provisioned
to the client last year we published a
static provisioning dhcp address which
deals with essentially you have pre
configured and kind of deterministic
ways of assigning these addresses to
clients and you know that cell that's
implemented and working but some
obviously with any color static and
pre-configured configuration model isn't
here and wastage in there and it's a not
possible to
you know gets a good well address
sharing an aggressive use of the
remaining before it sources that you've
got um another particular thing that
needs to be solved with soft wires is
that you need as an operator to know
what the clients tunnel endpoint these
six address is going to be so I mean
there's there's a way of kind of pre
calculating that that we've used in the
in the static provisioning model but
this provides a way that the client can
just simply tell the server in a
parameter this is what i'm going to use
and then the server stores that
alongside the lease information so that
you've got a kind of single point in the
network that you can say this is all the
information i need for v4 v6 and i can
use up to provision the other elements
in the architecture next slide please so
um yeah this has been around in software
for some time but hasn't really moved
very far in there because essentially
everything that's described in here is
dhcp 44 / dhcp 6 related so there's two
RFC's that have already been published
both worked on in DHC so that's 73 41
and 76 1876 18 deals with address
sharing in v4 least addresses and so as
this is kind of the final part that
makes the whole thing come together it
made more sense or hopefully it makes
more sense to put it in DAC next slide
please alright so here's a kind of a
rough overview I mean it doesn't show
the full DHCP message flow here but some
if you're familiar with DHCP for over 6
it all starts off by receiving an option
from the dhcp server that will either
either enable it will contain a unicast
address for the DHCP for over 6 server
you then have a new message flow which
is the DHCP for over 6 1 and in there
you're carrying DHCP for messages inside
a particular DHCP six message type so
within the flow we pass from the server
to the client a hint this is in the form
of an IP version 6 prefix and this is to
essentially help the client to find the
right address or the right prefix out of
all the one that's got
available so that it can have a chance
of getting a SoftWIRE built on the right
place that's going to be rootable and
whatever else the client then builds an
address on that prefix and indicates
back to the server this is my / 128 that
I'm going to use my tunnel endpoint as
my tunnel endpoint aggress so at that
point once all this is completed the
dhcp server has got the while all of the
information that's relevant for the
SoftWIRE crimes and then this can then
be pushed into the other network element
the AFT are using what we're using that
come for this but we talked about using
things like both of these query and
things like that for it and at that
point you've got a fully functioning
soft wire and a dynamically confited
address that can be you know works under
normal dhcp for kind of thumb leasing
okay next slide please so there's two
new options in here the first one being
the Prince of the hint option which is
just simply a v6 prefix and the second
one is the 128-bit address that will be
used as the tunnel endpoint that the
client pass back to the server next
slide please this is the kind of a ya
the minute a of what exactly happens at
each step and you can see that it's
aligned with the DHCP for message flow
so these messages are the additional new
options that I'm talking about here are
carried along with the corresponding v4
message as it goes through the ER than
or dhcp for leasing process next slide
so we're working on an implementation at
the moment and it's not completed but
there's already some feedback that's
coming back from there about the text
that's in so I submitted the 06 update I
think two days ago that took into
account some of those those things
there's also some other comments that
have come back from from our implementer
and some yeah those those will be up on
the list shortly there was another
review that came in fringe in May
overnight so some other comments that
need to be addressed there there's I
think there's still quite a few things
to be considered in here at the moment
so I don't think it's near to being done
but you know
hopefully we've been in DAC it'll get
the the attention from the right people
that it needs next slide okay so the
question I was really wanted to ask is
do we think this is suitable to move to
DHC and if so is it something that would
be adoptable so does anybody have any
opinions one way or the other or you
know supporting moving it or opposed to
seeing building it i'm gern so i haven't
read the draft but from what Ian's
presented it seems sensible enough to me
so description i read the draft i think
it's okay to move here like have you
talked to Terry about it or to Teddy yes
I before I suggested this as her started
okay something okay um I'm perfectly
fine if you do pose to take it up good
okay thank you okay prepare to let
something to add oh I'm just in favor of
taking it up okay governor yeah so with
my culture cut off i'm also supporting
moment it here so it makes sense it's
reasonable draft and it's a good fit for
DC so yeah we also have from the jabber
room lengua son and we both escaped
adopting us so i guess one question
though is do you want you know do we
want to start working group a call
adoption now do you want to update the
draft and then start the call given that
you mentioned that there were some
pending updates um I mean it's just when
I want to put the 06 update that we've
had it had some discussion starting on
the list so let's see how that pans out
I'll make an update based on that and
then we'll do the cfa odd map okay yeah
that that's what i would have
recommended ok good ring okay thanks
very much all right thank you i guess i
gotta send
the pink box okay so I'm going to give
you a little update on what's happening
with the dhcpv6 biz work and we have a
few open issues that we'd like some
feedback on so just as a reminder to
sort of where we are today the 05
version was published in june we
initiate a working group last call in
July which lasted a while and it ended
in august and we got approximately 290
you know comments it wasn't 290 separate
emails but we kind of took everybody's
comments and and chop them up into
individual items that were tracking on a
Google sheet and you know obviously
there were duplicates in there but most
of them are probably unique there are
were 16 serious reviewers you know that
that generated on the order of 10 to you
know 30 comments each so there was very
you know I really thank everybody that
reviewed it you guys did a fantastic job
this this is the way working through
blessed calls should work and it got
excellent coverage so you know that was
good obviously the bad news is that we
have 290 issues to go through and you
know well I'll talk a little bit more
about some of them but you know the
problem is is that it's just a lot of
stuff to go through we've addressed
about 200 the comments but there's more
to go there you know in that last set
there's probably some duplicates as well
next line many of the comments were
minor you know clean up text fix typos
formatting issues or inconsistencies
where the documents in one part said one
thing and kind of contradicted itself in
another section usually just stuff that
we had done when when we edited it we
didn't you know edit all the text in
certain sections there were a bunch of
comments about clarifying sections
adding new more definitions and even
reorganizing the text to improve its
presentation and
you know logical flow and we have a few
potential changes that we want your
input on so the first of those is the
soul mix RT and also impacts RT um you
know that the RC 78 III which we never
really caught during this is that it
never really clarified how the options
should be updated if there are multiple
uh you know advertised or replies
received okay um you know if the client
accepts an advertised should have used
just that the options from that and
ignore the others um but you know what
if it didn't contain options but others
did and what happens if no advertisers
accepted and multiple multiple
advertisers are receive so it's a
question of you know we can either just
say well nobody cared it 79-78 III so
we'll leave it alone and just copy the
text in here or we can try to address
this you know one proposal is to use the
smallest legal value across the received
options you know legal there's some
boundary checks that are specified in
seventy eighty three you know I should
point out that probably this is a minor
issue because on a properly operating
Network you would expect the last bullet
to apply and that they're there all the
servers if there are multiple servers
are gonna use the same values but you
know that may not always be the case mm
and I have a comment on that particular
bullet I think that as a way of avoiding
attacks which you know probably wouldn't
happen on a really you know secure
network but it certainly could happen on
a less secure Network like a home net um
it is almost certainly a good idea to do
the take the smallest length that you
here because otherwise somebody can just
sit there and send you the you know
super long sull max RT and bam you're
off the wire for however long right and
that's what we kind of figured is that
you know I mean they can somebody can
still
do the opposite and give you a small
value but that's less harmful suresh
krisshnan so i'm a bit conflicted here
right because like I hear what ted says
like an but the idea of like doing
seventy eighty three was to increase
this thing to reduce the traffic volumes
right correct in and it did two things
783 it changed them the default up and
it provided this option to override the
default and if you can only increase the
default I if I remember correctly from
that base of 3600 seconds no you can go
down to 60 okay you go down to 60 right
okay and so I have an alternate proposal
like no I haven't thought this out like
I just came up with it like if you get
like multiple different ones you change
to the default which is 3600 because
like then like somebody could like have
an attack where they put in like a small
number and advertise it and just like
increase the traffic on the link for
notation right so I don't I just don't
know like I haven't thought it through
but I mean it that sounds like a
plausible solution you know the one
thing that we have to remember is that a
client isn't necessarily going to wait
for you know lots of them to come by
either so but I think if it does receive
conflicting values may be the best thing
to do is you say is just say use the
default and and leave it alone right and
it really depends on the implementation
too if it's actually keeping track of
how it gots the solar max RT right so
well maybe it can check if it's already
non-default but maybe it's not non
trivial but it's yeah and that I didn't
bring it up on this slide but there you
know there's there's another little
complexity and that is what you know
when do you ever set so max RT back to
the default suppose you get a large
value or different value ok when are you
supposed to set it back because it never
really that 70 83 never really talked
about that issue I you know since since
you kind of stepped a little bit into it
I figure maybe it's work also trying to
address that is to kind of say that
maybe you know one way is that obviously
if the client solicits again and gets a
different value then it no
is ok I'm going to use that right but
that's a subtle issue that you know does
exist right and also another thing is
like maybe tom i can answer this like do
you keep track of where you got the
solar max Hardy from from itself right
because if if the server it solves
changes the solar max RT like you need
to know if it's it's an inconsistency
other so just change the solar max RT
right yeah I don't again it doesn't
really talk about that you know so
implementation-specific if you really
want to you can track of it but I just
wanted to know about kia like what it
does right sir ok so key is a server
only so yeah this is really we'd have to
ask client implementers and i don't know
how many you know Tim might know whether
there's a lot that have implemented
seventy eighty three or not so come
winners UNH i well so we've only really
seen it in home gateways most of them
when you reboot them will lose it yeah
well that make sense and really learn it
I do have to that keep it forever and
that's been oh that's been interesting
so we might want to say something about
this because I suspect more people will
just take whatever new value they get
and apply it forever and it's nasty it
is nasty if you set it to a high value
it's going to sit for a while but I mean
I will say this is a unique test case or
any case and it means there's nothing
answering it so I don't know how much we
care to put in crazy text here to try
right well that's the other question is
that is kind of a failure case anyway or
RK an odd case anyway Ted lemon so um a
couple things one I think suresh's
suggestion is great if we get
conflicting values use use the default
yes um I think that it's actually not
likely to be a problem in the typical
use case for this in the sense that you
know if your cable modem goes and sends
out a solicit it's on a cable network
there is relatively tightly constrained
and controlled and so the likelihood of
you getting an attack from some
third-party on that network is pretty
slim and it's not a bad idea to have
this this you know this fall back but
but I don't think it's a really serious
I issue it's more of a serious issue on
a home net but on home that you know I
think Suresh is solution works fine um
and uh i'm going to say sorry or your
second point was about oh right i think
that the time to discard the value is
whenever you see a link state transition
right and implicitly also that means on
a reboot because otherwise you know
certainly for for cable modems you're
not likely to ever see link state
transition it's not a big deal but if
you do like you know if one of the
things that cable providers will do is
they'll whack your link to get you to
restart to re initialize so yeah and
that that does raise a funny question
about you know should should these
options then be allowed in in the
confirm um you know refined case right
because that's what you're going to do
when the link yeah flips so you know
maybe it doesn't matter because you're
not soliciting in that case and so we
don't really care and that may just be
the answer right is you could restore
and when you do if you do ever fall back
just look phase you'll get new values or
so maybe that's the way to solve that is
it doesn't eat it's not necessary
because of that all right so we'll
probably you know that somebody from the
biz team will summarize and provide the
suggestions for confirmation on the
mailing list and we can discuss a lit
for their alright next issue so another
request that we received was to remove
the following paragraph from section 17
1 10 1 and we believe this is to allow
to run multiple independent state
machines on a single interface oh this
isn't the updated slides but anyway is
to discourage but allow is what I think
we wanted to say to run multiple
independent state machines on a single
interface and we got to feel that this
you know if you're going to do something
as complicated as that you should take
that text with a grain of salt you know
the the all required leases and and
that means just those for which that
state machine is kind of running because
we kind of say at the beginning of this
document somewhere I think we kind of
talked about that you know this is sort
of a single instance of a dhcp client
and you would run a different one on
each interface and things like that so
it I'm not sure we want to remove this
this paragraph or even reword it so um
Ted lemon my only reason for not loving
this text is that it does have the
effect that if you are running to DHCP
servers on a link one of which is doing
neighbor discover sorry one of which is
doing PD and 10 which is doing na then
this is going to make you do a lot more
work but well we don't really support
you ibly not a great thing to be doing
anyways right and it's not a problem and
it's not really the you know the this
7550 staple issues kind of route them
anyway okay and I think if you if you
want to build a client that does that I
don't think you're prohibited from doing
that right and you might want to use a
different iaid anyway because presumably
you have some reason why you're doing it
right yeah ok so again we'll take this
to the list with a summary of what we
kind of concluded here and confirm next
so the last one that I have here is
about ipsec encryption and we got a
comment that you know we kind of now say
that the null encryption can be used
because DCB messages uh you know that
the data in there is not generally
considered confidential and you know
that's that's very debatable today
because there's a lot of issues with the
iesg about this and that's why i wrote
the relay server security draft which
did
mandate but kind of highly recommended
ipsec usage so you know I'd like to just
drop the text in from that document but
that document is in working group last
call well they kind of technically
expired but hasn't yet really been
processed and I think I was only wanting
to comment on it and as a co-author that
probably doesn't count much so we
encourage people to look at that
document and indicate whether you know
you support this because then we can
just drop a lot of this text from that
document into the 33 15 biz so i will
send something Colless on this as well
but again I think the solution is
support the working group last call on
the relay server security draft and then
if everybody supports that we can
probably just copy that text and that
will also i think make the iesg happier
that we have a bit stronger statement
about security and things ok that's all
I had for that the next steps for the
document are that uh you know a what was
it yeah thanks for all the comments but
you know if you have some that our
cellar it's not too late we'll take them
you know we did publish the 06 which has
some of the updates and it's possible
that we made some mistakes and stuff so
we'll continue to work on it will
hopefully publish in 07 our hope is to
do that before the next ITF so that we
can do a short review of the document
with all the changes and hopefully send
it off with maybe an 08 published to
suresh shortly after the next IETF so
that's how we'll update those milestones
okay thank you
ah ok so this will be a very brief
presentation so we had the force honey
next slide please so we had the first
renewal extensions this was drafted was
presented in Buenos Aires it was adopted
in may 2016 16 the response doing the
presentation and adoption it was not
very popular but in general people who
expressed their opinions they were in
favor so after death there were
completely no updates no discussions we
tried to reach the outers also primary
alto liu yuan she used to work for
microsoft but she's now in a different
team so our site of microsoft and the
draft has expired so when next so the
question is are we still interested in
this work we I think we try to reach the
other routers three times and nobody
responded so is there anyone interested
in in this work to continue okay so I
don't see anyone okay in that case we'll
go and quit option we just drop the work
so we will mark it as they attend but
will confirm on the mail I'm us should
make sure that nobody else has any okay
right yeah before before taking that
action my purse mm I my personal feeling
is I don't object anybody continuing
this work if somebody wants to do it but
I have no interest in continuing it
myself okay and it's v4 so it's yeah
okay so that's it thanks
okay so I'd like to talk about possibly
resurrecting an old draft that we
started work on next slide back in 2005
of October was when the original draft
was written it was adopted by the
working group back in January 2006 kind
of lingered there for several years and
in January 09 the 04 was was published
which is the current version it
obviously has long since expired and
interest was primarily lost because
there were if I if I remember correctly
there was a concern about out of order
packets might cause issues and the other
issue was that CableLabs had had
specified in relay agents were starting
to implement just doing relay snooping
just to say done with dhcp v4 because it
worked great for v4 so why not use it
for v6 so the working group was a bit
too late in sort of doing this work next
slide so why now well you know the
original motivation was we wanted to
avoid relay snooping um you know they
shouldn't need to look really shouldn't
need to look inside the individual
client messages to determine what Lisa's
the client was assigned or what other
actions like you know when a client
release Elise that that the least was
removed and today the or the original
argument was that if we had strong
security some at some point security
might make this impossible we also want
to reduce complexity for relays because
some relay messages I sorry some reply
messages do not have details on what the
client did for example a release doesn't
you know the release message going to
the server has a list of addresses and
prefixes that might be released but
the reply coming back has nothing it
just basically says yeah I released your
addresses its success or failure usually
just success but so there's no
information for the relay so it makes
the relays job a bit harder because it
has to monitor the clients request not
just the replies and the idea is that
with this is that the server provides
the relay explicit details in the rear
wheel a reply message about what it's
done what Lisa's its assigned or
extended lifetimes on or even those that
it released next slide so the design is
that you know the relay added in Oro
with this new option to the relay
forward and this kind of was a little
bit unique in that the Oro you know
tended to be more views just by the
client whereas here it was making use of
it by the real I now we could have a
relay echo option if we want you know I
sorry a real a request option if we
wanted to an RR 0 instead of an Oro but
it probably isn't you know I don't see
the value of doing that because it's
clear where this this message this
option would be in the relay forward
part of the message not in the clients
message and the server added this option
to the real a reply with all the
addresses and prefixes in use by the
client the pretty much the you know real
agent was only supposed to use the valid
lifetimes and about lifetime is 0 meant
that the address or prefix was released
and again the advantage here is relays
no longer need to look into the clients
message and it's explicitly notified of
server actions next slide so the problem
today is that we're working on secure
dhcpv6 which is going to encrypt the
messages so the client to server
communication is encrypted so relay
snooping no longer works so what do we
do well I think in the short term
assuming that you know we can get the
secure dhcpv6 work done will be that for
certain
we're real a snooping is required such
as in cable docsis they won't may be
able to support secure dhcpv6 option
maybe not a big deal but you know it is
it is there um another option which is
the one I'm proposing is we resurrect
this draft and I think some of the
issues that were raised about it are
probably pretty minor because relay
snooping can suffer from the same out of
order packet delivery issues and things
like that and has been done very
successfully without to my knowledge any
significant problems or any problems at
all so I think that that was probably an
overrated issue you know was a nice
conceptual issue but it wasn't probably
a realistic issue um you know another
option is if you do secure dhcpv6 maybe
the you have to provide the relay the
server certificates but Suresh shakes
his head and i agreed that i don't think
that's a very good idea either um you
know there are other options like having
the real i used actively square e to
keep up with updates which that that
would be a fairly workable solution
potentially um you know and we could
develop yet another protocol but i don't
think we want to do that either so next
slide so what do people think do we do
we want to resurrect this do we want to
wait a little bit further until secure
dhcpv6 is further along do we want to
try to do something else telemon um so I
actually kind of liked your active lease
query idea the reason being that it
eliminates the concern about timing
right because now you're having an
actual communication between the real
agent and the server and it's also
something that real agents that do
snooping are likely to want to do anyway
right for example they might they'd like
to do both query for lease query for
example when they reboot because they
can collect all the state yeah yeah or
you know it could be that you even just
do at least query whenever you see a
release go by or whenever you well now
you have yeah you do have to do it well
the problem is yeah
again when we encrypt right you're not
all you're gonna see is a packet went by
you're not gonna know right right what's
in it yeah so that said I don't have any
objection to doing the other solution I
just I just think that we should
seriously think about it's probably
worth actually thinking about how
plausible a solution it is to use active
lease query if we think that it's not
really going to work then we shouldn't
do it but we should at least answer that
question before we develop a new thing
because you know we are now putting more
junk into the dhcp packet and you know
if there's if there's a better way to do
it maybe we should just do that and and
I think active least query at least in
principle is a better way to do that
yeah the only I think the only objection
that that might exist and again it's
only a theoretical thing at this point
would be that actively square e you know
is a separate communication channel yeah
and so the timing of it might be a
little bit interesting because you know
if you let things go to the client
traffic might appear before the active
lease query makes it through especially
if there's like a hiccup where the
actively scary query connection goes
down because it's TCP bays and has to be
restarted and things like that so I
think that would be the only concern
that you know might exist because if you
do want to you know if like on a CMT s
where you're installing a bunch of other
state when you get this stuff they would
really like to do it sort of as the
packet goes back to the client and so
that that's the only benefit I think for
the this option is that it's it's you
know will happen at the same time yeah
right maybe a better way to put it would
be that active least query is a good
thing to do in addition to this just
because that will clean up any mistakes
that happen that that could be an
argument yes yeah so anybody else have
any comments pro or con or suresh
krisshnan I don't have any particular
thing either I just don't three and five
so I'm okay with like 12 and four and I
would really like to wait until security
ICP v6 like gets out and
to see if like people have issues before
we do it like because and they had
similar things with send you know like
there's like lot of stuff done and it
never got the plight so like uh I don't
know like it's I'm fine with like
continuing working on this but I'm just
wanna see like uptake before um doing
this really yeah and I think it'll be I
I agree that I think you know we've had
a very long road with the secure dhcpv6
work and so it may be still be a little
bit premature to start something because
we don't know how it's gonna end yet
right um but hopefully hopefully one of
these days we'll get a security
mechanism that works right I mean so
yeah but so I think that your
recommendation is that we we sort of
park this for now and revisit
periodically depending on how secure
dhcpv6 your some though for exact okay
and I'm perfectly happy with that I
think you know I think um yeah I you
know was a little bit leery about
bringing this up this early because I
don't know how secure d cv v6 is going
to work out there there are you know
some there are some subtle benefits for
this because it solves like the release
problem and things like that so there
are some advantages in using this or the
active least square solution because the
the relay does get more more up-to-date
information Tim Chang might be a bit of
a naive question what about things like
69 39 where the relays doing something
based on what the client does is that an
issue was that irrelevant uh which is
that document that's the one where you
can squeeze the mac address of the
client to get it into the relay to
forward it for the people that have the
warm comfy slippers are wanting to see
McEnaney know the link is that an issue
or that type of thing
no cuz that's the link layer is that the
link layer that's a really odd fence so
that was a misunderstood yeah okay um
you know that might be encrypted with
ipsec but that's a that you know the
relays and and stuff will know how to do
that so all right thank you thank you uh
I think that brings us to the end of our
formal agenda so if there's any other
things people want to discuss briefly we
can certainly take a few minutes to do
so but otherwise call meeting adjourned
and this was probably the shortest DHC
meeting ever we could talk about the
Emmental bits tintern so I shouldn't
mention this if you want to get away now
there is a discussion in six-man about
updating RFC 6434 just the node
requirements document and there are some
words in there about DHC and support for
THC and there are some people in six-man
that have suggested that the heb support
should be a May and not assured that
type of thing I don't necessarily think
this point having a discussion here now
with 10 people but if people hear that
our interested can take a look at the
DHT relevant bits in 6434 and suggest
some words either that they think those
are still fine or suggests words to
replace those chunks in 6434 that would
be useful thank you yes that isn't a
good point and you know we should follow
that work and stay up with it because
just to see where it goes and comment on
anything that's really as you see there
thank you Tim all right well thank you
and we'll see you in Chicago thanks Jim
maybe well I mean there one of these
days we were probably gonna end up with
friday afternoon it's not too bad and
again thanks Ted and I think it was Tim
that did a lot of the the etherpad thank
you so we will make some modification
what to focus on the motivation right so
you really need to explain you know what
it is you're trying to