as long as it's okay thank you everyone
sorry for the late start so welcome
today to the EDT edu tutorial on DNS
privacy my name is Sarah Dickinson very
glad to see so many faces here today so
I'll move forward on to the overview of
what we'll talk about today so the
tutorial is basically split up into
three sections the first section is
going to be a background of why are we
talking about dearness privacy as an
issue and how did this arise and to kick
that off Daniel can't Gilmore has kindly
agreed to give a few slides to set this
in the context of the bigger picture of
Internet privacy after that we'll move
on to talk about the huge amount of work
that's been done over the last three or
four years in this area a lot of it
through the ITF a lot of it through the
deep I working group and then finally
I'll talk about the current status of
implementations deployment and tools
that are available today so thank you so
without further ado I'll hand over
so I want to talk just a little bit to
set the frame for why dns privacy
matters more generally it matters sort
of there's a bigger picture why does
privacy on the Internet itself matter so
just to try to motivate it so that we're
thinking about this stuff sort of on the
same page you can looks like it doesn't
want to do the full screen thing
is it a one page yeah all right so so
the concern here is that there's sort of
an issue of possibility of a centralized
surveillance state acting as a form of
social control now you might you might
be concerned about governmental control
you might be concerned about criminal
control blackmail a range of other
things but basically whoever controls
the network if the network is
transparent about what's going on has
potentially a lot more power over the
citizens so the people who use the
network so this is a this is a plan for
the panopticon which is a prison that's
designed so that a warden sitting in the
central tower of the prison can
effectively see everybody in all of the
cells around the outside and so that
allows one or a very small amount of
people to the guards in this case to
have control over a very large
population I find that troubling and I'd
like to make sure that network where the
smarts are at the edges doesn't make it
so that the center actually has control
over the smarts at the edges so the next
so so the DNS when we think about what
goes on in the DNS we're often thinking
about sort of that is basically like
little bits of metadata like what host
names are you looking up and that's
associational host data so a request
comes from you for a particular name
those names potentially mean things and
I want to just point out that like
associational surveillance is actually
probably the most sophisticated form
surveillance that we have if you're
thinking about global surveillance the
it feels creepy to think of somebody
knowing what you're saying but actually
the things that machines can learn at
scale are significantly more powerful
these days than just content analysis
and so this associational stuff this is
a slide from the elite slide from the
NSA their only one of the groups who are
doing sir like intense associational
surveillance but the the kind of
associational surveillance they can do
is mapping particular people to
particular groups so you can imagine
with the DNS the mapping the sorts of
mappings that could go on
like did you visit Alcoholics Anonymous
that well that tell somebody something
so whoever controls the network has an
opportunity to know if they're just
watching what traffic goes on what sorts
of people have connected to what sorts
of groups so the DNS is part of that so
you can do the next slides here so it's
also not just host names right the DNS
has we think of it as most commonly it's
just we're going to look up an address
from a name but there's lots of other
stuff that can be stored in the DNS and
if you look around what's going on at
the IETF there are a bunch of other
opportunities to use the DNS that are
not just host names they're not as
widely used of course as the address
lookups that we're all familiar with but
in fact there's a bunch of other stuff
that's coming down the pike there's old
stuff like MX records which which will
actually leaked information about what
what domain you're emailing to and then
there's things like Oakland pgp key
where you might actually end up sending
the name of whoever you're contacting
directly the DNS so another name but the
individual email account which is
significantly larger privacy leak so
there's a bunch of other stuff that
could go on in the DNS and people want
to use the DNS for that and so we need
to make sure that DNS queries aren't as
obviously subject to associational
surveillance and so so just just to sort
of reinforce why I think the social
control issue is a thing here so this is
a study that was done i think this this
year at the beginning of this year where
they basically took a bunch of people
and they asked them their opinion on
some topics that were fairly contentious
and then they asked them their opinion
of about the sentence is it like
basically is sent is centralized
surveillance okay and it turns out that
this is sort of along the lines of if
you're not worried about it if you have
nothing to hide you've got nothing to
worry about right there's a lot of
people who have that sort of instinctive
response and it turns out the people who
say if you're not you know I've got
nothing to hide I'm not worried about
surveillance surveillance is justified
to eat society safe the people who say
that when it comes to things where they
are in the minority where they feel like
they are more in conflict they're
actually less likely to speak up so this
is actually an ecosystem problem where
the fact that we have all of this
additional
means that people are less likely to
dissent and our society was less likely
to be able to evolve so these are the
like these are different groups of
people who have different opinions about
the legitimacy of surveillance and the
graph here shows friendly neutral and
hostile so if you think you're saying
something into a hostile environment and
you think surveillance is okay you're
actually less likely to speak up at all
so there's a chilling factor of having
the centralized surveillance so it's not
just about are you individually
concerned about being spied on it's
about what can society do as a like how
to society change have the behavior
change as a result of having this so we
want to make protocols that encourage
people to not to feel that they are
protected so they actually can
communicate with people even in an
environment where they might otherwise
feel like it's hostile environment and I
want to point out that DNS is one little
piece of these leakages right so this is
a boat here dns is leaking in the middle
of the boat but there's leaks coming
from the TLS layer of the server name
indication in TLS leaks there's leaks
from the traffic size of different kinds
of packets that you send timing patterns
there's probably lots of other leaks
that we don't know about and a lot of
times in IETF we're working in these
little silos and I've heard in multiple
situations people say oh well we don't
have to worry about that leakage because
it's just as bad as this other leakage
that's happening somewhere else well in
a leaky boat scenario you actually need
to fix all the leaks you can't just say
I'm not going to fix my leak because
this other leak over here is leaking
also right we want the boat to stay
afloat so the motivation here is to try
to make sure that we can actually get I
mean there's a lot of work ahead of us
we actually these are theoretical
concerns and some of these like the
question marks there are real question
marks like these are there's ongoing
academic research about what kind of
information can be determined from
things like timing patterns and we don't
have all the answers but we know that if
we don't fix the things that we know how
to fix we're not going to get to all of
them so that's just a motivation for why
we care about DNS privacy it's not going
to solve all the problems but it's a
step in that direction so give it back
to server
wait
okay thank you very much so I hope
that's given you a flavor for some of
the context of what we'll talk about
today so what I first like to do is
before we dive right deep into what's
been happening doing as well it's talk a
little bit about what's been happening
at the ITF level in general in terms of
privacy now of course the Snowden
revelations were a big thing and it got
popular awareness about mass
surveillance and out there a lot of
people sort of tend to think that kind
of caught the IETF napping but what I
want to illustrate here is that really
really isn't true the IDF was very
actively involved in all sorts of
privacy work well before that there were
numerous workshops and quite importantly
in March 2011 work was started on a
draft that was to guide protocol
developers on how to add privacy
considerations into their drafts in a
very similar manner as to the way
security considerations are quite
naturally put in draft so the folks
behind that started back in 2011 and
they were right on the verge of getting
it published as an RC when Edward
Snowden revealed his um a data to the
world so you kind of got a feel for
these guys a little bit get me my
Thunder stolen there but what the IDF
did is it came back swinging it very
quickly reacted with a very important
document which is RFC 7258 and this
declares clearly that pervasive
monitoring is an attack I'll talk about
that a little more in a moment the work
at the idea level has continued though
there are several other RFC's in this
area there are many drafts in progress
so I just want to illustrate that there
is a lot of work going on at the
leadership level in the ITF with regards
to privacy I just wanted to pull out
just a couple of statements from RFC
2558 in terms of clarifying that the
IITs position on this is that pervasive
monitoring is an attack on internet
users and organizations and the declared
aim in future protocol developments is
to mitigate the effects of monitoring
through pro
Cole design so doing it at the lowest
level not necessarily operationally but
making sure protocol design takes us
into account so to move on to see where
this inter intersected with DNS so if
you think back back in time a little bit
first of all I'd like to time travel you
back to nineteen eighty seven so pick
your your DeLorean your TARDIS your
phone booth time machine of choice and
go back to nineteen eighty seven so
there's a lot of bad hair a lot of good
music and the DNS has been standardized
at that time and to put it in context at
that time it was a building block in the
internet and the main goals behind the
design of the infrastructure of the DNS
were availability redundancy and also
speed so those are the things that for
most in the people who are developing
the protocol in privacy terms the DNS is
described as an enabler it's a system
that you use to get to other services so
you want to get to a web page you go via
the DNS you want to email something you
go via the DNS so that's where it sits
now the Sun it was still true of the
standards in 2003 that the standard
transports for DNS work UDP and TCP and
even last year over ninety-nine percent
of the traffic going up to the route
went over UDP and importantly this is
clear text so all you're doing as
queries are going clear text over the
internet so this meant this was fair
game for somebody like the NSA with
their more cowbell tool it really wasn't
a tricky job for them to monitored in
ass traffic because of the way it moves
over the Internet there was a very small
of TC amount of tcp around but it was
really only used for corner cases there
was also at this time and for much of
the sort of 25 year time period here
that I'm spanning a perception that the
DNS is
like right I mean anybody can query
these records anybody can get to them
they don't contain personal or sensitive
information so we really don't need to
worry about encrypting this or
protecting us in any way it's the DNS
and that was out there for a long time
so you have to bear those things in mind
when you look at the design of the dns
and be a bit forgiving so this is the
basics of how the dns works you're on
some client machine you want to resolve
a name you send the full name up to the
recursive server that you're using now
what the DNS does is if it doesn't have
that name in cash it sends the entire
name up to a root server to get a
delegation for in this case dot org then
it sends the entire query to the doctor
or authoritative server and so on down
the chain until it gets to the one that
can provide the answer now with
hindsight we and your privacy hat on you
look at this and go oh that infamous bad
idea ferry was around when they thought
of this right because those do queries
are leaking information who a troop
needs to know the full question that the
client asked they don't need to in order
to resolve it but this was how the DNS
was designed originally something else
interesting happened just about this
time frame as well 2013 and that was the
standardization of a mechanism called
Eden s0 now this was a really nice idea
and something the DNS really needed it
enabled embedding information inside DNS
query that was flexible it could contain
capability options it could allow
clients and service to negotiate things
like path MTU it was great the dearness
needed it as a side effect though what
this did is it enabled certain
organizations to take advantage of this
to embed user data directly inside those
DNS queries but the way this was
positioned at the time was that it was
all for the greater good so for example
one of the mechanisms here was ISPs
saying
we want to offer you filtering parental
filtering protect your kids or even more
sophisticated filtering and we can do
this at our cursors if we know who's
making those queries similarly CDNs
argued that if we know where you are
located geographically we can divert you
to your nearest server and you will get
great streaming and your cat videos will
never bother again isn't that wonderful
aren't we doing you a great customer
service so this all sounds great and
people sign up for it what they don't
realize is what this means in practice
so the way the user identification
worked is that your ISP would give you a
Rooter and very often that Russa would
add into the DNS queries as they came
out of your home network information
about you that might be a MAC address in
some cases it was observed that it was
usernames or user IDs something unique
and that meant they could do their
filtering at recursive but it also meant
that anybody who is passively monitoring
that link could immediately correlate
all those queries with the activities of
individuals behind that router so that
could allow not only for identification
of individuals but tracking of
individuals as well in a very similar
manner the way the client subnet worked
was that there was an implementation in
the recursive that said well we know who
sent us this query pick up the subnet
and send that up to the authoritative so
it can figure out their geolocation but
again this is leaking information to
anybody passively monitoring that link
up the authoritative again creating
correlations within the data with the
activity of users or groups of users so
what this really means is even when
you're sat at home you're behind in that
and you think you've got anonymity you
don't necessarily and even though you're
behind a recursive only think you've got
anonymity you don't necessarily and both
of these were done originally with
non-standard options some of them are
now coming through the standards process
but there really wasn't anything to stop
organizations doing this because people
happy to sign up to the services which
sounded
eight and as dkg alluded to the kind of
cruise you do reveal quite a lot about
you on both of these legs so I don't
know about me but I'm at home before I
came here I was looking up what
conference I was going to what hotel I
was staying a hat with flights I was
taking so this reveals an awful lot
about me including how distracted I can
get when I'm trying to put a big slide
deck together and what site so go
wandering off ting but this is all
information they can correlate back to
me so I hope at this point I've got your
spidey senses tingling with the idea
that there's all sorts of stuff going on
in the DNS that you don't necessarily
know about an end user even if you're
quite technically aware to take this
another step further so we've looked at
the kind of leakages you get on DNS
queries that are in flight this is
thinking about them at rest so you have
a recursive resolve that you're using so
you have to stop considering who are the
people who have authorized access to the
data there to what's been blogged about
all the queries coming in what's third
parties are they sharing it with what
legal commitments do they have to gather
data on users equally what are the risks
of unauthorized access to that data how
solid is the security could there be
breaches and also those concerns will
change as you move around different
curses so as you're at home at at work I
should rent a coffee shop as you're in a
hotel so and these are things that
people aren't necessarily aware of
equally those concerns extend up to the
authoritative because as you can see
information can make it up to that level
about the activity of individuals so
those are the sort of salient points
about DNS data leakage there are an
awful lot of complications I want to
just touch on one here which is
something which particularly lately has
become more active and that's Dennis
filtering so this is happening a country
level and isp level organizational level
and its activities whereby people
running recursos will have a black list
of sites they don't want people to get
to and they will actually tell Dina
in order to block access to those sites
again this is trying to be done for the
greater good keep you away from websites
infected with malware etc although
accidentally some other sites get
blocked every now and again that you
might want to get to like Google this
has happened by accident um but the
thing to think about is if you are using
a recursive it engages in this kind of
behavior with these black lists how
likely do you think they are to track
users who trigger their black blocking
do to try to access one of these
blacklisted sites even if you do it by
accident so this table tries to
summarize the hotspots in terms of DNS
data liquid leakage in terms of what's
happening on the wire and at rest and
I'll come back to this later and show
you where we are in terms of tackling
this so that's a picture in classic DNS
as you know it I want to spend just a
little bit of time talking about
something which is called dns service
discovery so this happens within local
networks and the mechanisms used can be
regular DNS constrained to that local
network or it can be multicast DNS what
this does is essentially the procedure
whereby a device can advertise some
services that it is willing to make
public and other devices can discover
those services and use them and this is
really cool because it means you can do
stuff like file sharing photo sharing
all sorts of stuff directly over the
network and that's nice and most of the
services that utilize this are secure
the problem comes in advertising those
services now I can see a whole bunch of
max here and I know that if you simply
just open find when look in your sidebar
you can probably see a whole load of
devices advertised and I bet a whole
bunch of them have names or identifies
in them and very typically the kind of
thing you might see is something like
this Stuart I was going to add one
pedantic point you said this is on the
local network but it's not it's on the
global network sitting here at the IDF
if you tap the errant button on your
phone it'll do a
rufa appt cebu meeting ITF dog which
will go across the Pacific to Virginia
or wherever the authoritative server is
for IETF dog yeah i was talking just
about the this service advertisement is
typically constrained to thee ah locally
well you're you're in the example of
giving orders dot local its local
multicast yes yeah what i was saying is
when you do it over unicast it's going
over the public internet in the clear
unencrypted every time you tap the air
print button on your phone and print a
document on the terminal room printer
here yeah even though you're printing it
on a printer down the hallway you're
sending a query to the US and back to
ask for the address of that printer
right i mean i'm assuming the
authoritative server for IETF taught
August not isn't this hotel somewhere
else thank you so in terms of
advertising what you're doing here in
leaking information the problem comes
with um the way this information is
advertising the amount of detail it
contains so for example you might quite
easily see this kind of information
advertised from an individual user and
you think well okay so what they want to
share this stuff they're willing to make
it public but think about what you've
learned about Alice just from this
information if you're in a very small
room and say they're only handful of
females and only one has a laptop open
then suddenly you've got a really good
idea of who Alice actually is you also
know that she's got two devices and you
know she's willing to share photos and
that she uses a chat application that
supports presence so not only do you
know a bit about her but what you've got
is a fingerprint here so you can see
this fingerprint as it moves around
networks and that means you've got user
tracking capabilities and this goes
beyond tracking user it can go deep dive
into exposing information about for
example when you advertise these
services you also often advertised
attributes about them so for example
which ports they use which part it says
you they use lots of details
and intelligent attackers it has been
shown can actually use this to determine
things like which software version you
are running and therefore that means
they might be able to detect known
exploits in unpatched software similarly
they can actually dive right down to
specific devices if they have enough
information so again this is leakage of
personal information that non-technical
users are probably very unaware of and
even technical users might not
understand the full gravity of okay so
what I wanted to do quickly was just say
okay so back then if he were savvy to
dinner perfectly being a problem what
were your choices at the time there were
a couple of things available DNS curve
was around for a little while Dena
script was developed and is still around
there are a number of implementations so
and in fact OpenDNS offer that as a
mechanism when you use their resolvers
and what I do want to spell out though
is that the real motivation behind these
mechanisms was authentication of the
information exchanged between clients
and servers so it was about anti
spoofing and anti dosing and the privacy
benefits largely came as a side effect
because crypto is used to achieve that
these weren't first and foremost privacy
mechanisms to protect users also
although these were documented neither
actually made it to through the
standards process other things that
people were doing some people chose to
run local resolvers on their machines
and the main aim here was to bypass
those intermediate recursos so you
weren't exposing your data to them it
doesn't solve the whole problem because
you're then exposing your client address
directly to the authoritative but some
people felt this was a better choice
than using an intermediate worker sir
also what came out around this time was
a total dns trigger now again the
motivation for this was to enable DNS
SEC on an end-user computer and the
privacy aspects were a byproduct but
what it did was it used as a last ditch
to tempt DNS over TLS
port 443 but what this did mean is there
was an implementation of encrypted DNS
out in the wild that some users were
able to monopolize and use for their own
ends to do private DNS even at this
early stage so having talked about the
historical context of this I wanted to
move on and talk about what's been
happening in the most in the recent
years so when the main places this work
has happened is the deprived working
group and this was created in 2014 in
the wake of the Snowden revelations and
the desire by the IETF to mitigate
monitoring through protocol design now
this had no small task before it you're
talking about taking the DNS which has
been a bass rock of the internet for
30-some years and worked in largely the
same way for all those 30-some years and
what you have to magically do sprinkle
it with a layer of privacy with minimal
impact and try not to disrupt the
internet while you do it so where do you
start well this was a big problem and
what the working group decided in its
initial charter was to focus solely on
the stub to recursive and step of this
and there are various reasons for this
two are summarized are one is that that
stub to recursive stage leaks the most
information so if you can tackle that
you're going a long way towards helping
and users secondly the recursive to
authoritative stage is quite challenging
when you come to think about how you're
going to do authentication of
connections in that environment and the
reason is this if you're an end-user you
your relationship with recursive
services is one to a few you have the
one use at home work when you're out and
about but generally you either have a
relationship with that recursive
resolver all you make a conscious choice
to use it by going through a captive
portal or joining a network whatever
whereas if you're a recursive server
your job is to talk to all and any
authoritative servers that you need to
in order to resolve a name that you have
been asked for and many
you may never ever have talked to you
before so that makes authenticating the
one too many unknowns difficult so think
of this a little bit like your phone
contacts compared to your Twitter
followers who do you know best so the
first thing that the working group did
has it decided to enumerate the problem
space and it produced RFC 7626 now this
is highly recommended read it basically
goes through the kind of situations that
I talked about in the first part of the
discussion here today but in much more
detail and also goes through other cases
of leakage so that's really worth
looking at to understand the details of
what's going on I'm really keeping that
this document does though is it robots
the alleged public nature of the DNS and
the distinction it makes is that yes the
data in the DNS might be public but an
individual DNS transaction is not and
should not be public so to use the same
example as earlier and this is actually
directly taken from this RFC the website
for Alcoholics Anonymous is public the a
record for that is public the fact that
you as an individual do the DNS requests
to get that record is not and should not
be public that is your personal data so
that's a really clear idea to keep in
your mind as we move forward so having
established the problem we now start
looking at solutions and there were
various ones that could have been looked
at and some of the well-known
technologies some dns specific solutions
were offered as well and drafts on all
of these came forward to the working
group at the time the ones that got
really serious consideration with these
three starts here less initially seemed
very attractive it could be done on port
53 it could be incrementally deployed it
was a known technique that was all nice
on downside though obviously the
negotiation can be susceptible to a
downgrade attack that negotiation can
also introduce latency and l word
dear folks really don't like and there
was also sort of big question mark about
hang on there's all these Reuters that
get DNS traffic on port 53 are they
certainly going to freak out if they
start seeing encrypted traffic and just
block it Oh again I have real deployment
problems here it was an unknown so if
discussion moved on to looking at doing
TLS or detail s over a brand new port if
we could get one now if we could TLS is
you know a very well-known technology
there's a lot of implementations it's
quite widely deployed so that was
attractive there was some concerns about
scalability of it if you try and use it
within the DNS and then in some ways you
might want to look at detail s and say
well isn't that a more natural solution
for DNS because it's UDP based and
initially it you might think that
however it runs into the same problem
that UDP does and the reason there's
this scattering of tcp around which is
that if the answer to a DNS query is too
big to fit within the MTU then the
server has to indicate the client it
needs to retry over TCP because you can
send that large response over TCP the
same problem happens over dtls if the
response won't fit in the packet the
server cannot send the whole response
and it has to request the client to
retry over another mechanism when you're
dealing with privacy that means if you
want to maintain privacy you have to use
another protocol like TLS all you have
to completely sacrifice your privacy and
retry over clear text so the upshot of
that was that detail s couldn't be a
standalone solution to DNS previously
you had to do dns over TLS regardless if
you wanted a deployable solution so in
that case it meant we had to revisit
what's going on with dns and tcp i mean
some people sort of shocked shocked to
find the tcp is even used for dns at all
but it was but none such a great way and
the reason was a historical one it was
that clients took the easy route and
if they were doing lots of UDP queries
and they got this signal to say you need
to retry over TCP they would do one shot
over TCP and then go straight back to
UDP and that was the pattern that
clients implemented across the DNS so on
the server side the service we're all
sitting there going well I don't really
have to worry about TCP I'm going to get
one query you know every now and again
so servers had very basic TCP
capabilities operators didn't routinely
worry about tuning for TCP or a bust us
against TCP attacks so you know it's
sort of in some ways at this point
treated as a second-class protocol oh
sorry Lykos in fact I'm completely wrong
side ok so we will have to go and deal
with tcp / TLS implementations at a
later point in time another problem that
we will have to deal with is
authentication so what do most other
protocols do when they want to
authenticate something hmm they do a DNS
lookup first so we're gonna have to get
around that in the DNS the other thing
to worry about is some really
interesting work that was done on
traffic analysis and what this showed
was great go ahead and crypt your DNS
that's fine but if I'm observer and I
can see both sides are recursive then I
can see lots of messages I can still
figure out how big they are and I can
still see the timing correlations
between them which means with a bit of
work I can still do juice a whole bunch
of stuff about what individual users are
doing so just encrypting the traffic is
not enough to obfuscate that so you need
to consider options that can defeat that
kind of traffic analysis okay so top of
that list was guessing you port how easy
is that well it turns out if you have a
really solid use case which this was
it's pretty easy we asked and we got
fantastic so a year ago poor 853 was
assigned for use for encrypted dns who
are
next problem deal with this issue with
DNS over TCP to enable DNS over TLS so
this wasn't an insurmountable problem it
was really just a question of
engineering so what do we do well we
throw the kitchen sink at it or you know
as matt damon might said we need to
science the hmm out of this so what we
do is you look at all the techniques
that are used in all the other protocols
that use these and you make sure to
introduce them into the DNS space in the
standards so for example when DNS
clients and servers are setting up
connections you need to make sure that
they're using techniques like fast open
session resumption and you want to have
a really close eye on till s 1 point 3
because that's going to do good things
in terms of reducing latency for setting
up these connections when you set the
connections up you want to stop this
behavior of one shot tcp you want to
recommend that clients wants to have a
connection open they pipeline their
queries over it not waiting for
responses just send them that when the
server gets them it actually processes
them concurrently not see really and
that when it gets the responses it sends
them as soon as it gets it now that will
sounds really obvious but that is not
what dn.m implementations have done
historically so work was done to ensure
that in the standards this was how
implementations should mature moving
forward you'll also note there's a
persistent connections are see here
until last year there was no standard
way for a DNS client and a dealer server
to agree that they wanted to do
persistent tcp it just wasn't there and
spec it is now also in terms of managing
TCP connections on a DNS server then
there's this huge amount that we can
just learn from the HTTP world these
guys have been doing it for a long time
and not just HTTPS
the other type of Tokyo 28 so Jake 58
edina subtilis it is thank you yeah
keep-alive is 28 isn't it thank you very
much apologies I'm fast okay um it's
been youtubed yes yeah sorry so there's
a correction to the RFC number for
persistent connections it should be 78
28 Thank You Stuart chatter okay and
this was just a little bit of
illustration of sort of bad in sotc p
versus good dns over tcp which is where
we want to be okay so having done some
work on that we now move on to
authentication the work that's going
through deep right at the moment has
attempted to present two profiles in
order to clarify to users what security
they can expect when they use one of
these two profiles because this is kind
of a new idea to DNS users so at the
moment what specified are two profiles
strict an opportunistic so the strict
profile is one where as a client you
decide that if I'm going to do Dennis I
want to get an encrypted connection and
I want to authenticate my server and if
I can't do both those things then I am
not prepared to compromise my privacy so
I just won't do doing this resolution
and I can't get to the internet but that
is somebody saying my privacy is more
important than my connectivity and
that's a choice to make as a user so
it's kind of a purist take on if you
like I like to think of it as a kind of
Jedi way of doing this I've let the
words of Master Yoda described the
philosopher here and whereas the
opportunistic profile is much more
pragmatic it's I really like the idea in
its privacy and I think it's important
i'm going to try every mechanism i can
to do it but at the end of the day i am
willing to go to clear text in order to
get connectivity and again that's just a
usage profile for users to make
depending on what they
that are important in terms of exposing
their dns queries when they use the
internet so hopefully this is something
we're opportunistic is a stepping stone
to everybody being enabled to do strict
and it's not an issue but that's
something for us to determine as we roll
this out so how do you do this
authentication well right now there are
two ways specified one that starts off
from a domain name and one that starts
off from an SP ki pin set now if you're
out there you're thinking okay these are
doing as folks and not these the folks
that tell every other protocol if you
want to do authentication you should be
using Dane so shouldn't we be kind of
eating our own dog food here well yes so
we do specify how to do authentication
by day but a really interesting idea
came out of the work on this because
you've got DNS servers involved in this
interaction so this is a very quick
demonstration of how it would work using
kind of classical Dane so you start from
a DNS client that has DNS SEC validating
capabilities you can figure it with a
domain name and IP address and one of
the bootstrapping problems here is that
it may need to do opportunistic so not
necessarily encrypted lookups to get
that information to start with again at
this point I don't have a connection to
a privacy server so if I want to get
those damn records that also has to be
opportunistic so probably we encrypted
but not Senta cated but I need to go off
and talk to some resolver and get those
records once I have those records I can
used in a sec to validate them say I'm
good to go then the client can start the
dl stls connection get the credentials
from server validate them and dns
resolution can start the alternative
mechanism is one using something called
the TLS DNS SEC chain extension and this
is a draft which is currently
through the TLS working group what this
does is it starts from exactly the same
point but it shifts the responsibility
for getting those Dane records onto the
day and its privacy server because after
all it's a DNS server it should know how
to get them and it should it can
prefetch them and it can cash them or it
can get them on demand in this case once
that server has the records the client
can then in the client hello indicate
that it supports this new extension tip
the tea LSD in a sec ascension so hey
server I I know all about this new
extension do you hmm yes I do here have
my Dane records in the server hello
along with my credentials have at them
client goes fine lovely okay first up
I'm going to validate your Dane records
with doing a sec because I'm a father
dating client I can do that next up I
validate your credentials against them
and off we go dns resolution begins
because the beauty of this is that all
that happened inside the TLS handshake
in this case so what you avoid is the
latency of those separate lookups by the
client and you also remove the need for
a separate resolver that can provide the
dane records so the streamlines the
whole process okay so on this slide I'm
just presenting where D prive is today
in terms of the documents it has in the
solution space for the stub to recursive
part of the problem so in May of this
year 78 58 got it right that was
published which is a specification for
DNS over TLS alongside that 7830 was
published which is the ed and a serum
mechanism so that you can pad a DNS
query by an amount and there's more
follow-up work to talk there about what
algorithms to use to pad that but at
least we have the basic mechanism in
place there's also a draft going through
the working group which is completed
working group last call to specify DNS
over TLS
and there's a separate draft which is in
working group last call to specify all
the details of the authentication maxims
that I touched on earlier so this is
pretty good work for two years of a
working group I think hats off you know
this wasn't an easy problem and a lot of
progress has been made so what next now
we have to start biting the bullet and
thinking about the recursive to
authoritative problem and in fact the
working group is meeting this Friday
here in Seoul and one of the agenda
items is the recharter discussion how do
we move forward from where we are to
tackle this there is a draft available
and what that attempts to do is
enumerate six options for how to do that
authentication between them curses and
the authoritative and that's also going
to be discussed in the working group
there's also quite a desire to get some
data from the experience of what it
really means to do DNS over TLS on
Stubbs recursive and feed that into
information about how to do that
recursive to authoritative as well
because this is new territory one thing
I do want to touch on is that okay we
don't have an encryption solution for
recursive to authorities yet but what
came out of the dns up working group is
a nice piece of work you know
minimization so we go back to this
picture earlier where the bad idea fairy
said leak all your information and we
come along with an idea from the better
idea fairy who says well no you don't do
that just send what you need to and stop
leaking information now this looks
totally trivial and it's not quite
there's some really icky corner cases in
this when you have to go following see
names and the like but the good news is
those are being solved in
implementations and this is now being
rolled out in some the major open-source
name server implementations today so i
got this slide up here and this is to do
with the day to handling and honestly i
think this is the area that has had the
least attention and probably has the
least progress and needs to be somewhere
with
kissing now um I mean so I could start
by saying hands up who in this room has
read the small print of the ISP contract
and knows exactly what their isp does
with their DNS data Alan I'm not one of
them say wow you'll have lives that's
great so that's a thing and we're the
kind of people who should really know
and care about that so what we need to
be doing here is looking at more it
needs to be done so for example
government policy and practice in terms
of surveillance and data sharing
particularly in like some recent
political events we might all want to be
thinking about this headset also what
you really want is much more
transparency from users and providers
about what are they doing with a data
why is it in small print why isn't it up
front and easy for you to find out
similarly okay if you have to keep data
do everything you can to do identify it
you can still do a lot with the data but
but in terms of certainly academic
exercises where you try and collect data
day in the life of the internet and the
like there needs to be thought given to
D identifying that data to protect users
a very quick note on a couple of topics
here um so DNS over HTTPS has actually
been around for a while non-standard but
used there's a really good review of why
it was used and some of the motivations
well one was privacy it brings that with
it others were bypassing middle box
interference others were exposing
high-level api's but this is kind of
gathering a bit of momentum so it's not
actually being positioned as a
previously solution first and foremost
it's much more a new technology and
their address to specify how to do this
Google is actually offering a DNS over
HTTPS service using a sort of
non-standard implementation but there's
actually now a non-working Vic mailing
list and there's going to be a buff on
Tuesday night on this topic so if you
interested in this side of things I'd
encourage you to go so this is the
matrix that I showed earlier where what
we're trying to show is the current
mitigations that we have for those hot
spots so recursive to us two story stub
to recursive we have encryption and
authentication today for recursive to
authoritative we have the mitigation of
kino minimization and we're working on
the encryption and it's just recognizes
that the error of data policies is
something we really need to be working
on and also to mention that there is a
draft to solve the DNS SD problem that's
been adopted by the working group so
there's progress in this area as well so
to quickly move on to implementation
status so i just want to show these very
briefly just to show that there is
activity in the uptake of the new
standards within dns so these are three
well-known open-source dns nameservers
other implementations are available i
should stress I've just chosen three to
illustrate it but there's work in all of
these on the new standards that are
happening the purple box in front of
bind is there because at the moment the
approach of the buying folks is not to
put tier less directly into the name
server rather what there and proposing
is using a TLS proxy in front of a name
server and there are lots of technical
reasons this makes sense and there are
lots of one's available so this is
certainly a viable way to do it I'm on
the stub side most of the energy and
effort has been expended over the last
few years towards get dns and i'll talk
about that a little more on the next
slide and you'll notice some emission
notable emissions from this in terms of
deployed and used at libraries and
that's a real challenge in terms of
getting new features into those
libraries so essentially there's uptake
of this as implementations I've Dennis
of TLS we're waiting for an
implementation of Dennis every TLS
that'll be good to add to the mix
and bii has a DNS over HTTP
implementation that's available as well
so to talk about what's deployed and
what's actually out there there are a
handful of test servers available today
that are up and running to start on
getting operational experience that how
you do DNS over TLS so and on that labs
are running 10 our car running one as a
few hosted by surf net dkg the man has
put one up there and so these are there
to start doing activities there's a
question marking its ITF because we've
sort of started exploratory talks about
well maybe the next ITF could offer a
privacy server maybe this one even I'm
getting faces from Warren I won't ask
that but but that would be a nice step
just to offer that so people can get
experience and if you want to know the
details of these servers they're at a
web page under that link so in order to
use those servers you need some client
software that will connect to them and
what has been being developed over the
last few years is based around get dns
so if you're not familiar with it get
dns is a modern asynchronous dinner
second abled api bunch of information at
the website what it does do is it
already implements DNS over TLS and it
is already a natively validating DNS SEC
client stub so it takes two boxes in
terms of enabling privacy so what has
recently been developed in the last
release is a new mode of using get dns
which is called stubby this is the
mascot for it sergeant stubby i'll let
you google him if you're interested
basically what stubby does is it runs as
a demon on your machine you point your
OS DNS resolution to localhost stubby
listens on local host picks up your
queries and sends them out of the
internet over TLS protecting your
privacy you can configure it for our
configuration file in that file you can
set up all the name servers that you
need you can specify
the authentication information you might
want to use you can specify which of
those two profiles do you want to do
stricter opportunistic this is all
configurable there's a web page on how
to build stubby configure it and use it
and if anybody's interested in actually
getting hands-on with this then come and
find me or William turret or Alison
mankan who are busy hacking at the
moment in the hackathon but any of us
would be happy to give you a tour of
this so that's the simple configuration
file and if you really care you can set
it up to do minimal logging and you can
actually watch it as it feeds your DNS
queries out over to us connections and
see the behavior of those up streams as
it answers your queries so just to
mention what's still ongoing at the
moment as I mentioned have been a lot of
work in hacking on this weekend we're
doing a lot of interrupt testing between
stubby and some of these upstream
service so we're hopefully maturing this
and making it much more usable a
challenge that I haven't really touched
on much is that of integrating not only
study but other client solutions into
os's making them accessible making them
usable for users and this face is very
similar challenge to do in a sack in
that respect so hopefully we can learn
something from that we need your
completeness in the recursive
implementations more deployment and
obviously there's still the recursive to
authoritative work to tackle so to
summarize I hope I've convinced you that
DNS privacy is is a real problem and
it's relevant problem as well one we
need to be thinking about and working on
that there is active work but this is a
large loose and space there isn't gonna
be an overnight solution but that work
is in progress and that there are tests
implementations out there that you can
use today if you're interested and there
are more privacy services and more
solutions on the way also I think in the
very near future the public awareness of
this is going to continue increasing
after all edward snowed and got
hollywood film out of this so people are
aware of the problem are thinking about
it and I do have her
that one day there might be an IDF the
movie to recognize all the folks here
all have braces and all the implementers
fighting the good fight to defeat vasive
monitoring and that that will happen one
day and casting suggestions for that
movie will be very gratefully received
in the bar later on so with that I will
thank you for your time I will point you
at a survey monkey website at as I have
been instructed to buy the edu team if
you can give feedback on this that would
be great and thank you very much I'd be
happy to take any questions lorenz are
clearly not sadly not dns specific so
for as long as s and I exist this is all
in vain right yeah so um d can he take
it away to fix that you came in you came
in late um so leaky boat you missed I
hardly use all of leaky boat okay yeah
so what was it how do you fix yellow
leak so that's not something to be can
fix in the DNS there are a couple of
possibilities I tried to get that into
TLS 1.3 and I got pushed back from some
large server operators that didn't want
to incur an extra round trip which is
understandable so it's not going to be a
automatic in TLS 1.3 at any rate so we
have there's a couple of possibilities
that would allow s and I cover traffic
basically and I'm not going to go into
that right now because I think usually
people with questions about the DNS but
I'm happy to talk with you afterwards
and if anyone has other specific ideas
about tina's taylor says and I I don't
hear him also this is not just for TLS
so right generate I just happened have
wandered in off the street Shara I
wanting to introduce a leonine question
here have you had any conversations with
any of the data protection authorities
about whether this DNS query traffic
would be considered as personal data or
not not direct ones and also that's
going to vary country by country I mean
that's a huge issue
and I'm not sure it's for necessarily
for us protocol folks to time travel I
think that goes up a level to an
organizational question what has been
remarked is that it would be quite
interesting if these there's uptake in
terms of this test servers and it's
observed that DNS traffic is being
retained encrypted and how certain
monitoring authorities might react to
that in terms of exact outfit occasion
of personal data I don't know that's an
unanswered question I'm just thinking
this memory to help with optic of these
technologies once the big become more
widely accepted and widely deployed and
there's also should probably where
there's a lot of operators particular
the European Union a very concerned
about data retention and all those other
considerations so stuff like DNS query
traffic is already an issue for them so
if there's a reason which that problem
can be can be minimized from their point
of view by using some of these office
keys and technologies that could also be
a good thing but the message didn't have
to be coming from things like the data
protection authorities disease we can
serve this personal data you need to
start taking things much more sisa by
how you treat than handle that data yeah
and I i agree i think that's that's an
error that hasn't received as much
attention as it should have and
certainly will need to in future thank
you any other questions nope right click
thank you very much again I think that's
a wrap everybody come to the deep-fried
working group on friday come to deprive
and help us figure out what to do next i
think the the HTTP the dns server HTTP
buff is i think tuesday
I was asking what times on the team this
maybe he said Tuesday I don't know which
tuesday thank you for the thank you for
this crap season