so I thought we'll take pictures in the
end zone leave you only they send me an
email all right so this is the I RTF
open meeting in Seoul can I ask you guys
that you keep the doors closed because
the noise is really distracting Matt
yeah bar the doors all right um this is
the IIT fip our policy it's basically
the same one as the IETF IPR policy
meaning with you make a contribution you
are required to disclose any IPR that
you hold or that a organization that you
work for holds that you know have
personal knowledge of and we request
that you file other IPR and
contributions that you know about so you
should know all this if you don't you
should really read it the slides are
uploaded my slides were very late so
apologize for that but they're up now
you can dial in remotely you probably
figured this out already we have two
mailing lists one is an announced list
um that sees very little traffic
basically when you RFC's get published
and new group start and stop there's a
discussion list that sees also very few
traffic because nothing much gets
discussed that is I ITF wide um most of
it is on the individual research group
lists today we have the usual like five
to ten minutes of me telling you what
has happened in the last couple months
followed by the two main events which
are the applied networking research
prices these are the last two prizes for
2016 we had six in total because we had
a pretty large number of submissions arm
and the 2017 selection is actually going
on at the moment um maybe a little bit
more about this later um so where are we
we have ten research groups meeting
which is a lot we have 11 charted right
now so almost all of them are media
meeting except for Gaia including a new
one which is
RG measurement analysis for protocols
and we have a proposed network machine
learning working group meeting that'll
be their last meeting as a proposed
group and after this me and Ellison who
is going to succeed me will sit down and
decide whether we want to charter them
formally or whether they have run out of
runway you are in the RTF open meeting
on Thursday morning the IAB reviews one
of the research groups traditionally
during each meeting this time it's the
human rights protocol considerations
group which had a meeting earlier today
which was very interesting out here I
wasn't there bit more nap RG since it's
a new group right so this is you can
think of this if you're been around long
enough this is the second iteration of
the imrg the internet measurement
research group so the idea is that
there's a lot of measurement efforts
going on in academia but also outside
but but the results are not really
widely used to you know dr engineering
and and the ideas to bridge that gap so
there's a lot of things that are in
scope here that are listed in these
bullets they're going to have a meeting
later on the last few meetings that they
had as a proposed group of very
interesting so i have sort of high hopes
that they keep up the history of
interesting presentations that I've
managed to invite we have a new addition
to these slides that i'm going to do
from that one until I stepped on march
which is called research group news so
far we have one news item unless there's
something in my inbox that i missed the
HRP seated i just mentioned human rights
protocol considerations they have their
first draft going into last call next
week it'll be a long last call and they
asked for wide reviews and it's an
interesting document because it's no not
very technical but it is you know
interesting in that it makes
observations about how protocol design
can impact fundamental human rights so
in it it is broadly applicable to
basically everything we do in the IR ITF
an idea so if you have nothing better to
do on the flight home it's
so good it's a good read and send
needles on the guys feedback we have an
IR TF RFC stream it is not quite as busy
as the IETF stream but we did manage to
publish for rfcs since the last meeting
three of which came from the
information-centric networking research
group and one came from Gaia their first
document and a few more in the queue
from various other research groups so
probably going to see a few more by
Chicago these are the four that were
published um you know research
challenges nice en video streaming over
IC and security considerations for ACN n
gaya has a tech sauna me doc youment on
alternative network deployments which is
actually an interesting read last time I
said that the IB wanted feedback on the
candidates for I RTF chair studying
March 2017 you've sent feedback that was
very helpful to the IAB in making a
decision the selection was Alison
Mencken who is not really a newbie um
but will take up this role there's a
little bio there that those of you in
the first row can probably even read
very happy with the selection thank you
for volunteering and I hope you have a
good time I had a good time she's
sitting up there if you wanna meet her
later on all right um we have two things
that start with a polite networking
research one is the workshop and one is
the prize this is about the workshop um
so the URL is wrong because I copied us
from Berlin so it should be 2017 there
so we're doing this again we did the
first one in Prague we're doing one in
2017 so this is a academic peer-reviewed
workshop it's it's technically
co-sponsored by ACM sigcomm we have to
tpc chairs for next year which are
Renata Teixeira and your Cod um they're
both on the sitcom Executive Committee
which tells you a little bit that sikkim
actually takes this as important
proceedings are open access and the plan
is or the we will co-locate us with
TF in Prague it will be on the Saturday
before the ittf meeting in Prague it's a
full day event the call for papers
should be out soon probably still this
year i'm guessing the submission
deadline will be somewhere in the
februari time frame maybe march on peer
review takes a month so notifications
probably April May it's it's an
interesting event so if you even if you
don't send anything in you should maybe
think about attending it you can look on
the web page for the 2016 meeting to see
what the papers and presentations were
armed it was a pretty successful event
so if you are in Prague on Saturday
because you wanna arrive early to get
rid of the jet lag before the craziness
starts come to this the second thing
that starts the plight networking
research is the prize we've been doing
this for five years now so this should
not be new anymore it's together with I
sock we had 53 nominations for 2016
which is the largest ever for 2017 the
nomination period just ended and I think
we have 4d but one was a double
nomination so we have 39 that entered
this election um the lumber is slightly
lower but I think the quality based on
what I've seen glancing through
submissions is is easily as high as it
was this year so I'm expecting we're
going to have again a very tough
decision to pick a few of these for the
prize selection committee is some mighty
effort some irt efforts and by now we've
also added a few of the usually senior
professors from the awarded papers over
the last few years and I think we're
going to keep doing that arm so that we
actually have academic representation on
the committee specifically from those
sort of people that seem to have
successfully done interesting research
in the past also they can help us pick
the next crop and part of the award is
the talks that are going to follow this
and i should say comcast is again
extended to sponsor this for I don't
know how many years were committed but
at least at least one year so thank you
very much if other
organizations would like to support the
ni p met fort from i sock will be super
thrilled to talk to you you might even
buy you a beer or something but but all
kidding aside right so this helps us
because there is a cost associated with
this because it's a travel grant to come
here it's potentially a second repeat
invitation right so a lot of the
prizewinners actually go on and
participate regularly and and part of
the prizes that if you start to get
engaged we bring you back a second time
even without a talk and without an award
and that has happened actually i think
we had 26 um winners up until today oh
no what 28 now but 26 of them 11 came
back on Isaac money and 13 came back on
their own dime so there is quite a sort
of good history of pulling people in
through the price and and the
sponsorship helps us bring the people
back right so with two talks um both of
them are or used to be student from
Olivia Bonaventure which is pretty
impressive so here's a two prizes going
to you see Lavar graduates if I see that
right so congrats I guess to do to the
group and and even more impressively
deck on completely different topics one
as well Tea Party CBD other one is
routing so that is also very interesting
so one is for flipping I think that's
the one we go first and the second one
is a application control for a multipath
TCP so congratulations before we go to
the talks is there anything that people
want to bring up sort of irt FY is in
general or is there any chair here that
send me email about and news update that
i didn't put in because i didn't read my
email in the last hour going once going
twice alright twice is enough alright so
Olivia first and I will make this big
angle normally isn't any way to get this
bigger I'll be like that no yeah i did
slideshow but then there's also a way to
zoom it's still right oh ah thank you
all right anything else you want me to
press or touch oh it doesn't work okay
um is it the right one because there
were two yes okay it worked earlier so
let's try again are you going to the
right okay maybe the battery ran out um
tell me next slide right hi I'm I live
here I'm from best week into the
microphone yeah sorry really close is it
better hi I'm Olivia I'm from Belgium
from you Silva supervise but yet another
review and this is joint work with
Stephanie avicii Shore van bebber and
Jenny 4x4 whoo well I've worked as at
least I serves me you can see so we'll
talk about fibbing so some people
yesterday told me is disciplined yes it
is you can switch to the next one and so
we call this fitting because we want to
lie to the rotors to control their fib
literally so that's as simple as this
and so you will have to skip a lot nope
so to start off to understand what we
mean by this out right before I get
started if you have questions be sure to
just ask them right away that's going to
be easier to follow the rest basically
so if we start with this simple this
simple network so we have while the
usual results icons that are from cisco
and a bit heavy if we switch your next
one it's easier for us as we search or
to just use graphs so note for the
routers with a particular name and edges
yes again switcheroo next one and so in
for routing when you we speak about
interior traffic in introd them in
traffic we use link set a gps typically
such as first pay for sis and these
protocols basically compute and try to
share a the network topology in order to
can switch in order to compute the
shortest path on the graph to for a
traffic in the network so for example
here I had a prefix so some reachability
information advertise on the control
panel on the left and the protocol
managed to compute their shoulders path
32 for the traffic giving the pattern
shown of the right you can switch so and
traditionally with this set of protocols
we have what we call a descriptive
minute descriptive management process so
that is you have the operator maybe you
that has to figure out what he wants to
do you can switch and then that that's
to figure out how to do it so I want to
have this particular policy in my
network I want this set of pass and now
I have a bunch of routers that I need to
configure so I'll provision the
configuration for each of them you can
switch and from there this is a disputed
protocol so we have every router that's
able to independently compute the
shortest path in order to further
traffic as we've done before so they
take some input drive fib and twist and
push them in the line card you can
switch so in the research role there's
been actually quite a lot of interest
over the past few years towards Sen su
software-defined networking so we had
people open flow eight years ago I know
the the new trend the new hot topic is
before
so the wageworks there is that instead
of having a distributed control plane we
have a centralized one so some software
running some when the networks and then
super simple devices like switches for
example you can switch and so in this
management model we have what we call a
declarative management model for the
operators because the operators just has
to think about what he wants the
networks to do and so express
requirements you can switch to this
centralized control plane so let's say
one or two servers that need some
configuration input and this centralized
controller will then to hold the heavy
lifting on its behalf so in this case
compute the part that match the
requirements the five entries that need
to be set up on every single switches
and purge these fit and twist towards
the switches so that's on do it but
there's like a lot of errors well that's
there's one errors that goes to this to
the controller and a lot of errors that
goes out to basically we have a
bottleneck in the network so we have
this huge program that's a single part
of failure and while they are quite a
lot a lot of other challenges it was yet
to be solved you can switch so basically
we have this state-of-the-art in the
sense that we have on the left what's
been major mainly used up to today so
distributed protocols so do is our super
scalable while the internet works today
and we have a BGP routing table that has
over 600,000 prefixes I think these
numbers speak for themselves these are
fairly robust I mean usually you have
access to the internet and it works and
on the other hat on the other side we
have at the end with a lot of all the
promises like it's easier to manage
because they just want centralized
controller it's more flexible because
we've we've opened flowable for example
to do more than just destination base
forwarding you are not restricted
anymore to plain shoulders by floating
because that's what the device supports
you you do have some gains there but you
can switch but yeah this can we have a
price and so the focus of this work is
well we are looking what's in between
these two so we are trying to find a bit
of a middle ground approach you can
switch which we call fibbing a
and where we aim to be as manageable and
close to as flexible as pure as the in
solutions but we still want to be able
to scale properly and to be robust to
failures so for example if you take the
SD in wonder easier the easiest failure
to understand is you lose the controller
where nothing happens anymore the switch
is under table to recover some themself
you use on a GP you break a router while
all the others are able to take over you
can switch and so that's what we that's
what we are going to cover today which
is well how do we get to make this
fitting this architecture that's a bit
in media in between these two paradigm
in the network go ahead so we start from
the same basic idea in a sense that we
want to be as manageable as sdn so we
have a centralized control plane a
control program a single interface for
the operators but we still want to keep
the distributed aspect of the control
plane for scalability and with your
business concerns you can switch so in
this particular model we have the
operator that same as far as en just
expressed some requirements to the
controller so it's easy for him it just
has to state what he wants and doesn't
need to care how its implemented so the
controller itself will figure out how it
what are the paths that need to be set
in the network in order to implement
these requirements you can skip and then
we want to play with this part this
distributed control planes which has
still which for which we still want to
be in charge of programming the flips
basically so we don't want to have or
controller touching each in the
individual hardware so how do we do this
while we use a well-defined Appy API
which is the IGP message themselves so
if we if you think of of SPF these are
the Ellises that you have so these are
in a way some form of API because when
you have our I GPS in the network well
you know that each of them will only be
able to run shortest path computation
but they will do so on a particular
graph that when for this graph is built
by the AGP message that they exchanged
between each other
so if we manage to send submit stage
that we control the intuition here that
we can basically modify the input of the
computation in order to control the
output which is well the set of paths
that are found in a network we can
switch so how does does it work well if
you go back to the sample network we had
before so in this network we would like
the blue the path towards the blue /
ethics to take a different focus to move
around so early on in the network you
add every single path from a be going to
router to towards see and in this case
would like just the blue prefix to go
all the way around so a bit more on the
left in order to select another path for
a single perfect so that's something
you're not you're normally not able to
do with normal a GPS because both
prefixes are reachable through the same
routers and well one of the condition
for GPS to work is that we don't want
loops so we cannot distance run path for
these prefixes but that's what we want
to do in this case let's assume for
example that the brute prefix requires
the traffic to go through a firewall
that's only located on the link between
our running out and r2 so we need to be
able to do this sort of distinction you
can can do it switch sorry so with this
information that's been fed to the
controller by the operator it's going to
figure out what are the modification
that I need to do to the 2d a GP
topology in order to implement this new
path so in this case it decides you can
switch so in this case it decides to
send an 8gb message with some
information to the router closes to
itself so through the AGP adjacency this
is a link-state protocol so this match
this single message that's been sent by
the controller will get flooded
throughout the whole network and even
truly reach every single router in the
network so that's easy for the
controller to speak to anyone it just
has to send it to its closest neighbor
and the protocol will relay the message
for him you can switch and there does
the the figuring path so we've sent a
message asking to create a fake node so
a fake router in the topology that we've
called FA and that also asked to create
a fake link that links this new node
this new router to an existing one so if
you just look at this topology with a
set of weight of link weights that are
on the graph if you do the work from the
control plane you can skip you are able
to compute some new shortest path on the
graph so if you take the shortest path
towards the red / fix while nothing has
changed however if you compute the
shortest path towards the blue prefix
well over all of a sudden you prefer to
use for router a the next step fa so
this new fake note that we've added on
on dhcp topology so that's well that
sounds great like this but that does a
control plan that doesn't tell you
anything about where is the traffic
going this is not a rear rotor it's not
evil connected to a real in physical
interface so that's what enough go to
the next slide so there was a there was
a third line on the adipic on da gb
message which was a physical mapping
between this these fake elements this
fake node it's wiggling attached to the
router a and a real in a real physical
element in this case a r1 so with this
we information we have modified the
control plane topology so we've added a
fake note a fake note with a fake lint
or will to a physical router with speci
we have selected a cost that caused some
new shoulders path to be computed and
then we have some information on what's
the actual physical interface I need to
use to reach that fake node so if you
have if you are able to implement this
kind of features in a routing protocol
well the hope and actually that's the
result we have is that when you switch
from the control plane view to the data
plane to actually measuring the traffic
flows while you see that all of a sudden
you you have different set of paths that
are being used for two prefixes that
share the same egress router so in this
case we've managed to
push to sear away the traffic towards a
blooper ethics / along a path at least
compared to the original situation so
that's a short of a view of what we call
fibbing which is this idea of lying two
routers in this case lying to water a
about a new a new new neighbor that
doesn't exist that should be reachable
with a particular cost and that's
announcing some destination prefixes can
skip there's motive that's there's more
to it so we've started with a single
fake note that we have added on the
graph in order to change to trigger one
next up change we could do it more often
than that you can skip so we've change a
requirement to and we want no to
implement a path that goes from a to R
12 hour 4 and 10 20 to blooper ethics
and so in this case we need to do to
next up changes so we need to go on well
to first cause a to change its net up to
pick a longer and longer path to Egypt
prefix but we can we need to do we're
willing we need our one to do exactly
the same so we can say we can send twice
similar information to add new fake
notes on the graph new fake router on
the graph with chosen cast and cool in
cause you can skip and goes the path to
be constructed and to follow again these
new shortest path that we have on the
control plane and sugar on the data pin
as well there's even more to it so if
added to fake notes on the graph and
well if you think of a network that has
let's say thousand routers if you want
to make a very complex path you probably
don't want to send a thousand ls8 a
thousand sgp messages to go to implement
that particular path so in this case
with a short path and we can simplify it
so by selecting properly the cost that
we use to announce these fake these fake
notes and to link them to the to the
graph we can minimize the number of
message that we sent so this is just an
intuition the arguing's to themself are
rather long but you can go to the next
one but if we take the original graph
that implements the path that we wanted
so the path going over on the Left we
are able to constrict what we call a
reduced topology where we inject the
minimum number of fig fig nodes that
implement the specified requirements by
playing with the cost of the fig note
that are chained together so if you come
if you look yourself on the right you
will see that with the chosen cost only
the routers that are supposed to change
an X up will do so and we'll do it
accordingly to the requirement from the
operator still leaving the path towards
the bird prefix unchanged you can go to
the next one so I've mentioned a Grange
so we have two classes of algorithms we
have one that's super fast that was the
one we use on the left part of the
previous slide which lets us compute
segmented topologies so these typologies
on the control plate side with the new
elements super quickly so to give a
rough approximation on a number on the
network with about 2,000 edges and three
on three hundred routers were able to
compute a rather huge amount of change
in a couple of milliseconds rom two or
three anyway able to reduce heavily the
number of fake note the number of igp
messages that we want to send in a
network in about a second so back
playing with these two algorithm to
gather variable for example to react
quickly to failures so if we see a
failure we are able to compute the new
desired state of the network within
milliseconds and optimize it over the
longer run to reduce the overhead on the
routers can see so we want we set at the
star that we wanted to keep the
desirable properties from the igp so the
fact that this scale a lot to huge
networks and that they are robust to
failures so we still have this we still
using entrada main routing protocol as a
as the basis for control plane so we are
still able to withstand failures if all
of a sudden or controller fails while
network is still working it's still an
energy beer the classical one that
you've been using well to know and we
can do a bit more than this you are able
to implement some form of security
policies such as Phil closed or open so
if the controller fails do I want this
particular traffic flow to still exist
in the network or should it be dropped
because I can no longer in force the
sake of security policies so that's some
benefit that we have because we are able
to centrally controlled a forwarding
state of the network but this is still
with an AGP with the scalability and
robustness benefit and go to next one
and so expressivity wise for the
requirements that the operator is able
to specify to the controller we can
enforce any forwarding dag so any set of
paths that does not create a loop on the
/ destination basis and when we say /
decision basis that's a knight be
perfect so a / 16 / 120 / full / android
and 28 if you're in ipv6 so we have a
resolution that ranges from a single
physical machine to a whole network with
any set of paths without affecting the
others so we believe that's pretty
useful actually and so we have we have a
few use cases that we developed in the
paper and in other labs and so on and
I'll present you one here you can skip
again actually and so in this case we've
built as a demo that we presented a few
month ago where we targeted the issue
with flashcards networks so these sudden
surges of traffic so for example one of
your friend of Facebook so a new video
that is that we really liked shade it to
all of its friend we did the same in
Ovilus all of a sudden you have 10,000
users that all want to use the exact
same video came from the same
geographical area and so hitting roughly
the same CDN and that only lasts for a
couple of in it because when they've
seen the video we're no longer we're no
longer interested in it and so it's
actually super hard to protect against
it however you see want the people to be
able to see that particle video so what
are the solutions if you skip to the
next one well currently operators have
basically not sure no choices
to over provision so it's super hard to
protect against an event on the network
that lasts for a couple of minutes and
probably never happens again so yeah you
buy back bigger pipes and that's all you
can do realistically so we wanted to
look a bit at heard the ability to
program an AGP could help to solve this
issue because the main the main reason
why you cannot really do something more
clever than just over-provisioning here
is that if you want to change the
fighting set of GI GP as of now while
you have to reconfigure all device
independently but now we had the ability
to do it centrally so if you go to next
one and so we build some experiments
while in a controlled environment and so
we had a few videos video servers a few
well a couple of dozen of clients that
all of a sudden wanted to try to get
access to a video to a stream to a video
while to swing this video and we're
monitoring the link codes in the network
and the goal was there to ensure that
every single client was able to actually
view the video without stuttering and so
we actually built the topology that we
have see we had seen before with the
same set of linkers and in that
particular topology if you put the video
servers on the tour if you attach these
to the two routers a and B the 12 that
I've drawn on the right if all of a
sudden you have a lot of clients hidden
behind the same perfect so in the same
residential area that all start to want
to access videos coming from that part
of the network well in this case we have
a bottleneck you have a single path
that's available from a and B towards
see these are the sames while you just
sum up the load over the links if you
get a number of people that's large
enough well you have a huge link
utilization in balance the network or
congestion depending on how big it is
you can skip Sophie being lets us
program paths in the network while
there's an easy fix here so we won't we
see that all of a sudden we have an
increased load over the same central
path while why can't we just spread the
load so link set a GPS
party simply well by default natively so
in this case the goal is well I want to
use multiple paths for example starting
a Trotter be towards rather see well
let's add a new path in the control
plane which has the same cost than the
old one so if you look at the fig Rutter
that's been attached to the router be
it's advertised with a cost of two which
is the same cost than the old PAP you
had which was be all to see so no rotor
be at least on the control plane is able
to compute two different shoulders path
towards the same prefix and so it's
going to try to use both of them even
three resulting in the load spread that
we that we have on the right we can do
more than that if you go to the next one
we can do the same behavior on rotor a
so if we introduce a path of a fake note
that rotor one with a chosen cost that's
reachable from murder a and I got the
best wrong whatever we should be able to
spread the load fairly easily between
well between the two paths that are
available if we do that we're able to
spread the load evenly across two paths
can go to the next one and we can do
even more than that by adding more and
more information on the control plane we
have able for example here to cause an
even load to introduce an evil load
balancing on rotor a so if I had two
different fake notes on rotor one I see
two different IP next stop for water a
and eventually what I have is that I
have I have a splitting ratio on rotor a
that's one further than twofold
resulting in while a much lower overall
link utilization in network if you go to
the next one so we build this experiment
and recorded measurement so busy so we
had initially a single client behind
rotor see trying to access videos on the
first server and over time we gradually
add added moment clients that we're
trying to request video from either of
the two servers eventually congesting
the
neck links so BR to see and so that we
and so we plugged our controller in fed
him with the link Claude measurements
that we had and so over time you started
to add these new equal cross paths so
the path that goes from B to towards r3
to spread the load once that's the first
reduction the first the first drop in
bandwidth consumption that you have on
the graph so at roughly 31 streams and
then again when we started to add more
and more demands from the clients behind
water seeped words the second streaming
service while we added another path
starting at rotture a to decrease again
d / the / link load so if we do this
while we basically were able to increase
the available bandwidth towards rotor
see starting at rotor a and B so a very
congestion in this case and we've been
to do to react like this in milliseconds
if we start over from the idea of flash
crowds in the network well once the
event is done what once people no longer
want to access the content but we can
just remove these extra fake elements
that we had had it previously in the
control plane and so stop using this new
paths so we're able to change the state
of the network quite fast and just to
fix temporarily whatever was happening
based on the policy that we have from
the operators should go to the next one
so I've said that we made an experiment
for that so implicitly this means that
we're able to get to well a working
prototype so we have running code with
something that does this idea of lying
two routers in order to change the next
step selection and so this works using
SPF so we're leveraging some features
found in that particular GP because at
selling set IGP it's actually super easy
for us to bootstrap the controller so we
plug it into a physical router and we
receive the whole topology directly from
the Ellises so that's fairly easier than
with a ZN where you ever have to
reinvent everything from ml EDP to
whatever this topology discovery
protocol you have and we've confirmed
that this work
against cisco iOS Xros an accessory and
journalist well the hardware that we had
so this works again current router
unmodified well we abilities to solve
the use case that wasn't before you can
go to the next one so use specific types
of SPF messages so you have a red ranger
of link set advertisement messages that
are available in ospf and more
importantly we have these two subtypes
the tie 5 and 7 which are which enable a
router to announce the rich rich ability
towards a specific IP prefix but also
mention a given IP next up in the
network and associated to a particular
cost so using this set of message I can
position a fake wrote advertisement
where wherever I want in a network and
select the cost so if I want to do this
I'm actually proximity approximating the
model that we had before and able to
modify the paths that are chosen by
router in the network this know this
before yeah this one this however one
single draw back from this which is the
fact that we don't want yet to modify
the prodigal which is that we've seen on
the previous slides that sometimes we
want to chain to change these fake notes
so we want to trigger multiple next up
changes for the same destination
prefixes so there's one sketch with type
of Alice's is that which is that if you
want to send multiple lacs announcing
rich ability for the same prefix and
don't want these to collide you
basically have to have to provision
several ospf router IDs and so when you
think about the controller that we have
in the network it's actually
multiplexing a lot of visual routers to
generate all the needed router IDs in
order to chain all of this that's one of
the limitation we currently have you the
solution which will see what people
could get for cleaner solution should go
to next one
we've run extensive benchmark also held
by the cisco lab in brussels and so
we've tested this with a hundred
thousand Alice's that were fed to the
routers in order to change to cause
farting changes and basically there was
no impact on the shortest path
computation so this whole process of
sending a GPS sending control in message
to change paths etcetera is basically
for free at least on the controller side
because well that's one of the quirks of
the ospf implementation that's a vector
addition it heats basically no ram on
the routers so 10,000 LSA it's about 10
megabytes of ram so that's close to
nothing and causing triggering one
except change is almost a constant time
at least on the rotors we've measured
and we're able to send which to cause
100,000 next up changes in the fib in
about 90 seconds so that's close to the
nine hundred microseconds per single
next up change that we want to set up so
it's a cliche / fast to do this we are
able to send it to quiet update on the
path to be chosen within milliseconds
and actually have them be implemented
I've mentioned I've started to mention
some of the drawbacks so we using
unmodified ospf well we first of all are
limited but what I space of SPF offers
so we are not yet close to this whole
idea of adding a fake note and then a
destination we kind of have to group
them together and plug them on the
router so if you really look into the
algorithm's while there are different
index passivity models and it's actually
a bit harder to do whatever we want with
pure SPF than what we wanted in practice
practice there's one huge limitation
which is that is PF ranks link set of
the ties meant depending on the on their
type and we'll ignore type five or seven
LSS if it has received another route
toward the same prefix of a preferred
time so literally for example an
intra-day main road so to get this to
work while we had to do some bit of
engineering just
to show that it's feasible into practice
but obviously would like to get
something cleaner in the end and I've
spoken a lot about ospf well that's
because it doesn't work yet we're ice is
so we don't have this ability to send a
message that gives us reach ability
towards an IP prefix given an IP next up
and some metric so there's no way to do
this with Isis as of now if someone has
an idea on how to develop some cleans
some clean slate extension we would be
more and happy to look at that because
that's well we believe there's value to
expand this and make something cleaner
skip to d1 and so just to conclude so
we've started to look at what we could
do with disability to program path na in
nigp and the more we looked at did what
the more were able to do so for example
we've seen that remedy able to modify
path and cost almost independently on
the prefix basis well there are a lot of
protocols that we are on the path and
the curse that are chosen by JP I gp's
for example the BGP decision process has
some criterion that depends on the cost
of the rod so by doing against some
feeling there we are about to control
the output of the BGP decision process
so in order to control a bit what would
be the path chosen by the transit
traffic in my network and make these
vary over time we believe that having
the ability to do this kind of exception
rotting can simplify the configuration
process on the routers because you could
get simpler configuration with a lotta
CCMP new networks example and program
the very specific path that you need for
the proof the few prefixes that recur
special treatments maybe the data
centers the entire data centers traffic
that require a separate path and finally
this ability to program the network
within milliseconds opens at least for
us a new new domain why we are able to
do real-time traffic engineering and so
there is a paper at the upcoming
connects so that's in about a month
that implements optimal traffic
splitting in the network at all times so
that ensure that you are always able to
maximize the link utilization in your
network which is fairly interesting in
which leverage fibbing actually the
closing remarks we have is that we've
built this whole system centered on the
fact that while we have this rotor
sitting in your desk what can we do with
this we've have this formalism of adding
fake notes fake links and playing with
the weights etc is there a better
solution well if you have one we would
welcome it quite a lot and we would
allow to be happy to the question on any
part of this thank you questions and say
your name for the minutes please follow
Matthews so I have 2 comments first of
all your approach looks actually while
they're similar to segment routing have
you I don't know if you've looked at
that or not but it has similar problems
and similar solutions to that so just
the suggestion to investigate that the
second comment is that this approach
works well for certain types of ISPs
what I sort of call the classic ISPs
which run you know take internet traffic
and run it is IP traffic at the core but
there's the sort of the newer class of
ISPs that don't do that anymore they put
them inside l3 VPNs instead okay and
this approach doesn't work for lv VPNs
so so or at least not directly now you
question is then can you modify it so it
actually would work with an l 3 v's day
on it there so there's dew points or the
first one was Sigmund routing yes so
we're actually playing with segments
writing on the side quad a lot more
especially most specifically the ipv6 a
tablet because that's d1 we are able to
implement the internet colonel so we
believe there's different use case for
both so segment rotating requires you to
attach a header a stack of Bibles to
every single
well if you have long lift flow you
might just not want to do it for a
reason or another doing an even load
balancing with Sigma working at least
for the solution we've had a Pinto
yesterday that there's anniversary for
that but in our solution required to do
some stateful load balancing which was
not very stable on the ennos and we are
able to we have this idea of triggering
multiple next up changes Network right
with a single message whereas for
segment version you have to reach out to
every single ingress so that's a
separate part but yeah segment routing
is something we look into it because it
does quite 11 interesting stuff as well
for the l3 VP and stuff that's the
comment on the very last slide which is
I believe in three VPN is dependent on a
deep I'll ldp for the MPLS label
propagation so that you are able to roll
to rico well a lipid depends on the igp
to select this path well that's if you
use ldp or if you don't if you use RSVP
and then obviously that's a different
way I'm operators do one or the other
yes it is that that's what but but still
you want to it's different because you
still would want your you know you still
want to influence how things go between
l3 VPN instances there which may be
different than what you want you know
traffic other types of traffic like
management traffic which is typically
you know sent a straight IP traffic
around so I don't think you know and you
know in that case you probably also if
you if you do that to affect one then
you would in fact affecting you know if
you have multiple l3v pnc presume we
just want to change one they don't want
to change all of them so you I would say
you would want instead play with bgp you
rather than play with your drawing IG
which is something we also do so we
since we control the cost we can change
the curse that BG pcs between the
different addresses and so by again
doing some craft engineering we can
choose bid you set cause bgp to select
to prefer one ingress over another and
wrote the traffic towards a egress
differently
and goes the traffic to follow it
basically but so you're talking about
again it sounds like you're talking
about changing the IGP cost effect how
bgp changes but i'm saying you know at
least from my point of view i don't
think that would be the way an operator
would want to do it instead they like to
affect the actual l3 VPN routes
themselves for a particular l3 VPN but
i'm sure we can dig this stuff like glue
would be maybe easier for me just to
draw what i think and maybe understand
what you're saying then ok ok questions
where all the routing people hey
everybody looks at me but nobody gets up
allison is coming
so you mentioned that in the paper that
security can be handled by doing md5
authentication in the ospf context but
the your by introducing this fake note
are you also allowing the possibility of
other fake notes could be introduced and
they could you know provide routing
information you didn't intend and you
might need a an object-oriented security
rather than appear type security so so
the md5 mentioned that we made in the
paper is a statement that yeah maybe it
was poorly phrased but we have the
controller that's seen by all the
routers in the network just as one of
them it is tablature normal RGB a GP
adjacency so we shared the md5 key
between the controller and all the
routers and from then on it's seen as
the same ospf area to put it that way
and so the message we sent our
authenticated because that the operator
himself that set up the controller
there's no possibility for someone else
to send an LSA that would not be able to
identify I guess if you if you're going
to operate that would be good to have a
detailed explanation of how not to
introduce a risky situation to the
network but thank you thanks for that
comment this is uh you broke it all
right did you guys not get enough coffee
in the break it seems like it ok thank
you very much
second hook and can you try your dongle
for the next talk since this one I guess
right now the battery slideshow
let's see if this works better want to
check
I guess it's my mac all right do the
next slide thing and it keeps me awake
all rights like the second talk Benjamin
husband's also from all us group in at
UCL who's also doing quite a bit of mptp
stuff there yep thank you eat the
microphone go very close and pointed at
your mouth a bit total for me okay like
this all right so this is a joint walk
with gravy do tell Sebastian ballet
clothes on oops like this yes Raphael
Buddha and already been around 30 so and
I self but announcements from UCL so
let's go to the first side so we are
going to see first the very simple
scenario in which we have a smartphone
on the left side and also on the right
side and you want to establish the
connection between your smartphone and
the server so if you are using plain TCP
what will happen is that you will have
to do establish one pass next slide
please and you will have to choose
between the Wi-Fi or next tide you will
use the LTE but you will not be able to
use the two together so with MP TCP what
you will be able to do is on the next
slide you will be able to use the two so
basically it adds a layer between the
circuit and TCP interface so I'm ptcb
lies in there and next slide and what is
exactly multipath TCP this is a regular
TCP extensions that a low packets
belonging to one connection to be sent
over multiple paths so this is described
inside the RFC 6824 the next slide
please and the idea is that we do not
change the socket interface so for the
applications this is exactly the same
and you don't have to do any
modification inside the application it
will
oddly use MPD CP by default and this is
completely hidden to the application so
next I please this one one of the
objective design in mp tcp we want to
support a modified application so let's
go to the next side but there are
various uski is in reality so first you
may have different plans so on the first
side we saw that we could it could be a
smartphone but it could be able to
router or next side again a smartphone
or it could be also a laptop on the next
slide that's not the only thing that
could happen some other stuff may also
be different so if you go to the next
side sorry about this you will have to
switch it up so the the server side will
also be quite different so in the simple
serio scenario you have only one server
but you could be in a case where you
have a load balancer so this may also be
a problem for MP tcp on the next slide
you can see that you could also have
multiple type of interface so for
instance you can have a Wi-Fi interface
which is really different from a
satellite link so for instance you would
have a really different a TT maybe the
bandwidth will be very different and so
trying to aggregate them all together
can be also a bit odd next time we can
also see that the network cannot concede
be considered to be a dump pipe anymore
so we have a lot of middle box that can
for instance play with all the TCP
options and in this case the MP TCP
options and on the next slide we can
also see that there are many application
for instance that could have really
different needs and they may want to use
MP TCP differently depending on the
needs and on the next I'd we can also
see that even if you have all of that
you may also have some interface that
have cost constraint constrained sorry
you may also have security constraint
and so on so if you go to the next slide
you will see the big picture you have
all of this that could be different use
cases for MP TCP and the conclusion of
this is the
on the next slide we probably need to
adapt MP TCP based on the context so if
you have really different context
probably we should try to tune MP tcp to
adapt to the different needs so let's go
to the next slide we will first now
introduce a bit more DMP tcp for
everyone just to have a basic idea of
how it works and especially we will talk
about the implementation inside the
Linux kernel so our next slide we can
see that NP TCP itself inside the Linux
kernel is already divided in small
modular and for instance we have two
specific model which is which are the
past manager and schedule so those are
two specific model that we can change
inside the colonel to adapt the behavior
of mptp based on the need so on the next
slide we will start to explain what is
the what are the responsibilities of the
past manager so first the past manager
will establish what is called the master
so flow so master cyl flow is the first
up flow established for the MP TCP
connection this one is a bit specific
because you negotiate the option during
the first flow and in those option you
will also exchange some material to be
able to reuse after to join the
connection with different source and
destination IP so you you can see here
that you exchange the key and both the
client and the server keeps the the key
so on the next slide we can also see
that the past management the vast
majority sponsible to establish the
additional sub though so to establish an
additional central you have another MP
TCP option which is called join you will
use we will reuse sorry the key that you
exchange in on the masters of flow to
join the the MP TCP connection okay and
our next slide you can also see that you
are able to play with what is called
back up sub flow so back up is not
really defined in Saudi FC just
back up and then the implement the
implementation needs to know what to do
with those kind of sub flow so this is
also a decision of the past measure the
next slide we can also see that the past
manager will receive some events from
the connection so for instance what can
happen say the multipath TCP connection
one of the sub flow may be destroyed for
some reason so for instance one middle
box could send the reset or anything
like this and the past manager will
receive an even and it will react upon
decisions so other stuff may still
happen but here we'll talk about the
second component this modular inside in
the MPD CV implementation and this one
is called the schedule so in this one
when you have a queue of packet to send
over multipath TCP connection you first
have to decide which packet will be sent
next so it's not clear that you want you
want to send the head of the of the of
the queue first because if the tooth of
flow have really different
characteristic it may be interesting to
send them out of order such that they
will arrive in order at the receiver so
first you pick the the packet that you
want to send in the second time on the
next slide we decide on which sub floor
we want to send this packet once we have
once we have decided we send the packet
over the sub flow on the next slide and
we add a specific multipath TCP option
that will map the TCP sequence number to
the MP TCP sequence number so we have
two level of sequence number and inside
the NPT cdss option we have the mapping
between the TCP sequence number and the
MP TCP sequence number so we can go to
the next side so if you are just a small
summary of everything that is modular
I'll already explained all the little so
we can switch to the next side and this
is a great thing we know that MP TCP is
modular so you can switch some part of
it inside the colonel but the problem is
that it's still inside
colonel and it's still really hard to
develop new module inside the colonel so
we want to bring all the modularity from
the colonel and push it up to the to the
user space so the idea really of this
work is try to move the pass manager
from the colonel side to the user space
so the result of it should be that it
should be more easy and more flexible
for the user to develop new pass manager
and it will it should ease the
development so let's go to the next side
and now we will briefly describe the
solution at a really high level just to
have an idea of how it's implemented we
have one part that is implemented inside
the kernel space and the other bodies
implemented this side user space so
let's go for the kernel space we have a
module that replace the past manager on
top of the already existing interface
inside the colonel and instead of taking
any decisions let's go to the next slide
what we do instead of taking any
decision if we have an event from the
apt speaker no we translate this event
into a message and we will put this
message on to a net link so net link is
a protocol that able to use that will
let you send message from the colonel to
use space so we just pack the
information inside the message and we
will send the information into user
space phonetic so this is an example of
even that we could have so for instance
the mptp channel could say hey I've got
a su flow that is destroyed and the
module instead of taking any decision we
just pack the information inside a
message and send it to user space so on
the other side what we can also do is
listening to the message cut that comes
from the user space so the model itself
will listen from use of space and you
can receive new messages that it will
translate into MP TCP actions so the
example for this one on the next slide
is create a new subfloor so the user
space will tell a I need a new subfloor
we will pack the message send it the
module and the module will translate the
message in
2mb tcp actions suggest such that a new
subfloor will be created so after that
we have on the next slide the user space
implementation so in user space we just
add a library that is able to listen to
the applications themselves and the
application can send a message to the
library and the library will translate
the message to nothing so let's go for
the example so again just the library
just listening and will translate it all
the way down to who NP tcp on the other
way to the next slide we have also the
same thing on the reverse pass and the
library itself allows an application to
register call backs so that if an events
happen it will call the application to
tell to tell the application i I've got
a new event so again I think we have a
small example on the next slide so this
is the same as previously so the
supplies destroy it goes through the
module then to the library in the
library itself call back the application
to tell the application that we have a
sub from that is destroyed alright so
let's go to the next slide so no we have
the basic solution that has been
described we will go to to simple use
case to simple use cases so if you have
any question I forgot to tell you these
acts now because I didn't go into
details for the implementation but if
you have any question about the
implementation is asked right early so
for the use case we have two of them
will file we will start with the first
one let's go for the first one you are
in a simple scenario where you have a
smartphone and you have a Wi-Fi access
and lt access and you want to connect to
your server so in today's implement
implementation you will use the default
pass manager which is called the full
mesh this pass manager will open a soup
flow over the default interface on the
next slide and then immediately after
you will also open another sub flow on
the backup interface even though it does
not plan to
use it so it will still open this
subproblem so know if the smartphone
user is moving away from the access
point and then yes sorry for it yep so
if the smartphone users is moving away
from the access point what could happen
is the sub flow could become really
really slow and if the sub flow is still
there and PT CP will still consider it
as active and you will not send any data
on the backup interface one of the
things that is important here is that
slow is somehow subjective and we don't
know where they went to consider
subfloors slow so this might be this may
depends in the application for instance
so if you are using a small application
that does not exchange mini data slow
can be enough for instance but if you
are looking at youtube video for
instance maybe just a few kilobyte will
not be enough and you will need to use
the backup interface so we'll go to the
next one so how do you explain that so
the two issue here the sub flow is
established really too early we
establish it whenever we don't need it
and when we need it we do not use it
because we never define exactly what is
a slow suffer so let's go to the next
slide so now we have implemented
something different we propose something
different and we implemented inside user
space and what we propose is to use the
same default interface establish the
subfloor just as before but now in this
case we are not using the backup
interface we will not establish any sub
sub flow on this one so let's go to next
and then we still have the same issue
the smartphone is still moving away from
the Wi-Fi access but now we detect that
the subfloor is considered as slow so
what we will do now is open a new
subfloor on the backup interface and we
do not describe it as a backup and we
will start to use it immediately
so now we have those those two different
so the difference is we do not establish
the backup in the interface immediately
and then when we detect the slow sub
flow we open a news of when we use it
immediately so let's go to a small
experiment so said that is the same but
described in text so we can go to the
next slide so we have still the same
experiment let's go to the next slide
and we will just exchanged a small file
from the smartphone to the server and
let's go to the next slide and after one
second we will emulate the move away
from the Wi-Fi access without thirty
percent losses on the default in the
first and then we will compare the two
solutions so the today's solution which
is the default pass manager inside the
kernel which is called full mesh and our
solution that we called your backup
redefinition so if you look at the
sequence number evolution of the two
days pass manager what will happen so
here we have a graphic with the sequence
number on the y axis and the time on the
x-axis and what you can observe here is
the sequence number at the MP TCP level
so in green you have the master soup
flow and in red you have the backup sub
flow so here you can see that we are not
using at all the backup interface even
if it's there and the Greens of flow is
still in use even though it's really
slow and we do not manage to terminate
the connection so let's go to the next
slide so here we see all the TCP with
transmission so at this point we know
that there is a problem but we do not do
anything and the time to exchange the
file is really really long so let's go
to next slide and I already say that the
backups of flow is not used but if we
use a new definition of backup what will
happen is at start it's exactly the same
we open the mastership flow we exchange
a lot of data and then after one second
we have losses if equal to the next
slide we'll see them
we have losses and the RTO is growing
and then MP TCP is well the user space
base manager detect that the RTO is
growing and we will open a new sub flow
and then we will use immediately this
user flow and we will be able to
terminate the connection in this case in
four seconds yeah so in this case we
complete the exchange of the file and on
the previous case we did not complete so
if you look at the left side we should
go up to 10 if we want to terminate the
exchange of the file in the default case
in the girl in the current
implementation it's not even possible to
terminate the connection because MPG CP
with still try to exchange you data over
this flow even if it's not working one
on the other side in the user space
place manager because we detect the RTO
we are able to open a new subfloor and
use it immediately so that's the end of
the first use case that we wanted to
present and the benefit in this case is
you can probably save some energy on the
smartphone because you don't need to
open and use of doing immediately you
will probably save money because you
still have to in the first class you see
left to exchange the scene in these kids
in some some of the case you will not
even exchange the scene and then you
will have a faster recovery so on the
next slide we'll go to the second to
scale so this one is totally different
let's go to the first side so this is a
completely different use case for MP TCP
MP TCP could be used when stands in data
in data centers even if the clients and
the server have only one interface is
still possible to use MP TCP so in this
simple topology we have ecmp on the next
side and what we will do we will use the
IP port source and destination and you
will urge them to to decide on which
pass you will send the sub pro so for
instance the idea behind this one you
can you can open a first so flow and we
go on the first pass and then you will
open a second step flow you will go on
the second pass and then a third one and
fold one and the idea is that you will
aggregate all the values of all the bus
with that so we want to know if it works
on that so let's try a small experiment
again and we use the same topology and
we exchanged a file over this topology
and we measure the completion time so
maybe good the next one yes so we just
use five as a parameter for n default so
it means that we will open five sub flow
on this particular topology so here the
result of the completion time of all the
experiment and we can see that there are
three tricky cases so what happened in
this case what will see it on the next
slide so there is nothing to prevent all
the sub-code to go to the same pass
actually because you don't know what is
the ash function exactly so what may
happen is that also throw me and on the
same path and at this point they will
not agree get banned if they will share
the same path so if also flow use the
same pass you will not gain anything so
let's go back to the result he actually
what we did is that we found 200 code
sorry we found two out of the four pass
then we found only we found free on the
next slide we found three of the four
pass and then actually found all of the
pass on the on the last one okay so can
we do something better by implementing a
new pass manager in user space yes we
can we can try to do something so the
idea is trying to detect when two sub
throws share the same path so in this
case we want to be able to move the
orange pass until the second link so how
do we do that we have a proposition so
instead of just opening an nu sub flow
what we do is we start by opening the
same numbers up flow but then every T
seconds which must be defined we will
measure
we will just take a look at the pacing
rid of all the sub flow and then take
the sub flow with the lowest pacing rate
closing this some flow and then open and
use it flow and the hope is that we will
find the sub flow that is on that all
the subfloor that are on the same path
and then try to find all the paths so
let's go to the next one so we retake
the same experiment and we compare the
two solution on the next slide and like
we can see here is that with all
solution we push the completion time to
the left and we are always small s
finding all the pass but it comes at a
cost on the next slide because we re
establishing news of relief why
currently we are often in the slow start
phase of the TCP so we are losing a bit
of time on the best possible time but
overall we are still pushing the
completion time to the left so we can go
to the next one so that's it for the use
cases and now we just take a few time
few minutes to describe this circuit
implementation so on the left side you
have the solution that has been
presented inside the paper so you have
the specific model the library and in a
lot of stuff so this one is quite huge
and is quite flexible and on the right
side you have the circuit option
solution so this one is much much easier
and actually what we did is extending
the socket interface inside the Linux
kernel so you have a systems of circuit
that is already defined and you have
gettin sick and set suck up for this
circuit and we extend those to be able
to control MPDC be directly from the
application so now you no longer have
all this auxiliary staff you have
control immediately from the application
to to the colonel so it was just a small
example so this was intended for the
patent so we did it during the I cotton
this weekend we use the API and we
produce as some some result if you are
interested we have a list of result that
we had this weekend so from a see good
you had just able to create a new
structure and put the address over there
and just create a new sub though with a
regular get scoped so let's go to the
next here is the just a simple list of
the things that you could do now in user
space through the socket API so
basically you are able to get a list of
all the sub though you are able to know
which software use which address and
port and you are also able to open and
close the flow inside the user space
yeah let's go to the next one so in
conclusion what we add here is a new
flexible API proposal for MP TCP past
management and we have some use cases to
prove that is possible to do and we
think it may be useful in the future to
be able to have more deployment for MP
TCP so another diplom the deployment is
quite small even if it started it's
still quite small and we think that with
this kind of API we could have a larger
deployment so if you want to test it is
possible MP TCP is always available at
will be pasty speed at all and socket
API is also available on the mailing
lists on the side and we have also a
virtual machine that is available on
multi passes feel awkward so you can
just try it and we can go to the next
one I think that is if you have any
question I would be happy to answer them
questions while we're never going to do
this on monday again yep do you plan to
extend the API to be more high-level
available for example for browsers or
something yes so when we designed the
API we had a lot of questions such as
what should be the right abstraction and
it's we find that it's very hard to get
an idea of what the application will
want so instead of having a liar and a
high level API we started with something
simpler with the idea that we could
build something more complex and more
abstract with this simple API so we will
do it in as for sure so um it seems like
the application will need to gain a
whole lot of knowledge about the
different scenarios it can be and in
order to do this effectively right i
mean the data centers may be a special
case because there you have a pretty
rigid topology but but an application
that runs on an end system that's you
know we carry around all right could
find itself in very very different
environments and so it would need to
implement quite a bit of smarts yeah so
one of the use case that we did not
present it was the streaming use case so
for instance if you know that you need
minimal bandwidth you can stick to one
sub for as long as you have the minimal
bandwidth to exchange the file to to get
the video streaming and if you know that
you will be too slow you start for
instance to open an user flow inside the
application to get fast enough so that
the video is not stopping for instance
so that's something that more there is
more for the application itself hmm I'll
keep going if nobody else goes um so you
in your example so it was always the
client that was doing stuff yeah do you
have an MP TCP sec on the server which
also has this API and which can also try
to express its wishes yeah and what if
the two down the line what do you think
what if the two logics on the client and
the server try to do different things to
the connection through the API on each
side
yeah that's also something that we
discuss it seems that at some point we
will have to do have a mechanism to
exchange the high level requirement
between the server and the client
probably so we could also start to
insert new mechanism to let the server
and the client talk outside of the data
or the over the TCP option for instance
to know what are their objectives it
might not always help right so for
example if if you have the so if the
server would prefer to use there a path
that goes through appearing link for
example right well the client would
prefer to use one that it gives better
performance but is not appearing linked
to the provider wins right or we have
come to yes yasha um do we have an idea
of how that how they play out I mean it
would just be a ping-pong thing or no I
think we should be able to define how to
resolve the conflict before it's pink as
you said that I'm not sure how to
resolve the concession all right any
questions from you guys okay in which
case we're all very early at whatever
break comes next thank you very much and
see you in Chicago