Wow
okay it's time to get started starting
the blue sheets
okay first thing is this is the lamps
group remind everyone about the note
well if you cannot abide by the note
well please leave the room this is the
agenda it is as was negotiated on the
mail list there is one slide deck for B
and C together 2b and 2c for those of
you who are downloading the slides to
your laptop is there any in the room
agenda bash okay then we will begin
whose is Alexi or way giving the
presentation neither ones in the room
all right we will start with Jim and
come back to them hoping that their you
know one of the long elevator cues
I told my last meeting I was presenting
first I guess was right um okay next
sector so I think we've managed to get
through almost everything that needs to
be done for these documents there's just
a couple of things that I wanted to
double-check consensus on as it were um
the first is there was a couple people
who wanted to list AES 192 in the
mandatory well in in the in explicit
must should may list um i think that i
saw enough people who were against that
position to say that the consensus of
the mailing list was not to do so um if
anyone believes that is wrong they need
to let me know I inserted text on
deterministic ecdsa um which I think
said use it if you have it because it's
much much better um if anyone objects to
that text um please do so otherwise it
will stay so Jim what I think the text
says is that signers should use it but
validators can't tell whether the sign
are used it or not right um I'm not too
sure it says the second okay that is a
true statement because it's really a
should use it to signers yes okay right
if you can figure out how to how to
check on the receiving end I'll give you
a math prize um somebody asked for
um inclusion of p38 for as they should
in the document on the basis that
there's a large amount of government and
commercial people who end up needing
this because this is a sweet be protocol
um I have pushed back on this using much
the same logic that I put it was used to
push back on aes 192 which is yes it's
there but it's not really something that
we're saying is if it's as you notice
let me rephrase this doing so we tend to
bless a government position and that's
not an ietf thing and it's not clear to
me that there is a reason to put this in
the document as the industries that need
it will push on provide on providers of
email clients to provide it anyway I
think that's what I want to say um this
does anyone want to say anything
interesting at this point in time so on
the list I will start with the chair so
on the list I've been the one advocating
it does is there anyone else in the room
who supports the inclusion of it as a
should level requirement Eddie Cooley so
as the yeah and I say cuz I'm all over
Mike can't doesn't move um it's okay so
we're not calling it CN SI by the way
not sweeping um true so we would like it
did you can we can we now call it the
keep them from part of my business of
them so what no
no um so we would like it but if you
don't see fit to put it in then huh
you're right well go ahead Sean do it so
um I guess Shawn Turner I guess it just
seems odd that we do have this group of
people who might be the largest users of
this and you're saying male like don't
put it in there it just seems weird I
mean they've got a profile so
technically you could leave it out and
say yeah I know we don't it's not part
of the base standard and then you know
that the people that need to go by can
go whack them but it seems really weird
that like I mean really it's I mean it's
usg it's other people in Europe I manage
people in other continents it's not just
us G so it seems weird that you would
not at least mention this somehow and so
we've said not to use the other one
right the smaller one nah what we waitin
it which how much smaller soapy 256 is
sort of off the list right I'm not 252
page 256 is a must ok yeah that's the
most so we would really like it if it
was released I should this one so anyone
else that wants to speak for or against
Tim lunch after being sign on it ok ok
um I will confer with we will take that
to the lenses um last one is sha 3 i'm
at this point in time I'm seeing zero
real support in the IETF for doing sha-3
on anything and I'm perfectly willing to
stay with that position on for this
document is there anyone who thinks
that's a bad position
nah not seeing anyone run to the mic to
say otherwise okay so front from that
list there that basically says we've got
one thing to slaughter to decide and
everything else stays put ok so we're
cleft um I need to add a really short
paragraph on padding which says you know
you may want to think about it um but
it's not probably a huge issue for us
mime it per se um and I need to
regenerate examples and try to get some
verra verification of them I'm debating
just stealing some Paul Hoffman examples
for everything's that the authenticated
date is so that's the only 1i have to
generate from scratch um if anyone
thinks that's a bad idea let me know if
anyone is willing to do validation of
these things let me know awfulest so i
can send them to you and say they're
right i think i can probably get Peter
gottman to do validations but not
positive yet so are these examples that
you're putting in this draft are
examples you're putting in the 158 page
s why I'm examples draft these are
examples i'm putting in this draft okay
great
okay said okay I'm done okay Alexei
Europe right I'm doing a very quick
update on the internationalized email
addresses in a pickax certificates my
co-editor did a very good job he did two
updates basically we received I think
three reviews one from Ross one from
Shawn and one from gym or something like
that I believe all of the comments were
addressed basically clarification on
where the new other name form is allowed
in issuer out name so it is allowed
without there was no reason to disallow
it disallow wildcard characters some
clarification on encoding byte order
mark character unicode characters
disallowed a send one module some oils
for temporarily allocated and then
deallocate it and that TBD so this will
be resolved by anna so i want to say one
thing on that point the other name ID
way just put it the next available one
into the internet draft so since i
happen to be the iono expert on that
registry i actually made that allocation
so that if anyone implements from the
internet draft or the RFC they'll be
implementing the same
point I thought it'd be really bad if
that changed yeah like that it should
have been a DVD but he didn't do that
and so I right I saved us from from
potential early implementers doing the
wrong thing yeah I think thank you for
that I did it explain offline to a way
that I n allocations typically happens
later but you know yeah I think you can
show the next slide which basically says
I think we're done I don't know of any
open issues there is no TBD in the
document as far as I remember does
anyone want to raise aleinu issues does
anyone think this document is not ready
for working group last call okay then by
the end of the week I will begin a
two-week working group last call thank
you
Sean so I guess just for completeness I
guess PhD in the chatroom did say that
he thought not including sha-3 and the S
Mon specs is a bad idea so just want to
key thought we should include
include I think of what he's saying
which should include sha-3 so right so I
just want to wake that out with which
signature algorithm okay all right hi my
name is Shawn Turner and I'm in the pink
box so why am I here um I asked even
Farrell 280 sponsor this draft and he
said that's awesome please go get some
comments go to lamps so here I am next
all the links actually go to things so
what's est right so he is T is an
enrollment over secure transport it's
the last RFC that came out of pickax um
leave the joke up there basically idea
is to allow people to do enrollment and
get certs and you know server generated
certificates over in HTTPS connection
and it's getting posts and it's just a
collection of this is one for CA certs
there's one for doing simple enrollment
which is tens and sevens simple rien
rolls the same thing server key gen
allows you to generate ask the server to
generate you the public/private key pair
full CMC which is another interface to
do you know the full CMC dance that you
could do and then their csr attributes
which was added to allow the DST server
to provide something to the client they
can then use to include in one of the
enrollment requests so an example of
essentially is https you know
example.com well known / EST and then
like this the service name so what do I
want to do stand all the protocols you
give me a framework and I do some stuff
so I want to extend it the key point
here is this an extension it's not it
updates I don't think that every EST
server that's out on the planet there
are a few need to do all of these things
it's just some additional services and
some people could adopt them so I have
actually talked with some people Dan
Harkins is not here he he thought some
of it was a little interesting some of
it actually implemented in Yokohama like
on the fly fairly quickly so that was
nice
and panels at Cisco I guess I also talks
to unfortunately butcher his last name
so I won't try it he said some of it was
good as some of that he meant me so I'm
completely understand that not all the
services are universally loved by
everybody but I think that if you put
them enough of them together I got
enough use cases that they could be used
so next so first thing I want to do is
extend the existing server key gen in
three ways the first thing I want to do
is that there are some additional CMS
content types that allow you to return
to allow you rap rap key packages in
additional thing so one of them
essentially is right now you could do
naked which is essentially just returned
in a Kiki over TLS which is good for
most scenarios but not for those that
are slightly more paranoid um the next
thing is you can use cryptid dated or
envelope data well there's this RC 760
32 which is encrypted key package so
that's useful if you want to do this
thing called CMS content constraints
which you can put in a certificate to
limit the person that's allowed to
authorize or originate these packages
what they can do so the idea is that you
would like essentially link the two um
the next thing is that actually um
because we also have a way to return
receipts and errors we'd like to have
the ability to return these back to the
server so the idea is that when you give
them a package you can say you know
please return this receipt with an
attribute if there's an error hey guess
what you post back the receipt or air
and you do that with a post and well I
had to figure out a way to someplace to
put this so essentially what i did was i
extended the syntax from server key gen
to someplace called return so it's
generic because it's post receipts and
errors i could have had one for each but
i figured since it's one thing it's a
post you would just go there um and the
one thing that both i think dan and
panels like was actually returning it to
kcs 12 we love that everyone would use
the standard formats that we came up
with but keep pkc s12 is still used and
so we're just going with the flow it's
just add another one that actually be
used so you know we tried our best and
everybody was like hey that's really
great but p12 is kind of what gets used
so I'm given up so next
and then all of the new services so the
idea essentially is this pal thing and
this is where I'm going to duck it's an
XML formatted file that essentially is a
flat file with a bunch of entries that
are included there's a iono registered
type there's a name for the thing
there's a pointer in it and a date and a
size and so basically you have this file
and you can just you would you get
pointed at it through some a priori
syntax and you would essentially just
walk through this file to know all the
things to get so the first thing you
would get is like your ca certs then you
can maybe get firmware tam stuff if that
wasn't interested um then you could get
some CR l's and then he get some skip do
your enrollment and you can do all these
things in at the end of the day after
you've walked through this whole file
you're ready to go you're pretty much
ginned up and you can start
communicating you off like guess what
the next step is so there might be some
other way to do this but this is the
part the dan implemented kind of on the
flop fairly quickly so distribute I have
some slides later if we have time which
we might or if you're bored we can just
get them and you can read them later um
distribute EE certs so this this service
would allow you to essentially say hey I
know that these devices are really along
going to talk to a couple of people so
just distribute certs that you know that
the device is actually going to talk to
so say you're setting up a thing in a
house or something and it's only going
to talk to for the things you could give
it those for cert so it doesn't have to
go just go find them later it's just
already got them so when it goes to
communicate it can use that it can use
them to just verify or decrypt stuff um
crl zan day or else I know there's a way
that you can do that that you can just
straight up pull the cl's and ariel's
from cas but you could also just use
this mechanist ribbit um symmetric keys
again it's another key format that we
defined in the IHF and the idea is that
hey it might be good to actually you'd
be able to use this est thing to
distribute them so the idea is that
essentially the the client would connect
to the server and the server would say
hey look here all these symmetric keys
that you could use in battle with
download them and again it's CMS wrapped
and you can encrypt sign there's a whole
bunch of you know various ways that you
can wrap these things to provide various
levels of security none if you want or a
whole bunch and then we get a more fun
ones like firm or it is an RFC standard
actually people that use it so the idea
is that we'd like to be able to support
those people that could use it damps
another one and then of course all of
these things that we you know require
that my TF protocols do like return
receipts and errors we included those
and for completeness were like all right
so we need to be able to support
returning those so that's where this you
know service name / return with posts so
the difference is all the ones on the
left or gets the ones on the writer
posts Sean yesterday we had an
interesting discussion and TLS about
Sutton groups in data centers that might
use preacher keys so is this a symmetric
keys thing appropriate to solve that
problem or is it orthogonal it could be
used so the idea is if they were to set
up their servers to be able to go pull
this thing you could you could see that
that could be a solution interesting and
back up and this is just kind of more if
you want to go to the next slide it just
shows you the format of the pal and
again I duck because it's XML but it's
basically you know it's a pal with a
bunch of messages it's got a type and
it's from an eye on a registered thing
which is we have on the right and
there's a whole bunch of them so we kind
of broke it down the ones that i've been
using um you know because the PAL could
be like a million long maybe you don't
want it a million long you can clip it
and make it short so you can have one
pal point to another pal and then all
the things that it might do you have a
date format the size of the thing and
then some info about the actual thing
that you're pulling down it's just a
format for amazing but it's like a
manifest basically yeah that's probably
a better name for apathy is it's
commonly used somewhere or was it
commonly used there are people that are
using it yes and the same you didn't
invent it I mean no ok I mean yes I
invented it but no it's yeah it's a
manifest basically it's not there's not
a standardized manifest format but it is
a what you don't want to use Jason yeah
so I need you guys say so I need
somebody who's gonna ask me that yeah
that's where all the cool kids are doing
now um yeah I'm not apparently I'm not
she bore I'm not cool and I'm getting
older um did it in XML this is obviously
not the newest
hang on the planet my kind of theory is
that I need to do XML and so if other
people want to do JSON that's great if
somebody can tell me how to allow both
but not require one and allow the client
to request what they get returned would
be great but if we get into this MTI
thing I'm gonna lose my mind because I
just need to return this format and if
it's JSON or XML I really just don't
care or the next thing I just need I
need XML there other people might like
JSON is there safe you know if you know
as an art guy you can tell me what the
right way to do this thing is I was just
such as you're poking fun t-that yeah I
thought I asked just because I can I
just because as I haven't read your
drafts can ask some ignorance so is
there a way to discover which one of the
new ones you support or not or like do
you have to support all of them or so
the way I wrote it in sense there's none
of them are required so they're all
optional so the idea is that if you if
you didn't want to do the pal you could
just skip the path you just want to do
the e search you just add it so you as a
client which is no if you were to go um
go to connect to it if you didn't if you
didn't get to that thing you get an
error basically so there's no way so the
client will use one of these hands get
America ok get an area it's not awesome
i mean so there there is some grander
schemes where we could do some like
service discovery kind of thing and a
lot stuff that's just a bridge too far i
think for basically what i need to do
which is like here's some more stuff you
could get here's a list of things point
to it go get it um you go back two sides
Sean gets skewered by the CMC author huh
two slides wait for it started started
sure not one so distribute source is
basically this is get all sorts or get
whatever is just hot air to know what
everything so it's not any root is not a
new directory query mechanism it's a
mechanism which the ca who knows a
priori you're going to talk to these
people here are some certs that you
might like there they go so it's not a
query mech
to be like hey I need search for
so-and-so it's the it's the EST server
giving it is to give me a set of sorts
that I saw in my life thinking of is no
publishing their issues yes give me some
bag it's again it's basically exactly
that it's a cert bag message because
it's CMS right so all these are
basically except for the xml stuff or
else essentially CMS wrap stuff right um
after this meeting i'm going to go to a
core meeting core me and EST is showing
up in core really though yeah it's not a
crazy idea i mean when they first came
out was like whoopee doo it's just like
CMC but you know it's that does there
are some other things that it does that
seem to work and it fits some other
people's deployment models for cert so
so so obviously they're gonna want to
you know change things at some point to
return some other things but obviously
they're gonna like get out roll over and
die if you feed them xml well that's
fine so my theory is that i don't so the
PAL is the only one that's XML right the
rest of that lcms blobs and if again you
can tell me how I can query and get xml
and they can query and get json now to
be great and I don't know if you do that
based on some oh you can ask for cut you
can't one do pal one do pal Jay son
doing do pal sure you could do action
format equally yes I guess you do that
yeah so if we could do that that'd be
great and then just not like you can
actually agree on the quote-unquote
schema but it can't be a schema cuz it
JSON cuz Jason doesn't have schema but
right but they basically a great day
they actually wanted to refresh your
pebble baby yeah seaboard JSON whatever
will make up a new format called Sean I
Sean hey is anyone I shot Sean Leonard
um so yeah just too although it sounds
like some of this XML versus JSON vs
zebra or whatever was a little facetious
this exact same issue of a type
negotiation has come up in net comp and
yang and they have an approach of
negotiating internet media type so I
would say that so but you know what you
just use a very similar approach
over HTTP over HTTP over HTTP rest conf
just use HTTP content negotiation I
think it's accept header okay so we just
say except and I the format the format
say cuz that works I mean that's
basically what i wrote this and was like
how the hell i knew i was gonna get zinc
this so it's like how do I get out of
this box Liz oh if you guys have a
solution I could go look at him yeah
don't need annoying thing from reskin
face they sort of said clients needs to
support both JSON and XML and so it was
suppose just one so I i would rather if
you want to recommend one you know
recommend one don't recommend to all
right oh you know make 11 mandatory to
implement and everyone is it's not a
must if it's a I'm okay because
there are times we can just be like
candy that the box doesn't do that so
that's life alright cool that is
actually really valuable input because I
didn't know how to do that at all so
this is not in the charter of lamps but
Stephen kind of said go here so John
came here so what I'm going to do is if
you think this work should go forward
please send an email to Stephen the next
slide is kind of more of a this is all
in the draft right so it's an eye chart
so basically this is you know what you
could do if you have the pile so
essentially you do a get to get the PAL
and then you were just like I said walk
through the whole thing so I just
provides you more information about you
know what's in the get and all the
fields and it's it's basically like an
eye chart and it's in the draft so all
this stuff is already registered there's
no new iono registries at all and I
stuff it's using know so the only thing
you're doing then is extending the
well-known / honey it wasn't clear to me
whether I had to do that via Standish
track or informational so I just kind of
did it and put it in a standard track
and said man cuz I'm not updating the
draft me obviously I would prefer to go
standards track everyone loves it to go
standards track if you tell me I don't
actually have to and I can go
informational and that's prob
okay I suggest you you talked to mark
Nottingham because he is expert right
for the registry for the doll well known
stuff yeah yeah we kind of got
shanghaied into that unfortunately when
we didn't I people I don't think he will
have a problem he'll just tell you you
know what the answers if you are
extending your extending existing
registration right yes so existing
registrations probably need to point to
your documents as well so it's EST and
then the next level down is what word
exactly so it's already it's already
allocated right I don't know that we
need to do that but again as usual Santa
tracker be lesser that's what I want you
probably want on in there I am I
registry for suitable known for this to
be discoverable hey so you yeah I keep
them updated i'll i'll check with mark i
got it m not the other things with them
too soon and that's pretty much it for
my presentation so again send read it 10
comments just even that'd be great or to
me and and i'll resolve them and get
them out the door so all of you are
sending email to stephen right now right
telling him either go forward or don't
go forward so one of the points I guess
is that like if you think that I'm with
the biggest idiot on the planet like now
would be a good time to hear that
because I think the problem with a lot
of times with a be sponsored drafts is
right is that Steven goes great i'm
going to sponsor this is there any
discussion right and and like do you
want to know like is it like the
stupidest thing on the planet I know
it's not the smartest thing on the
planet but it's also probably not the
stupidest thing so I'm I'm personally
interested in like no don't do this
you're wasting my time it's stephen de
Fora draft draft turner dash EST
extensions so alright cool that's it
thank you very much right there on the
screen click on the link okay we went
through that very quickly again working
group last call on the eai document will
start this week i was planning to do a
two week working group last call anyone
have objections to a two week working
group last call okay Jim when you said
you have one thing to discuss on the
list and then update your doc
is that going to happen this month
networ next next okay so we'll do work
in group last call on that afterwards so
it's going to suggest that I know that
we probably shouldn't do this but there
is a thanksgiving holiday in the US and
a vast majority of people won't be
working that week so can you just if
you're going to start one this week can
you just make it three weeks I can do
that anyone anyone think longer is
necessary it is a pretty short back
around okay then we're done thank you