how many bacon brothers newspaper in a
gravel truck and the person's of home
game java start with a longer here free
not refuse
we need folders of women okay
what
we get off the surface the Hitler was
under the coconut oil communicate and
budget
we got
hmm
keep your pack
yeah yeah
with your quarters 35
ok let's start up my name is Ron bonica
and i'll be sharing this meeting of line
if you're here for lime that's great if
you are here for a warm place to read
the email well that's okay we're
friendly to UM for the people online who
can't hear I see there are six seven
eight nine ten eleven people in the room
not counting myself Carlos Pena Taro's
interiors not attending this I ATF in
any event let's start out and as always
we start out with the note well slide
this is the IETF IPR policy if you're
not familiar with the policy please do
familiarize yourself with it bore very
bad things could happen
ok
let's start with the chairs slides um
well actually I should put up the agenda
first well actually the agenda is rather
short as the chair slides a update on
the connection less or documents that an
update on the connection oriented
documents so it could could be a very
short meeting and then we can use the
time that we don't use informal meeting
in a face-to-face update session
face-to-face editing session so let's
leap into the chair of slides our
Charter is on this website and if we go
back to our Charter we had three
deliverables yang data models and we
turned out having um we divided it into
two at first and three later to around
connection less protocols one around
connection oriented we were also going
to have an architecture document and an
applicability document but those both
got subsumed into the data models
because they they were both about a
paragraph long so basically our task is
to finish three documents and those are
the three documents that we currently
have as working group items all the
other documents have been subsumed now
what is our status well the two
connectionless documents in my opinion
and that's why there's a question mark
there they're really close to being
ready for working group last call we had
two really productive into her meetings
and I think they're pretty close to
cooked the connection oriented document
isn't all that far behind it we learned
an awful lot doing the connection less
and we kind of know how to how to attack
that one now but all the news isn't
cheery um it's much later than you think
this working group was charted two years
ago to do three young models and the
yang models were due over a year ago the
window of opportunity is passing when
this working group was initially
chartered we thought that we were
building a framework that was augmented
and different working groups that did
different oam mechanisms would augment
it BFD would put some stuff in and
everybody who doesn't know IM model
would put something in well as it turns
out we've taken so long that these
working groups are going ahead without
us as time slips so does our relevance
so here is the working group chairs
bombshell um we're going to work really
hard and get the connectionless drafts
to the iesg by the next IETF meeting the
connection oriented draft by the meeting
after that and we will shut down at that
meeting regardless of what kind of
progress we made so if we're not making
significant progress in the next two ITF
that's probably an indicator that um
that we're not making significant
progress and probably won't get there
before before the window of opportunity
closes anyhow um is there any any strong
reaction to any of that front bumpers
quick questionnaire um I'm sorry your
name again Frank brokers what's the
rationale so if you go one slide back
mm-hmm and you said that the
connectionless is me already no I think
the connection orientated is a little
further along than the connection less
yes yes right so it gets one more IETF
and I think if you go one step or hmm I
do believe that the connection or I
think you got the numbers wrong so they
the connection oriented it is a little
further along than the connection less
whoops my bad right I think that's cool
unless on this slide if I meant to give
the connectionless a little bit more
time sorry i right I reverse them on
this slide a connection less should get
more time okay because we're on the site
not in good shape I'll fix that slide
and post it again Greg yes great what
does
Greg Greg risky I think that what I
wonder is that at some point we agreed
that yes we work on a paradigm packet
switching networks connection-oriented
connectionless OEM but we understand
that we want to have some more abstract
model that will unify this to into some
single model which could be very thin
very light but still will be very
helpful because that will ultimately the
realization of our goal as ah abstract
OEM model for the multi-layer
environment because in a multi-layer
environment the transport usually will
be a connection-oriented network and
then overlay will probably be
connectionless okay this sounds like a
reasonable thing to find something that
you can abstract from between
connectionless and connection oriented
and put it on its own domain that is
what you're saying no yes abstract
what's common factor out what's common
I'd agree that might that might be a
good thing to do the question is can it
be done in two I ETFs or will it take
six idf's again with enough thrust and
pitbull I so it all depends on
participation of the group if you can
make that pig fly I encourage you to do
so and we'll all have barbecue okay
binoculars I'm confused here because
okay the goal of lime was to get one
young model then we said okay it's
impossible to get one yang model me to
divide us into two connection elestren
oriented then we divide into three for
the method which I agree with now we're
telling with was correct that maybe you
want to go back
the abstraction which was the goal
initially but it proved to be not
possible so what am I missing there well
um there is a question as to whether
it's possible or not and it's probably
not appropriate for the chair to say it
is or isn't that's the work of the
working group but what the chair can say
is if you can do it correctly and
quickly show it to me and if you can't
then two models three models or maybe no
models is the right answer okay
understood then we conclude it wasn't
possible a thesis was my understanding
by dividing into connection lesson
oriented hmm my conclusion was that the
groove concluded it was not possible in
abstraction mm-hmm and I believe that
was the conclusion too um I see some of
the people who were in favor of
splitting it up and don't see any of
them coming to the mic that's an
invitation my name is Jim actually I
think obviously bigger punch up into
several job i think is based on
discussion and the consumers who will
follow these condenser if we break these
consistent by too much it all of this
job into why i think i was also kind of
confused Ragnar ski again okay a little
bit history their initial draft to one
group came from the true model and it
took some time to agree that the trio
presents connection-oriented through OEM
presents connection-oriented OEM
paradigm and then we didn't split it we
just designated we clarified what it
does and then started the work on
connectionless but at a time of the
discussion are at least my recollection
was that we agreed that even though
we're working on
technology specifically a.m. our
ultimate goal is to have an abstraction
layer that unifies these two models okay
so it's not about merging them because
they cannot be merged they are distinct
because the paradigms of the network are
distinct but we agreed that it's well
worth effort to have an abstraction
layer that uses probably i don't know we
we call the test points and test
functions that will hide specifics of
their network paradigm let me ask let me
propose something and ask for a show of
hands from the people in the room I
challenge you Greg to produce some text
that describes the abstraction layer and
I don't mean an email I mean yang Yang
model that describes the abstraction
layer hang on if within four weeks you
can have that done and the working group
salutes it then it's adopted and it goes
in to our work path if it's not complete
or the working group doesn't salute it
then it may be the right thing to do but
we just don't have the time to do it
because the window of opportunity is
closing there enough i just want to
mention that probably before berlin i
send over a proposal and i got no
response to it could you send it again
and this time with yang tet with yang i
send with some yang prototype that
basically used a reference fat ok I'd
ask you to send that again today and
that will start discussion of it I'll
try to dig it up this week ok then
sometime this week is yeah the week is
kind of busy hmm by the way does
everybody like that proposal is anyone
paying attention ok
and jeff has is always paying attention
no it's a channel actually I'm not sure
I follow the Greg's proposal actually
you know for sale OEM model actually
solid dude on top of the length of logic
model network approaching model has all
the abstract thought logic so we already
do such kind of attraction so if we'll
grab a compose another active Rosie and
we can take a look like that but the way
already chaiyya chaiyya us to do that
the thing is that again in connection
oriented and connectionless networks the
topology could be described by the same
model but OEM is different because if
you are connection-oriented then you
have to care about their miss connection
defects which is not the case in
connectionless okay so there are some
distinct differences in models that is
why we discussed and agreed to have to
yank models for OEM connection-oriented
elfin connectionless at this point
probably debating about it in
abstractions won't help very much if you
could make the proposal in email we will
discuss the proposal on the list and
today's November 14th on December 14th
will have a cut off on the discussion
either we accept the proposal or not and
we can remember that because December
14th is Beethoven's birthday Benoit the
Nautilus so you know if the obstruction
would speak about is simply like the
endpoints it could be like it tight
death which anyway we have hit apology
right that's the first thing I should go
to your next slide please shut down by
ITF 99 I've been hearing so many times
that those draft and yang models are
almost ready for so many meetings
at this state is important the window of
mention I strongly believe in to
that if we don't deliver it does not
matter right because the different OEM
mechanism will have their own yang
models and we are not relevant actually
I want to clarify and so we already have
yank models that I believe I should not
be impacted by lime models but it
bearable be beneficial for the lime to
use them and I can name rbd young model
a t1 p and model i can name mpls LSP
pink young model and mpls-tp OEM en
model so these models already exist and
I believe that why model has to
accommodate them rather than force these
models to change so clearly but the
question now is given that these models
exist what value does lie mad ah I
believe that there is a value and
especially the value because we want to
create some abstraction and so because
for the same of VFD BFD is working in
connection oriented networks in mpls-tp
as it works in connectionless networks
in itni p.m. pls so I'm drawing a mental
model of what we would have if we
continued with all of these models plus
com lime there would be end models which
overlap which model a partially
overlapping set of stuff now the
partially over lettings overlapping
stuff would be modeled one way for one
protocol another way for another
protocol and yet a third way by yang in
the abstract way
I'm scratching my head and wondering
what the value does that add but again
in my view are four existing models why
more though can argument are the b of d
and be done with it because you know you
don't have to redefine how you enable
continually check-in connectionless
network because you already have VFD
model so really what you're doing is
turning lime on its head at one time
lime was the common area that was an
abstraction that all the other protocols
didn't have to do now lime augments and
other protocols with with something that
they already have in my view the lime is
their model of saying or enabling
operator to execute or instantiate
certain om functionality okay so
basically if you're in the network and
you want to say okay we want to monitor
continuity between a and B then are you
go into more technical our technology in
paradigm specific definition which is
based or argumentative I tech nology
specific solution how you do it whether
it's a BFD or it's something else 1731
like and then in that environment you
provide the specific parameters of your
protocol okay let's see I want to go a
little more into the role of chairing
and not the debater so does anybody else
have any other any other feelings on
this this is channel actually based on
collaboration from the greg i feel i did
with the contradiction you know for for
the motor design though so I guys I feel
confused
okay I think probably the best thing we
can do is ask Greg to proposes yang
model proposes changes to the yang model
will evaluate them by December 14 and
either move forward with them or not but
in any event we're still looking at an
ietf 99 deadline any other comments okay
um now we will move on to the this time
I'll get them right I always confuse the
connection lesson connection-oriented we
will go with the connection less update
first and
and I have the long one
and that is certainly the wrong one
I thought this would be easier to
control
okay let's do it this way
there
okay good afternoon everyone my name is
Michael from hallway and Saturn I will
introduce lime the seal and the CI
modules update first all modules update
ah since the Alaska ETF meeting we have
a lot of work to pulses see how module
move forward we have several internal
meeting which also join other internal
meeting his pfizer PFE working group in
this in this legend terminating they
discuss the CL and seal models update
and also discuss some questions such as
the relationship between the line model
and another model existed defined by the
proto working group and we also have a
several discussion in the email list I
include her why should we need to split
eights model into two and another is the
relationship with land another module
also have some discussion about ultimate
measured and skill among master fund
rate we are request as a young actually
have young doctor to review our work and
gave us some comments to our Simonson
they can make our multi-pattern know who
this work move forward okay this about
is a cell modules update so most of all
a changes we modify this places it's a
model into 2184 CL modules face motive
neither is traveling master and we also
okay this issue is a razor since last
night of meeting and Frank
initiated discussions email list most
people's part to explicit modeling 22
and working group makes its decision
then they do relative update coding
chooses to Syrian and discussion and
second important changes way aid a
section to describe the LA sale modules
applicability in this section we propose
to use both CL module and another
modules specifying the protocol working
group as basis therefore soul I module
can provide its structure and another
technology Pacific mother can provide
these are details the argument align
with this group in defending this
technology perfect module and therefore
we can address a line this narrows to to
to try some land problems such as
quickly drew found a luta fault location
our stage different layers Tessa roids
out we also do some small change in the
CL module such as they ate some
description to introduce a relationship
with Tessa at where I asked as a
topology motive and the way also
modified supporting juice attributed to
read only and finally we remove some CL
relative technology attributes such as
air three VPN and unhealthy p relative
attributes ok it is a piece above some
important you to discussion the first
days a week this has a large about the
relationship between the line and
another modules before days the topic
and Greg and run and the chin have
discuss about this relationship
I think we have already associated in
terminating in the society meeting and
also in email discussion and in the PFT
PFT working groups in terminating we
also introduce our proposal I think we
make some consensus that the technology
basic model can define that standalone
dr. standalone module and CMO do and
this specific module can work together
run as this leads to a dry salam this
narrows okay Greg Mirsky um okay um the
current state of connectionless model
does not address my comments that I send
when there was a adoption call for the
connectionless model I believe that
there are mentation of Technology
specific models and that includes VFD
and LSP think in a connectionless
methods model that has to be part of the
model not applicability because it's a
part of the yang construct and if we say
that we do have a comprehensive VFD
model in this case that it has to
argument augmentation of VFD model has
to be part of connectionless or a model
not applicability statement saying oh
you may do that no if we're saying that
you need to do augmentation because
otherwise you would not be able to
instantiate VFD are continually
monitoring in your OEM okay for this
question why we're going to do some
updating this model because I was seeing
if we want to shows a generic model wave
ounces attribute our structure and more
abstract and the way don't one
to defend a lot of parameters it can
describe in this techno specific modules
though so perhaps we want to address a
land problem of the urban didn't learn
independence a problem perhaps we need
to just provide a structure of commons
product model just come can show the
common structure and the common
attribute and if you have if you have
neither talk about specific module is it
cool you can provide another solution
for the user the user can flexible chose
to use it kind of a specific module uses
module and the land structure built a
new module to address it Lance narrow ok
I have two questions to that first if
you don't want to be a tied to the
specific mechanism to do continuity
check then why are connectionless OEM
model includes the container with a list
of RFC 58 8158 8350 84 and so on and so
on so that's very specific to me write a
second of all are if you say that there
are other mechanisms to do continue to
check in connectionless networks I would
be interested to learn which you mean ok
first first question is thus far into
theta shows as captivity it's now the
defense in detail it can shows this
device of ok i cants policies choose and
we know not defined it it more we not
defined more technology talk no specific
details so this is a part of I think it
is a part of abstract module it can
provide ability it can provide the
letter user know of what what what
should I
quote excuse me about it it's quite
specific that your listing I be the
single hub multi-hop and Vav over mpls
LSP and Vav or to the way I think that's
a very specific you're not saying oh I
can do continua t check and how I do it
you'll figure it out when you want to do
it okay I think that that's that's the
level of abstraction for the line is I
do continue to check fine okay we can
discuss it later and I I think that
that's that's the discussion that we had
for not the first idea and i sent the
comments in working group adoption call
and it's still there and at the same
time you say that augmentation of VFD
model is a to technology specific I
think that these two statements don't
connect to me look I think somebody want
you want to comment on the same issue
yeah question on the combination so red
would it be is the proposal to just get
rid of these references and with that
solve the problem because then that's a
fairly easy approach solve the problem
ah that would be only half solution in
my view I think that the solution would
be yes remove this list of RFC's not
only related to BFD but orbs is because
they are too cryptic they require a
person to know what this RFC is about
and instead of that use the
functionality if we are doing for
example LSP thing then its on demand
continua tea and connectivity check you
can do it overall LSP on to the wire
with ls meeting for the 379 this
probably now the better the reference
but we have a model for LSP thing or
just IP pain if it's likely a network
okay but you don't have to
reference particular RFC you just say on
demand continually check and activity
verification period everything else
technology-specific and if we have
already model like in case of LSP being
just augmented there that's actually
fairly easy change to make would be okay
yes yeah then the same in the same in
the same to do with the DFD instead of
listing rfcs that we view related say
are proactive continually monitoring and
then argument BFD to their okay okay I'd
like to flip axis comments to my closer
and we can discuss a user first we can't
do relative change or update such as a
common trouble san Cisco a great union
of mental model or you mean reporter
greetings from one of those lives I
usually see that you argument the model
okay so you've meant it that means that
the line model in infinitely like what
we have also imprint almost other models
well oh well otherwise how would you
instantiate BFD if you don't implement
the v-model like the don't you can do
you don't have just click your fee you
have to invent all the other earlier
models something augmented by the line
as well so it feels the discussion of
the Lima augmenting of the emoji
specific not all to see but the wrong
announcement so I mean fully green
dating site that's what see that's why I
am again um I don't see that if because
again the lime in my view of the line
model if we're talking about the guy I
don't know about other examples because
yes we can talk actually we agreed that
performance measurement is will be
separate and actually that's something
that I realized that is not on our
timeline so what will happen to the line
performance measurement model that will
something that I think that we missed in
the earlier discussion today but if we
talk about for example our existing LSB
thing model and the d model I think that
they have to be implemented if you want
to realize the potential of
connectionless om ah CFM is not
connectionless CFM requires your
connection you define your MA in the mag
and it's different it's a connection
oriented model action it's a different
question I think that we haven't really
got to do how lime relates to ethernet
models and namely for any f38 because ma
38 is a young model of fault management
for the carrier ethernet service so how
why model and MAF 38 correspond okay
then with then we can then we can ignore
CFM okay I'm again uh we had this
discussion and how who I'm work related
to ethernet service a.m. and we haven't
decided we I don't know whether we have
a clear solution I think that our
implicit agreement was that why model is
applicable to technologies developed at
ITA which includes in the connection
oriented domain trill and mpls-tp but
that's again if I misrepresenting please
correct me because that that's my that's
my that's my recollection of our
discussion we had this discussion yes
but we I think that agreed that we only
lime covers thrill and mpls-tp
okay for this cross for six to issue I
want to do this again and I'll for a
stir and the working group and another
such as carefully working groups a
discussion we can some concern sir and
we think we don't need to and argue
choir to imagine either technology
argument a lie or cheat engine lab but
you defined is a kind of specific module
and our way provide is a structure and
to address lamis narrows we can use it
to motor together to dress the problem
okay knocks on okay this is another
discussion about a scheme around my
certain document matter in the sale
module applicability we introduce a
matter that we can augment the mattress
sale module with techno specific group
to get as a to get the new mario and
grassland program and another master is
proposed by night mode the working group
ice cream among it also can solve the
problem or to make a different model
work together yes man yeah oxford house
screaming bound hi I'm Roger Luca and
I'm a co-author of this scheme amount
and draft in the net not working group
and I'm a bit worried that now that
scheme amount becomes sort of
fashionable term that people will start
using it instead of normal augment that
that we have been using for several
years so the idea is that scheme amount
is useful in cases where you want to use
the same yen module in different places
in your data are key like you f you have
a module that could work for a simple
physical device and then you also won't
use it in some kind of
realization like in routing instance and
things like that so suddenly the same
data becomes somewhere berating inside
the hierarchy and then of course if you
for example one to augment this module
eight something else you have to specify
a precise place so and you cannot do it
at the same time for both for the
top-level location and for some mounted
location so that's for this this is the
use case for scheme amount if you talk
about like adding some technology
specific knobs and things like that then
in my view of a normal augment should
work so as long as you really have only
a single place or you want to put this
new stuff then an augment should work so
I would recommend you to look at at
augment first as as soon as you realize
that it doesn't work for for our use
case then you may want to look at the
scheme among but as far as I can tell
this could work and also I'm a bit
confused about the use of grouping which
is what probably also mention is really
but a real the group he is some group in
defunding days technology specifically
such as dirty and obvious and Tiaras LCP
mpls-tp as it offends some a lot of
reels in groups we don't want to
redefine disease attribute in Thailand
The Contender module therefore we reuse
is cooking is they are not defending the
land motive there's a different me today
I don't know the details just to warn
you that these groupings you don't work
like object-oriented classes for example
so that really you you you if you want
to use a grouping let's use a specific
grouping from a specific module so it's
not possible like to to have some object
oriented inheritance and so you just go
for a grouping into it will it will be
somehow magically filton middle stuff
that that's really really harmful for
the particular device so but I just yes
this is about this is the fourth our
land
applicability for example you want to
extend the alarm to Jocelyn their Theory
my module you can reuse a lot some a
group in defunded dirty and the land
structure tis there is a way proposal
the means a flick bility yeah so my
conclusion this moment is just go for an
augment possible and if you have any
problems and feel free to contact me if
you on to us thank you thinking Bergner
skiing in I just want to stress is that
if argument statement that list
explicitly the model that we argument in
till I'm Liam model connectionless is
not part of their model then it would
not be augmented so it cannot be part of
all you can argument no it has to be
part of the base model the augmentation
has to be part of the base model if our
operator doesn't want to use proactive a
continuity verification then it's fine
but you cannot do augmentation on a fly
on the wheel okay so please understand
that okay this is a purple Emily faced
for land we just provide this a common
structure on the we can now that defined
is some techno specific modules you know
which each other way clarity to Colonel
aesthetic module need to defending the
protocol working group and kind of
specified working group therefore in the
lime audio we we just can provide the
Sun it's a land applicability or some
solution to the reader or to the user
for declare okay our line module can
provide this article city's ability you
can do this but we don't
12 effort and why is ok I think that
again I have to point the contradiction
of your statement and the fact that
model lists their numerous RFC's which
are technologists specific so either
remove all of them out of your model and
have no connection to their
instantiation because otherwise if you
don't have a way of use existing methods
which are protocols or am protocols be
of D or anything else then I don't see
the value of line model at all okay if
you cannot do from Lyme obstruction to
go into technology specific protocol
then what's the value I believe that
their value of lime is that you say I
want to do this or am functionality and
that gets you into technology specific
or if you want to see the operational
state say give me the operational state
between a and B and then it either does
you on demand verification or post the
state of a proactive session and how
does its technology specific but if you
don't have this connection to their
technology to the specificity of your
paradigm what's the value of lime
binoculars so let me ask the stupid
questions and goes I'm slightly confused
so connection less and bfg which one or
comment which one for lanza kwon do we
use the landline at this motive and also
in holds a BFA module so we imported the
FD module pocket fine now under you are
you know cell and module liability we do
some tennis okay this is your let me
clarity it a bit actually we in our face
model with not extend from base pft
model we empower network topological
model and import a metal instance model
but we don't actually import a PFD model
here we show this applicability we tell
you how to extend it base model so we
talk about the youth organizer honest
apply to the model exchange not apply to
them pace the model all right so I'm
hearing that the bfg model will go along
alone anyway right that's one thing so
we want to have a line model that will
be augmented for OEM specific technology
right yeah good so which one do we have
we've got like a potentially sfc or beer
or auntie one so these are those guys
are talking to in film trying to get
them to linked to lime while for BFD too
late this the idea trail working groups
they have trail OEM llamado and augment
seal motive yeah alright so change so
commitment let's see if I understand the
answer to your question the ultimate
value of lime depends on our ability to
influence these other working groups to
augment line
what this is what a charmander Stan it
was too late for BFD already is now the
next question is are the other groups
highly motivated to do so or are we
working on an airplane that will never
leave the ground that's the question
what is the value of lime or we're too
late already if we just have like a
module with a container a pointer to an
oem specific yang module I mean all
right so what is the value right a
container telling okay BFD anyone this
may be a derail in question but maybe we
should think about that for just a while
and think about whether it makes sense
to continue work project just one
comment so if the situation is that you
have some modules at our or they ready
some other working groups and you want
to take these modules and put them to
some place in your hierarchy then of
course it may be a use case or false
king among because in this case the
extra stuff that you want to add needn't
care about your your basic structure so
they needn't put any augments in there
more you so you can just take their
modules and put it somewhere there are
some limitations what you can do and
cannot do but that's of course the
option but I really don't know the
details I would have to look into what
you are doing and trying to achieve
because i cannot tell me we can discuss
it more just to come in on that below
again so let's remember that charter was
about consistent configuration reporting
and presentation if we change based on
what letter set right the configuration
it's too late for the FD they're going
to use their own module they're not
going to use a hierarchy that we've got
even if you do a scheme amount to what
they had right that's the first thing so
for BFD the config part is over
we might be able to influence some other
OEM mechanism the new ones sfc beer or
maybe t1 and I don't know whatever will
come right maybe if you got a nice model
we could augment that now to come back
to BFD then then the only value of lime
is what the potentially the command the
the consistent reporting because they
wink of a scheme amount that says and
this is the container that the pond
amount points for BFD and it's the same
level of the different mechanisms this
is the only added value of lime in that
case which is tiny but it right so I
think we just acknowledges for certain
things that this is Frank for certain
things the train has clearly left the
station via fig on trolled on fine check
there are other trains waiting in the
station beer maybe sfc let's go try
right and given that the work has
progressed quite far let's give it a try
let's go publish this stuff and then if
people pick it up and it's good if
people don't pick it up and it wasn't
good enough so and you have some printed
paper I think it's worth while
continuing and then getting it done and
trying to get it done quickly as opposed
to are seeing the question should we go
and continue right now given that you're
so close to the finish line velocity I
got not run was that it seemed that it
took us like so much time at ease in
little hat ujin's try to summarize this
right and and you know we asked to have
a wiki with the different OEM mechanism
connection let fashion oriented whether
we influence those guys whether in their
interest to augment line etc we have to
go back to this which was requested like
three meetings ago right because if in
the the column telling is their
interests to augment line and the answer
is no from everybody then except to
improve the reporting then the value is
Jeff Jeff tell us your name hi my name
is Jeff hey Jeff so Benoit specifically
about the BFD point BFD does allow for
configuration of VFD through other means
no that's for the reasons why we have
that dependency across several other
modules we have groupings exported for
time and configuration so for example
ospf can enable the FD sessions line can
do exactly the same thing I think your
broader question is what should the
general design pattern be 40 am like
things so that a device specific module
can be not only in control of its own
fate but allow for other no external
things by being an example to do its job
and similarly how can those device
specific modules you know provide
information that is useful so that the
layer independent portion of mine can
actually get its job done the first one
in terms of general configuration the FT
is obviously a good example of that
Elle's ping I haven't looked at the
module as an example so it would be
interesting to see if there's some way
to provide similar groupings to allow
for external components to configuration
I don't have a strong opinion about the
layer independent portions of the
operational state
okay so i will try to summarize what we
just heard here and that is that again
the window of opportunity seems to have
gone for BFD and for trill we may get
that window of opportunity for other oam
mechanisms so let's work fast and get
this done so aren't you know it seems
like a relevance has to do with our time
to publication and I'm sorry you name
slept Frank I'm sure ok Frank um Frank
mentioned we're so close to the finish
line ok if we get to get to the finish
line it's worth it if we take another
year to get to the finish line but the
train will clearly have left the station
so anyhow with that any more comments on
connection less let's talk about the
connection oriented draft yeah one more
chance that it would continue jolicoeur
ouya in the window for the DMV and
ensure all close absolute zero today
standing on sale model hmm no for me ft
it's closed but maybe for some other so
let's let's try hard to get get done by
ITF 99 and maybe we'll be there in time
to be relevant for some other away and
not mechanism I don't come up in fact if
flying proves to be useful then nothing
prevents somebody from adapting the BFD
model just be able well we had the
situation already weather radar outing
module that also try to provide some
some kind of a framework that routing
protocol would use but we now have also
some more use for me GP for example that
just ignore this work and just they
wrote bethe model that starts from the
top and so what we've been trying to do
is to convince people that maybe this
framework can be useful for them and of
course it will take time so I think it's
it's not carved in stone so if you want
you can just adapt their module use a
different name and put the VFD stuff
using an augment or something if it's
useful for you so that's another option
I I don't think that the fact that bfg
working group is done means that you
cannot use their work in some other way
I need I think you're real candidate ok
any more on connection less let's move
on to connection-oriented then ok so
conduction or n de tomate your way don't
you updates and society meeting but we
prepared some bozo to chat some problem
and but you know that we have to allowed
to enter meeting and not have many time
to update Ahmad trapped ser felices data
on budget this proposal is the right day
already prepared and if we can submit we
can submit new version this is talked
about as a host version you have similar
to the say a multi-way I do a lot of
work to prove this more work forward
it's in terminating and request a young
dr dre voh ok in this new proposal way
need to solve several questions first
issues how to deal with Sam McGrady some
makati maybe some techno specific
attribute and it equivalent to the
medina so Shh maintain association ID
and it be funded by a cutie it also be
used in technol hf sir NPR's TP
technologies so this term this attribute
miss Sims a technology fake our solution
very simple way Chester remove it from
the biz motive and if the multi-user
want you to burn a date 10 Oakland
Monsieur module eight eight eight isn't
a requirement oxide neither the second
issue is how to defend the knee placed
the Middle East in the original version
limes sale module the me please define
what is simple with only have one it is
only one leaves interface but we check
the standard standard document we found
that the maple a if one two completions
and made me at least we need to two
parameters among address letters in
eville but we also found that maybe you
are a created ultimate today another
need to expatiate operation cooperation
this parameter is sims
technology-specific so our solution is
similar to choose a major deal with mark
ID we just remove it and if the user one
sees how to build a sukkah element okay
okay it's a third question mr. issue
it's in a way i already the introducing
CL module is a relationship between to
another modules okay this is a final
question there are some AOE arrows in
this module so in the previous version
the sale module can pass the PM exam but
enough camp as a young editor a truth
check and the way this is arrows and now
it can pass the full of boxes to choose
and this way are deserve a proposal to
update yeah okay so next up with rod to
prepare another version according to
this meeting to this discussion and
require working group another welcome
google escoll thinking this is a sale
module
yeah I bregma risky okay so several
comments regarding the relationship
between this model and mpls-tp om model
so regrettably I see this model as a
tool model it's not mpls-tp or a model
because we do have I'm pell st peoria
model and I suggested to argument it so
the document has information formational
reference not the reference lists
mpls-tp OEM yang model as informational
reference but it not referenced anywhere
in the text so which is kind of odd it's
a stale reference which is not used and
again I believe that because mpls-tp is
another connection oriented network and
developed at ITF next to trill if you
don't want to replicate mpls-tp OEM
model you need to argument this model
into this base model okay so uh
otherwise you just replicating and
duplicating mpls-tp OEM yang model that
already exists isn't this exactly the
same conversation we just had a minute
ago and yes your vacuum again so again
if if you if we agree or we think that
mpls-tp OEM model left the station then
remove the references from this document
and make it trill model hear it anymore
comments
okay thank you very much thank you i'm
going to try very hard to come up with
some next steps um and I see two big two
big obstacles to getting getting there
one obstacle is the one of factoring out
some things that are common between
connection oriented and connection less
stuff and here we have come up with the
action item that Greg mirsky will
generate some text by hello next couple
weeks Beethoven's birthday that's right
December 14 um actually no I think of it
it might be December 17th but 16 okay
okay whatever Beethoven's birthday is
that's the day you'll come up with that
their 16th okay and um we'll decide you
know whether to use that piece of
abstraction or not by then the other is
we have this recurring discussion about
augmentation and we have it showing up
in both drafts um do you just reference
an RFC do you pull in parts do you ask
other working groups to augment the line
working of the line model and I think
we've come up with a solution that says
then somebody tell me if we don't have
consensus on this solution but I think
the solution we have consensus on is
that we will not reference any rfcs for
the oam specific stuff we won't
reference the BFD rfcs but we will ask
other working groups not trill not BFD
to augment the line model with their
stuff do I have that agreement right for
everybody except BFD in trill for BFD in
trill what will we do okay so my
understanding is that will reach to
other groups working on OEM frameworks
and solutions
to review lime models and consider their
relevance is that right understanding
because basically we're not enforcing
the Y model onto them that's true if
they if nobody contributes anything if
nobody augments us at all we are useless
with a capital you okay i see head
nodding is that not entirely oh you're
you're nodding left and right or right
up and down jeff has so the problem lime
has always had is it doesn't really have
a good sense of which direction things
need to go you know partially because we
started from two problems first one
being yang was a very new thing second
one being the OEM technologies involved
are very distinct things so I think I'm
DFD is anything i know well BF DS
management module and yang for the ietf
has to be self-contained and
self-sufficient for ietf purposes and it
has to also serve in the capacity that
it does for all the various protocols so
we have to have something that can
actually no satisfy those requirements
does lime add anything on to that not
necessarily mm-hmm does lime making use
of technologies add something
potentially mm-hmm but if you can't
figure out what you know that looks like
now that we've gone through i think in a
partial attentional I'm roughly two and
a half different schemes of you know
what the relationships of things look
like know what the initial one being by
example sort of know why 1731 i triple e
flavored no it was not something that
was a good fit and the authors of no
dental that work to try to actually work
around that if you can't figure out what
that looks like how can you ask people
to build on top of that
offers any it's an old discussion no
that's that's where most of the churn in
the documents has gone through is trying
to actually find good mappings between
these things know if this was not act I
TF technologies I think this would be a
lot cleaner problem because I tu and
other organizations but they build
technologies build o am as a first level
thing into each of them and therefore
it's clear what they actually don't tie
together ITF technologies don't do that
now they're loosely coupled I agree with
Jeff characterization of that so far in
too many occasions we left Oh am hanging
as a abandoned child something like I
can compare only to the mid work that
you know being very late always but at
the same time for new encapsulations and
that's something that would hope well
I'm may be relevant that work on sfc
beer and there are three as that's where
we try to come up with a comprehensive
OEM mechanisms in parallel to doing on
networking technology so where I think
something like lime has challenges is to
build that base model if they'll get
this with some other organization the
underlying base models would already be
there oh and I do you have circuits and
you know they have the only important
circuits and all the stuff that builds
on top of the circuits the layers just
keep on building up what we do not have
an ietf no spec and sfc as an example
that is effectively going to be a IP
technology there's no IP technology OEM
that we can build on top of so we're we
don't have the same foundation that the
other organizations
and that I think that right there i
think is really the thing that line has
been fighting with the entire time is
successful yeah well I'm is trying to
find some commonality among things that
aren't really common okay so going back
to next steps um there's the piece of
abstraction that's the easy part now how
to tackle the augmentation problem um I
thought we had a solution that we'd
agreed to that was to get rid of the
references to specific oam rfcs and just
wait for other working groups to augment
the lung data model does everybody agree
that that's what we agreed to on this
meeting is anyone wait does anyone not
agree that that's what we're we agreed
deal does anyone agree remember the
agreement differently okay I'll assume I
got it right then so i'll be looking for
a new rev of the connection less draft
pretty quickly like soon after
Beethoven's birthday yes and with any
luck we can send that to last call in
january-february and send it to the iesg
by next time and probably the connection
oriented one should go soon after that
no okay do we need a online editing
session in January a interim
should I take that as a no authors do we
need not an interim in January I guess
not well in that case um we have a path
forward I know this has been a difficult
meeting thank you all for bearing with
it see you all wherever we're meeting
next time Tom where are we meeting next
time Chicago cool okay see you all there
and who has the blue sheets
hey ok who are you to be that's ok
frustrated to my comments well you're
talking about the augmentation ones or
the involved Lisa jerseys ok I thought
that was in the agreement we just
rattled off that we would not let the
RSI I send them one years in before they
still they change now let me hit that
you make it clear