congratulations Bryan became a bina
figure out what area by area my makeup
day one sure chunker along to be its own
yeah perfect just another for a mistake
so let's let's start um Brian we have a
note taker not yet Wes Wes Mike dhoni
wit did you see Mike can you sure yeah
ah alright so we finished Monday this is
a little out of order did toe combining
um we were finishing with token exchange
I think there were a couple sort of
hanging pieces of that at the end one
was a request um from torsten in
particular but I think it's a more
general thing that need to further
explain the relationship between
resources the resource parameter the
audience parameter and the scope
parameter and I've talked with them a
little bit off
I think I know what to do there is
basically just described that the when
when requesting a token you are
requesting the scopes at the resource
and/or audience and if there's more than
one resource or audience you're
basically asking for the full set of
scopes at any of those one thing at any
of those targets so I'll put some more
tea than that Rick Lera Phi and I'm
considering maybe adding a specific
error code to for the authorization
server to say it can't do that or it's
unwilling to do that under certain
conditions because I think multiple
resources multiple audiences might be a
difficult thing for some some systems to
fulfill um if you have thoughts about
that chat with me but that's what I'm
thinking right now arm there was a hope
to get it to working group last call at
least from me but it sounds like people
are interested in holding off a little
bit for some implementation experience I
think that's that was says such as net
that the sentiment in the room yeah
right I don't I don't remember who such
as did that but just to get an idea I'm
talking about can you hmm it yeah okay
thanks Mike uh me can you take notes
like good you obviously paid attention
during the first meeting yeah that's
good um Tony said he had some developer
feedback he was going to bring forth
hopefully it'll be in English and
actionable and meaningful yeah so do we
um so uh who I'm so talking about the
doc needs change when who is currently
implementing token exchange for planning
to do that raise your hand finding one
two three four five five that's good so
like if we are able to collect the
feedback from those five folks or five
groups
that would already I think push us
forward quite a bit God could maybe I
should maybe we should write down what
who those five people are um I saw
Justin I saw you brian mike vick and
Tony okay excellent yeah good okay so i
think i think that's really all hmm so
when do you think we can see a new
version of the document 50s kara
fication that you mentioned at the
beginning resource slope ithaca some
time before chicago you think but to be
honest i'm going on about family
vacation immediately after this so I'm
gonna be out of pocket for a little bit
um but it just times a refreshment if
you sort of take the evening off yeah
you tell my wife that uh and my kids
probably in in December sometime okay
good that's uh I think that's course
okeana Thank You para okay that's good
Dustin it's your turn
I'm hello everybody my name is loss
I'm from veggie telecom and I
would like to present you a new draft as
the title suggests it's about security
Oh of security and real a brunette and
John Bradley and I have wrote this draft
and so show the first slide please and
the reason it is um we had some
discussions in Berlin about that would
be a great idea to have a comprehensive
list of all the topics that are right
now floating around on a really soft
implementation issues our new security
threats and so on arm and we sat down
and try to start work on those draft and
the motivation basically is because arm
Oh of itself was published in 2012 and
got massive traction since then and what
we have seen in the wild is that there
are some practical issues with
implementing it correctly typically
basic stuff like I access RF or openly
directors and so on and we thought it
would be a good idea to give
recommendations to developers how to do
it right that's the first motivation
second motivation arm my feeling is
technology or the underlying of
Technology Oh off changed a bit for
example the wave fragments are handled
in when redirects occur and user agents
arm and we should we should analyze that
and then find out what the body
consequences are for example on the
implicit grant well there are also
changes that will support us in getting
off security tighten up for example the
claims URLs which are supported by some
of the major mobile operating systems
Tony will take some time to present the
slides you're already in a queue yeah
okay
it turned this back to me and last but
not least are when we published off
originally arm the typical setup looked
very simple there was a single client
connecting to a single a s and
interacting with a single resource / and
this is changed significantly
significantly so for example in in
through Paul you login or federated
login scenarios clients typically
connect to more oh thank you that's cool
so I'm in full control again so if you
for example take a look into federated
identity scenarios they are a client
typically connected to more than one IDP
and they typically have today in blind
all of our open ID connect and this
opens arm and attack angle for things
like mix up attack and so on things we
we didn't really consider when writing
the 60 original security threat model
but more is going on or coming up more
dynamical scenarios are being used in
conjunction with OAuth and I think those
reasons or those different different
motivations drove us to to writing this
this RFC because the current security
reconsiderations RC 67 49 and 50 and the
security strap model no longer suffice
for that so what's the what's the
intention of this of this draft first of
all this is not intended to become a
standard document istana tracks document
this is intended to be a working
document something we can use to capture
arm everything we we think is worth
capturing about the open topics the
threads the implementation issues and
also write down our the potential
mitigations because what I'm observing
in the course of the last year would say
we have
isolated discussions about one threat or
another we have discussions about this
potential mitigation and another
potential medication where we don't come
up with a systematic comparison between
those mitigations and what we also don't
have is a big picture which of those
potential mitigations would solve which
problems because what I'm dreaming of is
that we say okay those are the changes
to all of those are the recommendations
we closed all the all the holes that we
see today and I would also like to
capture the status of discussion and if
you take a look on to the drafts by the
way has some one of you already read the
draft you're my hero I mean you are co
awful so yeah right okay so I read it as
well so thank you very much your heroes
so if you could take a look on to the
draft and you will see that before
example for the different medications
that we already described we discuss the
pros and cons for those different
medications so what I would like to to
come up with is a document that
facilitates the discussion process
within the working group and we do not
plan to document all the threats and all
the countermeasures in this document but
to have a kind of an umbrella document
and to refer to all the drafts that
other people already have written down
for example John as a draft and open
airy director mike is a drop on a mix-up
and so on so we can use the document as
kind of an umbrella when all the drafts
exists together to give the context and
we can put content in the draft when no
other draft exists so the long term goal
from my perspective and the perspective
of my my co-authors is we come up with
ideas what all of extensions we really
need to define for example for code
injection prevention and we've write
down a comprehensive list of items
actions or things a developer needs to
implement in order to implement all of
in a secure fashion the bullet I gave
are just examples so this is not the
real
list what just to get to give you an
impression so that could be a PCP and
either return this document in the PCP
or write a new by CP I don't I don't
care about that right so but that's
that's the long-term goal so that we
come up with a real comprehensive
description if you want to do it right
do it that way well it's a bit small so
this is this gives you an impression on
what what what the document covers so
far so the elements in red are the
sections that we already filled and
green or the potential countermeasures
that we are describing so the document
is structured as follows we first have a
section describing the different means
to steal credentials of the leak
credentials and off credentials meaning
access tokens authorization codes
refresh tokens and we've got a section
describing the different threats
regarding injections the code injection
access hook and injection all this stuff
xrf and we also have a section about
open redirect errs and all the sections
that have a TBD in the title are as the
name suggests to be determined so we
focused in the first version we focused
on the redirect URI validation leakage
via HTTP referer hetal's and fragments
and code injection oops okay so from my
perspective if the working group decides
to adopt this document and to use it the
way we are proposing the next will
believe is that next step will be to
complete the description of all the
different threads and the mitigations
and to really have a discussion in the
working group about the mitigations
their assessment from client side
perspective server perspective cost
perspective complexity perspective all
that all those different aspects that
needs to be into so taking into account
when meeting the decision to what are we
gonna recommend and then we should
document that and start work on on on on
PCP so that's basically the idea and
from
tactical perspective I would like to to
get your feedback on under your single
magazine makes sense what we proposing
and what are the next topics you would
like us to cover and us meaning the
working group so that's basically is it
yeah Tony nedlands so we've had a lot of
discussion at Microsoft lately about
this particular topic and you said that
and I'm just not quite sure what your
intent is here right there's over 12
documents that are in the list today
that have been standardized our
developers can't piece the 12 together
and understand what to do and what not
to do I think understand and so I don't
know what you'd run what you're trying
to mitigate are you trying to combine
them all together and find out the
mitigations be issues and mitigations
between all the specs when they're used
together or you're just talking about
OAuth so I'm a little little confused on
you know what's your total goal is and
I'm also you know carrying on the
message from from Microsoft that this is
it's somewhat getting out of hand for
our developers all the all the specs
that are that are here and how and so
what happens is they wind up creating
their own they look at it and says I
can't understand it they wind up
creating their own stuff and it just
drives us you know nuts at Microsoft
good that they have people like you to
explain it it yeah but that's you know
you can t yeah but you can't do that all
the time right they just you know
somebody says you know they've got a
problem to solve and they go off and do
it and you have no clue what they what
they've done until after it's shipped
and they had and somebody has a problem
but it but it sounds um all I answered a
question yeah because it was erected to
me outlet ritual that's it rich or
exciting
and I just thought okay so i asked you
ask for they did I agree I agree with
what you're trying to do here but I
don't think it's enough um I don't think
its broad enough surprisingly I would
agree with you um I think it's not
enough uh what what we trying to focus
on first all the obvious problems and
the obvious problems are the threats we
have been discussing for a year or now
and didn't come to a conclusion yeah but
I understand that but that doesn't you
know those are probably existing threats
right we understand that but that's you
don't we don't have the landscape of
everything to understand what the
there's no architecture to this yeah
that's right it's less so first first of
all one of the reasons why we need this
document is from my perspective because
we didn't really evolved and enhance the
securities fraud model the overall
security threat model why we were
adopting auto specifications namely our
dynamic registration for example which
which changed the capabilities of all of
a lot didn't we didn't do that now we
somehow try to to to fill those or fill
this hole and I also feel that our
documents like the RBC p or native apps
address a real need so I think beside
the specs there is a need to for
recommending best practices not only for
security also from a design and
architectural standpoint right i mean
we're running without much guidance here
maybe that's right maybe this will help
a little bit more guidance but you know
these add-ons aren't making a lot of
sense i mean pixie was just a patch I
don't think it was you know well thought
out and in something that you know we
could have avoided earlier and so we
have these little patches that are been
placed around here so I think that's a
question folder for the working open
general my personal opinion on that
speaking as torsten I think we like an
architecture overview on a vision and
that's why we have this pesci a
landscape yeah that's it
and may I i would i would say we need we
need more bcp documents for different
kinds of applications I the other day I
talk to one of our architects and we
were talking about how to implement
multi-tenancy resource service the
resource service that have relationships
with different autorisation service this
is from my perspective and very
interesting topic that could be solved
different in different ways I think this
is another example where we really need
a PCP or your question take over over
dinner on Monday who actually does
refresh crop rotation but why because
it's not documented in the RC yeah thank
you Tony Benkei duck I also support this
work I'm really happy you're doing it
i'm going to say Kathleen's name to get
her attention but if this is a supposed
to be used to living document this
particular thing I feel like you should
just go ahead and do it and not even
bother asking for a working group
adoption because if it's not going to be
published I mean you only care about
working reproduction by the time you
want to make a bcp why don't you just do
the word no not necessarily don't um so
you can still have a document sort of
the fact that it's a working group
document and services as a Dawson said a
point for discussion which then points
to the documents that mitigate specific
solutions and infer the PCB documents
you could still have a lot of value and
gives people an indication like what we
are we working on rather than having an
independent individual submission that
is one of many so just to say that
clearly I'm not interested in having a
draft that just expresses Maya John and
Andres opinion I want to gather the
opinion of all the working group members
and to come up with a conclusion what's
the right mitigation otherwise we want
come to a conclusion because what I have
been observing is we didn't come to any
conclusion for any of the of the open
security issues in one year okay
dick hard I'm so there's two questions I
have one of them is why aren't we
starting on the security bcp right away
as opposed to just just having this
draft like why don't we just say that
this is the start of the bcp or is that
what you're saying because I don't think
we have to leave we have this best
current practice right now ok in my
personal opinion because otherwise it
wouldn't be would be named best and no
wrong current practice or bad current
practice and my other question is what
about sort of broadening the scope of
this instead of it just being security
that it is just the OAuth best current
practice which i think is tying into
Tony's comment like here's a document to
read to know here's the best practice on
how to do often included in that as the
security pieces this is getting huge if
other people support that work yes do I
not yeah I mean you know that the
problem orbis is you need contributors
you know people that write text people
that review the stuff and so on so John
Bradley I support having best current
practices I think it's a dot if we
decide to start this work I think that's
a document management issue that in some
cases it may make sense to have modular
things like native apps single page
applications that developers who are
interested in how do I use OAuth to do a
specific thing may find more
approachable but we have to do the work
anyways we we can later decide how we
divided up whether it's one large
monolithic document yeah everybody's
going to no matter what we do half the
people will decide it was the wrong
document structure and it will be torque
yeah well be honest is fault so I think
we should adopt it it should be a
working group document because in some
cases
some large organizations and governments
etc if it doesn't have an RFC number it
doesn't really exist so you know yes we
can have a living document that that
keeps us all happy but unless we
snapshot from time to time when I'm
talking to just on government and they
say well what's you know what's the
standard we you know is it an iso
standard know it's an ietf standard oh
well I guess but if it's an individual
submission you know they just don't take
it as seriously I have one question on
what Dhoni was proposal and proposing
and what you because a python is a sort
of this architecture and I am not quite
sure how that looks like so for example
the best current practice for the native
apps in some sense this is an
architecture because it talks about the
specific aspect the specific deployment
very end then it makes dice a couple of
specifications together sort of epic
architecture something that is or a
single architecture is very difficult to
create in in OS because all along it was
used in in very different context so I'm
curious on how that would look like and
maybe you guys can earn enlightening
John again I think maybe we could have a
stab at an overall architecture but from
a developer point of view I think that
the architecture to do some particular
task is more approachable but somebody
who's doing a native app doesn't
necessarily need to know about token
exchange and various other things you
know so if we can focus the the BCPS to
be more task oriented I think that
that's going to be more helpful and I
also think that along with bcp like we
did with native apps we also at least in
the open ID foundation we created actual
open source libraries that developers
could look at the code and figure out
how to do it as examples it's not just
you know this is the high level
architecture because developers again
relate more to actual code examples or
things that they can incorporate
each other their operation that already
what we do today in be just on Monday we
talked about the completion of the
native apps work and and you are on the
agenda on the last item to talk about
future work and and there you will
entertain the idea of another best
current practice in in those in in the
native apps document for those who had
read it it points to for example pixie
and it this discusses other aspects and
so um I'm borrowing whether we are like
what we do whether we are so far off
what you guys are actually talking about
we just need to sort of continue along
that line at least from the act I'm
talking about really about the
architecture stuff writing but that
still leaves single page applications
what's the best practice for I have a
web service done I have this yeah be
start with one and then it was
well-received so right we add another
one and I think that's I'm to me it
sounds like from a from a um type of
approach to the work seems to be more
manageable rather than sort of trying to
work out the architecture which sir no I
yeah i agree with you agreeing with me
right dick dick do you agree to that
approaches one probably a dozen times of
telling people dare go read it and and
the good thing about that is that we
actually you know William and I have
gotten a lot of feedback from the
development community it hasn't been
just us telling them you know this is
the way to do it um well mostly it's
that but you know they do actually give
us feedback on well have you thought of
this in this particular environment did
you know that Windows acts in this
particularly bizarre way et cetera so
having that feedback from the developers
because there is an open source project
is helpful okay so toastin um from my
perspective after listening to discuss
I think it in the end it would make
sense to have BCPs for different kinds
of things as their a dick call it so for
different kinds of kinds of clients but
also for different scenarios and
different all kinds of resource and
authorization service the question is
how to approach that and and which tpc
which PCP is the right down and I think
if we write BCPs for this those
different arm clients types that we
should also incorporate the security
stuff but I also think that the
securities fraud model and the analysis
and the mitigations are cross-cutting
concerns so um I think it makes a lot of
sense to to to to work this way and then
we need to decide which BCPs to to write
in afterwards that would be my proposal
so I'd agree with that I think it's good
to have the security all-in-one bcp and
then you could have the other BCPs that
are say talking about a single page flow
say to refer to the security bcp for
people see what you're saying more or
less yeah iiiii i'm rather reluctant to
call it the bcp but um I can live us out
early yeah it's just an informational
draft run so ah discussion huh if they
are not about Disney's this is this
process I don't care i don't i don't
care about process but what content wise
re-interview what would be very
important for us already the substantial
of valuable feedback if people could
tell us which types of client and which
scenarios they carry the most so would
you like us to take a look especially
into JavaScript apps or a single page
apps or whatever because in the end
redirect URI validation for example
works completely different for those
different client types and we need to
anyhow i distinguish those in the draft
so uh what I would like to suggest will
oppose the message to the list or so and
people can can can can propose which
which scenarios which kind of
applications clients and back-end system
they want
us too to consider and but will be also
an indication where we need pc ps4 let's
have William uh say something hi yeah I
actually think this should be a DCP and
that it probably should obsolete RFC
6890 if possible and what what I like
about the bcp model is that it does
allow that kind of snapshotting that
that people been talking about so which
i think is a valuable thing now and
people you know last cool to give that
stable identifier for all the security
issues so I'm definitely supported over
security bcp okay seems everybody wants
a piece ep I'm fine I'm convinced okay
um what yeah let's uh so um I will ask
who is are in favor against adoption of
the document that um toss was just
talking about um and introducing to us
so please raise your hand if you're in
favor of adopting that document as a
working group item I see about yeah two
four six eight nine nothing beyond
certain hands husa again against uh I'm
adopting this document is working to
bite them no no he he races no no no no
he's an elegy don't wake him up okay
perfect yeah that was Kia so there was a
strong like like 15 people in favor
nobody against and so yeah okay okay ah
good thanks good thanks
Oh go there let's make us great again
you'd be remiss not to all right we good
uh with the owl do Oh does it work yeah
it works awesome okay uh so I want to
talk about what is currently listed as
the OAuth age should be signing draft
the whole motivation behind the entire
pop architecture was to have something
that was roughly in parity with bearer
tokens so you need a way to get a token
need a way to use the token need various
ways to validate the token as it's being
presented at the protected resource and
so getting a token is really um pretty
much the same except that you get a key
associated with that we've got a
different document that's working on how
to do that whether or not the client
presents the key or has the key issued
by the EAS we're not talking about that
here right now validating a token we
toss our hands up in the air and say
it's up to you go figure it out but
obviously we've got introspection jot
and a bunch of other things that will
need to be adapted for use in the pop
world what's interesting in this
conversation is the middle one is how do
you use one of these pop tokens so you
go through all this work to associate a
key with the token and how do you get it
over to the protected resource so what
we have right now is a presentation spec
that includes signing presentation of
the token itself and a method for
protecting the HTTP request in various
ways and bit of a historical note here
all these three are kind of wrapped up
together inside of a single
specification because originally i wrote
a draft spec that actually only did the
last bit hoping that hoping and assuming
that somebody else would write the bits
for how to do the signing and how to do
the presentation and nobody did so
eventually i added those in and said
like okay this is how you kind of do the
whole thing and the signing bits for the
HTTP request message are really optional
additions on top of that however that
seems to really confuse
use a lot of people so I'm going to
break down today exactly how these
things all fit together first off we've
got signing and it's basically you take
a JSON object you put your access token
inside of it you put currently it's in
there as a timestamp it could be a nonce
I really don't care just some way to
have a non-repeatable transactional kind
of thing of some type in there whatever
wrap that in a JSON web stick signature
and sign it with the key associated with
the token really not hard since we're
using josé there's a crypto agility re
in there if you want to do elliptical
curves or shared secrets or you know the
Jose quantum cryptography draft that
somebody's going to write some day I
don't care you know it's jose it's a jws
it's not a JWT incidentally because this
is not really an assertion it's not
carrying sort of application level
information that a jot normally would
but we are using the jws general-purpose
structure for carrying this stuff over
presenting the token is really in
parallel with 6750 so chuck it in a
header chuck it in a form body checking
in query parameter we did all three with
pretty much the same caveats and
limitations that 6750 has because that
honestly hasn't really changed all that
much in the last four years except for
the fact that the middle one is I would
honestly be willing to drop the form
parameter because back when we wrote Oh
off to form encoded in JSON out was sort
of the the rule of the day for writing
an API these days that's just not true
it's JSON and both JSON out so I'd be
happy to drop that one I don't think we
really lose anything for having it in or
out of there the other two I do think
are important because they have very
specific use cases and yes I do even
mean the query parameter but that's not
what I'm here to argue today when I'm
here to argue today is the third bit is
and that's actually the HTTP message
signing this is something that ofone did
that OAuth 2 doesn't now there's very
good reasons that OAuth 2 dozen part of
that is that a lot of developers got
this wrong in both one and we know this
we know this because many of us in this
room and in many of us that were
involved in the development of OAuth 2
were o auth one developers and we're
tired of screwing things up and having
other developers trying to interoperate
us screwing this part of the process up
however it still is valuable in a lot of
cases to protect the HTTP request that
you are making with a signature of some
type and so the idea here is that the
signature that you are generating is
going to be associated with the same
token key that you're using to make the
presentation proof the bat jws that we
had before well what we're going to do
is we're going to use that to create a
detached signature of the HTTP message
now unlike existing HTTP signature
methods that are out there so AWS has
their own proprietary one there been a
few others that are floating around this
one does not assume that the HTTP
message remains unscathed throughout the
process instead it very much admits that
lots of things can go wrong in the
middle of it what that means is that
this is not a this is not just take the
HTTP request exactly as is and create a
signature then take it exactly as is and
re-sign it on the other side no instead
that this is designed for a world where
things get manipulated in the middle
headers get injected query parameters
get mucked around all kinds of stuff
like that you know the stuff that
actually happens in the real world and
so you only sign the stuff that you know
as part of your API as part of your
deployment as part of your documentation
you only sign the stuff that you know is
worth signing that's not going to get
screwed up on the way through and it's
up to the application on the far side to
make sure that the stuff that comes in
and decide is the stuff that it cares
about and the stuff that makes sense for
it to be able to do its job yes this is
a compromised position and I think that
this is actually a reasonable compromise
given the complexity of the HTTP
protocol and the complexity of HTTP
deployments in all of the different ways
that they can get screwed up on the way
through any given process anybody that's
done a reverse proxy or any type of HTTP
application framework will know the pain
that this can cause if you have
something that assumes sort of you know
static pristine preservation of the HTTP
messages on either end IE anybody that's
tried to write an oauth one client in
any of those situations now anyway um
this is not fully comprehensive there
are some corner cases that it doesn't
cover and we've enumerated those and
just said that if you have you know if
you have stuff that fits in these cases
don't sign that bit you can't sign it so
instead of making this try to bend over
backwards to fit every last weird corner
case of HTTP of which there are a lot we
just said this doesn't this doesn't do
that part it doesn't go that far and
that's that's ok so you sign what makes
sense that's really kind of the the gist
of this whole thing the key point here
is that this is all optional this is all
optional in today's draft spec you add
these components in to the base
signature the base signatures over the
access token which is being presented as
is uninterpreted by the client still
opaque to the client just like a bearer
token and that nonce timestamp
transactional identifier whatever we end
up wanting to call it this is all in
addition to that all right and you only
add this stuff in if it makes sense for
you to do so in your API and if your
application needs it so what I propose
since this still seems to confuse people
is if we just split this into two
documents we put the HTTP signing in a
separate document how it was in the
first place and we put the core signing
bits in their own document and we move
the two forward together and if somebody
wants to raise a stink and say that the
HTTP signing is experimental I'm
actually okay with that because it kind
of is because signing HTTP is really
really hard as it turns out and we have
not yet had a single comprehensive
solution that I have seen now remember
this is in fact in a detached signature
this is not taking the entire HTTP
message and uh sort of you know
encapsulating it inside the jws nor is
it assuming that the HTTP message keeps
some pristine format outside of the jdub
so it's not the Mike can you remind me
what the the external jws is called okay
you wrote it you wrote it whatever
Mike's last draft and Jose was it's not
that either thanks anyway so my
suggestion is that we move both of these
uh
both of these forward if we want to mark
the HTTP signing and and and have them
cross-reference each other um so have
the course pack say and hey if you want
to add protection for the HTTP message
components here's a way to do that and
have the HTTP signing thing say well
okay we're going to tell you how to hash
the message how to do all the
verification you're going to have to put
it somewhere you might want to put it
into a no op op signed request alright
so we put the signing and presentation
in one document HTTP message hatching
and attached signatures inside another
document move both of them forward
publish it call it a day yeah um so I
think that there has been some chatter
about alternate presentation mechanisms
because it seems that some people forget
that if we're going to be doing all this
work with our pop we need to be able to
send the token from the client to the
resource server in some fashion um but I
haven't seen any concrete proposals that
said even if there were additional
concrete proposals that's fine we have
6750 and whatever the kitten one is did
the kitten know offing do you remember
safley yeah this is the sasal gssapi
thing whatever number that one is we've
got both of those and they don't fight
because they're doing different kinds of
things you can get the token in the same
way and use it in different ways
depending on what kind of API you're
talking to and everybody gets along just
fine same kind of things happening here
so that was always the intent that's why
token presentation was pulled out as a
separate document in the early days
early ish days of OAuth 2 to allow that
kind of protocol flexibility we're
inheriting that and embracing that here
so if you've got a different way to
present pop token go for it I haven't
seen any yet but if somebody comes up
with one that doesn't mean that this
one's not useful also side note I've
actually implemented this both server
and client side and a couple of other
people have done I've done their
versions of it as well so this is this
is a thing that does exist it's not a
thing that has a universal applicability
but we know that so bearer tokens get
the job done in
a lot of cases and that's fine this is
for cases where you want to kind of pay
the extra costs and and get the extra
benefits exactly alright that's all I
gaya clan is open and I guess Benkei
duck so I was reading really fast when I
read the draft do you talk any about
doing discovery for like when you learn
about the API you also learn about which
parameters should be included in the
signature um so yeah we don't actually
address discovery because discovery is
kind of a black magic voodoo box in the
OAuth world and it is and so how the
client knows even which server to talk
to oooff doesn't care and we we
inherited that attitude so we could we
do say that I forget the exact word but
we do say something like the API must
document or something like that which
things that expects to be signed but we
don't say what that means yeah we do so
we have this somebody who remember
discussion on Monday we had this
discussion about metadata and never
smell a date that for example also about
the resource so where this could
potentially belong to I um but but I
don't think it's there because the work
is still at the yeah there's definitely
no structured or automated thing I think
we have some language that says you got
to write it down but if we don't we
probably should yeah and it probably
also some security considerations about
that because if you're not oh yeah we
what you sign no we definitely do have
security considerations about that
thanks to Phil we've also got some
security considerations about things
like argument order and a couple of
other things that aren't necessarily
strictly preserved by the by the hashing
process so it basically like if these
things really matter to you this isn't
going to give you that information
you've gotta have some other way to make
sure that that works so yeah we did we
definitely do say that because that was
actually the root of a really big
problem in open ID to
real world exploit with opa 90 to where
providers were taking in taking in
messages validating the signature and
then just assuming that everything that
came in was signed which isn't the case
and this is really kind of its taking
the same approach it's you list what you
signed and you sign that and this is
kind of doing the same thing so that
this was not fully invented out of whole
cloth it's based on that same pattern
but it has the same the exact same
drawback so yeah as as an RS you if you
care about a parameter being signed and
it's left out of the signature but its
present in the request that's got to be
a problem but it's all it's up to the RS
to figure that out and he for a feedback
go up so at the last at the buena idea
for meeting which has been unfortunately
wasn't present from did we had and at
that time we also adopted the dough
combining work sort of is a little bit
of bad at that you got thoughts this
work and sort of the perception was that
since we're working on tow combining we
don't need this anymore um but i don't
hear the same type of feeling now
anymore so I i guess i'm letting i'm
leaving the question about document
management the side i think i would like
to get a sense of the room what they
think about moving this work forward
this is and so basically um please raise
your hand if you think we should try to
finish this work in in the East working
group this meaning HTTP signing raise
your hand up in case I you know sorry
you know us uh sorry okay yeah yeah okay
yeah but doing this all on what you
sorry about that uh that was could be so
1 i'll let me try it once more it's late
for me um um raise your hand if you
think we should continue this work in
this working group
see two three four five six six and
please raise your hand if you think that
we should stop this work you only own
one stony and Phil so we have two person
ass against this put it the list I I put
it to the list already hmm so as the
document editor apart from doing the
split the documents been done for ages
there's not really been additional
feedback there's a handful of
implementations it's just the working
group has not said kick it out the door
and go from my perspective so the cart
has there been anyone that's deployed or
tried to deploy not at like the Amazon
scale if that's what you mean but in
small pockets yeah my concern is the
worry that if we have this and we
haven't really thought it all the way
through and it isn't all the way baked
it's yet another spec for people trying
to figure out what to do with I wanted
to do and potentially leads the more
sort of incompatibility of people trying
to make things work together torsten is
going to fix that with the bcp we're
fine hi rich Saul's is a stranger um why
would splitting if it's been stuck for a
year why would splitting it unstick it
because some of the lot of the comments
about not moving it forward or about the
HTTP message hashing and signing portion
and not about the token presentation
that's like the caboose each will cut
off and let the rest go forward right
exactly and you know this isn't the
first time this working group has done
that in order to unstick things okay so
i was gonna say more or less they should
be signing has been
the sticking point for a lot of people I
think so maybe there's more hope for it
with just the presentation II sort of a
sidebar question is is there any
mechanism in the presentation though
that that keeps a token from being
presented by the resource server to
another resource server yes yeah yeah
asymmetric King what did the mechanism
it says the fact that the token is long
to a key no no but yes but you're
signing the token and Anna times down
yeah you you can't present that token
without the signature to another RS that
and when you present it right you put
those things and the signature right of
the RS can just turn around and go and
represent the whole thing represented
yeah you need to you need to tie it at
least to some of the other parameters
well that's why the h-2b message signing
was added in there but i think that the
presentation is is the key aspect of it
and the presentation needs to cover or
at least consider the security
implications yeah huh from my
perspective I would I would prefer to
see that the presentation sort of fully
baked in it and the htp signing
separated and even make it could be
experimental or just dropped but the
presentation needs okay my question then
is how would you do that without
covering portions of the incoming HTTP
requests well yeah that's part that's
one of the fields of so that's literally
those evolution that we already have so
this is what I find frustrating about
this conversation yes right so this is
John Bradley so the token presentment
without actually having an audience or
destination as part of that doesn't
actually move the ball very much further
ahead so if we're going to split the
document we should consider some basic
things so that we actually meet the a
worthwhile security goal by having the
presentment method you mean something
like that
um the resource indication oh well yeah
I mean are you gonna do a URL you're
gonna do resource identifier what are
you gonna do it could just be the host
that I i do i'm not making a proposal as
to what needs to be there but something
so that one host can't replay it against
another host so that unless you have to
API is on the same host and that doesn't
actually help you I mean that's just
that's security theater at best so yeah
Rep yeah so the sub again something to
identify the resource server otherwise
work we may not actually be moving the
ball far enough ahead to make it
worthwhile for people that's true except
that you can do audience restriction
without the presentment mechanism inside
the token it's alright that's true so I
mean this all this goes back to the
discussion we had on Monday right
exactly right so so the question then is
that is it that the token can't be used
at multiple servers or this specific
request and if it's this specific
request then then we're getting into
talking about signing what the recoil
this specific request is covered if the
token itself is appropriately audience
restriction so maybe unnecessarily but
go ahead so maybe it's having enough
security considerations to understand
that this alone without properly
audience restricting the actual token
you need to use the HDD be signing to
sign parts of that yeah so we just need
to make sure that it actually is
meaningful and actionable and people
don't wind up thinking that they get
security that they don't that's and
that's an absolutely fair observation
Mike Jones um I was busy taking notes
and didn't repeat my position at the
time that I'm already on record for that
I don't think we need to do this it's
not that it's terrible work per se but
we're already doing so many things that
I think it's been starved for attention
because we're doing other things that
people consider higher priority and I
haven't seen any ground swell of people
saying we're going to implement this so
it's not clear to me that it's a good
use of our time I've talked to a number
of people who are waiting for a
published spec before they touch
something like this those are the
circles that I tend to run in though I
guess we need to ask a saline said put
it to the list it was again a difficult
discussion like we had on a mailing list
um I hope we can make some progress on
this topic thank you thank you just I
think Kathleen a sign that Kathleen
Moriarty so this discussion really makes
it sound like it's still pretty stuck so
I put it to the list but I I don't know
if there's the drive at the moment I
mean what are the chairs think yet again
the slope it's stuck yeah yeah just make
sure on the list and then yeah the sad
thing is the sad thing is for this stuff
we actually have more implementations
than for some of the other proof
possession mechanism that we have been
looking at um okay it don't combining
for example token bindings yeah thank
you and token binding is not a proof of
possession mechanism for possession a
this is just done humanely yeah but it's
not bound to the chosen itself
necessarily of course it can mercies no
it's not a force it is there's a token
that a key there's a key in the token
yes but it doesn't need to be unique if
it doesn't need to be uniquely bound to
the token dis needa see this if das is
generating it but anyway but anyway um
doesn't matter um we put that we need to
discuss this on the list so we have five
minutes left um I'm a beach on you
could come over here and talk a little
bit about um potential future was he um
I wasn't going to dance there have been
requests so John Bradley ping so we
wanted to talk a bit about some of the
new work so on the resource indicator
which we've gone around about several
times Brian and a Ryan reposted our
original draft so I will point out that
this is essentially the same mechanism
that as your ad uses and when Tony gets
a pal point that out again when he
objects to it as a matter of principle
um so there is implementation experience
uh he's objecting you're confused it's
normal um the so we should consider
actually adopting that as as working
group document I don't know have you
with sort of stuck as as an individual
submission I don't so the chairs can
consider whether or not to to adopt that
there are other BCPs that we just talked
around William I've had a bunch of
inquiries from Microsoft in other places
around single page applications and what
the best practices are for that I'm
seeing like lots of Fortune 100
companies that have now all decided that
single page applications are cool but
have no idea how they're doing Oh off
with single page applications and that
is leading to some interesting
interpretations we can tell that he's
make that face every time he thinks of
it
uh and it's it's a little in line with
what we have discussed earlier in the
meeting when Tony and thick went to the
microphone I think it's a coincidence
but I think there's this more interest
now after its own native apps so we
should probably do some some polling as
to which yeah we only have so many
resources we should decide which topics
we want to work on once we have we have
the jasa JWT assertion profile we're
finishing off token exchanging cetera
there's a bunch of questions around it's
probably a bcp topic for
business-to-business um you know what
happens when your RS gets a token and
you actually want to do something with
it to talk to another Rs so I think we
have a bunch of sort of server-to-server
documents sort of user not present so
there's probably another DCP that what
what happens when you have this sort of
circumstance so that people can actually
see how those various documents work
together um there's also uh let ya know
he's just blocking the microphone for me
okay I didn't even bank he's going to
extract such as from me later I know I'm
just a spot enjoying the view I just
make one question John uh if you say
single page application what does it
mean is it the Jake JavaScript ok yeah
that javis people the trendy why I
didn't even know when I first heard it
there people were talking about single
page app I had no idea but that's no
posts for the snow gets requests yeah so
so out on the intertubes people refer to
the pattern of having a having
javascript in the executing in the
browser making web calls and API calls
using fetcher in various other
mechanisms as single page applications
okay toasting again so I'm
what support what you said hanas I think
if we make an enquiry let people give
feedback on where they see a real lead
for PC piece because we we have not that
plenty of capacity and I think we should
focus on the most relevant arm bc piece
the more the most relevant bc piece Tony
nodland just two for the record we don't
necessarily use a single page it's we
have a few applications that use that
that's not our main main driving force
in Azure the as your people have been
asking making inquiry there are certain
as I said there are some my girl as your
people that doesn't mean as you're okay
so okay so you ran out of time there
there are eight people who want to make
single page applications and God help
them some of them use as your butt on
that doesn't know yeah we are we ran out
of time um okay um but i'm going to what
i'm going to do is um i would boost a
message to the list to sort of ask for
the type of needs for pcbs that people
have and then we have to figure out on
how which one of those actually we can
work on first and which ones we have we
were late we also have some sort of
lingering work around post message for
authentication which probably depending
upon whether or not we actually are post
message for to replace using post
message to replace fragment encoding
which whether or not we go forward with
that somehow would impact on what the
best practice for single page
applications actually is twisting
postmessage just rang a bell in my head
so I'm Tolson
I think yeah you distracted me a man I
think our document can potentially
provide as the justification why it
makes sense to to have a postmessage
mechanism instead of our redirects for
fragments right so i think it was tested
could be one could be one way to pursue
ought to to to approach that topic yet
just as if he is more complicated there
are lots of hidden gotchas so that
probably also requires an open source
project and sample javascript to keep
people from shooting themselves in the
foot yeah but that what i would like to
to do what I mean is first we discuss
the need with all the pros and cons and
then if we decide to move that forward
then let's have a draft on post message
that's what I'm propose we already have
a draft on post message in the working
group it's just that people aren't
working on and we are running circles
yeah didn't we I thought you adopted
that ah no be we never okay we had one
document also in the open ID foundation
we never got anywhere and but we ran
over time already we need to push that
is that true I'm are we finished yes
yeah okay four minutes no time for the
song sorry quick get some drinks before
the plenary if you have the blue sheets
yeah please the blue should sign him if
you haven't Boston so so my did you not
gay no that I Medina given a mafia vs
guess somebody believe in it should oh
my gosh my can do that
I cannot secure topics