also um lindo dia and a bunch of data
yeah well enter and then we have to look
from their company
you start now okay awesome hi good
afternoon this is the wrong meeting
welcome okay for this meeting applied
they're not well so please rate you feel
like this flight attendants a very
important sinks and nobody's looking on
that okay please have a look yeah just
like that already internet okay this is
our agenda three some comments no see
okay and for our milestones we have done
the routing dispatch work and we have
the use of a weapon information in
working goodness corn so please comments
in the Middle East and then in January
we are going to reach out there or close
for the working group last call we have
had very little return so I really
encourage you to especially after the
nice dog by Michael that's coming to
comment on the draft and at least try to
read it and send your comments like I
tried it and I proof of this
for the publication of this rafter will
be very welcome indeed thank you ok this
is the state of the active internet
draft we have a mission editor and cue
the applicability template is going to
be like expired um loading this petition
iono and use of ripple information is in
last column and we don't have right now
open tickets okay they are related
internet draft a move them they are
going to present today okay lots of
these drafts are not just working group
to house but certainly I mentioned in
the the Charter which is still to be
approved so we will ask you for if you
are really interested in the dropships
they should become working cockpit so we
will ask after every presentation what
you think about if if it should go
forward but you have to be confirmed on
the mailing list afterwards of course
yeah okay okay we send the chart there
to our other detector and we got some
comment box back and we edited the
Charter we send to the mailing list on
these are the modifications so please
read the Charter that is in the Middle
East and send your comments thank you
and if you don't hear anything we will
push it forward to IES you so much yeah
Michael I went to present the status of
this draft thank you hi so as was
mentioned it's been in working group
last call um prior to the or app just
prior to the last ITF arm six men made
some interesting changes which were very
helpful to us arm in particular allows
us to leave RPI
in arm on the assumption that they will
not be processed whatever that means arm
and you can go to six men and enjoy that
debate arm that the so that's really all
that the most of that's changed in the
past three or four months has been
editorial clarifying of some terms we
had a lovely review from Peter thank you
very much about some of the things
they're still missing and um that's
really it again it is a long document
and it takes a bit of effort to
understand and there are some really
good slides that we we had in the last
the last ITF if you need help because
they're animated um and i really suggest
you take a look at it because it really
does define something has been missing
in this working group is exactly what
the data plane looks like and this
clarifies that i think great deal that's
really it not a lot else to say we'd
like to publish it get it done cummings
anyone read it in this room yes that's
what's the question Wow okay cool and
got some questions they're good avocado
from hobby my question is this this
decision of leaving the rpi yes intact
while moving it out of the network the
6lowpan network of whatever yeah so this
decision reduces the complexity as i
understand you know after reading the
graph so far from there is there any
like why was this decision i it's it's
it is possible for the the edge router
to remove the rpi header so why was this
decision taken to just simply allow it
it's not possible for the edge router to
remove the rpi header because headers
may not be inserted or removed in
transit okay so so that's an important
thing and whether or not that rule is
changed or not by by six men it has
until very recently been believed to be
it firm okay
that the the difficulty was that given
that we can't remove it at the edge and
given that the header has been marked as
critical or it's a header extension at
hop-by-hop extension marked critical
given that it's been marked critical
then the next router that does not speak
understand it according to historical
understanding was intended was would it
be expected to drop the traffic
therefore any traffic that unintended ly
would be contained ok ok the downside is
that of course we would like to send
traffic the whole point of a mesh that's
you know connected by IP is that you
might like to send traffic outside of
that mesh so arm in order to be able to
remove it what we discovered was that we
have to put I PA p headers in which has
a significant cost and which we then
have figured out how to compress such
that we can remove them so now that that
we we realize that we are not obligated
to remove that header then a number of
scenarios where we require to put an IP
IP header in arm become uh not so
critical ok ok and and that was that
that's that's really important because
it turns out there's some other
scenarios independent of sending traffic
to the quote internet if you have uh
what are properly called hosts or
sometimes in this we can group we call
nan RPL aware leaf nodes right those may
not necessarily understand that header
and if we would like to send traffic to
them then we need to know when to remove
that header and weird if we were faced
with the difficulty that in many modes
in particular story mode we don't know
what the node before the end header node
is and since we don't know that node we
wind up having to put hop by hop IP IP
headers which means we have to remove
them at every hop and add them at every
hop ok so that's a bit of a pain in the
ass it's complicated
code it's it seems dumb it's redundant
no one implements that and so in the end
with this so what I document in the end
does is it makes it clear you don't need
to remove them and at the end node will
deal with them okay right let's get you
mail that there's a few things we just
in flux and there is now the influence
of the new six flourish on coding which
might actually change the deal a little
bit first thing is 46 man nothing is
recast in stone i think the the
consensus right now is that the update
of 2560 will not change anything
dramatically because you just you have
to go to interest energy you don't
change the way things behave so that i
think the consensus about going
producing new specs about what you can
do and what you cannot do and the
arguments against inserting others don't
necessarily apply to removing others so
um what i'm getting at is if you've got
this packet coming from the ll n going
outside the other end through the root
ah i think it still if the root can the
best practice for us should be to remove
that header now doing that in the
uncompressed form is probably cumbersome
but if you look at the way we design the
compressed form it's really designed so
that you can play this sort of trick for
instance the rotting either the rs3 when
it's compressed with six leverage its
replaced at the beginning of the
compressed form so that you can really
cling remove addresses as you consume
them right and the next thing you find
and if you don't have in the packet
going out you don't have a rotting
either the first thing you find if you
have a packet which does not have a pin
ID right that's what we are getting at
we don't have IP in IP but we've gotten
our PR well if you look at the
compressed form
the FBI comes first which we tells you
that at the moment where you expand the
64 edge into an ipv6 packet to go to the
Internet you could actually cut it up
you could cut it out yeah and just just
ignore it when going to the Internet and
I think at the moment with what I know
the best practice should be don't do I
pinay p for a packet going out if you
know that's going out don't do IP IP
just to API but with at the root snip it
up so so that could happen I'm not
screwing with you and that the
documented says right now essentially
says don't do for upwards traffic don't
do IP and IP just do RPI that's true for
storing and non storing mode and that's
nice it's a single transmit path for
upwards traffic and the decision as to
remove it or not is a decision at the
root which is probably more capable more
configurable and more upgradable so
that's that's uh on some sense a
decision by the operator to do that as
for the arguments for removing the
headers are probably not as strong as
inserting certainly one of the arguments
is that it breaks pathum to you is not
true that it breaks authentication
header is true on that where this may
not be relevant because it's not clear
we're using a H headers ever but there
may be other things that matter so I'm
comfortable with it is and I'm
uncomfortable the fact that we can send
them out to the internet and not break
the architecture as it is I think that
that's a good scenario one of the
questions I know we did get from one of
the reviewers somewhere was how we know
whether we're using this this
formulation or the other one and I know
that the six low rh got the same
question
and essentially my answer as well we
know that the six lower age is a is is
deployed by Fiat you know you decide
you're doing it it's on and that's it
there's no there's no flag days but but
essentially if if if a node needs to
know whether or not it can follow the
use of rpi rules or that should follow
some historical process then I would say
well if it's doing 60 rh header
compression as we've described then it
should it should follow these rules and
that's the reality whatever is doing
happen before is some other scenario
right and just for the best get to go
again for the point of aah same
discussion applies to sleeping out
addresses in the rotting either as the
packet progresses down the non starring
network and so that's been your debate
as well and what past is G now because
it's in the RFC editor queue with the
six flower age is that we actually snip
those addresses so as to save energy etc
etc and there's a discussion in the
future RFC about the fact that it breaks
aah with the fact that we don't you we
don't have a specification for IH in in
those networks anyway so we don't there
is no plan to use it and we the only
value of using aah with rotting either
is that it's the role by 2460 that if
you want to reverse the routing either
to go the way back then you need to have
proven it by aah I mean that's that's a
value of IH there's not no read other
work for that header there may have some
value some some other header yeah yeah
yeah but but so far we don't yes that's
true but as soon as you get that I agree
with effectively the rules for removing
headers are as weak as for inserting
headers for our point of view and and I
think we could I think we could do that
I think that we should write that down
as a separate document and have a
separate debate over what the what the 6
lb are should do on outgoing packets if
if you feel strongly that it should
remove the RPI on then I think we should
write that down separately as a separate
document because essentially decidable
by the six la 6lb are independently of
any of the other other decisions okay
that's what I was getting at and my
point was we should have a
recommendation in this document about
that but you think we should say
something there well somebody has to say
something somewhere all right i mean i
agree with the way document is welded so
far that we don't do I pinay p I think
it's safe but now what do we do with the
rpi I think it's always safer not to
keep it in the IP packet mean what's the
point in putting it I mean at least you
know if you'd get the cisco reg
formulation it's very easy to snip it up
it's actually more complex to keep it
because you have to reincarnate into the
compressible uncompressed form if you
have a non six large packet i would say
okay pressing the packets always a risk
so why don't you pass it down so so
keeping the capability to either pass it
on or not pass it down but i would say
basically the recommendation would be
600 hu sniff it out plenty i catch you
keep it something like that can we
continue this offline oh oh please pass
calculus a Sally sampai refer to add to
the document well this yes I mean I I
feel I I feel that that will be that
will that will drag this document into
the six men morass and and so so what I
would that's why I would propose that we
we do this is a separate document and we
wait three to five months for 2460 bits
to settle and and then we will either
point to the resulting thing and say it
says we can do it so we're doing it or
we won't and that gets us out of
otherwise I think that we're going to
get I think that we're going to get
blocked on a review somewhere or you
know but I would not like to ship these
documents saying do but you know at
least if we do like logical 60 we don't
say anything but saying do keep the rpi
in the back of the Safari time you said
you can keep the rpi in the packet as it
goes out it's not it's you don't have to
remove it by putting IP IP header we
didn't tell you to remove it
we said you can leave it in right so
there so L aveiro like do you agree with
me that that I think we're stepping into
a disaster if we go somewhere else or do
you think God's I'm wrong it's over I've
ever gonna I don't know exactly where
six man is so yeah maybe having we may
not so the anima I'm sure that most of
you probably follows these men a lot
closer than I do so I'll let the working
group decide what everyone okay yeah but
I'm hearing is we should ask Suresh okay
okay thinking we could create a ticket
about that so we can keep working on
that that's one all right just to track
these I'd like to pop I could be done
with that's what I would prefer that's
why I don't want to open a new issue but
I mean tell me how strong you feel about
it I I think that we could easily write
this as a later document because I think
that it's operate a balut and it's
easily the route is relatively easy
upgradeable versus the firmware this
decision has no effect on the small
devices out in the out on the edge of
the network okay thank you thank you
very much icon thank you and please read
the document I mean that's important
enough to read it and the sense of
comments that please thank you very much
Michael mm-hmm our next topic LDV ripple
with Charlie Perkins
so I have to tell you what the chase
lines oh no that's not what I need any
you need to sing into it I don't see it
no no I need them okay I gun okay well
I'm Charlie Perkins and I'm here to tell
you a little bit about the updates to
our document a 0 DB ripple and um it's a
sort of a new take on the p2p our peer
to peer use of ripple and there's an
experimental document RFC 69 97 but able
to V extends the functionality from that
document so we support the story mode
and we have both the old wait a minute
I'm tally yeah now is working thank you
okay boy things change fast around here
so we have a sub support for symmetrical
and asymmetrical but still
bi-directional are links and this
approach avoids the requirement for
having an address vector as in the
product from the previous document p2p
RPL so the way it is we have route
request message and replied this sub is
more or less adapted for use with ripple
from the work that was done unnao TV and
a 0 DB version 2 and another working
group and oops now what I do holy smokes
sorry I must have a big thumb so the
changes that were made as we actually
wanted to reduce the amount of space
that is required in a rare reply and we
could do that by actually having us
repaired dode eggs and so we wanted to
have an easy association between the
route reply and the request and the way
we did that not fairly straightforward
way which I'll mention in just a minute
the route request actually is sent from
the requesting node or the originating
node to finally received by the target
and but the when when the target
received at what has happened is that
the target now has a way to transmit
package from from itself to the
originating node and the route reply
then is transmitted back towards the
originating node according to some path
possibly a symmetric path and when it
arrives then the originating node has a
way to transmit packets are transmitted
data to the target node so don't breeder
is that there's a adesh a3 document
that's available and actually this squat
this slide describes the changes between
our previous one document and the end of
three so the draft update specifies this
way of pairing the request and reply
instances and it allows us to eliminate
a large field in the route reply message
and we have implementations in process
there's a work that you can read it
there works on kontiki with the kuja
simulator which by the way I did not do
this work but one that co-authors and SV
Anand has done this so it does and
implementation supports about symmetric
and asymmetric modes and if making
comparisons against a ripple storage
mode so we will make a more full report
on this at the next ITF this has worked
it's in process and the intention is to
actually make a demo at the next time
ITF
so the pairing works so that you can
have the upstream is considered to be
transmission from the destination or
target node back to the originating node
and downstream the other direction so
the upstream sense instanceid for the
route request instance is selected to be
an odd number and then the intermediate
routers stored that instance ID and then
when the rat reply comes back it's the
route request instance plus 1 and so
that makes it straightforward for the
intermediate routers to know what is the
originating node towards which they are
establishing the reverse path so that's
the main technical difference of nuh is
now present in the updated draft the I'm
not going to go into the gratuitous
robbery right we play it's it's the same
as it was before but basically on now we
allow it to work with this some way of
doing a paired pairing between the route
request and route reply instances
implementation is mentioned before is
done on the kontiki and I guess it's
supposed to be available in github soon
and soon I guess means this year so we
are planning to run a lot of experiments
on various Network scenarios to see what
the performance gains are and then so on
and to put together a demonstration for
the March idea I guess that's it any
comments or questions Ravi Giada from
wally so uh one of the claim of the
previous draft I mean have not gone
through the latest dr. povitch's for
that the previous draft said that this
enables asymmetric operations a
symmetric link so basically but the way
previous draft of operated was by
sending message from A to B and
establishing route in the reverse
direction oh yes we distinguish between
asymmetric and unity
fictional so there's always a path to go
back but the asymmetry comes about by
enabling the reverse link to have a much
different metric or a much different
time that's a feasibility then so you
might want to have a union you might
want to have the best path going from
source to destination by a much
different mechanism than from
destination to source but we do expect
at least that the control messages will
be transmitted in the metrics evaluated
in that way so if you want to enable
fully the more general case for there
are unidirectional links then I think
additional work is needed ok ok one more
question regarding the simulation that
was done in the kontiki so which model
was selected was was it was it you GD
amor de grm so I mean basically I want
to understand if the default mode was
selected which I mean if you use the
default mode definitely the previous
doctor at least would work yeah well for
that I I have to tell you I don't have
that information since i'm not doing the
simulation network when contiki but its
own brush it do you know anything about
the kontiki platform you probably should
use a mic I'm putting him on the spot
here oh not at this moment all right now
okay more questions well ok thank you
Charlie thank you very much all right uh
whom read a document raise our hands ok
ok life who wants to review this
document and collaborate on it one once
I just review review our industry you
yeah 11 ok to actually test killed
encouraged me to do this in the first
place so you should use yeah how about
you go straining willing to review I
know the feeling thank you very much
thank you very much Pascal please it's
kyle next speaker tell projection ah ah
you can so I'm past caring with Cisco
presenting on the dial projection so
basically we've kept this yeah we've got
this well the repo protocol which
actually enables a number of different
ways of doing things which is so that we
could actually turn repo and we knew it
from from the experimental RFC before
into a reactive protocol we can also
easily turn repo into a centralized
routing approach and we've not done that
before but there are a number of
applications for which this could be
useful an example application is
industrial control loops so what you
build this ripple based cluster of
sensors and actuators and programmable
logic controllers and with this you can
enable control loops inside your factory
network but then at some point you want
to establish special path between this
particular sensor and this particular
actuator with guarnteed capabilities for
instance you had a six digit ACH Mac
layer and with this Mac layer you can
program time slots so as to to grantee
deterministically a path between the
sensor this plc programmable logic
controller and then back to an actuator
if you want to do that you need a a way
to go and program the path the rods into
the devices so at some point you need to
program the time slot themselves and
that's not the objective at all for this
work but on the other hand you also need
to program the rats into the devices and
if you're well it depends on which one
are you peek but if you want to use
writing you need to go and program the
rod and so this is one way of actually
using repo as the protocol to install
efficiently a route between the point a
and point B inside this disla policy
Network so what we do add two 6550 is
really this capability to to add routes
on demand and other control of the root
but the root itself and we don't have to
specify how that happens can be in touch
with a PC satirized rotting controller
which can tell the route which routes to
install so the first application for
this is kind of obviously because that's
where it started a way to comprise
source right path if you get a deep
network and you're using non story mode
at some point you'd say oh if I've got
this particular long line here on the
right and they know the capabilities the
memory space that you get in those
devices I could actually save all these
sort information in all those packets by
installing pinpointing some rods in
those particular nodes and since it's
done centrally it can be done with some
awareness of how much memory there is in
those devices so you know you're not
overloading those devices by this
additional rod so this the first usage
and there's some new text in in version
3 is about compressing the strict sauce
rod header and making it loose around
other from our way so the routing matrix
also will play a role when you populate
a part downstream so how would you take
care of that ok so the path is actually
in non story mode is actually already
decided by the dowel process which
creates the non store across so
so the cost it's done its work is done
the topology is built what you're doing
for the non story mode is you are just
compressing the expression of that path
but you are not changing the way you
compute it so the cost is past its it's
done ok ok so as I understand it
correctly so you're saying that since
that the node has already sent a dau is
it has already taken into consideration
the metrics and decided the bio yeah the
eieio and then it has already decided we
share yes I know the world knows that it
would build this long sauce wat header
to go down this path and I have picture
of that so what you really want to do
now is shrink the expression of that
path in the non story mode packet by
installing pinpoint state in specific
individual ok ok right but you're not
it's not a routing protocol it's just a
way of enabling a little bit of storing
mode in a non-story network so that you
can transform streets of rotting in
toulouse so Swati right right and this
is doable because the route is expected
to know the capability of the mode so it
goes on this node i can install 5 rods
let me optimize which not get which
information hmm now that the version 2
of this draft introduced a story mode
variation of that which cannot be fully
achieved until we send more information
into the route about the topology
because the non story mode only work
works on the information that the route
already has which is enough information
you just follow the same time if you
want to use the second technology which
is enabled by this draft which works in
storing mode as well towards in both
modes you need some additional protocol
element which this draft is not
providing and we have to decide if one
to take this path and provide those
elements within the
draft or with another draft and with
these additional topological elements
you can be able to transfer soul path
divus tration so let's go through those
slots okay so there are those two modes
will have to decide if we pursue this
draft whether we do or need a non-story
in which case we don't need new protocol
elements or if we also want to do the
transversal path which is really
interesting piece in in some scenarios
like industrial and in that case we'll
need to talk about topological elements
how we express that to the root or to
the PC like tease you know this type of
information that net so it's no nothing
much I I mostly did editorial work fixed
the abstract which was deal from version
1 so we talked about so throughout and
so clarified what you can do with this
transversal rods which were introduced
in version 2 so I am is we could work on
the draft a lot but at some point we
really need to see where the working
group wants to do about those two
technologies if you want to pursue them
and then we can work together also type
1 a-ron shadow from worry one of the
discussions we had on mailing list was
you know not related directly on this
draft the discussion was whether a
mixed-mode kind of operation be
supported would this draft enable by any
chance it is a mixed mode which of the
very very controlled mixed mode because
the problem with mixed mode is same
promise as storing mode is controlling
the amount of rods that you push into
the devices and that's that's really why
we have those two modes in rebirth I
mean this discussion was like years ago
but the discussion was like this storing
mode looks of like a very good idea
until you reach the limits of a note and
so we said okay so we could have and I
seen your work which is doing that again
we we could have some intelligence so as
to refuse a down from a child if the
table is already saturated
um and you could do that but then you're
pushing the Prime on the neighbor and
maybe the neighbor at the same Prime and
needs to be pushed and some point there
is no way right so so that that kind of
pushes the Prime a little bit and
enables a bit more well a number of new
situations but it doesn't solve the
problem it just pushes the prime for
further away the approach can it's very
hard to make the distributed approach
work and so we can try but it's very
hard the centralized approach is doable
because the route knows which routes
it's injecting into the network right so
it does that because it has information
about the capabilities of the node
that's part of the expectation you know
which notes you're talking about you
know how much stage you can install
those nodes you know the lifetime of
this state so it's very controlled so
that's the solution of the real problem
which is how do you know you're not
overloading the whole thing so that's
that's the low-hanging fruit in this
direction outside but the real prime is
much much harder thank you my questions
so angry provided slice which I won't
play but it's if you want to go through
how these things work in the
illustration in the coming slides which
will be published I guess on the side
yeah yeah we can so I just thank you who
has read this draft one two three four
five six seven eight okay who wants to
contribute or at least review this class
who wants to review this draft one three
four five six six and who thinks that
this should be part of our work mmm
lentils four five six okay okay so we
have to confirm the sphere the beylin
list yeah yeah thank you very much
Muskaan yeah
slice okay okay um oh good morning lots
of jet lag well I try to see if there's
any interest in the work we did it is
about nipple and especially about the
number of four virus you have any metal
in an internetwork if you have lots of
network which is very dense and there
are lots of four virus in it maple for
routers then when you want to multicast
the message you get an enormous storm of
broadcast messages and that's not really
helping the performance of the network
so for those networks it is important
that you can reduce the number of maples
so that the Equality the density of
maple for virus in the network is not
too not too high and you can have a
reasonable number of messages so that's
what we try to do here i have an example
robot you might like yo you have this
network if they're all forwarders and
one will start the forwarding you will
get all the other blue ones will forward
it only only one hop is dated to go to
the ones on the left and from the ones
to left on to the others if you only
select for example 24 hours in the
middle then the number of maple for
other messages company is reduced and
the performance of the network is much
better yeah how many forward a suit you
select well if you have some network
where you have only one hope network and
then you think more forward a sufficient
and you would need one for order because
suppose that you have a broadcast coming
from the right hand green note it was
sent it to everybody they receive the
message but then bounced the link is
between the dead link has done then
you're very happy that they're still and
passed which goes for you the forwarder
to the other nodes which has this
mission link so having at least one when
you have maple and you wanted more
reliability having at least one for
Weiser also in the single hope network
is sync encouraged the other case is
that you have them too hot network and
then you want at least 24 hours i think
because if the link to some of the
forerunners and the destinations breaks
down then you have the second forward to
continue so the reliable ability is
riddled increased we did some
measurements in an offices and we sold
that actually the even stable links a
better as is very good etc that if you
will say 20 minutes per week you have
links which actually crash and then you
have these two routers you just continue
working during during the year yeah
doctor so what does the note maintain we
might try to keep to it another simple
and what you do is that we have count
the number of neighbors which have the
state that there for barter state is FF
means I'm a for barter so every note
maintains the number of neighbors that
he has that he has a forward of is and
the other one is that he looks at the
number of neighbors there the number of
for virus is slow lagos by smaller than
the wanted number of forwarders and
duplicate which you should well in this
stuff work isn't course to be too and we
have also an hour both there's the
number of neighbors which is larger than
n duplicate because value constructing
the num is selecting the number of for
virus you will see that well it's not
fantastic every time so that when you
have too many men neighbors which has
for viruses selected within a certain
area you can reduce it and also then the
network configuration changes so you can
select other ones and they move on so to
keep this reasonable now i have a very
complex picture oh yeah this is the next
one so what do the notes they do they
sent a link locomotive cast and they
send their adverse there says I the
number of four
for bar the neighbors to have the end or
under and n are both deaf and their own
state of course she were format is used
who doesn't and only messages from her
yeah even draft so I the only messages
from fell out neighbors taken into
account and only message message
reception you updated note and you
execute the selection algorithm expect
complex oh here's the commissary here's
the complex picture I wanted to show
that this NR under actually gives you
information about the to to the to the
to help to hop neighbors yeah so i have
here to sit bones were selected to be a
forwarder you will see that the Wonder
in the middle he sees that this number
of for viruses to you see only others
that they have the number for viruses to
and then you have all these months which
are the neighbors which have to enter
under they can tell and by selecting the
one which has the highest and are under
for all your neighbors you may consider
that this is the highest number of notes
you are helping with this for Ryder so
what we do is we look at the number try
to select death note of all the
neighbors which has the higher numbers
of Anna rounder and that number may be
the same for several notes into town
break ties we use the network address so
choose the highest one for example to
have only one note of all the neighbors
which are actually going to be for
murder yeah you don't want all them of
them decide simultaneously so this is
what it on selection algorithm so every
note orders the neighbors including
itself on the N or unknown number value
and the address so that you have this
and what do you do is select at the
first one and if that you and become a
forwarder simple as that you also look
at NR above this first star ignore and
if it's equal to the number of valid
neighbors you know that all neighbors
see too many months and you know that if
you are and forward your
Islam too many in this company and you
remove yourself yeah so that's how first
there's also an you want this to happen
in a stable network so you don't want to
make decisions about networks which are
constantly changing aspects so what the
cotillion for that is to look at the
looking at all the neighbor messages and
if the NR undervalue is changing if the
end are under value changes you don't do
anything once that you see the deer in
cycle all the message are the same it's
the same and a runner for oldham you say
look here I'm stable I can make my
decision yep some examples so if here
and that did some simulations of it the
distance between the notes are about 10
meters it isn't too hot network so the
ones down below don't see the ones up
above but the month in the middle
apparently see all of them you want to
have in the past between all the four
murders so what to do I first make sure
that there is long for water and a
forwarder can only be selected when he
sees another forward so which issues
that there is a path between all four
murders otherwise you may get have
separate set of forward a switch and you
don't want it so here it looks rather
nice I don't think you can do much
better than that however if the distance
between the notes is harder is larger so
the density has decreased then the
things become a bit more less optimistic
you see that where they're very good
ones are each note is marked with the
number of forward as it sees and they
all have at least two where you see when
the number of for where this is five or
six you may wonder if it should not be
removed while giving the algorithm where
we had you see that actually some of
them remove themselves yeah so one of
those there the life blue one has been a
forward but you saw that the density was
too high if the others do not go down it
means that on the edge at least there is
one note which only sees two 4runners
and you can do not remove himself yeah
so
probably when you look at the evolution
of the Anne Arundel etcetera can do much
more with so all the data you get in the
algorithm and do some refinements I
didn't do them I've here another example
also so it is a very dense network it's
not too bad actually this egra also is
not too bad and they all have see the
two 4runners so now I'm pleasantly
surprised and the question askers sorry
so I wanted to continue the work if
there's enough interesting it if not to
know let me just stop it I'm I'm Charlie
perkinson I think this is a great idea
was involved a lot with the forwarding
specification in manet and there's been
a huge amount of work on this area I
mean I one of the terms that's used is
connected dominating set when you're
trying to construct one so I but I guess
to have a couple of questions I mean
first of all do you really think that
it's typically important to have more
than one forwarder yes I mean that's if
you want at least one hundred percent
availability over a year in this room
and not when you switch it off you say
all right good quarter or for now and
try again yes you need at least in one
hop networks at least one and in larger
network we have multiple hops you need
as many forward ssink yeah you mean
you're saying you need duplicate brownie
district at shell so and duplicates 14
Milty of networks I try to discourage
that's idea okay and I guess it's so you
know your pictures are all sort of
regular arrays Oh sites of overall I
think that could be end up being a
little bit misleading I quite agree if
there are other misleading sings I mean
may choose your network addresses such
that the algorithm is improved I mean
there are lots of things you can do but
yeah what I also wanted to do is look if
this how far is from the optimal so how
many forwarders you look for the optimal
case I didn't do all these things I mean
I just was happy with this for the
moment and so it's I guess it's is it
agree that it's really for this working
group mainly of interest for stabili
located devices ah that's a very good
question what is stable I mean this
table is with respect to the number of
times you sent your you sent your
message out so if you sense out your
maple let's just like they did every
five minutes and you have about twenty
neighbors then stable is longer than 20
times five minutes yeah okay thank you
welcome um Michael Richardson so trying
to understand that the diagrams in this
diagram for instance to all do the nodes
on the far left can hear the nodes and
the far right no no this is a multi
network how far do they here okay can I
point it out sure so the one the left
mark zero can see as far as the month
one marked 11 okay okay that's that's
great to understand and I think you said
I was going to ask something about about
uh about your definition of stable as
well and it sounds like you couldn't so
you can basically if the if the
instability of the of the network or if
it's not fixed orbits moving if it's
slow enough compared to your your
transmission time then it effectively
stable yeah so you can this can be set
so actually I wanted to make the
protocol search the dependent on what
you see you decrease or increase that
cool um well so my other I haven't read
your documented also i really have no
idea so is is your does your does your
protocol live on top of
um trickle on trick on trickle so it's a
it's a it's a independent of the the
nipple forwarding itself okay so that
what I was curious about is that it that
I I know little about this but they're
the people that are trying to do beer to
rip to do multicast it sound I think
that they would benefit from having this
minimum set of devices that they could
address that would then do that so I
think that would be a you're absolutely
right my disgust is disgusting and its
first salt three months two months ago
they saw that it might help to reduce
the number of offer pass that they had
to look at yeah ok cool no it can be
used for other ones as well I mean not a
living piscataway I love this so if you
you're looking for voices to say yes to
continue please continue this work okay
um it looks to me that it's an
interesting variation around and
something very similar acronym which is
NPR the multi punch realize you know and
i saw and i was just wondering it seems
to me that you're looking for an optimum
for certain radio condition you know the
radio conditions change a lot there's
also if you're talking about power
non-pom advice is battery-operated
devices then you may be draining the
battery of the same devices all the time
all the time and i was wondering if you
could inject some viability in the
algorithm so you would periodically
maybe not get the optimized thing but
optimized with the radio matrix is never
perfect anyway but have some rotation
mechanism so that it would not always be
3 11 24 and sometimes would be this guy
above three and this guy and the high
level on the left but the more notes but
excellent i think excellent idea
actually it's fits with my mom of my
other sorts because when we when I see
the stable solutions if you move around
the forward a little bit to another
location the whole pattern may look
differently and you may remove of them
so i was thinking of actually an
implementation
you may improve by moving them around
and so moving them around would be a
good idea i think actually in general
yeah okay thank you very much Peter who
have read the dot he written ok too ok
please read it and comments on my mini
list everyone sign these ok some more
questions or laps or comments no
comments on the progress no comments on
the Charter everybody happy to go
forward as we are intended to yep right
ok ok thank you very much thank you very
much have a nice day how nice thing we
needs the other one where is the other
one blue