okay we start this sunset phone meeting
so there is no magic I'm neither where's
nor much I'm Eric drink yeah I'm a
lifeboat or whatever right I'm a guy in
these guys Markus to leave the ATF
yesterday to go to Amsterdam and what is
unable to join so I'm you're agreeing
and I'm will be acting as your chairman
here we have a jab escribe thank you
Michael for doing it I am still missing
a minute taker Tim in the taker you'll
volunteer yourself to be the mid taker
okay so thank you
team for volunteering somehow let's go
further note well we are Thursday second
session so mostly you know that
everything you say here even the public
basically blue sheets so they are
circulating don't forget to fill them
out that's maybe next time we get a
bigger room maybe the agenda for today a
quick session introduction that's what
I'm doing here then we have given to Lee
45 minutes talking about is old and new
draft and Emily stack will be joining us
at the end to talk about the specific
problem about the localhost OHS name in
HTTP mainly but basically no application
i want to remind because it may be open
to discussion some point of time today
with elise session I took some extract
from the sunset for charter it really
says the working group will point on
specific areas of concern which may be
applicable here provide recommendation
and satellites protocol that facilitated
by blahblahblah you can read and at the
end the second bold statement the
working group will report on common
issues provide recommendation and so on
and so to keep this in mind because it
may be useful for the description during
the least session so thank you eat and
we have a kicker for you and you know
the pink box right hi I had I had I had
their mi mi mi audio am I am I audible I
know oh yeah thanks Davy you're right
next you can hear me yes ll decide this
way so I had so much fun at our last
meeting that I decided to come back and
talk some more uh before I get into the
draft I want to sort of review some
action items from the last me this sort
of the notes that I took away from our
last face
meeting first of all is we asked that
suggested the IV could make a statements
to SD OS on ipv6 done we are still
working the mechanics of actually
getting our liaisons to send that to the
stos not all stos need that statement
for instance or not all of our liaisons
need to for that statement for instance
i can has actually done you know they've
got the website they're not doing
networking protocols they're they're in
pretty good shape the statement doesn't
apply um iesg statement on ipv4 work so
the iesg said you know we probably could
say something about continued ipv4 work
or stopping a ipv4 work but it would be
much stronger to have an ietf consensus
statement on that and that's why I'm
back so that's what I'm doing that one
we could update the v4 historic draft
I've got a note on that a minute draft
PHP Phillip Holland Baker had ideas
about ipv4 sunset is complicated and
what the steps might be I've asked him a
couple of times hey do you want to work
on a document can I help what would you
like to see in it and I haven't heard
back so that's what status is they're
updating the I Dean its checkered to
check for ipv4 literals that was done
while we were in Buenos Aires that was
fantastic cleaning up documents that
have V for liberals examples of
dependencies I don't think that's going
to I don't think this probably gonna be
a major effort to go back and revise
existing rfcs that have those but it's
something I think everybody ought to be
paying attention to as we're seeing
document drafts coming through and I
think we are seeing that and then
finally running v6 up winning the the
the IETF nat64 SSID as our default SSID
well you've heard about that the plenary
last night genres ASCII said hey we
should totally do this I think there was
very positive response to that I'm
curious how many people in the room are
using or have been using IETF nat64 at
the meeting this week okay okay so
people raise your hand are you sure to
turn the right room so uh and and i'm
very curious why people who aren't using
it aren't using it i will say that i'm
not using it because my primary email
account isn't working on that SSID i
can't pop my mail from that point for my
primary mail server
so I've opened a ticket with a knock and
said this is an issue for me if
everybody would please get on that SSAT
find out what breaks open a ticket with
the knock then we can start working
through what are the broken issues and
either then reveal issues back to IETF
that need work or reveal issues to you
know the the company's some of that
think that was it Spotify that was
mentioned to the tech plenary so we can
go thurs escape so Mike you can speak
the real question is is net 64 the
correct ipv4 mmv 6mm protocol to use
there are others which have less impacts
on the end user than that 64 and then s6
for David's can I see Apple like John's
remarks question I won't make any
comment on what the correct one is there
there is no such thing and we can write
or four days about it nat64 is the de
facto one that is being used it's the
one that's being deployed where network
operators today fact so I don't think
there is value in wondering what the
perfect one or the best one is we just
need to pick one and move on like
otherwise we'll never transition so too
is there slight a nap and other things
just because this how people seem to
think this is the best guess for some
inverted commas the best it actually has
lots of operational issues which the
others do not have and as far as I can
till it prides no benefits over the
others it has women in fact that it is
there in the real world well so am i
curious why great dual stack light is
also deployed in the real world for 64 X
lad is also deployed in the real world
in different 64 next flat is an at 64
with Connie's I'd to go well the same
fact that the mechanics malice angry
teen the Nick it's a funny
okay rattling okay yeah so yeah if you
can push the two Mike you quickly
Charlie palette I think that's that's
actually the problem we need to first
define what is our goal and our lawless
break things or allow the people to keep
working without breaking things and at
the same time make sure that every
single keep working in the future which
ipv6 hungry because if that's the case i
mention already in the in the plenary
mailing list what we need to do is not
use just a half solution like nat64 we
need a solution that behaves like in the
real world and the real war is people
having private ipv4 addresses and
probably as more the times goals on
we'll have ipv6 only access and that's
not not 64 because applications still
use little addresses like Spotify skype
and so on so what we need to do is to
try that solution in our own network as
primary as SSID and at the same time in
the select if for example we choose X
for a 4 64 X lat in the Select diamond
in our first hop router have some kind
of logging that allows us to identify
what applications are using the select
which means that in future meetings we
can have tall those application vendors
this is not working sort it out and then
we can go to a solution like only not 64
but first we need an intermediate the
stage German koi I think there are a lot
of networks around Eugene has been sadya
not 64 vis v6 only because it's from
operational perspective it's much better
than heaven doorstep and there's like a
lotta stuff and I do not think that
introducing this as a default IETF SSID
will break addition because there are
other SSID always fall back to do a
stack if you have problem so I think
we've done a tripe at some point right
so it will it was communicated to users
please try
v6 only if you have problems which back
to dual stack and if you fix your you
show cave and all we know it's because
of I v6 all right now we need to
stop here it's not the main topic
awfully sorry I would think this is
great for the list though right we've
started this conversation on the list
let's carry it on there alright so I
mentioned that I would come back and ok
doesn't work next slide and next slide
so I have not updated v4 historic
because i didn't think that folks were
actually ready to talk about it anymore
just yet these are the three fairly
minor notes that i had from the last
meeting on the updates to make so if you
want other updates net send it to the
list and i'll get them done next slide
so today's draft and work on ipv4 next
slide the abstract says the IETF will
stop working on ipv4 except where needed
to mitigate documented security issues
to facilitate the transition to ipv6 or
2 enable ipv4 decommissioning this is
what I was trying to get at this is in
some ways similar to the previous drafts
but this is again the goal of this
document is we had asked the iesg to
make a statement about not chartering
new ipv4 work and that's so that's
that's what I'm try to get it here next
slide I think it'll be incredibly boring
if I actually read all the slides to you
because they're just sort of beads of
text like this but if you'll take 20
seconds to read this
okay obviously what I'm trying to do is
give everybody a chance to read the
draft I have the entire draft up here
it's about 200 words the one note i want
to emphasize here and i have it
emphasized on the slide is that ipv4
focused activities in some in support of
security transition and decommissioning
will continue and maybe i should say
orchid decommissioning where accompanied
by a problem statement if nobody commits
based on operational experience if
nobody can say this is an actual problem
is just a philosophical problem or a
speculative speculated problem I let's
not work on it okay next slide so it's
will update protocols and features to
facilitate decommissioning will
explicitly support ipv6 or if it's IP
version agnostic because it's a higher
in the stack for instance then that's
fine except for we still do ipv4 up
except that before specific transition
technologies which I come back to you on
the next slide to say we will not
initiate any new ipv4 extension
technology development and the point
there is we can work on and this is a
potential point for discussion we could
work on additional transition mechanisms
maybe somebody has a great idea we
haven't come up with yet and it's not
too late to design and deploy it I doubt
it but any training future transition
mechanisms we might work on or you know
or enhancing our existing transition
mechanisms we won't work on ipv4
extension mechanisms so ipv4 address
sharing probably isn't a place that we
really want to spend a whole lot more
time because there's only so much
further we can go next slide there is
security considerations um pretty much
the same that you've seen before maybe
there will be an issue that we've
discovered an ipv4 I don't know I think
it's been fairly robustly tested but it
possible that there are inherent
security flaws in the ipv4 spec so if so
we can document and mitigate them next
slide there we go so I'm looking for
comments and obviously we're gonna want
to make some revisions but I would love
to see whether this should be adopted as
a working of document so I'm Chris
powers and I'd like to see some wording
in there that allows for the iesg when
evaluating charters to sort of include
the impact the actual impact because so
on you know focusing on perhaps
applications as opposed to in my case
routing protocols as a good example ospf
uses as a system identifier a router ID
whereas is is uses a system ID that so I
I think it would be a bit a waste of
time for ospf to try to now there's
ospfv3 but it's not been particularly
widely deployed and there's good
applications for just straight old ospf
for carrying mpls information which can
then carry ipv6 i I think it would be a
waste of time to try to make that router
ID ipv6 and so I would like to see
though so we don't have this argument
later on I'd like to see wording and
here that makes that exemption pretty
clear yeah I can see that technically
the ospf router ID is not actually an
ipv4 address right it's just a 32-bit
integer that everybody uses an ipv4
address right but it's a pair but I
think tonight yeah just making back
we're so that someone on the iesg who
maybe doesn't understand that goes oh ok
yeah whatever yep
Aaron Hughes 6 connect sir I'm not going
to unravel that so in your list of steps
at the beginning of the slide debt there
are six steps in there I think the first
five of them missing a timeline create
some of the challenges and animosity
that you're getting around or not done
with v4 yet if we added a timeline next
two steps one through five we probably
come to the conclusion that you're not
going to get till step 6 until you know
years out because there are so many
things that need to be rewritten I've
been through projects that design
routers that our v6 only that include
removing all 32-bit identifiers and
going through that process we drafted
updates to probably a hundred different
rfcs so I fully expect that if we start
along this path we're going to need to
spend quite a bit of time updating rfcs
to get to this point where we actually
have default being v6 only and I'm in
full support of this kind of work going
forward thank you for bringing it to us
I think so I well I think that we still
have adopted as a working group a an
ipv4 gap in our transition captain
alisis document right and that's that
document is still open is still a
working group document and I think it's
specific goal is to list rfcs that need
to be updated so please forward that and
we'll get right on that happy to help
yeah hi David skin Ozzy again I have
kind of a question on or asking for
cooperation that should I think appear
in the draft regarding new work that can
be dual stack what I mean by that two
examples that come to mind are home net
and the multiple interface PVD work
they're both v6 centric as oh I'm a host
and I have these two v6 prefixes where I
do with them however all these
properties that we're getting from the
network also apply to v4 in the case of
home net the if my memory care tell me
if I'm wrong with my recollection the
whole net documents is that your home
network may support ipv4 from reading
the draft it sounds like you're saying
oh no no it shouldn't even say that so I
think that should be made clear because
I agree that these things should be more
of these eccentric but things that do
both should be okay
can you go back to statement 104 because
I think that's the one where I say uh
nope okay go back to go next slide I
think so i think this is a word smithing
comment and i think we have to find up
at the words up here uh next slide okay
so the bullet says the work will be
capable of operating without ipv4 um
right so new IETF work even even home
net explicitly supports ipv6 or is
version agnostic so homenet specifically
supports ipv6 it also happens to support
ipv4 which is great but so I so I think
I think that your point is actually
covered in the text all right then we're
on the same page it's just ordinary to
make it clear if you wanted to say it's
somehow differently send text Tim shy
and the other thing I remember from the
home net architecture document is
whether you then say doing something the
best way for v6 only whether that might
somehow break be four operations I think
that's maybe another thing to consider
in the statement and maybe we will you
put it on it goes better job yes Alex
he's ever had there's a powerful yeah
chef you sell cisco so i just want to
confirm that i think home the Charter
and work is covered by these statements
like yeah we support ipv4 but we are not
supposed to add anything to it right
today I think that's that's good that's
my understanding yeah trance cutter um
can you go to the next slide maybe um
when I read the draft almost I think the
only thing that jumped out at me is kind
of weird was the not initiate new
technology development elm and when you
talk to over it actually I I would
summarize you're just now I would
summarize what you said as well we've
pretty much covered that waterfront
already there's not really anything new
to be you know no more blood to be
squeezed out of that stone which if
that's true you don't even need to say
so and if it's not true the technology
will be developed anyway because that's
just how things work so I mean I don't
really care if you put that in the
document or not but I think it's kind of
you know either it's true anyway or if
it's not true then it's not going to
matter so it's a reasonable point the
reason I wanted to say it is that people
keep coming to us with great ideas for
new versions of IP for instance and new
versions of extension technion new
proposed extension technologies I'd kind
of like to give the iesg the club just
say we don't even have to talk about
this we've already said we're not doing
it point taken so I use the example of
router ID and so for ospf is Chris
powers again I'm curious the feeling in
the room though on you know interfaces
between routers that use v4 addresses so
that those are clearly v4 dresses and
not 32-bit integers now what I'm
suggesting is that that'd be extremely
low priority in getting rid of compared
based on the impact on the overall
transition to v6 um I'd like to be very
clear about that that I'm not just
talking about router IDs so I don't
think that we're saying that this
statement actually tells us to go route
out those things it's saying we're not
going to initiate new work that allows
us to require ipv4 addresses show like a
an LSA that is in ospf that would ride
the only place it can go is over an
interface that has that those properties
where does that stand um so I I would I
I would argue that you know in terms of
impact on you know so networks that are
running v6 only enterprise networks okay
they're running ospfv3 but v2 would
still have a function in service
provider networks with a miniscule
number of v4 dresses
so I I think allowing for that decision
to be made in this statement is a
reasonable compromise well let me ask so
in that example which i think is a
really interesting example um new new
communications um might well use IP use
links with ipv4 addresses and be
required to understand that but they
should also be able to run over ipv6
only links and networks yo you're right
ospf you tues never gonna do it you're
right um and we have not actually said
we're stopping working ospf e2 right I
don't think we've said always made that
statement no yeah yeah so do you want so
you've nodded do you want me to propose
some wording to to do this you want to
come up wording so well um I'd like to
get a little more feedback because there
comes a point where maybe we say yeah
people are using ospf and and eventually
we're using ospf e2 and eventually we're
going to stop working on ospf v2
eventually so and when is that so what
they look like let's think of us p FV to
as you know it carries mpls information
in the TE opaque ill essays right so you
could have been so v6 goes over and pls
so the fact that you've got v4 addresses
you know they could be some I so some
strange addresses but to happen to be
you know v4 dresses but a miniscule
quantity of them given in the scheme of
things it seems like a lot of it seems
like basically a way to kill ospf all of
ospf relative to I esaias instead so
Michael Abramson so do you generally do
things so if you if you propose a new ll
say you wouldn't that go it both in 20
spiffy v2 and v3 and they have different
encoding so sometimes yes sometimes no
it's a an
general yes it seems get done in
parallel it's are you saying there would
be like an exemption if you did both of
them or what what's your the intention
here is not to do it is more beef or
only work yeah it's a feature parity
thingy yeah but I think we're missing so
that that is so that I think I'm sorry
to interrupt you but but I think that
that point might carry us but it would
need to be wordsmith 2.8 out but even
then it wouldn't necessarily make sense
because so right now mpls is not done
over ospfv3 in terms of practical
deployments so carrying the tea opaque l
essays that traffic engineering with
mpls is not done so saying that oh we
would have to sort of do the parallel v3
version of that you know one could think
of ospf v2 turning into basically an
MPLS infrastructure mechanism and have
nothing to do with v4 per se except that
it uses a small number of v4 addresses
and the impact on service providers of
saying oh you need you know we can't
actually modify this protocol anymore
would be significant so Michael Abramson
again so are you saying today that I
cannot use oh there's from a protocol
point of view is there anything I can do
a no Smith v 2 that I can't do you knows
maybe three if the vendors implemented
what's in the standard I think there are
still still gaps yes so when are these
going to be fixed I don't know I don't
know as soon as somebody's writes the
drafts as an asset operator I would like
those gaps filled what is the impact
on just the existence of ipv4 addresses
ipv4 addresses just on links in your
network that's that's that's the
important thing so the fact that i can
in 2016 if i were to green feel like if
i quit working and i started up at my
present employer and started a new one
the fact that i have to configure ipv4
or to run mpls i don't like that yeah I
Aaron Hughes again to this point the way
I interpret this draft is that we begin
work on ospf be four and bgp v5 and
resolve these issues we get rid of the
32-bit identifiers as we get rid of the
problems where we cannot wait will be
required to have altered protocol
support I mean why not if we're going to
move forward we move all the way forward
to a v6 only operating environment so I
do think a lot of rhubarb sorry that
that's a phrase for muttering in the
background I do think that we need to
make sure that our protocols can run v6
only but I'm i might be content well an
ospf tp2 is it is it an unusual case
that we need probably need to talk a lot
more about um but I I'm content to say
to just have a short draft saying you
know router IDs or not IP addresses
carry on good it's a simpler way out now
their way well the other we clear its
interfaces between routers with ipv4
addresses but it's the interfaces that
matter when you're doing link state you
know that's that that matters yes yes
it's not just the router ID and and that
right jump and but those are different
things um that's not to say that we
don't want to start new work on routing
protocols and there's no routing 80 in
here that I see right now so ha that's
not oh hey there you go so there may be
other reasons you wanted to do routing
protocols but I'm not gonna I don't
think that's in scope for us here well
actually based on our charter maybe it
is
a lot of cisco speaking as myself not
throwing any i was gonna say that one of
my concerns here i'd not opposed to this
sounds great is that yes need some
wordsmithing because new ITF work maybe
you mean brand new idea for converse is
continuing say Wes canopy to atf work
for example but there's of course new to
the ATF voice we have you too ITF work
etc some of that things to be clarified
I think on page one for example you talk
about it says ipv4 only for features of
vital operation to me that's the door
right that it's open where if I say well
I need to update those 22 or whatever
for vital operational issues that's it
right that that's the door that's open
of course everywhere else in the text
except that sentence says transition
security and something else not
operations so we still need to look at
while and it says they're right well I
appear before still operational we still
need to make sure that we support that
so I I tried to close that door with the
must have a problem statement based on
operational experience but if the door
is too wide open no write that in there
in that other part you nourish and
secure a transition of the commissioning
not up operations like that right so
it's yep yeah we're little worse here
there I think the intent is fine and I
think that eventually we just need to
clarify what is really new ITF work or
your continuing you have to support
whatever we have so then question back
to the folks here is should this say
working group charters or should this
say should this mean that 80's sitting
and working group meetings and watching
lists seeing something that's v4 only
should SWAT it down what do you want to
see yeah I heard in all of the above not
at the mic so so yeah it but I but I'm
seeing Chris say yeah but we just talked
about OS we have v2 that's a specific
example it you know it's open work it's
still things something we can work on
and having a routing ad say no no you
can't work on ospf v2 is a serious
consideration that matters in the real
world so we need to be very sure what we
want to do about it I'll update it to
you know if the working group wants to
adopt the dress the draft I will work on
whatever the working group tells me to
do but when we go to IETF consensus
we're going to have you know it's going
to be allowed long last call or maybe it
won't people and they'll be you know
rough consensus that no forget ospf you
too you're not running the mic with that
I am shooting flames out here so Michael
Abramson so um with the example of ospf
here if someone came and said I want
something you know 52 I don't care to to
make that same functionality knows baby
3 i'm going to get really upset there
needs to be at least be feature parity
the ice to understand that people still
want this functionality now 52 which is
fine but not caring about those be 33
and making sure that they can do the
same is really bad so maybe there's a
word smithing thing that we can do here
and that says something like a no-no
feature can be added that's ipv4 only
unless there is a Nike v6 comparable
feature or equivalent feature in an
equivalent system and even maybe give
the example of ospf v2 v3 with I'm
seeing some nods and shrugs and saying
maybe that's the right way to finesse it
I'm hoping somebody was taking note
taking I'm hoping you got that because I
just said it out loud um Tim I help you
yeah some something like what I said
will be close enough then we'll fight
about analyst we should just move this
to the ospf working group um is the only
example anybody can come up with is ospf
it it is convenient that both v2 and v3
live in the same working group yeah
that's true
so Leah questions as you must really
know these do better than anybody else
do you think it fits the Charter that's
a great question um so I think as a um
you the punches said there it's covered
under advice um but I wait we haven't we
have an ad here who can tell us whether
it fits the Charter and if it doesn't we
can just you know Terry Madison in Terre
a day it is provide recommendations yes
I believe it does fit the Charter if
someone would like to disagree with me
I'll happily take that offline and could
you quickly summarize what the process
for ITF consensus would be but I
probably could but yeah yeah Terry
medicine again so the process for this
consensus will have to go through
working group last call go through IETF
last call then go through the ballot
procedure with the the iesg Gia yes the
iesg and then it would be published okay
then so again so weak oh oh I'm sorry
you didn't have a you know the newcomers
bad we didn't know the cameras I know
he's a working group chair is a whip
okay I'm they are very confused I'm very
confused okay thank you my guess is that
we would take a hum to see whether the
working group wants to adopt it I would
then spin a revision based on comments
made here and notes made here named for
the working group if we adopted there
will be more wordsmithing online at some
point we'll say gene no more comments
are being made we seem close enough and
the working of chairs will do it will
issue a working group last call either
that could be at the next meeting or a
meeting and saying do you think it's
ready we'll take a hum or it could be on
the mate just on the mailing list and
then we run probably to two to four
weeks whichever um to see if anybody has
any further comments and then if there
are no further comments or the strong
support then it goes to IETF last call
which is
same two to four week process which will
probably generate a lot of comments but
if there is consensus and that's judged
by first the working group chairs to say
what so in the working groups just by
the chairs at last call i think is
judged by the the 80s and then it goes
the iesg to to put discusses on it any
more questions fully so question for
myself now which is the same as you we
will do a ham quickly to see whether the
working group wants to get this document
that Duquette it's a working group
document so we'll ask the first one will
be yes I won this as a working group
document and the second I'm would be no
I do not want this as you can group
document so we would like to give to f
this document is the working group
document kiss em now thank you for those
of you that do not want to add up this
document is yoking group document please
em now okay it was to be expected but a
clear physically for the noting a clear
adoption there thankfully so the next
session is about the locale owes name
and it's emily and by day for those of
you attending removed as i am acting as
a chair and not with the full power of
the chair at dinner i was unable to
upload the latest version of emory
slides you need to send in the pink we
have Eric Nate migrant hi and I'm Emily
stark i'm here from the chrome team um
I'm pretending to be my quest um uh I
was hoping he might appear remotely so
that he can answer all the hard
questions but looks like not so no hard
questions um so I I'm presenting a
pretty simple proposal that might put
together I've been tangentially involved
in some of the issues here but this is
really Mike's proposal he just going to
be here so um so the the problem that we
are trying to solve arises for
the fact that 6761 advises users that
they can assume that that local host
names resolve to loop back IPS but in
fact the the sections that actually
outline the behavior of name resolution
libraries and and DNS servers says this
frames this has a should not not a must
so um uh DNS servers and numerous
Aleutian libraries are actually free to
resolve local host names to anything
they'd like including something on the
public internet and that is surprising
um several implementation
implementations do do this we've
encountered them in the wild um so the
implication of this is a few things um
it makes local host names difficult to
use or I'm impossible to use for
security decisions and I'll give some
examples of that in a moment but it
means that there's no guarantee that
local host names actually resolve to to
look back they can go anywhere um and
and because of that we are not able to
give certain functionality that we would
like to give to local host names which
may encourage developers to hard-code
address literals um and that is probably
not good for all of you people who are
trying to kill IP before because it
proliferates IP address laurels and in
applications um so I'm gonna uh there we
go ok so just a little bit more on the
motivation here and comes from w3c where
there's a speck that defines a secure
context in the web platform and very
roughly a secure context is currently
defined as when a frame and all of its
ancestors are HTTPS or the WebSockets
equivalent or um or a loopback IP but
localhost is is very conspicuously
missing from this list of URLs that
define a secure context and that's a
pain for developers developers um well I
guess another key thing here is that a
secure context
used to to grant special privileges and
functionality to web applications so
certain powerful web platform features
like the geolocation API for example are
only available to applications that are
running in secure contexts so developers
want to test these features they want to
test them on localhost but we are
currently unwilling to to give them to
localhost because we don't actually know
what what localhost is it could be could
be anything um so letting developers
test secure contacts features on
localhost moreover you can you could
imagine that a an application might want
to talk to a local service we don't want
a local service to we if that local
service is being talked to from a secure
context that secure contacts is only
really allowed to talk to it if it is
also a secure URL and and so currently
we the the mixed content specification
which defines how secure content is
allowed to load sub resources from from
insecure for load insecure sub resources
currently that spec doesn't allow local
host and will trigger mixed content
warnings and web browsers for for
localhost and it's using the same
definition that secure context uses um
so basically the proposal is basically
it's just like replace the shades with
the musts appropriately um so there are
you know like three or four places in
6761 that define the behavior of name
resolution libraries and gayness servers
with respect to local host names and the
proposal is to change those roads to
musts so that um applications can assume
or or constrain um their dns lookups for
local host names to to loop back so
that's basically it it's pretty simple
proposal um kind of removes and need a
need for proliferating um loopback
address literals and and will be very
useful to us over in w3c lands to
to add local host to the lists of URLs
that um that define secure contacts any
questions hi Stan York and my my head
was exploding sort of because I was
having this collision between my
previous ipv6 world in my current dns
world and and just reading this because
i had actually double checked 6761 was
what I thought it was I guess my
question is um why are we having this
happen did Mike bring this to DNS op or
anything like that and the mailing list
um I don't remember ever seeing in a
list I am Not sure unfortunately I know
he has been soliciting feedback from
Deanna's people but i'm not sure to the
exact communication mechanisms that he's
done useful for that well my feedback i
guess would be for him to say um for him
to bring this DNS op because this is
clearly an operational and we've been
having all sorts of fun with RFC 6761
and special use names and in fact we're
having an interim in a couple of weeks
to talk about that or not it's or month
or so or something right Terry it's
someone that space so I would say that
this would be something that he should
send in there and we're watching a
pacman eat Mark Andrews ok so anyway
that would be my suggestion because this
is something that would be that would be
the group to updater yeah ok thank you
um video called Enoch I I second that
that question I was wondering why we're
presented here second is setting all the
problems in 6761 aside um the discussion
whether or not localhost should resolve
to defined results is like decades old
that doesn't mean that it doesn't
deserve an answer but there's lots of
history in baggage which might lead to
certain biased responses so just be
aware that this is old stuff and muddy
waters I'm not sure I understand how
reliable the result is really meant to
be again setting 6761
moving this from a show to a must
doesn't guarantee any any any future
performance I guess is that it's the
term that you usually use it may or may
not be implemented today questions for
local host may leak to the root service
today and actually at that place the
responses annex domain so what you
probably really want and again a warning
this is not leading anywhere what you
really might want is that the
authoritative service for that part
respond with whatever result you you
desire there you can't assume that that
is happening anytime soon yeah so um to
two things i think i just want to say i
think how this ended up here is the
issue of proliferation of ipv4 literals
and so I think that the relevance to
this group is like um if we can remove a
common you know and a that's thing that
pushes developers in the directions of
ipv4 literals then that makes it easier
to kill off ipv4 um uh to your second
point yeah like we just changing RFC
doesn't change the simple fact that
implementations are not gonna probably
ever update I think what we would do is
make this change and then um in the
secure context spec maybe I don't know
if it would be I probably wouldn't be
normative but like make it make a note
that this is the state of the world and
then browsers would in fact on some
platforms chrome already um forces local
house to resolve to loop back so we
would sort of implement it in the
browser and that would make us feel safe
about giving local host secure context
so it's sort of um the purpose is not so
much that implementations will change
overnight but to sort of bolster the
case for the user agent um kind of
pretending that this is the state of the
world so if i may ask a follow-up
question so i now hear that you were
looking for a maybe i'm completely wrong
but this looks like getting a
justification for doing this in a
implementation which doesn't necessarily
mean you need to change the the current
entry in the registry I don't think it's
a justification so much as as a thing
that makes sense to do in parallel like
I think this is continuously surprising
22 people and it's I think it's just
sort of like um how how it should be
like people expect a local host to
resolve to look back and it should
resolve to look back and and it's a
change that makes sense to do in
parallel with what with with what we
would do for first gear contacts ok I
understand too little of this web stuff
so well let's take this offline ok
thanks any other questions family so
maybe a questions for I detail theory if
you don't mind where do you want this
work done where do you think it's the
most suitable I actually think this is
going to be a little argument that I'm
going to have with joel is responsible
ad for dns up so what do you think Joel
now I can relay joel is essentially
saying he thinks it should be discussed
in dns up though he's not sure it has to
be advanced there ok so we'll put this
on a placeholder cuz i also want to
argue with Joel okay
David skin Ozzy Apple channeling Stuart
cheshire actually the up one of the
authors of 6761 uh he supports this if
there's consensus usual thankfully okay
so Thank You Millie thank you we are the
blue sheets they disappeared somewhere
okay who is enjoying them so can you try
to follow the blue sheet to those people
and then after thank you so much sunset
for edition 97 is a journal and write me
I just point out while I was jabber min
eating that slides that Emily presented
don't seem to be in meeting materials
okay it's okay I didn't minute that side
in here yeah I was assuming some shield
against you but no no hey I wasn't going
to be kind so you are open sessions
emotional imagery you were there see
it's a TV I usually on this one robust
way from chemical into it