all right right sorry yeah might as well
okay so this is the tcp ink working
group congratulations on surviving IETF
all the way to Friday here's the note
well it applies to everything that is
said said done posted cetera in this
meeting or in the working group alright
Carl to be yeah yes so time for agenda
bashing does anyone have anything to add
here yeah so chair update in case P you
know tcp crypt and then i'll be talking
at the end about some of the messages
that the chairs sent to see FRG and by
chairs i mean that i sent to jerky yeah
I decided may give his problem excellent
he was surprised hit cooperative so
since Berlin there hasn't been a huge
amount of work but there were two very
long discussions on the mailing list the
those two discussions one of them was
around the urge and thin bits and the
other one was around a sin data and both
involved long drawn-out discussions with
Joe and some other folks that actually
were produced some very subtle semantic
changes in the documents but I think
that as a result of that the last
remaining real blockers to work group
last call have been resolved yeah this
is this this is the 99 yahoo a project
manager was striking again you know
first time several times in a time last
ten percent takes the other ninety
percent speaking of which yes we're at
receiving probably post very close to
our milestones unlike a number of other
working groups including one a tight
ship yeah I I will point out however
that's sticking close to the milestones
in this case means that we push the
milestones back I think three times
these these dates are not the original
dates yeah i don't think i'm gonna make
January day with the API we need me to
figure out what we're going to do about
that api doc late plate later in this
meeting yes actually that's a good
question do we want to add a specific
agenda item for discussing the api doc
okay so why don't we do that after i
want to put mine last just to maximize
the potential for TLS people to be in
the room so why don't we put it third so
after TCP Krypton okay this quick check
Aaron you still willing to take notes
for us um we've basically sorry that
we're going to win + lock into the
agenda to talk about here sorry where's
genda we decided that down under open
mic know we're after TCP crypt before CF
Archie question not we're going to talk
about the api doc yes now after TCP
crypt the first on the second column
yeah tcp you know then teach me crypt
then api doc and see if RG questions
than anything else thank you anybody in
the jabber room ok so anyone willing to
the scribe
ok we have a volunteer thank you okay oh
great naps again I upon the work work
group with with with Pete with with with
nats not sure what we're gonna do about
do about about middle box probing let's
figure we do with the api doc let me
figure out what we're going to do a
middle middle box program well
thankfully it's not a milestone so yeah
that's wise decision up here are that
one okay so yeah and this is almost
copied verbatim from the last
presentation we still we we haven't
gotten any bites yet on independent
implementation so so I implore you if
you have any interest in this please
contact one of us and we will direct you
toward resources to get you started all
right okay so and I minute here see what
we want the enos slides right okay not
just see if this works it does charge
okay ah great so yeah update on TCP you
know went through a bunch of drafts
right off the last meeting and then a
couple more recently so just to remind
everybody of how you know works and what
the goals are you know the goal is to
facilitate adoption of future TCP
encryption protocols so we used to call
these things encryption specs we've now
coined the term tap for a tcp encryption
protocol and so the idea is that we when
there are going to be new taps because
we didn't want to like try to be all
things to all people and solve all
problems and when you taps come along we
don't want them to have to go through
the trouble of getting a new tcp option
kind because those are limited and it's
a pain to get them we don't want we want
you to have to be incrementally
deployable so you can fall back to
existing ones and possibly more
importantly once we get this stuff
deployed there may be applications that
then take advantage of TCP ink and we
want to make sure that those
applications continue to be forward
compatible with future taps if you
actually go through the trouble of
integrating the TCP the session ID for
example in your user authentication you
want to make sure that that works with
the future tab taps so the goal of Ino
is to kind of abstract all these things
away from the application and uh and so
we also want to you know minimize
consumption option space since that's at
a premium and avoid unnecessary round
trips and you know of course because
this is has to be backwards how do we
want to make sure we fall back to
unencrypt the tcp rather than causing
connections to fail as much as possible
so just an overview of how it works in
the common case of a three-way handshake
you have an active opener we sent the
sin segment and the sin segment contains
a an e no option and inside that II no
option is a list of type identifier
saying you know what TTP level
encryption protocols are supported by
the accubow then the the passive opener
replies of the syn ACK and replies with
a
Kristen try try it again there you go
good and so replies with ideally the one
tap that that the act that the pass
opener wants there's also this new
change we made last time where you have
to add this this this be bit here to say
that you're the passive opener and that
was in a way you know I never want to
say it's nice to have middleboxes doing
horrible things but we didn't have kind
of like all these debates about should
we have this like perfectly symmetric
protocol whatever and all that turned
out to the irrelevant because we found
out the places like Baidu just like have
these these middleboxes that like echo
any unknown TCP options back to the
opener and so it just had to be the case
if somebody echoes your option that it
just you know is disabled because it
would be disastrous to start encrypting
when the other side didn't know that it
was encrypting so basically one side has
to set the Biba 20 the other side has to
set the be bit to one otherwise we fall
back unencrypted TCP and that just makes
a lot of things simpler and then you in
the third leg of the handshake keep
sending the e no option to make clear
that it you know that you know didn't
get stripped off the syn ACK segment and
you keep sending a no option until such
point as you you've received a segment
that doesn't contain a sin flag and at
that point you know you're done and both
sides know that they're encrypting and
the connection is encrypted if any of
the e knows our options are missing the
beginning then you fall back to
unencrypted TCP and also gives us the
backwards compatibility okay so what's a
nanny no option Willis two kinds of you
know options or two forms of you know
options there's the ones that are in sin
segments and the ones that are nonsense
segments so at the top you see in a sin
segment the e no options they say
container for a bunch of sub options in
otherwise it's just ignored right just
the presence of the you know option is a
flag but the contents is ignore but you
know and unless the temp that you've
selected that you negotiated specifies
that you should put some bytes in there
it must be zero bytes so it's just an
empty option but it's available if the
pep wants it okay so
within the sin segments each sub-option
starts with an initial sub-option bite
and that bite has two components it has
this high bit v which stands for
variable like data and then has a 7-bit
thing that used to be called CS but now
we're calling it g LT which stands for
global sub-option length ortep
identifier and we've sort of broken it
up into four quadrants when the GLT
field is less than 32 then if v is 0
it's what we call a global sub-option
music all that a general sub-option with
the name global it's clear these other
options of by across all taps and and if
it's one then it's a length bite and
reset this more complicated thing with
length words whatever we just got rid of
that so that now it's simpler and then
for values of 32 or greater it's a temp
identifier that seven value is a temp
identifier and if the V bit is 0 that is
just a one-bite kept otherwise oh it has
variable length data so in one more
detail there's basically three kinds of
tap identifiers that you can embed
inside a sin for me no option you have
the single byte happened under fire that
doesn't have any data just as hey I
support this tcp encryption protocol
sorry my popping my PS or am I am I not
louder with oh yeah sorry because I
don't have my slides in front of me so
I'll try to I'll try to speak across the
mic like this actually I guess I can
speak usually when you speak into a mic
you pop your P's better talk across but
ok so uh so yeah so here's the one bite
when when the V bit is 0 otherwise
there's two options if you just set the
V bit to one and you set a type
identifier which is where the low 7 bits
are 3qr higher then it means that the
data extends to the end of the tcp
option and we special case this because
we think the common cases there's only
going to be one tap that actually has
data just cuz you don't have that many
bytes inside us in header and then the
other option is that you have this link
bite and then you have a temp ID with
the veba set one and then you have that
many bytes of data so that way you can
actually if you want have multiple taps
of options that have data and then
the other option is this global
sub-option the global sub-option starts
with 30 bits and then has three Reserve
bits that must be zero and then uh then
these two bits ambi so a little bit be
that's the thing that breaks the
symmetry of the protocol the Pasig
opener always has to set be equal to 1
the active opener always has to set be
equal to 0 although 0 is the default
value if the active opener happens to
admit this this global sub-option that's
because like in the very first sin
packet that's one up you know option
spaces at the greatest premium and then
the second thing is this application of
where bit which is a bit that's
available to the application to
negotiate something out of band that
triggers authentication of the TCP level
encryption right so that's how you have
some legacy protocol there's no way to
add like a you know a start TLS command
to it it's are the protocols already
fixed but now you have this extra bit
that says hey when we do our
authentication step if both of us agree
that we're aware of TCP you know will
you know somehow incorporate the session
ID and how we do application if you
remember last time I used to be this M
bit uh you know we decided to push us
that offer later we still think that
there's room for application independent
authentication protocols and that we
should negotiate those out of band but
we now have these three bits named Z 3 Z
2 n.c one that we can use so ideally
xiii you know at some future draft will
become a you know and a separate
document would say like how could you
combine dane and tcp you know for
example okay so you're only allowed to
have one global sub-option you have to
ignore subsequent ones that means if
five bits turns out not to be enough we
could just say when you get a second
sub-option it has these five new bits
that have five new meaning so probably
what happened but at least we're future
compatible if you'd be okay so now the
the interesting stuff so this is
probably the biggest change since last
time and we had a lot of special Manila
I hope that where we ended up made
everyone happy and that is we talked
about what does it mean to you to for a
tap to embed data inside a a sense
segment to do something like you know
tcp fast open for example so uh so
couple things so first of all we said
that when you have a sin segment with an
e no option the last type identifier in
that you know TCP option is what we're
calling the sin tab and thus in tap is
responsible for defining the meaning of
data that's inside that's inside that
that's in segments so in particular if
the sin tab doesn't say anything about
sin data then you are not allowed to put
data in a sin segment right but we're
leaving the option open for future taps
that that might wish to do this right um
and then of course the symptom i turn
out not to be the negotiated tap right
you might propose a bunch of peps the
last one is one thing you embed a bunch
of data for that and it turns out that
you know you're the active open of the
passive opener decides to choose a
different one so at that point you have
to discard the data because it doesn't
because it was the data only had meaning
to one particular tap and you chose a
different tab so we say that you have to
discard the sin data if the sin tap is
not the negotiated that including the
case where ino fails entirely and it's
not an encrypted connection and we also
say they have to discard the data if
there's any off any other tcp option
that implies something about the meaning
of the sin data so right now the the one
that's most relevant btfo so if you have
a non-empty TFO option you just you have
to discard the sin data basically it's
it that doesn't make sense because if
you have the TFO option telling you hey
this is some plain text application data
and you have say a sin tap telling you
like hey this is um you know some part
of a key exchange or something then like
that which is it right you don't know so
so you know you're not supposed to use
TFO in conjunction with this so that's
one safeguard that you can't use the
data if it's unah if it's ambiguous what
it means the second safeguard is what
happens if uh there's a host that you
know receives its data and appears to
discard it because doesn't actually act
the bytes that were in the ascendant but
it actually caches those bites anyway
and when you re transmit the those
sequence numbers with different bites it
uses the cash
original version of that and because we
don't know that TCP implementations
don't do that we say that we require you
to do it if you implement you know but
of course the other side might not
implement you know so what that means is
that if the UH so that means is
basically if the other side if you're if
the other side doesn't appear to support
you know and it is required to drop
those bites then you actually have to
abort the connection and you know send a
reset right and so so what that means is
of course you don't want gratuitous
resets so that means you should avoid
sinner only data by default so we're
saying we're leaving the door open for
this in the future but we're saying it
you know it shouldn't be enabled by
default so either there should be a mode
where you don't use that or if your tap
always uses that and not have shouldn't
be on by default but we're suggesting
that the API might contain a flag that
says you know I know that TCP II know is
going to be enabled so just reset the
connection i'm only interested in
talking over and a temp encrypted
connection and if if the application is
actually asking you to reset an
unencrypted connection anyway you know
then it's fine to use these and you're
obviously not going to want to use that
for web browsing or something but might
make sense for like NFS or something
where it's like you're on a land you
know they're talking to a server that
supports this you might want to just
configure yourself to always require the
encryption and then you can save
yourself a half a round trip basically
okay so that's the one big change and
then the this looks like there's a
question a question because I looked up
in the draft and I didn't find it so
this is only for session resumption
right no no this is for this is not for
session resumption this is this is
actually at the inn II know it's not a
TCP crib so it's kind of we're not
actually using it in TCP grip but this
is to leave the door open for future
taps that want to subsume some TFO like
functionality and what we're saying is
it's fine if you want to do that but it
has to be off by default and uh and
you're going to have to reset the
connection if you talk if the remote
site doesn't support you know and you
sent it a bunch of
protects your key exchange stuff that it
probably doesn't understand therefore
and therefore you'll have to reset the
connection okay so it's not it's not
actually application data you put in the
payload its data you need for it I mean
that is up its up to the it's up to the
debt tap the specific tab and and right
now no taps actually do this but I could
one could imagine that it would be like
if we did this for TCP crypt it would be
one a few things in the case of session
resumption it would be encrypted
application data and in the case of like
a fresh connection it would be key
exchange data or you know symmetric
cipher preferences or both okay so the
the second thing is in either berliner
argentina there it's been at this and
long enough that starting to blur but we
became we became forcefully convinced
that in under no circumstances doing
what tcp you know to be like required to
modify RFC 793 and so there was this
problem that we were saying things like
well you know you can have some
mechanism for end the file that's
separate from fin and and the language
kind of made it sound like maybe the fin
bit was no longer the fin bit and so I
so and same for urge and so instead what
we've done is we've rewritten these tap
requirements to make everything in terms
of like authenticating the existing TCP
mechanism so we're not abandoning TCP
mechanisms right so particularly say
that you know taps have to authenticate
the fin bit and you know they can do
that with some parallel mechanism but if
the parallel mechanism the fin bit don't
match them that means you've got some
packet corruption so there you can
discard the segment that's corrupted or
reset the connection with an error or
something but you can't treat it like an
authentic and defiled and similarly so
this is this is where things get a
little tricky we want to kind of walk
this fine line with with urgent data
that it is part of TCP but a lot of
people don't use it but like if people
could inject urgent data it could like
mess up existing applications so we want
to make clear that you know a temp
cannot cause urgent data
to be delivered when none has been sent
by the sender that's really like the
important thing and uh the the problem
is that there's no way in hell that TCP
use TLS is going to support urgent data
properly look exactly the way uh TCP
does TCP crip does but but it'll be hard
to fit in the TCP use TLS and so we want
to do is make sure that you know can
accommodate TCP use TLS but not that
we're like modifying RFC 793 in
particular you know there's this more
recent RFC 69 degree that kind of
reaffirms urgent data and talks about
how it's supposed to how supposed to
work so we have this thing you know it's
maybe theoretically used by some really
old FTP servers and and maybe telnet and
rsh which people aren't using that much
anymore it's not used by most
applications so basically what we did is
we left this loophole that we hope is
big enough to fit like TCP use TLS
through so we're saying that basically
you know it's okay to you you might have
some taps that would just basically
ignore the urgent flag pretend it's
clear no matter what and but you
shouldn't enable that kind of tap by
default except when you know for a fact
that the application is not going to use
urgent data and like it just happens
that we know for a fact that almost all
applications are not going to use urgent
data so so that's our hope that this the
week minutes a kind of thread the needle
okay let me say one quick thing about
threading the needle it's basically
another way to think about the phrase
everything in terms of technique TCP
functionality from a functional point of
view one way to think about what's going
on with uh with the temps is that you've
got crypto function between the TCP
implementation and the wire which means
on receipt you get to go do the decrypt
look at what the temp put in there to
tell you where the thin bit is authentic
or not and if the TCP header contained a
thin bit but the decrypted a tech
payload said no Finn bit here at that
point you discarded the regular TV
implementation never see
is it and it's basically if all else
fails we will we can phrase this in
terms of processing sequence where you
run TCP and then do the encryption and
on the on on sending on receipt you do
it in reverse order and that's how we
can be be confident that we're not going
to need to update RFC 793 okay so so
yeah so these are really the only two
big changes this is kind of summary of
everything we've changed I've got these
new terminology that specs are now
called taps the general sub drop shin
became the global sub-option we've got
this notion of a sin tap we get rid of
the length word so now the other than
the last tap sub-option you can only
have 32 bytes of sub-option data but
remember the total space for all options
is 40 bytes so that's not you're not
going to have more than one sub option
that's more than 3 q bytes anyway so
again let's just simplifies things we
got rid of the n-bit called the reserve
bitsy ones QV c 3 to make it easier to
name and future drafts that might use
them we talked about data and since
segments another kind of changes that we
changed some shoulds to musts and for
the remaining shoulds we tried for
everyone that way actually say like the
exception is whatever because basically
have pushed back on the mailing list you
shouldn't just blindly throw around
shoulds if there is if you're saying
should instead of must because it's an
exception like explicitly state with the
exception so we try to be clear about
that and then you know we tried to
improve the wording for the temp
requirements already talked about the
pin and urge the other thing is someone
I'm sorry I forget who did this but
brought up the issue of forward secrecy
on the mailing list and saying that you
know basically we didn't want to rule
out some application some possible
implementations right you could you know
imagine an application where you have to
like seed your system random generator
from some seed file but stored on an SSD
and you know because of your flash
translation layer like we technically
it's like really hard to do forward
secrecy and that kind of
scenario but the important thing is we
want the at the protocol level all the
tests offer forward secrecy so basically
we're saying like you can't depend on
long-lived secrets Percy on long live
keys for secrecy and uh and and yeah and
that's it so just a few tiny things left
to do I hope so you know one question
that still have I don't think discussed
this before but should there be a way to
signify that like a host implements Ino
but it's just disabled and one reason
you might want this is because it would
help in the case of in that corner case
where you have to discard some sin data
that's like because there's a sin tap
ended up not governing the connection
well if you know the other side
implements you know even though it's not
enabled you know it will discard that
data so that might be nice it might also
be useful in terms of like data
gathering to be able to you know people
well advertised hey like my kernel
supports I just haven't turned it on yet
then that could help make the argument
that people should eventually turn it on
because like it's at least that the code
is out there and it just needs to be
configured another thing I think this is
just an omission but we should have some
kind of in the API document some kind of
TCP you know mandatory thing that says
hey abort the connection if I don't uh
if it's not encrypted and that that
option would allow us to enable taps
that Duty fo like things that have
sinned data you know then we need to get
get our actual option still hoping we
get 69 since we had used that earlier um
and yeah I hope not much else there's
other stuff kind of fond work so we
still need TCP you know middle box
probing document there's this
experimental spec ID so we'll need
another drop just talks about how to
multiplex that and I think some exi d
like thing I think that should be very
simple and then uh yeah ideal it also
like this you know see application
independent middleware authentication so
that you can like load a shared library
that you know when Dane is deployed or
whatever it can actually do like server
authentication and transport
application so this is different from
the a bit and that it would say like
here's a little mini protocol that you
can do ahead of handing the socket over
to the application but again we've got
three bits and we could co-opt one of
those bits for doing that okay few
suggestions from up here and I'll go
bottom the top since that seems we seem
that stack a life of you way my brain is
working this morning application
independent authentication would be a
fine follow-on I would strongly suggest
writing the draft against a specific
mechanism as opposed to writing a
general drive so you could do this
figure out how to use Dane and bright
then write down the details yeah that's
that's why we're not that's why it's not
part of it you know a good we want to do
you have any experience with the a bit
for application awareness in the
prototyping he done um yeah andreia did
it was it was a while ago right didn't
we use it in the original tale tell us
yeah trying to go to the mic here if any
was listening or Muttley but uh there's
I've got two people on me dekho so yes
please use the mic
yeah so there's an address so the
question was whether we use da bit in
our prototyping and we certainly did we
had a drop-in replacement for lib ssl a
binary for placement actually and the
idea was to use the a bit if the other
end you know supported TCP crypt we just
kind of use TCP crypt and then do the
authentication ourselves we get the
session ID uh using a cell and if it
didn't support the a bit we just did
vanilla TLS basically reason the
question was to ask whether
implementation experience with the a bit
to figure out what it actually works and
sounds like yes yeah those guys and
you've got good idea there's a slightly
older version of TCP grip but I mean the
rest of us would be the same level as
opposed to the end of it which is
something something will come back to
later okay working our way up dedicated
TCP option um okay i suspect i spec
house gonna make me go Sydney a shepherd
for this draft in part because this one
well I believe you are the Shepherd for
the stress yes okay game plan here we
get through worker blast call first and
then we will at that point with it or do
I believe the rough consensus of this
working group is to ask for 69 however I
don't even have I would ask Joe touch to
do a working-class core of you I suspect
that request is not going to be
necessary now but let's be serious Joe
is one of the people who has the best
understanding and the most scars from
fighting TCP option so having them do
the technical review during a vesicle is
very good and as part of that we get to
go deal with a which option number and
uh and what 69 decide whenever any
options fine well I understanding
options fine however i'm pretty sure
based on discussion I think in berlin
yes um 16 not that the rough consensus
is this working group is to reuse 69 and
we can then have an argument it's where
the work group is working group is right
or wrong about that but we will have
that argument on the list yeah I believe
the the the philosophy behind that was
you broke it you bought it kind of thing
so which is fine i think everybody was
was okay with that you know and i mean
and i recall correctly joe is arguing
something stronger
but this point I'm going to stop trying
to stop trying to channel Joe finally I
would speaking now as an individual not
you're working group chair and not your
draft Shepherd and I've osteria the
gratuitous walk walk before Mike to make
the point i would suggest not doing the
first item on this slide this is already
subtle complex and unlikely to be used
let's just not do anything more that we
don't need to do there's we can get all
three things so first bullet on which
part of LA the option way to signal you
know infinite but but disabled sounds
like you're proposing to add some some
additional functionality um to cope with
sin sin data which you don't date we the
only think use anyhow well living but
let me make this more concrete what I'm
proposing is saying that instead of
saying you have to send one or more pep
IDs you could be changing it to zero or
more and if there's zero then you
there's no negotiated tap but it's just
it's making it legal to send basically a
gratuitous you know option in a sin
segment this is sounding like we're to
dysfunction out it isn't closer to
getting the job done okay so I'm gonna
have to start kairos not speaking as
chair I'm gonna have to disagree with
with David on this actually think this
is a really good idea for the exactly
the reason you specified which is that
which is that it solves the problem of
knowing whether a peer support you know
but just has it disabled for purposes of
dealing with early data and it doesn't
seem like it complicates the protocol in
any way so it seems like it seems like a
good idea if the if the client sends an
e no option then you just you always
respond with one if you support you know
whether you have it turned on or not and
that solves the ambiguity regarding
whether you have to terminate the
connection if you send early data or not
yeah I mean we older versions that like
really old versions of TCP grip had some
way of like declining or whatever but
that so we don't feel that strongly but
it's yeah you could have been yeah I
don't I don't I don't see a big benefit
of it because you're anyway I have to do
the negotiation next time you never know
what was before and then like I'm not
even sure if you want to catch this
information
is next time try something some
different you know one thing that week
one thing that's kind of like been a
thorn in our side for the whole time is
like people talking about you know
whether middleboxes are gonna like strip
options and this kind of stuff so be
kinda nice a like you know what like
okay nobody's you know most people are
using you know yet but like it appears
that it like it gets through middleboxes
but but again it's not well if the
consensus is don't put it in then we
won't put it in this is a small change
either 10 can you feel explain how it
has middle books because if the other
end doesn't support you know I don't
know anything about the middle box in
between no no I'm saying suppose that
like you know you know gets deployed but
just it's going to be off by default at
first right and so people are going to
want to know like well should I turn
this on and if you say like oh well it
does appear that like when I send an e
no option to this person on getting one
with the B bit set properly back and
that that they're our path appears to be
clear through this network then that
might encourage people to turn it on to
configure it on so I believe if you if
you deploy the implementation and you
have a turn off by default what you want
in this case is not having a traffic
change at all and we don't want to see
me on other also it's like it's also
options face right there are given it I
don't think it's actually matters I mean
talk if you if we put it there another
end it's going to ignore it anyway
because there is nothing to do with a no
option because there is no steps to
negotiate so the other one has to be
able to ignore it anyway because and
fall back to that clear fixed anyway so
it doesn't affect it doesn't affect any
implementation if you allow it or not it
can allow it can allow you to you know
to you know probing in any cases where
you for a point for example want to do
you know measurements how many things
works and you know this without one of
the things for example ipsec we doing
better revenge it's always that you sent
a proposal and you get same response
regular basis you know enabled at all
but it's too running or if you had just
available from corporations this would
allow you to the propane without you
know
caring if that don't support CC pink or
epic ripped or TLS racer so you're in
favor or actually I think it because I
mean it doesn't affect the normal
implementations without because I mean
yes you could you just put it in there
and you know other ones just okay so you
think that's okay yeah so I've got two
in favor to against count yeah Kyle rose
yeah the the two cases it helps are the
probing case and the preventing spurious
resets case and I think maybe what we
want to do is kind of go into more
detail on the mailing list on the on the
the ups and you know the upsides and
downsides of this because myriad pointed
out some some good downsides to doing
this including option space and the fact
that you that you know ideally you would
like an implementation to have a way to
say really turn it off and don't even
send you know don't even recognize that
this option exists but that adds
complexity to the API so I think
outlining it on the mailing list and
then getting making a consensus call
there is probably the right way to do
that because I just want to make sure
that everyone understands all of the the
implications of this fully before making
a decision good wanna try this fairly
quickly on the mailing list so that we
can get yes anyone important is worth
delaying stuff but it's just one thing
that I noticed we kind of lied it needs
to be further need for fairly simple
this Martin do um so we talked a lot
about the potential benefits or like the
realm of this but can you give us a
sense of costs I don't you try to
implement it like how many how many
paragraphs of spec is it it's like it's
like a changing a 120 I mean it's like
it's well no it's more than changing 120
you're also gonna have to write a
paragraph that explains what happens
when when the Eno option shows up all
shows up on a sin Carrie Carrie carrying
no carrying no temp a low actually
that's already it's already clear then
there's no negotiated tough you still
gonna have given one chance to say like
yes go away but you're still going to
have to have to explain what I'm happy
to propose a diff on the mailing list
that would be like you know probably two
sentences come and
and so I can be convinced the other way
I mean my immediate reaction was we're
not doing sin data what was the point
but data gathering I can see some much
so if it doesn't make the RFC to TL DR
and it doesn't put an enormous burden on
implementers and it doesn't take up a
bunch of Vienna space I I don't see any
reason to not produce something that
someone might find useful I think the
real in my mind the biggest downside is
like we might men need like an extra API
for like completely disabled or it'll be
another value for like that you know and
evil but me I could have been so
thinking about the middle box cases and
what you also reflect a basically empty
TCP no option from the receiver beckoned
was it's the neck because otherwise i
would you have to set the be bit to one
so wouldn't exactly reflect it and but
basically the idea is if you if i send a
TC if i send tcp you know to some server
uh and then the server like support ccpe
know but like doesn't want to actually
encrypt it would just send back an empty
TCP you know would be equal one so ba3
bite option including the kind kind
length and the global option would be
equal one and no proposed taps and then
encryption would be disabled but that
would allow me to know that it would let
me to differentiate the case that you
know the the middle box is stripping off
the you know option around the case now
case report it it's just for weather for
the reply not for the initial sin I mean
it could also be the initial Sam I don't
know that doesn't seem like as useful
just in terms of functionality in the
spec if we're gonna define what it means
to have no tap IDs say it's zero or more
tap ideas instead of one or more we
might as well have it both but I don't
see or probably more useful and are in
reply from the server but we could also
have it be from the sin for like
explicitly like measurement stuff I
wouldn't expect implementations want to
do this by default but we can make it
legal so that to facilitate the
measurement of you know how many
middleboxes this again through yeah what
I was thinking is if you want the
measurement case you can at least
say if you if you receive an empty um
you know you should you know reply to it
so you under the measurement so you just
specify what the receiver has to do and
not specify that you yeah you have to do
they make it and make it legal for the
sender to send an empty one but not
suggested yet do it yeah yeah so that
yeah okay good heart I think the path
forward sounds like proposed proposed
two diff on the list proposed that the
text if on the list and it comes out is
comes out as short as you think it's
going to come out we could leave we can
write a consensus calling the list of
this but but my concern up there isn't
so much technical merit or lack thereof
it's a colonizer it it's a reasonably
short path from here to work or blast
call because I know I know that one's
when I know that's going to be
interesting okay good yeah we do have a
history of doing a lot of work for a few
weeks right around the meetings and then
like a long space in between where
nothing seems to happen so we don't want
to wait until to me I would very much I
mean um don't know about next mugs I
have some as mirrior probably knows I
have some some tsv WG stuff I gotta deal
with but I very much want to get these
drafts working group last call by Jim
let's go get us know that all right let
me know andre's up and go slides so we
need PCP critic all right all right yeah
so I Mandrell talk about these speed
gripped so I'll start with a refresher
on the protocol so this is the four-way
handshake of TCP crypt we use you know
to signal support and so in the first
round trip we we do the negotiation for
the public key ciphers so in this case
the act of opener is saying can't
support p 5 to 1 and p 2 56 the pass an
opener replies saying hey let's go ahead
and do you know p curve 256 and it sets
the passive opener bit that David talked
about extensively so the second round
trip is about symmetric
Seifer negotiation and exchanging public
key material so in this case the act of
opener saying escort aes-128 and 256 it
sends its nonce and it's public key and
the passive opener selects the symmetric
cipher this case aes-256 and sends its
own non send its own public key material
so we basically extended TTP's three-way
handshake by adding one extra leg for
negotiation and the fundamental reason
for this was that you know public keys
are large they don't fit an option space
so we put them in data that is invisible
to apps and that's why we start sending
key material only on the third leg
because that's when we could start
sending data so after we've done this
key exchange both ends compute their you
know their do their diffie-hellman or
whatever algorithm they're using them
they get their key agreement result
which is not transmitted on the wire
obviously that's how you get your
protection against passive eavesdropping
so we take all that information the key
agreement material and all the bits of
the handshake and the hash that all
together and you you get your session
secret from that you derive your session
ID so you can see from this that
intuitively if you create a TCP
connection and the two session IDs match
it means that nobody tampered with your
handshake nobody modified your bits in
the unit one or nobody modified your
publicly or something like that and
that's how applications could do their
authentication top of TCP creek by
verifying that the session IDs match and
from that session secret you also derive
all your keys for your symmetric ciphers
your max and essentially for your
authenticated encryption so once you
have your key material how do we
actually encrypt the data so we take the
user data and we create records out of
it so we have our own framing the user
you know in the user data of the T speed
portion and we've got a control bite a
cipher text length and a cipher text so
the controlled by currently has only one
bit defined which is the rekey bit and
that's used for
you know rotating your keys question
yeah I have actually question about
previous lighter one of things i would
say so so you put both the Holy no
transcript we've mean this a secret you
know this means that if middle box are
anything necessary single bit there this
will generate the different keys it's
built and how do you detect that that
the keys are wrong because they take us
one of the problems with ike ike wash
one was that they've used to same thing
we actually put everything and if you're
something wrong you get an encryption
failure then you don't notice it
anywhere else don't have a decryption
fatal wreck its first serve it annoying
because you you know and i think it
would like to disable it and fall back
to clear decks in here this case but I
mean yeah and I fear some kind of in a
handshake to take check out that yes
this is something wrong or right so and
I think this was even brought up
previously like you know should we
normalize the TCP options in certain way
like if they get reordered or something
like that um David I don't know if we
actually ended up doing that and you
know yeah so I just this is David let's
hear some Stanford I just want to point
out that the the eno transcript doesn't
mean like the entire like tcp segments
right that you know transfer is like a
very specific thing that's defined in
the inner document and it just actually
I was to get bite more or less that they
eat because there is there's no possible
that there's something else wrong with
this and it's it's usually better to get
you know clear feedback that okay
something wrong una authentication
failure right and do something else than
to just get you know I get random
garbage in because I my decryption fails
for it for every pocket after that point
so it yeah but it was still getting out
indication failure in in that you know
you don't get weeded back at okay
there's something wrong the system ids
are wrong not like one way to focus
attend testing ideas both ends and don't
attend oh they are actually wrong yes
and you don't have explicit key
verification that's that's your voice oh
yeah it's untested so the Mac would fail
but it does but it does feel reliably so
somebody really screws we really uh
bleats with this in the middle so that
the session Keys don't match you get
authentication failure
you don't get ciphertext going up the
stack you get a connection hang okay
okay cool so yeah so that is a
difference with us which has key
verification okay good so we got our
keys and we frame our user data I was
saying there's a controlled by currently
there's only one bit defined in that
controlled by which is a rekey bit used
for rotating keys and long live session
there's a length and then there's a
cipher text inside the ciphertext we
replicate some of the TCP flags so we've
got a flag bite currently we replicate
the fin bit and the urgent bit so we
could support you know clean connection
shut down an urgent data if urgent data
is present we actually have we include
the urgent pointer and then we just
follow it with the actual application
data and all of this is both Mac then
encrypt that it's authenticated
encryption so I want to talk a little
bit about session caching because that
was one of the biggest change since
Berlin so if I talk to you in the past
and I want to talk to you again we could
optimize things we don't need to do
public here operations anymore but what
we could do is we could take our
previous session secret and compute the
next session secret for the next
communication i have with you and based
on that i could compute the you know the
next session ID and the next encryption
keys and so on we could keep doing this
essentially forever until we just clear
our cash so that's good it saves us
computation power you don't have to do
public key operations anymore but more
importantly I think it saves us on
latency because now we could
re-establish a TCP crypt connection in
the existing three-way handshake we no
longer have to add that extra fourth leg
so the way it works is it's very similar
to the original handshake we say hey I
support you know p 5 to 1 and p 5 to 6
but in this case what we're signaling in
the p55 21 case is i want to resume a
session with this session ID and in this
example it's you know 392 and so on so
we use iNOS variable length a sub
options
it's a signal session resumption so
we're basically saying we want to resume
that previous session of p52 with the
set with this new session ID and then in
the response if session resumption was
successful we reply yeah sure let's do
that and we use a variable length sub on
tenth so basically we're saying yeah
resume 521 it's a variable-length sub
and nothing there so that one bit lets
us distinguish whether it's a fresh key
negotiation or whether it's a resumption
attempt and then we just send a knack
with the email option and at this point
we could start sending encrypted data
right away so that's how we do session
resumption this is a little bit
different from the original TCP crypt
spec were or hint back from a couple of
meetings ago where we would have an
explicit tip for session resumption so
it would be something like TCP crypt
dash session resume and then that could
have been that could have meant any
cipher effectively here we're being
explicit and saying what the cipher is
and that has some nice properties which
I'll talk about later so really what
changed since the last meeting was we
cleaned up session assumption so one of
the things we did is that if we're
resuming you know p five to one that
also implicitly means that we're willing
to start fresh with p 521 so we don't
have to say hey resume key 521 and also
by the way include a couple of extra
bytes saying we're also willing to do
five to one fresh so we're kind of
saving options space there because it
seems like this is a pretty common use
pattern the other thing we've done is we
explicitly forbid resuming you know two
sessions in the same connection so I
can't say resume five to one session idx
and resume five to one session ID why
because now this creates ambiguity and
it also feels like unnatural I don't you
know there's no real application for
this so we explicitly disallow that you
can only resume one specific session
intuitively makes sense and also
something that changed that I briefly
mentioned from the previous meeting in
Berlin actually this change happened
Berlin is this notion of being explicit
about which cipher your resuming so we
have an API after you connect the TCP
crib that tells you what cipher was used
in your public key negotiation
previously we used this generic session
resumption tip and our session ID it
sorry in our session resumption and that
would mean that if the app asked what's
i forgot negotiated he would get back
this answer saying you know the session
resumption tap which is not very
informative it's a little bit weird just
by changing the protocol by being
explicit now the API is more kind of
home of genius and makes more sense and
it also lets us do this implicit notion
of if you want to resume X you're also
willing to start fresh with X so these
are kind of the you know the main
changes that happened since the last
meeting with regards to session
resumption there were a few other
changes in TCP crypt ah some of them
were where we are explicitly disabled
disallowing sending data in the sin
segment so you know if you want to do
stuff like TFO it just doesn't work out
of the box you would have to build
something on top of TCP grip than you
know like David mentioned before and we
also move the TCP crypt specific api's
to the API documents so now the TCP
crypt document just focuses on Krypto
aspects Nassib document got shorter that
respect to so that's really it you know
not a lot not a lot changed I feel like
you know I've been saying this for the
past couple of meetings in terms of
crypt I think we're getting for the end
you know it's like really small tweaks
and polishing the you know we haven't
gone from you know packing base that's y
lv you know the big changes already
happened in the last couple of years now
i think we're really getting for the end
so in terms of the draft yeah like is it
complete it sounds like we're getting to
a last call pretty soon the
implementation we still need a kernel
implementation we personally haven't
made progress on that and also which was
mentioned by the chairs we are always
seeking for independent implementations
I think this is where we're going to
kind of weed out the bugs and and
possibly even fine
you know ambiguity in the spec you know
if somebody actually sits down and tries
to write code that's when you spot you
know we've all been see done that effort
but as author sometimes it's you know
it's kind of harder to see past that
will keep trying looking for people to
implement a little comment that there is
in the broader community significant
competition for the attention of likely
implementers from both TLS 13 and quick
there are given in i think you should
try to you know use the chicago
hackathon or suchlike that predicate
people to come there and without through
implementation and testing and so on
because the Teotl s1 poetry is using
tacit owns throughout the interrupt
testing and writing the code and so on
and i would expect if you just get you
know try to get students or something
like that will come there and to make
making all implementation of that you
bring a pile of code to seed the
hackathon yeah i mean one of the reasons
that one of the reasons why tell us is
successful what the hackathon is that
these are these guys are working on this
yes i felt i'm joe i obviously the web
pateros if there were some student teams
this time also for a for do not do some
other things and i was thinking about
there is some you know university people
here could actually you know try to get
anna some of the students were actually
working from there you know not
traveling actually the ruptured working
no over the lines and so on some but I
starts to get but I I don't have time to
do the TCP crib sorry but I was thinking
about that would be something that
actually also they take you know the
list of you know things but where people
are interesting doing in in hackathon
and if you put you know TCP crypt and
you are willing to be there there might
be some other people also be like I mean
I think it's a good idea yeah at every
suggestion especially if we start that
effort early maybe we can start
identifying some people and we could
provide some framework code you know
some frame unicode give give give the
crypto code give them the gift in the
parse code I mean basically it given the
functional blocks of code that they can
reuse and then you can have people who
aren't the experts in the crypto or in
options whistling just go fight the
fight the integration into the kernel
stack internal environment you could
even there's also a new initiative i
would say a website which was called
code my match and it's now called
somehow differently forgot
name it's a website basically I can say
what what you need where you need
implementations and people can look up
if they want to do an implementation I
can send information the nativist it
please your bright okay anything else I
guess we're going to talk about the API
I just point out that David my zero-sum
Stanford if anyone here has deep pockets
pockets course I'd be delighted to hire
someone to Stanford to do this stuff but
like this thing has gone out for long
enough that we kind of ran out of
funding and we'll pass the collection
plate around all right so you want on
the api doc and then bring up the CFR g
slides yes sounds good so api doc who
wants to address that since we don't
slide for it i assume the api doc is
functionally complete and it's about its
it'll be ready for work last call along
with the other two drafts right yeah
David misers that that's the idea yeah I
think you were you know I as I was doing
the slides I realized were missing this
mandatory bit and then maybe there'll be
another option to stay like you know
disabled completely versus like respond
with an empty you know option but I
think we're you know a very small patch
away from being final this look my
inclination is to sequence the last
calls to send to do a first last call on
the protocols take ino and TCP crypt as
a package in one work with last call and
that one might run a little long because
we're going to have to go find outside
experts we know where to find at least
one expert on the options I'm sure we
can find one or two other other dtp
people take a look Kyle probably has
some some likely suspects to go triple
check the crypto and then but not
include the API document first review
last call but send it to a group glass
call shortly thereafter so that we don't
get the docs to disconnect from each
other um can we increase is it possible
there's a kind of a procedural question
but the star
tcp Krypton TSP you know last call's at
the same time but then oh I plan I I
plan to do more than just our the same
time I planned us in one in nelson says
these two drafts are going are in
working group last call and it's a
single working last call on both docs
yes but then could like if you know
could like to say i mean i would imagine
it might take more time for crypto
review for tcp crib versus you know so
they have to finish at the same time are
could you know we can decide what what
to do my preps workgroup chair is to is
to chain those two drafts together and
just keep them going as a pair because i
think asking someone to review one
without the other is a bit much whereas
I think the api doc is separable it's
got a relationship i think if the api
doc runs a month or six weeks behind
behind the main drafts that's probably
okay because if we find anything we'll
still have time to catch it before the
iesg pronounces on the any of them well
that was easy no all right okay all
right
alright so there was some interest among
the security area directors and
transport and the chairs to get some
additional additional eyeballs looking
at the looking at the crypto in TCP
crypt before mgcp you know before we
decided to go to work in the class call
and there were some it this was the
result of some questions that had been
sort of bubbling up over the course of
the last year and a half or so and so
what I tried to do was compile them into
into small edible chunks that we could
send to the CFR gmail enlist and
hopefully get some get some some
guidance on and so the first question
was around the TCP crypt session ID and
specifically what properties does it
need to have and why does it need to
have those properties or what properties
does that does it have as described by
the by the draft and so so for instance
the one of the properties that the
system relies on it feeds into the
session ID feeds the transcript and and
some other information the the key
agreement and whatnot and so is it
necessary for instance for that for that
session ID to in order to in order to
have the the security properties that we
want out of this protocol is it
necessary for that ID to be to be
unpredictable or is it or does it just
need to be unique overall time so that
you can't have you can't possibly have
two connections with the same ID unless
they were engineered by two endpoints
colluding which is kind of dumb so so
that was the first question that i had
and there's actually like a it's it's
probably written better in the email
that i sent so so if you want to take a
look at that it's on the CFR gmail
enlist from october second and actually
got some really good responses to this
the best response I got was off list and
it was by someone named Nataniel el I
don't know if any of you guys know who
that is
I don't know who who what L is but he
sent me a fairly long analysis of of how
he you know of how the cryptid works and
what properties he thinks is that it
requires and so I think I sent that to
you guys if anyone else wants to see it
I'm happy to forward it along I didn't
want to put it on the list because he
didn't respond to the list but but I'm
happy to give it to anyone individually
so just send me send me or they did an
email and I could forward that along and
then there were there were some other
responses as well that were of interest
and those all went to the list um so
that was the that was the first question
so the second question that I sent was
around the the generic how does the
generic nature of Ino as a negotiation
protocol for Tepes a feed into what the
requirements for session IDs are right
and so the idea here is that that you
use an application that makes use of you
know in mandatory application-aware mode
is assuming i mean it's it's it's it's
mandating that that uh you know is
available and that there is some tip
that is in common between two machines
and it produces a session ID that is
then used for endpoint authentication
what properties for instance does that
session ID need to have and what
properties should be no guarantee to
applications that are mandatory
application-aware so the the situation
that I was concerned about I know I sent
an email about this like a year ago and
we stood around for a while on it i
didn't i didn't really feel satisfied
with the answer that came out the the
worry that i have is that applications
will treat this interface as a black box
with the properties of whichever tap
happens to be the default which in this
case of you TCP crypt um but is that
it's not without explicit without
explicitly listing what the properties
of the session ID need to be that
assumption may wind up falling over if
you if say the default tix which is to
something completely different that has
totally different security drop
right like let's say it's let's say you
switch to some tip that for some reason
requires the session ID to remain secret
right in that case publishing a signed
list of session IDs to you know to a
public web server and using that as your
out-of-band authentication channel is
not is obviously not something you want
to do because you might be able to
derive session piece from that or
whatnot right so going back I made these
slides in a rush so I didn't get them in
quite the right speaking order but like
so one of the one of the questions I had
was well does the session ID need to be
computationally indistinguishable from
random well not really and in fact it
isn't because the first byte is always
is is predictable or at least it's in a
small space right so and even even if
the session ID even if every bit of the
session ID was slightly biased toward
one for instance it would still be
secure as long as there was enough
entropy in the whole thing to prevent
someone from from guessing it and there
and as long as there are mechanisms in
place to guarantee that its unique
overall time right so what I really
would like is some is some generic
crypto guidance on the right way to
phrase some of the properties that we
want out of this thing because I think
like right now they're either over
specified or under specified and I'm not
entirely sure which I'm also not sure
that this is that this is worth all the
trouble because I think this is this may
be one of the situations where people
see the spec and they kind of they know
what it means but I feel like precision
at this time is probably worth pursuing
as long as it's not going to consume
undo resources um yeah so David Mazouz
so I think that in you know in general
the sort of what we've learned and
encrypt though is you want to like over
specify these things like most people
don't actually you know most attacks
don't actually take the form of like you
know a chosen ciphertext attack but the
idea is that like if you can survive
vacuum if your algorithm can survive
that game then it can survive any game
so we've attempted in the Eno draft to
be you know to err on the side of
of kind of over specifying and that's
why currently the Eno draft requires all
but that first bite to be in this
computational indistinguishable from
random which that wasn't actually our
idea someone else suggested on the mail
is but that seemed like a nice way of it
seemed to encompass a bunch of things
like not enough entropy and you know
things like that that you might
otherwise worry about so even though
like probably you know you're not
conceding your random generator with a
session ID if it is competition to
single random that might like rule out a
bunch of other kind of weird things that
might be problematic yeah I mean I think
one of the one of the things that I was
trying to that I was sort of hoping for
because there are other protocols that
need this the specific property that I
think you're implying like the there's
an NTP draft going through for ntp
security that wants kind of the same
thing around session identifiers the the
all but the first byte thing just kind
of like it hits that button of
architectural purity that I have
somewhere in my brain it just sort of
bugs me but again I'm not sure that it's
worth the effort to fix that it's just
it's something that feels that that
feels kind of kind of like a kludge if
that David black if if specifying it
that way which is that the the first
byte is it is on its own and everything
else is computation is indistinguishable
from random is sufficient to solve the
problem there may be a tighter necessary
condition but we don't have to go
looking for we simply need to be
convinced that that the problem is we
understand is solved I mean I think that
like this multiple necessary condition
so one necessary condition is because
you know is so agnostic about the temp
it's that you cannot ever have to uh you
can't ever have two different uh taps
producing the same session ID so I
totally agree that that first bite right
I understand what the first fighters for
there's just there's no other way to do
it right there is no no cryptographers
out there so you know they say you can't
find a sháá 512 collision you can't
find a catch a collision but nobody is
assuming that you can't you know provide
one message that
who's sha-512 hashes the same as another
messages like ketchup hash right like
that's just not a common assumption
people are making we can't make those
kinds of assumptions across this all
right well you can I mean I actually
like a year ago or so i posted a message
to the list describing a naive way of
constructing two hashes that are easy
that you know you can find collisions
between the two but not within each one
and this this also helps it's a variant
of what Tara was asking about earlier if
somehow you get confused about which uh
which cipher you're using the session ID
immediately d confuses you you can take
a look at the trace and you can and you
can see what went wrong yeah I think one
of the just again I think this is more
like food for thought than anything else
and I want to get what I really want is
some input from from cryptographers who
are who have worked on stuff like this
before and just sort of understand maybe
maybe get a better understanding of what
they think these properties are should
be and should be called um you know like
we talked about like unlink ability for
instance right to protect to protect
client privacy what does that really
mean like is there a formal definition
for that somewhere and if so what does
that mean for like does the session ID
as defined in TCP crypt uh achieve that
and does TV you know properly require
that so I i mean i don't i don't think
that this this stuff is going to hold up
working with less call like that's not
my intent it's more just to get input
and see if there are ways to refine the
the language and if there if there
aren't then that's fine too I mean David
again to be clear unlink ability is not
provided by session assumption right
this is a trade-off right so one one or
the other but if you're behind a not
like in your resuming TCP crepes look
even though at the API level they look
the same but like obviously someone
could instrument there Colonel or their
TCP stock and like figure out that
they're using session resumption to the
same person this is dkg just wondered
whether there are two different kinds of
ability what is unlink ability to the
pier the others unlink ability to the
network and I think it does session
resumption here does provide on my
ability to the network so just again if
we're talking about being clear about
what we're specifying there are just say
unlike ability unlink ability to whom
and dkg could you see the microphone
because I got a question for which you
might have have an insightful answer
discussion is really interesting on it
sounds like uh we're looking for some
precise terms this this working group is
not the place to write those definitions
they buy they belong somewhere over in
the security areas response to of the
pervasive monitoring and the like where
do you do you have any idea where we're
in security area that ought to be I
don't sorry I'm not deep enough in the
IETF fine-grained bureaucratic
hair-splitting today okay but and in
particularly you haven't seen a draft
going through over there that does that
does the basic definition of privacy of
privacy relevant security terms of
kyle's looking for there are there are
several places where that kind of thing
has been discussed but I don't think if
it'd been directly applied the folks in
the HR pc working group research group
have actually got a fair number of
specific terms trying to map like human
rights concepts to technical detail go
um I hear you well good for unlink
ability that's probably useful yeah yeah
but but I don't think that anyone has
done assists systematized all right at
the very least we could pray I'm sorry
at the mic folks at the very least we
could record a a sense that that
something more general ought to be done
um and we would have found it useful if
we could have gotten to these terms but
it's probably a security area uh-uh-uh
activity not not not transport let me
just say that this is dkg and um I'm not
sure that something more general should
have been done right this is we have a
specific use case here where specific
needs and I think that if we do this
specific to TCP crypt that would be a
useful contribution and if that turns
out to be generalizable that's fine but
I don't want to block this kind
review were all invited women on the
head that the objects are trying to make
i panted garbled is if somebody had
written down definitions of the relevant
crypto oriented properties like privacy
and virginal mobility and what that Kyle
could have just pointed to we would have
found that useful but not having that
should not block us I agree completely
yeah I mean I again I wasn't suggesting
holding up the documents on this basis
but it's more like education and
dissemination of knowledge about the
right ways to phrase these things it
seems like we need to it seems like that
stuff doesn't actually exist at the
moment that we need to we need to build
up that knowledge maybe have a set of
informational dogs that that describe
these properties more precisely more
formally aaron aaron falk uh so as
conversation makes me think that this is
this is actually much more general topic
than just this working group right yes I
said yes at the D kgs observation that
you know that this is shared in the in
the human rights research group so I
think that maybe this is a reasonable
thing to try to bubble up to the IAB
because this is this is related to the
you know this strategic interest in
privacy and pervasive encryption and and
it's actually probably one of the more
useful dimensions of it from an IT
perspective which is to try to give some
guidance to working groups on on a link
ability and and you know what what's the
toolkit and what are the what are some
candidate requirements that a protocol
developers might want to include cool
mirrior to put you on the spot could you
get this onto the security areas radar
screen in the iesg wrap up discussions
from this week please she said yes which
means which means Mirror Mirror either
doing the iesg meeting or talk of
Kathleen in private all right that's it
any questions okay so
long discussion but probably in good
shape yeah I think that's it any other
comments questions dead cats rotten
tomatoes that was a shockingly short
session lots of really good songs like
um thinking about what happened here
more importantly what didn't happen here
i think i agree with nebula who said
this this really does feel like we are
we are at the point where we r group
last call is the next step and the
drafts are ready so many thanks to all
the hard work from the team from the
team that's working on the giraffes and
i think i think this this is i think
this is really good the the i think just
I just didn't estimate my head I think
the the flight to session time ratio is
about twenty to one now I could all go
to TLS for the rest of the way I think
the chair is going to have to do a
little bit of uh well before we go we're
gonna have to run a round of a round up
a few known expert reviewers I think
we're looking for for ween top of my
head 2 1402 for tcp crypt we know we
know Joe touch is going to be one of one
of the Eno experts i only have to find
one more kyle has fine too fabulous all
right anybody not sign the blue sheets
Andrea did did you sign the blue sheets
i think we pass from around while you
were talking anyone else
alright I guess that's it okay I drink
we're done and i look forward to beating
chicago's worker glass call done and if
nothing major happens during working
group last call we may not need a
meeting in Chicago that that that would
be a stunningly wonderful outcome enjoy
the rest your day in song don't worry
about me when a plan comes together yeah
I think we've basically been at this for
value year right and we've gotten job
done fifth I'm perfectly happy to tell
this is gone yeah I mean it certainly
could have gone faster but I yeah it was
all right and I think I think she'll
open totally saw today which is both of
the trash and visible changes from
Burlington al-nour negates that there
are means about writing with work we're
hitting about where we hid your be all
right now paul david i don't see you
again before
you