>>David is going to talk to us
about drones and ah anti-drone
ah countermeasures, ah beyond ah
just simply handing me a drone
remote, because ah I got a drone
and the only thing I can do
apparently is fly the thing into
my face, [laughter], um and I’ve
done that a number of times, so
let's big, let’s give David a
big round of applause.
[Applause]. Good Luck. >> Thank
you >> Have a good time >> Thank
you. Thank you. Well [Clears
throat]. I can say that I’m
pretty iterate so let's get it
started. Well, welcome to my,
welcome to my talk, er glad to
see you here er and I’m going to
present a project interceptor,
um oh it's uh it’s about owning
anti-drone systems with
nanodrones. So, er, thats me,
er, well, I’m David Melendez, er
and I sit on the embedded
software engineer er, in er
company in Spain and and I er,
the creator, the actor of the
[indiscernible] robots and I
want to explain later. And er
the author of the book Hacking
con drones, it’s in Spain, it’s
in Spanish and ah recently
speaker but not here. And a
trainiac. Why, why, why are you
saying that I a traniac? This is
a, this is the autobus espanol
it’s a pretty cool train, its
fast and it's cool and you’ll
fast but, I’m pretty er, fond,
of er, your trains because they
are pretty bada**. They are
stack containers [laughs] big
fun, big fun of you guys, big
fun of you folks, absolutely.
So, you, you meet later with me
er, be careful, because I, I’m
maybe I start talking with
trains and I cannot stop, so, be
careful. So, I will like to
start with um, with this,
[laughs], you laughing [laughs],
brill, good job folk, [laughs]
I, I, I thinking about this guy
living at home and er honey, I,
I’m, I’m doing a pretty good job
today [laughs], so thats thats a
one point. The second point
previously in defcon, er, want
to start the, with drones in
defcon. And I think that what is
the first drones seen in defcon
er, with pretty cool stuff and
um with with hacking
capabilities, you, you can take
the drone along the city, er,
taking a lot of networks um,
make some cooler stuff, right,
and the second one was the, the
the year ago for the danger
drone, and er it is a pretty
cool stuff because er, it will
use er, 3G and 4G erm,
communication and telemetrics,
so, er, that's because several
er anti-drone systems works
indeed with 3G and 4G systems
and if you oos, use, the same
system, um the anti-drones, they
can be ‘trol you. There’s,
there’s no way to jam your
drone, but er, only because it’s
illegal to jam 3G, 4G erm,
frequencies, er, you can say
some kind of er, problems. So I
want to explain drones as a
threat, I, I, I like this that
picture, because it’s it’s
[laughs] pretty um, pretty cool.
Well, er we can I start er
talking about drones as a flying
computers. It’s like er internet
of things over your head er,
IoT, it’s, we can call iot us
before we return to, to us host,
because er, there were er, name
Quadcopters, ok, you can use
custom payloads, sniffer
jammers, network analyzers, 3D
mapping cameras and so on. Some
kind of cooler stuff you can,
you can put it in your drone, so
er, any type of thing you, you
can imagine, you can put into
your drone. A drone is a, it’s a
vehicle, it’s not a weapon, it's
not a it’s a bill its a tool,
alright. So, we, how we can
detect er drones, well er the
first one is ok, I, I’m seeing a
drone ok. I detected it. So,
there’s a, there are thermal and
extended cameras er, well,
[indiscernible] out of systems
that er, they are able to detect
drones by its heat and, wait, er
artificial intelligence and so
and er with thermal cameras with
electronics and motor heat
detection. Ok, you see four dots
on the sky are are pretty hot.
It’s not a pigeon, I think. Mmm,
also othe, othe, detection
method is a extension of drone
noise, er, a detection extension
[makes sound] “vvvrrrrr”, ok,
we, we got it. The detector
radio frequency in white form,
this is the most important
method to detect drones because
er every drone has a signal too
of radio communication and is
pretty easy to detect that this,
those drones because for
example, ok, um and wifi with a
access point, name er, put here
a manufactured drone, its much,
it must be a drone ok. Well,
other, other methods to detect
drones I make pretty fun of
this, er voluntary measures.
Well, if you install in your
drone an application that report
to cops that you are flying a
drone in a certain area in a, at
a er certain time, ok, no
problem at all, everything will
be alright, right? [laughs], er
so, this application gives to
cops the ability to take down
your your drone, imani, imagine
if you install this application
in your car, ok, rethink where
we are right. So, perfect plan,
so, how about the counter
countermeasures? Well, we can
use uh several methods that they
are already on the stage they
are like the spread spectrum but
in, you can transmit, in a, in a
very white er area of radio
frequency and er with the hope
that nobody can gam on, on all
the area, for any hopping, you
can hop too many channels and
use unexpected frequencies like
the jammer, the jammer expects
that the drones works in a
certa, certain frequencies and
robot protocols that we are
talking about this. Well I want
to explain my first er, my first
round of this stuff, that, it is
called Atropos it’s a Quadcopter
that I build like 6 years ago,
you can google it, it is in
hackaday and so on and I decide
to build er with a wifi router,
it’s a wifi router, an La Fonera
router and er, well some cooler
stuff like er, wheel remote er
of nintendo, as an internal an
internal sensors. So 6 Years
ago, there’s no chinese er
manufacturers that you can buy
and tay, take your sensor to
your home, so, there was er
easier to take the sensor er
from, from the [indiscernible]
and I decide to, to put the
sensors to the router directly
er, by attaching the, the, the
bus to light, ok and er control
it by by a web server, er
installed on the router, there,
there programmer distribution
program is programmed in in c
inside the router and it has a
it has an embedded system. I’m
not sure er, some of the
capability with bully that it’s
it’s able to attack other wi
wifi’s so you can see the, the
La Fonera router and some pretty
cool and professional soldering
skills and that's perfect. I’m,
ah, num num num, so now what
else. I like to see this movie
because er, well, well all the
star wars movies made me cry, so
I like the, this one ok, and I
like practically in a scene um,
we count fifty rebel ships Lord
Vader but they’re so small
they’re evading our turbo
blasters that makes er, that
give me an idea why not make a
small drone, ok, with chopsticks
ok, because, people ask me why,
why are you using chopsticks?
[laughs] Do, don’t you have a 3D
printer or somewhere, are you
poor or, or, or what? Em, well
I, If I print the, he drone,
nobody believes me it’s mine.
[laughs] So this is mine.
[laughter]. Erm, I’m going to
check that erm, actually the
drone is draining the its
battery, so maybe I have to, to
fly before the battery
drains.[laughs] Ok, alright. So
the brain interceptor is based
on low budget, now, seriously,
low. You take er, um a cheap
sensor, a cheap er board and a
cheap everything. Minimum size
and weight, harder to detect ok,
and with all the stuff that er,
that this on this thing, hacking
capabilities and receding
control. Well, this is the the
drone and the chopsticks. We can
see um, um a a Linux board
inside that is indeed a, a
router with open, OpenWRT line
Linux er, distribution. Er,
inside er, and some cool stuff
so er, like, brushed motors, why
use it, because they are cheap,
ridiculously cheap ok, and
small. So er, we have
transistors and steer and camera
and so on, so you can, you can
compare with 1 euro coin ok, and
this is the Vocore2 I think this
is small, this is the smallest
board on the market er, that
this run Linux and we have WiFi
and er, ya, it, the spe, spi,
specifications and we have a cp
one core of cpu and 3 serial
ports and the most important
thing is er, powell, uh PWM er
ports, there is 4, there are 4
ports of pulls with modulation
ok, this, er, those ports are
used to control the motors
without any other integrated
circuit just because, it have to
be a small, it have to be cheap,
um we have to take advantage on
all the, all the hardware stuff
ok. So, we need er 4 powell, er,
PWM signals to control the
motors, one for each one and
they are uh hard real time
constrained. Uh, we cannot
emulate and or it is very
difficult and uncomfortable to
emulate er, those signals er,
with the quality required, to
er, to make the drone works. So,
we have 4 channels available,
we, but we only 2 enable by the
manufacturer. We have 2 enable
the other, the other one but,
what, what happens when the,
with the, the other 2? They are
the serial debug console. Good
job, right, ok. So we have to
disable, to disable the er, the
serial port for debugging and
enable all the 4, pins. I went
to the forum and the guy that
design the the code, er, is
answer all your questions and,
one guy, I ask for to enable to
the, these pins and the guy
answer, well there’s a hard way.
Well you have to download the
open, the Linux software from
vocore, second, find the DDS in
short, try doing the try to
understand the pin control and
you have understand some kind of
this stuff, and then you make
magic, ok. And you will be a
good Linux hacker [laughs] ok
[laughs], what the f**k?
[laughter]. Thank you for
nothing [laughs] guy. Er, so,
here you, you have the, all the
stuff that you need to, to
enable and disable, all the
stuff. You have the UART er
pins, er, defined, you have the
pin marks, ok this is a maxer,
uh, I interconnected er, inside
of the, of the, of the
sysinternal chip. You have to
wire, er, functions, wire with
outputs, because er chip has
more fraction, more functions,
than outputs and you are saying
a faction, a function to an
output. So, you have to, to
reassign, disable the, the UART
and enable the er power with er
modulations. We have to redefine
those pins, we call, I call
[indiscernible] pins. We have
the first one, the serial, the
one, and they are already
defined, but I’m going to define
the, the other 2. But this code
UART2 P PWM. The group is UART
but the function is powell, en,
PWM. Additionally in the I2C
mass, I attach an er, a sensor
to, to take into account the
battery ok, we disable UART and
we enable the, the 4 channels.
Well this is for, only for, for
your information from the data
sheet, where, where I found the
information to change that. Well
the power stage is almost it
that’s me in my work er
pretending to er, to know what
I’m doing. With an oscilloscope
um, there is a, er, my my
personal version of electronic
speed control. Ok. This is the
oscilloscope because er, with
brushed motors, we have to deal
with er, counter electromotive
er force, because er, when the
motor is a spinning er, I have
to deal, I have to power it, but
a motor act as also as a
generator. And put er current in
the circuit, a reverse current,
so I have to cancel it with a
capacitor and a dial and a
circuit dial. This is the P the
PID tunning this is the worst
part of build a drone, you have
to turn it from 0 0 0 ok. And,
um, well. Er, I’m going to
explain, the WiFi Architecture
of this um, of this drone, that
is not a WiFi regular drone
because er, it works er, as a
beacon frame based
communication. That’s because if
you are not authenticated to any
network, you can not be the
authenticated, ok. Nobody come
here to the authentication
attack and they’ll authenticate
my drone. Because it’s not
authenticated to anything. Er,
we have a joystick, the joystick
is not a fancy recei drone
remote. [muffled off-mic
talking]. And er, we have a um,
a pilot side that this is my
laptop with an additional WiFi
adaptor. So, er my, pro my
communication protocol is based
on beacons, beacon frames, so in
the payload those beacon frames
er, travel er, all the data from
my remote, from my joystick and
to the BI Load and reverse. It
will turn on your laptop from
wireless, you will see 2
Networks, one called interceptor
and the other one call pileto or
pilot. Er, They are fake
networks ok. One network is er,
generated by my laptop and the
other network is generated by
the drone. Er, both sides are
designed, to, listen to east,
each other and erm, well, for
control and telemetry, as you,
as you can see that on, on the
other slide. Er, protected with
a encryption algorithm, because
if not, we are not doing nothing
[laughs]. So, this is the
packet, er packet format, and
you can see all, all the stuff
of um the encryption, algorithm.
We have an a initialization
vector, we have a common
sequence number and a integrity
check. So this, this is the er,
this is the travel inside the
beacon frame. So, I would like,
um, we can turn on the drone. I
will put er, on the ground for
my safety, not for yours
[laughter]. [Cheer]. [Laughter]
[Drone flying, laughter, muffled
talking]. Maybe I’m going to
change the battery later. [Drone
flying]. I have to change the
battery. I will try here.
[muffled speech]. Well, um,
while it, it its starts again,
I’m going to explain er you um a
particular um, er, er
characteristic of the, of this
protocol, but er, because erm,
its allowed me to change er the
channels of the WiFi, of the
both WiFi’s, the drone and the
pilot er, while I’m flying it,
without, without losing control,
er, that because, um, the WiFi’s
adaptors, er, they are no
perfect. So, if you are on
channel one, you are listening
er, packets mmmm from channel 2
for example. Er, this protocol
takes advantage of this.
Because, if you are, if I want
to change the channel of the
drone to, from channel 1 to
channel 5. I turn it on, change
to channel 2 ok. The drone
acknowledge that, ok and channel
2 change, dual changed to
channel 2, so, both pilot and
drone are in the channel 2. So,
they in a loop changing
channels, each other, until er,
they reach, all the er, to the
channel 5 or, or the target
channel, that I set. This is the
interface er, well, this er,
some come of stuff of this er,
work interface, the inter inter
interfacing is created on the
laptop. Er, the laptop receives
the bee, the beacon frames,
they, they, they turn into web
circuit package and it’s er,
seen er, on the, on the web
page. So. I want to show you a
video. This is the interface on
the drone. And er, now the, the
networks on my house. [Clears
throat] The, the drone keeps
updating the the networks but,
I, I can control the drone while
the drone is er, attacking the
networks why with bully, ok. So,
there is so many er, networks
on, on here. I, I’m changing
the, the channel of the drone,
while, you see. They it show on
our system they, they change of
the, of the channel. You going
see, you can see that, here.
Here. Channel 8, both, ok. And
they Chay and they change
seamlessly. I don’t, I don’t
lose the control. That because I
don’t, I don’t want to put our
next eh apto, our next WiFi
adaptor, on the drone ok,
because it's very expensive.
[laughs] It's er, er, an extra
weight to the drone er,
especially. Ok. [Drone flying]
[Applause]. Are you safe [laugh,
audience comment] . Well, it so,
it’s almost ok, ok. [Laughter] .
So, er, I’m not a very, a very
professional pilot indeed, but.
Well, the other, the other
demonstration that I’m doing
with this is to prove that, any,
anybody who, is able to build a
drone with a, a custom flight
controller like mine. This is
all, all programmed on C, both
the distribution program er,
inside the, inside the recall
and the protocol em, of
communication. It has um, I’m
working right now on a extra
file doc communication system
based on er, er, SDL ok. Just,
just incase, er, every er, just
in case, a pile, a, a drone
jammer detect my network,
because my network er, you can
see as a pilot als has an
interceptor, but they can change
to, to be the same as the, as
the, as the nearby networks, ok
that is er, to hide the, the
presence of the drone. So, er,
another protocol is a, fibre
protocol based on on niefie, on
FM that is [indiscernible] and a
radio frequency, inside the
range and er, start transmitting
if the pilot detects that no
more telemetry comes from the
drone. There, that the link is
is broken. So, er, you have, it
transmit to, with a radio
frequency, and the, the limit of
this, of this project is that
transmitting illegal frequencies
are the less problem for bad
guys, if, if you are to, to do
bad things. The less of your
problem is to transmit on FM ok.
So, er, this is a warning to, to
drone manufacturers, because er,
I I still, keep er, sending
commands to the drone even,
without WiFi, using a raspberry
pi radio transmission with a
RPTX er project ok. As proof of
concept. So, er, I am selecting
the, the frequency dynamically,
so er, we, we survey the the
spectrum and I take the, the
peaks and the valleys and then I
select the, the best suitable
er, frequency. So, the fallback
FM base er communication, we
have a the joystick. They, they
are limited to 4 bytes packet
and they are transmitted to F,
FSK modulation, using the mini,
the mini, mini modem er project
and er, there are, they turn on,
into a Rev format, ok with our
FM modulated transmission and
they are on air by Raspberry Pi.
So um, as the dongle on drone
captures that frequency and
makes the reverse path ok, we
have a, an audio capture and I
we have to demodul, demodulate
that eh, packet with er, the
same mini modem but compile with
er for er, for er, architure of
the drone of this
[indiscernible] and we have erm,
the 4 byte er format er, for
flight control, ok. Ok, this was
the demo. I you can see that I’m
like Porkus [laughs] Ok. I would
like to, I would like to
explain, mm mm mmm, more, we
have more time? I would like to
explain er, a little bit more er
what, what map do I follow to be
tuning, because it's the hardest
part to, to make a drone. Er, I
attached to a, to a 6, 8 er vent
professional grade. Er with also
chopsticks ok. And other part,
other home parts on the, you can
see, so, you have to turn the P
that is the proportional gain.
It’s uh you you send uh we stay
here. The drone it stay, it
stays here and I want to stay
straight the road is zero Its
a, If if if it moves, the road
change, so we have to multiply
the road by the proportional
gain ok. We have one force, the
second force is the integral er,
er, term, so I have to take into
account, how much time is the is
the drone in another state, ok.
And the erm, relative term is it
takes into account the speed
that I’m reaching, the the side
position ok. That, erm those er,
values er we multiply with a
gain we have a real control of
the drone. Ok. So. Ok  This is
my paper. Ok. I would like to
see you. So as conclusions. I
will like to show you the
conclusions. Ok. We have a
regular small size weight and
cost. This bring us to the next
point, how i’m hacking from
scratch er even, er you can’t
track that you buy a router er,
cops can’t track that you are
building a drone for bad or for
good ok. So, er, we have a site,
hidden channels, communications
as our central philosophy, no
vendor or 3G 4G communications.
Erm, we keep the costs er, low
because we are using WiFi also,
but er, we have er, um,
provisional capabilities to keep
the communications safe, or as
the safe as we can. Er, if an
unexpected attack is performed,
or or all the Specs, or WiFi
Spectrum is er, is jammed, er,
we have um, a fallback system,
to keep the, the drone control.
And we, we have er, people can
can see us. We also have er
hacking capabilities, to erm,
hack another WiFi networks
pentesting and so on, keeping on
only one er, adaptor on the
drone, ok, with the same
adaptor. We have travel er,
throughout er, all the er, WiFi
channels. So er, under file
control based on er, SDL
protocol. So. I will like to
thank you to say here and er,
well if you have any questions,
so thank you very much.
[Applause]