>>When you’re a younger person
who runs for office, the last
thing you want to do is run for
office, especially when you
don’t have your own. That just
looks weird and so I don’t want
to go there. Alright. My name is
Daniel Zolnikov and I’m a
Montana state representative and
we’re gonna talk about politics
in the surveillance state and
there’s one thing that might be
a uh some of you kind of catch
is all this is obscure. For
example I’m from a town called
Roundup, Montana, I’m 31 years
old. I uh actually first served
in the legislature at 25 years
old. Currently I chair the House
Energy and Technology Committee
in the State house. Yeah, they
let a Russian help dictate uh
energy and technology policy for
not only Montana but the the
northwest. That’s a scary thing,
especially in today’s politics
if you ask me. Um, I am a
Republican and that may even
seem crazier wi- with this issue
but I’m gonna talk about the
politics on these issues. And
try to help clearly dictate how
you can push for both sides of
the aisle and hopefully pass
some of the laws we’ve passed in
Montana. Uh we have two terms in
Montana so again we have term
limits after four terms. I’m
running for my fourth term, the
fact that the term limits allows
us to go up in inf- influence
and power quicker. That’s why I
get to chair the committee, do
one more chairmanship and then
I’m out. And it also means each
of our voices are a lot stronger
even if we’re younger or newer.
Uh random facts about me. I am a
swimmer. I am a current MBA
student. I previously spoke at
DefCon 21 where I did not do my
shot. So. That’s why I had to
come back. Um I’m half Russian.
I’m half Italian. And that’s a
lot of chaos mixed in it all and
last fun fact is I still use a
Blackberry. I just thought I’d
throw that out there at a tech
conference to just. [laughter]
Ok, so why am I here. What have
I done, what is the legislation
I’ve worked and passed to law. A
lot of politicians say what
they’ve worked on, but they
never talk about if it passed or
not. These all passed into law.
In 2013 I passed a bill that uh
required a warrant for GPS
location. No one knew about it
and no one cared and then um
Edward Snowden came out. We’ll
talk a little more about all
these later on. 2015 I passed
the strongest nation, th- the
nation’s strongest freedom of
the press law in Montana. I also
passed a bill for medical
immunity for minors. That has
nothing to do with this speech,
but it’s a really good bill that
if you’re under 21 and dying,
you call 9 1, no one gets an
MIP, you just get them to the
hospital. Uh co-sponsored asset
forfeiture, uh in 2015 as well.
Uh also in 2017 more recently I
carried a bill that required a
warrant for electronic devices.
All devices, that bill is state
law in Montana. Carried a bill
that required a warrant of
fourth amendment subpoena
requirements which was like a
special kind of subpoena that
had a follow the fourth
amendment for electronic
communications. That passed into
law. I put severe limits on
license plate readers in
Montana. Uh that passed into law
and did major reforms and
restrictions for vehicle spot
checks in Montana. Uh also law.
So we’re gonna go through a
series [applause] oh yeah.
[applause] Thank you. [applause]
I’m actually just here to get
you guys to move to my state and
invest in the big tech companies
and things along those lines. So
if you like skiing and hiking.
Uh shameless promotion for
Montana. So first and fourth
amendment. I know, some of this
I’m gonna cover, you’re gonna
know a little bit about and
that’s fine. I just am doing it
just it’s nice to touch on it
again. First amendment protects
the freedom of speech, religion,
press, assembly and to petition
the government. Uh and am a what
you call a liberty conservative
or constitutional conservative.
Very similar lines where I like
the constitution. Uh and I like
uh all I think all of it, I like
all of the constitution.
Especially the Bill of Rights is
what I focus on. So. First
amendment, freedom of speech, uh
the nation is founded on the
concept that we can share ideas,
be who we want, do uh what we
want with our lives. If you want
to go into technology, you can
do it. Education you can do it,
it doesn’t matter. We have
opportunity here and the idea to
talk and have conversations is
huge in this nation. The fourth
amendment prevents the
government from unreasonable
searches and seizures of their
houses uh on them. Their cars,
their papers and effects and you
need probable cause for that.
Well, without probable cause you
know the government's listening,
looking, watching and you’re
more likely to censor your
freedom of speech, express,
discuss, talk, live and now you
are no longer in a free society.
So why isn’t our data ours? And
this is why the fourth amendment
doesn’t apply to our data as
third party doctrine which is a
legal theory states that your
information really isn’t yours.
If I send you a text message, it
goes through Verizon. Verizon is
the third party, now there’s no
eh- expectation of privacy
through that digital
communication and through uh
court cases and legal doctri-
legal theory this isn’t
considered your e-mail or your
private information anymore. You
shared it with somebody. Thus
why your data can be mask
collected by government
agencies. Uh there are also
outdated laws from the 80s a
little bit updated in the 90s.
But also uh have very limited
protections of your digital
communications. Uh also the
Patriot Act which I would rather
like to say the Un-Patriot Act
is the expanded government’s
ability to monitor, collect and
retain the data of Americans and
then they don’t de- then they
can delay or not even notify you
of some of these searches. So
your data technically is just
not yours. And that le- led to
these other problems.
Technically gov- the data’s not
yours. So then we have the NSA
of course we all learn 5 years
in continuously the mass data
collection of your digital
communications and then there
are private companies who took
part in this through back door
channels. Microsoft, Google,
Yahoo, Facebook, YouTube, Skype,
Apple. They all participated.
Um. So there’s a problem of you
have your data, it’s not
considered yours and now through
large companies, it’s siphoned
into a database of the federal
government to simplify this. I
know it gets a lot more
technical, but let’s just keep
this simple. Um, then there’s
secret courts that are supposed
to have checks and balances over
the government, which of course
we know these secret courts uh,
a court that’s secret is not
open to the public, the public
cannot be critical and hold them
accountable when nobody really
knows, plus the people who are
appointed on the secret court
are appointed by the supreme
court justice who’s appointed by
a president so there’s like 3 or
4 levels of not being
accountable to the people once
again. Um and from the the late
70s to the early 2013, the court
requests. All I know is it was a
very low number which means they
were rubber stamping basically
every request. Um then the
national D DA license plate and
facial recognition tracking
program uh is another one that
came out a few years ago that we
learned about through the ACLU
foia request for information
act. That the DEA had a national
database of your driving
information so if you are a
local individual in Las Vegas
driving around, you are likely
having your picture taken uh
with these license plate readers
either on vehicles or on bridges
and infrastructure of your
vehicle, of the license plate
and of the people in it. This is
me taking pictures of you. So
they’re just taking these
pictures all the time. Well a
lot of times local law
enforcement work with national
uh agencies. They upload the
data and so even if there’s good
rules of the data short term in
your state, this data is being
uploaded nationally into a
database that’s forever and
connect all license plates
across the country and the
people in the vehicles and
that’s permanent and we don’t
know what’s happening with it
and how big of a database and
where it’s going. So not my
favorite um not my favorite
route of where the third party
doctrine has led us. And then
they got people which this is
like the worst thing. This just
bothers me completely is we have
nothing to hide. I uh there’s
there’s so many philosophies
based on the freedom of speech
expression that we kind of
talked about already, but there
are major problems with self
censorship. First off if you
have nothing to hide, you’re
probably really boring and
haven’t lived a single day of
your life. Because I don’t know
about you, but I have a lot to
hide. Right? Like I went to
college and I had a great time.
[laughter] Um let me give a good
example of the problems with
self censorship. So we’re
driving in rural Montana, which
all you will one day visit, I
hope. And the radio is on some
great like 80s song pops on that
you love. And you just crank it
up, there’s nobody out there,
there’s nobody listening,
there’s nobody watching. Your
windows are down because it’s
not 100 degrees like it is here.
You’re just cruising and you
just start singing that song and
you don’t care and you sing that
song when you just scream
because you know you have the
best voice, right? Put that same
person in a scenario in a city,
say Las Vegas. Driving down the
street and their favorite song
comes on and they crank it up
and they start singing, they
look over and somebody’s looking
at them. They’re most likely
going to turn the volume down
and maybe not scream at the top
of their lungs because it’s
their favorite song in the
world. That is a for of
censorship, because when you
know somebody’s watching you you
change your actions even if you
don’t know you actually changed
your actions. Um and that
applies to government. So if I’m
having a conversation with you,
then we can talk about whatever
you want. You bring a microphone
in it, I’m a politician, I might
censor myself a little bit. You
know, I know that my phone is uh
recording everything I’m saying
in a national database. You will
most likely keep that in the
back of your mind. You may not
censor a lot of you’re talking
about what pizza you’re gonna
get. Who cares. If you’re
talking about something else
that’s no one’s business. Some
idea, whatever. That will likely
force you to change your
actions. And if you’re changing
your actions due to the fear and
threat of government, you are no
longer in as free of a country
as you thought you were and that
means you’re reacting out of
fear even if it’s a fear that
has not led to any logical
conclusions yet. Um it’s
something to keep in mind. One
other thing I want to touch on
was Montana literally 100 years
ago had some of the worst
Sedition Acts in the country
where if you spoke German you
were uh beaten, ju- uh, you were
arrested, beaten and imprisoned.
If you said you didn’t support
the war you were arrested,
beaten, imprisoned. If you said
some of the companies have
horrible um uh conditions for
work and labor you were
arrested, beaten and imprisoned.
And so really bad laws where you
were not allowed to have
anything, say anything, if you
didn’t buy bonds then you were
also considered like maybe
treasonous. Uh really bad. So in
100 years, we wanted to uh- we
were basically able to go from
the worst, one of the worst
states in the nation. Which
these laws were pass- passed
federally for a period of time
too. To literally one of the
best states in the nation
regarding having um solid
privacy rights. The last thing I
wanted to touch on is you may
have nothing to hide, but one
day you might. We only know what
we know and what we live
through, but all scenarios
change, all governments chang
and history has proved that
everything that has ever existed
And almost 500 years ago, 400
years ago in forms of
governments, they always change.
K, so we’re going to touch on
some quick historical examples
of why this is relevant today at
least in the last 50 years.
First one, J. Edgar Hoover, he
had documents, information on
congressman, uh senators and he
would leverage them and say hey
we know you had sex with this
person over here, you really
don’t want your wife to know or
your voters to know, so please
do what we want. That happened
in our government which means
that our legislative branch, the
voice of the people was actually
not truly representing the
people, it was representing fear
at one point. Now it’s not like
J. Edgar Hoover was asking for a
lot all these times, but the
whole concept was our our
government was uh hijacked for a
period of time out of fear. Even
presidents feared the guy and he
tried to blackmail Martin Luther
King uh Junior to stop. Uh with
sex tapes actually that uh did
not stop him. But one person
with data can do crazy scary
things in our country. Uh
Watergate is just proof how
political parties will do
whatever they can to collect,
obtain data on their ad-
adversaries or enemies or their
um their opposition to beat
them. This speech after I give
it, if it’s uploaded or
whatever, it will be sought
through, it will be gone
through, they’ll be looking for
me to say one or two lines that
I said something wrong or dumb.
Which I say that all the time so
they have plenty of material.
Um. Last one’s East Germany with
uh in you know East Germany, you
know East Germany was the part
that was ho- um held by
Communist Russia and with the
Stasi and they were only able to
tap 40 phones at a time. They
were able to silence and keep an
entire country or at least that
region of the country in fear of
their government where people
would actually tell on their
families and friends uh very
scary. Um. Very scary but real
example. So we kind of talked
about how to use these tools on
how to take over the world, but
they are they’re they’re real
because you have a huge amount
of data on everybody in this
room and everybody in the
especially people who are
running for office. You have
examples of how data was used to
blackmail, leverage uh expose,
discredit individuals and as you
know in politics today I know
it’s fa- everybody’s favorite
topic, but you get one person
who can bend the the oversight
or access that information, they
could stop anybody they want to,
um and that is a real thing.
That’s not like some conspiracy
theory. If you had a, if you’re
in the powerful position, you
could stop anybody politically.
So there are some limits and
standards worth imposing. I
would love the data be deleted
if it’s not, how about we do
what this country is based on,
which was checks and balances.
Um required records of searches
of the mass data collected, who
searched it, why were they
searching? At some point,
release this collected
information and insure that that
way knowing that what you
searched and who you searched
and why you searched is released
one day, we’ll know that one day
you’ll be held accountable so
you might think twice about what
you do today. Um, have a better
court system that is overseeing
this. Either have it have a more
public process or again uh a
more transparent one. Have
burdens of proof for the data
that is requested for when
people’s information is being
softened through these mass
databases um that there’s fourth
amendment standards or
notification standards. If
you’re ever, if your
information’s ever sought
through to see if you were
involved in any criminal
activities with your cell phone
number and all the messages or
your e-mail or whatever they
use, have notification standards
to ensure that one day you’re
gonna know. So unless they
really know your’e guilty of
something they’re gonna think
twice. These are pretty solid
and easy and uh basic limits and
standards worth considering.
Considering. So, story time. Uh
I ran for office at 25 I knocked
a lot of doors, I knocked doors
for months. I called for, called
people for months. I had to
raise money, it was a great
time. Um, it’s something that I
wish everyone else would
acknowledge and appreciate
because you think of
politicians, you these guys, who
need like money and like doing
all these evil deeds, but it is
a lot of it is it is not
glamorous, put it this way. It
is a lot of alone and you’re
trying to just talk to people
and knock on doors and get
elected so you can actually do
something good. Especially the
newer politicians, like not
newer as in the guys who used to
run, but someone who’s new and
running for the first time,
there’s a lot of idealism behind
that and uh a lot of effort and
they’re challenging an entire
system uh that they’ve never
really experienced most likely
before. So every state is
different, my state is a smaller
state, other states are larger,
some have donation limits, um
represent more people, some
represent less people, some
rural, some are uh urban, more
urban states. Uh anyone can run,
but keeping that in mind uh if
people do run, it is smart to
have a strategy not a plan. I
know a lot of people who are
like, I’m going to run, I’m
going to go talk to people,
people are going to care about
what I say and then they’re
gonna like me and I’m gonna get
elected. And really it’s no, you
got to obtain fundraising and
you have to use that to market
yourself because people care
about the presidential race,
maybe the governor race, but our
bottom, lesser races, they kind
of go by the wayside. So you
have to have a strategy.
Everybody has a plan to get
elected and change the world,
you got to have a strategy. Uh
so I’m going to talk about a
little of my experiences. I’ve
befriended befriended colleagues
on both sides of the aisle when
I first was elected. I just
didn’t like politics but I liked
people um so I was I saw no
reason not to befriend somebody
super far left, I’m pretty
conservative liberty. Uh there’s
people in the middle, on both
sides and it was very valuable
and it was not a strategy just
luck that I tried to do a
privacy bill of rights 2013, it
failed, said your data is yours,
you need consent to collect.
There’s got to be security. Um
it was well intended, but not
well written, so where it landed
is probably where it should
have, but the lobbyist wanted to
make an example of me, because I
told them I don’t like them and
other words. And um I created a
reputation that I’m not easy to
work with and that’s not true.
I’m very easy to work with if
you don’t lie to me and you
negotiate so I make sure
whatever bill I’m working on
gets 90 percent of what I want
[laughter]. Ok, so um but then I
talked with a democrat senator
whose like, Daniel, your bill
failed, but we really liked what
you attempted to do or I like
what you attempted to do, so why
don’t you try to do GPS warrant
requirement bill? And I said, ok
and so democrats knew I didn’t
care about like working my way
up. Republicans knew that um I
have pretty conservative values
and I really like our freedoms a
lot. Enough passionately to
basically ruin my political
career in three weeks of being
elected. So [laughter] um I
think that basically not being I
mean it us- eh uses motto for
life, but don’t be a d**k. LIke
that applies to life, but also
applies really well to politics
because I gave a really good
simple bill that we ended up
passing in Montana being the
first one to pass it. Um 2015,
went back and I was like and I
had a whole slew of these
privacy bills that needed to
have good uh precedents set
nationally. And the one that
ended up passing was the freedom
of the press for privacy saying
the digital communications of
the press cannot ever be
obtained. There are no
exceptions. They can never be
obtained. Freedom of the press
is the watchdog of the
government, although it’s very
bartisan and biased and probably
not doing as well a job as they
could be from when this was
historically written, without it
we look like North Korea, where
you don’t know anything and the
only government, or the only
media you hear is state
sponsored and that’s never good.
It’s never good. So that bill
ended up passing. My warrants
for devices and digital
communications bill failed in
2015, later passed in 2017. But
that ended up failing because of
politics and the there was a lot
of misinformation from
prosecutors and law enforcement,
how if we pass these bills uh
like we’re never going to pass
rape victims and uh I don’t
know. Make up the argument,
that’s what I had to defend
against. Um, the bill li- limits
on license plates readers and
spot check legislation, that
also failed. There were some
people on the other side of the
aisle, who uh, tried to leverage
my vote which I did not give up.
There were some people on my
side of the aisle who just
thought I was a arrogant punk
and they wanted to put me in my
place. And I can’t always argue
with guys on my side of the
aisle, sometimes I can be a
little bit of a punk, but I
don’t think they should kill
legislation based on my
personality. They thought they
should have. So I’m going to
tell you one thing, I spoke at
DefCon 21. Edward Snowden came
out. It was real life, I passed
the first uh privacy bill of its
type in the nation 5 years ago.
Forbes put me on their 30 under
30 list and all of a sudden I
got more positive national press
than anybody else in Montana
politics. That’s not a bragging
thing. Why I’m telling you that
is it helped me cause people
wanted to take me out
politically. They wanted to
remove me from office and I was
not removed because you can’t
take the guy who’s getting all
the positive press in your
party. And so su- and it is the
conservative who were on my
side, there were just some of
the other guys who were not and
a lot of the industry was not.
So the power of DefCon 21 is
actually what allowed me to come
back up here with successes that
uh that I’m going to talk about
in a few minutes. So thank you
all. [applause] So one thing
about this legislation though
that I realize the importance of
model state legislation we
passed that GPS privacy bills,
other states started passing
that GPS privacy bill and there
was a proof that we can do it
successfully. So Montana being
that passing that bill was about
Utah then passing and Main then
passing it and as some of you
may or may not know in 2018 the
Supreme case Supreme court case
ruling stated that there is a
warrant there should be or it
deems there is a warrant
requirement for GPS uh location
to to obtain that, which means
that the entire country is now
under that that uh that ruling.
So one state it can create a
whole precedent. [applause] So
next was my third term, so I I
didn’t explain one thing. We
serve 4 months every other year,
so we had to do all of these
bills in 4 months a- um every
other year. So I actually only
had a year to do these bills. I
actually only had 2 months to
pass through our body and then
the other body. So it’s like
very time crunch period, um so
third term I had an election,
second most expensive primary my
seat became more conservative
because I was rediserted, so I
had a very expensive lo- primary
with industry, law enforcement
uh uh basically anybody from the
contractors, hospitals,
utilities, a lot of money spent
against me. Um because they knew
if I won I would first off I’m
gonna keep trying to do my
privacy bills and also I’ll be
the chair of the energy and
technology committee, Montana’s
an energy state, that wasn’t
some people’s ideal uh result,
that’s not who they wanted to be
chairing that committee. So
again with term limits I won
that election, I uh got to um
chair that committee and when
you’re chairing a committee,
people are a lot nicer to you,
because they know something of
theirs might go through that
committee and then your future.
So it’s amazing how some of
these bills have a lot less,
there is a lot less leverage for
my vote on the house floor
because people are like yeah
that’s a bad idea. Let’s just
leave Daniel alone and bother
somebody else. So nice, nice uh
term limits do have their
benefits right? Uh so 2017,
these are the bills I kind of
touched on but we passed the
warrant requirement for digital
communications and there was I
uh some of these model bills
that are now in law in Montana,
there had to be a few um meeting
a little bit in the middle. Like
notification was 90 or it was 6
wait 6 months versus 3 months of
notification standards if they
ever go through digital
communications. There were some
other things along those lines,
but I still think it’s a pretty
solid model bill that Montana
passed. Warrant requirements for
devices. You need a warrant to
go through electronic devices.
They can’t pull you over, say
are you texting? Let me go
through your phone. That’s not
going to happen in my state.
That’s like legally it can’t
happen. Um or your computers or
whatever and we define devices
as things that haven’t been in
invented yet either. That’s not
what it says in the definition,
but it’s a very broad
definition. A lot of times when
you pass laws you make the
definitions to tight to not
apply to the future, I did not
want to do that. Uh, then
license plate readers, we never
had we did not have these yet in
the state, in my state, but they
were trying to get these put
into um place and so I worked
with the well with the one of
the main guys in law enforcement
in the state and probably one of
the most reasonable guys. He’s
like Daniel why do you want to
ban these. I was like, national,
like databases of where we’ve
driven in Mont- like Montana
being uh applied like and held
forever by our federal
government, I don’t want to take
any part of that. So a- with the
exception um of a few certain
things like kidnappings, they
can be used, the data’s
collected 90 days I think at
max, whoever goes through the
data um has to be recorded of
who of what data they went
through, why they went through
it and then if any other any
other law enforcement group
wants to obtain that
information, they have to get a
warrant. So the if the sheriff’s
office wants the police
department to have to get a
warrant, the federal government
wants the state state um police
department or one of the police
departments have to get a
warrant with the defined license
plate number they’re looking
for. That way they can’t get a
warrant for all the information
ever, it’s the warrant of just
one license plate. So that
either means they have to do a
few million request daily or
they aren’t gonna get our
information and hopefully
they’re not, I don’t, I’m not a
prosecutor, so maybe there’s a
loophole I missed, but I tried
to basically say, you could use
it for very close limited
things, but not for pulling
somebody over because they have
a a license like a license
that’s expired or something.
Like, it’s not really the big
crimes we’re worried about. Um.
So that’s the the license plate
reader law that’s in place, then
vehicle spot checks, we really
reformed those so you can’t just
pull people over. I keep, that
has nothing to do with
technology, but it has to do
with the civil liberty side of
things. And then also this whole
time I was working on like like
handfuls of energy policy. And
uh um that were good, some
removed special laws from huge
corporations which I know a lot
of people in this this group
would probably like. [audience]
So passing the bills, this is a
little bit more par- this is
where it becomes more applicable
to you if you want to apply it
in the future. Um so my question
here is what do gun groups, the
ACLU like family like Christian
organizations, hackers, citizens
and I forgot to add into there
libraries have in common? Those
were the people who supported my
legislation. So unique
coalitions are key. So let me
say that again. You got, gun
groups and the ACLU and like
family organizations and hacker
citizens and libraries. That is
the island of misfit toys
politically. [laughter] You want
to talk about like a funky like
family dinnertime where like
nobody should have even been
there and had a conversation?
That’s what my committees looked
like when you had a prosecutors
who have been doing it for 15
years argue, could really
influence, you got the
department of Justice, you have
members of law enforcement, um
who else did we have? Those were
the main ones that showed up in
opposition and they um they were
good. They were very good at
what they did. There was a lot
of misinformation that would
lead you to argument, well if my
kid got kidnapped and you didn’t
have this in place, then this
could really go and we couldn’t
catch these people. Well then
the whole argument would go into
like license plate readers that
aren’t even in place yet. So
it’s like well if we don’t have
something in place that’s not in
place yet, how could that impact
you catching the person who’s
guilty. So I had to defend
against these impossible
arguments. Um or the whole like
so there’s distractions or there
is just build up arguments where
they burn the whole thing down
and all I was saying is all I’m
doing is just requesting a
fourth amendment warrant
requirement. You can email, you
can get it, this is like for the
the warrant requirement for
devices, you can email the
judge, they can sign it in
minutes. They could send it back
to you. Boom. That’s it. Not
really some crazy stuff, like
I’m saying you can’t ever access
this information, just do it the
proper way. So um, one with I’m
gonna touch I think with the
yeah unique coalitions a little
bit later. But that goes back to
be nice to people. Um there was
a lot of of republicans who had
never talked to the ACLU and
there was a lot of democrats who
wouldn’t talk to the family
groups. You’d be surprised
somewhere along the lines what
you have in common. We have 95
percent of everything in common.
I don’t think if your politics
are diametrically opposed,
you’re a member of the NSA and
love every second of it. We
still have almost everything in
common. I know it’s a crazy
statement to hear, but it is it
is very true. Um I’ll touch on
that a little bit later. Uh our
efforts, so there were a lot of
efforts to become a privacy
technology expert. I I’m not I’m
not a natural public speaker,
reading isn’t my favorite thing,
especially technical reading,
especially technical reading of
laws. Uh especially then looking
at 4 cases and amending them.
Learning how to negotiate. All
these things, uh I had to teach
myself over 4 or 5 years. So
when somebody came up to me with
a argument, I was able to stand
up and have the reasoning,
understanding and oppose it. We
don’t have staff in my state. We
don’t have personal staff. So I
had to learn it all, negotiate
it all and get on the ground and
call people out in committee and
lobby the votes, do all the
votes. It wasn’t like a- a lot
of politicians come up. Their
staff do 90 percent of the work.
Their the ones, their staff are
talking to their constituents.
No, I had a 10 minute little
break, I’m on my computer
emailing back my constituents
while in session, then sitting
back down, go in the hallway,
negotiating a bill that were
pretty big pieces of
legislation. Emailing people out
‘til 9 or 10 at night with um
new amendments, getting it to
the people to get them written
legally for our bill drops and
then going back at it in the
morning. Non stop um so
basically had to become a
privacy technology and and and
legislative expert. Um one thing
is there were groups who showed
up like I mentioned, there were
groups who did not show up. I
talked about the ACL- -ish ACLU
showed up. Other type groups
that you’d think are very
helpful weren’t even in the
room. Weren’t even in the state.
So I was trying to pass some
good precedents, they didn’t
show up. I won’t call them out,
just to be respectful, but I am,
they almost actually at one
point derailed my legislation
and it infuriated me since I’ve
been working on it for 4 years.
Um so here’s here’s what we got,
we got multiple model bills for
your states and that’s good
regarding government, but here’s
my main failure is I try to
amend a bill saying you cannot
collect browser data and that
failed 52 to 48. 48 to 52 on the
house floor. I believe your data
belongs to you. It’s like my
philosophy that’s weird in
politics, but your data is your
personal information and if it’s
obtained, just ask for consent.
Um so we’re gonna be working on
a bill like that a little bit
more uh and it’s more for ISPs
not edge providers. Consent to
click is huge and also the other
one that I’m going to be putting
more of my political capital
into is uh biometric data. I
firmly believe even more than
personal data, personal browsing
data that biometric is complete-
you, completely your property.
Working on the legislation, I’ve
got smart people working on
that. Um I think it would go
through my committee, so at
least it would have a chance, a
good chance of going through
half the legislature. See that’s
what happens when you get people
in power for too long, they
start to move bills through
their committee, um but
hopefully I think that’s a
really good precedent policy
that we could pass in Montana.
So what drives politicians. Uh
influence, power, change, anger,
political involvement. Some
people want to influence an
industry that they’re part of.
They think it’s the best way to
do it. Some people just want
power. They were treated poorly
as a child and now it’s their
way to get back at the world.
Who knows. I don’t know their
family background. But people
want power and you can see it.
They, they just, they just, you
feel it, they want that
influence, if there’s an edge,
they’re gonna find it. Some
people truly want to make change
uh some people are just angry at
the whole system and the angry
people are harder to work with
because they’re angry and they
want to be angry at you and at
everybody. And then there’s
people who have been following
politics their whole life and
then they buyin to the rhetoric
of both sides. And so they’re
just they’re through political
involvement that they’re driven
and they listen to their left
wing or right wing media all the
time and that’s uh so those are
those are the five major points
that I say drives politicians.
One thing to keep in mind if you
ever talk to politicians in your
state about these issues, ‘cause
that’s what I’d like you to do,
you’d be surprised how much
influence you have as an
individual on your politician.
Is there are hundreds of issues.
People run for energy,
education, healthcare,
transportation, taxes, family
issues, gun issues, I don’t
care, there are hundreds of
issues, hundreds of issues and a
lot of the people who are
elected are older so your
issues, my issues aren’t really
relevant to them. They’re not as
informed to them, that doesn’t
mean they’re not core issues it
means that they don’t just study
all hundreds of issues. They
kind of focus on theirs and
somebody else focuses on another
one and my legislature I focus
on technology issues and other
um than energy issues. Then
other people will focus on
healthcare and others education,
all along. All across the board.
But to expect people to care
about your issue is a it’s it’s
a fair expectation. Yes, there
is a lot of issues, yes, it’s
your job to know about them, but
to in expertise and be like, why
don’t you have fourth amendment
standards on my digital
communications? They’re going to
be like, what are you even
talking about? Because it’s not
an issue really that people
would know about and you have to
be ok with that, so then you can
sit down and explain it with
explain to them what you’re
talking about and why it’s
important. Um there are
political issues, there’s policy
issues. Political issues are in
the news, crazy rhetoric. Policy
issues can be political issues,
but sometimes they’re just like,
how can we make the budget fund
this group and what’s going on
over here and this tax is not
bringing in a lot of money and
this one’s bringing a lot more
and we have extra surplus here
and then pretty soon it gets
really wonky and nobody really
wants to talk about it ‘cause
it’s really boring. So um,
political issues can be trendy,
but they’re not the same as
policy issues and political
issues usually are the extremes
on both sides. So if you jump on
board with that, you’re going to
be missing the policy side. Um
it’s ok to not follow the trend,
it’s even better to do
legislation and that’s not
trendy. No one’s really talking
about the- some of the
legislation we’d talked about
here. Um and that’s ok because
it’s not partisan, it’s ok
because no one’s really talking
about it, so it’s not like, if a
republican stands up for it, a
democratic is going to be
against it. In other words, it’s
not political, it’s not full
partisan politics, there’s a
chance that people can be like,
this is an easy bill we can all
support and push it through. So
the fact it’s not political is
on your side. If you use it that
way. Um one last thing to
remember with politicians, say I
have five bills, I have my two
priorities bills, I know they’re
popular, I know they’re
important, I know I can get them
passed, but I got 3 or 4 other
bills. Maybe 2 are for
constituents, 1 is kind of
important, it’s a technology
bill that is important to some
constituents who bought it to
me, but it’s not my major
priority. I’m just using that as
an example, um my political
capital is going to be focused
on my most important bills to
me. Which mean you could be
leverage, you could have your be
trading votes, um you could be
just asking the committee to
pass these ones, because the
more you ask, the more they kind
of get annoyed with you. It
matters per state how they do
their politics. Uh cutting
deals, it’s ll the, there’s all
the stuff behind the scenes
you’ll never see. But there is
so much political capital, so
when someone’s like, oh this guy
sold out, well maybe he did 4
great things or she did 4 great
things and then like the other 2
things they didn’t end up
passing was, it just was not
politically feasible and it’s
really hard to put it into
words, but it’s something to
keep in mind. That there is a
limit on how much and what you
can push through a legislature.
Having said that, I just push my
political capital to the max, I
try to do everything because
we’re only there for a few
months. We’re only alive for 100
years or less, so might as well
just go all in. It results in
primary elections, so maybe be
smarter than me if you ever do
this. Partisanship, so I kind of
talked about this a little but,
but politicians divide and
conquer the electorate. If you
are married to a political
party, uh I completely, I mean I
ran for office so it’s maybe a
little bit different, but if
you’re married to one, uh really
question it, question what drove
you, question the rhetoric. I
see so many times people jump on
board with one political party
because of one issue, they don’t
know much about the other issues
so they just follow and jump on
board with it completely. Like I
know social issues really drives
people either side of the aisle.
Um we don’t have to go into
detail on the issue, but if
you’re pro-life or pro-choice,
you tend to say, these are
really important to me and then
you slip these other issues and
say these are my guys on my side
and you know what, we gotta, I
agree with their issues as well,
so you have one or two main
issues and people jump on board
the political party and pretty
soon they’re married to the
everything the political party
has. And what happens is you
lose your independence as an
individual and a voter when it
comes to that and you’re
actually playing into a game
where you’re divided and
conquered. Do not lose that
independence, that is a that’s
the independent vote is the most
valuable vote. So if I maintain
that, you can have a little bit
more influence is what I would
suggest. Let me give a great
example of politics. Sorry I’m
just, I’m trying to cover a lot
of information haha. Um,
there’s, let me give the best
example. Blue lives matter and
black lives matter. Ok. I’m
going to talk about the politics
what one is right or wrong,
that’s not what I’m here to do,
I do think it’s a very fun
example that blue lives matter
are the people who support law
enforcement, but it’s usually
the right side of the aisle who
hates more government and more
laws in their life, yet they
strongly support the guys
enforcing the laws. Well black
lives matter is the group that
tends to be more laws, I’m doing
stereotypes, so just work with
me, they do um, they want their
views to be more democrat lean,
they want more laws in place,
but then they don’t like the
guys who are enforcing the laws
as much so do you see the irony
in politics? And no one even
questions it. You got one group
who’s on one side, but they’re
really fighting their own ideas.
And you have the other group
who’s on this side and they’re
really fighting some of their
own ideas over here. It’s a
crazy concept, so in Montana, we
passed most those laws, would
fit under the um the blue li- or
the black lives matter matra of
politics of we want more rights
for people to make sure if
they’re arrested they’re
following the right procedures,
but instead of jumping on that
like political partisan division
path, these were sold as
constitutional bills as well
because they are. They are first
amendment, fourth amendment,
mostly fourth amendment pieces
of legislation. That fit the
same argument in California of
what the black lives matter
group was doing. The difference
is my approach wasn’t saying
this is a co- constitutional
conservative issue, I’m just
saying we’re following the
constitution. If we left all the
uh division out of it, so
although some of the people on
left would say you know this
really fits what’s going
politically, people on the right
were like, these are really good
constitutional bills that are
imp- putting into law. If I’m
saying anything it’s don’t jump
on a bandwagon too early because
there are reasons why it’s
leading you down that path and
it is not always for um it’s
there’s usually some reason
behind it. And just don’t don’t
be blinded by it. Ok. Uh
partisan politics invokes
partisan behavior. Here’s a
whole other thing. Tribalism.
You are say I’m the republican,
as a democrat they say, he’s a
republican. First off they’re
opposing my election so that’s
like we don’t like those guys.
Second off, um, they were they
like under they’re for the exact
opposite of of beliefs that I
want. So now it’s like anything
that I say I don’t like. Third
off, they’re just these greedy
people and we don’t like them.
So they found reasons to dislike
somebody before they even met
them. So but their party helped
them raise money, helped them
knock on doors, helped them win
and now they’re all working
together on common issues. When
you have this tribalism, where
you hate the other person and
you really like your people.
When what you lost was your
ability to question the people
internally what they’re going
for and figure out if you have
any common ground across the
aisle. Our politics right now is
huge differences where you can’t
even trust and there’s very
limited dialogue. Uh my
legislation all passed because I
had people on both sides the
aisle jump on board with me um
and say this is good legislation
because I did not adhere to
tribalism and follow those
basics rule of this is my team
and I hate that team. If you had
that mindset politically this
is, this type of legislation
will never move forward. This
legislation can move forward in
the U.S. Senate and Congress at
the Patrick Leahy, Rand Pauls
and the Mike Lees and the uh um
Biden out of Oregon. If those
guys really spearheaded it and
held back their political
capital together, thing is a lot
of those guys literally hate
each other and so it’s hard when
you have a coalition of people
who can agree with the idea but
they sometimes can’t get past
personalities and tribalism. And
like I said keep this issue
non-partisan. If, do not make it
a one group or another group. If
it’s especially if it’s more of
a liberal legislature, then you
know that it follows more with
uh like I said black lives
matter concept. If it was more
conservative one, these are
complete conservative issues.
You’re not lying to either
group. You’re not, you’re not
like tell him half a story
you’re just ta- talking to
somebody how they want to be
spoken to and the way that they
can relate to what you’re doing.
Um, the last thing, one of the
last things is forced
politicians to listen. So people
think of federal politics as
their everything. But state
politics is everything. We make
a lot of rules and we are very
accessible, so you can literally
sit down with almost any state
representative or senator. Some
of them are not the nicest
people, but a lot of them you
can reach out to, ask their
offices, say I want to meet
them, I want to talk to them.
There are 15 minutes, you can
talk about these issues that are
important to them. You say these
guys represent me, but most
people don’t ever reach out to
them, they don’t even know who
their representatives and
senators are at the state level.
So make them represent you.
You’re the constituent, it is
literally your job to figure it
out, ask them to hear you. Um,
make this especially more
importantly, make a politician
in a tight election earn your
vote. If you say, hey I know
you’re running, I know this is
an expensive race, this is
important to me, they are so
likely to placate and give you
their support on an issue that’s
not important to them. You can
literally get them on your side,
get their support and uh if the
bill comes up, hold them
accountable. You can do that. So
a tight election is very
powerful for you. Um, again, be
persistent but do not be
offensive. Do not insult these
people, they don’t listen to
you. That doesn’t get you
anything, uh it actually makes
you look obnoxious and makes
your issues look obnoxious and
makes their support of your
issue for opposing you a lot
easier for them. So be
persistent, call, call, call,
just don’t be rude. Um, if they
don’t care, you can always
challenge them for office, you
can make it the main issue of
why you’re running. Uh and if
they don’t do what you want,
people liked you on Facebook.
It’s their solution, it’s not a
solution, and it makes you feel
good, but it’s not the best way
to do it. I would go and use
opinion editorials in papers.
Write something. Say this guy,
they wan-, he wants a government
going through your e-mails. You
know who wants a government
going through your e-mails and
phones. Nobody. Cause
everybody’s got something to
hide again. Unless you’re really
boring. Um what you talk about?
So then the last thing is
politicians fear controversy.
They hate to be bothered, they
hate to have something. So this
is an easy thing for them to
support or they’re never going
to lose a vote or gain a vote
really. So you want to make it
so that it’s easy for them to
vote for and not easy for them
to vote against and go hide. Um
but it’s very easy for them to
vote for and just be left alone
if you ever pushed any of these
types of legislation. Just a
last thing is expecting them to
know better is never reasonable.
Because sometimes they just
don’t know about these issues.
It’s not even in their
generation. So we can go a
little bit further. I have just
a minute or 2 left, but identify
the bill sponsor, you got to
have somebody carry the bill
into legislature, that’s really
important to do. Um, and then
organize, you need to just
contract contact the people um
contact committee members of
were the bill would go through
and you could get support of
this type of legislation. Um
work with groups oh the other
group that was very helpful was
the center for de- democracy and
technology with this
legislation. They gave me the
original model bills before they
were like in law so that I gotta
kind disrupt. So work with
groups, doesn’t matter where
your politics are. Find the
commonality, in the end testify.
I worked on legislation, 4
people who didn’t show up to
testify. That’s really annoying.
So a please, if you ever do
this, and have somebody working
on this legislation, testify.
This is the last slide of why
you matter. And this is a little
bit different than everything
else we’ve talked about.
Regarding technology, if
technology is used
inappropriately, it could really
ruin our republic and uh it
could put a lot of fear into
people so I think this law, or
this quote is proper. When law
and morality contradict each
other, the citizen has the cruel
alternative of either losing his
moral sense or losing his
respect for the law. So in other
words, if you’re going to follow
a bad law, you might use lose
your morality. But if you refuse
to follow that law, uh, you lose
respect for the law, but you
know, you might actually be some
of the most important people if
if the worse case scenario comes
into fruition. So with that,
thank you for having me and I
appreciate having this
opportunity. [applause]