>> Uh so with that, uh, Feng
Xiao. Good luck >> Hi everyone,
thanks for coming. I’m Feng
Xiao, a zero year PHD student at
the Pennsylvania State
University and there’s supposed
be- to be another speaker but he
can’t come due to some visa
problems so I just put his
picture here and my stand so we
can together to give the
presentation to you all. Thank
you. Alright, so today, we are
going to talk about the new
attack. The attack is about uh
with this attack, a weak
adversary is able to hack the
brain of the software defined
networks, the SDN controller.
Well, here is the difference
between the legacy networks and
the software defined networks.
Uh the legacy network is always
vendor dependent, it means the
network devices always work
independently with predefined
functions and we cannot change
it anymore. But in SDN, the
whole network is treated as two
planes, the control plane, the
upper layer, and the data plane.
So, uh all network functions are
now being placed into the brain
of the network, the controller
and the host and switch this
forwarding device are now placed
into the data plane. Alright, so
this is the difference between
the two networks. So, and this
new architecture now is widely
deployed in production
environments with growing
communities. On one hand, the
open source organizations like
Linux foundations are sur- are
supporting a large number of SDN
projects like the OpenDaylight,
Floodlight, Honors, and
companies like Huawei, Cisco,
also released their commercial
products uh uh and their
applications. And on the other
hand, the growing communica-,
the growing community
accelerates the replacement of
the network infrastructure. For
example, the world leading web
scale providers such as Google,
Microsoft deploying SDN in their
data centers. So, the this is
how SDN are used today. So when
some people are using it, where
people consider to hack it? The-
the attack and when the attacker
can successfully break into uh
software defined network just
like we connect to the wifi here
if it is a software defined
network architecture So uh, he
will probably target at the
controller ‘cause it is the
brain of the network. In this
talk, we concluded three
categories of common attack
objectives for attacks on the
control planes, the denial of
service, data leakage, and
network manipulations. And in
this tables, some objectives
have been achieved by previous
researchers and some- some are
not. And we discovered that this
exist in attacks, for example
just like the topology poisoning
attacks, our focus- focus on the
service logic of controller
which means uh, these attacks
for example the topology attack-
attack. He will attack the
topology discover service in the
controller to report face to- to
report force links and le- li-
let the controller make wrong
decisions. So, uh, to discover
these vulnerabilities, you
should be a hacker and an SDN
expert. You should know the
details of the SDN protocol
interactions, the relationship
among the service logic. But I
think most of us are not SDN
expert and we even not so
familiar with SDN but it is
widely used. So how? Um, so I’m
consider if whether I can find a
method to hack the software
defined network without learning
so much about SDM and my attack
should be powerful in the best
case, it- it should achieve all
the object- attack objectives in
this table, all of them no
matter if it is an existing one
or a new one. So how to hack the
SDN like a hacker? Well the
controllers are software
systems, and we both know that
the software systems are
inherently vulnerable so it is
possible that the controller
components contain our
vulnerabilities. This is cool
cause we are hackers and we know
how to find this code
vulnerabilities right? However,
the data plane and the control
plane as I mentioned they are
decoupled, which means they only
communicate with each other with
pretty fine protocol
interactions. So this
architecture make us hard to
exploit this code
vulnerabilities from the data
plane where we are always in. So
in this talk, we introduce the
custom attack which breaks the
border built by the decoupled
planes. Uh, unlike previous
attacks that focus on the
attacking the controller service
logic, custom attack can be used
to attack all kinds of code
vulnerabilities in the
controller. So, how to do it? So
let’s see, how to conquer the
difficulty built by the
decoupled two planes. The- the
SDN protocols provides some
fields to let the switch and
network device to custom
themselves. Usually the customer
field is subscribed by a
specific control, specific
controller components uh for
example, if a switch um, if a
switch may send a fault toler-
notification message to the
control plane and this message
will be first collect by a
service, we can call it a
collecting service maybe. And
the service will send the
message to the to subscriber,
maybe a network monitor
component. So this is how the
customer field works. So, I’m
sorry I’m, my leg- my leg, my
hands a little bit tired so
maybe Jianwei I’ll put you on
the table. Alright, let’s move
on. So, there’s a semantic gap
built by the customer field.
Since the customer field can be
totally controlled by the
control- by the data plane, by
the hacker so any improper
treatment of may break the
security border of the decoupled
control plane and the data
plane. Let’s revisit the
notification example. The
monitor component does know how
to pass the notif- notification
message however, the collecting
service who collect it first,
did- does not. So, the
collecting service may store the
message in the database without
any security considerations. If
a hacker inject a malicious
cycle in into the customer
fields, the database will
endanger and this is the start
of custom attack and it- this is
only the start. Alright, and
with the custom attack, we can
exploit serious vulnerabilities
in SDN controller to bring
several advanced objectives. For
example, we can issue arbitrary
SDN commands by calling the
exposed network management API
or we can read some confidential
data with a sql injection or
other things. And this is the
threat model of the custom
attack. First, uh, the hackers
don’t have to directly access
the network of the controller
with which is sometimes
separated from the data plane,
the- the network devices and he
can- he will not need to access
any applications in the
controllers. Also, the hackers
don’t need to hack into the
encypt- protocol channel between
the control planes and the data
planes. What the hacker needs is
to, only to perform legitimate
protocol interactions with the
control plane so a malicious
host or switch is enough. Just
like we can use a mobile phone
you know. Um, however, after
attacking, a vulnerable
components handling the
malicious chris- customer field,
we can only introduce limited
effect to the network.There are
several reasons. First, every
single component in the
controller runs in separate
context. For example just like
uh, independent threat so the
failure of a single component
will not affect availabilities
of others. And second, the
contr- the critical components
are usually specially protect.
As a result, it’s it is
difficult to abusing this
important one if you cannot
attack them directly, attack
them with these customer fields.
So as a result, if we want to do
something big, want - we need a
more complex attack, a
multi-stage exploitation to
control more resources in the
controller. This is the
workflow. The lower part is the
data plane where the network
host is and switch is. Normally,
they cannot directly access the
controller because the two
networks are always separated
but they will always be able to
interact with the controller
with using the SDN protocols
like the Open Flow or other
things. So uh, we need several
stage. The first stage is the
toe-hold stage, this is where we
attack the components with
customer field. In this step, we
will inject our craft payload
into the customer field and send
them to the control plane where
legitimate protocol
interactions. After the first
exploitations, we can now
control a small number of- we
can only control a small number
of asset in component. To
harvest more control plane asset
we need a harv- harvest stage.
We will need to exploit more
vulnerabilities in or- in other
components with previous
controlled asset. For example,
we can- we may launch an http
request in the first stage. So,
in the second stage, we can
leverage this asset to do more
things. We may access the rest
API to issue some commands. So
after we controlling a large
number of asset we try to chain
them together to achieve ouratt-
advanced attack goal. And as you
can see, instead of merely
attacking the components that
handling the customer fields,
with this attack model we can
now able to exploit all kinds of
vulnerabilities to hack more
components. Okay, now it’s time
for us to hack something real.
First, I will show you a video
demo. In this demo, we attack a
open source controller; it is a
popular um, maybe the most
popular one, the ONOS and we,
the attack effect is we get a
remote show from the controller.
Okay, uh and the ONOS controller
is on a remote machine the one
one one and- and our compromised
switch is this machine, the one
oh eight so- and this is the web
component of the ONOS. We can
see there is no devices in the
controller yet okay. And we can
load our framework to attack the
ONOS controllers and get a
system show from the
controllers. Now this is our
devices connected. Well, as you
can see, we successfully get the
system show. Um, yes, so this is
uh a exploit chain with smart
stage exploitation that works.
So how it actually works, let’s
next I will give you more
details about the, the RC chain.
As shown in the picture, our
target is the get diagnostic
function which read and execute
a script from the file system.
So to abuse this function, we
need to control two assets, to
harvest two assets. The first is
the script itself, to execute
arbitrary commands, we need to
inject payloads into the script.
However, controlling the script
is not enough. We also need to
access the rest API that caused
the- caused the diagnostic
function. As I have mentioned,
important components are usually
specially protected. So the rest
API is protected by by a basic
authentication. We need
authentication token for this
rest API. Let’s check out what
assets we can actually control
in our first stage. Well, we
found a XSS in the web
components and as you can see.
This vulnerability can exploited
by a customer field so now we
can control the assets that
expose to the XSS such as some
network configurations. However,
we cannot still directly attack
our target function so let’s
move on the second stage, the
harvest stage. First, let’s try
to handle the basic
authentication issues. We found
that the authentication code can
store as plain text at the
config file. So as long as we
can control and read this file,
we can get the token. This means
that we need to find a new
vulnerability that can read some
contents. After several days
hard work, we find our fourth
zero days in ONOS. It is our
XSE. It can be, and it can be
exploit by a customer field that
we control. As a result, we can
read the token to solve the host
problem. Now, we can try to
control the A- the script asset
with the fifth zero day we found
in ONOS. It is a past traversal
bug in the unzip function. This
function is to handle the zip
files uploaded from the web
component. Remember that in the
first stage, we discover XSS
vulnerability in the web
component. Now we can leverage
this attack, this XSS to upload
a crack zip file, and then
override arbitrary files with
any content we want. So finally
we control the script. This is
the complete attack graph for
the exploit chain. We- we use
five previously unknown
vulnerabilities in three
different stage to construct
this remote command execution
chain. I’m sorry. So, how about
the impact of the customer
field? We analyzed five popular
SDN controllers and they are 54
appli- applications. In total we
identi- identify 18
vulnerabilities and construct 24
exploit chains and all these
exploit chains are involved in
two or three stages. This is the
impact of this exploit chains.
Uh, we all these exploit chains
we construct can con- introduce
a serious attack effect to the
controller. And this tables
shows all the zero day we found.
We can, as we can see from the
last column, every vulnerability
can be used to introduce the
more than one attack effect. And
we found that ONOS has the
largests number of
vulnerabilities and I think this
is because ONOS is very easy to
use. We can install any
components we want with a simple
click. By contrast, hacking the
OpenDaylight is very difficult.
Uh, to install or debug a
component, we need to spend the
whole afternoon and usually we
found nothing. So we can only
found three bugs in the
OpenDaylight. So maybe, making
your project hard to use can be
a great defense. [laughter] Yes,
that’s- that’s what I found- a
important finding in our
research. Okay, that’s all.
Thanks for listening. [applause]
Okay I forgot him.