>>So twenty years ago, most
people didn’t know what a DDOSS
was. What- They thought phishing
was a boating activity and
hacker was a bad word. In a loft
in Boston, a group of hackers
stumbled into this world in the
early ‘90’s. They created L0pht
Heavy Industries and in ‘98,
they were invited to testify
before the Senate committee on
governmental affairs about the
risks and the- risks with the
emerging internet. That unlikely
event marked a turning point for
the industry. Today’s cyber
attacks dominate the news and
eth- ethical hackers and
researchers are on the front
lines pushing for better
security practices and more
critical thinking. We’re going
to hear some never before
revealed details about that
historic trip hopefully. And
we’re going to, um, hear their
vie- how- see how they view
security issues that are still
problems today. Um. So. I’m
going to introduce them. So. Um.
King Pin, also known as Joe
Grand, is a computer engineer
hardware hacker former DefCo-
DefCon ba- badge designer and
proprietor of Grand Idea Studio.
He joined L0pht as a 16 year old
and worked on the- a bunch of
acronyms- POCSAG Pager. Thanks
Grant- Thanks King Pin.
>>[inaudible] A little tracking
of the president. You know.
>>Decoder Kit AMPS based
cellular phone hacking and palm
OS application development.
>>You guys remember that one,
right? [laughter and applause]
>>What- what was the name of
that, Joey? >>Harry Pom >>Was
that Harry Pom or Booty Call? I
don’t remember which one it was.
The wart dialer probably. >>Yup.
>>So Chris Wysopal, also known
as Weld Pond is a co-founder and
chief technology, uh, officer at
Veracode- was at CTO at
Veracode. At L0pht, he was a
thorn in Microsoft’s side
researching security in Windows
and writing Windows versions of
L0phtCrack and Net Cat and was
web- webmaster for L0pht dot
com. Tan- [applause] >>That was
Space Rogue right there. >>Tan,
um, published a paper in ‘99
envisioning a cyber
underwriter’s lab to test
softw-software for security
weaknesses. And he led incident
response after a logic bomb was
planted in a UBS, um, at- at
UBS. He did pen testing and red
teaming for 12- 12 and a half
years at JP Morgan Chase and now
works in security at a large
health insurance company.
[applause] Peiter Zatko, aka
Mudge, uh-uh, worked in DARPA as
a senior government official for
DOD running cyber- [laughter and
applause] He also worked as VP
of engineer- engineering at
Motorola and he was a deputy
director at Google. He’s head of
security for Stripe and chairman
of the board at the Cyber
Independent Testing Lab.
[applause] Uh. Cris Thomas, aka
Space Rogue, is a founding
member of L0pht, was a longtime
editor of the hacker news
network, and is a public
advocate for security topics
through speaking, writing, and
general gadflyness. He worked at
AtStake and then went on to work
in research Trustwave Spiderlabs
and Tenable. He currently leads
global strategy for IBM’s
X-Force Red Team. [applause] And
then Dildog, Christien Rioux,
better known here as Dildog was
the cofounder and chief
scientist at Veracode. He’s the
founder of Hailstone, a security
incubator inside CA Broadcom. He
was a researcher at L0pht and
Outstake and a member of the
Cult of the def- Dead Cow. And
anyone remember Cult of the Dead
Cow? [applause and cheering] He
wrote original code for Back
Orifice 2000. [applause and
laughing] Co-authored L0phtCrack
and AntiSniff and wrote some of
the- some of the first buffer
overflows for Windows.
[applause] So thinking back to
that testimony that was May of
1998, what, um, what did you say
or convey to them that day that
you think worked? >>Um. So I’ll
start. So I-I-I think the thing
that worked and it was something
that, you know, you never plan
it, right? I-I think Mudge
dropping his-his line of the 30-
30 minutes worked. But, um, we
were like a visrable-visual
representation of what the
adversary viewpoint was. Like we
were the first ones, to actually
talk like- these guys, you know,
these guys who were building
security systems, building the
software, they didn’t know what
we were doing. We’re hackers. We
could break this stuff. Like we
made it really real to them, um,
that-that there are people that
can do that stuff. Um. And we
were talking, you know, person
to person. I think the other
thing that we did that was
important was we conveyed the
poor state of software security
and vendors just couldn’t say,
you know, all software has bugs,
we have security bugs. Because
if we could find them, we said
they should be able to find
them. So I think those were some
of the- some of the basic
foundational things that, you
know, go-got through. >>I think
going-going along with-with what
Weld had said, sort of raising
awareness of hackers in general.
Um. I was just at the- the Mob
Museum in Las Vegas recently and
learned about something that was
pretty cool. The Kefauver
Committee back in like the ‘50’s
where they were basically
exposing organized crime to the
masses- it was the first time
people learned about organized
crime- this is like a little bit
of an exaggeration- like a
little bit of an exaggeration,
but the testimony was sort of
like that because people that
sort of heard about hackers and
up to that point they’d thought
they were always bad, criminals,
whatever. You’d see something in
the newspaper once in a while,
but this was the first time
where we were on stage and
saying “We can do good.” Like
hackers can actually do the good
side. Besides the adversarial,
we can educate people and do
stuff that we, you know, think
is helping. And I think that was
really important. >>It was, um,
sensitivities that was. I’ve got
a mic. [laughs] >>You’re the
only one with it on you. >>Um.
It was one of the first examples
of cultivating sensitivities
across the chasm. Um. Hackers
were criminals. That’s the only
way we were referred to in the
media. Uh. It’s actually kind of
how that whole thing came about
in a strange way. Um. And on the
government, uh, side, you know,
we knew that there was some
overlap where we all wanted the
same thing but we didn’t want to
become government and we-
government didn’t- sure the heck
didn’t want to become us. Uh.
Sort of set up. So why can’t you
just ignore the other parts and
like figure out how to make
progress in the areas where you
both have interest. One of the
things that actually worked
really well out of it, um, which
took about 2 years afterwards
was that Senate testimony was
leveraged to introduce, uh,
verbiage into PDD63, President
Decisional Directive 63 under
Clinton which stood up the
scholarship for service program.
Uh. So if anybody went to one of
the 73 colleges, um, and got a
tuition and then later had to go
work for the FAA, FFC, FTC or
anything else but had your
tuition paid for, that was
largely driven by that senate
testimony as an exemplar of this
is why we need smart young
people. Not just the old like,
you know, old guard and the
bureaucrats, and the policy
wanks which are very valuable
but maybe didn’t know that new
thing coming in. So it was- it
was an awareness sort of set up.
Historically, the government was
being briefed that, you know,
um, you know, like it was the
cold war. That if cyber was
coming, you’d be able to see it
the same way you’d be able to
see missile silos built up. But
it would take 10 years that
you’d see large movements of,
you know, equipment and funds
and everything else and you can
track it. And this was different
because it was like, you know,
here are some kids in Boston who
did nation state stuff out of
dumpsters as far as they were
concerned. And they did it in a
matter of months. So what does
that do for your threat
modeling. And I think that was
probably the biggest wake up
call for the government. >>How
do you think change- things have
changed since then? >>Well, uh,
is this thing on? Ok. Um. Like I
think that definitely, uh, that,
uh, exploits have definitely
gotten significantly harder to
write over the last 20 years.
Um. I remember writing a lot of
the first early Windows exploits
and finding bugs was something
that I literally stumbled
across- it was not something
that I had to search for. Um.
You know. Exploit trading, uh,
for cash definitely existed but
this sort of nation state
support for, uh, exploit market
places and things didn’t exist
back then. Um. So as
vulnerabilities have gotten
harder to exploit, the relative
cost, uh, and price associated
with an exploit is skyrocketed-
sky- has completely skyrocketed.
So. Um. Exploits also didn’t
usually, uh, require nearly the
amount of training that we have
to do today to actually, you
know, fully exploit a system.
Uh. Laying, you know, all these
layered defenses, um, have
really raised the bar on
attackers. Um. It had an effect.
Uh. And the most well-f
well-funded attackers are also
finding that the lowest hanging
fruit is-is uninformed and
unlucky users. Um. You know, you
happen to click on the dancing
bears. Um. So. That- but that’s
it. Instead of, like, phishing
people’s email, just, email or
making a crappy phone call,
you’ve got online forums and SMS
texts, and, uh, whatever it
takes to get to people. Tinder.
I don’t know. Um. [laughter]
There- there are a lot more
opportunities to phish people
these days because of our
increased connectedness. So
while that it may be harder to
exploit things, it has become
easier to exploit people over
time. Um. That’s it on the plus
side. More- far more people are
aware of, uh, the need for
security these days. Uh. Even a
grandma on Facebook knows about
hacking, um, and might even know
what phishing looks like. Um.
Two-factor authentication is
available in many places and-
and when it wasn’t and- and, but
that’s a- still surprisingly not
in a lot of banks. You know, out
of all the places they should
have it, more, uh, banks don’t
have it in enough places.
>>[muffled] even in your games
though. >>Yeah, yeah. Right.
Video games have it. Not your
bank. I don’t know. Um. And,
yes, SMS two factor sucks.
Please everyone stop using it.
Um. Um. So yeah, I mean, I
definitely- the- the profile,
um, for the attacker has changed
in terms of the amount of work.
Um. You know, it took me weeks
to write a really good
weaponized exploit back in 1998
and now it would take nine
months to write something that
was, you know, from initial, uh,
you know, injection point
to-to-to full control. I mean,
it’s >>Against a hard target.
Yeah. >>Yeah. Against a hard
target. Yeah. >>One-one of the
things that’s changed, and
actually since we have two folks
from Veracode here [cough] and
this goes back to Slent, uh-
>>Yeah. >> which was like the
original, you know, Lexecal
Integrity source code checker
that >>Yup. >>was, you know,
kind of maybe helped you guys a
little bit with the idea there
>>Yup. >>was, um, Apple often
wanted to do this sort of like
consumer reports thing and say,
like, let’s look at software,
whether it’s binary whether it’s
source code and say like, you
know, tell people what’s good
and what’s bad. And the problem
was there were no examples of
good. Everything, you know, was
just >>Yup. Yup. >>crap. And you
can’t go out there and give
people actionable advice by
saying like, “well if you’re
going to choose web browsers
well you’ve got, um, you know
Serns browser and that’s it, um,
and it sucks so there you go.
You’re welcome.” Uh. If you want
a word processor, you know,
you’ve got this one option and
it’s crap so you can’t do it.
Now we actually have examples. I
think Window 10- Windows 10 was
a huge step function for
Microsoft. >>Yeah. >>as far as
hardening. You’ve got Chrome.
You’ve got a couple of good
examples that show that you can
do solid build quality really
hard targets. You know, at the
same time for every one of those
just don’t do it, uh, that are
out there at mass. But now we
have examples of good and bad.
>>And- and- and plenty, you
know. >>Beforehand we didn’t
have examples of good. >>You
know. Plenty more examples in
general. Uh. Now it’s all
indexed. Um. It used to be that,
you know, if I wanted to exploit
every single, um, network driver
on the planet, I would go find a
bug in MSDN’s example code.
>>Mhm. >>because everyone would
cut and paste that. Now if I
wanted to do something like that
[inaudible] >>I-I go to stack
overflow and find bugs in stack
overflow samples because people
are just going to cut and paste
that. So, yeah. >>One option,
yeah. >>Yup. If you want to find
bugs in ICS stuff or SCADA DCS
stuff, stack overflow. >>Yeah.
>>Seriously, you’ll find- or
look for the resumes and people
will post examples of what
they’ve done in code in those,
uh, embedded control systems.
Yeah, and, uh, then you just
look for where they worked.
[laughter] >>So- so >>And by the
way, Github is the new Payspend.
Anyway. >>I-I-I think another
dimension of what’s changed
is-is definitely the adversary
space. Um. Senator Thompson
asked us when we were there, he
said, “Could a nation state hire
a group of hackers such as
yourselves and hack the United
States?” I don’t think he would
ask that question in 2018 ‘cause
it’s in the news every day. But
it was actually, like, a
theoretical thing back in 1998.
Will governments do this? And,
yeah, of course our answer was,
yeah, you know, yes, yes then
can. >>Well, a funny thing was
the national security council
visiting the L0pht prior to the
Aenate testimony where, uh, they
all huddled out in our parking
lot and we all got freaked out
so we ran over. And, uh, and we
said, no- no, we just invited
you in. That was a huge
extension of trust sort of
stuff, you know, you have to go
back to your skiffs in
Washington and talk all you
want, you have to tell us what
you’re talking about in front of
us, like, huddling. And they
said, “Well, this blows our
threat models. What you’ve done
we’ve always thought was only
nation-state capable and so we
were wondering if any
governments have approached you
yet.” And you know, the answer
was no, but if you’d like to be
the first we’re willing to
entertain offers. [laughter]
>>And, uh, luckily they laughed.
[applause] >>I think that’s- I
think that that’s the time when
we gave them the L0pht root beer
also and all of you got
headaches and stomach problems.
>>And everybody got sick. Thanks
Joe. >It’s amazing they invited
us back. Um. But yeah, related
to the- >>Joe poisoned the, uh,
uh, uh >>poisoning the
government unintentionally
>>national security council in
mass. Yup. With homemade root
beer. >>Um. But going off- going
off what Weld said is that
nation state or not, like,
attacks are some common now
where back in the day they
weren’t. We’re, like, so
desensitized to it, and, you
know, we’re naming our bugs and
we have giant presentations
about it. And it’s like a real
circus. When an attacks happens,
you know, stock price goes up,
there’s a media frenzy, stock
price goes up, and then everyone
goes back to work, and then you
do the next one. Right? So it’s
like really this, it- very
different cycle. Um. Related to
the tools, you know, like we
were creating our own tools and
we were getting stuff out of
dumpsters and- and reverse
engineering thing that weren’t
available because the
documentation wasn’t there. Now
everything’s online. And the
tools to do stuff, especially
from the hardware perspective
from where I’m from, the
resources are- are out there.
You can get every tool you need
to hack hardware for under 100
dollars. >>I mean, we went
dumpster diving for
documentation on more than one
occasion. >>Mhm. >>But now you
can just Google for it. >>Right?
>>Yeah. So that’s, you know. I
think it’s the access to
information and the resources,
uh, which is great and possibly,
you know, for people on the
defense maybe not so great.
>>So, uh, one question before I
let the audience have a chance,
um, how did the testimony- the
invitation to come to Congress
happen? [panel laughter]
>>That’s a point of debate.
>>Yeah. It’s actually really not
a point of debate. >>No. It’s a
point of a debate. >>We can have
a debate. You might as well tell
it. >>Well, um. So. Uh. Well, I
mean. What had happened was at
the L0pht, we were trying to do
it full time. Um. So we actually
had a couple folks on really
payroll and I was going out-
>>This is pre-payroll. >>Well,
actually, yeah, it’s- that’s
right. Well, L0phtCrack was
paying a little bit of stuff.
>>A little bit. Yeah. I mean,
L0pht crack. But we got press.
>>Yeah, we were getting a lot of
press and that’s actually what
kind of started this in my mind.
Um. We were getting a bit too
much press. And I was really
worried. And this was- Remember
the MIT thing where I had to sit
up there against Annette Day who
was the FBI director- or the
>>Yup. >>cyber crime FBI part?
And this was hackers for
girlies, when they had hacked
the New York Times and so I’m
sitting on a panel, you know,
that MIT had invited me with-
all the L0pht guys were there,
Tan was there- you know this one
really well. And, um, you know,
and the FBI Boston cyber part,
uh, says like, “We- we’re
investigating all the leads.
We’ve already talked to all the
relative people.” And so I
opened my big mouth and say,
“No-” on the same panel “No you
haven’t. Because if you look at
the source code on the hacked
page, it calls out greets to the
L0pht and Mudge. And I’m sitting
here on the panel with you and
I’m telling the audience that
you never talked to me.” You
know. [laughter] >>Didn’t go
over too well with the Boston
FBI. [laughter] >>Um. We were
also, you know, making like a
lot of news, you know, the local
AO ABCN the cable news and stuff
like that. And I honestly
thought that we needed a
contingency plan. So I actually
started to go out to the
government. And very quietly I
started to advertise that I
would train. And you guys
remember me going out to a bunch
of these. Air Force Information
Warfare Center, you know, uh-
um, you know, Quantico, uh, NSA,
FRY4, C4, EXGroups and stuff
like that. Anybody in the
government could get me to go
out and I would educate them and
train them just on tech stuff.
And I would not take any payment
because I didn’t want to be
under- you know, I didn’t want
them to have chains or strings
to pull sort of stuff. And the
goal was- I figured that the FBI
or the DOJ was going to at some
point just for the media, try to
make an example out of us. And
like pull us up and make us some
big sort of like, we’ve got the
hackers. You all know about
them, sort of set up. I-If that
happened that, um, I wanted to
be able to, like, reach out to
the folks at West Point and
have, like, you know, Colonels
and Majors show up in uniform
and say, “No. These- these guys
aren’t the bad guys. They’ve
actually just been very up front
and help.” Through that, um, I
ended up briefing the national
security council several times
and became friends with Richard
Clark. And then we had the
meetings with them and then he
became kind of a friend of the
L0pht and he brokered it with
the Senate. Um. And he and I
kind of talked a lot about that
and I was uncomfortable with it.
And then they reached out to us,
uh, and then I had to approach
it with the other law folks. And
I remember Weld is familiar and
Tan with some of the back stuff-
I didn’t do a great job of
sharing it with all of the L0pht
folks. Uh. But it was kind of
prepared because we were not
going to go into the Senate and
get ambushed and just get- get
raked up and down the hills. It
was going to be friendly or else
we weren’t going to do it. >>We
were- we were very scared ahead
of time. >>We were terrified.
>>Walking into that room what
kind of reception we would get.
Right? I think it’s one of the
reasons why I dem- demanded
everybody wear a suit. Uh.
[laughter] >>Because we didn’t
know >>I hate you for that >>if
we were going to walk in there
and have the senators call us
all brown noses, right? >>King
did not have a suit. He wore his
father’s. [laughter and
applause] >>And I haven’t worn
one since. >>I mean, I mean,
we-we were assured that it was
going to be a friendly meeting
but we also in the back of our
minds felt that, you know, we
could get in there and they’re
just going to call us all
criminals and-and what do we do
then? So. >>And-and ‘cause if-
if you watch it, you’ll actually
see that it was Senator Thompson
that says, like, uh, “I’m
informed that you think that you
can take the Internet down in 30
minutes.” And he was talking
about my BPG work that I was
doing at my day job which was a
government contractor at the
time. Um. And there’s no way
that they would have known that
had it not been the fact that
from the day job and the night
job, I shared that with the
folks at national security
council. So I mean a lot of
these questions, you know, were
sensational but they were
relatively safe. And it was a
little weird because we were
still terrified. Well, I think
we worked out for-for
sensitivities. >>I think we did
a good job preparing the written
testimony because looking at
that, like, the spoken, for me,
I’m sort of embarrassed about.
But the wri- you guys were fine.
[laughter] >>The written
testimony was like a really good
description of what could happen
and so we prepared that in
advance. I think we had to send
that to them a little bit in
advance. So we had no-
>>it’s-it’s still a part of the
public record if you can find
it. >>Right. It’s in the public
record. So we didn’t know how
they were going to react to us,
but by doing that, it put
something into the public record
that actually was going to stick
regardless. >>And John Glen
obviously, uh, messed up a
little bit when he was like,
“Awh, and I’ve worked with some
of you.” And I’m like, “Oh,
geeze.” >>So one of the other
interesting things about it was
we only agreed to do it if we
could testify under our hacker
aliases. [laughter] And, um, we-
we- we just almost couldn’t
believe that they allowed this.
[laughter] They said- they said
the only people who, uh, ever
testified before under their
aliases were in the Witness
Protection Program. [laughter]
Which might not have been a-
>>This ma- this made expense
reimbursement really difficult.
>>Well, this-this was hilarious
and I-I might be giving away a
little bit of opsec for it um
part of it was- was, I mean, and
these guys all know this
intimately. I hate flying. I’ve
got- I’m- I’m petrified of
flying. And we wanted to go to
NSA Crypto Museum And if we took
a train, we weren’t going to get
to the Crypto Museum before it
closed so we rented a Dodge Ram
3500, you know, 15 passenger-
>>Like an 11-seater van. >>Yeah,
15 passenger van, black,
tinted-out windows and like
Brian Oblivian and everybody
else- like the hardware guys
were like let’s put in atenas.
Let’s actually, like, you know,
map the northeast corridor. The
thing looked like, you know, it
was- it was a SIGINT sort of van
going on. [laughter] This is
1998. And, um, there’s a story
about taking the wrong turn
which I won’t go into when we
went into the NSA wrong
entrance. Um. [laughter] With a
van that looked like SIGINT.
>>We really fit in because we
had all the atenas. They didn’t
know what to make of it. >>But,
um, when- when we get down
there, um, uh, they were like,
you know, uh, we’re checking
into the hotel and it was Al
Anderson, Bob Bondurant, you
know, CC, DD, EE, FF- >>We got
some big names at the hotel.
>>and the weird thing was the
hotel was like, “Yeah, we’ve
seen this before. You’re going
to the senate aren’t you?”
[laughter] >>So the- the other
thing about under the hacker
names was the reason we did that
was because we were protective
of our day jobs. Right? Like we
were going to be talking- we
didn’t know how the vendors and
the partners of the companies we
worked at were going to- we’re
going to take this. >>Well, we
did know how Microsoft used to
handle it. >>Yeah, Microsoft,
you know, because obviously they
can pull strings with your
employer, right? Um. But it
didn’t work out so well because
there was reporters there with
microphone- with cameras and our
picture was on the front of
Internet Week when we got back
into work the next week- Monday.
>>Our picture was on the front
of the Washington Post. >>Yeah.
Washington Post. Yeah [laughter]
>>I mean the handles- the
handles though it wasn’t just
for day jobs because not all of
us had day jobs, um. [laughter]
>>Some of us weren’t old enough
to work yet. >>But the- you
know, we were pi**sing a lot of
people off because we were seven
kids in a warehouse and- and
there- you know, you had some
professional jobs still, but
whatever. It was- We were- I
remember reading some mailing
list post that people f- on,
like, academic cyber security-
whatever we called it back then
list saying why don’t you guys
come out from behind your
handles if you have something to
share and whatever. And we’re
like we’re sharing the technical
information. You don’t need to
really know who we are. We’re
the L0pht in Boston. We’re King
Pin and Mudge- this is what you
need. Uh. But it was also a
protection mechanism just in
general because we- you know,
what we were doing was not
normal. >>Also even at that
point, we had built up a-a
considerable reputation
individually and as a group
under those names. And if we
suddenly started using our real
names, nobody would know who the
hell we were. [laughter] >>Well,
one of the reasons you don’t
give up the names, if you- if
you remember when I- when I went
down to the- to the Clinton
round table in the- in the White
House, uh, for that and this is
where my name actually- ‘cause I
had done I thought a pretty
decent job of never having a
picture of me, never having my
name on the internet or
whatever. And so I get invited
to go down, uh, ‘cause Dick
Clark was like, “Hey, you know
you guys have done good. Mudge,
why don’t you come down and meet
with the president for this,
like, sort of photo op?” You
know. This was right after
StekleDrot, the big Ddot sort of
stuff And to go into the White
House, you know, you have to
always give them your social
security number and other stuff
like that. You know, ‘cause they
want to check- it’s embarrassing
if you owe child support or if
you have, like, warrants out for
you and you’re, you know, being
he- you know, being invited in
to see, like, the president.
They gave that list directly
over to the media. And so they
had my name. You know, they
don’t give the social part, but
they give the names. And I think
it was- yeah. >>Well and I get a
call from a reporter. I’m back
in Boston and they’re like,
“Hey, uh- uh, Space Rogue. You
know, I just got this sheet from
the press report at the White
House and it has everybody’s
name on it.” >>Is- is Mudge
really Peiter Zatko? >>And I’m
like- I-I was like, “Ok. Thank
you very much.” I hung up and I
immediately called you. >>So I
called the national security
council going, “You just blew my
cover.” Um. And goes the White
House communications agency, and
they’re like, “Oh, we’ll fix
it.” So they- so what they do-
[laughter] Well, yeah, they
fixed it. What they did is then
they- then they send out to the
same press folks the exact same
thing with my real name replaced
with Mudge, uh, on- on the exact
same thing. [laughter] Now, I
got death threats from that from
the hacker community, uh, ‘cause
folks were like, “Hey, you know,
you’re a sell-out. You know.
What are you doing? Are you- you
know, are you a fed? Are you a
hacker?” I mean, look at all the
stuff I contributed open source
or whatever. You can look at
CFT. You can see why I’m doing
it I hope. But, yeah, this is
part of the reason why you don’t
want your real name out there
sometimes. I mean, that wasn’t a
lot of fun as, like, 26 year old
getting random phone calls to my
cell phone, even cell phones
that nobody else knew ‘cause,
you know, there are some good
phone freaks out there, you
know, threatening your life.
>>So you guys caused some, um,
uh, prompted some interesting
news room discussions when I
was, um, reporting on your
activities and- and my editor
would say, “Um. Ok. So we’re
supposed to identify people with
their real names. So who is
Space Rogue? We need a real
name.” And I’d be like, “Well.
But that’s the name that I have
to report. You know, that’s what
they’re giving me.” You know. So
I-I had to do some education
that this is a new type of, you
know, world. A new, um, you
know, reporting era. And so, um,
that was really fun in the
newsroom. >>Not just the media.
The academic journals had to do
the same thing. I published
papers with Bruce Shnier and
David Wagner, Microsoft, Crypto
stuff that I worked on. Useniex
wouldn’t accept, you know, my,
you know, my uh- uh, judged and,
you know, vetted paper because
they didn’t have my real name on
it. >>I don’t know if you
remember the >>Do you remember
those federal’s papers? >>Well,
yeah. I don’t know if you
remember this Eleanor but I
think it was- you specifically
asked me, uh, what my real name
was. And I was like, “You know
what, if it’s good enough for
the US Senate, it’s good enough
for Wired.” [laughter and
applause] >>Alright. So let’s
take it to anyone have any
questions? >>Alright. So we’re
going to take some questions.
I’m going to ask pe- >>Really?
>>Come on over. Alright. Anyone
who has questions please queue
up right here. >>Oh boy. Hey
Render. >>I hope at least it
should be a friendly question I
hope. >>You never know with him.
>>Well, you wonder who was
sending you all those death
threats and everything.
[laughter] >>No. Uh. I just want
to say all of you are directly
responsible for me. [laughter]
>>Is that- is that- >>Sorry. >>I
don’t know if we should take
credit for that. [applause]
>>No. Formative years, you know,
late ‘90’s there was no- there
weren’t a lot of examples out
there of what to do with these
skills and these interests. So
you guys were really the only
thing out there. And I think you
did a damn good job. So thank
you very much. [applause] >>And
if you agree and you think that
these guys, like, you know,
helped form who you are, please
stand up. I want to see. You are
responsible for all of this.
Yeah. And it’s- some of these
people probably have- probably
weren’t even born then. But
thank you. Thank you for
everything you’ve done. >>That-
that- that actually means a lot
because when we were doing the
L0pht, I mean, especially when
we were trying to figure out how
to fund ourselves, we looked at
going into government contract.
And we looked at any sort of
funding thing where we wouldn’t,
like, have to become a
commercial entity. And it’s
honest to God why I did cyber
fast track when I went into
Darpa because I’m like, I want
what we needed at the L0pht in
order to keep doing stuff
available for other folks even
if I don’t get to do it. And
actually some of the guys
actually did do, you know, get
to take advantage of it, uh, in
there. And the biggest thing was
it was a pain in the butt for us
to figure this out. And it
shouldn’t be that pain in the
butt for other folks because
they should be able to do it
more easily so they can figure
out the next thing and take it
further. And, like, that’s the
whole sort of thing. Like how do
you get the next team and
inspire them or the other people
and not make it as difficult.
And you’ve released a lot of
really good stuff. And a lot of
other folks in here have
released a lot of really good
stuff. >>No, you have man. >>No,
it’s good stuff and that- [off
mic comment] that- that’s why I
think we were successful. Is
that other folks who think that-
or that we might have inspired
did neater stuff than we did.
>>And, well, I mean, look how
Defcon has grown too. Like, we
were standing on the shoulders
of other people that inspired by
other people. And then it just
keeps growing where it’s like
this exponential growth where
everybody can do something.
>>Yup. >>Right? It’s amazing. So
it’s just going to keep going.
And, you know, I feel like we
were just this little- >>Yeah.
ADLGM. There was LOD. There was
a whole bunch of just- we were
just [inaudible] >>Yeah. We were
just this little piece of it.
And it really is- is- it’s, I
mean, yeah, it’s an honor to
hear that. And- and other than
feeling old, thank you. But it’s
amazing. So yeah, thank you.
Thanks. >>We’re- yeah. >>What’d
you guys screw up along the way?
>>What? >>What did we screw up
along the way? >>A lot. >>A lot.
>>Yup. >>A lot of stuff we’ll
not talk about. >>Yup. >>That
answers the best. >>You’ll
notice AtStake’s not being
talked about a lot although it
actually was really important
for a lot of other- other areas.
But it was very personally
painful for all of us. And
that’s just- that’s not
comfortable. >>Yup. I- I- I
don’t want to say that was a
screw up, but it was definitely
a learning and growing
experience. >>Yeah, but I- I- I
tell people that I wouldn’t have
changed it. Like, even though it
was hard. >>Yeah, it is what it
is. >>And it is what it is. And
we were trying to do something.
We wanted to fund ourselves and
we were trying to do something
that nobody had done. There were
not sm- small security
consultant companies. >>For
those that don’t know, AtStake
was the commercial entity that
L0pht turned into after we got
DC funding or got bought or
however that went out >>Right.
Pack or sell out. >>And then
that all kind of fell apart.
>>But we want- but we wanted to
do it full time and- and we took
a risk. And nobody- it’s not
like we could follow the path of
anybody else. We didn’t know
what would happen. And yeah,
there were a lot of personal
stories- >>There weren’t a lot
of vendor appointed security
companies out there at the time.
>>Especially [inaudible] one-
>>Yeah. But it shaped- it shaped
a lot of what we did moving
forward also. >>I’ll tell you
one of the things I always
wondered, uh, if I did right or
not is- I kind of buried what
the take the internet down in 30
minutes was. And I did that
during my day job. I did it
during my night job. I didn’t
even share a real lot of it
inside the L0pht with, like, the
BGD update attacks, there’s a
whole bunch of tricks with
putting, like, the target inside
an AS set so it gets discarded.
There’s a lot of- we’re seeing
it now in the media. And it’s a
very viable one. And actually if
you go back through, um, you
know, uh, like Batarus or some
of the other route views sort of
thing, you can see some
interesting nation state stuff
going on if you know what to
look for. And it goes back
almost to 1998 which was
interesting. And I always
wondered if I shouldn’t have
actually released a proof of
concept for them. >>Yeah, no.
[laughter] >>I’m still wonder-
I’m still wondering if >>Not
then. Maybe now, but not then.
>>I know! Well- well- well now
it’s actually more like, you
know, an hour and a half rather
than 30 minutes because all of
the- all of the ind- you know,
the private peering exchanges
and the IXB’s and stuff like
that. Uh. But, yeah, I mean,
that was our big thing. >>Yeah.
>>was you can’t hide behind it.
You can’t make it opaque. Here’s
how it works so both offense and
defense can understand it. And
there was a lot of confusion
about that. And a lot of
sensationalism. And I always
wonder if it shouldn’t have been
backed up with an actual O-day
release >>So scary. >>Uh oh, uh
oh! Man down. >>Hey guys. Um, I-
>>The panel recognizes Deviant
Nolan >>How do you do? Uh. I
guess what I wanted to ask about
the changing landscape- both of
the hacker community and- and
the world at large because
people- my first question’s kind
of easy because I think it’s a
no. Could the- could the L0pht
exist today? Or we- we think of
the L0pht, we think of Hacker
Halfway House. We have like
maker spaces and hacker spaces,
but a lot of younger people
could see you like, “Oh my god.
I want to do that.” But that
isn’t really that any more. If
people want to share minds and
maybe even crash together or
maybe not- maybe that’s not-
what is feasible for people who
really want to collaborate in
this economy and in this time
and in this job market and- and
could the L0pht exist today or
what is it now? What should
other people do now? >>I mean,
look at all the hacker spaces
that exist all over the world.
And there not exactly like the
L0pht because we were much more
private and, you know, careful
with what we were releasing.
>>And focused. >>Private just as
far as people couldn’t come
over. >>We- We- We wanted to be
physically located. We wouldn’t
have virtual members. >>Right.
>>Because of the direct
interchange when we had, like,
you know, group meetings and
stuff. >>Well we couldn’t do
virtual back then because
virtual didn’t exist. [laughter]
>>But the hacker spaces that
exist are in different regions,
you know, around the world for
people to get together- like
minded people to get together
and work. It’s not exactly the
same. You know, it was just that
particular time I feel like we
were lucky that the seven of us
plus Sillian and Dildog when
they came in later, like- >>And
Stephan. >>And Stephan. We just
happened to all click. And it
was just- it just worked.
Because there was a lot of other
people in the Boston community
that we hung out with and did
stuff with. But for us, it was
just a really special, sort of
lucky thing. Um. Maybe- maybe it
can exist. I- I feel like the-
there’s more kind of
commercialism of it. Right?
Because we were doing it and we
didn’t expect to make money at
first. When we wanted to, we
tried to by selling tshirts and
services and stuff. But it was-
>>L0phtCrack [inaudible]
>>L0phtCrack. Yeah, I mean. It-
we weren’t- we weren’t planning
on doing that. But now- >>People
want my code. >>It’s- it’s very
financially driven I think a lot
of times. And you can- you can
do things on your own and have a
hobby, but if you want to
survive, you have to promote and
do things that maybe are more
sensational than prior. >>I’d-
I’d like to go and say, “Yes, it
can.” And here are the examples:
Kiosk Computer Club, right
there, you know, Tool, right
there. Fantastic examples of,
you know, that sort of hacker
mentality at a much larger
scale. You want to look at,
like, specialization as stuff
Dildog really started to go in
to. You know, Project 0, I mean,
who doesn’t want to be a part of
that. You know, sort of set up.
So it exists out in that sort of
like, uh, you know, uh,
philanthropic sort of thing,
that sort of like open thing
like CCC. It exists inside of
organizations like the Google
Project 0 sort of stuff. So,
yeah, I think it’s even better
than it used to be. >>One- one-
one observation that I’ve got on
that is, um, that many times,
um, um, the availability of the
internet conntra- internet
connectivity has allowed people
to collaborate on shorter
projects. Like, individual
projects. Um. You know, we have
re- Repose now where people
collaborate. We have slack
channels were we collaborate.
And they usually- they might be
overlapping from person- you
know, uh, certain groups of
people, but um, you know, you’ll
have people working together for
a sole- a single purpose. Um. As
opposed to simply just having a
group of friends that hang out.
So instead of being people and
sort of place orientated, a lot
of the organization these days
is project oriented and, you
know, outcome and goal oriented
type work. Um. You know. I can’t
count the number of slack
channels that I’m on now. Um.
And, you know, it just, you
know- all for different kinds of
purposes. And not necessarily
for the- the purpose of, like,
making friends and being a close
knit group, but for helping,
like, to bring something to bear
to help solve problems, to push
some agenda forward, to make
some software that should exist
a reality, or whatever. Um. But
it’s a- I’ve- I’ve just found
that it’s easier to, like, make,
uh, small bubbles of projects
and- and work on iterit on
those. >>So I’m actually going
to comp the mic. So, uh, I have
a day job and, uh, we actually
had Karen Olizary at our
conference in Washington and one
of the things Karen talked about
was that corporate environments
and corporate America need to
embrace the hacker community,
the security community ‘cause a
lot of the clients that I talk
to still view all of us as
enemies. And I’ll walk into a
client meeting and I obviously
don’t dress like this and people
are like, “I know you from
Defcon.” And I have to say, “No.
That’s not me.” Because it’s
still- there’s still a
perception, and I, like- I
brought my- buy my daughter a
tshirt and she goes to school
and people go, “Oh, aren’t
hackers bad?” And she knows the
answer. You know. Hackers are
people who get stuff to do
things that the creator didn’t
think could be done. Right? >>Do
you have a question? >>Yes.
[laughter] The question is- >>I
specifically told you before
the- before you got out here.
>>No, but I can’t moderate
myself. So- so what are your
thoughts on- on how we can
better get that sort of-
>>desensitivity. >>fix the
relationship between what we all
do here and what businesses do
‘cause we’re in conflict more
than not. >>I- I- This was
actually, you know, what drove
cyber fast track and what a lot
of folks don’t know is that I
would get pings from NSA and the
White House periodically saying,
“You seem to be a DayWater. You
can, you know- you’re- you’re
friends with the hacker
community. You may or may not
have a whole bunch of clearances
sort of stuff like that. Over
here, you know. How can you- how
can we trick them into doing
work for us? ‘Cause they seem
really clever.” And I’m like-
[laughter] Did you really just
phrase it that way? I mean, this
is how you make new adversaries.
And I think the- the thing that
worked the best is not embrace
the hackers or whatever. It’s to
recognize that it is another,
you know, group of people. And
they’re different. And you don’t
have to turn them into you and
you don’t have to turn into
them. So if the lost city of
Atlantis just pops up out of
nowhere. It has significant
capabilities, you don’t go,
like, “Oh, we got to make them
become Americans.” And you don’t
say, like, “Oh. Well we have to
just, you know, attack them.”
You don’t know what it is. You
build out a relationship and you
figure out where you have like,
you know, goals and
similarities. And you focus on
those and you let people be
themselves in the other areas.
That’s what worked. And that’s
where- I- I- I can’t tell you
how many times I just sent back
nasty emails. Heath Alexander
and I went head to head a number
of times on this. But I don’t
think you have to embrace it. I
think you have to respect it and
figure out where you have like
overlaps and where everybody can
move forward without trying to
co-opt people. And say like,
“Oh. Cut your hair and become a
government person.” Or, you
know, “the hacker way is the
only way.” >>Well, if you cut
your hair! >>Where’s my hair?
[laughter] >>But I-I think it,
you know, it’s funny that you
say that because I don’t go into
a lot of corporations but I feel
like we’ve done a really good
job as, like, a community to
share the good side. And what I
get from people when I do- when
I do go into organizations, they
say it’s nice that somebody’s
here that has a different
perspective, right? Because so
many people are in their sylos,
they’re working, they don’t go
to Defcon. We sort of think it’s
normal to come here. But it’s
not. Right? So having that
perspective and- and- [laughter
and applause] Much better. >>You
may not have noticed but that’s
not Weld’s real hair either.
>>Yeah, you’re still wearing
your wig you know. >>It’s my
real hair. >>Yeah so I think
being- you know, coming in and-
and having a fresh perspective
is ok. It’s just trying to maybe
convince people that that’s ok.
>>But we- we feel you. >>Yeah.
[laughter] >>Alright. Thanks
Render for breaking the seal on
this one, but I just wanted to
say you guys, um, you were the
original bad boys. You know, you
were the original sort of
hackers and, uh, you guys
through ups and downs through
the years, here you are all
these years later and, uh,
you’re doing good. You know.
You- you turned it around and
you’re doing good for the
community and for our industry.
And I just applaud that because
it paved the way and showed that
it’s possible no matter how you
started out that you can turn
around. You know. And you can-
you can encourage the community
to do awesome things so thank
you for that. And yes, there is
a question. So if- >>But- but
folks should realize, who this-
that means a lot to us because
that’s Johnny Long for Hacker’s
Charity. >>Yeah [applause] >>So
hearing that from you, given
that that’s how we feel about
you means a lot. Thank you.
>>Yeah, thank you. That- You
guys showed me that it was
possible so, you know, it really
encouraged me so thank you. But,
uh, my question is so let’s
assume you weren’t the good
guys, how long would it take you
to take the internet down today?
[laughter] >>Well, kinetically
or? [laughter] [inaudible]
>>Well, it’s- it’s actually- we
got that a lot right afterwards
and it was weird ‘cause we- we
rode that a lot, but honestly, I
mean, I honestly didn’t even
share a lot of the PGP stuff
inside of the L0pht. Um. And a
lot of the questions were well,
if somebody could take the
entire internet down, why
haven’t they done it to
demonstrate it? And even back at
that time, you saw people
hijacking prefixes. You saw
people redirecting it. I had a
friend at MIT that used to
periodically take the east coast
and just route it to a dorm in
MIT in order to saturate the
lines just to mess with the
other dorms, uh, over there.
[laughter] You know. The- the
L0pht web server was physically
at May East. It was on the fiddy
ring at May East. So we- we knew
from whence we spoke, we had a
friend who actually put it there
for us free of charge which was
nice. Um. The MD5 components
were all zeros for everybody for
the shared secret in order to
talk PGP for the national access
point. Um. But what people
didn’t realize is there’s no
value in actually taking down
all of the internet because then
you take down all of your
targets as well. If I want to go
in to a foreign area and do a
strike, why would I black out
the skies so I can’t fly in
there myself? So the problem is
that you can still take it all
down. It will be- it would take
a lot more because the cascading
effect and some of the
dampening. And there’s a little
bit of RPKI, some 3379 BGPish
sort of stuff. Um. Not much. But
by going to private peering
points, they’ve made it really
easy to go in with a scalpel and
take out individual areas,
reroute it, and nobody else
notices. And we are seeing the
Crypto hijacking for the mining
pools happening. We’re seeing
that, you know, places like, you
know, Iran and other areas, you
know, occasionally, you know,
leak the- you know, their route
advertisements out. It’s
probably not even a hijack. It’s
because they’re intentionally
routing the stuff through their
own monitoring infrastructure.
>>Remember that time North Korea
just disappeared from the
internet for, like, I don’t
know. How long? >>I have no
recollection of what you’re
talking about senator.
[laughter] >>There’s another-
there’s another aspect to this
question. Uh. Because after we
did the testimony, we had
several people come up to us and
say, “Hey. I heard your
testimony, take down the
internet, blah, blah, blah. Was
it because you can do X, Y, and
Z?” And we’d be like, “Well,
that’s not what we were talking
about, but that would work.”
[laughter] >>Yeah. That would
work too. >>And so there were-
at the time there were multiple
ways to do what we were talking
about and it- are there other
ways that we don’t know about to
do it now? Maybe. >>I mean, I
think you’re seeing it being
taken down in a very interesting
way by social media right now on
its own. >>Yeah. >>Thanks John.
>>Hello. Uh. I’m guessing you
guys all have a lot of
experience, uh, with the law and
being on the good side and the
bad side so my question’s kind
of around that. Uh. The supreme
court came out with the decision
a few months ago, uh, and this
is my translation of what I read
was police need a search warrant
to go track down a cell phone,
but, uh, the government for
national security reasons,
don’t. What do you think of
that? >>I-I think it only
applies to geolocation
information. That, in other
words, where the location of the
phone is and tracking of it if
I’m remembering the court case
properly. No? >>I thought there
was more to it. >>I don’t know.
>>I’m sorry. I thought there was
a lot more to it ‘cause it
rambled on [inaudible] >>Yeah, I
didn’t- I didn’t follow up on
that particular case. >>Ok.
>>And I definitely wouldn’t say
that we’re all caught up on the
law. How I- [laughter] >>I don’t
think the law’s caught up with
Joey G. >>How I- how I ended up
in the L0pht was I got arrested
as a kid because I had nowhere
to do what I wanted to do and
these guys accepted me in. So
no, the law is- I don’t think- I
don’t know how much we’ve
actually paid attention. At
least, I haven’t paid attention
to it even now because I would
rather do something I want to do
and share it and then pay the
consequences later. Than not be
able to do it and then, you
know, not be able to release the
information. So. [applause]
>>So. So literally I was a
senior official of the
department of defense, um, and I
funded, uh, about, uh, 180
different small projects from
hacker spaces and individual
folks. I did have to follow the
law, uh, a lot and in particular
a lot of US code for Title 10
and Title 50 in addition to CFAA
and electronic communications
and privacy act sort of stuff.
Um. I’m not familiar with that
particular case so. Yes, some of
us had to follow the law. And
that’s why we became midnight
basketball for hackers for King
Pin. >>So I will say though that
since you brought the legal
question, there are a lot of,
uh, issues that occur at the
federal level and the state
level that can require, um, a
different viewpoint for input.
Ok? Uh. A lot of the people who
are writing these laws may not
have the vision to see all the
angles that a specific law or
rule may impact. And that’s
where we can come in as hackers.
Right? We can help, uh, inform
the lawmakers of our point of
view and how we think that
certain proposed laws may impact
us or other parts of the
internet. And so, you know, one
call to action I’ll give now is
to get involved in that process.
Right? Call your senator. Write
your representative.
>>Seriously. >>It- it makes a
difference. And if you hear
about a law or proposal that’s
getting put forth, let them know
that you may be an expert in
that topic and are willing to
talk to their- their staff and
their aides. >>Or at the very
least, give them your opinion.
>>Give them your opinion. Write
the letter. That stuff makes a
big difference. It makes a big
difference. >>They assume for
each call, that there are 100
people that didn’t call. >>Now-
now might be a great time to
tell every, you know,
congressperson that you can to
go ahead and read Matt Blazer’s
paper on the safety of, uh,
secure voting machines. >>Yeah.
[applause] >>I mean, and that’s
a key topic right there. I mean,
I’ve done several briefings in
DC for different staffers of
different representatives and
senators and they eat this stuff
up. They really do because
they’re hungry and thirsty for
that knowledge. >>For data- for
quantified data. >>They don’t
have any other place to get an
unbiased third party opinion
that’s not paid for by a
lobbyist. So if you can get
those- maybe if you can write
those letters and let them know
your opinions of- of whatever
bills are being passed, it makes
a huge difference. >>And even
more importantly, give them your
opinion, but if you have data
points, nobody’s bringing data
to this game. >>Yup. >>Our
industry is the only industry
that doesn’t have clinical
trials and ground truth and
anything else. You bring numbers
or other things, you stand out.
Give them your opinion but for
god's sakes, if you have data or
if you start to measure stuff.
That’s how I rebooted DARPA.
That was the entire ALIAC
framework. That was the 125
lines of code malware that took
half a billion dollars away from
Keith Alexander and redirected
it. You know. ‘Cause it was,
like, we brought data. What do
you have? Well, you’ve got an
opinion. That’s great. Here’s
data. [applause] >>Uh, that
actually leads right into my
question. Uh. If you guys were
invited back to the Senate now
20 years later, what would be
your main message to the
senators? [inaudible] >>I don’t
know. So many to choose from.
>>Well, we sort of did that.
>>We did- we did that a couple
of weeks ago- months ago.
[laughter] >>Yeah. A couple
months ago. But it wasn’t
directly with the senators. It
was- it was with staffers and-
>>It was with staffers. >>you
know, it was basically what had
changed, what hadn’t changed.
Um. And you should wa- watch the
video. I mean, there are, you
know. >>I guess- I guess a big
message that I would like to
bring is that we’ve come a long
way in 20 years, but we’ve got a
lot longer to go- long way to go
with what we’re doing.
Especially with the rise of new
technologies like IOT, the risk
in electronic voting, uh, we’ve
got, uh, other issues that we
need to talk about. So we have
come a long way in 20 years.
We’re not dealing with the same
old doom and gloom, but we still
have a long way to go. >>And my-
my personal campaign is, um, you
know, don’t stamp things with
safe or not safe. Don’t do and,
you know, I- I’ve got this thing
going back and forth- >>It’s not
hackable. >>Like a UL Seal or a
fips with 40. Sort of like does
it pass or not pass sort of
thing. Give them a continuum.
Give them a fuel economy. Give
them crash test- crash test
rating. Give them the
nutritional labels on the food
so folks can make informed
decisions. Give them
transparency about the libraries
that are coming with it.
Something that is measurable
because all of the other
industries have this. And we
don’t. And I have nothing for or
against. Like, FireEye versus
CrowdStrike versus, you know,
Carbon Black versus whatever.
But, like, they all say they’re
the best. And they’re all very
different and you’re putting
them in your environment. I
mean, like, if you went to the
grocery store and you’re like,
“Well, all the food is just
food.” And there’s nothing else.
No other information. And your
doctor’s like, “Don’t you dare
have sodium because you’re going
to die.” And you’re like, “Oh I
don’t know. This looks pretty
good. Bacon.” [laughs] There’s-
if there’s no information you
can’t make an informed decision
so that’s what I actually talked
to the senators about. It’s
like, that is something that the
government can do a little bit
and I wouldn’t use liability
like we said during the first
time. That went over like a lead
balloon, um, with the Senate. I
didn’t said- say- like, you
know, instead of structures. Um.
You know, or other ways of,
like, encouraging people, to you
know, in- you know, maybe giving
them tax breaks or whatever for
organizations if they al- you
know, gave that data so that
folks can make their informed
decisions ‘cause one size
doesn’t fit all. >>It’s all how
you word it, right? >>Yeah.
>>Yeah, I think the other thing
sor- that we sort of touched on
in this meeting here and
something I think that I would
spend more time talking about is
they had asked us, like, “Well,
what can we do for legislation.”
And sort of the answer was have
less of it. You know. Get rid of
DMCA and- and don’t prevent us
from doing security research
‘cause we’re- we’re the good
guys. We’re still the good guys.
So I think that would have to be
a big point of, like, letting
them you know you don’t need
more laws to make stuff happen.
You can kind of let back a
little bit and let people get
some more freedom to do things.
>>Well, that was an interesting
time because they draw 514,
DMCA, and, uh, uh, WIPO, uh,
Weld and Intellectual Property,
you know, uh, stuff was all
coming out. So our big message
to them then was do not make it
illegal to see what’s in the
sausage. Uh, you know, because
that’s what they were going to
do. And I think today,
unfortunately, it’s kind of the
same message except now it’s
advertise what’s in all the
sausage so that folks can figure
out whether it’s kosher or not
because it matters to certain
people. >>So this is a tweet
from Dan Kenzking 2014. For an
industry built on layers of
abstraction, there is a
remarkable lack of historical
awareness around older technical
design decisions. In the context
of the Cloud and DevOps
development, do you think that’s
making the problem worse or
better? [off mic] >>It’s what I
heard the question. >>Could you
repeat that? >>Yeah. Sorry.
[laughter] We missed a little of
that. >>Sorry. Uh. You- you
could tweet wo- >>At the
beginning. >>Just swallow the
mic also please. We can’t hear
you. Thank you. >>There you go.
Right up there. >>Ok. Dan
Kenzking tweet, 2014. For an
industry built on layers of
abstraction, there is a
remarkable lack of historical
awareness around older technical
design decisions. In the context
of the Cloud and DevOps
development, do you think that
the problem is getting worse or
better? >>Awh. >>So- you know,
some of these foundational
things that everything still
sits on have really not been
fixed. Like- like BGP still has
problems. DNS has problems. Uh.
The whole SSL certificates
system has problems. Um. And
this is something that we talked
about when we talked, uh, a few
months ago up, uh, up at the
Senate is, you know, it just
seems like we’re just sort of
biting time and just hoping
everything just keeps going ok
as we become more and more
dependent on- on- on technical-
that- that technical
infrastructure. You know. Every
year goes by, we’re more and
more dependent. You know. I- I
don’t want to be dependent on
that when, like, the only doctor
that can operate on me is doing,
like, telepresence across the
planet and someone launches a
BPG attack. Right? So we’re
getting more dependent on this
stuff, but nobody’s really going
back and doing a good job trying
to fix the foundations. >>And I
think the hacker community and
InfoSec in general has a pretty
short memory. Right? So because
there’s so much information
coming out, there’s, what, 500
something talks just at Defcon
now. Um. And it’s hard to sort
of know what the pri-prior
decisions were or even prior
work. Right? So we’re seeing
repeating stuff and I don’t know
if there’s a way Cloud or not,
like how to- how to cha- how to
consolidate that in some way.
And I know, you know, the Dark
Tangent’s trying to do it with
InfoSet dot org or something to
harvest all of everybody’s talks
from all over the world, but I
don’t know how- how we can get-
have a cohesive memory of, like,
our entire community or
something. But I think that’s
what you need to- to learn what
happened in the past. [off mic
comment] What’s that? [off mic]
>>A lot you might want to
forget. Well, a lot of you might
want to forget. But- oh, you
know what. Maybe we should just
put everything in, like,
blockchain. [applause and
laughter] Woul- would that work?
I’m a hardware guy. >>Uh. Ha. In
terms of, uh, you know, the
processes by which we, uh, write
software and things changing
over time, um, it used to be
that you simply did not find out
about security issues until
software was published. Um.
These days we find out about it
sooner and sooner because of the
availability of, uh, various
types of testing. You know, I
made it my business for, like,
10 years to write static
analysis software that can make
it easier to find flaws before
they went out the door. Um. But
that was met with a lot of
resistance by developers. Um. To
really continue to affect change
in the future, to improve the
state of things, developers need
to be more involved in finding
their bugs and fixing them
sooner. Um. That said, there’s a
lot of friction there because
the tools aren’t very good for
developers. They’re not written
with developers in mind. They’re
written with AbSec people in
mind. And the profile, the use
case for developers iterating
quickly on code and trying to
get things out the door quicker,
is, uh, counter- it- it- it’s
dis- disincentivizes, uh, uh,
uh, security analysis. So coming
up with tools that developers
can actually use that are low
false positive rate and, uh,
fast enough to be part of their
process is really key. And I
know, I’m going to go ahead and
say this is something that I’m
working on actively, um, you
know, today I know that that’s,
you know, where I need to be in
terms of developing tools. Um.
You know, but, in general
pushing the cultural envelope
for developers to make it such
that security is something that
not only is something that they
want to do, um, because it makes
them feel good. I mean, the
developers that I talk to do
want to write secure code. They
do want to use tools. They just
don’t want to be a pain- have it
be a pain in the butt. Um. So,
meeting them where they are.
Instead of forcing their- the
hand through, uh, you know,
draconian security teams who
won’t let code out the door, um,
is- is really where we have to
be. Um. It’s hard work for the
security community to do that.
It’s been historically over the
last 10 years, we have simply
said, you know, “Fix your code
or by the time it goes out
you’re going to be a- you’re
going to have your pants pulled
down or be embarrassed by all
these vulnerabilities.” Uh. But
that’s intellectually lazy on
our part. It’s simply, you know,
saying that, um, it’s good
enough to, you know,
em-embarrass developers, uh,
into- into attempting to write
more secure code. That’s not
going to attack the problem at
scale. We actually have to help
them make it easier. Um. And
that means becoming their
friend. Uh. It- it means not
being an advers- seen as an
adversary to development. So.
>>One- one of the things that
would actually help a lot for
developers and DevOps and
everything, and then I’ll touch
upon the Cloud thing because I
think that’s a very, uh,
important question, is some sort
of feedback. So if you turn on,
like, StackGuards, you have no
clue whether it actually
inserted them or not. >>Right.
Right. >>You turn on Fortify
Source on, like, a linux system,
you have no clue whether it
removed 90 percent of the weak
functions that you didn’t know
that you shouldn’t have put in
there with strong ones. Or point
0, 0, 5 and actually it’s closer
to the latter in a lot of cases.
So there’s no feedback for
developers- >>Right. >>as to
whether, you know, when they’re
trying to do the right thing,
it’s having an effect or not.
Um. So I do think that’s
something that we could do a lot
better as a security community
is, like, providing feedback and
measurements. Um. But on the
Cloud stuff, I’m actually really
impressed with the Cloud from
the large providers, not so much
from the small ones. And it’s
because they’re essentially
getting fuzzed all the time by
their users. So if you look at
Amazon or GCE or anybody else,
they’ve- they’re really hardened
in a lot of ways- or Azure- you
know, sort of stuff because they
have millions of users who are
doing crazy stuff all the time
in the real world and also
they’re doing AB testing as to
what to roll out. So, yeah, I
actually think that abstraction
at scale if it was, like- if you
think of the world as AFL at
large, you know, just, you know,
as a- a Mechanical Turk version
of AFL, um, yeah, that’s
actually really useful for the
large providers, but the small
ones don’t get that benefit. And
I- they scare me. So Cloud’s a
mixed bag. >>Yeah. >>This is for
Mudge. Tell us about the
election hacking and your
response. >>Does it have to be
Mudge? >>Does it have to be
Mudge? >>It doesn’t have to be.
I just know- >>It’s a topic I’ve
talked about a lot. >>Um. >>So
I’ve got a question for you.
>>You’ve got a question? Go
ahead. >>I’ve been wondering
how- if you can tell me, um, I
don’t know, statute of
limitations- when they- you
know, when that ends, but, um,
what’s your most- >>Are you
implying that we did anything
that requires statute of
limitations? Ma’am? [laughter]
>>I don’t know! You’re- you’re-
you’re at Defcon. You’re up on
this stage. I don’t- I don’t
know. Um. [laughter] >>What-
what was- what are your most,
like, what’s your most fun or
entertaining or memorable hack
that you can talk about? [panel
laughter] >>No comment. >>Yeah,
no comment. [laughter] >>Do you
guys remember the midnight poker
nights with Hobbit? [laughter]
I’ll see you a guddopleble a
high Sp enlotvia and raise you
a- a small, uh, internet
connectivity area in the, uh,
gulf states for, um, you know
>>Ok. You- you need to shut up
right now. [laughter] >>It’s a
joke. It’s a joke. >>But back to
the- back to, uh, Rogue Agent’s
election question. Um. I think
the thing to keep in mind when
we read about election hacking
in the press is that there’s a
big difference between, uh,
probing a registration database,
and changing an actual vote in a
real election. Uh. And there’s a
very big blurring in the media
between oh, my god. The election
was hacked. Or the- the- the
voters were hacked in some state
and whether or not a vote was
actually changed. I, aeh- You
ok? >>Yeah. >>Alright. So that-
>>But what have you heard?
[laughter] >>So I just- I think
it’s important to keep that in
mind. And when you- when you see
these, uh, media reports of a
registration database was probed
or- or copied or whatever,
that’s not the same thing as
someone breaking into an
election and changing an actual
vote. >>It- it- it’s not the
same thing, but all this in the
media over and over again, votes
are getting hacked. Votes are-
systems are vulnerable with
this. It makes it so that people
don’t trust the system. >>And I
think that that’s partly-
>>Right? People don’t understand
it so they aren’t going to trust
the system. >>That’s- >>So less
people are going to vote. And
there are actually people out
there who don’t believe our
president was elected
legitimately because they
believe systems were hacked.
There are people who believe
that- >>Right. And I think
that’s part of the problem.
Right? >>So if that gets worse,
right? >>That’s part of- that
was part of the goal was that
they’re trying to dis- uh, cause
mayhem by forcing people- or
changing people’s mind. >>Who’s
they? >>I’m not going to get
into who’s they. It could- it
could be anybody, but a lot of
this- [laughter] a lot of the
information that we’re seeing
reported in the media. And I’m
not going to 400 pounds.
[laughter] I’m not going there.
Uh. There’s a lot of people in-
that- now I’ve lost my train of
thought. Go ahead. >>So- so it’s
>>Actually it’s- it’s- it’s
really- >>We only have a few
more minutes left. But- >>I just
want to give a pointer to the
answer there. Um. >>Ok. Please
do. >>Alex Handleman and the
folks that- of, uh, University
of Michigan, uh, went over to
Winstonia and what a lot of what
folks don’t know is that was
actually a part of the Google
project that I ran for Project
Vault. And watch the video of an
actual online e-voting internet
sort of environment. It is
amazing and terrifying and it is
15 years old and hasn’t been
updated. And it is still the
exemplar of the best thing out
there which should make people
pause. >>Yeah. Bear in mind that
the real election hacking is
being done by our own government
is called gerrymandering and you
can vote against it. [applause]
>>Yeah! >>That is the perfect
point to close on. >>We can just
drop the mic and walk out on
that. Honestly. >>So- so I want
to thank all you guys >>So-
>>That- that was awesome. Uh. Go
ahead, Eleanor. I’m sorry. >>One
last question. Um. If you- what
advice to you have for hackers
are researchers- security
researchers today? Let’s go-
let’s start with at the end of
the- the line and just move this
way. Advice for people in the
audience. >>Um. Never be afraid
to get started on something. Um.
I, uh, often times get into form
of analysis paralysis wondering
if the thing I’m going to do is
going to either make me money or
be valuable or whether, you
know, people will notice it. Um.
You just simply don’t know. Um.
If it’s interesting, get started
on it. Tear it apart. Um. You
know. Make it your quest to
learn that thing as much as
possible. Um. Break new ground
whenever you can. Uh. If you
think nobody else has maybe done
it, just do it. Um. And try to
finish what you start. It’s the
hardest thing ever when you’ve
got a million ideas but it’s-
that’s the only way anything
ever gets done. So. >>I think my
big advice to security
researchers today is just be
careful. Alright? There’s a lot
of companies that don’t like
you. There are laws that don’t
like you. Uh. Um. That doesn’t
mean don’t do it. Please keep
doing what you do, but be
careful. Do some research on the
laws. Don’t cross the lines.
Stay out of jail. Stay out of
the courtroom. >>I’d say play
the long game. Um. You know, I
remember going out to talk to
kadets when I was at the L0pht.
Those kadets are now Colonels.
Um. And they actually have
impact. Same thing with
senators’ aides. Um. Same thing
with CFT. I mean, King Pin came
up at the end of my talk at
Defcon, like, a few years back
going like we didn’t know what
the heck, you know, Mudge turned
into the man. What’s going on?
[laughter] And I got a lot of
crap for it, but then folks saw
that no- actually, no. It’s
still kind of Mudge trying to
make a dent in the universe sort
of thing. >>And you made it easy
for us to take government money.
[laughter] >>We got one minute
guys. >>So but- play the long
game. Everybody else is
optimizing locally. Optimize
globally and for the long term.
>>Uh. I guess a lot of people
ask me, like, what they should
focus on in terms of uh, uh, you
know, people I work with that
are actually coming to me to
learn how to get more advanced
in their security testing and,
uh, everybody wants me to point
them at something that companies
using or would be useful or
whatever. But ultimately it has
to be something you’re really
interested in because it’s going
to take tons of hours of, uh,
your devotion so, um, obviously
focus on that. And then the
other thing I would say is that,
uh, it’s really easy to get
wrapped up in the excitement of
things and make mistakes and
today desk space is cheap and
there’s this concept of big
data- everybody’s collecting
data on everything. So a lot of
things that we may have gotten
away with as kids, I think we
got really lucky. Um. And, uh,
so def- definitely a much more
dangerous, uh, environment out
there for people so, um, you
know, make sure you- you, uh,
are careful not to cross the
line. More careful than, you
know, I think kids normally are.
>>Yeah. But don’t be afraid to
fail either. Otherwise you’ll,
you know- >>Uh. So- so I would
say, you know, I hope you
welcome the newbies. Be nice to
them. They have imposter
syndrome. Um. And, uh- but- but
if they’re here, they want to
learn. Um. And the- the other
thing I would say is network
with people that aren’t just
like you. Like people when you
go back to the office [applause]
developers, UI people, managers-
get them to understand how we
think. Um. So, you know, s- s-
spread it a little bit outside
our community. >>I think you
just have to love what you do.
And it doesn’t matter what it
is, but if you are passionate
about something, like, that’s
really what you want to do. You
want to find something that you
really care about. And you
shouldn’t be searching for
money. You shouldn’t be
searching for being on a stage.
You shouldn’t be searching for,
you know, branding your
whatever. Yes, I’m up here. That
wasn’t the goal when I started
hacking. [laughter] But it’s
because I love what I do and if
you do that, you can look around
Defcon and there’s a lot of
people that do amazing things
that- that are not on a stage.
They’re doing stuff that you’re-
you’re not going to read about
in the news. And it’s all over
this entire hotel. Right? So
you- you find something that you
love and good things are going
to happen. >>Great. Thank you.
[applause]