>> Hi, my name is Morgan
Gangwere. I’m a student but uh
first you’ve made it to uh a
talk about ARM and all sorts of
fun stuff. So, uh first a little
bit of a dedication to my
father. Um my father is a Vet
Assistant Engineer. Uh what
you’re seeing right here is he
has one arm. He uh taught me to
build my own tools. Keep
building your own tools. Um, you
will learn so much just by
exploring your world and he
taught me that. And I want you
uh to come out of this at least
with explore your world. Know
how it works. Thanks dad.
[applause] So, I’m the hoopiest
frood that ever did cross the
universe. I know exactly where
my towel is, it’s in a little
pack, I bought it from REI. Been
fiddling with Linux SOCs for a
good 10 years now. I got an old
EmbeddedARM board from my father
at one point. I’ve done ARM
services for the last little
while. Uh I’ve even build my own
version of Cyanogen just to try
and get it to build on a
machine. I’m actually a student
by day. Uh, I try to not talk
about it as much because it’s in
a completely unrelated field.
Uh, I’m here because it’s fun.
So, this talk is a fair amount
of kind of theory. There’s not a
whole lot of complex and like,
ooo look at this ya know sweet
trick that you can pull. This is
because this sort of work, the,
uh reverse engineering is 1 part
science, 1 part estimation, a
dash of bitter feelings about
everything in the world and a
little hint of, what the f**k
was that EE thinking when they
built this? A lot of things come
from experience. I can point the
way but I cannot see the future.
You will have to learn many
little tools and techniques on
your own. There are a lot of
seemingly random parts in this
talk, they’ll all come together.
So first let’s talk about ARM.
The BBC to your face. Uh, ARM
originally stood for Acorn RISC
machine. If you think you are
away from an ARM machine you are
sorely wrong. Um, ARM originally
built the ARM1 chip for the BBC
micro for a lightweight risk
system. Um, Acorn changed
hand-ing, hands a couple of
times. Uh they’ve never cut
silicon but fun fact, Intel has
cut silicon for 9 Tele-Platform
multiple times. Especially after
they bought deck. Um the ISA
actually hasn’t changed in about
20, 30 years. You can still read
ARM1 assembly from the 80’s.
Kind of figure it out and then
run it on a s-, a brand new ARM
chip, today. There are ARM
devices all around you.
Including in routers, cell
phones, uh NAS devices, QNap
actually has a version of their
NAS that runs on a cortex ARM
system, uh Synology is another
company that produces 100s of
devices that run on ARM chips,
and even new laptops with uh,
Qualcomm Snapdragon chips are
coming out today that are
running Windows, Linux,
everything. In the non-SSE world
ARM takes up everything. From
smart watches to home lighting
to even in your laptop today.
Um, in the Surface alone there
are 4 or 5 ARM chips just for
things like firmware control,
disk access, even the touchpad
has 2 independent ARM chips. Uh,
the steam controller is both run
on Cortex M0 and IKEA’s touch
free lighting system is built
around an embedded Zigbee end
cortex ARM zero uh, base
station. Uh, Sony has been
building ARM into their cameras
for good long while, and your
cameras today probably runs ARM.
So, let’s talk about embedded
Linux on uh kinda high level. An
embedded Linux device, uh looks
like 3 parts. Storage, SoC and
Ram. Everything else is a bonus.
Um you’re going to see physical
devices on I2C or USB or SDIO.
Um, there’s standards for how
cameras and displays work. A lot
of this has been hashed out
pretty straightforward. Um, it
looks a lot like a standard PC
today and the lines are getting
pretty blurry. Uh, so let’s ask
the question of what is a system
1 chip? Uh it’s a just add water
sort of easy design peripheral.
Uh, what you’re seeing here is
an orange pie. Um with an all
winner chip. That is a quad core
ARM device that you can get for
10 dollars. This is, this is
really amazing actually because
now we have stuff in today’s
world where you can put this on
a breakout board, add power,
boot Linux from an SD card and
actually build the device. This
is been touching a lot of
devices that are using really
cheap SoCs. Including our
phones. Everything looks about
the same especially when you
look at a block diagram.
Everything sits on an internal
bus, there’s a peripheral for
external content, there’s a
storage controller for boot
content, a GPU, a CPU, some
external peripherals. Once
you’ve seen 1, you’ve seen them
all. Including ones from Intel.
You don’t actually always see,
uh ARM stuff on an SOC. This is
from Bay Trail SOC, that goes
into a laptop as you can see
down there, there’s even a old
SM bus and uh, it looks to be
like boot rom and legacy stuff
to hold all the old x86 stuff
that has been sitting there
withering away in a corner
because nobody runs 32 bit x86
anymore right? Storage comes in
a couple different flavors. MTD
which is basically a cheap way
to say, ooo this is flash. Um
eMMC which have, called embedded
multimedia cards, uh SD cards.
And if you’ve ever seen an SD
card in a device you have just
won the jackpot. Then there is
UFS. UFS is the new standard
that’s come along in recent
years for the purposes of cell
phones for higher speed, higher
density uh stuff. If you have a
newer cell phone you are
probably using this. Uh there’s
a lot of different variations
for this, uh some devices have a
loaded on board flash on the
chips that they can load. The
first stage boot loader. Um this
is common on phones, stuff like
Fastboot, boots from this. Every
vendor has their own way of
shoving bits onto a device, they
all suck. Uh, RAM, uh you’re
gonna see a whole lot of
different variations of this. Uh
vendors are notoriously tight
assed especially after the
terrific price fixing that SK
Hynix was found of doing. Um,
but consider that there’s a lot
of devices that have 8 megabytes
of RAM. Uh including the WD4G.
And later they did another
revision that had 4 megs of RAM.
But modern phones are hitting
the g- uh the realm of a gig to
4 to 6 gigs. In a pure flash
environment you might actually
be losing RAM because flash can
sometimes be slow and it’s
faster to shove things to RAM.
When it comes to peripherals you
got SPI, I squared C, I squared
sound, ya know these are common
stuff. But you’re going to
really crazy s**t in there. Uh
SDIO wireless cards are not
uncommon. Turns out y- ya know
SD cards were also built for
general purpose IO devices and
so they actually talk slightly
different variations of SPI.
You’re gonna see sound cards
over I squared sound, uh GSM
modems, most of them are just
pretending to be Hayes AT
modems. Power management is all
the rage. Um, you’ll see LEDs on
your GPIO pens. Go look around
in syanage and MOD and you’ll
see all sorts of different
examples of this. Linux doesn’t
care if they’re on-die. This is
an example from uh, Snapdragon
820. A PCIe, a UART to PCM chain
are all used jus for the
wireless LAN and Bluetooth. This
is so they can turn Bluetooth
audio into just another channel
on the audio stack and
completely abstract away the
actual hardware. The PCIe is
typically for uh wireless LAN
connectivity and the UART is
actually gonna be for probably
part of a baseband controller
for the Bluetooth. Um, again
Linux doesn’t care if these are
on-die. You could have these
emulated somewhere. You could
have them completely
non-present. Uh, another good
example of this is uh, this is
an X-BIT robin. The flash on the
camera is done through GPIO.
It’s a bi-color LED, but all of
the LEDs in the back, including
the bottom notification LED are
actually run off of a small TI
light LED Controller that has
its own ISA and is actually its
own state machine. When it comes
to bootloaders there’s one
predominant game in, in the
market. Das U-Boot. It has a
very simple scr-, simple
scripting language. Talks over a
serial port. It can pull over a
TFTP, HTTP, all sorts of stuff.
You can shove X Modem kernels at
this thing, it doesn’t care. All
you have to tell it is I want to
put this thing in memory at this
place and then jump to this
place and execute. Uh some
devices don’t use U-Boot though.
Uh Fastboot is a very common
thing to see on phones. Um, some
uh Linux tablets are also built
around U-Boot but more often
commercial devices you might be
seeing uh, Samsung has their own
stage 2 bootloader and such.
It’s all something interesting.
So, let’s talk about the life
and death of an SoC based
device. Uh first of it does a
DFU check to see if there’s
anything to load fresh code onto
it. Uh, then d- it loads it’s
internat – uh initial program
loader. This is from the vendor
typically it does any signature
checking from the initial image.
Uh, this is typically burned
straight onto die at factory.
Then it pulls in the bootloader
for uh early UART network
wakeup. Especially if it’s a
network boot device. Um, then
you get U-Boot loading kernel
into RAM for some other fun
stuff. It kicks the kernel and
then you’re in user space. The
fun s**t is in the DFU because
that’s the first chance you have
to actually attack the device.
If you can get uh, life of DFU
then you can run whatever you
want on it. You have full
control over everything that’s
happening. If you can interrupt
U-Boot or any other, uh
bootloader then you can run your
own kernel. Now you can start
attacking other pieces. If
you’re gonna get it attacking
userland that’s still fun you
can go and attack the actual
surface that most people be
hitting. In order to start on
the next system, you need uh
root filesystem. It contains the
bare minimum to boot Linux, uh,
any shared object libraries,
binaries, other content. Um
other fluid content actually
gets tarballed up in a lot of
routers. You’ll see this on a
consistent basis. Uh this means
like tmpfs is going to look
really huge and if you try to
extract content from It, it’s
going to look weird. Uh
sometimes there’s actually
multiple root file systems. Uh
newer Android phones are running
off of a more consistent uh AB
platform. Uh which means that
you have 1 version of Lin- of
Android that is no good to boot.
And you have an unknown version
that has just been applied. You
might find yourself scratching
your head at times especially if
you’ve gotten a dump off of a
live system as to why you’re not
booting that. That might be why.
Um some cases, might actually
try NFS. There’s a whole set of
uh, devices that uh, internally
they have a bunch of ARM uh SOCs
running DSPs and they’re gonna
like boot off of NFS because
that’s the easiest thing to do.
Um, attaching these devices
comes down to scoping out your
device. Um, get to know what
makes your device actually run.
Get to know it, what it’s
running in terms of Linux, what
it’s software stack is,
etcetera. Um, if you’re gonna
start attacking uh Cortex ARM0
devices and friends then what
you’re gonna start doing is
looking at what SOC it has, what
sort of Jtag ports it has, what
kind of backup stuff does it
have? Um is there a known way to
dump the code off of your chip?
ARM executables are really
generic. Um, ARM really doesn’t
care as long as you can wake up
the peripherals in the right
way. Uh under Linux this means
that you don’t have to compile
for a particular chip. Debian
has an ARM-hf and that’s for any
ARM that has hard-float. If you
have ARM arch 64 binaries
they’ll run on any ARM arch 64
device as long as they can load
up their loader, uh and their
necessary shared binaries. Uh
hardware vendors are also dumb
and lazy. Um, you will see a lot
of devices that are variations
on current existing devices.
Don’t reinvent the wheel as
well. Um, embedded d- devices
like this are going to be really
common and really popular and
they’re going to be consist.
CenturyLink for example sends
out really consistently similar
devices. Kobo puts out devices
that the only different is what
kernel they’re running
internally everything else gets
loaded at run time. Uh, OWASP
has a whole set of tasks devoted
to looking at uh embedded IoT
devices. They’re little toolset
can actually become really
helpful for devices which talk
over the internet or which
you’re trying to figure out
what’s going on. Tools like
Firmwalker and such, uh they are
built for ya know turn key push
this, at our device and see what
happens. They’re intended to
start looking and interrogating
devices and services and
especially uh, running binaries
to see what’s going on. Um, if
you are curious about this,
there is a fantastic blog called
the Firmware Security Blog. They
have a whole list of tools. Um,
so one option uh especially if
it’s Linux system is uh, say
it’s a Unix system. Ya know I
know this. If you can get a
shell, beat against the shell.
Um you have only what’s on the
target, only what’s available at
that moment. Um this is a bit
like going into the wild with a
bowie knife and a jar of piss. I
mean it’s gonna work you’re
going to beat your head against
a w-, uh a brick wall for a bit
but you’ll eventually find
something. But you have no
debugger, you have no compiler,
you have no fuzzer you have none
of the tools that most people
like to play with. The second
option is to black box it
entirely. Done’ even uh try and
pull a part the system. Just
attack what’s uh externally
visible things are. Um, I’m not
a lawyer. If you think you might
be touching something that’s
gonna violate some NDA’s get a
lawyer but you have a less
likelihood of running into some
secret. You’re only out, uh
externally attacking this as
though it were a backbox. But
unfortunately, you have lost the
jar of piss and all you have is
the bowie knife. Both of these
options suck. So you go, okay
let's reverse it. Uh pull out
IDA, Radare any of your standard
reversing tools, grab a beer,
learn you have a new ISA and uh,
off you go. This is a great way
to start with stuff like uh,
embedded IOT devices like those
light bulbs from Philips, Ikea,
etcetera. Uh your smart watch,
etcetera. Um, the c- problem is
how the f**k do you get those
binaries? We’ll get to that. Ya
know, b- I’m a lazy a*****e, I
want to fuzz this thing. I don’t
want to learn IDA. Then you
emulate it. Um you have every
tool at your disposal if you’re
emulating. Y- debugger, fuzzer,
cool. Um, but you still have
that problem of how the hell do
you get your actual, ya know
binary of interest? You get the
root file system. Especially if
it is a Linux device. If it’s an
ARM uh, such as a standard
embedded device, a lot of these
tools are gonna apply as well.
Easy mode update packages. Um
these are the probably the
fastest way to get a root file
system if you have a complete
OTA. Or a lot of routers just
ship an entire complete version
of the file system. They open up
the disk, they say, cool here’s
my update and they just plow
right over what is there
already. Uh sometimes they are
actual executables. The downside
is, sometimes they’re encrypted,
sometimes they’re really
obfuscated. They, sometimes
they’re actually intended to
keep you from doing this. Um,
the second trick is, In-Vivo
execution. Um you’re either
going to need a shell. Hijack
some administration
inter-interfaces. Uh go back to
stub zero and start looking at,
ya know, what can you do? Is
there a known attack against ya
know, command injection? Can you
start netcat? Can you explore
what’s on the file system
through some blind uh, in-
command injection. Um you might
need some kind of packer. Um
there’s a lot of stuff built
into most busy box
implementations You’re gonna
have to find a way to get it to
somewhere. Netcat is a good
example. Uh curl can do some
amount of push. You might
actually have an HTTPD to fall
on, on the device if you can set
up a SYMlink into whatever it’s
using. Uh and you might need
some creativity. I’ve actually
done this at one point, I just
simply had the device send its
entire disk straight over the
internet, over the local network
to a broadcast address and used
Wireshark to capture all th-,
all the traffic and then pieced
it back together. So, let’s take
a look at what that looks like.
So, this is me the first time I
looked at the, technicolor
C1100T. This is a DSL router
sent by uh CenturyLink. I’ve
turned on the admin interface
here and I’m just poking around
of what the admin interface
gives me. Gives you some
information about the memory of
allocation. There’s some DNS
redirecting that you can do. Um,
this is really cool. Um, it’s
been running for a couple
minutes. I can actually muck
with the WAN interface here.
We’ll see if we have a shell. Oh
look we have a root shell. The
world is our oyster at this
point so let’s go uh, peak
around. Um, they put f****n
plain text credentials all over
PS. But what I was wanting to
see is like GDB server. I’m
starting to see, uh config
stuff, TFTPD. I’m starting to
actually find some really cool
stuff. Uh especially if you look
very carefully there you can
actually flash from uh, W get
straight to the device.
>>[Audience question] >>Yeah
this, this is definitely the, is
this security. Um, th- this is
available to CenturyLink over
their back door. So I start
figuring out ya know can I
netcat this thing off? And then
I go and plug a flash drive into
the back because this meant for
like shoving printers onto, for
printer sharing. So I’m gonna
copy over the mtd flash blocks.
Just directly. And there’s a
handful of them. Um, I don’t
care how many it thinks it has.
I’m gonna copy them all over
just because I think I can. Uh,
some time passes, this takes
about uh 10 minutes in real
time. And, let’s go uh poke
around some more. Um, turns out
we have like scratchpad stuff.
Um, there’s actually some
arbitrary memory read and write
that I uh end up finding here.
Uh, this is some interesting
useful information about how mtd
is laid out. Uh looks like
there’s a rootfs and rootfs
update. Which uh, do not appear
to uh, be intentionally
overlapping. But they are
overlapping entirely. Uh I know
what kind of file systems it has
access to. And, ya know, just
kind of playing around. So what
did we get out of that? We got a
whole bunch of information. We
know that this thing has uh read
and write commands that can
touch arbitrary chunks of
memory. And that it can do
things like DNS redirection and
that this is available to
CenturyLink through their
administrative interface. But
more importantly we got the full
root file system. These are EXT2
file system, uh, blobs just
hanging out on a flash drive
now. Um, other methods, um
surprise is uh direct
extraction. All of these devices
have an SD card. So pull it out
and image it. And you’re telling
me okay a**hole tell me
something I can’t figure out my
own d**n self. SD cards are
hiding in f****n plain site. Uh,
these are like kickstarters for
devices that are literally just
a raspberry pi. A like, there’s
an Anti-Villain box which is
intended for like uh TOR
security. Um over on the bottom
left there is the first
generation uh, Amazon kindle
device. It just had a standard
off the shelf 2 gig SD card that
you could just pull. Oh, you
need more space, well put a
f****n 16 gig card in there.
It’s doesn’t care. Uh, KOBO is
the same way. That’s an SD card,
just SAN’s SD card. You can pull
out, you can image it, expand
the file systems, off you go.
Um, eMMC is just a variation on
SD. They’re actually both uh
simply multimedia cards. Um, it
can be done. You’re gonna have
to pull some stuff. You’re gonna
have to understand how the disk
is laid out. In the end, um
having some in-VIVO information
is really helpful doing some
reconnaissance, shelling in your
device, playing around like a,
like a traditional Unix hacker
would given any random machine.
Um, somethings are made a little
harder by the face that eMMC is
also now burned into eMCP. Which
is LPDDR and eMMC combined. Uh,
however all this is made simple
by China because they need to
work from iPhones and iPhones
use eMMC devices. So these are
SD card adapters that you slot
your eMMC device into and they
turn it into a USB or SD card.
Or you can make your own. Um,
it’s just an SD Card. It talks 4
bit. Um it’s a little bit slow
but it works. And these things
are everywhere. These are up
raspberry pi based devices. Uh
ModBerry and uh, Revolution PI
are both din-mountable. These
are going in industrial control
systems. Um all else fails, uh
solder to the rescue. Uh you
might need Dsars in storage
especially if you’re on an e-
eEMC. Um, you might need a p- uh
to drag out some, uh, uh,
traces. You’re gonna look at,
for Jtag, um if you’re
interested this weekend, go
check out the hardware hacking
village and start looking at
what you can do. Uh at this
point you might be looking for a
logic analyzers, uh Saleae makes
a very good one that’s cheap,
runs over a USB, uh does a lot
of the T cutting for you. Uh
there’s also hardware interfaces
to talk to a lot of this stuff.
Uh, on the left is the bus
pirate it is an open source uh,
S RAM backed uh, protocol
analyzer. It has a lot of stuff
baked in. On the right is the
SPI driver. It is a little USB
device that um, lets you make up
a uh, a SPI interface. But you
can run it at any speed, you can
see and visualize what’s going
on in the uh, wire. So, now that
we have that you know, what the
dell do we do? Um you try
extracting it, you mount it, you
take a look at what you just
pulled. Uh eMMC regularly and
sometimes do have uh little
partition tables. SD cards more
than likely, because some of
these actually on a PC had to
touch this thing. Uh go back to
the reconnaissance, go back to
step 0 and see what you found.
Then let automation do your
work. Look at Binwalk. Um,
binwalk is a fantastic tool for
anybody who’s getting into
reverse engineering especially.
Uh tools like Photorec might
actually be useful. Uh you might
be, have to get a little bit
more creative. Uh losetup and
uh, friends can do a lot of
stuff like finding partition
tables, uh they can find uh
certain records that mark that
this is a file system. Um, if
you’re only looking for stuff
like IDA and rotarae, once you
have your uh binary of choice,
automation might be the easy way
to get it. This is kind of where
you’re gonna stop. Um, however
if you’re looking to actually
like attack this thing live, you
also want QEMU. Because the
problem is these devices are
slow, the device that sits and
does my, uh internet at home is
an 18 megahertz device. It has
s**t all for ram. I don’t want
to sit and try to figure out how
to cross compile, uh my fuzzed
and something and run it on
there and try to beat it against
it. And it takes 5 minutes to
boot every time I touch a bad
chunk of memory it reboots and
I’m down for another 5 minutes,
now I’m back to where I started.
So QEMU uh lets you uh do some
stuff. It’s a simple fast
processor, emulator uh from also
stuff like mainframes, ARM,
MIPS, uh open risk. You can
pretend you’re an STM QF34 or
you can pretend that you are uh,
a DEC Alpha. You can OSX on
Amiga. You can even run Haiku on
BeOS. Um, there’s 2 ways to run
QEMU as a full fat VM or as a
translating loader. Um, with the
full fat VM. You have full
control of everything. You are
the hardware. This is an end
circuit regulator for
everything. Uh, you’ve got GDB
at kernel level because you get
to step through the entire
processor. Uh requires your
trust and whatever binary you’re
working with especially if
you’ve got something that you
think is malicious. Um, you
probably want a special kernel
if you are working with this
however there’s a lot of ways to
make QEMU do what you need to
do. Um, any tools that you need
are you, y- you’re gonna have to
push them into the target
environment. I hate
cross-compilers, so that’s why I
typically use a translating
loader. Um, you have access to
whatever you’re doing. Uh the
downside to translating loaders
is that uh it’s kind of like
whine, except it can’t run
Windows executables. It’s
intended to run Linux
executables directly. Um, you
can run in a container so now
you can completely automate a
process. You can run this in
parallel. You don’t need a
container. Uh, so this is
actually a full-fat VM. Um, I
have a friend that needed uh
some work down. This is a 9
track tape drive uh from
Overland Data with a laptop
running MS DOS 6. As a full-fat
VM over the parallel port,
interfacing with real hardware.
Uh here I’m actually reading
blocks out of an AOD install
tape from a data general
mainframe that we had picked up.
Um, this is just protected to
the system. It’s running on an
old DOS machine. It’s old, it’s
slow. I’m running on a CORE 2
duo. This doesn’t require a
whole lot of power, all things
considered. But what it does
mean is that you don’t have to
worry about is the hardware
actually like there. Do I have
to drag out a DOS machine? No
you just boot DOS out of a QEMU.
Um, as a loader you’re relying
on binfmt. Uh long ago Linux had
the ability to just say hey I
need to say that this is my
executable for this type of
executable. Uh it was virtually
for running JARs. Um, so that
you can run JARs from the
command line. Uh, turns out it’s
a great place to put emulators.
Uh, QEMU has a static version
which runs entirely in user
space. And it un, it uses the
magic number system that’s baked
into BIN format. Uh Debian puts
it in their binfmt-misc package
and a couple others. Uh, without
a container it’s dumb simple to
set up. You just call bin QEMU
whatever static. Call your
binary and off it goes. Uh you
have to trust that your
executables not malicious. You
also have to have all your local
libraries sync up to whatever
libraries it had. Um this works
best for like big static
monolithic executables like
Busybox. However, for a
container you know you can bring
that whole root filesystem
along. You can bring those weird
versions of GlibC. You have
effectively a little jail um,
you can run it in Docker you can
run it in SystemD’s, um machine
containers. It’s great for when
your binary is linked against
some weird like, oh we had this
idea and let’s go mangle GlibC.
Um for this next demo, uh we’re
gonna look at a piece of
software, or that’s uh running
on what’s more normally known as
IBMz 14. Um, if anybody is
familiar with s390x it’s
actually compatible with the
system 360. So this is a quick
user demo. Um, so here we are,
we’re starting uh, s390x, uh, uh
container from system D. Um, we
have, ya know, standard thing,
here you can see that it’s uh,
changed a little bit in htop but
to everything it’s standard
s390x system. But for fun, uh we
can also do this for ARM. Uh
again my machine just says, yeah
your ARM system, never- uh mind
that this is actually internally
just an s86 box. It’s actually a
VM running inside a VM. Um, QEMU
in this was is really,
astonishingly powerful. Um, the
big part is this can run AFL
internally. Um, AFL is a
fantastic fuzzer. And AFL has
support for QEMU. There’s a
little bit of setup. Uh you have
to bring uh a copy of QEMU built
for AFL, for your target
alongside. Um, I’ve done this in
a VM, it’s really slow and it
works. So, so here we are, we’re
gonna run our s390x and we’re
gonna bind a couple of things
over from the Debian machine
that I’m running this on. I’ve
compiled an AFL for uh, x86
already. Uh here’s our uh target
executable. It’s a 64-bit IBM
s390 uh executable. Um, we’re
gonna tell AFL, hey here’s your
AFL pass. And AFL starts up.
It’s got a couple of small
simple tests, uh environments
and this is actually really
slow. But here we can see AFL’s
attacking s390x binary. I don’t
have s390x hardware. I have a
cheap uh laptop with a VM. So,
um, what we learned is that uh
hardware vendors are lazy. Uh as
we saw ya know a lot of these
devices are going to be very
similar to each other. There’s a
lot of duplication in so many
things. Um, attacking hardware
means getting really creative.
You’re going to see a lot of
stuff that a whole process of
pulling off uh a CenturyLink
routers firmware. That was the
first time I had seen it and it
took me just over an hour to
get, ya know take and peak
around. You spend a lot of time
doing reconnaissance. You start
look at what is my device doing?
Um, QEMU is pretty new. It is
fundamentally a way to make a
device pretend, a piece of
software def- depend, uh,
pretend that it is on the actual
piece of hardware that it
believes it is. Uh QEMU can
actually be used for way more.
There is again, a STM 32 port.
You can run it on embedded ARM.
Uh you can run QEMU on ARM to
pretend that it’s ARM if you
have the wrong kind of ARM. Uh
for a little while I was doing
this so that I could use ARM 64
binaries on ARM 32 systems. It
works, its slow but it works.
Um, AFL also runs really slow
when you’re emulating x86 uh,
stuff on uh, s390x, uh, the
other way around. Um, and
remember rule zero. Okay. This
is the, the big part here. That
little rule zero, a lot of
reconnaissance, a little bit of
planning can spend you, can save
you hours and hours of headache.
Um, sometimes just simply
noticing that there’s an EMMC
device means, oh I’ll solder it,
pop it into a ready. I’m done, I
don’t have to worry about how
I’m gonna extract this. Then you
find out that it’s encrypted.
Well alright then you go back.
You start looking. You start
sniffing the wires. A lot of uh,
creativity comes with things
like when fail overflow, did
their attach on the PlayStation
4 they found out it was just an
x86 system. So what they did is
they intercepted a lot of the c-
the communications between 2
sides. By running PCIE over a
uART at 9,600 bod. So they could
watch each frame visually, as it
went through their entire
system. Um, and people are lazy.
Remember that the Xbox 1, PS4
and probably upcoming versions
are just x86 systems. They’re
just putting newer and more
creative uh, forms of control on
how code gets loaded. Attack
early. And find interesting ways
you will pour over documents in
broken Chinese. You will pour
over documents in broken
English. I have spent many hours
sitting in front of data sheets
that were, I copied and pasted
this out of a do- a pdf into
google translate and then had to
retranslate it. Because the
company that makes it only makes
it in Chinese. Because all the
engineers are Chinese. You’ll
see stuff, ya know don’t be
afraid to look for TFTP. Your
device actually might pop open
TFTP early. Um, Marocki devices
for a long time did this. And it
was really interesting.
>>[Audience Question –
inaudible] >>Yes, uh. >>[
Audience Question – inaudible]
>>The comment was that a lot of
consumer routers will boot from
TFTP if they can’t boot from
their normal file system and
yeah that happens. Uh if you can
induce that failure. Might be as
simple as a paper clip, m- kay,
um this is ya know, a paperclip
is how you defeat on a lot of
older ThinkPads the lock out
mechanism. So you cause the
thing to boot, misread the boot
configuration and then out comes
an empty slate. You go back into
the boot configuration. The bios
echoes, I don’t have a password.
All the encryption keys been
wiped so now you just have to
reboot and do new encryption
keys. This sort of stuff is
pretty common. Um, again if
you’re interested go look at
hardware hacking village.
Explore what uh, hardware
engineers have to build, because
you will wonder, what the hell
was that EE drinking on that
day? Because, w- people put PCIE
devices on ARM. There’s even uh,
there’s a GPS receiver there as
well. And that’s going over it’s
own custom proprietary BUS.
There are many different ways to
attack these. Uh, AFL is an
amazing tool , if you can get it
working, great! So, any
questions? Yes. >>[Audience
Question – inaudible] >>So for
SOC for, um, the question was
how do I emulate uh peripherals
in QEMU. I’ve worked
predominantly an environment
where I don’t have to worry
about peripherals uh I know
there is a framework for saying
when you write to this memory
address, really write to this
device. Um, check the QEMU
documentation. They have a lot
of how to emulate external
peripherals. Um something like
the uh, SPI driver or Bus Pirate
can be used as a bridge to the
real hardware as well. Um, you
would have to check the
documentation. Other questions?
>>[Audience Question –
inaudible] >>I can’t see all the
way back. Fantastic. Thank you
so much. Um there’s more
resources available on the
internet. [applause] Um
definitely check out if you uh
are more interested in this uh
RECON 2010 there was a fantastic
talk by Igor Sko- Skochinsky on
reverse engineering for PC
Reversers. As well as the
fantastic JTAG Explained
article. Uh go like at eLinux
and Linux MIPS Uh there are many
target that you can attack.
There are ARM devices and
embedded Linux devices all
around you. Like right here.
This is a 100 megahertz ARM
chips. There are ARM devices on
your body. There are possibly
ARM devices in your body. There
are embedded systems everywhere.
Keep on hacking. [applause]