>>alright, so right off the bat
I just want to say that I’m
disappointed that my like talks
on security unit testing just
don’t get this many
people,right, that’s probably
more important so we’re just
gonna switch it up and that’s
what we’re gonna talk about
instead [laughter]. Okay,
alright, alright we’ll talk
about the hacker tracker, ummm
so right off the bat I’m Seth
Law I’m an application security
consultant, I’ve done
development in the past, uh, I
actually started my career at
IOmega, uh anybody here remember
the Zip drive? >>yeah >>Yeah? K,
I was not responsible for the
click of death, that was not me,
blame the hardware engineers
right, if you lost data that was
not my fault. That dates me,
I’ve been around for a long
time. I’ve been coming to DefCon
since Defcon eight, or something
like that, um but now I just do
application security work, I’m
an independent consultant. So,
that’s me, I do the ios version,
um, I’m gonna turn it over to
Whitney really quick. >>I’m
short, how does this work? Um,
Hi everyone, I’m Whitney
Champion, shortxstack, um I’ve
been doing the android version
of hacker tracker since 2012,
uh, so I um am a systems
engineer out of South Carolina.
Android is a hobby for me,
that’s why this guy is here now
(chuckle) um, but yeah thank you
guys for coming. >>Hey guys, I’m
Chris, uh also known as advice
dog. Ummm, I met Whitney at
DefCon 24 and started talking to
her about hacker tracker because
I liked using it but was like
I-I feel like it could be better
right? Um, and it was open
source so I was really excited
I’m like oh I can totally commit
to this you know I can change
things, um and I started talking
to her and she was totally cool
with me changing things so I
joined the team, started work
things and I took over def uh,
the android version for uh
hacker tracker eh, for 25 and
26, so the current version,
yeah. Uh I’ve done a tone of
rewrites. Pretty much its uh
whenever I’m board, I guess I
just look at hacker tracker and
I’m like ‘how could it be
better?’ Um, so any performance
you enjoy, I spent way too much
time on haha [laughter] >>Yes,
th-that is a running theme as we
spend too much time on it. I’ve
got my family here, they know,
like the last couple of weeks
especially, every spare moment
of my time has been alright can
I get this in so I can get it in
to the app store so we can
actually get it into the ios
version. Um, so the first thing
we’re going to talk about is
where it came from, I joined the
hacker tracker team or the IOS
version was uh started in about
2014, I think it was, something
like that right? So, it was a
couple of years after Whitney
did the first one, so we’ll let
her talk about what she came up
with and then we’ll move onto
you know when ios came and you
know how we’ve done things.
Alright so what happened was-
>>hehe what had happened was um,
so I wasn’t able to go to DefCon
in 2012, um I’ve been coming
since 2009, and I was really
bummed that I couldn’t be there
that year, sooo I wanted to give
back in someway so I wanted to
contribute um, I was pregnant
and couldn’t leave, so I spent
probably 2 months pretty much
pouring my heart into the f-what
was the first version of
Android, which is what you see
here, which is- don’t knock the
awesome photoshop skills, I
know, it’s just mind blowing,
but,that if, if you came the
first uh first version was like
2012, 2013 and that is what it
looked like, um it’s just
beautiful. Um, so that was the
first 4 years and like Seth
said, he joined a couple of
years later and did the ios
version. >>The ios version,
you’ll notice that the you know
all the, the margins are off and
things like that, we had a lot
to learn about how to actually
put this together, um again you
know awesome photoshop skills.
As you can see, nowadays we’ve
got actual designers that work
with us a little bit, uh we’ll
get into that um, a bit later,
but the first ios version, I
think the version that made it
through the app store that most
of the attendees downloaded
actually crashed for the first
two days of the conference right
it was not necessarily in my
case a successful effort. I
remember being pretty
disappointed that I couldn’t
push through the version that I
wanted people to have. Um, and
that's, traditionally that’s
what happens to us, we-we have
these ideas, Chris pushes
something, we talk about it, we
put it into the app and then
whether or not it actually makes
it out to you is another story.
Um, that being said, we’ve had a
lot of great feedback. So, we’ll
step into some of that here,
here in a f- um here in a
minute. Now, it’s official
right? This makes us happy, uh
DefCon actually brought us on
board, uh when was that >>It was
right after you joined >>20, so
it was what 2015 2016, yeah.
2016 I think it was the first
year that hacker tracker was the
official app of DefCon. Um, And
now, actually uh, Chris and I
are members of the info booth
team, uh so we are related to
the guys that you’re seeing
sitting around in the booths
telling you about maps and other
things. We’re working with them
closely, uh mellows helped us
out, uh immensely to actually
get events and get them into the
application um, but we are the
official application for DefCon,
obviously, that’s why we’re
here, that’s why the promote it
at each of those info booths,
it’s so that you have this
information at the palm of your
hands. I mean part of the reason
that I wanted to do it initially
was the fact that I-I had the
booklet and it just wasn’t
tenable, I had my phone with me
as well and I got involved
because I wanted to be able to
track all of these different
events and actually do
something. I saw that Whitney
had the android version and
thought yeah we can do that on
ios as well. Pain points, now
there are a lot of pain points.
Um, first off is scheduling, you
wanna talk about this? >>Yeah,
so, scheduling for the first
like 3 what, well actually until
this year when, so Seth’ll uh
get into his part of this after
I talk about how difficult hand
jamming thousands of lines of
json was for the first several
years. Um, it was mind numbing
haha the other part was all the
villages, all the um like
contest, all the events all the
talks, everything was in a
different format so there was no
like easy way to go scrape every
website, there was no easy way
to get all the data, it was very
much a manual process. So, I
don’t know how many hundreds of
hours we spent staring at these
files, but my God I’m glad that
those days are over. Um,
especially this year there’s
what like 28 villages, something
like that and every single one
has a different format, so
hopefully that will ease up um
going forward. >>So, if, yeah,
if you-if you’ve never
handwritten json files and made
sure that the modified date is
changed at 2 am, you just
haven’t experienced joy, right?
>>right >>that’s i-it’s really
easy to do and really easy to
mess up, and then the
application crashes. Or if your
dealing with the ios you know
json parser and happen to have
an errant you know uh, new line
character inside of a string,
you wanna know what happens to
ios? Yeah, it crashes right, so
there’s all of these pain points
that we’ve dealt with with the
schedule. Uh, now the-the next
one is you know, don’t trust the
hackers. Um, the first well, I
mean as soon as I got involved
we started advertising out on
twitter hey guess what we’ve got
this app that we built for
DefCon, how many people do you
actually think downloaded the
app that first year, guesses?
Five? There’s some trusting
people, there’s more trusting
people out there than that. But,
our-our biggest response on
twitter was exactly this, “No,
no, no there’s no way I’m
downloading that”- >>yeah
>>right? You know. “You guys are
shady” >>It doesn’t matter that
the source code was all out
there they were like “Who are
you nerds putting out this app?”
Especially for the android
version cause you know th-that’s
just kind of a free for all but
they’re like “there’s rootkits
don’t do it, they’re gonna take
your data they’re gonna steal
your pictures, don’t install any
of it” so- >>So the answer is
yes we have all your data
>>right >>Let’s just get that
out of the way we’ll move on
>>You weren’t supposed to say
that >>sorry, uhhhh. Okay the
other thing is bug fixes at all
hours. Um, how many people here
are like uh ios developers that
push things into the app store?
We’ve got a couple of you >>7
>>I feel your pain, um how easy
is it to actually push bug fixes
into the app store quickly?
Easy? No, it’s very difficult
right? Um, and we’ll get into
this in a little bit but you
know this was realistically our
lives over especially the month
before DefCon,okay, is the bug
fixes and when it actually has
to happen. >>See, I had the
luxury of being able to blast
anything to production at 3
o’clock in the morning after 6
shots and who knows what’s gonna
happen so, that was-that was the
toss up between android and
apple for us. >>yeah >>Seth had
a little more uh, validation on
his end. >>I did, and it’s about
finding time, I mean obviously
we’ve got normal jobs right? I
guess, kind of normal jobs.
“Normal jobs”, um and so
actually finding the time to put
this together, it’s not
necessarily something that just
happens in one afternoon as much
as we would like to think we’re
great developers, there’s always
bugs, there’s always things that
uh, that- >>This doesn’t happen
in the afternoon >>No, it just
doesn’t happen in an afternoon,
it happens, at 3 AM when you
push directly to master, that’s
when it happens. >>after the
kids go to sleep >>Yeah,
alright, waiting on redacted.
Anybody seen like the-the mobile
operating system? In the ios
version? Yes, why do you think
that is? Okay, this is the app
review process. K, we get random
people that are looking at the
application and I have marked
the app it was explicit,but you
wanna know what uh okay, so, so
it’s okay for in the app for us
to say D**n and H**l and SH**
and everything else, but you
know what I can’t say?
Jailbreak. I can’t say that,
that’s not okay. Um, so last
year especially this became a
huge issue, I’ve had i-it’s-I
I’ve had, I just got rejected
you know 3 days ago again you
know on the latest version that
I wanted you guys to have in
your hand for ios. Because it
says hack and it says uh you
know there’s other things that
are in there that whoever it is
that’s in the app review process
looking at the application
actually thinks its hey you’re
promoting hacking, there’s like
the whole apple terms of service
and like we’re doing our best is
realistically what it is and
we’re coming up with ways to
actually get around this. So,
the redacted in their that
you’re seeing is because we,
yeah we’ve just learned if we do
that, if we take out the term
watchos, or take out the term
macos that they accept it. Uh,
but if we don’t and it happens
to be in somebody’s talk, they
won’t right. So,I feel really
bad for the speakers whose title
of their talk is breaking macos
or something like that cause
it’s you know redacteding
redacted os. [laughter] sorry,
that’s-that’s all I can do I um
we’re doing our best. Okay so
last year we did a big overhaul
um and even this year you’ll
notice it’s a lot different than
those images that we put up
there first. I’ll let uh Chris
talk to the android version
first. >> uh, sure so DefCon 25
was the first version that I
came onto it. So, I did a ton of
different changes and all that
stuff, so, pretty much from the
ground up I rebuilt the app um
probably multiple times over the
year just cause I’ve got a lot
of free time. Um but like a lot
of the focus is just trying to
figure out exactly how we can
make a, like a hacker conference
good in terms of schedule. Cause
we don’t really know-there’s
guidelines I guess out there of
what we could do and what we
can’t do, but we’re trying to
figure out exactly what kind of
information you need and like
what you want and everything
like that, so we’re also trying
to do a lot of stuff. It’s like
everything from the ground up,
rebuild it and make it
impressive you know from like,
and like I’ve rebuilt it
multiple times also for DefCon
26. Um, for like las- example,
for last year uh hacker tracker
on android was what 19
megabytes, this year it’s about
4 point 2. Uh, it is insanely
small, it should be the fastest,
smallest app on your phone,
hopefully, uh and that’s pretty
much what I’ve been doing is
just trying to make the best app
for you guys you know? Cause I
found if I hate it, then you’re
probably going to hate it, you
know, if it bugs me, it might
bug you, but it’ll probably bug
you eventually. >>yeah so the
whole idea is that we want it to
bug you right? Like I-I I even
just saw a bug pop up on my
phone on the reminders for ios
that’s yeah, um but last year we
did a pretty extensive overhaul
of ios as well, um, we’ve got
the animations that are in there
if you seen like the little
jitter as it starts up, that’s
us stealing, I mean that’s us
just animating the initial
screen that your on [laughter]
right there it’s not sending
data anywhere right um, but
along those lines we’ve upgraded
right, we don’t support ios 9
anymore like I may try and push
a version out there, especially
for those of you that have
burner phones that have decided
that we’re all going to hack you
because you’re here. Um, yeah,
so we may support that in the
future, I’ll do some downgrades
to make sure we can actually
support some of those older
versions of ios, uh but that is
kind of a forward looking thing.
When I tried to compile it
initially I got a whole bunch of
error messages for ios 9 and so
I scrapped it right, there’s
only so much time in the day.
Um, the other thing that we did
last year was the ui redesign we
actually engaged with a graphic
designer um, Chris Mays who may
be here somewhere in the room?
Chris are you here? Alright, I
don’t see him. Chris uh actually
uh worked for a company last
year and their graphic designer
was willing to chip in um and
help us actually do some of the
ui designs so a lot of the
elements that make it look a
little bit more polished came
from her, uh that was Megan,
she’s listed in the ios app um
and it has made things more
streamlined, it’s made it so
it’s easier to actually use and
navigate. The one thing that we
did away with this year was the
uh, tab bar down at the bottom,
for ios, we moved to the menu so
that we’re trying to get more of
a unified look and feel. Um, the
other thing is we do support
multiple conferences. Has
anybody used hacker tracker at a
different conference? No? Oh we
got a couple, ok, yeah, it their
nowhere near as big as DefCon,
DefCon is definitely our primary
conference, uh but we support uh
ShoCon, TourCon, we did
HackWest, we did a couple bsides
events during the year. If you
would like to use hacker tracker
at other conferences, just hit
us up on twitter it’s not
difficult we’ve structured the
app so that we can load
different conferences in there
and make it easier to use and a
community resource. The whole
idea is the codes out there, it
can be reused these other
conferences could compile it but
we have the ability to actually
switch and use it within the
same interface, okay. Alright,
so high points- >>So, I think
one of the most fun parts over
the last few years um, that
we’ve had is hiding Easter eggs
in the app, so uh, several
people have come to me to hide
things for different contests um
specifically the DC darknet
challenge, that’s been one of my
favorites because we’ve done
that probably 3-3 years now. One
year I hid a password in the app
and a bunch of you came to me to
get the most ridiculously dumb
unicorn sticker and I don’t know
why any of you took the time to
come find it because it’s
horrible, but there it is. Um,
Seth uh, went to the trouble of
making stickers and hiding
things in the ios version as
well, so it’s, it’s been a lot
of fun to like engage everybody
and try to do whatever we can to
get other contests and events
involved. This has been
especially interesting, um we’ve
gotten good attendee feedback,
we’ve gotten bad attendee
feedback, and we’ve gotten weird
attendee feedback. But the good
attendee feedback has been by
and large the best. Um,
especially since Chris joined
and then put in a lot of work,
um I don’t have nearly as much
anymore to-to contribute so he’s
done a huge uh, it’s been a huge
effort on his part um to make it
as awesome as possible for you
guys on his end and so with
Seth, so the reviews that you
guys have given us are just
amazing and especially like the
ideas you’ve come back with,
like feature request, bug fixes,
bug reports, like all of that
stuff has been amazing. So just
like keep sending that because
it helps us and it helps us make
it better. >>yeah just one thing
okay if you if you review us 4
stars and say some schedule
items are wrong just hit us on
twitter please [laughter] don’t
don’t ruin our rating, we’re
trying, you know hit us up on
twitter we’ll fix it immediately
>>scheduling is hard
>>[indiscernible] eventually.
Cause all the negative feedback,
I get an email, I read it, I get
depressed, it’s not great.
[laughter] people might feel
like it is but it’s >>don’t make
Chris cry >>don’t make Chris cry
[laughter] >>This is probably my
favorite email I’ve gotten so
far. Um, there’ve been a lot of
worse ones but this is
definitely the-the best “My
email has been hacked. When I
reply to certain people it tells
me that it came back unreadable
with crazy text covering up my
info.” But bottom line, the last
part is the best, “If it does,
will it report the hacker to the
police?” [laughter] Nooo
[laughter] umm it will not, I
never heard back from this guy,
um, I also did not respond.
[laughter] So, ha, so I mean I
thought about it but he says
I’ve been having issues with
cyber stalking so I a- I decided
to avoid that. >> yeah so, uh
like we were saying last year
uh, Chris took over the android
version, Chris Mays has helped
me immensely on the ios version
he’s like a full time ios
developer he’s on he’s in the
app if you if you see his name
you know click on it give him
kudos as well because he’s been
a huge help in actually
debugging and making sure that
the app runs expectedly it
doesn’t crash. Um, you know a
lot of good just kind of overall
design patterns and things like
that have come from his brain.
Um, I was hoping he was here so
we could you know recognize him
a little bit but that’s fine.
But otherwise, right, just
getting feedback from you has
been the best thing. If you use
the app and there’s something
that bugs you like Chris said,
let us know, tell us about it.
If you haven’t downloaded the
app go download the app and use
it. Make sure and update the
events because it is being
updated every yeah, pull-pull to
pull down to update because
that’ll actually get you the
latest results and the latest uh
events that are going on and
what’s going on right now. Um,
but let us know if those are
wrong, and also if there’s
something in the app that is an
issue. Especially if the app
crashes. So we’ve got a whole
bunch of lessons learned, right?
Um, first of all haters gonna
hate. >>Yeah, so some of you are
mean.[laughter] just saying ha.
Um, the first couple of years or
the first 4 years um, at least
from my end was soloing this
which means like a lot of late
nights staring at this and then
I’d get on the reviews page and
I’m like holy S**t, you people
can be evil but we already know
this cause we’re on twitter
we’ve seen the worst of the
internet but, um, uh, I think it
definitely garnishes some thick
skin over the years. Um, so yeah
the 3 of us have poured a lot
into this and we’ve realized
that you can’t please everybody,
so the best we can do is just
try to make it as good as we can
for all of you guys, but I will
say it has been highly
entertaining reading some of the
stuff that we’ve gotten over the
past what 6 years. Yeah, I don’t
know what you’ve got on your
end. >>Oh, all the ios
developers, they’re totally
trustworthy and nice. [laughter]
um, the other thing we’ve
learned is like taking feedback
right? Obviously twitter is a
great way to do this, um you can
hit us up that’s why our handles
are there in the applications,
but aside from that if you hit
us up on github that’s where
we’re actually tracking the
code, uh you put in a pole
request or you put in an issue
uh we will track it in there and
close it out so that you know
that that we’ve looked at it and
we’ve done something with it
right? >>Yep. >>um we do have to
wait >>you have to wait >>I have
to wait, I have to wait. Like I
said there’s a version that’s
out there that’s hopefully going
to be released soon, uh I get
denied on expedite requests um
I’m waiting on jailbreaks,
whatever. Right um, you know the
other thing I was thinking was
that we could push it to like
cydia,uh the you know the
jailbreak store. Uh is anybody
here using a jailbroken device?
Even as a burner? So, I mean if
there’s enough of you that are
doing it then I’ll look into it
and we’ll push it that
direction. Because, it would be
a lot easier for me to be, to
push in there for soric then it
is to actually push into the app
store.I Just I’m not sure if
apple is going to be too happy
about that, you never know.
Backup plans, you have to have
backup plans right? >>I think,
we’ve kinda learned that we
don’t have a solid back up plan
yet. [laughter] Um, so, we’ve we
tried various different ways of
scheduling and this actually
ties into what you built over
the last I don’t know however
long you’ve been working on the
uh on your event manager so uh
we’ve tried pulling from the
info booth, we’ve tried static
json so we’ve kinda tried to
combine the two of those and
have some like main dashboard
for um loading all of the events
in because it’s just gotten so
big and so many villages and so
many pieces of this we’ve we’ve
gotta streamline it somewhere.
>>Yeah, guesses on how many
events we have in the hacker in
hacker tracker this year? [all
of them] all of them ha I wish
but I don’t think we’ve gotten
there. >>probably not >>how many
did you say? >>150 >>ok keep
going up >>250 >>keep going up
probably around 800 right now
that you can actually do and
that’s between parties, events
and all the different talks,
contests. Um yeah especially the
villages we’re at 25 plus
villages this year. And each
village is basically it’s own
conference. Some of those
villages the con, like the
content that is there is bigger
than the other conferences that
we’ve been talking about. Uh, so
you know we’re trying to give
you ways to actually filter
things and actually you know do
searches, that’s where you're
going to have to become familiar
with to actually get that data
back. Okay so going forward,
first of all we-we want it to be
more streamlined, the whole
process from the feedback to you
to us actually getting the
features out. Um the ios android
parody, to make sure they look
somewhat similar so that the
experience on both is the same.
Now that is difficult based on
the design patterns from android
or from google versus the design
patterns from apple. Um, but
there’s a lot of different apps
that do this we’re gonna, we’re
kind of creating our own look
and feel and we will be
maintaining that parody to some
extent right. Um, you guys want
to say anything else? The
scheduling application, like
Whitney said, we built a back
end to hacker tracker um and if
you can find it and insert an
event, kudos to you right? Um,
that’s a- that would be a
challenge but most likely you
won’t be able to figure out
where it’s at so it’s fine. Um,
it’s fine don’t worry about it
>>You just challenged the real
hackers >>I know I did, that was
stupid [laughter] um, I have
been here for too long. Yeah, so
the scheduling application is
going to make this a lot easier,
we are coordinating like I said
with the info booth uh next year
we’re probably going to take
over infodotdefcondotorg right
um, and so we’re hoping that
we’ll be able to bring that into
parody with what the app looks
like, it just depends on the
time. If you are interested and
have development skills and want
to jump in and help us out, let
us know, we’re always looking
for more people to help. I mean
how many hours did you spend
inputting- >>Yeah, if anybody
likes data entry [laughter] join
us. >>We need a mindless
factotum. >>Yes >>Who's out
there? You can’t leave until we
find one, come on. Um, more
conferences, like I said before,
if you’re attending a conference
and they don’t have a scheduling
application, let us know we’d be
happy to add that data to hacker
tracker to the back end and
actually push that out so that
it becomes more useful.
Realistically we want this as
the go to for not just DefCon
but for the community for the
wider security community or uh,
development community for that
matter. How many people have
used an a- did use the black hat
app this year? How awesome was
that? Yes that was great, yeah,
No, okay. Well that that's all
I’ll say on that. Feedback is
always welcome. Did you want to
say something? >>no, um so as
always like Seth said, feedback
is always welcome hit us up on
Github, hit us up on Twitter. If
you want to contribute, do so,
it’s all open source, it’s all
out there um, the three of us
are responsive pretty much all
of the time. So, if you want to
contribute please do we would
love to have you and we would
love the help. Yeah >>Ok, it’s
open source, but please don’t be
too critical we’re on a time
crunch, things are messy we’ll
fix it up later, next year, next
will be better. Haha. [laughter]
>>Any Questions? I think we only
have a couple of minutes before
the Defcon 101 Panels coming in
here. Yeah? >>How often does it
refresh its data? >>whenever you
pull >>yeah uh on ios whatever
you pull on android there is a
>>should be 7 days could be 15
minutes I don’t know it’s mainly
how android handles work
manager, I specify 7 days but
it’ll kinda hopefully if you’re
on wifi it’s like oh I’ll do it
now or whatever. >>but you can
also do it manually, so >>yes
>>we’re we’re throwing in
updates like this whole week
it’s been pretty much hourly
that we’ve been adding events so
just refresh >>just swipe down,
when you go to that first event
screen just swipe down let it
refresh cause there’s other
stuff that's being added and
those dates change. We’re
getting told that we need to
leave the stage. So we’ve got 10
more questions before we’ll
leave [laughter]. No, no wait I
need the mindless factotum
first. Alright, well thank you
for using the application,
follow us on twitter leave us
feedback and I hope it’s useful,
that was the whole reason that
we built it is we wanted
something. So it works for us
but if it doesn’t work for you
it’s not as cool. So um, yeah
download, download us, download
it and let us know what you
think. Okay [applause]