>>So um, Joe really needs no
introduction, but how many
people are here for their first
time? Yeah, okay. So a little
bit of history. Uh back at
DefCon 14, there was kind of a a
big change, a big shift. First
DefCon moved to a real casino
and a real big hotel but then
also somebody came up with an
idea to do an electronic badge.
Uh you can blame this guy for
all of the blinking and the
smashing and the crashing that’s
all on your chest. So let’s give
uh Joe Grand a big round of
applause. [Applause] >>Thank
you. >>Have a good time man.
>>Cool, thank you. So yeah, I
officially retired making badges
at DefCon 18 and we didn't know
what to expect so it’s come
quite a ways. So alright, I like
to move around a lot so I’m
going to switch between these
two mics because I can’t sit
still. And this is so exciting
to me that it’s hard to stay in
one spot. Um yeah, so I’m Joe
Grand. We’re gonna talk today
about a project called OpticSpy.
And OpticSpy is a device that
lets you receive data
transmitted over light waves.
And I’ll go into the history of
why this is so exciting to me
because it’s not you know a
typical kind of security thing
but it actually is. So quick
little background um I’ve been
involved with electronics since
I was 7 years old, 1982. Figured
out how to make my first free
phone call when I was 10. Just
loved ma-making mis-mischievous
devices of of different kinds.
Um and that’s when I realized,
oh you can build whatever you
want, if you think of something,
you can build it. Um and a lot
of what I end up building
nowadays are open source
projects for other people to use
as building blocks to create
their own projects. Um and
that’s, you know that’s more
exciting to sort of see what
other people do with your stuff.
So that’s been fun uh on the
engineering side of things. Uh
but yeah I worked on a bunch, a
bunch of different stuff along
the way. Um got in trouble when
I was younger and that sort of
redirected my passion towards
like oh I can share. I can share
stuff and maybe not break into
buildings and computers and
stuff and and do things in a
legi - legitimate way so that’s
that’s really what got me
involved in DefCon even though I
sort of you know known about
that world I’d been in that
world before that. Um I’m gonna
switch to this one, hold on.
Alright anyone who knows me
knows this is really hard to-to
do. So I’ll move this one out of
the way and no wireless mics at
DefCon, which is probably a good
idea. So anyway this project
OpticSpy, um again I’ll go into
the history but it’s a device
that I just thought would be
really cool to just let people
explore a different sort of um
uh thi-thing about electronics
and about hardware. Oh is this a
longer one? Awesome. Hello,
check. Is this one on? Oh -
okay, not as loud-oh, look at
that so I have three microphones
now. This is even better. Now I
should have someone following me
with like boom mic or something,
alight. So there’s a bunch of
wires up here. So yeah, Optic
Spy's a project that will
convert light into voltage. An
open source project, I’ll go
into like the details of it. Um
but uh the whole research into
this really started with
something called Covert
Channels. And Covert Channels
are methods of communicating in
ways that are secret. And that
might be a one-way transmission
from a computer system uh to the
uh outside world saying you’re
trying to exfiltrate data. You
know we see that a lot on the
network side. Uh you know where
someone breaks into a computer
and just infiltrates 50 gigs of
data and nobody in the IT
department or security
department notices. Um but
that’s sort of an old way of
like doing it, you can do it
using the network. I’m more
interested in like what can you
do if you compromise the system
uh somewhere along the way. How
can that then be used to
exfiltrate data in a non
standard way? So using um other
sorts of the environmental
conditions. And to implement a-a
covert channel, uh there’s a lot
of different ways. Uh if you
have network access to a device,
if you have physical access to a
device, somewhere along the
supply chain you could load this
code in, you can change the
design. Uh a lot of times
products, especially since we’re
dealing with visible LEDs on
products, almost every product
has visible LEDs anyway. So if
you can compromise a device and
you’re just changing the
twideling of the IO pins to now
send data instead of appearing
instead of just being on. And
the data, the lights still gonna
still appear to be solid so
there’s lots of stuff you can do
along the way whether you know
it’s changing modifications or
modifying the physical device.
Maybe intercepting a device as
it’s going from the factory
going to the end customer. I
know our government’s been
really good at doing stuff like
that uh and then they complain
when they discover other
nation’s states doing the same
thing. Uh but it this is not you
know this is not a theoretical
sort of thing. You know, like
implanting malicious code,
malicious functionality, covert
channels, um is real and that’s
what got me really excited about
it. So different types of ways
to exfiltrate data. Um there’s
been a lot of work in this area,
uh whether it’s changing kind of
optical or changing uh RF
characteristics through
electromagnetic interference. Um
patterns from a computer system.
So tempest monitoring from back
in the day where the CRT um was
emanating a whole bunch of
different high voltage and noise
and spikes like as the, as the,
as the raster went across the
screen uh you could pick that
from far away. Even before then
like spark-spark gap
transmitters. I don’t remember
when, I think maybe World War
One. You know Morse
Communication over Spark Gap. Um
transmitters were generating
huge amounts of noise, and
everybody else could listen in
so maybe not exactly a Covert
Channel but it is an
unintentional sort of you know,
emission. Um you can do things
through thermal, through the
sound. Um Mordechai Guri gave a
great presentation as Black Hat
this year. He’s been doing
research of kind of Air-Gapped
data exfiltration techniques for
a long time. And he shows how
you can have two machines
separate and use Ultrasound to
communicate, which is actually
what advertisers do a lot of
times on television on
television sets. They’ll,
they’ll uh send Ultrasound on
them that we can’t hear but
you’ll mobile phone with an app
can hear and then they can track
what you’re watching and
everything. So there’s been a
lot of covert data communication
stuff going on. BUt the stuff
that really excited me are
Blinkenlights. Because everybody
likes Blinkenlights and they’re
on most products and uh I always
make this joke that nobody
laughs, um so hopefully you will
since this is being recorded. Is
I always say, that the more LEDs
there are on a product the more
secure people think it is.
[Laughter] Cool. That’s almost
like the can you know you press
the button and it’s like the
audience laughing. Um but it’s
true you know, people-people
take hardware for granted. They
- they don’t really understand
what’s going on behind the
scenes and if you have a device
that has lights, you can’t
really tell what’s going on. So
this project, that-that’s what
inspired me. The original paper
actually has information leakage
from Optical Emanations from
2002. I read that when it came
out and I was like this is so
cool ‘cause I’d been interested
in-in kind of Optical
Communications for awhile. You
know like I said I built
mischievous stuff as a kid, and
one of the things I built was in
7th grade was this laser
listener system where I guess an
attempt at a laser listener
system where I had a laser beam
uh sending shining on to a
window and then receiving that
reflection back from the window.
So as thewindow vibrated and
talking inside I could spy on
them which apparently the
government also does that. I was
using a visible red laser but
probably most governments are
using an infrared laser or
something you can’t see. Um so
it was neat when I read this
paper, I’m like wow this is
cool. And maybe at the time was
shocking but maybe not. What
they had discovered is a lot of
off the shelf devices without
even being modified or
compromised, were leaking
information through LEDs.As an
unintentional side effect or
artifact of the way that the
designers designed the product.
So I’ll show you a demonstration
of that later, one of them is
this Hey smart modem um from
back in the day that’s actually
leaking information on the
transmit and receive pins. So
you don’t have to have direct
connection in line with the data
you can just see it from the
LEDs. So I bought one of those
on EBay to demonstrate it
because I thought that was
really cool. And of course I
have a bunch of other demos to
show how easy it is to kinda-
kind of create your own. But the
point is that besides
intersec-inter inter in you know
um adding your own type of
interface, there might be
products out there even today
that are leaking information
through LEDs. Uh we have
wireless you know light
networking systems now and as
IOT gets bigger and network
connected things get bigger and
as the RF space gets more kind
of crowded, we’re gonna see more
kind of information being
transmitted over light from
light bulbs, from other things.
Mesh networking through light
bulbs, communicating with light.
Um and that’s something that’s
been going on for that past few
years so it is happening. And
all this stuff we can now you
know, with the with a piece of
hardware kind of listen in and
sniff around and see what’s
going on. With a lot of this
work though, I found is there
was never like a uh defined
here’s how to build a receiver
that you can actually experiment
with this stuff and I was like
Well I want to build a receiver
because that’s what I do. I
wanna actually try it. Like
reading the papers great but
doing it is better, and that’s
really where OpticSpy came from.
So yeah, a little history,
there’s been a lot of work with
transmitting information over
lightwaves um definitely not
gonna claim I’m the first. And I
always say that we’re standing
on the shoulders of giants and
we’re building- we’re taking
little steps, right? And you’re
seeing what somebody else has
done and you’re improving it or
modifying it uh to do something
different and-and this is the
same thing. So you know, Graham
Bell had the Photophone back in
1880, I’m not gonna do the math
in my head but it was what like
a 100 and 30 something years
ago? And uh he was using the sun
the reflection of the sun off a
mirror to modulate light and
then somewhere down the way uh
that modulated light would be
captured and replicated back
into- into voice. But the
problem was it was it was very
weather specific, so it didn’t
work on cloudy days. And people
thought that was sort of lame uh
so they decided to use the
telephone instead. But he had
actually says that the
Photophone is more important to
him than anything else that he
had done. Um Fiber Optics have
been around for a long time. You
know, were basically doing the
same thing, where-where we have
a light, and we’re modulating
and were sending data on it but
it’s been around for a long
time. Uh laser tag, everyone
like laser tag? Yeah. A few
people. I think it’s pretty
cool. Um did anyone have the
Star Trek laser tag from 1979?
Yeah, you guys are all too
young.Um this is a system that
actually the-the way that laser
tag works is it’s actually
sending data, infrared data so
it can receive data and know you
know who’s shooting and who’s
being-being hit. Um so it’s not
just a light, there’s actually
data in it. And then like I
mentioned, Optical Networking
Systems, started in 2011 but
they’re coming more popular now
and it really is something
where, it’s just another kind of
medium where data’s being
transmitted, right so we know
it's’ network and wireless and
now it’s optical. Uh and perhaps
the other things. Lots of more
other projects also as well. I
have more resources at the end
of the slides. Um Craig Heffner
gave a talk a few years ago at
DefCon that was a infrared
receiver specifically for um it
was a high gain infrared
receiver for looking at things
you know output from mobile
phones um proximity sensors and
things like that, and I’ll show
you uh there-there’s many
difference with OpticSpy uh
mainly that it will work with
visible light but and on and
also tunable but there’s been
you know people working on this
for awhile in-in
different-different ways. So the
goal like with most of my
projects is have something
that’s easy to understand
theory. So the, the sort of
Optical Receive Chain, is very
kind of simplistic and you’ll
see what I mean as we go through
it. So it’s something that’s you
know not this super complicated
voodoo that um you know kind of
black magic sort of thing, it’s
like a very simple thing you can
mess around with. Uh and
solderable, using off the shelf
components. And uh I know, some
of them are small, um but you
can’t really avoid that because
sometimes they don’t make them
in big sizes. Uh but
everything’s hand solderable.
And again this whole project
comes down to raising awareness
of-of their communication
methods getting more people
involved in hardware, and for me
it was a great experience with
working with analog electronics.
Because the receivers have no
microcontroller on them, no you
know intelligence, it’s doing
everything analog and I
typically stay on the digital
design side of things ‘cause
that’s where I’m most
comfortable. So this is a good-
a good example of sort of
experimenting with amplifiers
and comparators and things like
that. So just some early
versions, I like showing
pictures of this stuff. If
you’re getting into hardware
development, this is a typical
process where you start with
some sort of bread board system
in the upper left uh where you
can and the upper right, where
you can plug components in and
out and sort of fine tune things
before you go design a circuit
board. Even though nowadays with
places like Hodge Park, where
you pay 5 dollars a square inch,
it’s almost you know some people
just go straight to a circuit
board because you could just
re-revise it and iterate so
quickly but i love having
that-that chance to you know
plug things in. There’s a few
other variations of the board,
all the stuff is available on
the website, these different
variations. The first one in the
lower left is a digital receiver
and that’s just using a toslink
type of optical receiver module
that’s for like SPDif audio on
receivers and and you know
stereo equipment. And that’s
designed to just receive red
light and it has to be certain
brightness and it has to be NRZ
encoded, which I’ll talk about,
which actually Optic Spy is
similar. Uh so very simple
receiver but there’s like a
little in the uh uh in in the
little receiver module, that
black thing, there’s a little
door and you have to shove the
light into that door otherwise
you’re not gonna be able to see
it so it’s a little more
intrusive to whatever you’re
doing. But that was the first
one I built to kind of prove the
concept but then I went to an
analog version which is
ultimately what this one turned
into and that has some
potentiometers to let you adjust
the gain and threshold and
really fine tune for particular
type of target. And another
thing too that’s sort of funny
is I originally, ended the
project on the lower- the lower,
the final version of the lower
right, so that’s a prototype of
what ultimately was like a kit
version that had potentiometers
and like a square and you needed
a little FTDI USB-C to serial
adapter to power it. And I had
been using that in some classes
and workshops and stuff and that
was sort of the end of it but
then I ended up meeting with my
friend Josh who runs Crowd
Supply, who specializes it kind
of you know open source
hardware, providing open source
hardware to the masses. And he
saw it a little bit ahead uh and
he was like you should make an
easy to connect up module so
people can just use this to
experiment with and we can like
hide secret messages in things
at our conference and stuff. He
was putting on a conference, so
he sort of had this vision a
little bit ahead, where I was
already done I was like alright
whatever, but he was right. So
it turned into like this
streamlined version um that did
make it a lot more easy to kind
of look around for stuff which
was sort of fun. And again all
of that stuff is online and you
can build your own. So some
development process, you know
there’s always going to be
problems. So the first version I
came back with, I was an FT231X
for the USB Serial adapter
instead of the the typical FT
232 which is what most people
use. so it was like the lower
cost version of the FTDI part,
but newer. And some of the pins
were a little bit different so I
ended up and you see i the uh um
upper left, there’s some blue
wires, really small blue wires,
I had to reroute some stuff
before I went to the production
version. UIm but you know,
typical sort of testing before
you go to production is is
highly recommended. Um this one
I decided, so I had a hand built
the first one to make sure it
had worked and then you see in
the lower left, I was actually
screening solder paste onto the
board because hand soldering
surface mount parts uh tends to
not look as good, as like you
know you put it through a reflow
oven and you have maybe
professional or
semi-professional assembly. So I
wanted to have one that would
that I would be able take nice
pictures of and that’s what I
used the silk screens for um
with the with the solder paste.
And that screen you can actually
get. So the boards, they’re
purple, they were made by
OshPark and then there’s a
company called Osh Stencils,
that will make the sold-make the
stencil for you that matches
your paste layer for your
circuit board and you could just
get solder paste and kind of
sqeegee it on yourself and make
your own. So it’s sort of like
do it yourself production
manufacturing. Um which
sometimes is easier than hand
soldering depending on how small
your parts are. So here’s the
block diagram, um we have our
photodiode which is the receiver
that’s gonna convert the uh the
lightwaves into current. And
then we have some amplifiers
that are going to amplify 2
stages that i’ll talk, I’ll talk
about all of these stages in
more detail. Adn the threshold
detector that turns the received
data into actual ones and zeros
and then passes that to a usb to
serial adapter that is gonna
then connect to your computer
and make it easy to decode
stuff. BUt you know not-not too
complicated which is-which is
what I like. Here’s a visual
view of the, of the board.
Points of interest. And the way
the board works, if you start at
the left at the photodiode,
that’s sort of the received
chain. It just you know the
light comes in the photodiode
and gets processed and goes out
the usb port on the other side.
And it’s just uh I just like
that process, and there’s
different test points along the
way. So you can check it at
different stages, like how’s
your recieve going. Um
especially in the case of if
you’re dealing with signals that
are not NRZ encoded, non-return
to zero, which again I’ll talk
about in a second. If-if there’s
somebody that is intentionally
creating an optical covert
channel, it doesn't want to be
detected, they’ll probably
create some custom modulation
scheme or maybe they’ll put in
some error checking, or other
sorts of things. Um so if it’s
not NRZ, the usb to serial
adapter isn't going to be able
to process it and show you on
the terminal program. So you can
tap on at a test point right
before it goes to the USB to
serial adapter and then connect
that up to your logic analyzer,
your oscilloscope, your arduino,
whatever it is to demodulate
whatever modulation scheme it
is. You might need to do some
reverse engineering but it’s
generally you know, there’s ways
to break it out if you have some
custom thing you're working on.
And then to demodulate, you
might need to do some reverse
engineering. I’m not going to
explain the whole schematic
here, ‘cause it’s you probably
can’t even see it. UIm but you
know it is, very sort of simple
clean design. So here’s the
Photodiode. Most systems that I
saw for receiving light and um
especially photodiodes are
designed to receive infrared
light only. Uh so you know we
have infrared remote controls
and a lot of other things that
are running infrared, this
particular photodiode mimics the
sensitivity of the human eye.
Which makes it a lot different
than other ones, which is
probably why they charge so much
for it. [Laughs] I think it’s
like 11 dollars a piece of
something but totally worth it
because now you can capture
visible light. And that’s how
most status indicators are
products are, they’re visible
light. Um so it’s really pretty
cool. And we’re running it in a
photoconductive mode reverse
bias um and current flows
through uh when we receive
lightwaves that’s gonna be
proportional, current flow and
then we have a load resistor
there that’s acting as-as our as
our gain and we can adjust that
with a potentiometer which ends
up being our first-first stage
gain which is a very-very small
compared to what comes next. And
then we have our ampli-
amplification stage, that’s the
light comes in. We have two
basically the same amplifiers um
in a row and the reason to have
two instead of one. Is if you're
amplifying a small signal a lot,
you;re gonna end up amplifying a
lot more noise with it at the
beginning. So if you do smaller
amplification, you can amplify
it a little bit and then you get
more signal less noise and then
you do it again more signal less
noise. So it’s uh it’s a little
trick to uh give you a less
overall noise. And there’s
potentiometers o both stages of
those gains so you can have a
pretty giant range of gains if
you need to. Generally, the-the
way the systems set up, the
default values uh are gonna be
pretty good for just about any
general purpose for any
investigations you’re doing. And
there are some-some capacitors
and some other things in between
the stages, to help with-with uh
sort of we have compacive
coupling in there to-to get rid
of the DC offset on the first
stage and that brings it down
but you run into problems with
[laughs] with um relaxation that
you then need to deal with. So
I’ll show the the screenshot of
what that looks like and what
these things and what these
things do but the whole point is
we're trying to get the data,
we’re trying to get the light in
and then get it to a point that
ends up being a 023 point 2 3
volts signal. So you have to do
some extra analog stuff to bring
it down. So once we have this
amplified stage, it should
hopefully look pretty close to
digital data by then, but then
we have this comparator which is
our threshold that we set that
with a - with a potentiometer
and that’s going to set the
state of whatever’s above that
threshold becomes a logic level
one. Whatever’s below that
zero. And now we have digital
data. And it’s hard to see on
the slides but TP TP5 on the
crowd supply version is the
output stage before it goes to
USB to serial adapter. So that's
where you can tap on if it’s an
unknown modulation scheme. And
then the USB interface, this is
going to power the device. And
also give us that virtual
comport on our computer so it's
just a much simpler thing than
having extra wires and
everything. So it’s like just
this.Right? Data goes light goes
in one side and data goes out
the other.Power goes in the same
thing. Uh this FT231X is a great
part. I know a lot of people
don't like FTDI anymore because
of the FTDI gate that happened
when they uh bricked all
counterfeit devices which ended
up being many more than they
anticipated because the chip was
the FT232 was so popular that it
ended up being counterfeited in
the counterfeits ended up being
in legitimate supply chains. SO
even if people thought they were
buying a legitimate one, they
were buying counterfeits and
when they updating the driver,
it was a big deal. [Laughs] So a
lot of people protested and
don’t use them but I still like
their devices and assuming I
don’t get bricked. If I get
bricked im gonna come up here
again and-and yell and rant. So
yeah, that’s sort of the
different stages to the
electronics design. Here’s what
the circuit board looks like.
Um, I made it a kind of pen
shaped for a few reasons. One of
them is I thought it-it would be
easier to hold than like the
earlier rectangle ones, sort of
like a pencil. Uh the other
thing is I originally tried to
fit it inside of the inside of a
standard whiteboard marker
because that would have been
pretty cool. Because then you
have the diode sticking out the
end. The width of the white
board marker, the internal well
the internal diameter of the
whiteboard marker was just
slightly too small compared to
the width of this. And I could
have made everything smaller and
that would reduce the likelihood
of people being able to hand
solder it so you have that trade
off. So it barely fits. You
might be able to maybe sort of
mill out or use a lathe or
whatever to carve out some space
inside a white board marker um
to fit it in. The other thing to
is that you'll see the range is
pretty limited, so you have to
be, maybe a few inches away with
infrared but much closer a lot
of times with visible light. You
could adjust the gain and adjust
that a little bit but you’re
pretty close. So this is a nice
size that you could maybe put
inside of a rifle scope or use
some other optics and fit it
inside-inside of some other
optical thing to amplify the
light from further away and get
a better get a better you know
get a better capture. Plus it
looks cool. Um, on the on the
back side there’s test points
and those are the ones that you
can see each stage but they’re
labeled you know with real words
so you can actually look at it
quickly. And I do this all the
time,I’m like what, I wanna look
at the second stage it's like
just like which one is that? Oh
yeah, TP3 so,it’s just an easier
thing instead of having to look
at your computer or schematic or
something. So Bill of Materials,
there’s a handle of parts. Um,
they end up being about 40
dollars for 100 pieces and the
photodiodes the most expensive,
actually yeah-yeah 12 dollars
single quantity, the Op AMPs
were 4 dollars. So you could
probably cost reduce this if you
wanted to but really that diode
I think is the key and those
amplifiers are-are really nice.
Um, low noise and uh I figured,
you know, keep with those. I
should mention too, this design
is actually based off of a
reference design that Maxim
Semiconductor made a really long
time ago and it’s been modified
since then and there should be a
link to it somewhere in the
slides. So yeah, those are sort
of the big ones, everything else
are called what like popcorn
components so you know the
discreates and other LEDs and
stuff are pretty cheap. But the
ones in red are the-are the
costly ones, but still if you’re
making one it’s not a big deal
right, it’s not like I’m mass
producing these or anything. So
that’s the receiver side, that’s
the OpticSpy side. For
transmitting, there’s lots of
different ways to control LEDs
and different drivers, and I’ll
show you some variations of
things, but generally a systems
gonna have something like this.
An IO pin is going to drive an
LED, it’s either going to be low
to turn on the LED or maybe it’s
gonna be driving from the high
side. But just a standard LED
driver circuit. And for the
demos, I was sort of, mimicking
like the original paper that I
had read, and these modems were
using NRZ data because that’s
how asynchronous serial data is
encoded for modems is non return
to zero. So I was just emulating
that and saying okay if I’m
gonna build demos, I’m just
gonna use the UR functionality
that exists are various
microcontrollers and just send
the data the same way, and we’ll
be able to capture it. So that’s
all my demos, it’s not limited
to that, right? Because we can
capture any sort of lightwave we
want of any modulation um as
long as the signals being sent
within our 100-100 hertz to 1
point 5 megahertz speed, we’ll
be able to capture it. It just
so happens NRZ this UR um
encoded data um is very common.
Asynchronous data. We see it on
products all over the place. So
that’s-that’s what I’m using to
transmit information. Here’s
what data stream looks like.So
ultimately you want to get to
this stage when you’re capturing
to have a nice looking you know
square wave there. And it it
literally is as easy to doing
like a printF function. If you
want to transmit data through an
LED and you have a standard LED
driver circuit, instead of
printF to a debug console or
outputter you know terminal, you
just do Printf and point it to
an IO pin. And now you’re
modulating and you’re sending
data over the IO pin. Or
over-over the yeah-yeah and then
over to the LED. And if your
speed is fast enough, then
you’re not gonna see it blink
and that’s like, I think that’s
the coolest part of the whole
thing. ‘Cause you’re gonna look
at it, you’re not gonna see it,
the human eye just doesn’t
respond that fast um to-to
motion like that so we’re gonna-
it’s gonna look like the LEDs on
and it’s gonna be sending data.
So different ways, there’s like
a pick uh example at the
beginning, Arduino down at the
bottom but yeah, you know Print.
Here’s the receiver side and
then I’ll show you some demos.
Um so first stage is still very
noisy. The signals in there
somewhere but it’s you know
really, really low down in some
of that noise. And that’s going
to be the first stage and that’s
going to be before it goes to
the amplifier. So that’s the
Photodiode um connected to the
resistor that generates voltage.
First stage output of the first
amplifier, is the signal, you
can actually see some-some data
on there but it’s up high and it
still has a little bit of noise
uh on the peaks. So then the
second stage is how you know we
have the capacitor in there and
some other discrete components
to bring the signal down and we
see some relaxation at the top
and bottom, that’s uh uh an
effect of the distance we are
away from the from the
transmitter but also because
some of the relaxation effects
from the capacitor is in there
as things are discarhing if the
signals too slow, that happens.
So we have to account for all of
that and generally what we have
is our threshold voltage by
default is set to 2 and a half
volts. Which looks like it’s a
pretty good level where that red
line is, anything above that is
gonna become a 1 and anything
below that is gonna become a 0.
Which seems to make, sems to
make sense. But depending on
which system you’re looking at
you might end up seeing-seeing
your data in a different way,
your voltage might be something
different. So you can tweak that
and adjust your-your threshold
voltage if you need to. It all
depends on what you’re
encountering thats transmitting
light. And here’s the-here’s the
ultimate sort of output of you
know, nice, NRZ encoded data.
And you can see down at the
bottom my oscilloscope is
encoded that data and it says
insert secret message here. So,
that’s what we wanna get to. And
then yeah, so calibration,
besides adjusting you know that
target voltage you might want to
increase the receive distance by
increasing the gain. Maybe you
want to reduce ambient noise, so
you’ll see up here, it’s pretty
bright, there’s some lights up
here. Um so we’re going to
receiving more noise than a
typical environment so I’ll
probably have to cover things
with my hand to reduce the
noise. So if I really wanted to
I could have my screw driver and
and reduce the noise with by
reducing the gain. Um but I’m
not going to do that live on
stage. And yeah, all of this
depends on the brightness of the
signal and the wavelength of the
signal so the-the-the-the type
of light. Um if it’s closer to
that center of that band, of
the- of the sensitivity of the
module, you’re gonna get much
better signal to noise than if
it’s like right on the edge. But
all you know, visible colors
I've worked with red, red blue
green yellow, like those all
work, white um all work fine.
And the potentiometers again are
for three stages of the gain
adjustment, two of the OP AMPs
and 1 at the the photodiode
stage and then the threshold.
Adjustment. Alright, let’s do
some demos. So for the demos,
I’m going to switch back between
my slides and my terminal
program. The first one I’m gonna
show is just using this Parallax
um hackable badge so this was
inspired, they had help build I
think it was the DefCon 20 and
onward for a few years the
badges for DefCon. Um so they
created sort of a general
purpose badge that you can hack
on. And this is uh using a
Parallax propeller processor for
those who know some previous
projects I’ve worked on. Um I
like this part. So this I’m just
gonna turn on, and you know
again a very simple proof of
concept, this is just a simple
microcontroller. Adn there’s a
little LED that or LCD on here
that’s says what message it’s
sending so I’m not going to show
you that because then it won’t
be very fun when you see it. And
there’s an infrared LED on here
so, we can visually see what’s
going on anyway. Um but I’ll
hold up the receiver and you can
see. So I’m gonna share the
screen. Yeah so you can see like
super noisy already because
there’s like light everywhere.
So I’m not gonna bother trying
to fine tune it. See if I can do
this while holding the
microphone. [Applause]
[Laughter] Yeah, hello DefCon 26
and everybody watching at home.
Um alright so let’s switch back.
And also the baud rate so I have
this set you know the bauds rate
usually with Asynchronous serial
data you-you need to pre agree.
The transmitter and the receiver
need to agree on the baud rate
beforehand. Or you can measure
the baud rate by looking at the
wave uh the wave form and figure
it out. Um but I have some
different baud rates set up
because different LEDs and
different systems um respond
differently, or they take more
time to start up and slow down.
So you can’t always use the
fastest but you could go way
faster than 9600 baud, which is
what I am showing here. So the
next one is another LED um
example. I wanted to show this
because it’s just a cool-cool
little device and it’s something
called Tomu. And um this is a
tiny little USB uh size like
literally the USB connector
sized. Little microcontroller
that has 12 compon-12 components
total. And it’s uh EMF32, it’s
an arm cortex M0 25 megahertz.
It has 8 K of ram, 64K of flash,
USB functionality built in and
2-2 color LEDS and 2 capacitive
touch buttons and it’s actually
you can see, that picture on the
right side it's shoved into
the-the side of the computer. So
this could actually be great for
like you know turn this into a
USB rubber ducky or some sort of
offensive red team tool or
something like that, where you
just plug into someone’s machine
and maybe they’re not gonna
know. Or if it's like a desktop
computer, you plug it in on the
back of the computer. But in
this case I’m just using item as
a way again to send information.
So we wrote a little program
that has an interactive mode, a
little menuing system that we
could just set and clear a
message and then the red LED on
Tomu is gonna turn on. So this
one’s a little more interactive
but this is a great example of
if you have a computer and you
want to optically isolate it
from other things or create your
own air gap this might still be
a way that you could send data
you know from a computer. So
this one, I am connected to
Tomu, on a-on a different
terminal program so my OpticSPy
is here and then Tomu’s here so
we can type a message in. Um,
alright hold on, I have to put
this down. So I typed a message
and now the red LED is on and I
have it plugged in to the right
side of my computer here. So I’m
just gonna, I’m essentially
connecting one serial port to
another serial port through
light. Um let’s switch over to
the terminal program side. And I
think I’ll put this down again.
Oh. I’m at 19 200 so I have to
change the baud rate here.
[Applause] Thanks, so this one
actually, this LED is much
brighter so I’m probably like 2
inches away or something like
that which is pretty cool. I
didn’t mention also, that the
there's a switch on here to
switch between polarities.
There’s a data inversion switch.
And because sometimes NRZ
encoded data or UR data is sent
idle high sometimes it’s sent
idle low and it sort of depends
on the driver um that’s
controlling it and how the
system is designed. So if it
doesn’t work in one way but you
see repeatable patterns you
might say oh that looks like
data. You flip the tog- you flip
the slide switch and it inverts
the signals and now it, now it
will work. Alright, so that’s
Tomu. Here’s a cool one. Lasers
right? Everyone likes lasers. Um
so this is another example of
just using a standard type of
optical interface where we know
we could do it with LEDs and I
have another LED example but
this one is fun because I have a
little laser diode drive module
that I made. And this laser
diode is an off the shelf diode
uh that has the internal APC and
other control stuff so you just
apply voltage to it and it's
gonna turn on. Really small, I
used these in a laser range
finder project from a few years
ago. Um so create-created a
little module that-that's open
source so everything's on my
website and then these circuit
boards are linked on the Osh
Park link um and that little
schematic is there. There’s a
little tiny voltage regulator
and that and then the uh system
powers goes through the voltage
regulator and connects to the
laser diode, and then the
enabled pin of the voltage
regulator is what we’re using to
modulate on and off. This one, I
had to slow it down, I’m at 4800
uh 4800 baud because any any
faster was too fast for this
particular diode to turn on and
actually start transmitting. Um
and any slower you would be able
to see if flicker a little bit
so this was a pretty good mid
range. And the cool thing about
diodes is they go really far so
this one in theory, I don’t even
remember how what I have on this
demo so I’m gonna run it and
see. I hope it’s nothing
incriminating. Um I’m gonna try
to set it, I’ll set it at like
the end of the table and see how
far it goes and the trick is to
align it. Actually you know
let’s have a volunteer. Zas,
come here. Zas is gonna be my
laser control module. [laughs]
Uh everyone Zas Brookes.
[Laughs] [Applause] Don’t you
love you just get roped into a
demo ‘cause you- because you’re
right there. Okay so, he’ll put
it here and I’ll try to align
the system um the trick is that
if the laser hits the diode
exactly right um it’s too
strong, it’s gonna overpower it.
So we’re going to try to do, I
have to try to get it at the
edge. And again it’s going to be
hard to-to actually see what
happens because I might have to
cover it a little bit. But we’ll
try this out. So we’re at 4800
baud, let’s go back to my
terminal program. What’s cool is
you can just change the baud
rate on the fly, which is really
nice. So 4800, and I don't even
remember what’s what um what
polarity this is so we might
have to fiddle around a little
bit, but let’s see. [Applause]
Cool, that’s awesome, it
actually worked. [Laughs]
Thanks. What did it say? I’m
Arduino speaking through
lightwaves. Yeah. Cool. Um
alright. Yeah so that one’s sort
of fun. So sort of related to
the laser thing. I was at TOR
camp um and uh [laughs] Will C
was there and he’s big into
lasers and high voltage crazy
stuff. He’s like, hey we should
connect an OpticSpy with my 1
watt blue laser. Um so to give
you an example, this laser diode
is 3 millowats. Typically your
red lasers are 3 or 5
milliwatts. Like your brighter
ones are like maybe 5 or 10
milliwatts. And you could see
how far this was and this will
still hurt your eyes if you look
into it. So 1 watt interface. 1
watt blue laser. Um I didn’t
know how bright this was but he
gave us um goggles to wear and
everything. And so I set up a
little system and it was hard
because he had a battery uh this
battery powered supply that
connected to this laser. Um so
we had to make this little
transistor circuit and we were
at TOR camp in the middle of you
know the middle of Washington.
Um on an island and we’re trying
to cobble something together. So
I made a little interface that
would that would take serial
data and then hit the transistor
that would turn on and off the
laser. We got part of it working
um but what ended up happening
is you could see the laser in
the upper part uh [laughs]. So
my kids decided to show up like
right as I was about to test
this laser and I’m like guys you
gotta stand behind me. Um and I
was wearing the goggles and I
wasn’t thinking about you know
that they didn’t have goggles on
and um and my wife didn’t have
goggles on either. So I’m like
you have to stand behind me
we’re gonna test this thing, I
don’t know what is gonna do. So
I turn on the laser and it’s you
know uh sending it’s doing
something and we see the laser
uh but I don’t see it much
because I have the goggles on
that are filtering the
wavelength. And um apparently
what was happening, is the laser
was hitting, imagine like a
tent, you know one of the
outdoor tents. It was hitting
the metal, one of the metal
poles, like it just happen, like
it was a huge tent and there was
one metal pole and it was
hitting the metal pole. So
reflecting off the pole. So my
kids decide to walk in front and
then my wife goes after them and
looks and the reflection gets
her right in the eye. She’s like
what the hell are you guys
doing? ‘Cause I didn't even tell
her that there was a blue laser
or anything so. [Laughs] We were
really scared about that, her
eye was a little bit red for the
night but no damage. And uh we
thought it’d be a pretty funny
story if she actually like
burned her eye out with testing
OpticSpy stuff but luckily that
didn't happen and I’m still
married so. Good. I’m gonna aim
for that. Um and yeah um we
ultimatey didn’t-didn’t weren’t
able to test it because Will
forgot his charger back at home
in Boston uh so the battery ran
out and it was like flickering
so it probably would have
worked. He was here and he
offered to do it and I’m like no
I don’t want to take the risk.
So we ultimately put a box over
it to do our testing, because
that blocks the laser much
better. Um okay so then-then the
smart modem is the last uh demo
and then I’ll show you a video
and we’ll be done. Um this is
the original Smartmodem
discovered by the guys that
wrote this paper and datas
leaking through SD on the uh on
the input and it's also the
received data that is getting
through the telephone line and
is showing on the other LED. Um
and it’s hard to see on the
slides, but there’s a direct
path, a direct electrical
connection from the DB 25
connector to the modem receiver
chip but also directly to the
LED. And then same thing from
the receive side from the modem
ship through the LED to the
DB25. So it’s you know, a great
way to save IO pins. The
engineer doesn't have to worry
about adding extra status LED
‘cause it’s just showing the
data and in appears to be solid
because the data’s going so fast
anyway. And even if it blinks,
it doesn’t matter. It’s a status
indicator. It just happens that
it’s passing the exact data. So
this one I made a little USD u-
uh-uh micro SD card to serial
interface which is a little
board and I have it plugged into
the modem and you could use it
as a standalone demo board also
that has an LED on it for
demonstrations and the 3 pin for
the laser diode module. We can
power it with a 9 volt battery
or with the Ac charger from the
modem um and it’s gonna read
data off of the micro sd card
and then transmit it over
the-over the lights. [Laughs]
I’ve been waiting for this one
for a long time, so it’s great
for demonstrations and trolling.
Um alright so this is at 9600
baud. If this is how I expect,
I’ll be very happy. Alright so
there’s 9600 and now let’s see
if I could do this. [Laughter]
[Applause] [Laughter] And the
terminal program crashed.
Perfect. Could you guys see what
that was? No? Did someone say
no? I think someone- I think
someone said no. So just for
that, just for that you get it
again.Yeah, never gonna give you
up guys. [Applause] And so
that’s reading an entire,you
know that’s reading a text file
so it shows that you could do
more than just send you know a
silly one-one lined message. And
then this-this is a video, but
this is showing like okay what
if you modify off the shelf
consumer device to do something
useful. Um this is a TL-WR841N
that has that I loaded DD-WRT
onto so I could actually control
the GPIO pins um which directly
connected to the LEDs. So I
already have administrator
access so this is a little bit
contrived but the the you know
example is if somebody remotely
compromises a device and then
turns it into an Optical Covert
channel they could do that. This
one is going to read the ETSY uh
shadow file and then print the
password hashes that you could
then you know optically receive
and then decode and do whatever.
But it just sort of shows what
you could do on modified
hardware other than you know
loading DD-WRT, but physically
unmodified. And um for this one
I’m using a prototype but you
could see that I had to
basically touch the device
because there’s the light wasn’t
very bright and there’s a light
pipe there. Um so it sort of you
know makes-makes the LED not as
bright. So what you’re seeing um
on the- on the left is the shell
from the DD-WRT. And I’m using
the uh orange led light, the WAN
light to transmit the message
and because this is Linux,
there’s a whole bunch of
overheard that happens. Even if
you’re controlling a GPIO pin.
You have to go through all these
libraries and stuff to actually
get to the bare metal um which
was super frustrating because I
normally deal with bare metal
not with Linux. So I had to like
figure out, how can I, how can I
do this in a way that’s gonna be
timing timing accurate. And I’m
baidallc y sending characters at
2400 baud every second. So you
can see, that’s what I’m
transmitting and then on the
right is gonna be what I’m
receiving. And I’ll speed it up.
And it’s just gonna send that,
send that entire password over
and over again. I think I
actually have it set it up to
just send only the first line
because that’s the only one we
care about in their case. So
yeah, you know it shows you can
do it on real consumer stuff as
well. Um what about other sorts
of devices? MacBook Pro, I
thought it’d be cool if I could
um if I could modulate the-the
keyboard backlight um I tried to
do it on the screen backlight
but that was way too slow. Uh so
the keyboard backlight thought
they modulate their LEDs at a
100 hertz which means, and at 75
percent duty cycle. So you can’t
really transmit stuff to turn
stuff on, on, and off too fast
because it’s gonna blink. So
this is the fastest I could get
data to transmit, it looks like
morse code but its not morse
code. Um the signal on the
right, it is the it’s what was
picking up with OpticSpy so you
can see the 100 hertz
modulation. And the width that I
have there is the actual time
per bit. So if you want to look
at these slides and recreate
that transmission, it’s going to
be another secret message that
you guys will hate me for. Um so
this is an example of it’s not
standard modulation you can’t
use NRZ encoding so you have to
tap on TP5, hook it into some
other way to decode it. Here’s
one of a remote control, just
one that I happened to have at
my house. Um most infrared
remotes in things that are
transmitting infrared are riding
on a carrier wave so this is 38
killahertz. the cool thing with
OpticSpy is you can adjust the
gains and the higher gain you go
the slower the response times
gonna be on the system. So you
can adjust the gain and actually
end up demodulating the data. So
here we have the carrier all the
solid white is the carrier than
normally you'd have to filter
out, OpticSpy will do it for you
which is pretty cool and then
you’re just left with the 1’s
and 0’s that you can-can go to
work on. And here's an iPhone
sensor so you know proximity
sensors on computers and
bathroom stalls and whatever
else um are sending signals
sending data in some way so I
thought it’d be fun to just see
what what would happen if I held
OpticSpy up to that um to that
device. And you can see it’s
something, I didn’t figure out
what it was, but it’s these
pulses um at 30-30 hertz and
then you have a little bit of
data sent in there. So yeah,
ideas for this sort of stuff.
It’s like you can create your
own interfaces, you can sniff
other people's interfaces, I
just feel like you never know
what you’re gonna find, right?
And that’s sort of the fun of
hacking in general. It’s like
building something like this,
really no other purpose except
to just learn something new and
do something fun. And um of
course limitations. If it’s not
NZR encoded like we talked about
you have to uh tap earlier, the
receive range is short so maybe
you can amplify that in some
way. And the one thing that
really gets me is that
potentionmeters are mutlturn so
you can’t tell what you’re gain
settings are because it’s not
like this but it’s like this. So
you can’t really tell where they
are so it makes it you know a
little bit trickier. You could
take the potentiometers
measurements and check the
resistances of each one and make
notes of that you know that’s
your settings for this
particular target, depends what
you wanna do. Um so future work,
I have a question mark here
because I'm probably not going
to do it, but maybe something
will get inspired and do it. But
maybe somebody will get inspired
to doit um maybe have to
additional intelligence uh but I
like-I like the simplicity of
this probably not. Maybe having
automatic gain control though
would be cool. So if the signal
you know is very weak, it’s
going to amplify more uh
otherwise you know maybe if its
too strong like the laser, it
would-it would reduce the
amplification which would be
kind of cool. And then there’s
actually some work that I
thought would be awesome, was of
so instead of you know
transmitting LED data through an
LED, you can actually transmit
data, into a device through an
LED depending on how the system
is set up so I thought that
would be fun to maybe
investigate. Maybe that’s a
future talk and not really
related to OpticSpy, I don’t
know. But that’s another one of
like simple device that could
like possibly be a problem. Um
so then some other resources of
you know other things that have
been done and of course final
slide with the link and all the
information linked to Oshpark
for stuff. If you wanna get
assembled units, Crowd Supply I
think has a few left. Uh maybe
he’ll do another run it depends
but everything you need to
build, test, uh example code all
of that stuff, even MacBook Pro
keyboard thing, stuff that
didn’t quite work, it's all on
my website. Um so feel free to
contact me uh you know if you're
building something and you find
something cool or have any
questions or anything. So that
is it. Thank you for coming. And
uh do we have any questions?
[Applause] No questions. Oh a
question! >>[Inaudible question
from audience] Right so for the
receiver, did I put try to put
a-a soda straw on it or
something like that to limit
the-the uh the kind of area that
it’s seeing. I haven’t and that
would be a great idea to maybe
use like a paper one or
something, or maybe some heat
shrink or something to narrow it
down that rgane. And that would
reduce the amount of ambient
light also. So I haven’t tried
it but yeah, great idea.
>>[Inaudible comment from
audience] Right so once you have
the data coming in, before it
goes to the USB toC adapter how
hard would it be to detect the
baud rate assuming it’s an
asynchronous serial NRZ. Super
easy. Because to do that you
just have to measure the
narrowest bit time within the
signal and that's gonna
determine what your baud rate is
because your baud rate is 1
divided by the bit time of the
narrowest bit. So yeah, you
could do auto baud rate
detection, um which would also
be good, luckily like most
people are just using you know
uh uh like at least for these
demos all standard baud rates.
And if a vendors trying to be
sneaky, and they do a non
standard baud rate you could
measure it but it’s just gonna
look like noise, and you might
say oh um maybe that's not
anything so yeah some auto baud
rate would definitely be
possible to do for sure. and if
a vendors trying to be sneaky.
Stick that from tp5 in to a-a
Arduino or something. Good?
Okay. That is that it. Thanks
again and enjoy the rest of the
show.