>>Alright, Truman Kain, um
Social Engineering [clapping]
yeah, another clap please, ha.
[applause] Thanks. >> Thanks.
Blake had too much to say about
me so he figured there wasn’t
enough time. Ok so who here is
from the abstract? Who here read
the abstract and that’s why they
wanted to come? Raise your
hands. Yeah. Dragnet one hell of
a catch, one hell of a catch.
Okay so I’m Truman Kain I‘m a
security Associate from Tevora.
We do cyber security, pen
testing, that type of thing.
And, I’ve decided to make a
social engineering framework
called Dragnet and that’s what
we’re going to talk about today.
So, if you didn’t read the, the
abstract. Uh basically um, you-
your conversion on phishing
emails, phishing calls, physical
engagements, uh those
conversions are all going to
increase when you use this
framework. What do I mean by
conversions, basically things
like credentials being entered.
Um people giving you information
they’re not supposed to be
giving you. That type of thing.
Uh so that’s what I’m
considering a conversion for
these purposes. Uh first I’m
gonna, I’m gonna get into the
current states of OSINT,
Analytics, Social Engineering
Engagements. Um, and, and then
we’ll, then we’ll, we’ll talk
about the tool, but uh I also
want let you guys know that
these are my insights, you guys
might not feel the same way,
about everything I say, hey I
recognize you. Um, and, and so
this is just what I’ve observed.
Okay, so wh-when I think about
OSINT I think that um, I want a
high quality reliable data that
I’m collecting on my target and
the collection process usually
ends up being manual because,
well when you, when you see a
successful spear phishing attack
there’s almost always manual
OSINT going on. Uh, it can be
for a few reasons, a couple. It
might be that you want to verify
the information that you’re
getting is, is accurate. Also,
so that you can tailor your
attack, uh to your target. Uh,
as you learn more about them but
all of it is so that you have a
higher chance of conversion uh
when you when you execute the
attack. So, a-aside some minor
variations this process is
extremely repetitive. And once
you’ve gone through the OSINT
phase on a couple of targets uh
you kind of have down your
process, maybe you have a couple
targets form each industry, you
kind of um, you know, you get
down what you’re going to be
doing. So, you think okay why
can’t, why can’t this be
automated and sometimes you can
automate things, uh but once
the, the automation um, starts
turning into the heavy lifting a
lot of the times you’ll see big
sites start to change their
template and, and they just
coincidentally um roll out an
update that just destroys the
most populate, ya know scraping
tool. Um so, so that would be
why um, when when we see
automation work it’s fleeting,
it, it doesn’t last very long.
So, here, here’s the current
state of analytics. A-A, sorry I
had something else I wanted to
say about the last slide. So why
do these sites care so much
about protecting their publicly
available data? It’s because,
analytics. As a side note, I’m
going to use big data and
analytics interchangeably for
the purpose of this topic. So
regardless of what the company
does or what they say they do.
If you look at the companies
with the biggest online
presence, Amazon, Google,
Facebook, that type of thing.
Um, if, if you were to take away
their analytics, in my opinion
they would not last very long.
You might not all believe but I
believe um, when you’re a
company that big you can’t act
on intuition alone. Uh so not
only is every major decision
driven by analytics, even the
smallest decisions is driven by
data as well. An example would
be the way that Facebook has, uh
is split testing thousands of
different versions of their
website as any one time. Uh and,
and pushing only the highest
performing features out to the
public version of the site. Uh,
but not only do these big
companies live off of analytics,
sometimes it’s the way the
companies are born. Uh, this is
a, a quote by, by Jeff Bezos in
1997, I’m not, I’m not going to
read it in the Jeff Bezos voice
from the video if you’ve seen
it. Uh he says, “3 years ago I
was working in a quantitative
hedge fund when I came across a
startling statistic.” So that
statistic uh stated just how
rapidly consumers were moving
online. It’s also what caused
Jeff to leave the company he was
at to start Amazon. And it’s now
why we’re inpatient uh when we
can’t get things delivered the
same day. Uh, so you’re sold,
right? You’re gonna go out,
you’re gonna study the blade, I
mean study the data and, and
start the next Amazon, right?
Well as I look around the room
I’m not so convinced. Because
for, fortunately for those of
you who take Jeff’s quote to
heart, the data is already out
there and it can be used for
things other than starting or
growing business. Like
destroying them, no, like social
engineering. So, I’m a fan of
Amazon by the way, I don’t need
my accounts shut down this is
all educational purposed with
this tool. So, for those of you
who conduct social engineering
engagements legally you may
resonate with this chart. The
client doesn’t even get to
choose two, they get to choose
one, effective, quick or
inexpensive. In this current
state and I’m generalizing a
little bit but uh, the companies
with big budgets are the only
ones getting social engineering
pen testing and I believe that
needs to change. Let me grab
some water. Uh so Fortune 5000
companies are already being
targeted in mass. I believe that
smaller business in certain
industries are gonna quickly
become uh th-the next big focus
for social engineering attacks
based on the data they hold and
the lack of uh security
awareness training. I needed to
include Zucks somewhere in here.
So, I think I’ve depressed
everyone enough with that last
part so what can we do about
this? So, Dragnet is this social
engineering framework that I’m
going to get into now. We’ll
watch demo in a little bit uh,
but um I believe that Dragnet
is, is gonna be a populate
solution for pen testers. I’m
committed to continually
improving on it as long as the
demand is there. What I said
about uh OSINT auto-automation
uh being fleeting. For every
start on the GitHub that’s going
to mean an hour of me, ya know
going back and re-improving. So
free labor basically, I- I mean
it’s, it’s a cheap, it’s cheap
labor for you guys. So, I- I
would recommend starting this
project if you like and, and
maybe ya know the OSINT stops
working, star the project and
that’s an hour I’m just going to
be sitting in my mom’s basement.
So, I, I, where was I here? So,
I’m gonna quickly cover the
frameworks OSINT, Automation,
and Machine Learning
capabilities and then we’re
going to check out a quick demo.
I’m also happy to see, say that
Dragnet is um and will continue
to be open source. So, I believe
that this target template
correlation learning thing.
[applause] Oh. [applause] Uh, so
the whole correlation, thank you
whoever started that, very nice.
Uh, the, the whole
recommendation system thing, AI
is being implemented into
everything. The data is already
out there. I think that pretty
much every phishing tool, is, is
going to start implementing
this. That’s why I’m really
excited to, to try to be on the
cutting edge. I think this is a
cool thing and it’s becoming a
lot easier to forecast like me
to implement this in the
projects. So, this is
essentially The Stack.
TensorFlow for machine learning.
Firebase for the Zeno SQL
database backend and Vue.js uh
for the front end. Uh things
like Asterisk and Flask are also
used and and there’s, there’s a
bunch of different integrations
as well. So, here’s how Dragnet
OSINT works. Uh you’re gonna
start a new engagement you’re
gonna Dragon Drop in a CSV with
your, uh with our targets names
and emails or phone numbers. And
then OSINT begins. And if a
particular target already exists
within the company uh that the
engagement is for then the OSINT
is going to restart, changes are
going to be tracked and a new
recommendation is going to be
made. This almost entirely
automated, hence keep your hands
near the wheel. This is using
lead enrichment integrations and
also manual scraping at times.
So, their reason for the hands
near the wheel is because
sometimes you’re gonna get
people with the same name from
the same company. And so, you
need to decide who is your
actual target. Uh because if you
choose wrong, you could skew the
uh model uh for, y-you could
skew the entire model so that
the recommendation for someone
completely different that you
think there is no correlation
between uh gets a different
suggestion, one that’s not
accurate because you chose the
wrong person and because the
data points about them uh
weren’t correct. Um, so. Am I on
the right slide here for
everyone? Okay cool. This is the
old version. Sorry guys. Alright
that didn’t work. [clicking] Is
this where I”m sup- start
dancing like Ashley Simpson?
Okay, so, okay, so this is the
model uh essentially. I really
don’t know how any of this
works. I kind of just like
watched a bunch of videos and
was just like trying, to, to get
it to work. It barely makes
sense to me but essentially how
it works is, ha, essentially how
it works is you’re going to tag
the templates that you’re using.
Uh so you’re gonna say, say for
example unusual login detected,
so you’re gonna say urgency
might get a tag. And it’s from
LinkedIn so you’re going to give
it a LinkedIn tab. Maybe you’re
doing an Amazon Wish, Amazon
Wishlist uh phishing template
and you’re gonna use tags like
amazon, shopping, maybe it’s a
Facebook poke email and you use
things like, lust, ya know for
example. Things like that. Uh
then the OSINT automation is
going to um, create data points
which essentially, we’re calling
target features. Uh things like
someone’s age, their name,
maybe, maybe their gender, maybe
uh previous work experience.
That type of thing. Uh labels
are gonna be what are taken from
your previous engagements, uh,
the, the data on whether a
target ya know clicked, uh
filled out a form they weren’t
supposed to, executed a payload,
that type of thing. It’s going
to give them a rating, all to
end up with a probability of
Pwn. Uh so that’s what we’re l-,
we’re after. So, i- put simply
you’re going to tag your
templates. You’re going to
import the prior conversion data
and then you’re gonna say your
prayers. Alright so we’re gonna
watch a demo. Alright so here we
are in the dashboard engagement
section. You can see that we
have an upcoming, in progress
and completed uh, filter. We
have some clients that we worked
with recently. But we’re gonna,
we’re gonna start a new pen test
for Pied Piper. They’re, they’re
a client we decided to take on.
So, we’re gonna choose from the
existing companies. We’re gonna
choose the type of test that
we’re running. This one’s
Phishing and Vishing. And we’re
gonna choose a start and end
date. Okay so these 3 uh,
contacts are our essentially
targets that we have already
uploaded for Pied Piper, they’ve
already, we’ve already run uh,
e- e- an engagement against
them. But I’m gonna drag in a
new file with some new targets.
The target list is populated and
now I can choose who I want to
include. And um, ya know, and
also choose which uh type of
test they’re going to be
involved in. So, Gilfoyle is
only going to be uh doing
phishing. We’re gonna get rid,
I- I’m scared of Jared so we’re
going to get rid of him
completely Uh, he’s just too
easy. Uh, uh big head so we’re
gonna get rid of him. And then
we’re gonna run uh, just the
phishing on a couple of other of
the targets here. And I think
yeah there we go, so view that
bug. Okay, so now we’re going to
save and OSINT begins. So, as
you can see on the right uh this
says attack ready that’s how
fast, let me see, I don’t think
I can go back. That’s how fast
essentially that the OSINT is,
is being done and because the
model is already trained and
will be trained each time
someone uh coverts or, or we get
one of those labels that you saw
from the, from the equation
slide. Uh the model is going to
be retrained. Once that happens,
to create the prediction is
going to be extremely quick. So,
you can see we have things like
starting ML prediction. This
last update column on the right
is going to show what the last
thing to happen was. But we, we
also see that we have an action
required in addition to the
attack ready. The action
required is on Jin Yang.
Interesting. Kay, click the
button. This is prerecorded.
They started, they wanted us to
pre-record these so which is
probably a good thing. Click the
button, there we go. Okay, so
which of these is Jin Yang? This
is what I was talking about
where hands near the wheel. I
have to pick which one is my
target. I just happen to know
that this is a male, maybe,
maybe I’ve seen the target,
maybe I know roughly what age
she is, I can call the client to
maybe get that data. So, choose
the easy target. It started
OSINT, it completed OSINT uh
because I’m, I have an
integration like clear bit or uh
full contact and that’s why the
OSINT is going to be faster.
Okay so now I just launched, you
can see some people say email
scheduled, some people say
sending email. This is based on
the, oh, what’s this? So, I want
to explain a little bit more.
Uh. But it looks like we have a
notification that Jin Yang
already opened out email. Would
we like to phish him now? So,
this is because it’s a linked
template that wants you to call
and follow up as soon as uh, the
target opens the email. Not all
of these templates need to be
linked. On the right you can see
a mini dossier area this is
going to be that, uh check mark
indicates that its’ confirmed.
The data is confirmed. The
fingerprint indicates this was
um using OSINT that we found
this. Things like education
history info, background, work
history and so we see an attack
log that shows the email was
sent and opened and at what
time. We have our script right
here that we’re going to be
using with his name uh included.
And we can place the call
whenever we are ready. And it
should be hopefully sound for
this. [phone ringing] So, this
is calling my attack phone, then
calling Jin Yang from the masked
number. >>Richard, you are ugly.
>>Okay, so he apparently knew,
knew that this was um, not a
legit call. Uh so did we get the
goods? No. He’s not falling. And
uh, the, the recording if the
client allows is going to be
uploaded uh to, to our servers
and, and we would be able to
play it here. [phone ringing]
I’m going to fast forward a
little bit. [phone ringing]
>>Richard, you are ugly. >>Okay,
Okay so we see the attack log on
the bottom right has updated.
And we can go back and we see
now there’s some o-other
updates, on last updated we see
call unsuccessful on Jin Yang.
And call scheduled and we see
credits captured for Monica.
Okay so we’re gonna click on the
phishing template and we see the
email that was sent, Gavin
Belson wants to connect. We see
the credentials captured there
right on the top right, or in
the middle. We have her mini
dossier area and we can see the
credentials entered on the
attack log as well. So, if we
click we can see that this come
on click on this email here.
Basically, we’re gonna be able
to see the landing page that she
was sent to, is not LinkedIn.
It’s Line-k-d In. So, this is
the landing page and where she
fell for the uh credentials
captured attack. So, we can
click on her little avatar there
and see the full dossier and
it’s essentially just a, um a
more spread-out version of the
mini dossier that you saw. And
also, one cool thing is this, in
the target history section is
not just about the attach it um
all attached and it’s also
things like when she was added
to a certain company, when OSINT
started, was completed when
templates were suggested, that
type of thing. Okay. So, I
believe that is it. Yep. Cool.
Okay so that’s the demo. And.
What’s next? Um things like
ringless voicemail drops once uh
ya know once we get inbound
calling setup you’ll be able to
do things like this earlier in
the morning. Maybe when someone
is not going to be around their
phone and try to get them to
call you, call you back. Things
like really focusing on
individual targeting so you
don’t have to do things through
a company, again for educational
purposes. Uh distributed vishing
so you might be able to have a
team setup and, and be able to
get them, um, um setup with
multiple attack phones. That
type of thing. Native Mobile, I
think would be really cool, uh,
to be able to have in an app to,
to manage this and to be able to
d-do all the calls through an
app. I think that would be
really cool. And your requests
here is the bottom one, so I uh,
I really am committed to working
on this. Uh, I’m not gonna be
the guy that’s like eh submit a
pool request. Like I’ll do the
work. You guys if there’s enough
people that want something they
can plus 1 it if somebody
suggests it, suggests it on a,
on GitHub’s site. I’d really
appreciate if you guys give your
ideas there. I’d be happy to do
that. Thanks. [applause] Thank
you so Dragnet is going to be
released on GitHub in the next
few days. Uh the repo is live.
You can get it through the Dwarf
threat link. But I’d like you to
watch the repo so you’re
notified as soon as the
framework is released which will
be in a few days. Also thank you
to Kevin, Steven, Clayton and
Ray from Tevora. This uh,
framework wouldn’t exist without
them. Thanks again guys, thanks.
[applause]