>>This is uh, this is going to
be a fun talk um I mean there
are things on the stage,
hopefully we see some demos.
There are videos, there’s audio
um this should be a lot of fun
and remember um and remember
this is a first time speaker
he’s going to have his uh, he
wants his hydration afterwards
so we’ll give it to him
afterwards uh per his election.
Um, let’s give him a big round
of applause [clapping] >>Thanks,
so, thank you very much,
every-everyone can hear me? Yes,
no, k, great. So, uh, welcome to
my talk about having fun with
IoT, the reverse engineering and
hacking of Xiaomi IoT devices.
Um, so the outline for my talk
will be the following if your
short uh, motivation uh why I
did that. I’ll give you an
introduction into the xiaomi
cloud um, then we go to the
overview of the devices, next up
will be the reverse engineering
of the devices and at the end we
modify them. Um, some info about
me I’m a researcher at
Northeastern University in
Boston, and I’m working with uh
Professor Guevara Noubir. Uh,
but I’m also a grad student at
TU Darmstadt in Germany and uh
my interest in the moment is
like reverse engineering all
kinds of interesting devices,
for example IoT’s, smart locks
and of course physical locks.
Um, that’s all the things that
you need to know about me. Uh,
ok. So, fort-motivation, why we
reverse IoT devices. Well, some
people do that to find and
exploit bugs to hack other
people. Um, but for me it’s like
a little bit different. Um, I
want to de-attach the devices
from the vendor. There have been
like a very famous example in
Europe, the company E-large
which has disconnected all the
European uh light bulbs because
of the gdpr. Uh now they work
again but I mean it shows that
it’s somewhat critical. Um, the
other thing is we want to
enhance functionality, for
example adding new features,
change the localization, uh the
vacuum cleaner for example talks
chinese with me, my chinese is
non existing so, English would
be better. And some devices have
some uh, ge- Geo blocking thing,
so basically if you buy a device
in Taiwan, you cannot use it in
China for example. Um, another
very important thing is also to
support our researchers, for
example there’s a Mon(IoT)or Lab
at Northeastern where we have a
lot of home appliances and
they’re looking uh into the
traffic of these. And then this
lab washed last week my laundry
so it’s a very nice lab, um
yeah. One important thing, um
responsible disclosure mm I get
always the question like hey did
you disclose the uh
vulnerabilities to the vendor,
and the thing is, it’s always a
little bit complicated. So if
there is a specific conflict
between vulnerability and device
security. Um, when I presented
initially my talk in the cross
communication congress about
some rooting method for the
vacuum cleaner for the
generation one um if I would
have told the vendor about that
before hand, then I would have
to tell him that probably no one
would be able to root his device
and so see is, see it as more of
a service for the community,
instead of getting me rich by
the back pocket program. Um, in
this case, uh for this
presentation, I contacted also
the Xiaomi security team before
that and told them what I want
to publish. Ok, so, how we
started, in May 2017 uh, I uh,
Donnie Bigama and I were looking
at a couple of devices and I
bought a vacuum clean robot to
clean my apartment and this
whole thing continued to these
smart home gateways and
lightbulbs and over the time it
got even more and more devices
which I bought and I take a look
at. Now you might ask hey why I
started with vacuum cleaners?
And um, the thing is the
following, um this is the
advertisement of um Xiaomi about
the vacuum cleaner generation
one and it tells you this thing
has 3 processors and one of them
is a quad core. Don’t you think
like hey a quad core in a vacuum
cleaner? How cool is that,
right? So, this was the initial
thing how we, uh, uh, started um
doing this research because it
was like very interesting
platform. Ok, let’s talk about
the Xiaomi cloud. Um, Xiaomi
claims that they have actual the
um biggest IoT ecosystem
worldwide with over 85 million
devices and 800 different
models. Which can be uh starting
from a vacuum cleaners, cameras,
up to smart toothbrushes, smart
toilet seats, every- you name it
they have everything probably.
Um, the-the interesting thing
here is that not all of the
products which are labeled as
Xiaomi are actually from Xiaomi,
so there like different vendors
which are breaking this
ecosystem by using the same
communication protocol, and um,
this cloud is also supporting
different technologies. Um, the
interesting thing here is the
implementation is different from
manufacturer to manufacturer,
software quality is also like
very, very different. Ok, so,
this is like a simplified uh
like overview over the cloud, so
what we have here is we have the
three uh main technologies, we
have BLE, WiFi and Zigbee. The
central component for you as a
customer is the smart home app
which is um, installed on your
smartphone, and this is also
used to uh provision the devices
um to connect them to the WiFi.
As soon as you provisioned them,
they have their own connection
to the Wifi uh, uh through the
WiFi to the cloud so your device
is more or less out of the
gateway there. Okay, let’s take
a look at this communication
which is going from device to
the cloud. So, to be able to be
able to communicate with the um
cloud, you need a few
credentials and these are the
following so, you have a device
ID which is uh, unique for every
device and you have two kinds of
keys uh, the first key is the
cloud key which is used for the
device to cloud communication,
and this is static and is never
changed so if you do firmware
updates if you do provisioning
this is always staying the same.
For many devices it is also
written into one time
programmable memory so, even if
you would like to change it its
not possible because its uh,
burnt into the device. The other
token, uh the other key is the
token um which is used for the
app to device communication. For
example, if you want to control
your device in the uh local
network, then you have to use
this token. The thing here is
that it’s dynamic, so basically
every time you provision your
device newly, for example to a
new WiFi, um, and this this
token is like regenerated. Ok,
the cloud protocol itself looks
like the following, so you have
like um, um, message-messages
which is JSON formatted, and uh,
if you want one example of that,
this is the uh command for the
registration, just to give you
impression of what’s going on
there, as soon as the device is
connected to the cloud it tells
like hey I’m connected to this
WiFi ID, um, I have like this
version number and so on and so
on. Um, the firmware updates are
interesting. So, there are like
3 different methods how to um,
or like 3 different firmwares
which you can update over the
cloud. They are for example the
app updates, which is the usual
software on your device, um
there you have like the url and
the anti five tracks of the- of
the- of the of the image. Then
you have the MCU updates or the
WiFi updates if you have like a
WiFi core in your device then
you can uh also update it. And
you have subdevice updates for
example if you have a smart home
gateway and connected like to a
smoke detector then uh you can
update the firmware of the smoke
detector over th wireless. The
interesting thing here is the
MCU and firmware updates are not
uh protected at all they they
don’t put a md5 tricks in there
system in there so you can if
something happens on the way uh
on the download way of-of the
firmware updates you have no
possibility to check actually
integrity of it. Ok, so let’s
take a look at the other
interface, the interface between
the app and the cloud. Um, the
communication here is um
authenticated over OAuth and
they have layered encryption, so
basically um they connect over
https, but inside of the https
they have a different payload
which is encrypted with AES and
for the specific session key
which is generated. Um, the
message format here is JSON RPC
and interesting function here is
that the um, the um the home app
actually doesn’t have uh all the
functionalities which are
required for the uh for the
devices, um but the app installs
like plugins after that. So as
soon as you add a new device to
your um to your app, then its
automatically downloads in the
background like a new plugin and
the functionality is provided by
the plugins. How does
communication look like? If you
um open your um smart home app
and this url is caught by the by
your smartphone, and it demands
small list a list of devices
which are belong to your
account. And here in this
example is one device, its like
you see here device ID, what
kind of name it has, what-what
kind of local IP address it has,
but interesting thing here is
the following: there’s a
longitude/latitude field. And
now you might ask hey wait why
is that, right? So, um, I take a
look at this-this uh position
and I google it and I figure
that is actually the exact
position of the device, in this
case, uh, uh, powerplex. Another
question is how we got that and
uh the- the answer is very easy,
um, if you have new devices they
open an open WiFi access point,
to be able to find this open
WiFi access point, you need to
give the app permission for
localization. Because this is uh
like the permission to scan for
open WiF- or for WiFi access
point, its bounded to
localization permission and in
Android. Basically, you give
them the localization
permission, they find your
access point but they know also
the position and they tell the
cloud like hey I saw this device
at this position. At the end of
the day they know exactly where
each device is. Um, here’s one
example of the communication
relations uh if you have any
random device, um so the green
box is for example the all the
internal components in the
vacuum cleaner, and the right
side is the cloud. So um as a
search you need two credentials,
the device ID and the key to
connect to the cloud and then if
the cloud is sending you any
information it’s encrypted, but
you have a center component
called Mio client which is
encrypting all the stuff and
sending uh to the internal
component. So, the Mio client is
the core uh component bonus for
the cloud communication. This is
the most important for us as
reverse engineers. And, this
lead us to the next part, how to
gain independence from the cloud
and uh, the trick here is um,
that we can proxies
communication. Um, and for that
we developed um, our own
implementation of the Xiaomi
cloud which is called dust cloud
and what it does is um by this
direction you can redirect
traffic to the cloud and then
you can just proxy it through
dust cloud. Um, the exact thing
about dust cloud is it has um,
it can act as a proxy or
endpoint server for devices, uh
and its more or less the Xiaomi
cloud emulation so the device
can’t tell that it’s not the
cloud, for example. It can read
traffic in plain text, you can
send commands to the devices,
you can change or suppress
commands. For example, a lot of
times you don’t want to have
firmware updates on the devices
so we can just suppress them.
The requirements for that is
that we need to have the device
ID,the cloud key and we need to
do DNS redirection that um the
device is communicating to our
cloud. Ok, that’s so much for
the cloud, let’s move on with
the devices. Um, if you, if you
have the, uh if you use the app
from-from mainland China, or
just like use-use the server
from mainland China, which most
of the people do because it
supports most of the devices, uh
then you have more or less 260
different models which are
supported. This could be WiFi,
Zigbee, Bluetooth LE. Um, and
this is very depend- it’s
dependent on which server your
sitting, so for example if you
use mainland China then you have
like nearly all the devices and
Taiwan is like way less, in the
US is a total of like I think 25
devices. Um, the thing here is
the models are not always
compatible so like I said, if
you buy a device in Taiwan, then
um most of the time you can not
connect it to mainland China or
vice versa. Um, like I, like I
always told you, the um, if you
see some device with the label
Xiaomi, doesn’t mean it has to
be produced by Xiaomi. So, I
just figured out uh what kind of
devices are actually produced by
Xiaomi and you see its own-only
11 percent. So, out of the 260
devices, the biggest part is
produced by uh, lumi, um Xiaomi
has 11 percent and for example
the company which produces
nearly all of the lightning
stuff uh, um yeelink has like
around 10 percent total, yep.
Out of this devices, I own like
42 myself, uh like different
models and I have like 99
devices which I bought
personally so I have more or
less a quite good overview
what-what’s going on with the
cloud there. Ok, um, so because
this is a 1 on 1 track, I want
to give you just a quick idea of
what’s going on with these
devices. So we have different
architectures we have like
Cortex-A, Cortex- M um, which is
um so Cortex-A is more or less
the stuff which is in your
smartphone so it’s very
powerful, Cortex-M is uh more
like an embedded controller
which is like um not so powerful
and it has two flavors which
they use more or less. Um, if
you have only WiFi, then they
use Marvell chips, if you have
WiFi and Bluetooth LE combined
then they use Mediatek chips.
There is like MIPS chips
available and also Xtensa
meaning more or less ESP8266 or
ESP32. So the focus on this talk
is actually only Cortex-A, um,
if you’re interested in
Cortex-M, I give a talk about
binary patching in the IoT
village, um, I think 1 hour
after this talk. So, you just
can follow me to the other room.
And I’ll also give for you a
short introduction why I hate
ESP8266 also at the IoT village.
Ok, speaking of operation
systems, there are different
operation systems which you can
find in these IoT devices, there
are some Full Linux like in the
vacuum cleaner, you have some
OpenWRT which is used not only
like in routers but also in
speakers or in a washing
machine. Have some embedded
linux, we have RTOS which is um
some um, real time operation
systems more or less what is
used in lightbulbs uh, light
strips and so on. Speaking of
implementations, um, they are
very different from vendor to
vendor and here is like one
example. So, I have um, for
example the vacuum cleaner here,
uh which has three processors,
uh the firmware updates are
encrypted, and uh they use HTTPS
to download them and all the-
the debug interfaces are closed
down, and the manufacturer here
is um Rockrobo. Another vendor,
Lumi, uh they have a smart home
gateway and uh they use this
Marvell chip this Cortex-M chip
that I told you and they don’t
encrypt their firmwares at all.
The thing here is they don’t
even have an SSL stack in their
firmware so even if they want to
use SSL they can’t because the
firmware doesn’t support it, and
the Debug interfaces are open
here so jtag everything is
there. Uh, another case is
Yeelink there uh they have some
lighting products, they’re um uh
they use the Mediatek chip, and
here the firmware is also not
encrypted but they use HTTPS.
The thing is they don’t check
for the certificate so you can
just give any certificate and
the fun fact here is actually
they have root series in their
firmware but they don’t check
for that. There’s a small bonus
on the smart home gateway, so
it’s a chinese device only so it
can only-theoretically you can
only buy it in China, but it has
some unknown communication to
some server in Salt Lake City,
which is kind of funny. Ok, so
one good news about ummmm
de-devices mmm the vendors are
very lazy and the developers are
too lazy and so the thing what
they do is they um just take SDK
which is delivered by the, by
the chip they modify some
example which fits more or less
for the case for example switch
gpio just like let us take this
and as soon as the thing works
they just publish the firmware.
For us, it’s very good because
the firmwares are more or less
all similar, so the memory
layout is quite the same, the
functions which are used for
specific things are the same and
the strings for example so
lock-lock entries are also the
same. So, it’s very nice for us
because uh as soon as you know
one device you more or less have
idea, have an idea what’s going
on with other devices. Ok,
speaking of devices, let’s get
access to them. Um, some of the
people say like yeah I don’t
want you open my device the
warranty seal and so on, and
it’s not always necessary to
open the device, so we here have
an example of the Xiaomi WiFi
router, and you can access the
serial ports through the holes
in the uh, in the case. You can
see that in the IoT village, so
I have the router with me, you
can just try it yourself so you
just shine with a ligh-with uh
some kind of light, and you see
the port and you just connect
directly to the serial port.
This is especially important for
this device because uh after the
first power up they close down
the serial port. But if you um,
connect to the serial port
before um you power down on-for
the first time, you can reset
the select which enables the
serial port and then you’ll have
serial port forever, so very
important for this device. Ok,
let’s start with our first
device and this device is uh,
this camera here, um which has
also gateway functionality so
it’s a quite special device
which can stalk Zigbee. Um, the
internals are the following: uh,
they use the Hi3518, uh
processor, which is quite it’s
typical stuff which you find on
cameras actually. It’s a
Cortex-A processor. Um, we have
64 MB of ram, 16 Mbyte of flash,
we use uh the Mediatek WiFi
chip, um over USB which is also
interesting, and we have some
kind of embedded linux. In
addition, uh to the camera
functionality, we have also the
uh Zigbee module so we can also
speak Zigbee. Um, the kind of
device which you can connect to
this thing is uh motion
detectors, temperature sensors,
power plugs, smoke detectors
what could possibly go wrong, or
like uh smart door locks for
example. Um, so I opened this
device a few times and its uh I
found at some point the serial
port unfortunately after I break
this device because I unsorted
it quite too often, so, you have
the serial port there um, which
is uh quite a little bit hidden
so you see on the left side uh
it’s next to the USB connector
so um if you um put in some
bridges there then you can
access the serial port over USB
without using real USB but
serial. Um, yeah, right so
speaking of leaked informations
ummm, apparently we have no idea
how JFFS2 works, it’s a special
file system which you use most
of the time for-for flash which
is rewriteable and the thing her
is it usually tries to avoid
writer, writes on the um on the
flash. So what happened here is
apparently somewhere in the
background in the development
process they uh set up a base
system then they uh created
credentials, then deleted the
credentials again, copied the
whole partition to the next
device and so on and at some
point it landed in the final
firmware so they took just the
whole partition and put it
there. And what you can find
there is, just by walking
through the-the image of the FBI
flash, you’ll find there
credentials of the devices. This
is like one, only one example
for that, but they have like uh
3 different credentials for 3
different devices from the
development in there. Which
doesn’t, this would show that
not a super good quality of
software here. Um, speaking of
rooting, um actually, serial
wasn’t necessary. So we have an
open telnet port and we have a
hard coded password there. Um,
this was kind of a thing, I mean
the hard code password isn’t
always bad if you don’t know it
so this pub- this password is
not published yet, and the thing
is um, apparently they used the
standard example again in this
in this uh chip, and the
password is not encrypted in the
file but it’s encrypted with
DES-crypt. And what DES-crypt is
doing actually it takes a
password, cuts it to 8
characters and then encrypts uh,
uses this password as uh, uh key
to encrypt zeros. Um, so took me
like um half a day to actually
run it through the gpu to-to
crack it. So this is the
password for the um, for this
camera, and unfortunately this
is the same credential for all
the cameras. Um, yeah, which is
kind of a problem I guess,
right? Um, I reported that to
Xiaomi but they didn’t like
really responds, I mean
responded but they just, yeah,
nevermind. Ok, speaking of
modifications,um, first thing we
can do is like replace the
Chinese sound files one that
speaks English. You can replace
uh, telnet through dropbear and
of course you want to change the
root password and sometimes you
even want to replace the buffer,
uh, uh sorry the camera
software. Ok, let’s go to the
next device uh to the WiFi
network speaker um, which I have
also here which is more or less
a thing like a sound bar with
some integrated functionality
like Amazon Echo but with a
different Chinese echo uh alexa
thing. Um, if you open this
device you see again that it’s a
Cortex-A chip uh from Amlogic
which is quite usual for stuff
like TVs and so on. It has 128
uh Megabyte of RAM, 8 gigabyte
of flash so you can put your
music on it to play it around.
It has WiFi and bluetooth
through a Broadcom chip and it
runs openWRT. Uh, the thing here
is they use quite the old
version of Samba there which is
not so nice actually and this
whole thing was released in
2006- sorry 2016. Um, if you
open it, you can use again the
serial port which are sometimes,
which are like directly
accessible, not protected at
all. But the thing here is for
the rooting, you actually not
need to open the device. It’s
like um, classical- classical
thing, no input validation, so
what happens here is you can
just [let me see it] you can
just execute any command here as
root um so as soon as you have
access in the local network to
this device, you can just
execute anything. Um, Xiaomi
told me like a few days ago that
this was fixed in April 2018, um
so it might be fixed but most of
the people who I know don’t
actually update firmware of this
kind of devices to-to be able to
root them, so um yeah. Speaking
of firmware updates, uh it’s
funny because they like bury the
firmware update information over
http, and uh yeah, this is how
this file look- is looking like
so um I don’t know if you can
see it but the thing you have
here at the top the md5sum of
the firmware image and the
package is downloaded again over
http. Um, this whole thing is
packed in some kind of xml
format and it contains the EXT2
images and again it doesn’t have
any signatures, so basically um,
this is good for us because we
can just modify the- do some DNS
redirection and just push any
firmware updates we want on this
device, uh but it’s a little bit
scary in terms of you know
software quality, uh because
especi-so we actually have again
an L stack in open XML on this
device it could do ssl if it
wanted to, but we don’t want to
apparently. Um, I’m not sure if
it’s still like vulnerable,
maybe they changed it again also
with this latest update, but um,
just to give you an impression,
what you see out there in IoT.
Ok, so let’s move to our the
hottest device more or less and
th vacuum clean robots. Um, so
the, for the generation one um,
Danny Bigama and I uh published
that under cross communication
congress in 2017, so last
December, um, but now is also
like generation two and so on.
So, to give you an overview of
what kind of devices we talking
of, um this is uh, generation 1.
What you see here so it has
lighter sensor, this laser thing
to measure the room, it has a
lot of other sensors like um
infrared sensors, um ultrasonic
sensors, a gyroscope is
integrated in this device and
the accelerometer. So, it’s
basically a smartphone but have
some wheels and have some vacuum
function. Um, if you tear down
then it’s actually it’s very
nice to-to open the device
because you don’t have any weird
connectors which can be can,
which can break, so it’s like
the other pods are open pods and
it’s very nice to you know
reverse engineer that and the
device is engineered. And take a
look at a PCP you see that
there’s on the main PCP we have
two processors, and one on the
left side, um, uh this is the
quad core R16, um and with that
connected is like 512 MB of RAM
and we have 4 GB of flash. Um,
the WiFi module is connected to
what sdio, and for all the uh
return tests, for the tires for
example, uh for the wheels,
sorry uh for the uh sensors, we
have the STM32, uh which is
taken care of this one uh in the
orange field,uh which is taking
care of all the retimes test.
One fun thing here, so the uh,
the quad core, the R16 has the
SWD connection to the STM32 so
it can update to a flash over
like more or less a Jtag thing
and on the other side the STM32
is taking care of all the energy
stuff. So if anything is
happening while the firmware
update, if anything goes wrong
on these devices, it’s a breaked
one because the STM32 doesn’t
power on the device and the main
processor doesn’t have any
chance to update, to repair the
STM32 that’s like a texican
mixoff uh- texican standoff
train here. Ok, um on the
backside, no big surprises at
some point after reverse
engineering we’ve figured out
where the serial port is. The
serial port is actually the only
two test points on this like
huge field of test points, which
doesn’t have label, which is
kind of interesting. Alright,
generation 2, this is a device
which was uh popu-uh released in
the end of 2017, so I think in
December, November-December of
2017. Um, no big surprises, they
use still the same combination
of uh of chips, they just
changed a little the layout of
the chips. So another question
is hey how we root that? And, so
a possible way to retrieve it
through the firmware is actually
the following, just unsolder the
MMC chip, but I guess for most
of the people here in this room
and including me, would actually
mean to break the device because
I don’t think I am able to re
solder VGH uh very, very nicely.
So to resolve the VGH chip is
working after that. So the um,
the weapon of choice for this
case was aluminum foil. Actually
to-to get access to the device
and now you might ask hey
how-how does it work right? Um,
and the trick is following, so
if you taking a look at the pin
layout of the chip you figure
out that the um pins for the MMC
um for the MMC chip are actually
um on the side of the
application processor so we can
technically reach them somehow.
And the trick is the following,
so if you ever bricked with
organized CPUs for example if
you have an orange pie you know
that they have a special mode,
if they cannot load a valid
image from the uh from the SD
card or from the flash then they
go in this FEL mode which is
like a special mode to reflash
the device. So what we did here
is we uh we took like s mean
fall and we’re going under the
VDA chip and shortcutting the
MMC data lines. Um, as soon as
the um device was uh trying to
boot up, the image from the MMC
flash was impossible so it was
falling back in the FEL mode and
then you could access it over
USB, upload a small tool which
dumps the whole MMC, modify the
image and rewrite the image
again to the flash. So, this was
our initial way how we got
access to this device. Um,
looking at the image it was
quite big surprise because we
run ubuntu 14 04 uh, mostly
untouched and they patch it also
on a regular basis so you see
like new package versions all
the time if you have firmware
updates. Um, for all the
navigation stuff we’re using a
software which is called player,
an open source software, and we
have of course also some
proprietary software on the
device, and one of them is
custom adbd version so you, as
soon as you connect over u-micro
usb you’ll see that there’s some
adb server-uh adbd server
running but you cannot really
connect to that because it needs
uh authent- uh to authenticate
yourself against the device and
you can’t do that because you
don’t have the information for
that, so the vendor can do that,
but you can’t. Um, there’s one
interesting thing here, they use
iptables to block the device
against like hackers or you and
they block the SSH port and they
block the player port. But
apparently we don’t know the
trick IP version 4 and IP
version 6, so they don’t know
that um, IPtables blocks version
4 traffic, that’s a good thing,
but it doesn’t block IP version
6 traffic, so IP version 6 is
not blocked at all. As soon as
the vacuum cleaner has IP
version 6 address, all ports are
open, not a good thing. Speaking
of data which is available on
the device, as soon as you get
access to the device they
produce a lot of log files and
syslogs, stats, WiFi credentials
and log files and maps. And, um
the all the data is more or less
uploaded to the cloud. So, I
figured out it’s more or less
100 gigabyte of of writes on the
MMC per year which um so it
creates tons, a lot of log
files. And the most important
thing for you now is, uh if you
do a factory reset, the data is
not deleted, so the maps are
still there and the log files
including the WiFi credentials
are still on the vacuum cleaner.
So, be careful if you sell these
devices on ebay. Um, speaking of
maps, this is how the maps looks
like. So you have like uh, um
accuracy of more or less like 5
cm per pixel, uh I think in
stupid units it’s like 2 inches,
I believe, yeah, okay. So, let’s
take a look at MMC and here um,
so what you see here is you have
like multiple copies of the
operation system. So system a
and system b and the recovery
version. And now for the next
step of the firmware update only
like these partitions are
involved for-for our interest.
Um, so let’s take a look at the
how the update processes work.
Um, so in the introduction I
told you but the cloud can send
like the update command to the
device and this is how it
happening, so, we uh, it sends
an encrypted packet to the-to
the vacuum cleaner and says okay
please don’t let the firmware
update from this url and the md5
track is the following. In the
next part, what the vacuum
cleaner is doing, is we’ll
happily do that and download the
um firmware package to the, to
the data partition checks in the
next step if the Md5 track is
actually the one which has which
was received by the cloud. If
it’s that’s the case it uses
some secret key to decrypt the
image and it unpacks it to the
download partition. In the next
step what it does and this is
actually quite clever, they
update the root password so
every device have a specific
root password which is like
burnt into the device. And in
the next step, uh, the- this
updated version is now now um
imaged to the passive copy of
the operation system. Next step
is the, the vacuum cleaner needs
some time to think and reboot,
and reboots the now updated
version of the-of the operation
system, and in the last step the
update like to form our active
version and um at the end of the
day you end with completely
updated vacuum cleaner. So, this
is more or less the standard way
also how operating devices do
that so we have like two copies
of the operation system, you
always update first the passive
copy and then you change uh, you
do updating the active copy.
Okay, taking a look at the
firmware updates themselves,
like I said, uh the Md5 is
provided by the cloud so this is
the integrity. Um, the images
are encrypted to archives and
they have an ext4 file system in
there. And they are encrypted
with as256 and they use a tool
which is called CCrypt and is
delivered in all uh linux
distributions. Interesting thing
here is the password is rockrobo
so uh not very cr-creative for a
firm encryption password, and
also like I said, the same
password for all devices so
basically you can create
firmware with that. Um, the fun
thing here is actually the
protect the sound packages way
better so that the password for
the-for the sound packages is
more, way more complex. Um, so
sound packages are these things
where you can make your vacuum
cleaner speak like the
transformers or something. So,
this kind of stuff is better
protected than the actual
firmware. How you can figure it
out, how uh, how you find this
kind of password, well um if you
reverse engineer like the
binaries, and you just look,
taking a look at the strings
when you find something like
that. So, secret and then next
to that, some, some other
string. First, uh when I
remember, um when we were
looking last year at this kind
of binary we first thought it
was the house name because the
house name is also rockrobo.
Later, after we figured out the
password for the sound files we
figured out oh it’s actually the
password rockrobo for the- for
the firmware, we couldn’t
believe it first time, was like
totally weird. Ok, now we have
the firmware passwords, so,
let’s root this thing remotely.
So, we can rebuild the firmware,
we put our authorized key file
into this image, we remove the
iptables roots for ip version 4.
And then we just uh send the
updated command to the device
encrypted with token, and point
to our own http server. So, this
is how it look like, so we put
our vacuum cleaner for example
in the pr-unprovisioned state,
we ask them for the token um and
then we send the update uh, uh
command to it and it will
happily update that. And after
today, you can add SSH to that,
you can install all your
software that you get. Update,
for example installed,
everything runs, and you can run
everything. There’s um, sadly
some countermeasures which they
can do against us, and one of
them is for example they can
change the firmware key. Um, but
this is more or less um now I
think it’s useless, cause we can
quite easily figure it out
being, we can just take a look
at that. And, the other thing
which they started to do like in
the in like recent versions of
the firmware, they encrypt and
obfuscate the log files and maps
on the device, so it’s like,
it’s a little bit more difficult
to- to see the cloud
communication clear. But, here
is again the typical case of
yeah here’s the encryption key,
and at least we tried. Um, they
quite, they make a quite good
job to obfuscate the actual
encryption key in the battery,
but there’s a small trick how
you can get a key and the trick
is the following. So, this
binary is using the AES
encryption functions of openSSL
and uh so it’s imported as a
dynamic library and um, the
interesting function here uh is
EncryptInit. So this is the
standard openSSL function where
one of the parameter is the AES
key. If you use a tool like
ltrace which you can probably
install on the vacuum cleaner
it’s an open tool, then you can
intercept this library call then
you’ll see just the password in
plain text. Um, so very easy.
Um, as soon as you have root
access you want to stay
persistent on the device and the
first thing you want to do is
actually patch the recovery
partition. So, uh if eve-if
anything goes wrong, you can
just reinstall the recovery and
then you have a rooted system
again. So um, the same stuff you
can replace for example the adb,
um with the open source adb
version, then you have usb
access and disable the file for
example too. Um, if you want to
make sure that this device can’t
do any updates anymore, you can
kill the sys- uh Sysupdate
process or you can just disable
um the Ccrypt tool then it
cannot encrypt the updates
anymore. And the good thing
always if you have root access
to a device, get a copy of uh
specific files like the device
ID and the cloud key, or, they
have also the root password
there, um which is like device
specific and later on you can
access this device uh, for
example if it says h4 over
serial which is kind of root
password. Um, there’s a small
side note of one thing which I
noticed like last year
incorporation of young
[inaudible] and actually the
token is AES 256 bit key and the
method of use to generate this
key is the following, so we
initialize the C function called
Srand and give it the seed its
actually the the the time which
which they use there and the the
thing about srand is actually
it’s only 2 to the power of 31
states so maybe not the best
idea to create AES keys and then
we just run 16 times the rand
function to get every byte of
the of the key. So, at the end
of the day what this means uh is
so instead of breaking a 256 bit
key, you just have to break
something that has like 251
sorry which only has 31 bits, uh
not the best idea to generate
cryptographically safe keys. Um,
this by the way, this is just an
example so this is like at
multiple times an also in other
IoT devices, uh a lot of devices
generate there keys this way and
this is not super clever. So,
how about a summary? Now we can
uh root this device remotely, we
don’t need the foil attack
anymore because we know the
passwords now. Um, for the cloud
connection we can run it
completely without the cloud, um
there’s some support for uh from
third party tools like uh, uh
FHEM, uh FloleVac which is like
an android app where you can
control vacuum cleaner without
the cloud. Or you can run it
with your own cloud and this
case, dust cloud. So, we have
now rooted devices so let’s get
fun with hacking them. Um, so
the first case uh like some
examples what you can do with
them, first case is get a
connection to the dark side. And
this was an idea um initially by
professor Noubir, who said hey
can this vacuum cleaner actually
run Tor? And it can and um, so
um let’s just run a Tor hidden
service on it. And so for the
reason for that, why he asked
that is there is a paper from
2015 um which described a thing
named OnionBots where you used
Tor to create a stealthy botnet
um with compromised IoT devices,
which communicate with some um,
uh neighbor devices and um so it
cannot be detected. And,
installing Tor is very easy,
it’s in the bluetooth so you
just install Tor package, uh you
can make for example SSH
accessible over Tor and you
don’t need any NAT anymore plot
for waiting so you can just
access your vacuum cleaner
remotely. Another thing, um the
generation 2 here, uh has a lot
of empty space, in um in the
case, and you can use that, um
for certain things. For example,
if you remember the breaked one
of the camera gateways and it
has a Zigbee module I uh just
unsoldered and connected it to
the vacuum cleaner. I could take
just the ad binaries uh for the
gateway function and here uh
from the camera put it on the
vacuum cleaner and run natively
and now I have a zombie gateway
vacuum cleaner which has Zigbee
functionality, and it can clean
your uh your room. Another thing
what I- what some people did is
they um uh tried to put like
more stuff there on the device,
but the thing is you have only
like 512 megabyte of this
partition and one break around
for this is theoretically you
can solder a micro USB stick
into this thing, so we have more
space. Another example, you can
use it as a mobile WiFi mapper.
Um, this vacuum cleaner produces
a lot of log files and the log
files um give you the x and y
position, the drop position and
um from the counter you can ask
it specific information about
the WiFi. The link, level, kind
of SSIDs. So, this was one
project I developed and um this
year I think a few months ago
with Andrew Tu, on some um on
the hackbeanpot in Boston and it
was a mobile WiFi mapper. So,
what happens here is uh so on
the left side you see the layout
of the office where the
hackathon was happening and then
the right side you see the
signal strength of it so x an y.
Uh if you were see it from the
side it looks like a little bit
better and in terms of you see
here again um x and y, and here
the signal strength. And this
vacuum cleaner was driving
around to this office and was
mapping the WiFi signal so then
you know exactly ok where the
WiFi is like good or not good.
If you need more additional
space, um this is one thing that
was done by one of the dustcloud
users because it breaked uh he
has a broken MMC chip and it's
usually not recommended for
everyone. So what he did is he
actually unsoldered the um MMC
chip and soldered the SD card to
it, and at end of the day he had
like double the space. And, just
to give you an idea how precise
he worked, I mean this is uh
really impressive, I couldn’t do
that..my hands are too shaky for
that. And the last example, this
is like a demo, I actually
wanted to do like a real but the
thing is I can’t connect really
vacuum cleaner to the to the
WiFi here so I have to do it
here on video. Um, IoT can chat
with IoT devices, and you see on
the left side there's an Amazon
Echo, and on the right side
there’s the vacuum cleaner and
let’s see if it works. Here
nothing [inaudible sounds from
the echo] okay I just redo it
again >> “Alexa what’s the
weather?” >>“Currently in Boston
it’s 21 degrees celsius with
mostly sunny skies” >>So you
have like some speaker which can
drive around in your apartment
and which can speak to your IT.
Okay, um one word of warning uh,
this is always um a very
important thing, because many
people don’t understand like a
problem in all this kind of
cases. Never leave your devices
unprovisioned. Uh if you leave
your devices unprovisioned it
has this open WiFi access point
and someone else, your nice
neighbor can provision that for
you, and can install some
malicious firmware. The other
thing is, be very careful with
used devices. If you buy devices
out of Amazon marketplace or
Ebay, you have no idea what kind
of software is running on this
device. Um, you have no way to
figure out if its malicious
firmware or not. Um, yeah, and
another thing this should be
actually I mean common sense but
some people still do that, never
install rooted firmware from
untrusted sources. For the
vacuum cleaners we have to like
in Russian forums like uh here
we pre rooted the devices for
you and we changed the language
files for you I mean why people
do install that? I mean it’s
very easy to create your own
firmware but some people said
like oh yeah I saved the 5
minutes I just downloaded this
weird firmware from the Russian
website. Uh, geeze, ok. So, for
the conclusion, um, the best
practices for IoT devices is
actually to not used, the
firmware signatures are
completely missing um if they
use https then its sometimes
broken or not existing.
Certificate verification is
sometimes a real problem, um
actually all hardware security
features are missing, so
sometimes, things like you
disable jpeg but enable secure
boot and so on. They never use
that and never saw that in any
of these devices. The good thing
is we can modify the devices
which is a nice thing; the bad
thing is someone else can do
that too, so um be very careful
with that. So, this is almost
the end of my presentation but I
want to thank some people, um,
first I want to thank Danny
Wegemer whose like sitting here
in the front uh this was my
partner when the research when
we started that. Um, another
person I want to thank is
professor Noubir in Northeastern
University, also I want to thank
the SEEMO labs at TU Darmstadt
and because legal stuff and
seeing US as a little bit more
problematic also Andrew Sellars
and his team from the Boston
Cyberlaw clinic at Boston
University Cyberlaw clinic. And
that’s all, and if you have any
questions, I don’t know if we
have time now but you can meet
me at the IoT village in 1 hour
or just write me a telegram
message, and I created just for
you guys a Twitter account so
you can send me twitters,
twitter messages, or meet me in
Boston, if your in Boston, I’m
also around there. Thank you
very much [ applause]