>> Hey, um, thank you all for
coming. Um My name is Yawnbox, I
co-founded, ah, Emerald Onion,
um, we’re a 501(c)3 transit ISP.
We currently route a whole bunch
of Tor exit traffic Ah, based in
Seattle Washington. [Speaker
clears throat] Um, three years
ago, um I started, ah this idea.
I started um, sharing this idea
with some friends of mine in the
privacy community, that the
current way of building up the
Tor network might not be ideal
for our th-the version of the
internet that we want and that
might be to Torify everything,
ah, to push everything through
Tor whatever, ah . I think that,
ah, Brave ah, is testing, ah um,
using Tor in the private browser
mode, um, that’s awesome. Um,
facebook has their Onion that’s
awesome, um DuckDuckGo, ah, all
of the ah, media organisations
that use SecureDrop um, that’s
great, um but if we want more,
um providers using Onion
services to protect their, ah,
users privacy, then I think, ah,
we need to go about building our
Tor infrastructure and privacy
infrastructure, ah, a little bit
better. So, a year ago, um, me
and some friends, ah co-ah-co-
founded Emerald Onion, um, we
registered in Seattle, in
Washington State Um, and ah,
we’ve been online for a short,
ah, little over a year now. Um,
most of the content in, in my
slide deck is, or details of the
content, is on our website
emerald onion dot org. Um, cause
I don’t have enough time to go
through all of the detail
[Speaker laughs] in this talk.
So, um, starting up, we ah, did
the Washington non-profit ah,
status, um, for a few dollars.
Ah, the articles and
incorporation that we did, were,
are compliant, are compliant
with, ah, the IRS 501(c)(3)
requirements, um, it’s there on
that website there emerald onion
dot org forward slash articles,
um, so I should step back
actually real quick. So, one of
the overall um, purposes of
Emerald Onion, is to, like, try
all of this stuff, make it work
and then publish, ah, what we do
on our website. So, like the
articles, um, like all the other
stuff in-in this, ah,
presentation they’re gonna be
online, so that you all can, ah
easily, ah, approach, ah,
these-these problems. So um,
step two for us was registering
with Arin, ah, to get our ASN
and our IPv6 and IPv4 scopes.
So, Arin, if you don’t know is,
um like a domain registrar,
except instead of going for,
there for domains, you go there
for IP’s. There’s an application
process, ah, you, um have an ASN
that you use to talk to other
ASNs if you're using, ah,
protocols like BGP, which we,
which we do. And, ah, this
process, ah took a little, a
little less than a month. Um,
The, ah, [Speaker makes noise]
um, application, ah process that
we went through is also
published on our website, um, so
that you can, ah, more easily,
ah do that. So, um, this is our
ASN, um, we have a slash 36 IPv6
scope, ah, we have a slash 24
IPv4 scope, um, AS-ah, we, we
use our ASN, again to
communicate with other ASNs that
we peer with in the Seattle
internet exchange, um, [Speaker
clears throat] This is hard,
[Speaker laughs] [audience
applause] Thanks. Oh So, yeah,
ASNs, they’re cool. So, um,
[audience laughter] use your ASN
to announce to other ASNs, um,
yeah, we use BGP, um. So, one
really cool thing that we found
out, um, someone randomly told
us on twitter, which was pretty
cool. So, um, IPv4, um, scopes
are exhausted in a few years
ago. Um, Arin, um, actually has
this 4 Dot Ten policy, um, which
was ,ah, set aside to facilitate
the adoption of IPv6. Um, so if
you can articulate to Arin and
apply, go through that process,
they’ll actually give you a free
slash 24, ah IPv4 scope, and so
that’s what we did. Um, we were
able to articulate this because
Tor in its current state, um,
only supports IPv4 traffic. IPv4
traffic between, ah relays, so
from middle to, or from guard to
middle, from middle to exit,
that’s all IPv4 only. Um, Tor
project wants to expand and, and
do more IPv6, but we need more
operators to use IPv6 in order
to, ah, curtail potential
surveillance issues around ah,
having a limited, ah, subset of,
um our, ah, nodes, um, being, ah
IPv4 only. [Speaker sniffs] Um,
so please, ah, add, if you're an
operator, please support IPv6,
because we need it and hopefully
one day we’ll be able to only
use IPv6 and we can get rid of
our-our IPv4 scopes. Um, So, ah,
because our, long term goal was
to get 501(c)(3) status as a
public charity, ah, Sorry,
that’s a little early. Um, so
the IRS EIN, so this is
basically you're social security
number for your organisation,
it’s a quick easy thing that you
do online. Um, 501(c)(3) so we,
ah, wanted to become a public
charity, so that we could be
sustainable in our funding Um,
it’s easy, ah, if you do it
right. Like, this was one of the
biggest hurdles that we had
mentally, like going into this
we had no idea how long it was
going to take, if it was going
to be possible. We were being
coached by Riseup networks and
Calyx Institute and other
not-for profits, and it just
seemed like this might be an
impossible task, in this current
day and age for a-a tech
organisation to get 501(c)(3)
charity status, um, it was
actually real easy. Um, so, um,
The trick that we learned, is
that, ah, don’t make 50 000
dollars in your, um, operating
budget, like for your first
year. Um, and that qualifies you
for the 1023-EZ, the 1023 is
what you would use to apply for
a 501(c)(3) status, ah, through
the IRS. Um, and make sure you
do that, um, within the first
year roughly, um, so do that.
Um, so the 1023-EZ, ah, n-not
only made it, ah, cheap, it was
275 dollars compared to, I think
the normal 1023 process is, like
850 dollars. Ah, we didn’t need
a CPA, we didn’t need a lawyer,
ah, and if, you can see by these
dates here, like, it was, it was
like six- sixteen days. I mean,
for some reason the IRS didn’t
actually tell us that we got
charity status, we had to look
it up manually online,um, so
cool, but we got it. So, um,
Part of our articles of
incorporation, ah, this is
article four, um, one of our
goals as a organisation that
wants to support privacy, was to
try and make sure that our scope
was general, um, so the purpose
of this corporation is to
promote and support online
[Speaker stutters] anonymity and
privacy. Ah, we wanted to keep
it very general, so that in the
event that Tor is, you know, the
hot stuff right now, maybe mixed
nuts, maybe whatever is gonna
be, um, what we need to build
out in the future. Um, and
there’s a whole bunch of other
stuff that we could potentially
do as a 501(c)(3) charity, so we
wanted a, a general mission
statement. [Speaker sniffs] Um,
another small, ah, thing in the
1023 process, ah, this is how
you, ah, signify through the IRS
what kind of an organisation
that you are. Ah, there’s a huge
list of NTEE codes, um, we spent
a couple of weeks, like , going
through all of them and deciding
which one we wanted to go with.
Um, but we felt like this was
the best one, given our, um,
presumed scope for operating as
a transit ISP. Um, so as you can
see here, um, this was the
timeline and how much it costs
to like, legitimately become a
501(c)(3), 501(c)(3) transit
ISP. Ah, if we had known that
the IRS process was gonna be so
easy, we’d have done that, ah,
sooner and we probably could’ve
done it by July. Um, but, yeah,
so, like bottom line it’s, this
is something that you can do,
this is not that hard. We didn’t
need a CPA, we didn’t need a
lawyer, we had them anyway,
because we were fortunate in our
network of friends and family,
um, supported us. But it's
actually not needed, if, if you,
if you do these things in the
right way. So, ah, we turned on
our exit relays in July, um, of
2017. Um, we actually made a
small mistake that, um, I wanna
touch on real quick. Um, we
originally first leased our IP
space from our upstream ISP. Ah,
we should have just run as a
middle relay until we got our
own IP scopes. Um, so there was
one day when our ISP, ah,
e-mailed us and said, hey, we’re
getting abuse, ah, we’re gonna
start charging you a dollar an
abuse complaint, if you ah, if,
if you don’t stop. So, that
would’ve been kind of expensive
and, ah, thankfully the, um,
Arin had already approved our IP
scopes, so-so we were, um, in
transition already to use our
own scopes. Um, but it’s just a
lot easier starting out, if you
start as a middle relay and then
once you get your own IP scopes,
go towards, ah, you can start
exiting. So in this,ah, year
process , we, ah, transit 3
point 5, ah, pebibytes of data
and we received, ah, r-roughly
3100, um, unique abuse
complaints. Um, 99 percent of
these abuse complaints were
automated, um, we noticed, but
they came in none the less. Um,
most of them also don’t require
any kind of response, but we
responded anyway, just to be
proactive, just in case
something were to escalate. Um,
and we, we use, ah, Zendesk to
automated that, um automated
response back and we serve our
legal FAQ, which I will be
talking about shortly. Um, to
educate them about what we do
and why we’re doing it. So if,
ah, basic math here, ah, which I
think is pretty cool, um, for
every 1 point 2 terabyte, no
sorry 1 point 13 terabytes, ah,
we receive an abuse complaint.
And that’s a unique abuse
complaint and it could be
anything from spam, because,
we-we run as an unfiltered exit
router, so we don’t block any
ports. Um, could be spam, could
be SSH attacking, I don’t know,
like there’s just a bunch of
random stuff. We used to get a
bunch of DMCA, but that stopped
randomly. Um [Speaker sniffs]
So, ah, Emerald Onion, ah,
preemptively develops, um, a
strongly go backbone right at
the beginning, ah we reached out
to, um, M-Marsha Hoffman at
Zeitgeist Law, um, to help us
create ah, some legal FAQs. Um,
that are also on our website
site for free. Um, Im so please,
check them out and use them if
you're a-a operating like we are
in the United States, cause
they’re not really valid
anywhere else. Ah, we have two
versions of the legal FAQ, ah,
one of them you would give to
your ISP, if your ISP receives
an abuse complaint, you can give
them this FA-FA-FAQ and um, it
would be valid in explaining,
like, what you're doing is
legal. Um, And then, we have
another legal FAQ, which is if
you would receive abuse from
anyone, so that is the one that
we use for automated responding
now that we have our own IP
space. Um, So, um, one small
thing we ah, we just note
publicly that, ah, we don’t log
any information. Um, Tor does a
good job of this already, but
we, um audit our um, devices to
make sure that we don’t log any
network information, um, above
and beyond what Tor already
doesn’t record. So, the extent
of what we, I guess technically
have, is like DNS cache, um, and
BGP ah, caches, but none of
those are super sensitive, um,
thankfully. So, this is, ah,
this is our policy that we state
on our website.. Um, there’s
Yeah. So, DMCA is interesting
it’s stupid, but it’s here, um,
basically, ah, in order to be
compliant, ah, with the, ah
DMCA, ah safe harbour-r. The
DMCA protections have a conduit
provider, um, you need to have a
termination policy. Ah, this is
our termination policy,um, here.
Um, it basically says, ah, we
don’t have any subscribers, we
can’t identify our users, but in
appropriate circumstances we’ll,
ah terminate. Um, we don’t
really have a technical way to
do that because of Tor, but we
have to have this policy just to
be compliant with the DMCA, ah,
protections, so cool. Okay, so,
um, also in the past year we
received two subpoenas, um this
is just one example, um, both of
them were from the, ah,
Department of Homeland Security.
Um, we published a transparency
report here at this, ah, on our
website and, ah, there’s a whole
bunch of other things beyond
subpoenas that we list just to
be explicit. Um, so we update
that regularly. Ah, this was
pretty scary for us to receive
the first time, like, we kinda
expected that something might
eventually happen, just talking
to Calex and other operators.
Um, these came in via email,
they don’t come in via mail,
that surprised us. Um, so they
send it to our admin ad-address,
ah, it-it was really scary at
first, but it-it doesn’t seem
that way, ah now just because
we’ve had a little bit of
practice. Um, so basically like,
some takeaways, don’t run an
exit router from your home
obviously. Tor project does a
good job, ah educating people
about this. Um, the reason why
you don’t want that, is because
you don’t wanna be at the you
don’t want law enforcement to
come and kick in your door and
take your computer's just
because, um, someone did
something, presumably malicious
from your exit router.So put it
in a data center and ah, ideally
own your own IP scopes, ah like
you own, s-ah, V6 and V4 address
scopes. Um, and that way you
can, instead of being at the
part of law enforcement where
they come and kick down your
door and take your stuff. Ah,
they come, they-they send you an
email and they’re civil and like
okay and we have this IP
address, ah, we need some user
data and we can just literally
just reply and say hey we’re
running Tor, ah, we don’t have
data, here’s your legal FAQ. Ah,
please let us know if, if we-we
can help further. Um, again, a
lawyer isn’t needed for this
process, um, at first we did
have a general council call and
just talk to them, just to
understand this process. But, ah
it’s actually to the point where
we’re just gonna email them back
now if they send us another one
and just say, hey, we can’t
help, sorry. Um, so today we’re
launching a new program, ah,
it’s called Onion dot Lawyer.
Um, something that's been
missing in the Tor community for
awhile, is clear legal support.
Ah, so, our general counsel Matt
McCoy is, ah, leading this and
in partnership with the Yale
Privacy Lab. Ah, it’s a
distribution that you can
contact in the event that you
are under legal duress, because
of your operations with Tor. Um,
it’s a network of pro-bono
attorneys that um, will do their
best to support you in the event
that you need help. Um, if they
can’t, hopefully their networks
can find someone that can, um,
but hopefully this is something
that becomes important in
supporting, ah, operators. Um,
oh, yes if you're an attorney,
ah please reach out and um,
volunteer for this. If you have
a friend that’s an attorney,
please convince them that this
is something that they might
want to do and have them reach
out, ah so that we can grow
this. [Speaker sniffs] Okay ,so
data centre stuff. So to move in
we had to have three types of
insurance, this is the three
types. Ah, we bought our own
hardware, ah we used low power Z
on D platform that has
integrated 10 gigabit, ah fibre,
so it’s nice and ah, cool and
has good connectivity. Um, we,
because the Tor network is
roughly 90 percent Debian, ah,
we, decided to go with a BSD
platform. We decided to go with
hardened BSD, because of
its,inherent, ah, exploit
mitigations and general
security, which we think also
improves the health of the Tor
network. Um, this is an
outstanding project if you are
into BSD, please support them,
ah, if you're an operator,
please consider using hardened
BSD or something that isn’t
Debian, that’d be cool. Um, Yeah
[ Speaker sniffs] Okay, so this
is our current call location and
our costs, nothing special about
it. We have a gigabit, um,
unmetered link, um this
particular link is actually part
of our, um, internet exchange
point connectivity, so we
transit through that connection,
so we only have one ten gigabit
fibre drop, which is cool. And
then,um, we have connectivity
with the Seattle Internet
Exchange, which I will talk more
about here. So, um, internet
exchange points are really
cool,ah, they provide, ah direct
access to a whole bunch of peers
and what, what I mean by peer
is, someone that you physically
connect to. And this is really
important for Tor exit
operating, because instead of
you, that Tor exit traffic. Say
you're facilitating the Tor
traffic from a middle relay to
your exit and then its going out
to the internet, ah from that
exit. Ah, it is ideal, I think
in that, that traffic that
you're exiting to its final
destination has as little hops
as possible. And what I mean by
a hop, is some other router or
switch on the internet, that is
owned by some unknown company
and every one that it traverses
is an opportunity for
surveillance in some form or
fashion. Ah, so peering, is
really awesome I think for, ah
the Tor network, not just
because of latency minimisation.
Like, I think our average, ah
latency to our peers in the six
is point 3-5 milliseconds, so
it's really quick. Um, so that
also helps, ah, ex-user
experience kind of. Ah, but
mainly it’s, it’s the
surv-surveillance
min-minimisation properties of
IXPs that we think that is
really valuable. So, as you can
see here, we appear here
directly with Google, with
Amazon, with Akamai, OpenDNS,
twitter, so if people are using
our exit relays, they’re gonna,
um, terminate at those endpoints
very quickly and with no other
third parties observing that
traffic, hopefully. Aside from
like the route servers that we
connect to in the IXP. Um,
hoping that they’re not
backdoored and I’ll talk more
about that. Um, So, um, we are,
we - jumping into this like we
were kinda fortunate with the
Seattle Internet Exchange, it’s
a non-profit IXP, um, it’s
[Speaker stutters] it’s, it
advises that you don’t surveil
the ports if you're a peer, um,
which is good. Um, I’m hoping
that they eventually one day
adopt a transparency report,
that would be better. Um,
nonprofits have inherent
transparency aspects to them,
like publishing where they get
their money, what they spend it
on, stuff like that. So, finding
non-profit IXPs, I think is
really awesome. Ah,
geo-location, so, um, that could
mean, ah, it’s proximity to,
like an undersea cable. It could
mean, ah, it’s, ah proximity to
a certain provider, it could,
ah, there's like a hundred and
,um, I think twenty about IXPs
in the United States. Ah, so
there’s quite a selection and
m-most of them are, um in dense
areas to begin with, so there’s
not a lot of choice. But there’s
some strategic things that you
can, um, some strategic choices
that you can make. So
participation, ah, this could be
like, ah, a certain provider
like Amazon, ah like CloudFlare,
Akamai, like big providers. Ah,
places that traffic [speaker
stutters] ah, will go on the
internet. Um, the-the more the
better, ah, so that there’s more
peers, ah, that you exit-exiting
traffic to. And then of course,
costs, ah, most of the IXPs, ah,
that we’ve seen are for profit
and pretty expensive. Our’s, we
paid 2000 dollars for a 10 Gig
port, ah, it’s a one time cost,
there’s no recurring fees, which
is awesome, ah, so, not many are
like that. [Speaker sniffs] Um,
this was a recent article, um,
about the biggest, one of the
biggest IXPs in the world and
wh-a-ah, it’s in Germany, which
is unfortunate, because a lot of
the Tor network is in Germany.
Like, just because of their, how
cheap their brandwidth is, um,
it’s not clear how good or,
obviously not good. How bad this
might be for the Tor network,
um, personally I would try to
avoid DE-CIX, just because of
this known issue of active
government surveillance. Um,
also part of Five Eyes, um so
it-it’s best to,ah avoid that if
possible. Um, so challenges for
finding good IXPs, um, obviously
if they’re under active
surveillance that’s not ideal.
Um, there’s lots of data centres
without IXPs, like I said
there’s a 120 roughly in the
United States. Ah, there, um,
large IXPs so Comcast, ah AT&T
whatever um, because they’re
profit driven, they tend to have
restrictive peering policies,
which means they’re not open to
peering with anyone. They’re
only going to,ah, charge money,
um, which is not good for,ah, I
think surveillance. Um, or I
should say privacy. And then
content providers with no
peering policies, so ah, some
providers just re-refuse to
peer, because it doesn’t make
sense. Um, which is also
unfortunate, because that means
we can’t, it means we have to
send traffic around in some
other way and it’s going through
some other provider, that we
just have no accountability for.
That there’s no accountability
for. Okay, so under sea cables,
so we know that these are, we-we
have a good, guess, that these
are all tapped. Um, which is
lame, um, The way that the Tor,
ah, bandwidth authority is
currently work means that the,
the Tor traffic largely, um,
bounces back and forth between,
West, ah, Western Europe and
Eastern United States. So
there’s a whole lot of traffic
that crosses the Atlantic ocean.
Um, This, um, We-we have a
working theory where, um there
could be some more strategic
decisions made in order to
place, ah, Tor routers,
especially exit routers. Um, one
of them is to place them in
IXPs, because of the early
termination and the properties
there. Another, is because, or
if- if they can be placed close
to under sea cables, so again,
so if it can receive that
traffic as soon as it comes into
the US, ah, and it can terminate
as quickly as it can without
going anywhere else in the US,
that I think is better. So, we,
um, are just developing this
theory, or we’re trying to find,
ah, things that can help us
m-more strategically place exit
routers around the US. Ah,
today, we’re also launching this
project called Safe Crossing.
Ah, the first part of this is
just ex, us ex-ah, Emerald Onion
expanding into other places in
the US. Ah, we think we’re gonna
go somewhere along the east
coast, um, because of the, um,
things that I've just discussed.
Um, but more importantly Safe
Crossing is going to be research
and development around the
deployment of net new IXPs. Ah,
so because of our experience
with not being able to find
non-profit affordable,ah,
[Inaudible] IXPs of the
qualities that I already talked
about. Ah, we want to build our
own, so, ah, where there is
dense connectivity, um, we’re
looking there. Um, there’s some
underserved areas that we think
that IXPs could be built, ah,
places, ah, like Puerto Rico, we
think would be a really great
starting point for something
like this. Um, But it’s
basically to compete with, ah,
the profit driven IXPs that are
also generally surveillance
friendly. So, it’s about
creating safer spaces on the
internet, ah, like basically
kinda the backbone of the
internet. Um, this kind of a
cheap way to do that. Um, create
safe spaces for traffic to, um,
move about. Um, if you are
interested in helping create,
um, non-profit IXPs and being
involved with Safe Crossing,
please contact us here. Um,
particularly if you're involved
with like the open compute
projects or interested in that
platform, because, ah, it’s open
hardware, ah, free delivery
software. Um, it goes up to 100
Gigabit, um, it just seems like
an ideal platform that creates
a, a safe space for ah, your
compute infrastructure. If you
have any IXP management
experience, we are interested in
learning more about how to
actually build one. Um, we'll
figure it out. Um, if you have
IP scopes or are working for a
company that has IP scopes, ah,
that you’re not using, ah like
IPv4 scopes. Um, consider
donating them to us, um, cause
we will either use them or we’ll
give them to an organisation
like us, that is able to, to use
them for privacy. Um, and we’re
looking for partners, so if we
can create, um, I, one IXP
somewhere, um we wanna have like
big partners on day one. So that
it ah, entices other people to
become part of this new, um,
mission. And, ah, grow, grow the
infrastructure in that region,
ah, cause the more peers the
better. So, ah, this is our ah,
just some quick details about
our income. Ah, we, to get
started we received a grant from
Tor service dot net, ah for 5000
dollars. Our directors have been
donating monthly, um, currently
up to the sum of about 10 000
dollars. Ah, we’ve received
about a 1000 dollars of direct
funding and ah, DuckDuckGo
included us in their privacy
challenge, this pa - couple of
months ago. Um, and we received
enough money to s-ah pay for our
whole year of operations for
this next year,which is awesome.
Um, in the, the PayPal giving
campaign, um, someone signed us
up for that and they just sent
us a random cheque, which was
cool. Um, but that’s like the
benefit of like being a
501(c)(3) ah, charity, is you
can take advantage of some of
these programs. Another one that
I didn’t mention here, that we
haven’t really used yet, is, ah,
um, if your company ah price er,
matches donations that you make
to non-profits. Um, because
we’re in those networks as well
[Speaker counting] which is
cool, um challenges. So,ah,
fees, obviously money, it costs
money to do this stuff. Um, IP
transit, that’s our ISP, ASN
fees, IPv-IP scope fees.
Transport is where you have to
lay like fibre from point to
point within the data center, so
that has a recurring cost
sometimes. Um, call location
fees, equipment fees, peering
port fees, so these are all
challenges that we have. Um,
we’re trying to figure out ways
that we can make these, ah,
cheap or free and share that
information with the larger
community. Ah, Generally, it’s
hard to prioritise privacy over
anything else. Um, like it’s
really cool to work for Emerald
Onion and - and like, think
about privacy first. Ah, not
logging, ah, using disk
encryption, whatever, um, But
it, it makes it hard, because we
can’t, we can’t log. So, when
someone dosses us, we actually
have no idea who does it,
because we don’t - we don’t log
the perimeter firewall, just in
case, ah, some Tor user ends up
hitting our firewall in some
weird way and causes us to log
the traffic. We just don’t want
the IPs. So, making those kinds
of choices makes it hard to
operate in that way, ah, but
that’s what we think is
important. So we prioritise
privacy, ah, over money. Um,
open source networking hardware,
so, there is more and more open
hardware showing up, but
specifically networking hardware
is unique. Ah, both Firmware and
like Fullstat Compute is-is, is
challenging. There’s some
options out there, out there,
like I mentioned the open
compute project. But there needs
to more, ah, we can always use
more. Ah, network redundancies,
so one thing that we want to do
better, ah is having redundancy
in our WAN and LAN stacks, but
if we want redundancy there,
we’re going to be multiplying
our costs by at least a factor
of two. Just because we have to
have at least two of everything,
but that usually comes with
other additional costs as well.
So, we, we want to, ah, have
that, but again that’s, that’s a
big challenge. Um, IPv4 scopes,
ah, obviously because of the
exhaustion issue, um, it creates
a higher bar for someone jumping
into this, to get started. If
they could just jump in with
only an IPv6 scope, that would
be easier. Um, and of course
technical volunteers, is hard to
find people and keep people that
are passionate about this stuff.
Um, so it’s always a, a
challenge. Um, so I wanted to
give a quick shout out to Tor
projects for hiring ah, their,
their relay advocate, um,
Colon,ah, aka Fool, is ah, their
advocate. Um, he, if you're an
operator he probably has already
reached out to you, if you have
updated contact information in
your Torrent C-file. So, um, if
you need help, ah, directly
something you can’t get from
the, the email lists, ah, you
can reach out to Colin and he
can help you out. Um, lastly I
want to thank, ah, my team so, I
have a really amazing team of
volunteers. Ah, on the, the
board of directors and our
advisory board, um, it, it, we
just wouldn’t be here without
[Speaker laughs] the help of
everyone. So, um, Yeah, um,
thanks [Speaker laughs] That’s
I’m all done. [Audience
applause]