>>A little bit about myself. I’m
malak on Twitter. I’m 18, I’m a
student from the Bay area and I
really like locks and computers.
Lately I’ve been getting really
interested in duplicating high
security keys. Uh this my second
time going to DefCon and my
first time speaking and if
you’re working on any
interesting lock projects, come
say hi. I’d love to hear about
them. So you’ve probably seen
these things before. There’s a
good chance you even live or
work in a building that has one.
And these boxes contain the keys
to the building. So when the
firefighters show up in an
emergency, they don’t have to
start breaking stuff to get
where they need to bed. They can
just open the box, get the keys
and let themselves in. A low
tech way of doing this would be
to just keep copies of
everyone’s keys in the fire
station, but having a single key
for an entire area saves a lot
of time on an emergency. Uh the
most popular rapid entry system
is made by Knox and the Knox box
is mostly what I’ll focus on
today. And a lot of places these
things are required by law on
commercial buildings. So you can
have the best high security
locks in the world on your
doors. But you still have to put
your keys in this metal box so
that firefighters can get in. Uh
sometimes these things even have
alarm codes in them. They make
really big ones for commercial
buildings and tiny ones for
people’s houses. Again same
idea, you put your keys in the
box and the firefighters can
open the box. They also make
padlocks and key switches for
overriding gates and even boxes
with circuit breakers inside.
And all of these devices take
the same keys, which are held by
the local fire department.
Sometimes one fire department
will get their own unique Knox
key and sometimes many
departments will share the same
system. Sometimes even an entire
state will use a single Knox key
throughout. So this is basically
a physical backdoor to an entire
city or even state. Bruce
Schneier referred to it as
physical key escrow and as I’m
sure you all know by now, key
escrow isn’t really that great
for security. These are pretty
powerful keys and as you can
probably imagine, it’s kind of
bad when they fall into the
wrong hands. Here’s some footage
from a burglary in Seattle, this
guy walks up and starts messing
with something on the wall and
then he comes back with someone
else and enters the code into
their keypad that was supposed
to be reserved for the fire
department and they open the
door, go in the building and
leave with some packages that
they were not supposed to leave
with. Seattle then spent half a
million dollars to rekey their
Knox boxes. Something similar
happened in Austin. Someone used
a Knox key to break into a
children’s hospital and steal 31
thousand dollars. Austin then
spent 300 thousand dollars to
rekey their Knox boxes and one
and a half million to make sure
it never happened again. They
also didn’t know how many Knox
boxes they had in their city,
but they thought it was around
to be claiming that only the
fire departments have these
keys. They got some videos on
their website where people say
like, only the fire department
has access to that box. Or only
we have a key to open it. And
I’m just not sure if that’s 100
percent accurate. I mean, this
Phoenix fire department somehow
managed to lose 850 of these
keys. And they didn’t even
notice until they counted them
after hearing about the
burglaries in Seattle. So who
knows where they are. Uh, people
can also get in a lot of trouble
for refusing to install these
things. There was an article
last year about a butcher from
Pennsylvania who didn’t want to
install a Knox box because he
didn’t like the idea of giving
strangers access to his keys.
The city threatened to put him
in jail for 30 days, fine him
building as a fire hazard. So if
people are going to be forced to
use these, I think they have a
right to know to know what’s
inside of them. A couple years
ago I got in touch with Knox to
ask about the locks they’re
using and they pretty much told
me to pound sand. They did not
want to talk to me at all. So
Knox boxes almost exclusively
use Medeco 72 series cam-loks.
Older ones use the biaxial and
newer ones uses the M3. These
are really cool locks that work
a little bit differently than
what most people are used to. I
don’t really have time to go
into exactly like they work, but
basically the cuts on the key
can have different angles as
well as depths. With the normal
key, the only thing that really
matters is how deep the cuts
are, but with Medeco’s the angle
of the cuts is also important.
The key rotates the pins as well
as lifting them up, so if you
look at a Medeco key from the
top down you can see that some
of the cuts have been twisted
one way and some have been
twisted the other. They also
don’t have any driver pins uh
this is what the key pins look
like and I think it’s a very
clever design. These things are
physically very tough and the
lock is super hard to pick. It’s
rated by UL to withstand many
different types of attacks for
30 minutes. I only know a
handful of people who can pick
these things, but unfortunately
I don’t think they offer enough
protection against of
unauthorized replication of
keys. Uh Knox is pretty serious
about key control. Uh the keys
are supposed to be kept inside
these electronic boxes, which
I’m sure are completely
unhackable. They’re also
connected to radio and wi-fi
sometimes. Which is great, but
the firefighter has to enter a
pin in order to remove the key
and it keeps track of when that
happens. So these are pretty
well protected. But even if
someone has physical access to a
key for just a few seconds, they
can still gain a lot of useful
information about it. Someone
can make measurements of it by
taking a clay impression or by
using a key decoder or just a
photograph. You don’t even need
a good photo in 2008 some
students at UC San Diego showed
that they were able to copy a
key that was photographed from
around 200 feet away. And
sometimes it’s not even
necessary to take your own
photo. After about 10 minutes of
searching on YouTube, I saw
several videos of people showing
off Knox keys. It’s probably not
good that these keys are being
posted to the internet. A, a key
is pretty much just a metal
password. Anyone who can read
it, can copy it. That being
said, it’s not always easy to
replicate a Medeco key. You
wouldn’t just be able to get one
copied at the hardware store
because they use special
restricted key blanks and only
certain people are allowed to
make copies. But these keys are
just chunks of metal and with
the right tools, any chunk of
metal can be reproduced. If you
already have the blank, you can
make the cuts on the certain key
machines, or even just by hand
with the metal file. But getting
restricted key blanks can be
kind of tricky. There are plenty
of ways to make key blanks
though. For example, modifying
another similar blank until it
fits into the lock and there
have been some attacks presented
at DefCon before. In some
situations you can make a key
blank out of a thin piece of
metal or plastic, like a credit
card. Uh this will work if the
keyway is wide open, but not so
much on the more paracentric key
ways. If you want to make a
better blank, milling is a
pretty good way to go. CNC is
good, uh there are also mills
built specifically for
duplicating key blanks, but they
are very expensive and have some
drawbacks. If you don’t have
access to one, a good 3D printer
will work too. Cheap FDM
printers are usually precise
enough to duplicate something
like a house key pretty easily,
but with higher security locks,
sometimes you need more
precision to make a reliable
key. SLA printers are really
good for this and shapeways has
some extremely precise
materials. Shapeways is a
service that will 3D print
things for you. You just upload
your file, choose your printer,
pay a couple bucks and they mail
it to you. I’ve tested most of
their materials and I like their
MJF process the best. So I’ve
been wondering how hard it would
be to print one of these keys
from scratch. It turns out it’s
really not that difficult. The
printing is pretty easy, but the
real fun begins when you start
trying to model the key.
Obviously I don’t have access to
the original key to begin with
and I can’t easily get a hold of
one, I mean, all things
considered, I think Knox is
doing a pretty good job of key
control. They’re using patent
protected keys, that are
slightly harder to duplicate
with the normal keys and the
keys are kept in special boxes
and obviously they won’t just
sell you the key, but what they
will sell you is the box and the
interesting thing is, the lock
in the box contains all of the
information necessary to
reproduce the key. The lock and
the key are pretty much mirror
images of each other. I mean, it
has to be this way because the
lock has to somehow check if the
key is correct. There’s no
encryption, no challenge
response, just some pieces of
metal interacting with each
other and they’ll sell one to
anyone who wants to put one on
their building. So I bought one
to check it out. [laughter] It
came with some cool documents
which I immediately ignored and
sure enough it shipped with the
lock installed. These things
also ship open, so it’s really
easy to just unscrew the thing
and pop the lock out. [applause]
So now I have the Knox lock for
my city and that means that I
effectively have a negative
image of the Knox key for my
city. And so does everyone else
who has one of the boxes. If I
can make a key to open my box,
then I would have a key to
almost every commercial building
in my city. I didn’t really want
to mess with mine, so I bought
some very similar locks on Ebay
and started trying to make a
model in OpenSCAD. It’s a 3D
modeling tool where you define
your shape in a language similar
to C, but instead of compiling
into a computer program, it
compiles into a shape and since
it’s completely parametric, it’s
perfect for modeling things like
keys. Once you have your model
setup, if you want to change
something, it’s as simple as
just updating some numbers and
recompiling. Uh I’m not the
first one to use it to model
keys. Nirav Patel, Christian
Holler and Eric Van Albert have
done that before, but I wanted
to try making my tool that
suited my needs a little bit
better. So one of the first
challenges I ran into was
modeling the key way. Sometimes
Medeco will remove a lot of
metal from the face of the plug
and this makes it kind of hard
to get a good image of the key
way. Like if I try to scan or
photograph it, the wording is
really hard to see because it
doesn’t start until about a few
millimeters back from the face.
But a quick and dirty way around
that is to just slice the plug
in half and look at a cross
section of it. You can just cut
it with a hacksaw or something.
It doesn’t really matter if it
leaves a nasty, rough edge,
because you can just lap the
face until it’s perfectly even.
And then if you polish it and
put it down a flatbed scanner,
you should get a pretty crisp
image of the key way. The next
thing to consider is that this
cross section is not perfectly
circular, we’re taking a cross
section of a cylinder and if the
face we’re scanning is not
absolutely parallel with the
front and back of the plug, the
picture we’ll get will be
slightly elliptical. This is
pretty easy to correct for
though. I made a program that
just transforms the ellipse back
into a perfect circle. And then
once we have the image, we can
bring it into Inkscape, trace it
and we have our profile and then
if we extrude that profile, we
have a blank. Then also if you
didn’t thin the profile down at
all when you traced it, it
probably won’t quite fit into
the lock. Maybe it wasn’t traced
properly or the image wasn’t
completely accurate or the
printer wasn’t calibrated
properly so I recommend thinning
the blank down a little bit to
give it some room. Uh you could
just try to eyeball it, but I
made a program that lets you
print a bunch of keys all stuck
together like this and it
smoothly changes the parameters
from one side to another. So you
can start it out thick on one
side and have it get thinner
towards the other and then just
snap a part to see which one
works the best. Uh and then to
model the cuts we can just take
the pins out and measure them.
The key pins are kind of hard to
measure because they all have
the same height, so I recommend
making a 3D printed measurement
tool. I’ll open source mine when
I’m done with it and you don’t
have to be super precise when
measuring pins because you can
just compare your measurement to
the closest one published by
Medeco. Also, the only
difference between a biaxial key
and a M3 key is this groove
that’s been cut out of it so the
key can interact with the M3
slider element. This element is
protected under patent, but it
would be trivially easy to print
a key with a similar cutout.
This element does give the key
some legal protection against
duplication, but it provides
almost zero technical
protection. And people have
attacked this element at DefCon
before. It was shown to be very
secure as long as the attacker
doesn’t have access to a paper
clip or something similar. Um.
[laughter] So after some
tweaking and trial and error, I
was able to make a working
Medeco key [audio breaks]
sticking out and it won’t go
back in unless the correct key
is in the lock and here it is
with the correct key. It’s a
little, yeah. [applause] Um, so
that really wasn’t all that
hard, uh the process would be
exactly the same to produce the
Knox key to my city. This means
anyone who has access to one of
these locks and a good 3D
printer could produce one of
these keys. Also, if someone
really wanted to get a hold of
one of these locks, they
wouldn’t even need to buy one.
When these things are properly
installed, they’re really tough
to remove if you don’t have the
key. Like, good luck getting
that thing off. But they’re not
always properly installed.
[laughter] Here’s a Knox box on
a chain link fence, so anyone
with some wire cutters could
take that thing. Let’s see. It
would also probably be pretty
easy to take one of the
padlocks, if someone had some
bolt cutters or lock picks. It
would be pretty hard to pick the
Knox padlock, but what about
that other lock. What if someone
just left one open? That lock is
available to anyone that has
access to a wrench or a pair of
pliers. I took this photo about
8 months ago and it’s still like
this today. Uh I’m releasing the
program I made for this. It’s on
GitHub right now. The repository
is called Gatekeyper. It’s a
couple hundred lines of OpenSCAD
code designed to help make keys
for locks without requiring
access to the original key to
begin with. It’s nice
necessarily for Medcos, but it
can reproduce all of the
elements of a biaxial key.
Unfortunately I’m not releasing
a version which can do this cut
out for the M3 slider, because
that’s still under patent and
I’m not entirely sure if it will
do that, but some could modify
this program to include that
characteristic. So check it out
if you’re interested, but please
don’t mess with locks that
aren’t yours. I’m not talking
about this because I want people
to start breaking into
buildings, I’m just trying to
show that these are a security
risk. I’m also not trying to
talk trash about Medeco, I think
the M3 is a very nice lock. I
just don’t think it should be
used for this application. So
how could we improve these? Knox
could try switching to a
different mechanical lock, but
then people like me would just
do the same thing to that one.
Uh there are some keys which are
a real pain in the a*s to
duplicate, like the multi-lock
interactive or the Evva MCS, but
you’re never going to stop
people from recreating chunks of
metal. I think the best way to
avoid this kind of attack would
be to avoid key escrow
altogether. I think the biggest
flaw in the Knox system is that
all of the locks in each area
are identical. I can reverse
engineer my Knox box and gain
useful information about my
neighbor’s Knox box or the
hospital down the street or the
bank. Things might be more
secure if we switched over to
electromechanical locks because
electronics let you make it very
difficult to extract secret
information, since you have
challenge response and all that
fun stuff. It took years for the
Desfire EV1 chip to get broken
by a differential power analysis
attack. And that’s a lot longer
than it took me to make a Medeco
key, but the most secure way to
do this would be not to store
any secret information in the
lock. Each lock could have its
own unique credential. That way
if I reverse engineer my lock, I
would have no useful information
about my neighbors credential
and I think that’s how it should
be. And it would be much harder
to do stuff like this. Uh
there’s a very neat combination
lock called the RKS which is
like a very tiny safelock that’s
dialed with a robotic key. Uh if
they use something like this,
each building could have it’s
own unique combination and they
could just load them onto the
key when they need to. Knox also
recently announced an electronic
of their product. Coincidentally
they released the promotional
video for it. It’s a completely
electronic system, kind of like
the Medeco XT. I don’t know how
they’re doing the electronics,
but they say the key can hold
100 codes. That’s not very many,
so it leads me to believe that
they’re not doing away with key
escrow altogether. Just making
it electronic. So you’re
probably wondering what if
someone hacks the electronics?
Wouldn’t that be really bad?
Well, don’t worry, according to
Knox, it cannot be hacked.
[laughter] They say it is a
completely hack proof system.
They also say that it can’t be
hacked via RF or Bluetooth,
which kind if makes sense given
the fact that it doesn’t use
either of those things.
[laughter] Um. But until we do
get these 100 percent hack proof
locks, what can building owners
do to mitigate key duplication
attacks? Knox does offer to sell
them with a tamper alert, which
is nice. Uh it’s got two
buttons, one is detect the box
coming off of the wall and the
other is to detect the door
being opened. You hook the up to
your burglar alarm so it can go
off if someone messes with the
box. This is a nice feature, but
it’s almost never hooked up.
Pretty much nobody uses these
things. They probably should
though. The tamper alert seems
to be pretty well designed, but
on the residential 3200 model,
Knox was kind enough to include
a drain hole on the bottom. This
allows me to just hold that
button down with a bent piece of
wire and defeat the tamper
alert. Here’s what that looks
like from the inside. Here’s the
button and I go in and grab it
and I can open the door and the
button stays down. And if I let
go, it pops back up. Knox’s
website says that the tamper
alert provides highest security
and I really hope this isn’t the
best they can do. Uh so if you
are using that switch, maybe
don’t get one with an exposed
drain hole. Also, have cameras
pointed at the box, don’t rely
completely on locks for your
security. Get an alarm and maybe
don’t put your alarm code in the
box. I know you’re supposed to
but if your building is on fire
or something, I guess it’s not a
huge deal if your burglar alarm
goes off. And as for long term
solutions, I think we should be
switching over to a system where
this is just intrinsically not
an issue. I’m not saying this is
a huge issue, but just that we
can do better going forward. If
you’re interested, check out the
GitHub page for helpful
resources and programs I used.
Also, huge thanks to the
Electronic Frontier Foundation
for answering some of my
questions about this. Please go
do- go donate to them. And thank
you for listening. I hope you
found this interesting.
[applause]