[Applause] >> Ya, thank you, for
the short introduction. Um I'm
Siegfried and this is my
colleague ah Stephan and today
we'll talk about our, ah,
tracking application
investigation. Ah we are both
from Germany, from a research
institute called Fraunhofer SIT.
Its located in Darmstadt close
to Frankfort. Um, few words
about my, ourselves so I'm
Siegfried. I'm leading a
research group at this research
institute called secured
software engineering and our
main focus is on static and
dynamic code analysis. So
writing new analysis in order to
find vulnerabilities in
binaries, as well as soft, uh,
source code, and was the founder
of team called TeamSIK, which we
will say in a second and the
founder of code inspector which
is a reverse engineering for
tool for android. So, Stephan
would you like to say a few
words about yourself. >>Ya
hello. My name is ah Stephan and
I belong to the Testlab mobile
security group. I'm also
developing static and dynamic
analysis tools and in my spare
time I'm digging around bit with
IOT stuff and together with
Siegfried I'm a co-founder of
our hacking team. >>Thank you.
So, we talked about this
TeamSIK, so what we present
today is not, um, the results of
our, of both of us, it's
basically the results of the
team, which is called TeamSIK.
So what is it? A few words about
it. It's a research, it's ah
hacking group so we meet once a
week in our spare time. So, the
team cons, the team consists of
researchers of the research
institute as well as students
around our Universities, uh
around the university and um, so
we usually look into different
interesting projects, then we
try to find someone abilities
and that's basically the goal to
learn from each other. So, the
credits definitely goes to those
brilliant students and
researchers mentioned below. Two
of them are actually here in the
audience. Good, so before we
start with the talk um a short
beer announcement, um, since we
are uh, well you already know,
we are from Germany and actually
from Munich well close to Munich
thought it might be a yet
another cool idea to bring or
import some boxes of beer and
since this is our 3rd, first, ah
Defcon talk [speaker laughs] ah
we imported 2 boxes of beer this
year, so, after the talk feel
free to come and grab a cold
beer. There are 40 bottles for
you guys. [audience cheers and
claps] Thank you. So, let's get
started. Ah. Short agenda for
today, um I'll start with a
little motivation, um, and then
do a little background
information and then we dig into
our results of our security
findings ah first topics is
client-side authorization. I
will explain what I mean by
that. Then we will talk about
the client-side vulnerabilities
and then we will talk about
server-side vulnerabilities. In
the end, a few words about
responsible disclosure because
this was funny this year, and ah
summary in the end. Good,
motivation. Um so when I started
um, we started um, putting the
slides together I said how can I
motivate tracker application so
while you first of all think
about surveillance. So looked a
little bit up online and I found
a cool block post about a CIA
museum and well instance in the
60's already there was um, um,
radio receivers inside of pipe,
so very small stuff which was
interesting to see. In the 60's,
again, like ah camera inside a
pack of cigarettes to hide
into-to video record the
environment. And in the 70's um
like a microphone fit already
into a dragonfly ah in order
to-to spy on people. So guess
you already get it that was the
past so how is it right now? I
guess we all have it in our
pocket. Um, it the smart phone.
Um, well because there is like
sensors in it like GPS and this
kind of stuff so you get a lot
of information from people. Um,
this is the reason why there
already spyware and wraps um,
abusing this um, this stuff
and-and-and extracting all the
information and using it for
whatever reason. Um, what we
also ask ourselves or we ask are
there any benign reasons good
reasons to use such kind of apps
or surveillance apps or tracking
applications. And then we found
3 different topics which was
interesting. First of all, app
families. So, there are apps out
there where adults want to know
where their child's are. So they
want to know if they are safe in
the environment based on a
location information. Um, there
are couples, which was
interesting like, track my
boyfriend, track my girlfriend
apps. Um I don't know why they
do this. So, they mutually agree
on installing the application
and whatever to check if they
are not cheating on each other.
I don't know. But there are many
of them out there. And friends
as well. So, while you want to
know where your buddy is in
order to meet or whatever. So
there are benign reasons. The
question is how do you
differentiate between the good
and the bad now, right. Because
from the implementation
prospective both are implemented
in the same way. So, for this we
looked up on Google play and we
found these kind of apps so we
thought there might be a
definition. What are good apps
and what are bad apps. So, I
found ah, well one of them us a,
The Android Security Report that
stated, that ah commercial
spyware is any application that
transmits sensitive information
off the device without user
content um, doesn't display a
persistent notification that
this is happening. So this means
if you wanna install a benign
tracking application and if you
wanna upload it to the play
store you need to show the
monitor person notifications
like, whatever, right now I'm
accessing your um, location
information whatever and I'm
sending it to your mom,
some-some kind of this. If this
is the case then this is ah
legitimate app and if not its um
considered a spyware and it
shouldn't be in the play store.
This is at least ah, what we
found. Good. So, so we've only
focused on this in your talk on
your project on those legitimate
apps um, and we ask ourselves
the questions cause they are
collecting a lot of data um, how
well is the collected data
protected. On the client-side or
on the server side. For that um,
we looked up as I said, Google
play store, we typed in tracking
application, track my boyfriend,
track my girlfriend and then we
found 19 different apps. Why is
this an odd number? Well we just
founded a few of them the first
hints and at some point we
stopped. And then we found so
many vulnerabilities that at
some point we got bored and this
is the reason why there are 19.
This is no special reason for
19. So we looked at we at least
those um, that have um, the most
installations um uh based on
google play store statistics.
And another point is we only
look for free applications so I
know that there are a lot of
commercial spyware applications
out there. Those where not um,
the target in this um, project.
Only the ones that you can
download for free. And you get
for free. And can use for free.
So as a spoiler um, we found 37
different vulnerabilities in
total. A very very sensitive
ones. And um well in this talk
we will show a few of them or at
least a few categories of them.
Good um, well before we sssss ya
the takeaways of this talk um so
what will you learn today um, I
have to tell you that if you
expect any sophisticated exploit
in this talk unfortunately I
have to disappoint you. So It
was in this project very easy to
get access to this highly
sensitive data and even to do
mass surveillance in real time.
Um and we usually play this game
of um, can we upgrade the
applications which you have to
pay for premium features be
up-upgraded for free and ya, we
will also say a few words about
that. And yes it was possible
again this year. Good um, and
then we come to the background
information just very very um
small background information
very easy set up that your all
on the same page. So how does
this work? So usually you have
this application and you have an
observer and a monitor person
and both install this
application and then there is
some kind of pairing process
where they know ok I belong to
this guy or whatever or I can
monitor this person and on the
monitored side well it collects
all this sensitive information
like location end zone and sends
it to the backend and on the
backend side you basically
observe a pulse the information
saying right now I want know
where my kid is or whatever. So
this-ah this means on the
backend side there are
information like location
information and call history
text messages Whatsup messages,
whatever and apart ah- couple
applications also had the cool
features of installing a
messenger into this tracking
applications of this means that
you can chat with your
girlfriend or whatever. So you
can also send pictures and
videos and this is important for
the remaining talk. So all this
data are stored in the backend.
So what are the attack factors
here? Well like I said the usual
gain can be upgrade um, premium
features for free, so we will
say a few words about that. Then
obviously the 2 complications
channels um, can be a man in the
middle and how was it
implemented and how was the
product implemented and we will
say a few words about that. And
the ah last um, attack factor is
um the backend basically. Good
so in the following we will talk
about all of those 3 stages now.
First client-side authorization.
Um, so before I do this I stop
cause we all know this just to
get-get clear, what-how and what
it means to access the sensitive
data, so you have an observer
and you would like to access
sensitive data or data from the
backend. So there usually 2
steps involved. First
authentication, including
identification and then
authorization that your
authorized the check on the
backend that which checks if
your allowed to access this
data. We all know this but I'm
just saying. Um. And then what
we saw is usually, so there was
most of the time this kind of
authentication process. Many
times broken many times there
was none but at least it wasn't
there. Then there was something
where we found a client-side
authorization and I will explain
this ah in second. So I will
show you 4 different examples of
what we found out which was not
okay. Good. The first one um, ya
as I said the usual gain of
premium features. So this kind
of applications contains um
features which are disabled by
default and if you pay whatever
5 dollars or something like
this, then you get super cool
premium features one of them are
for instance um, removing
advertisement that you've rid
[speaker stutters] that you're
not seeing advertisement
anymore. Very easy. So, we ask
ourselves um how was this
implemented to for instance to
get rid of the advertisement and
then we looked into the code.
And we found the following um,
shared preferences get Boolean
`l_ads` for instance then there
was a check if removed so if
this flag is set to true, if yes
then they basically disable
thi-this few on the client side.
For those of you who don't know
the code here or wh-wh-what the
shared preferences is in
android. Shared preferences is a
file that comes with the
application um, it's a XML based
file and it has a key value pair
so in this case `l_ads` for
instance was set to faults. If
you set it to true then you can
basically get rid of the um,
advertisement um the question is
for those who don't know it can
how can we manipulate this file
while there are basically 2
ways. First one if you have a
routed device, it's very easy to
change this um, value on a
un-routed device you and the
application allows you to backup
so you backup the application
including this file. Then you
can then you do modify a file
and then you restore it. This is
all known and well known from
learned from the past. Then when
we look into this ah shared
preferences file, we found some
other cool settings there. So
one of them was SMS full. So SMS
full is like um for a monitor
person, all the text message are
basically can be um, can be
accessed by the observer. Um. So
for the first text message
because they want to know if the
girlfriend or the boyfriend is
cheating or whatever so they
want to ah, exactly know what's
going on and as I already
mentioned so if you said this
one guy from faults to true, uh
oh yeah sorry, I forgot to say
what this full mean. This full
means if you did not pay, you
only get first x characters of
the text message and if you pay
then you get the complete text
message as an observer. Um, well
if you set it to true we already
learned this right now then you
get the full text message. But
the question is how is this
implemented. It was implemented
in such a way so that the
observer basically says, hey,
please give me all text messages
from this guy or from my kid or
from my girlfriend and then the
service says ok then sure, you
get the complete text message.
Text message 1, 2, 3 like the
complete one and then at the
client-side there was a check
like, okay, so if you did not
pay, I only show the first 50
characters. And if this is not
the case you, basically see the
complete text message and this
was a little bit funny to see
and you shouldn't do this.
[audience laughs] Ya because I
mean come on [presenter laughs]
so ya [presenter laughs] what
the f**k. Um, good so next
stage, ah, second stage of of
this kind of box where um, so as
I said there are basically these
2 roads you all have a parent
which has the admin role and
then you have your kid which has
a le-less privileges and if you
are an admin you can um create a
new admin or whatever and if
while um you can monitor
basically your kid. And the
question was okay how do these
apps differentiate between an
admin or a a a a parent and a
child a children. So and the
question was ya there's a shared
preferences file and there is a
set called east parent and if
this guy is set to true, um then
your parent and your admin so
this means that if you are the
kid and you change your shared
preferences file to true then
you are an admin and you can spy
back to your parents if you
want. [audience laughs and
applauds] Good, next stage and
another example of this kind I
guess you already get this um,
thing there was this application
that contained um additional
security protection mechanisms
which um, once you opened the
application umm you can enter a
pin and then it asks you for the
pin and if you enter the correct
pin then you ow- ad then you can
access the the application and
the data in the application. So
this is ah ah good security
feature. The question again was
ah how was this implemented and
I guess you already get this
kind game now. There was a flag
in the shared preferences file.
This time pflag so it's not so
directly pointed to remove ah,
to lock screen or something and
if you set this to false then
you do not see any lock screen
at all. Even if you edit a pin
or something you can directly
access the data there. Ya. And
last but not least um obviously
the same also worked for log in,
so honestly so there is an is
login and if you were logged in
before so the store basically
user and a password and if you
set this guy to true it
automatically locks you in even
without typing the user name and
password. Again shared
preferences. I mean ya . So the
last slide here in this case is
please don't use shared
preference for authorization
checks. So for those of you who
are buck hunters so please look
into shared preferences it's
always fun and you find a lot of
stuff. And for developers please
don't use this again. We talked
about this 2 years ago and last
year about shared preferences
and ya. There are for sure more
apps that um don't under- or
developers that don't understand
this so please don't do this
again. Good so this was it from
my side I will now hand over to
Stephan who will continue um
with the remaining slides. >>
Okay tha-thank you. Um I will
explain the rest of our findings
and vulnerabilities now. First
the the client-side and
communication vulnerabilities.
And um for the people who are
not aware about the concept ah a
few words about um the man in
the middle attacks. The basic
idea is just to to get as an
attacker between the
communications. So between the
user and the backend and try to
eavesdrop or even manipulate the
communication. If for instance
the app communicates in plain
text this would be very easy for
an attacker we can cause he can
read everything change data and
so on. Another case would if the
app has implementation laws like
it uses broken inscription or
has um errors so that the
attackers easily can can bypass
the inscription and the last
step so this would be ah the
only reliable protection against
many middle attacker to
implement secure correct and um
and confidential integrity
protected authenticated um
communication. So, our first
step, as I mentioned to the man
in the middle attack we had a
application where is was
required to sign in and we
wanted to know how secure this
ah is um log in process. So as a
user, you have to enter your
credentials as an attacker we
observe them the first thing
that you can see is a http
connection so it's plain text.
So man in the middle attacker
would be able to read the plain
text credentials but as you can
see in this GET request, they
are not our credentials. So we
replied a few times to get to
see some pattern and as you can
see, we have different parameter
names and different parameter
positions but we always have 2
um, same parameter values. So
this this looks interesting and
we we dig now in-onto the code
to find more um about the
implementation. The first thing
we saw was our hot coded
encryption key. Reverse
engineering then this algorithm
we saw ok, the user data, the
user name XOR with this key
base64 encoded and there was a
pretty fine set of um, random
values. One of them was randomly
picked and combined with the um
user name. This is the same
procedure for the ah um
password. So this means if that
now as the man in the middle of
the attacker observe the traffic
we just simply take the value,
decode it, xor'ed it and we get
the credentials in plain text.
The other parameters we saw so
where um garbage. So we had 2
additional parameters that were
also randomly selected from a
predefined set and but they had
no no value and this this is
some kind of obfuscation we
don't know why are this would
stand by the developer but um
it's the wrong way. So, as I
said, if you were able to
eavesdrop this data you can
decrypt it can get the log in
data and authenticate. How to do
it rightly in android so secure
communication is not so hard.
You just have to do an https
connection, use TLS 1 dot um 2
or then later 1 dot 3. You just
need a valid service certificate
to get it for free for instance
from Let's Encrypt and on the um
android side doing ah https is
very easy. Define a new ah URL
object, open a connection. Ya an
an that's all. Then it's done.
Um k. So the next thing we saw
problems with authentication. Um
as Siegfried already mentioned,
um the apps are transferring all
the the tracking and location
data to some kind of backend. In
most cases, this backend hosts
the database. And if you want to
connect to a database, ah for
instance an android, you have to
for instance instantiate the
database driver and then you
have to establish a connection.
Now what we-we saw in the
application is typically a
Patton how you should not do it
in an application. At first they
established the connections so
you need the URL. You need your
log in name and you need a
password. And the problem now is
that the password is stored in
the application. This means
everybody who has access to this
application or to this code can
simply extract the password so
when the user name has the URL
and has complete access to the
backend storage where all the
data was stored. We have a few
apps that you will see uh um
simplified um database schemes
so this backend stores the email
address, some name, and
especially also the location
information. And in our findings
we had in common 860 thousand
um, tracking apps uh locations
and even if you make regular
requests of quarry you also can
um observe or tra-track the
people in real time cause the
app regularly sends um updated
data to this um database. Um
that's not all. Um of course so
when we looked also in the code
a bit um a step further. We
thought okay ya SQL um so they
for SQL you should in the right
way you should use prepared
statement. You can see okay they
already define a prepared
statement and now we will expect
some some method which will set
the values in this statement.
But what we see was they
override the prepared statement
with the concatenated statement
and as a user you can for
instance control the email
address and in this sample that
you see here, is a classic SQL
injection vulnerability. So
th-the app was broken already by
this sign but we stumbled above
this additionally. So, I don't
want to be unpolite but this is
really stupid code. [audience
laughs] Okay now there are more
exciting things, let's get to
the servers, um, which are
hosting all the data's. Um
Siegfried already introduced we
have an we need a authentication
process and authorization
process and we um try to analyze
and find if there are problems,
design flaws, or rather
vulnerabilities to bypass or to
break this uh um processes. So
we have deferent let's say
stages of vulnerabilities and
findings, in some fife and um I
will now explain the different
findings on the server side. So
the first thing is not really a
vulnerability its more um, let's
say a feature or ah um, a
usability thing. Um. Um. The
application after the
instillation by design or by
default a-an option that says
all located and tracked data are
sent to the backend and
everybody has excess. This means
they are freely accessible. So
this is kind of let's say design
flaw. A better option would be
some op in where a default is
not everybody can access it and
if the user agrees, he can
activate that everyone can
access this data. How you can
look at this data or how you can
access it is very easy you just
need to know the website and the
user name of the person you want
to track or want to listen and
for this we have prepared a
short um demo video. So if you
go to the website, um, you just
as I said you have to know the
URL of the website. Then you
have to answer ah ah a user
name. for this we choose a
random user name we call the
user the sexy. If you open it,
you already see, you get some
some tracking on on Google maps
and now you can open um details
to see when the track was
stored. You also click on-on
this um track button you get the
correct location when the track
was stored the starting time. Um
you get some some kind of
profile information the altitude
and so on. You also see a
altitude diagram. And now you
can also track or reply the
track the person you can see
okay he is entering his car, you
see his speed. He's driving
around. Cause with the
connection with Google maps, you
can also zoom in or look in
details so they can see okay the
person is going to some some
school. He's driving around and
so on. It's also a bit curious.
This this in this track this
person who is going to a school
at 1 pm he is moving between the
school and the ATM several
times. Don't ask what she is
doing or he's doing there and ya
at the end she is just going
back to his um um home address.
Okay. As I said this was just a
feature, this was not really a
bug but this is not all we also
stumbled about a bug in this
website. So this is not a
feature, this is a bug in form
of an XSS. So, next step,
authentication problems.
Sometimes you have the,
impression ya, authentication
what. Um we took another
application, if you look at the
traffic of the application or
reverse engineering the code,
you see some http request there,
so already mentioned, nothing
new. Plain text communication.
Then we have a user id. The user
id is the id of the user itself
so th-the person who wants to
monitor something. This user id
was protected by Caesar
encryption. I don't know why um,
makes no really sense. [audience
laughs] Then we have the child
id. This is the id of the person
you want to observe. This is a
simple 10 digit large number and
we have the current date. This
is the date where the last um
tracking of the person was
stored. And as you can see, this
is not a very complex request if
you can also try it or guess
this child id if the person who
you want to monitor. If you
enter this, the host responds
the whole track of the person.
We choose this um tracking data
and printed it into some Google
maps and here you see some
tracking profile of one of our
students. And this is completely
um assessable without any
authentication log in process or
whatever. Everybody who knows
this well can track other
persons. Okay, so Siegfried
already introduced some some
additional features. Apps also
have th-the possibility to send
um or track um text messages.
And the question was can you
also get this um messages. Oh
sorry. Um. Um, if you look into
the traffic again to to get our
message from the monitored
person you have to make a
simple, there is a API you have
to make a simple post request,
you get ah ah a number ah how
much SMS you want to have from
this user and his user ID. So
after that you get ah timestamp
and the phone number and ah the
messages the monitor person um
sent. Now what happens when you
leave the user name empty? You
get all storage text messages
from the server. [audience
applauds] Ya. Okay. So, as you
can see this is not no rocket
science. We have no complex
exploits. You just have to know
who to to use your browser and
send a UL. Now we get into
exploiting. Um we have here SQL
injection, very simple. So again
we have another type of app. And
in this app it is also possible
to track a person. Here you have
to know the the mobile number of
the person. So this means um a
the backend provides an API if
you enter the mobile number. You
get the latitude, the longitude,
the location, timestamp of the
person you want to monitor. K
now a little spoiler, we are
talking about SQL injection, so
what do you think will happens
if you do this. Yes, you get all
um data, phone number, location
data from the backend. If you
look at the history, the um
first recorded started in the
year 2016. That's all. Simple
SQL injection. The next one is a
little bit more um let's say
complex SQL. Um Siegfried also
mentioned additional features
like messenger functions or
people can for instance with
your girlfriend you can exchange
images. As an unusual messenger
these images are storage on a
cloud system and of course there
are 1 cloud for all images. Not
every user has its own cloud and
in this case the user is needing
to authenticate the cloud on the
backend. There are also filters
that means okay this user has
authenticated the images belong
to the user so he just gets the
images of just his girlfriend or
not images of foreign people.
The question is now, can we
somehow bypass this
authentication or where we able
to compromise the cloud. Um,
spoiler, a little demo. So. If
you take a look at this cloud.
It already provides some some
simple web interface. Um, by the
way we have to obfuscate the UL
because this um bug was still
not fixed from the vendor. So,
um. We provide a the a cloud
storage provides us some simple
web interface but you see when
you enter the URL in the
browser, we get no images
because we are not
authenticated. And, we are in
the section SQL injections so
let's try a simple SQL injection
at the parameter. That should be
in the upper corner um bigger
image of the injector, of the
SQL injection you can see it
here. And surprise surprise, we
get a preview of the images
stored on the cloud system. We
can also, um, open these images
and download. And as you can can
imagine if people are exchanging
images and there is a
possibility to exchange images,
they also will exchange not just
burgers or or selfies, they will
also exchange um more private or
sensitive information. Let's say
from the section of um adult
entertainment and so on. Um so
we also found very um um
sensitive data. On the cloud and
um[audience laughs] yes we I
cannot say how much data we um
we did not count them or
download them because of-of um
um, privacy reasons and so on.
And um as I said, the block is
still not fixed. Okay and so in
this way we would be able to
dump all images. So. Ya thank
you. [audience claps] Then the
last step these where just
images, now we want to go to the
crown jewels. So can we get the
credentials? And um one of our
application had a strange ummmm
lets say strange insolation
process. So the app, we are able
to recognize if it was already
installed on the device. So they
had some special installation
procedure. This means when you
install the app for the first
time it generates some kind of
um device id and stores this on
the backend. And you remove the
application and reinstall it, it
requests to the server for the
device id and it compares and
able to detect ok it was already
installed on this device. And if
it realizes that it was already
installed on the device, the
server already sends ah the user
name and the password um and the
email address back to the
application. So our first idea
was ok the device id, um how can
we spoof it but um the problem
is th-the device id is a long
number its very complex and then
um  number and it's hard
to reproduce it but perhaps it
is not the best way. So, I would
rather trick the empty ID does
it also not work? So let's try
an SQL injection. Here you see a
little curl command which is ah
doing the SQL injection. And
what we get was a storage um
user credentials. The user name,
the user id, the password in
plaintext. Now you can imagine,
we can iterate over all values
and all in all we were able to
or could extract of 1 point
seven million data's. Passwords,
credentials, everything in
plaintext. So if you think, what
the f**k, so then um [audience
laughs] okay, there's there's
more. [everyone laughs] Surprise
surprise. Um a few words at
first about firebase. Who are
not aware, firebase is a service
from Googles supporting um app
or app developer. They providing
service for crash analysis,
cloud messaging storage. In our
case we focus on 2 services. The
1 is a real time database and
the other thing is a
authentication processor API on
this. So, just imagine this real
time database like a classic
database if you are not aware
about this firebase um service.
So we have another app that have
implemented an authentication
process. They hosted their own
authentication server. And as a
user or or an attacker, first
you have to send a login
request. For this you have to
send the user email. In our case
as an attacker, we will send the
victims email. On this um,
backend, there's ah, there is ah
database, a classic database,
with ah public available table.
And this table stores the user
email and a corresponding user
id. And so if you are sending
your post request, the database
is querying the database, if it
finds the corresponding um email
address he replies this user id.
In the next step, the app now
try's to access to this firebase
database by sending the user and
this queried or corresponding
user id to get access to the
stored data. So we are querying
in this user id in this publicly
available table. And as a
response, we get the location
data, the address, um date when
the request was sent. So, that
was the first thing as you can
imagine, guessing the email
address will give you very easy
access. I'm sorry I have found
in this movie not a better
facepalm but this is the first
one. So in the next step you see
in the app or the ah database
back and also replies the
userbase credentials back to the
app. [audience laughs] The
question. The question is now
why, ya um, this is an example
of how you should not do it. Um
the developer implemented a
client-side verification. This
is mean there um expecting the
credentials from the server and
comparing it in the application
and if its correct, they allow
access. So, I think your aware
of it, it's not the correct way
how to do this. Another thing is
our old trick, what do you think
what happens if you remove the
user id. Of course we get all
stored data from this database
containing location, address
status, user credentials,
security token, whatever. Ya,
s**t happens. [audience claps]
So, it's sometimes easy to to
bash um people so whats the
problem here? The first thing is
um they did not set any any
authorization rules on the
firebase. This is always a
common problem developers are
not aware about this thing and
they use some different
configuration and then the
authorization is is disabled.
Further thing as I explained, if
you're doing um authentication,
you don't do it on the
client-side, you have to do this
on the service side. Especially
if if you want to work with
firebase then use the SDK. Don't
um um conduct some strange code
constructs by yourself. The SDK
reports um ah Google sign-in can
use um email password sign-in
Facebook, whatever, they already
implemented it in the correct
way in this SDK. It's also
possible to use your own
authentication backend. Um um
there a good tutorial on the
firebase side. If you do this
step by step, you are on the
right way but don't do anything
with public available database
construction and other weird
things. Okay a few experiences
about our responsible disclosure
process. Of course we informed
informed all vendors. We gave
them 90 days to fix them but 90
days are not strict. If the
vendor says ok, I need longer
because of some development
cycles or whatever, we say its
ok, long as you fix it. Um this
time we got a few strange
reaction, the first one as
expected. We will fix it, thank
you, everybody is fine. Second
is um ya sometimes you have no
reaction. Um, one reacted um how
much money do you want? They
thought we want ah ah eavesdrop
them but then we clarified no,
we just want to give you the the
report. Please fix it. Ya the
last thing, it's not a block,
it's a feature. [audience
laughed] Um, for this um, people
are um or manufacture that do
not react, on on on our emails,
we tried tried to involve
Google. Google has this um app
security improvement team and
also security team. We wrote an
email, ah to them and send the
advisory's report everything,
but we didn't get any direct
replay or any um reaction. Um
last week we checked the store
and 12 of the applications where
removed. So 7 are still
vulnerable. I also di-di-did the
demo video you saw, this backend
is still active and and nobody's
is ah um um reacting. So a short
um summary of our talk. Um as
always as you saw, don't use
plaintext communication in
mobile. This is is a radio
communication. In most cases,
its very easy to eavesdrop sniff
from many [indiscernible]
data-ers. SQL prepared
statements, its its nothing new.
Each, especially android that
will provide a huge API of of a
for SQL and prepared statements.
Um. If you are doing app
development, don't don't just
focus on the app. If you use
backend, this this is a bunch
you have to consider also the
security on-on the back-end
side. And very important also,
don't store any user secrets
like passwords, inscription
keys, or whatever on the clients
side. Everybody who has excess
to the app and there a lot of
like reverse engineering android
apps , it's very easy to extract
the information. Um also
Siegfried already explained the
shared preference thing, if you
have anything um, any special
feature, you need you need a
license. Google provides an API
for this. And also if you're
working with firebase, use ah
read the firebase tutorials um,
use the authentication and
authorization API they provide.
Here you see at the end, ah
again, the list of the apps we
analyzed. Um so you can see the
left um column are the apps with
the client-side vulnerability.
The right side, this where, apps
where, ah the backend is
involved where we are able to
access location data or even all
storage data. If you look at the
table, nearly all apps um ah ah,
especially on the backend where
vulnerability against some some
kind of attack. So this is the
end of the talk. So thank you
for your attention. Um [audience
applauds] Ya, 2 last words um,
all our findings we wrote ah
even for the vendor, we wrote
advisories. The advisories are
accessible on-on the website.
Find on the findings. And the
last thing who wats to talk with
us, or discuss or has a
question, come to us. Grab a
cool beer. We also have a bottle
opener, so you don't have to be
thirsty and thank you again.
[applause]