>>So very excited to bring up
our next speaker. And I am going
to try this again Jianjun
Jianjun Dun Dai Jianjun Dai.
Awesome! So he is going to talk
about uh owning Android devices.
How many of people have Android
devices? Yeah be afraid be very
afraid he’s coming for your
things. Let’s give our speaker a
big round of applause.
[applause] >>Thank you, thank
you. >>Have a great time man!
>>Thank you Jon. Hi everyone.
Today I will present how we Pwns
the toughest target and won the
largest bug bounty in the
history of the ASR program.
Originally my colleagues, Guang
Gong and Wenlin Yang came to
explain to you but they could
not come due to their Visa. As
we know the Pixel phone is
protected by many layers of
security. In the 2017 mobile
Pwns war Samsung, iPhone have
been pwned many times. But only
Pixel was a survivor. No
research no researchers even to
challenges. But our team
discovered a working
exploitation which could
compromise the picture phone
remotely. Because of the
severity of our detailed report,
we were award the highest reward
in the history of the ASR
program. Next I will show the
details. First introduce myself
and my colleagues. I am a
research, security researcher at
three sixty Alpha Team and
focused on Android system
security research with mobility
hunting and exploiting. Guang
Gong senior security researcher
at Alpha Team and he focused on
Android and Chrome security
research. He has spoken at
several security conference and
the winner at many famous
contests like Pwn2Own, Pwn2Own
Mobile. Wenlin Yang is a
security researcher at three
sixty Alpha Team and he focuses
on Android system security
research. In this talk I will
introduce how we pwned Pixel. We
used two bugs to pwn Pixel. One
we V eight bug ending to
compromise the renderer and
other is system server bug. That
is use to escape sandbox and
achieve elevation of private
manage I will show the details
later. Here is my agenda. This
piece mainly includes three
parts. How to exploit the V
eight engine bug and then
exploits the bug of system
server process. Finally we will
make some conclusions. So I will
show the first part and
introduce the Shared Array
Buffer and Web assembly and then
analyze the first part of the
exploit chain CVE twenty
seventeen fifty one sixteen and
then I will talk about how to
exploit the vulnerability.
Shared Array Buffer object is
used to represent a generic
fixed lense low binary getter
buffer similar to the array
buffer object. We add six dot
zero introduced support for
shared array buffer a low level
mechanism to share memory
between between JavaScript
workers and the synchronized
control flow across workers.
SharedArrayBuffer gives Jav
JavaScript access to certain
memory atomics and phonetics
SharedArrayBuffers also unlock
ability to port thread
applications to the web via asm
dot js or WebAssembly.
Unfortunately SharedArrayBuffer
was disabled by default in all
major browsers on January twenty
eighteen in response to Meltdown
and Spectre. But we reported the
bug on July twenty seventeen so
not a fair date maybe the web
enabled in the future. It’s
worth paying attention to.
WebAssembly is a new type of
code that be run in the modern
web browsers. It is a low-level
assembly-like language with a
compact binary format that runs
with near-native performance and
a profile language such as C, or
C plus plus with a compilation
target so that they can run on
the web. It is also designed to
run alongside JavaScript
allowing ports to work together.
Here is an example how this
unfold the function that export
from the simple dot XXM file. Ok
I introduced some basic
knowledge so and I will analyze
each bug in detail. The
vulnerability was fixed in
Chrome sixty one dot zero dot
thirty one sixty three dot
seventy nine. So from sixty to
person priorities maybe effect
by combining the three features,
SharedArrayBuffer, WebAssembly
and Web Worker in chrome. And
OOB access can be triggered
through a race condition.
Assembly speaking. Web Assembly
code can be put in to a
SharedArrayBuffer and then
transferred to a web worker then
the main thread parses the web
assembly code the worker switch
can modify the code at the same
time which causes an OOB access.
Here is a buggy, the buggy code.
The Buggy code it’s in the
function GET first argument as
bytes. Where’s argument args may
be in an Array buffer or typed
array object. Other shared array
buffer is imported to javascript
a typed array can be backed by a
shared array buffer. So the
contents of a typed array can be
modified by other work threads
at the same time. Here is the
POC. The workers thread modified
by a web assembly code. At the
same time another thread is
parsing the code. Yeah. The web
assembly code is put in to a
Shared Array Buffer then a typed
array buffer object is created
using the shared array buffer as
a buffer. After that a worker
thread is created and the shared
array buffer is passed to the
newly created worker thread.
While the main thread is parsing
the web assembly code the worker
thread modifies the shared array
buffer. After the main threads
bug bug check the instruction
code zero can be modified by the
worker thread to code one
hundred and twenty eight and
then parsed and compiled by the
main thread so OOB access
occurs. The last part is the
assembly code. So it’s function
core zero was modified to call
one hundred and twenty eight
making OOB access. The call zero
function can be modified to call
any other web assembly function.
So the exploitation of this pack
is straight forward. If call
zero is modified to call dollar
leak researchers and stack of
contents are dumped to web
assembly memory because function
zero and function dollar leak
have a different number of
arguments the result this
results in many uses of pieces
of detter in the stack being
leaked. Sorry. We cannot modify
the instruction call zero any
core function x instruction can
be modified. Assume function x
is a web, WASM with six
arguments as shown above. When
we V eight compromise the
function is IA thirty two
architecture the first five
arguments are passed through the
registers and the sixth argument
is passed through stack. All the
arguments can be said to be
divided any by java script. So,
when a java script function
calls a web assembly function V8
compiler creates a js to wasm
function internally after
completion the java script
function will call JS to WASM
function and then JS to WASM
will call the web assembly
function JS to WASM function
used different call convention
its first arguments is passed
through stack. So if we modify
core function x to call JS to
WASM function what will happen?
The JS to WASM function will
take the six arguments of
function x as the first argument
but you take the first argument
as an object pointer so tab
confusion will be tracked when
the argument is passed to the
two number function this means
we can pass any values as an
object pointer to the two number
function so we can fake an array
buffer object in some address
such as email type array and
positive address to number
function Exploit of an OOB
access in V eight is
straightforward. Usually through
these few steps. Leak array
buffer’s content and then fake
an array buffer a double array
by using leaked data next pass
faked array buffers address to
ToNumber. Modify BackingStore
and Bytelength of the
ArrayBuffer in callback. Get
arbitrary memory read and write
and finally overwrite JIT code
with shellcode. A lot of
researchers have talked about
the exploitation methods. I will
not explain this in detail. Here
is the patch. Just copy the web
assembly code and two pairs
without using shared memory.
Next I will talk about the
second bug of the four
exploitation. Analyze the bug
and introduce a way to escape
sandbox and show how we exploit
the bug. The sandbox is caused
by map and unmap mistake and
cause are used on unmap the bug
and code is in the function
grallocmap and gralloc unmap
both standards are in libgralloc
map module. Gralloc maps graphic
buffer to memory space the
gralloc, graphic buffer is
controlled by the arguments
handle. The handle pointer is
controlled by chrome renderer
process. While mapping, the map
address plus the plus an offset
is sent to a base pointer. The
mapped memory will be all mapped
in function gralloc map. Let’s
have a look. While mapping base
pointer is passed to system core
unmap give actually without
[indiscernible] offset this
offset is not used at all. As a
result map and unmap are
mismatched. However the member
offset can be manipulated from a
chrome standard process so its
possible to unmap any pages in
system server from chromes
standard renderer process. We
have achieved RCE but if you
want to trigger the system
server bug from the from the
group we have to bypass the
sandbox then I will introduce a
way to escape sandbox. In the
picture we can see that crew is
a sandbox process belonged to
isolated app domain. From the
sepolicy file of isolated app a
view service like an activity
service can be caused in sandbox
process. Or so we can get
activity service from the
sandbox process. Then when
starting activity function
inverse not isolated caller will
be involved invoked. Which will
check if the caller is is in
isolated app domain. Because of
selinux most system service has
have been restricted to access
from sandbox process and a view
and a viewer functions can be
called in the isolated app
domain attack surface is getting
narrow. From the code you can
see that. This path various
restrictions regardless found in
an ingenious way that can get
renderer process reach system
server by binder core with
parcel object. A lot of classes
implement the interface
parcelable the member function
creates from parcel of all of
these classes can record from
groups center post using binder
call. Graphic buffer is zero one
is used in the exploitation. I
will use that later. This is a
case to reach system server
avoid avoiding inverse
[indiscernible] caller and its a
remote transact by binder core.
The binder departs from the
window is pressed from activity
options constructor. So we get a
way to reach the system server
from Chrome. Core creates from
parcel to create a binder
encapsulated with a graph buffer
and [indiscernible] method
convert to translucent and pass
a miniature responder to system
server. Exploit bug. We complete
the exploit through the six
steps shown above. Next our
detail is step Step one. Address
space shaping. We make the
address lookout as shown above.
A heap chunk is right above some
continuous ash memory mapping
Step two, trigger the bug, unmap
part of heap and a ashmem memory
unmap four kilobytes in heap
chunk and two million minutes to
four kb in shared memory. Shared
memory twenty nine. So there is
two m cap between heap chunk and
a shared memory twenty nine Step
three fill the unmapped space
with ashmem memory. The gap is
filled with a shared memory one
thousand and one. Step four
spray the heap. The heap theater
will be writing to the shared
memory the heap manager believes
the memory range between the two
red address is still monitored
by each and the will allocate
resulting in heap theater is
writing to a shared memory. Step
five allocate graphic buffer
objects in a shared memory
overwrite virtual function
pointer because the felt shared
memory in step three in step
three is mapped both in both by
system server and rendered
process partial heap of a system
server can be read and writing
by renderer process and we can
track our system server to
allocate some graphic buffer
object in a shared memory we can
read future table of graphic
buffer object and overwrite the
reader function pointer by
writing the a shared memory.
Step six as graphic buffer is
inherit from IEF base which has
a member function named on last
strong ref we can read future
table address from a shared
memory and then calculate the
address of function on last
strong ref. We found some ROPS
chains in libui and modify the
virtual table of graphic buffer
to trigger ROP. When our graphic
buffer object is deconstructed
the virtual function on last
strong ref is called so we can
replace this function this
virtual function to jump to ROP.
When GC happens the control flow
goes to ROP. Ok finally lets
summary contents of this talk.
First we compromised the chrome
rendered with v eight bug and
then we achieved getting the
privilege of system server by
using an ingenious way to escape
sandbox and exploiting the bug
cve twenty seventeen one four
nine oh four composed we
replaced the four remote
exploits chain. All of these
bugs have already fixed security
updates of December twenty
seventeen. Thanks to our
colleagues at Alpha Team and
Core team. That’s all thank you!
[audience applause]