>>From time to time we have a
new speaker that has uh, made it
through the gauntlet of uh, call
for papers. And um, they’ve been
sort of vetting. And um, we, we
really appreciate their effort,
and their work, and their
research and their, their uh,
this is a lot of work! And we,
we really want to congratulate
our new speakers for making it
through and for having the guts
and figuring it out for the
first time. It get, it’s all
down from here. [laughter] So,
um, give Josh Mitchell a big
round of proplause. [audience
applauds] >>Cheers. I think that
makes, 4. >>I’m sorry. [audience
laughs] Um, so, Josh is here to
talk about uh, some critical
issues with police body cameras
and ride along adventures.
>>Yeah. It’s cool. [speaker
laughs] Hello. Hi. Welcome.
Welcome. Oh. Welcome. [speaker
laughs] Alright, so, uh. This is
what we’re gonna be talking
about today. Um, yes. I have to
have this up front. You guys can
read that. K. So here’s uh some
of the things we’re gonna be
talking about. I’m gonna go with
a little bit of an introduction,
say hi to everybody. Um, talk
about some of the technology
involved in these devices. Uh, I
have 5 specific models to talk
about. Um, I had 7 but, due to
circumstances out of my control,
I can only talk about 5. Uh, and
then we’ll cover some industry
wide issues that I think apply
to uh, all of the devices. Uh
have some, see some impact
that’s kind of important and
then have some questions. So
here, this is me. And yes that
is a hamburger phone. Uh, I’ve
been, been doing this for quite
awhile. Uh, Former military. Um,
then [audience applauds/cheers]
Uh, I specialized in uh,
electronic warfare. Uh, then got
into doing a little bit of
malware stuff, cause it’s fun.
Uh, and then I became a
professional exploit developer
for a number of years and now I
do security research uh, at
Nuix. So [speakers clears
throat] there are approximately,
I’ve, I’ve categorized 77
different devices, um, out there
in the wild. [speaker laughs]
Uh, you have the big ones,
Panasonic, Motorola, uh,
PatrolEyes. Now these, these
devices they have uh, a wide
variety of technology. Um, kind
of forced into them. Uh, it’s
wifi, bluetooth, some support
NFC that uh, some devices have
um, triggers. Event, event
triggers you can use. Um, some
do live streaming direct over
GSM. Uh, those are really
popular in Europe. And other
ones have uh, proprietary RF
communications and they ride
along, uh, they, they, they
piggyback on the, the walkabout
radios that uh, police are
using. Alright and it’s very
important to note that these
devices were primarily designed
for transparency versus secrecy,
although, that may be uh, a bit
of a vendor line. Uh, because of
some of the issues that I’ve
found. And we’ll play a little,
little game uh, feature versus
vuln um, as we go through this
presentation. So. Alright,
again, um, so these devices
they, they interact um, the,
they have an entire ecosystem
surrounding them. It’s not just
the camera, which, I’ll show you
more about this one later. Um,
it’s, they, they have, they have
desktop software. Um, some of
them use a blended, uh storage.
So you have onsite storage, you
have cloud repositories, um,
some even have a dedicated uh,
docking stations that use um, an
embedded Linux disko, and they
create, like, a IPSec tunnel
back to a cloud repository. Um,
and uh, most of the ones that
are interesting um, have
smartphone applications that
allow, uh, that allow officers
in the field to annotate uh,
videos, uh, and review the
contents of the camera. Which
we’ll get into later, it’s quite
bad. Um, so this is the first,
first device. Uh, I kinda
started looking at um, back in
January, um, and uh it’s, it’s
sold on Amazon. Anyone can go
and buy it, pick it up. Um, it’s
sold under this, the CEESC
people but, uh, Advanced Plus is
actually the manufacturer of the
device. And um, they, they’re
located in China. Uh, and, I
wanted to mention really quick
that I did get in contact with
the vendor and they have given
me firmware and desktop, desktop
application, uh, but I didn’t
get a chance to review it
because it happened, uh, last
week. So. Anyways um, so this,
this uh particular device, um,
got it. Took it apart, took the
remote apart. Trying to figure
out how the remote is, is
interacting with the, the
camera. Um, and uh, you know,
had to, had to go and look at
some chips and see what, what
frequency it’s operating. It’s
actually 433 uh, and RTL 4D, 433
identifies it as smoke detector
which is kind of interesting.
Um, and the, the neat thing
about the remote and why I
wanted to get these, this device
is because, um, the remote uh,
can be used to be used to
trigger multiple different
cameras, not just one. You, you
can actually um, update the
remote so that it, it triggers
like, a wide variety of cameras.
Um, and so we can kind of be
annoying with that. Because this
is the simple signal that’s
being transmitted. It’s uh,
there’s no rolling codes,
there’s none of that. Um, so, if
you want to you can, you can sit
there with the RTLSTR or receive
the signals. Replay it with
something more powerful than the
hackrf because, well it doesn’t
have much power. Um, uh the
other interesting thing about
this device is when I was
getting in contact with the
manufacturer, um, they told me
about their RF certification and
it was not FCC certified. So,
there’s that. Uh, [speaker
laughs] wow. Another thing about
it is it’s essentially a USB
drive. So anything that you have
uh, you know, records the
videos, it drops’em down onto
the, the, the dedicated storage
on the device. You plug it in to
your computer uh, you pull the,
the things off just like a, a, a
USB storage. So if I wanted to
put autorun dot inf, or take
advantage of some link
vulnerabilities that have been
popular in the past, uh, that’s
completely possible with this
camera. Alright so here’s
another, nother camera, this is
the uh, on call OC P Pro. Um, as
you see the architecture of the
system uh, down there in big uh,
but uh, unfortunately uh,
because of the, one I got, um
nothing really works. [speaker
laughs] Uh, so, I, I got it, um,
it, it, I think the USB was
broken. It wouldn't, wouldn't
maintain the USB connection. Um,
so everything to the uh, to, to
your, your right of the arrows I
didn't get a chance to test out.
Uh, but there were enough
glaring issues um, on the other
part that it's fun to talk
about. Um it uses an RTOS called
eCos. Uh, that’s um, hasn’t,
there has, there hasn’t been
very many updates on that, that
particular um, website in, in
quite awhile. Uh, when you
trigger the wifi on it through a
button press, um, it comes up as
FIRE-CAM and that is the default
password. Uh, [audience laughs]
and yes, and it, it has a uh, a
wonderful embedded eCos HTTP
server, um, that I thought would
be kind of fun to poke at, but,
you’ll see that it wasn’t really
necessary. [audience laughs] Um,
yes, so, so this is the contents
of the uh, the movie folder. Um,
and you see the, all the videos.
But it’s coming up as 2014
because I kinda never got a good
time sync for my, for my laptop.
Um, but these are all the same
videos, and you see you can
remove them, download them,
upload files. Um, you can
actually even uh, upload
arbitrary HTML and serve that in
the browser. That’s not good.
[audience laughs] [speaker
clears throat] Um, yea, so.
Totally unprotected. 100
percent. No, nothing. Nothing at
all, preventing anyone from
downloading these videos or
uploading ones in, um, ones to
uh, kind of overwrite these. Um,
and uh, I have a, uh, I wrote
some tools that use GITs and
posts, um, to overwrite files
and download all of the
contents. Um, It also has a, uh,
a nice settings file, uh,
that’s, um, you can download as
well that has all of the
relevant information about the
camera in it. Which is
interesting. Okay. So here’s the
first, kind of, big device uh,
widely kind of used. A device
that I had, had a chance to, to
look at. So this, this
particular device, has, has um,
smart, um it has a smartphone
application that you can go and
download on, available on the
playstore. Um, it has desktop
software that is, is available
for download on the
manufacturer, or the, the
resellers website. And I say
reseller because we will, we
will show, I’ll show you this in
a moment. Alright, and the
firmware is also available for
anyone to go ahead and pull
down, and browse, and look
through because it’s not signed
and it’s not encrypted. Which is
awesome. Uh, right, so
smartphone application is
primarily used to access the
RTSP server that is not
protected from anyone. Uh, and,
um, you can view the saved
videos on the device. And the,
the desktop software is, is used
to um, to authenticate with the
camera. Uh, and, and download
the video files off of the
camera. So, uh the desktop
software, as you see there, is
the, it’s simple, it's a simple
um, wrapper around the DMT10 dot
DLL. Um, and that is uh,
actually, the, the name of that
comes, I think, comes from um,
the Chinese manufacturer cause
they sell the DMT10 version of
this camera. The admin and
general user passwords are, uh,
6 characters, they have to be
exactly 6 characters. No more or
no less. Um, it has the SSID as
you see for amba boss. Uh, and
that’s not something that you
can change. And I’ll, I’ll get
into that, why that’s, that’s
kind of a big deal later. Um,
and you have some other things
you can, can mess with in the,
this is the administrative
interface. Um, as with all of
the other desktop software that
I have looked at, um, it’s
missing a lot of the uh,
exploitation prevention
mechanisms, like, ASOR. Uh, um.
And that, that’s kind of across
the board. Uh you see here,
there’s little bit, a little
clip from IDA, uh, to verify
password. Um, routine, coming
from DMT10. Uh, and then you
have the set password, uh export
that’s called from uh, that’s
available in DMT10 as well. Uh,
and you can see that there’s no
correlation between the two.
That means that I can set the
password without having to
verify the password, and, yeah.
So that’s awesome. [audience
laughs] [speaker laughs] Yeah.
K. Again, it comes with a
smartphone application. If you
wanted to go find it, there,
there it is. Uh, and that is
primarily used to uh, view said
videos and livestream whatever
the, the camera is looking at.
Um, and the uh, I want to, be
sure to, to mention all of these
cameras except, I think, for the
next one uh, when you activate
the wifi on these devices they
um, they create a access point.
Right? They act as, as a wifi
like, hotspot without internet
connectivity. Um, so, uh, so
that, that’s kind of important
because if anyone’s wanting to
review videos they created
essentially a beacon upon
themselves that uh, anyone can
kind of find and play with. And
we’ll talk more about that part
later. Right, so, again, this,
this device um, it’s running a
little bit of an older version
of Linux. That’s, that’s not
really bad. Um, again, it has,
has a JSON messaging server
which I was really surprised
about. Um, and the RTSP and, and
DNS and, and after um, after uh,
I got to poke around on the
system, I found out that it was
incredibly simi, similar to um,
a talk GoPro or a get the f**k
out. Um, that uh, if you wanna
know anything more about how
this system operates I would uh,
really recommend going reading
and looking through that cause
it has a lot um, it goes to a
lot in, in depth about the
messaging subsystem. Um, and I
wish I would have found that out
[speaker laughs] right? When I,
when I was looking at this. But
uh, I didn't need to because it
has root telnet exposed with no
password required. [audience
laughs and applauds] And I, I
wrote a wrapper script a bit
around pi Telnet that allows you
to upload and download files if
you don’t feel like using
Telnet. Um, again, here’s the
contents of the, the uh, media
um, yea the media folder. So any
videos that you make are saved
into here. Um, this directory is
mounted when you use the desktop
software um, to download and
upload videos. Um, and it, it
essentially sends a uh, a
trigger to the camera uh, and we
can then, it’s like it, it
treats it as a, as a removable
media drive. So, if you wanted
to upload, again, link files or
any type of Windows based
exploits um, to take advantage
of the back end digital evidence
storage repository where these
videos will be saved and, you
know, have something nice like,
wanna cry, um, you could
definitely do that. Uh, what,
yea. So, there we go. So this is
um, uh, this device, the Digital
Ally FirstVu HD, is
architecturally different than
all of the other cameras. Um, it
treats it, it is a client. K?
And it has other devices in its
ecosystem that uh, that act as
servers. For example, the um,
the rearview mirror in a cop car
will act as a wifi access point.
When this device is within rage,
it will automatically connect to
that wifi access point. And then
um, you know, interact uh,
through that. It’s also how if
you’re able, if you turn on the
sirens uh, it will automatically
start recording. It has event
triggers. That kind of
technology. Uh, and again it sm,
it supports, has its own desktop
software that I tried to
purchase 3 month uh, 2 months
ago and I did not get. Which was
unfortunate. It has a smartphone
application that anyone can
download. Um, firmware is
available and easy to look
through. Literally Tar. We’ll
unpack the firmware uh, and it
uh, does have a, a docking
station um, that, you know, you
can, you take the camera out and
plug it in and it will download
stuff. Um, but, interestingly
enough, it does come with a
minimal software bundle um, on
the device, for anyone who, who
gets ahold of it and wants to
uh, [clip glitches] minimum
configuration manager and a
minimum software viewer to uh,
to view the contents and, and
um, see whatever’s going on on
the device. You can also um,
yeah it also has a, like, uh,
read me’s on there about how the
device is supposed to work. So
it’s very, very usler, user
friendly. And kind of nice. Um,
so here is a picture of the uh,
it’s a, um, the minimum, the
like, the minim, minimal viewer
that comes packaged on the
device. Right? Uh, the software
VuVault I tried to purchase um,
and, well hopefully it will get
here eventually. Because there
was a lot of features that I
wasn't able to um, interact with
and, and play around with
because I didn't have that. Uh,
one of those main features being
you turn the hot, you turn the
device into a wireless client,
right? I couldn't, I couldn't do
that because you have to pay the
800 dollars for the desktop
software. Um, but we were still,
we were still able to um, get
some good stuff out of it. So
the uh, the packaged installer
is written in C sharp, which is
awesome because it’s really easy
to uh, decompile and play around
with. Uh, the configuration
manager uh, generates 2 types of
files. The wum, WUM config, and
that’s for wireless. Uh, it also
generates the device config and
that is a binary format that’s
um, that you can uh, use to set
the time and stuff like that.
Now the uh, the viewer um, which
is used for evidence review and
making comments and, and uh
clipping videos and stuff
generates 3 types of files. The
DAZ file, which is the digital
ally zip file. Uh, the metadata
file and then the VM2 file which
is XML. Uh, and we, we’ll go
into those right now. So, the
WUM config file is quite
interesting because it does
something that you’re supposed
to generate through the
configuration uh, software and
then put on the device. And it
configures the device on how to
interact with uh, police
networks and police cam, um,
like, systems, right? So that
would be important. So that
would not be a good thing to
have that uh, XOR as, as the way
to decode it. Uh, and you can
see here that the, it’s
configured to use the, to look
for the, the SSID that is
associated with a police network
and has the PSK um, that is just
text encoded. Uh, and the
password for FTP logins um, so
that it can upload and download
whatever media is on the device
as it goes. Um, then the, the
device config file is, again, to
um, to insert time and other
information onto the device. Uh,
that, um, has uh, couple lines
worth of an X mark, but it
basically is an equivalent to a
X88 XOR. So that’s, that’s cool.
Oh and um, 001 is before and
then the small one is after when
you decode it uh, with, with
XOR. Uh, here is the DAZ file.
The DAZ file is generated
through the viewer application
when you, you have, so you have
the, the AVI and the metadata
file. You insert that into the
viewer application, and then you
mess around with vid, with the
video and you save it out and it
creates this DAZ file and all
this other stuff. Um, the, the
VM2 file here is included in
the, in the ZIP file. Uh, and
it, you see it has a huge amount
of metadata associated with how
this, this camera was operating.
Um, and how um, you know, like,
what sensors were used, what’s
the GPS cords, all of this kind
of stuff, right? And you see
here it uses AES128CBC. And the
final name is the decryption
key. [audience laughs] See here,
we have it, it like, in, in this
we would have D0018002 and then
we just basically make that
unicode and we have the IV and
the decryption key for our AES
uh, whatever. That’s, that’s
awesome. [audience laughs]
[speaker laughs] Right. So since
uh, since the digital ally was
so nice to include an unsigned
installer on their application,
uh, I thought it would be fun to
um, insert a back door into
that. Because, I can override
it, uh download it, modify it,
push it back, override it, and
then if anybody wants to install
it, they, they give me a nice
shell. Uh, so. Uh, you see here
the um, top IDA, that’s the
normal entry point. I just hand
jammed this assembly. And all
that does is it creates a thread
on the, uh, on the section that
I added to the application. And
that section is oh noes. Uh, and
then underneath [light audience
laughter] I, uh, simply put in
some metasploit, reverse shell
shellcode. And this is the uh,
here, we have the install
shield. Uh, and down here we
have the shell. Um, that’s
generated. I had to cut a lot of
videos. So, for time. But. So
that’s really bad. [audience
laughs] [speaker laughs] Right.
So um, again, the, the android
application, which you can
download on playstore, um, is
used to uh, basically use the
configuration manager and use
Sideload Config Files onto it.
And that will turn your, your
phone into um, into an access
point that the camera can then
talk to. Now I was hoping that
after 2 months I would get the
software that I purchased. Uh,
and so I didn't bother to
reverse engineer it on, with
Frida. Um, but I might have to
soon. Or get my money back. I
don't know, like [speaker
laughs] Right. So, again, uh,
here is the firmware that you
can get from the, from, from the
manufacturer. Um, again, binwalk
and Tar is really all you need.
Um, but as you’re going through
the uh, the firmware, cause one,
once it gets extracted it has
some, some really interesting,
uh interesting things going on
in there. Um, but I think I'm
gonna put in version 2 of this
talk. There’s some serious
unbounded memory copy operations
going on. Uh, but anyways if, if
you don’t um, want to uh, uh
debug anything running on the
device we create a nice little
log file on the, on the, the
camera. Um, it creates every,
after every operation here, we
have this, this log stuff going
on after ev, in every function,
it generates that. So there’s
tons of login information and
stuff. And all you gotta do is
create the log file and [speaker
makes fart sound] it’s good to
go. Uh, the Gui application in
the MDVR, mobile DVR, pretty
sure what that means. Uh, is
what’s used to do all of this
interesting stuff. And it does
some really interesting stuff.
Because there’s lots of wifi
triggers and peer to peer
operations going on with all of
these devices when they’re
within the same network. Uh, and
there’s a lot of unbounded
memory copying operations going
on on these devices. [audience
laughs] And they are peer to
peer network. Um, but yea I
think I’ll, I’ll save that for
the next version. Ah! This guy.
I wanted to spend some time on
this because um, this camera is
used uh, uh in some pretty big
um, in some pretty big
departments. Uh, again it has
the smartphone application, it
has the awesome desktop
software, uh, it even has
docking station and, and it
supports cloud storage. And you
can get the firmware. Um, and
they tried, they tried to be uh,
have a pretty professionalized
uh, operation. Um, again,
smartphone for live streaming
and viewing media which we’ll
talk about later. And uh,
desktop software for actually
verifying that the media files
that are coming from the device
are valid. And we’ll talk about
that later too. So here is the
desktop software. It is a fat
client, right? So, essentially
you have a sequel database
install and then you have some,
2 fat clients for admin. 1 for
admin and 1 for officers, right?
Uh, and it’s used to um, the
admin app is used to configure
the cameras and then assign them
to, to, to various officers. Uh,
and then the client application
is used to upload, download
video uh, and, and that’s
essentially it. Right? You can
add comments but really
uploading, downloading videos
from the cameras, exporting them
from the, the, the fat client is
essentially it. Um, but another
application that is installed
with this is the import export
tool. Um, and, there’s, there's
2 types of authentication going
on here. You have the
authentication and then the
passwords that are created for,
through the admin app that is,
that are used to uh, interact
with the, the software and with
the, the contents of the
database. Now, then you have the
uh, Windows authentication
mechanism which is actually used
by the import export tool, to
authenticate with the database
bypassing all of the um, uh
VieVu at auth and uses straight
uh, Windows auth. So if I am
local admin, somewhere out
there, on a desktop that is
used, that the officer is using
the client app to upload and
download videos, I can then
connect and uh, export videos
but uh, I’ll show you that in a
minute. There are other things
associated with this. We have
um, we have lots of the install
folders that kind of spreads out
everywhere when you install it
on your, on your box. Um, and we
have logs about the, the uh,
communication between your
computer and this device. Um, it
communicates over uh, USB.
Creates a calm serial over USB.
Uh, it attaches to the, the, uh
file and then starts writing
stuff out to it. Um it also uh,
has, has a downloaded metadata
that like, downloaded videos
that are cached on the
computers. So uh, bypass
download, you have access to the
downloaded metadata by boss,
bypassing the upload client by
just looking into the, the
correct folder. Um, yea. And,
and again, if you go there you
can see all the cached videos.
K, so domain credentials. What I
was kind of talking about
earlier. Uh, I used to export
the database instead of the
application credentials that you
use when you uh, create users.
Um, and that is the uh, admin
user super. For supervisor I
suppose. Uh, and that’s the SHA
1 of 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6. Which is
the default password uh, for all
of the uh, admin um, yeah. For
the, for the supervisor for the
admin interface, right? Um, and
they, they try to, when you
install this you start it up
but, this is how I found it. Uh,
it requires, they ask you to, to
contact their help and support
system to configure the desktop
software. Really it’s so that
they can upsell you. Right? And
so I was like, well no I don’t
want to do that um, because it
probably wouldn’t be good having
Josh at his house contacting
support people. Um, and, and so
I was clicking around and found
the import export tool and
Googled the password. Uh, and
then I was able to have admin on
their software. Which, also, you
have to buy, so. [audience
laughs] Uh, ah! Another issue
with this, is when you download
videos off of the camera um,
you, it, it uh, you can, you can
play those videos through the
interface. Right? Through,
through the uh, um, the admin or
the client interface you can
review the videos. Um, and to do
that it comes bundled with
ffmpeg. Uh, and um it also uses
ffmpeg to uh, to create
thumbnails based on the videos.
So, not only when you just play
the video does it use ffmpeg,
uh, but when you uh, when you
upload all of the videos at, at
the time of upload it uses this
to create thumbnails of the
videos. Which is important
because it’s processing videos
with a version of ffmpeg that is
from 2014 and has over 122
public CVEs out there for this
version of ffmpeg. So if I could
modify those version, those
videos beforehand, insert and
exploit, I know I have a really,
really vulnerable piece of
software that’s gonna process
those videos, which would then
give me, uh, gain me access to
the evidence storage repository
where these, these videos are
stored. Ah, so here we have the,
the admin interface um, of the,
of the Veripatrol software. Uh,
and you see here we have, we
have several videos that have
been uploaded by supervisor and
their durations are, you know,
in there, and they have valid
digital signatures. Alright and
then we have over, over here we
have it making a copy of the
video and exporting it and
stuff. And there’s an important
video that we need to look at
right there it has a time length
of 0 and a valid digital
signature. So, [speaker clears
throat] as we export these AVI
files from the interface, uh we
have, we, you know, just pick a,
pick an output folder and it
creates the AVI file and then it
has the log file that uh, that
requires all the comments put in
there. Uh and it saves them to
wherever you want, and again it
says this file has a valid
digital signature. A valid
digital signature. [audience
laughs] So this is the contents
of that AVI file that has a
valid digital signature.
[audience laughs] >>That holds
up in a court of law, right?
>>That is used to prosecute
people and put them in jail.
[audience laughs] Uh, and I’ll,
I’ll show you how I did that,
uh, in a moment. Again, so we
have the interaction uh, with
this device. Um, it has uh, you
know, when we created our log,
it has a lot of files that are
nice and kind of cruise through
those. Uh, it uses serial
communications over USB uh to
upload download files, update
firmware, uh, and do all that
kind of nice fancy stuff. Well
the other day when I noticed
when I was downloading those
files, which were quite big, uh,
it actually just tells the
device to mount uh, uh this,
the, the application just tells
the device to mount itself as a
removable media drive. And then
downloads the files. So if, if
you want to write an application
to interact with this we see
that, that the command system is
incredibly complex right here.
[audience laughs] Uh, and very
difficult to modify. And we can
see right here that the device
gets mounted as the e drive. Uh,
and then it begins to upload the
files so as I see this random
drive pop up on my computer I'm
like, oh! What’s in e? [audience
laughs] Let me, let me open
that. And then you can just
download the files off of that,
completely bypassing all of the
evidence collection software.
[audience laughs] So, awesome.
[audience laughs] Uh, right.
Again so we have the, the uh
smartphone application um, that
is supposed to interact with
this device in the field. Um,
and it uploads metadata to each
video based off, with JSON,
which is pretty standard. You
can also download any file off
of this device, right? So, uh,
and then you can live stream uh,
with RTSP. So the only thing you
need to do is if, if you found
one of these in the wild, is
download the app. And you can
see anything on it. Also if
you‘re within proximity of some
police officers and you’d like
to see what they see, you can
see, you can see that over RTSP.
Um, there was some pretty good
talk a little while ago about
the sunplus format. Uh, and
there’s some tools out there
that I definitely used. I
conversed the sunplus uh, burn
firmware burn format to uh, to
IDB, which is great. Uh, it’s
freaking awesome. You should
check that out. I love it. Uh,
so you don’t have to unpacked or
unpack firmware or do anything
like that, it’s just ready. Good
to go. Now this device has
several services that are
available on it. And it is this
1 right here. Uh, uh it has FTP
uh, it has the photo transfer
protocol and it has RTSP. FTP is
used for uploading downloading
files. it's also used for, with
the smartphone it’s used to, you
know, upload and download
metadata. So you can download
any video off the device. You
can also sign um, you know, any
type of metadata through the
JSON interface. Now, for you to
be able to get um, for, for the
smartphone to get a directory
listing of which files are
available, uh, it uses the photo
transfer protocol which um,
there’s some really great git
repos out there about using PTP
over wifi. Um, and that’s gonna
be important in a minute. And
then of course RTSP which, you
know you just use VLC. So, if I
wanted to see what all of the,
what all of the, uh video that
was stored on this device, you
simply use PTP. Uh, and we can
see here that we have some AVI
files that were filled with A’s
earlier available in our PTP
directory listing. Now for us to
interact with that incredibly
sophisticated uh, FTP software
and overwrite files that should
be digitally signed and use to
uh, put people in jail, uh, we
use FTP and we have some
passwords Wificam and username
wificam. It actually accepts any
combination. [audience laughs]
So if you don’t remember
wificam, you can try any other
combination and it will work.
Uh, then we have uh, we, we just
use type 1 and then we uh, we
enter pass, passive mode. I was
playing around here trying to
delete video files, it wouldn’t
let me delete the preexisting
video files, but it would let e
overwrite them with whatever I
wanted. [audience laughs] And
that is how we got A uh, in that
digitally signed valid evidence
file from earlier. Okay so we
have like, a little demo we’ll
show you here. Let’s turn this
guy on. Cool, it’s on. Alright.
So another thing that I, I
wrote, um was a tool to uh,
identify these cameras in the
wild based on their Mac address
and their wireless access
points. As I said, I was in the
military and I, I think a very,
very important yet often
overlooked thing uh, is the
ability to, to locate something
[speaker clears through] uh,
like in the field and be able to
identify the emitter with the
platform. The platform being the
police, and the emitter being
the camera. Uh, and if I know
that VieVu, I and look in the
OUI database, and I see the Mac
addresses that are associated
with this company, that is
published by the I triple E. Uh,
and I can say that this company
only makes cameras. If I pick up
a Mac address or a SSID that’s
associated with that, well guess
what it’s only gonna be? It’s
only gonna be this. Right? And
uh, as a bad guy, you might want
to know that. Right? Maybe find
out about cops running around in
their area. Let’s see if this is
working. I don’t know. Yep. Live
demo’s a**. Let’s see if it’s
connected. Okay. Let’s see. Okay
yeah there it is right there.
See if my bugging software
works. Nope! It’s not working
right now. Oh well! This is a 2
part demo. [audience laughs]
Alright so everybody knows that,
like, USB, wifi and Linux is
s**t. It’s been the story of my
life trying to get one interface
that works right. Um, but
anyways uh, if you want it’s
supposed to identify this guy
right here that we see. Uh, and
we can just connect to that. Um,
and then the password is
1234567890. It's very
complicated. Anyways so here um,
again, no, nothing really
protecting uh, anything that’s
going on. We’ll just go ahead
and we can just use VLC. It’s
that easy. Takes awhile. Ta da!
[audience applauds] Hi Defcon!
Heeeey. So again, again,
feature, feature right? This is
a, this is a feature. >>I don’t
want that feature. >>That is
awful, right? [audience laughs]
Anybody that would be like, yeah
I would like to live stream some
video off of a police officer
whenever I want. That’s a
feature. Oh and the
manufacturer’s like just say
that, oh it’s only supposed to
be right here. Yeah cause, cause
wifi antennas can’t pick up
stuff from a mile away, like,
that hasn’t been proven years
ago, right? Okay. And, and we
can change the default password
on this to give it something
very complex because crack
doesn’t exist. And neither does
that wifi uh, thing the other
day where um, you could, you
could get the, the key without
even needing a client on the WPA
to uh, uh network. If you guys
haven't read that I highly
encourage doing it. Okay so
where’d my presentation, come
back. Alright. Here we are.
Bang. Okay. So, cool. Industry
wide issues. Right? So I analyze
many cameras, I can talk about
5. Uh and an industry wide issue
is digital signatures are not
applied to the multimedia coming
off of the device before it
touches anything else. Which
means that if anyone is able to
get in between that being,
either being on the desktop or
interacting with the device in
the field, you can corrupt any
kind of evident trait in
information on that device. And
that is supposed to stand up in
a court of law and out people in
jail. Again, unencrypted
firmware, unsigned firmware.
Unsigned. Your smartphone signs
as firmware, right? That, how
much does that cost? How much do
these things cost? About the
same. Right? So you can cruise,
you can see anything you want.
If you have physical access to
the device you could roll your
own malware, drop it on there
and then as soon as it gets
synced back in the back end
[speaker snaps fingers] you own
them. Done. 3 minutes? Okay.
Cool. Uh and again,
localization. Being able to find
stuff out there, I wore walk,
find cops. Cool? Why it’s
important? Uh because this
happened here last year. Right?
And the guy had cameras in the
hallways and he was targeting
police. If he knew about this,
he’d be able to do that a lot
better. K. Thanks. Thanks to
SAHA and everyone at basement
brotherhood. [audience applauds
and cheers] Uh, Nuix CTAT. Cool.
And I think I have a couple
minutes, I got questions? I got
time for questions? Like 1, 1
question. >>I gotta question,
what time is it?! >>It’s team
grind time, Tim. >>That’s right
baby! That’s right! [speaker
laughs] >>Yes. >>[inaudible
question from audience member]
>>Some do, some don’t. Some you
can actually configure to always
be on the wifi. Always have wifi
on. Some use bluetooth.
>>[inaudible question from
audience member] >>No. This
doesn’t show anything. It’s just
on. It’s still connected to my
laptop. >>Have you tried to
[indiscernible] >>I have but
it’s very difficult to get any
response at all back and they
don't publish who uh, you know,
who they’re selling these things
to. Except for the NYP, you can
go to these guys’ websites, they
have a couple of their big
contracts on there. >>Yeah they
won’t even send you the software
you purchased. >>No they won’t
even send me the software I
bought. [laughter] So, cool.
[music outro] [applause]