>>Hello everyone, thank you for
coming. Uh and we are very
excite, excited to share our
research at DefCon. Our
presentation today is to talk
about the security of smart
speakers. We find and exploited
some vulnerabilities to attack
some smart speakers such as
Xiaomi AI Speaker and Amazon
Echo. First, please let me
introduce my teammate and
myself. Li Yuxiang is a security
researcher at the Tencent Blade
Team. He has found several
vulnerabilities in Android and
he was the speaker of Hack in
the Box and he worked with us to
complete all the work of our
study. Unfortunately he is not
hard work today and this is my
teammate Qian Wenxiang. He is
also security researcher for our
Tencent Blade Team and he's on
top 100 in the world list of
MSRC. And he write a book called
named “Whitehat to Talk About
Web Browser Security.” And my
name is Hui and you call me, and
you can call me Nicky. I'm a
security researcher at Tencent
Blade Team, I'm also a bug
hunter, winner of Geekpwn and
speaker of Hack in the Box and
POC. And here we would like to
thanks some people especially
Lake2 and GMXP they give us
another support. Next, let me
introduce the Tencent Blade
Team. Our team comes from
Tencent security planned fund
department. Now we are focusing
on the security research of AI,
IoT devices, mobile devices. In
the past two years, we have
found more than 17 security
vulnerabilities for many
companies such as Google and
Apple. And you can contact us at
Blade dot Tencen dot com. Before
we start our presentation, let’s
take a brief look at our
tonight. First, we will give
introduction to smart speaker
and then we will talk about the
attack service of smart speakers
then we will show the details of
remote attack Xiaomi AI speaker
and how to break in Amazon Echo.
And last we will summarize our
research. Smart speakers is the
most popular smart home devices
in the last 2 years. Amazon,
Google, Apple and some Chinese
vendors have released their own
smart speaker products. The
Amazon Echo family is the most
popular smart speaker on the
market. It has more than 30
million users and many people
are very interest -are very
interested in its security so we
choose it’s uh, our research
target. Another research target
is Xiaomi AI Speaker. Xiaomi AI
Speaker is very popular in China
because it can control many
smart devices in Xiaomi
ecosystems. Next, let’s briefly
analyze the attack surface of
the smart speaker. In smart
speaker architecture, it mainly
includes three parts. Uh the
part, the first part is smart
speaker device, the second is
cloud server, and last is mobile
phone application. The attack
surface of this architecture
contains, contains many parts.
The first part is the hardware
interface and the net code
words, uh of the sm- speaker
device. The second part is
security of the mobile phone
application. The third part is
the security of the cloud server
and the last part is security of
the communication protocol
between them. Then, uh I will
talk about how we can explore
MIIO term vulnerabilities to
remote attack Xiaomi AI Speaker.
Uh, this include bad part.
Xiaomi AI Speaker had built in
system based on OpenWrt. Uh, -it
it uh S, S -uh SH service design
board and the firmware of the
speaker can be downloaded easily
by http request but we cannot
replace the firmware with the
Man-in-the-Media attacks because
of uh, -it’s security mechanism.
In addition, it opens up some
network parts and uh, the
5-4-3-2-1 is the communication
board of the MIIO Protocol. MIIO
Protocol is used to configure
and control smart home devices
made by Xiaomi. It is uh
encrypted the binary protocol.
After analyzing the firmware of
Xiaomi AI speaker, we found that
the data included in the MIIO
packet was passed into UBUS
commanders and executed by
Xiaomi AI speaker with root
permission. So, if we can
simulate Xiaomi smart devices to
communicate with Xiaomi AI
Speaker, you can use this
protocol to execute root
commander which is a root
commander execution
vulnerability in line. In order
to explore this vulnerability,
we first need to examine each
collection with the speaker and
pass the certification of MIIO
part protocol. This will require
us to obtain a AES key for
connection because it keying as
token. This token is 16 bit
stream. To get this token, we
need to use the MI home
application to reband the
speaker to attack the arm
account. Then extract the token
from a- applications database.
We found a web interface WEP
authority vulnerability so we
can only need to get the device
ID to un- to unbind any speaker
device. And we find the device
ID can be opened by sniffing the
line. After got the token, we
can use some tools to connect
the Xiaomi AI speaker by pro-
MIIO protocol. Then we can send
some UBUS commanders to the
speaker. The first commander is
used to modify the dropbear
configure fair, and the second
commander is to turn off the
dropbear pass- password
authentication. Finally, we need
to start the dropbear. After
executed this UBUS commanders,
we can suc- successfully to
access the SSH of MIIO speaker
and logging without password and
it means we have obtained the
root permission of the speaker.
In addition, we find another
vulnerability problem called
Message Agent which is used to
MQTT communication between
speaker and cloud servers. When
a user controls some the
speaker’s function in a mobile
phone, the application
communicates with the cloud
server first, then the cloud
servers sends the device ID to
the message agent, then the
message agent will executed the
commander. We find the two
special web interfaces, one is
remote UBUS which is can call
the UBUS server remotely and the
other is UBU- remote OTA. The-
the commander in the bios
calling this interface will be
executed using the system
function so which is a remote
system com- commander execution
vulnerability. There are two
pieces of the vulnerability code
that are highlighted in the
using [indiscernible] Once
[indiscernible] codes UBUS
service and the second finally
works with the system function.
Since these two vulnerable web
interfaces have identity
certification, if we want to
exploit this vulnerable
remotely, uh we have to get the
users cookie for the speaking
bonding. In the later research,
we find two excess vulnerability
in -in Xiaomi dot com which
allow us to remotely steal a
large number of, uh, MI IS users
cookies so now we- we can
exploit these vulnerabilities to
complete the attack chain of
remotely obtain the root
permission of MI AI Speaker.
Now, let’s take a brief look at
the first demo video. This video
demonstrate the two
vulnerabilities we mentioned.
The first part of the uh video
demonstrate the connecting the
to the speaker with SHH in the
night and control it play a
piece of audio. [Indistinct
voice in the video] Um, because
Xiaomi AI Speaker doesn’t speak
English so we control it say a
Chinese meaning “Winner winner,
chicken dinner”. In the second
video, the victim is the sm-
smart speaker is remotely
controlled by the attack after
connect URL. Okay, now we will
finish the section on Xiaomi AI
Speaker. Let’s talk about how to
break in Amazon Echo. This
include six parts and now we are
beginning to talk about the
previous four parts and the
exploit detail and demo video
will be shared by my teammates.
First let’s have a brief look
at, let, let’s have a brief look
the Amazon Echo. In the newly
released second generation Echo
family or the Amazon Echo Device
use similar hardware and
assistance so we chose the Echo
Dot as our test devices. Amazon
Echo Dot has built in Fire OS
which is actually as system
based on Android. This runs on
SELinux and ASLR, loads the
bootloader and is has a USB
interface but it can only use
for charging. We also found some
another way by scanning At the
beginning, we tried to get the
firmware for a long time but we
got nothing so we chose to start
with hardware and extract the
firmware directly from the flat
chip. In order to extract the
firmware from the flat chip, we
needed to pre- prepare a lot of
hardware tools which included
hot air gun, soldering iron,
reballing tools, and so on.
Okay, this is the second demo
video. This video shows how to
dis- desolder the chip from the
PCB in six minutes and then
rebond the chip. To save time,
we doubled the speed. The most
important skill is to choose a
suitable temperature and be
careful. Okay. When we desolder
the, desolder and rebond the
chip, we need to choose a
suitable temp- chip adapter
according to the chip's data
shade. Amazon Echo uses the
BGA221 package EMCP Chip which
we can easily buy a adapter on
Taobao or eBay. And we can also
buy a universal EMMC reader and
uh connect the adapter to the
USB reader device so that we can
read and write the firmware
content in the EMCP Chip easily.
And this is the disk um
partition information we
extracted from the flash chip.
It contains many parts such as
preloader, bootloader, boot
image, system, and so on. When
we got the firmware, we had
another important thing to do.
That is to modify the firmware
to create a Amazon Echo Dot with
root permission. This can help
us quickly debug some
vulnerabilities because Amazon
Echo Dot turned on SELinux and
logged on the boot loader, we
cannot directly modify the boot
image to,a to root. We need to
close SELinux and then a -the
superuser binary field to the
system and the start. And then
we need to open the system IDB
function. We add this operations
to a shared script that start
auto- automatically so that
every time the system boots, it
can make sure we can connect the
Echo Dot from it’s USB interface
and get the root permission.
After complete this, oh okay,
sorry. And this is the third
demo video to show how to solder
in the chip. [Video] After
complete this modification, we
need to restore the flash chip
back to the PCB. This video
demonstrate how to restore the-
the chip back to the PCB in
three minutes. And to save time,
we also double the video speed.
[Video] Okay. Uh, before we
complete this operation, we have
got a rooted Echo Dot and okay,
my part is over. Uh, thank you
for listening. Now please
welcome my partner Qian
Wenxiang. >>Okay, uh hello
everyone. Now I am going to give
a talk about how to turn Amazon
Echo to an exploiting device on
the basis of software. Uh,
earlier my partner has gave a
great talk about how to uh hack
into the Echo Device on the
basis of hardware. The physical
hack’s very important; without
that, exploiting will be much
difficult for me. So, how many
steps would it take to hack into
a device. The first attacker
exploited, and then the victim
connects to the hacker and next
the hacker do whatever he or she
wants to do. Yes, the step is
simple but on a well protected
system, things will get a little
complicated. Since we already
got firmware and debugging
environment, we are able to
check the restrictions that
Amazon has set up for us. So
first, please allow me introduce
the protections we need to
bypass first. There are three
firewalls or firewall-like
things . The system use IPtables
to allow only a few ports from
accepting connections and the
uh, the uh SELinux is also
enabled. We manage to find a
binary with high privileges to
bypass it. This binary is a
vulnerable program uh shows in
the picture and it has a web
server activated. To communicate
with it, we must pass our client
authenticated TLS handshake.
That means we must get
certificates and other things
but those certs are all obtained
from the card synchronizing. In
another word, we need to get the
card synchronizing information
of other devices. So attacker is
always happy to see there’s a
web server available. That
explains why we choose this
binary to be our target. In the
next few slides, please allow me
to produces some background
information so we can go through
these things more clearly. THe
WHAD, W.H.A.D which is a whole
home audio deamon. It is a huge
binary runs at the root and with
network access and is able to
recall the voice. Also, the most
excited part is it would open a
web server. The https server
runs on port 55443 and it
accepts control commands. But uh
things are not going as we
wished to be. The https server
introduced client authenticated
TLS handshakes. Uh that means we
must have a third server
certificate, uh client
certificate and a private key to
communicate with it. Though this
sounds difficult but we have
also noticed that the physically
rooted device uh can also pass a
check and communicate with other
devices. So the information must
be stored in somewhere. By
reading the document of
libcurl’s we know we can scratch
all certificates and private key
from libcurl’s negotiate
function on a rooted device. To
do the trick, the first thing we
need to do is to bind our rooted
device into victim’s account.
I’ll explain this why -why, why
we do this later. By auditing
Amazon’s website, we have found
two XSS and both need two steps
of users’ actions so we decide
not using them. But the XSS here
is fatal. You can steal privacy,
or control the device with a
cookie obtained from XSS because
XS-4 is makeup modern
protections such as SP which is
uh content security policy and
https only protects. Yes, by
using the XSS you can get the
same result of what we’ll talk
later but we also found another
method which is the quickest and
easiest for us, that is to spoof
an Amazon website. We have found
that every time when we log into
the Alexa, there’s an OpenID
login page and there’s also a
redirect parameter in the url.
If I modify that parameter, it
will redirect to any domain
which is a subdomain of Amazon
dot com in https. SInce we want
to mimic an Amazon’s website so
we don’t want to mess up with
the https certificate so we’d
like to have a https downgrade
redirect. And luckily we have
found the site asso-redirect dot
amazon dot com. It’s validation
rules allows to downgrade to
http. It also have some
vulnerabilities that could re-
uh that could be redirect to
other site which is not belongs
to Amazon and making some token
from OpenID. But now the only
thing we need is the downgrade.
Okay, we want to spoof Amazon’s
website inside victim’s LAN but
there are two preconditions. The
first one is the attacker need-
need to be joined uh the
victim’s LAN and the second is
we need to find the Amazon
domain which resolves to a local
address. An attacker can be
joined into the LAN with that IP
address and both are not hard to
be satisfied. You can get a list
of subdomains from Google
transparency report, then you
can use TCP/IP to use a static
IP address to join into the LAN.
Uh, we have found the
aapsservice which resolves to a
local address. If attacker could
join the LAN of victim with that
address then start a web server,
when victim tries to visit
aapsservice dot amazon dot com
in his or her browser, actually
the victim -victim is visiting
the hacker’s website. Also,
because it has the root domain
of Amazon dot com, the cookie
will be sent to the attacker
automatically from the browser.
To sum up, uh first the attacker
joins the LAN and when victim
log in from the Alexa login page
with the redirect parameter set
to associate with redirect to
Amazon dot com and when victim
finish the login, the page with
redirect to assoc-redirect dot
amazon dot com then this site
will downgrade and redirect to
aapsservice dot amazon dot com.
This domain resolves to
attacker’s computer and the user
will finally visit the
attacker’s website with the
cookie sent to it. Then the
attacker bind his device into
victim’s account using the
cookie. And finally we can
communicate with other devices
of victim and the first problem
is solved. We have got a device
to pass the first check. Then we
will use a device to extract
certificates and private keys
from negotiate function. But
first, I’d like to show you a
simple picture about the
architecture which shows how
WHAD gather device info when it
starts and why we need to bind
it -bind it into victim’s
account first. Uh, if you have
many devices in your account,
they will group as a cluster
automatically. When Alexa D
starts, if will obtain
information from Amazon Server
and when WHAD starts, it will
get those information from Alexa
D. And when a device wants to
updates something, the Alexa D
will notify the Amazon Server
and the server will later notify
all other devices in that
cluster to synchronize. Because
the key will change when WHAD
starts to automate the exploit
later, we choose to patch the
WHAD. The WHAD will per-
periodically send an https
request to other devices to know
if they are still online. By
replacing the negotiate function
to the assembly code written by
us, we can dump the certificates
to a local file. It is simple
and violent but anyhow it works
so we don’t need to crack the
complex algorithm. Since
everything is taken place on
attackers device uh to simplify
the environment we have disabled
all protections on the
physically hacked device. The
code is a little complicated so
we are not going to talk about
this now. You may check our
Github page to get the full code
in assembly. So in another word,
we try to dump those things to
three files and use them later
in the attack. Now we have dealt
with the client authenticate
function- authentication
problem. Every time before we
want to perform attack we run
the patch, the WHAD to get the
certs and private key then we
can go to the last step to break
the vulnerable program WHAD on
the victim’s device. Since we
are going to attack it, there
must be vulnerabilities to be
exploited so let’s back to the
binary auditing. So we have
audited almost every binaries
and we found the binary written
by Amazon themselves are secured
by design. But we have also
noticed that Echo is using the
very old version of the 3rd
party libraries. They’re all
nearly four years old. You can
see the pic- uh you can see the
picture, it shows they are using
some code of year 2014. So also
Amazon tries to apply security
patches to them; there are still
many N day and 0 day
vulnerabilities, they’re a gold
mine. Okay, it’s time to “dig
the goat” That is to attack the
web server and get control of
WHAD. And how the feeling for
you to audit some code written
from four years ago, maybe a
little relaxed I guess because
old code with poor test often
leads to serious problems. It
tooks me a week to find the
treasure but when we first find
the exploitable function, nobody
would caught it. Luckily Amazon
updated the binary two months
later and we have found that a
lot of functions are referenced
in this function. The root cause
of the vulnerability is the
library has final- has fail
failed a condition check and so
a lot of vulnerabilities happen
in sequence. Let’s take a look
at the personable code. First
you can see the content lens
this useless black code and
Civetweb tries to get the value
from http header and convert it
into an integer. The ATOI
accepts negative numbers as
input and will return an
assigned integer. What I don’t
quite understand is why they
convert the value from signed
integer to unsigned here. If the
variants is unsigned, the code
if content length is greater
than zero, it’s actually uh
equals to if content length is
not zero so maybe the unsigned
here is a typo. And next uh the
EVE check negative one equals to
the biggest number of unsigned
int so we will also pass the
check and then the number plus
one is again an integer
overflow. The result is zero.
Uh, malloc zero is value because
Echo system is used in dlmalloc
as uh as the malloc algorithm.
As the menu says, even include
zero it can still allocate a
small buffer for you to write
in. Next, in the MG Read code,
there’s a heap buffer overflow,
we’ll talk about it soon. And
there’s a minor one, the post
data bracket content length
assigned to zero will write zero
at negative one position. Leave
the string not zero terminated;
that is a potential information
leak cause this- this function
is used to get the parameter’s
value. So it just like the
chess; a bad move might lead to
a total loose. Okay, let’s back
to the heap buffer overflow. The
code is malloc, dlmalloc zero
will locate 16 bytes, that means
8 bytes metadata plus 8 bytes
buffer where we can write our
data to. In the MG Read, data
read from http request is
written into buffer. The good
thing is this function will fix
the input length so if you are
giving the huge number as we
did, it will fix that length to
real data length remains in the
source buffer. Then it will copy
the data from socket to malloc
buffer. So if we try to post the
screen longer than 8 bytes,
there will be a heap buffer
overflow. So do you remember the
size of malloc is controlled by
user. We can set content length
to control it. If we don’t send
the full http request by
omitting the terminating uh
return carriage, a new line, the
malloc T buffer will remain in
the memory without being free.
When we need to free the buffer,
we could simply send the
remaining written carriage a new
line, then the connection is
closed and the buffer is freed.
By the way, the MG Read will
write anything including zero
charge to buffer so it is very
common for us to exploit. Since
we can control the content of
heap, one thing we wanted most
is uh the vulnerability to
bypass ASLR. That would be good
for us to do the heap buffer
override and heap spray later.
First, let’s talk about the
heaps read, heaps spray part. If
we want to exploit it, we must
try to confirm the area to put
our shellcode in. The anonymous
memory is a good place. Large
heap allocation request caused
the malloc to use mmaped
anonymous memory. It’s
controlled by the mmapad
threshold variance of the
malloc. Although there’s a
hundred of threads running in
the background, there’s only we
want to allocate such huge
memory. Because of the reason of
the mmap the address is started
from a predictable range even
when ASLR is enabled. You may
check the article in our
reference in the last page of
the slides to know the detail.
In our case, we have got an
address that has a good chance
to be located. We have got this
value by just run the program
again and again and it is a exp-
experience value. So after we
have, ahm, we have got a buffer
to put our shellcode, we may
also need an information leak to
do the rest of things. The IOT
device is different from the
desktop application. There’s no
screen for us to know the result
so if the leak the data, it’s
done to use through the network
that would be great. Finally, an
information leak of libcurl in
FTP connection is proved to be
exploitable. By the way, this is
a N day vulnerability so libcurl
don’t give the POC but we try to
reproduce this problem from
libcurl’s patch and test cases.
We see to trigger this
vulnerability we need to reuse a
curl handle. That means we need
to use same handle to connect to
the same FTP server not less
than twice. Okay, let’s back to
the program logic of WHAD. We
have found the control command,
ah, it’s name is downloadAudio.
Normally it would download only
a single file and the curl
handle is closed. But we have
dug into the code deeper and
found that if the extension is
PRS, it will part the PRS file
and use the same curl object to
download every file in it. And
from the second connection, curl
will- will reuse the FTP handle
and trigger the vulnerability.
The picture shows the detail of
the file we use php redirect to
bypass the protocol distribution
of WHAD. Also, if the PRS don’t
loaded successfully, WHAD will
use the cache and will not
accept the same request twice.
That means if curl’s FTP
function fail to leak any bytes,
unless it is restarted, WHAD
will not accept our download
request again and we don’t want
to see this happen so we check
the code branch and found if one
of the URL points to a file that
doesn’t exist there will be no
cache. So we can send the same
request as many times as we want
till it will leak another
address. We use a Python script
to automatically adjust the
payload and finally we have
found uh the size 103 will reuse
a grid area which contains an
address point to a function of
curl. And based on this address
we can calculate the loading
address of curl and furthermore
address of every libraries.
Because the ld dot so will load
dt needed, libraries in sequence
so you can simply calculate the
next or previous libraries
address by plus or minus the
length of an adjacent S.O
library. So we have everything
we need, so how do we execute
the code? The web server is
powered by openSSL an SSL object
is created when a request is
coming so if you happen to read
the source code, you will find
there are many function pointers
in that object. When live
Civeatweb wants to respond
something to the client, SSL
write is called. So all we need
to do is to override the SSL
write pointer and to simplify we
have found a fast way to trigger
SSL write. It will send more
form http version. Well this is
a code in the older version of
live Civeatweb. This code only
works safely in Linux. You may
try whatever happens if you
compiles it in individual
studio. In summary, we have got
six attacking primitives. The
first one is to restart the WHAD
so we can cause, we can cause an
exception in WHAD in case we
can’t leak that address or stuck
for a long time, we may want to
restart the program and give it
another try. Another five
primitives are also listed here
so now all we need to do is to
combine them to get a remote
code execution. So now is time
to PWN. I have to say, it has a
possibility to fail because the
background threads are messing
up the heap and another reason
is in the last step, the memory
condition is a little like to
fall into a risk condition
problem.We have a connection to
override the SSL object of
another connection. If anything
on the thread be written is
called before the overwritten it
is done, it will fail. Or if any
background thread cause
[indiscernible] there’s a fail
too. For a four bytes testing
gadget, we have 40 percent
chance to set the PC value to it
but a real life gadget is six
time longer and the success rate
is down to about 8 percent . But
the good news is uh WHAD will
respond af- after, after it
will- sorry, the good news is
WHAD will be respond after crash
automatically so we can do the
exploit again and again. That -
that is to entrust the hack to
time.The average success time is
about 30 minutes in our
laboratory with about ten tries.
If can control the PC, we need
the last thing to start
eavesdropping, that means a
shellcode. We use function of
set from library plus leaked
library’s load address to get
the function address in memory.
We added two handlers for
SIGSEGV/ SIGABRT with infinite
loop in our shellcode to prevent
any background threats from
crashing the process. We have
also narrowed the length of
metadata of the memory page
where the shellcode are placed
to prevent this page from being
freed. We tried to use the class
audio recorder to record the
voice and send it by TCP to
attacker and the voice was
recorded in PCM format. And the
shellcode could be found in our
Github page too. And finally you
can see we have dealt with every
problems. WHAD is now turning to
a eavesdropping program. It’s,
it’s uh eavesdropping in the
background and sending every
voice data to the attacker. Do
you want to watch the video? Of
course we have prepared a demo
video which shows the whole
story. [Inaudible voice] Yeah,
this is a normal Echo Dot, and
the left part is the attacker
server and the right part is the
exploiting script. When the
exploit success, the victim
connect to us and you can see
log is shown on the left.
>>Hello, do you have any meeting
tomorrow? Yes. Hello, do you
have any meeting tomorrow? Yes.
>>Yes, that’s it. [applause] So
you don’t need to worry about
this. Uh, vulnerabilities we
have found have all reported to
the developers and fixed in the
June 2018. Amazon has already
automatically updated Echo
devices with security patches
and the vulnerabilities we have
mentioned are already all fixed.
And you can find the code and
the contact information on our
Github page and last a little
hack tips from our experience.
The first to hack a LT device
you need to get a firmware first
and it’s- it is good to master
all kinds of soldering and
firmware extraction methods. And
web plus binary vulnerabilities
often equals to remote code
execution. And most important
thing is to be patient; your
hard work will finally pays off.
And that’s all. Thank you for
listening and thanks my partner
too. If you have any [applause]