>> So it’s Erwin and Matt Day,
let’s give them a big DEF CON
welcome. [applause] >> Hey, good
mo- good morning all, uh thanks
for being here early for some of
you who don’t have kids yet. Um,
so just a quick introduction.
So, I’m Erwin, uh that’s Mattijs
or Matt if you may want to call
him. Uh we both work at uh Nixu.
Uh which is a Finnish company
but we actually work for the
Dutch uh branch in fo this so
we’re based in Amsterdam. As you
can see it took us quite some,
some time to get here. Um, so.
What is it that we’re gonna talk
about. Well we’re gonna talk
about what is industrial
SensorNet works. Um but let’s
get to look back at like what
has been done before. Um, as you
can see, um, the earliest
research was ready don’t in
2009. More academic research
about potential attacks and um,
the attacks were, were, were
described but not demonstrated.
There was no information how you
could actually uh recreate the
attacks yourself. And um there,
there’s and that’s, th- that’s,
sort of continues because then
in, in 2015 was actually a PHD
student in the Netherlands who
did also similar research and
actually tried to build i- uh, a
tool to, to interact with these
networks and um, h- he didn’t
really succeed. So w- he was
using XDR based systems
initially, in the end he, he
didn’t really succeed in, in
actually uh capturing, trap-
trapping or modifying the
traffic. So, then we came along
and we did a presentation at S4.
Um, and then we already opted
the ID to actually create a
toolkit to be able to um
actually uh capture traffic,
inject traffic, etcetera. Um,
that, that’s a couple of years
ago but unfortunately, we never
got around to actually doing it
because we, we soon l- left the
company we- we were working at,
at the time. Um and in, in the
meantime we had, we had Blake
Johnson again, um th- using SDR
based approach uh to, to
interact with this network. But
again, no codes were released,
no tools nothing, so. I mean
these networks are around for
quite a while but still there
are no tools and, and we
strongly believe in, uh, in
Wright’s principle which is
written down there. Uh, the guy
Joshua Write uh who actually, uh
said that well if there are no
tools uh security will not
improve. So, we, we were
actually attending DEF CON uh
last year as, as just um, not a
speaker but as a regular
visitor. And we’re like, well
let’s build those tools because
it’s still missing. Um, and just
to give you and idea. Um, w-
what’s in, what industrial
revolution is for this type of
systems. So first, uh we’re
talking about industrial control
systems here. So first we had,
uh the Air Pressure systems, in,
in 1940’s. Uh, 1950’s they start
using analog current loops. Um
in the meantime I’m really
familiar with that part because
it actually allowed me to
destroy some of th, uh the
component we were testing. Um,
but later on they actually
started creating digital
protocols. So on top of the
current loop, they, they
implemented the HART protocol
which you may be familiar with,
or not. An, and, and in late
2000,’s they thought well let’s
do it wireless and they created
2 uh standards, WirelessHART and
ISA100, 11a. Formerly named SI
7100. So is anybody familiar
with this protocols. Have you
ever heard about it? No. Uh, not
that many okay well it’s, for
most people it’s very niches but
uh still, it’s its interesting
and if you’re wondering where,
where this systems being used.
Uh for instance oil and, and gas
fields, uh, you you can see
those transmitters. So you see
the blue ones, they’re actually
field devices. So these are
transmitters and, and they’re
actually measuring things like
uh pressure or temperature and
then transmit wirelessly to uh
the central system but we get to
that. Um, also an industrial uh
control loop process control lop
I think it’s good to, to sort of
explain how that works. So
basically, you have a flow
transmitter all the way on the
right and uh there’s an a- a
signal being sent to the central
controller and that for instance
indicates the flow rate. Uh
that’s called the process value,
and that process values is
actually uh checked against um
set points. And, and if it’s
within r- ranged nothing happens
but if, if something needs to
happen there’s actually control
outputs. So that’s the bottom
line and then a valve is
actually changed i- in uh from,
from open to closed to, to
adjust the flow and so this is
the typical uh process loop. And
what you see is that typically
up until now um, m- mainly the
mastering part is done wireless.
Either with WirelessHART or ISA
100. Um so if you at that a bit
more at, at WirelessHART it’s
actually um the same HART
protocol the application layer
but they, they uh created a
wireless uh, wireless deck for
it. So, it’s, it’s compatible
with, with the HART devices out
there. Um, it does use
encryption so it’s not the most
uh insecure, uh control uh
protocol. Um, but it’s, it’s
metric encryption and, and we
get to that in, in the uh later
slides a bit more. Um, it’s
based on, on, on wireless
technology from uh, from Dust
Networks because they are also
the ones creating the, the
radios. So, radio system on the
chip. Um, and, and you see
there, there’s, there’s a couple
of vendors who actually build
equipment uh for, for
WirelessHART. So, ISA 100, th-
there’s fewer companies actually
uh supporting it, uh the main
driver is YOKOGAWA and also
Honeywell. Um and there’s
actually uh, like a whole bunch
of standards, it’s, it’s its’
based on. So, there’s the
6LoWPAN there’s IBv6,
surprisingly. And UDP on, on top
of that. And um, it’s it allows
you to tunnel under uh other
protocols. So, it’s not like, uh
they, they took an existing
protocol with w- has with
WirelessHART and, and built
wireless tech for it. But you’re
able to, to tunnel and so it’s
it’s it’s more uh, vendor
neutral. And th-, th- the mainly
developed by a company it’s
called Nivis. Um, who, who
created the system on uh, on uh,
on the chip. Un initially. But
now they’re more up chips out
there from, from different
vendors. So, what does typical
topology look like? Um, well
these are mesh networks so there
is not well there is a central
system that orchestrates the
mesh. Um that’s the gateway,
network manager, security
manager. Typically, that’s just
1 box, 1 device as you can see
on the right. Um, but there is,
there, there’s still devices out
there and there’s, there’s each
a couple of um, different ones.
You can see in the picture. So,
you have the field devices,
devices that actually measures
stuff. Um that, that have, have
wireless transmitters themselves
or you have the situation where
for instance where you have a
HART. Uh, a HART enabled
transmitter and then you can add
an adapter, and, and they can
communicate. But since it’s a, a
w- a w- wireless and mesh
network. Also, the field devices
can route traffic for all the
devices. So it’s not point to
point, uh, only. Um, and you
have on the, the right-hand side
you have the wireless hard
handheld and that’s being used
to actually configure uh the
devices. So, before they can
join the network you have to
configure them and then uh,
they, they will join and the
network. So, if you look at the
protocol stacks um, y- you can
see that, that on, on um the
HART side there, there’s
actually on, on, on the
left-hand side you can actually
um, see the, the, th- the
traditional HART and, and um, on
the right hand side you see th-
the WirelessHART. So, it’s space
related to 15 dot 4. Um, but
they uh they use only very thin
layer of, of that protocol. But
everything that build on top is
specifically wire- WirelessHART
and, and one of the things uh to
l- to play attention to, is, is
the channel hopping because, we
get back to that later, that’s
something that was challenging
to, to show. Um, and, also on,
on the ISA, on the other side we
see a similar thing so, it's
again a, a thin, uh 802 dot 15
dot 4 layer and then you see the
whole protocol stack uh, on top
with a UDP etcetera, etcetera.
And although it’s not listed in,
in this um, in this overview
they also do channel hopping uh
as well. So, to, to summarize to
the similarities because we have
2 wireless protocols out there
which sh- somewhat similar and,
and we thought, well can we
build 2 kilt to actually uh
assess both of those, uh of
those systems? So they both have
the, the shared 802 15 dot 4
layer although they uh both have
a different version subversion.
Uh and they both work with 2
dot, 2 dot 4 uh gigahertz. Um,
and they’re both do time slotted
channel hopping and, and the
reason they do that is so the
hop from channel all the time.
And the reason they do that is
actually uh to minimize
interference because you, I mean
these systems are being used in,
in, in uh in plans in industrial
sites. There’s a lot of
interference from other systems
that are, that are out there.
And also, to uh, to mitigate
multipath fadings. That means
that if um, a signal gets
reflected back you might cancel
out the signal, and because you
hop the channels you actually
prevent that. Uh because there
is a lot of metal around a
large, uh large, uh storage um
containers etcetera. So there’s
a lot of reflections. So, they
both have a central network
security manager. Uh to
orchestrate the communication
between the nodes. It doesn’t’
meant that the nodes can’t also
route the traffic for other
nodes but there’s a central
point that controls the network.
Um, so we though well we can
probably build a sniffer for,
for both protocols. Um, so we,
we um, um if we look a bit more,
at, at, at the, the things that
share is that they actually use
th- th- this exact same E, uh
AES CCM star uh encryption. Um,
so at the network layer they use
it for integrity only so IDA 215
dot 4 is only integrity. But at
the transfer layer th- th- they
apply encryption and uh, on both
systems have both actually a
join process where, y- they
actually uh shared an,
encryption key. Uh and that’s a
handshake with the network
manager so that’s a central
component. And um, for
WirelessHART it’s, it’s, it’s
meant only uh shared secrets so
th- that’s really an interesting
thing. Yeah, symmetric
encryption. So how do you get
the key across and, and, and
where do you store it? Uh and,
and ISA100 supports certificates
though we haven’t seen it being
used. Um, so, so they th- ISA100
supports both. Uh shared secrets
and certificates. There’s a lot
of different keys. Um, so if we
started at the left uh, ISA100
um, th- the top 3 keys are
actually new, they’re during
provisioning phase. Uh so you
have the global key, the K_open,
K_global. Um, and, and during
the provisioning phase the
master key is being um, is being
shared and, and from that master
key they device 2 keys the D-key
and the T-key. Um, it’s also not
important that you remember all
the different keys it’s just to
show there’s a lot of different
keys out there. Uh and the same
is true for WirelessHART the
well-known key was used at the
network layer that’s actually
not an encryption key but an
authentication key. Because they
don’t do encryption in network
layer. Uh, and, and there’s a
network key then the join key uh
for the join, which is being
shared during the join process
and, and derived from there is 2
session keys. So both Broadcast
and Unicast. So, first question
of course is how do you get the
key material? Um, well one of
the things you can do is
actually read documentation
because there’s a lot of default
keys out there and uh I must
admit that since we’ve done the
research 2 years ago, a lot of
the documentation is not
publicly available anymore
before we, back then already
published some of the keys that
are, are uh default keys and,
and seems that a lot to the
documents have, have vanished.
So not all the keys we list here
you can still publicly find, but
uh we’re pretty sure uh that we
initially uh, found them
somewhere. Um, and uh ISA100
specifically also has uh, OTA
provisioning of the devices so
that’s also a weak part we could
sniff, uh could sniff the
transaction uh, o- or the
handshake. Uh but they need to
be able to sniff of course. And
previous research we’ve done, we
actually took apart transmitters
and looked at if we could u- um,
interface directly with th-,
with the radio spark because
actually there’s, there’s
multiple components and, and
there’s a radio spark on, on
there and uh it turned out that
they actually JTAG SPI enabled.
At least for, for, for
WirelessHART. Because back then
we only looked at WirelessHART.
And, uh we showed that you could
actually sort of location where
th- where the encryption key is,
and, and worse case you can
always dump the complete
firmware and load it onto
another similar device and then
you can also join the network.
So, there’s a couple of ways to
actually obtain those keys. Um,
so if you, if you are a plant
manager and you’re getting rid
of old equipment also pay
attention to the last one.
Because you might not erase
those keys and ends up on eBay
somebody might buy it. So, um
there’s a couple of default keys
for WirelessHART. We haven’t
located any default keys for
ISA100 yet. So that’s why I’m
only listening WirelessHART
keys. Uh, the first one you see
a lot. And that actually has to
do with, with Dust Network who
created the SOCs, and that’s why
they used us. Dust Network work
at uh in a lot of locations. Um,
so it’s, it’s uh you can see
it’s a 16 bytes hex decimal,
hexadecimal key so it’s quite
long. Um, but you can see that
it, they use a couple of values
uh out there. And, and the third
one, the Emerson one is also
interesting because it’s taking
from a Emerson WirelessHART
gateway and if you do a factory
reset it actually sets the key
like this. So you see a lot of
zeros. So the key space is
really, really small. So, if you
ever have uh, reset those
devices and use the default key
you might be able to easily
reverse it. Um, and, and
sometimes you can see it’s a lot
the name of the vendor. So the
last one is actually exactly
Endress and Hauser. Uh but and
X. So if we um, look at the
sniffer hardware uh we first
looked what’s out there. Um,
because we, we want to build
something new. Uh and, and
during previous research we used
the BeamLogic. We basically is,
is just the sniffer but it, it,
it uh sniffs now 16 channels
simultaneously. Um, so it has no
injection support and very basic
Wireshark dissector, and it’s
quite expensive. It’s the, the
box on the, on the right. Um, so
yeah, it’s expensive and also
quite limited what you can do
with it. Uh initially we thought
about using the a- Atmel RZ, RZ
Raven uh, stick. Because also
the regular transmitter she
used, uh, used an APR uh based
system uh but already reached
end of life and it’s very hard
now with to find admins to those
somewhere. Um, so then we looked
for other options and we went
onto the BeeKit from NXP um, and
by default that already allows
you to sniff on 1 channel. Um,
but it’s standard firmware
although the standard firmware’s
not open source but that also
reached end of life. So we
continued our search for another
1. Another stick from NXP. So,
this one is still supported as a
free IDE and uh, it allows you
to sniff on single channel. It’s
quite powerful. Um and, and we
need that for the channel
opening. Um, Mattijs will
explain later. And um, you can
actually modify the this USB a
bit to, to put an external
antenna on it. It’s extremely
small so I already ruined the
device trying to do it. But it
is possible and you could cause
wardriving. Yeah there’s,
there’s documentation out there,
and examples. But only with a
few important omissions here and
there. So this one show you the
default, uh application. That,
that’s already provided by them.
Uh I hope you can see it. Uh so
basically this is the
application just select a
channel so it’s sniffing IDA 215
dot 4. Uh you can start
Wireshark and you can at least
see packets. See y- you can see
the packets but if you click on
actually uh, eh, on, on, on,
o-on the bottom side you can see
that it’s just data so it
doesn’t have a dissector for
this protocol. But the basis
there, we can already sniff
packets on one channel so that’s
a start. So then we figured out,
okay how does this actually
work? Uh because there is, there
is a whole SDK around it. Um,
but actually it’s, it’s, it’s
relatively simple because the
hardware is detected as virtual
COM port. Uh both on Windows and
Linux so that’s a really plus.
Um but they implemented their
own protocol which is called
FSCI and is developed by NXP and
is a communication protocol
over, over serial. Uh and
there’s a post SDK available
with Python bindings. Uh but we
thought, well we don’t want to
ship a tool with h- host DSK
around it. We might run into
legal issues so can we dir-
communicate directly? And um, as
it turns out we, we can actually
uh do that. Um so we, we created
th- the driver for, for
KillerBee. And Killer Bee
indirectly drives this and
drives the stick now so we don’t
need a full SDK anymore. Um, so
this is what it looks like uh,
schematically so the, K, KW4, 4,
1 zed is actually uh the import
text. Uh there’s a second one on
there, uh, where you can
actually load, uh, uh a
different bootloaders and that
way you can also uh, provision,
n- new um, new firmware on the
divide through USB’s so you
actually have the MCU Express
Hub, it’s called? >>[inaudible
comment] >> MCU Express or IDE
and actually allows you to
develop sort of firmware for
this device. So, up to you.
>>Thank you Erwin. So, we wanted
to about, to build uh something
more powerful than was uh, out
there. So, we thought we, we
found our hardware platform that
we could s- develop on. Uh so we
start building the toolset. And
the first thing we uh, wanted to
e- accomplish is uh, snip the
packets ourselves. And uh, n-
um, not rely on, on uh the SDK
that came along with the, the
hardware. Um, so actually we
build a driver for the KillerBee
framework. Um, KillerBee because
um, it’s just th- the same uh RF
layer 8 oh, 8 oh 250 dot 4 uh
protocol. So that seems uh quite
a good match. And uh we also
developed u-um, uh extensions
Scapy so uh we were also being
able to uh, to inject uh packets
rather than just listening in on
the traffic. Um, and to bring uh
a packetsnip to the masses, ya
know we also decided to, to
build uh Wireshark dissectors
for protocols, WirelessHART and
ISI100. So, we will show you, a
short demo. This in action. So,
you can see we use, uh the CB
Wireshark uh utility that comes
with uh, b- with KillerBee. And
here you see we are picking up
traffic. In this case ISA100s,
you see also the Wireshark
dissector in action. On the
left, the screen you see we uh
decode the packets. So, the next
challenge was uh, um, the
channel hopping problem. So like
here when, so um, the protocol
uses a fast based channel
hopping uh algorithm. And when
s-, e- started developing uh and
studying this toolkit we thought
well okay. Uh there’s a new
exchanging way 250 dot 4 if we
rem- remember cor- uh, correctly
that’s uh the, de-amendments
which also uses uh, uh, time
slotted hopping mechanism. So we
thought, well maybe we could use
that because that parameter was
already supported by, uh by the
uh SDK. Uh but it turned out uh,
that, uh that wasn’t useable a-
at all. So, ha, uh we r- really
got to get our hands dirty and
uh, w- write ya kn- the pretty
uh extensions to the firmware
itself. So, none of us have any,
had development background, it’s
a, it turns out to be quite a
challenge. So, if I mean um,
fast paced channel hopping. Uh
that means that uh, the
intervals you see here on th-,
on, on this slide are at alt 10
milliseconds. So, every 10
milliseconds uh you c- uh the
frequency change. So, in order
to keep up y- you have to um,
think through how you’re going
to accomplish that. Um, also
that here we need to rely on the
firmware itself from the
hardware. Because uh, yes you
can c- change channels from the
host system but as soon as you
send an FSCI command to the USB
device uh-, the timing, uh the
time slot already has lapsed so
that doesn’t work in practice.
So, you really need to implement
this in firmware. So, uh, ha.
That uh, w- we needed to deep
dive into uh, embedded
developments. Which was uh, new
for us. Um yeah there are a
couple of approaches you can
take so um, for this type of uh,
devices you can rely on a
real-time operating system. Um,
there are a, uh, quite a few
around. Uh one of them is
FreeRTOS for instance. Uh but
there, this co- it is pretty um,
th- this uh, i- i- it’s pretty
um, um, complex. In the sense
that um, eh- i-i-it’s not a
full-fledged operating system
but it had, has task scheduler
that will uh, preempt so that
means that it will enter up your
code right in the middle of y-
of your function and you can get
all kinds of uh, of challenges.
Like raise conditions, you have
to deal with so you need to mess
around with uh semi-force and
other synchronization
mechanisms. Um, the other
approach is um, th- use a bare
method task scheduler. Uh,
they’re, uh, th-that, that will
not uh interrupt right in-into
your code section. Uh but as
soon as uh, as y- d- the task
scheduler is running through
code, you’re responsible for
releasing resources. So, part
that means that in practice you
have to uh, to make sure that
your code doesn’t uh, run longer
for longer than 2 milliseconds
otherwise you’ll start uh, you
will stop other tasks and that
means that for instance there’s
separate tasks for collecting
the packets, uh, yeah you can
m-make sure that uh you change
channels but uh if you don’t
pick up th-the packets you
don’t’ have anything at all. So
a-as I said, yeah th-th it
requires uh, uh quite some
discipline and uh, in
programming. Um, well th- that
side is that you c- can achieve
fast execution because you don’t
have the overhead of real time
operating system. So, this is
uh, what uh, what it looks like.
These are the modules in the
firmware. A part is uh offered
by the framework itself so you
have the memory management uh,
uh task that is taking care of
uh allocating the heap stuff.
You have the MAC/PHY layer uh
that’s uh taking care of picking
up the packets from the radio.
And um, uh the Serial Manager
obviously because these packets
need to go to their hosts. Uh
you have a bunch of timers which
can program and uh will wait
your task so you can do actually
something useful with these
packets. And of course, uh,
everybody needs blinking lights.
So, uh on the right side you see
actually what we uh needed to
do. Um, the MAC 5 layer was only
uh partially useful. Um we
needed s- to implement the
channel hopper and yeah that th-
that was called the MAC
extension layer, cause we need
to e- obviously extend these
capabilities. Uh, on top of that
uh we actually get to the
industry protocols. ISU 100 and
WirelessHART and we also needed
to parse information out of
these packets. Uh, on that l- uh
layer because we uh needed the
information in order to
calculate when uh, their uh
their particular time slot
occurs what you're interested
in. So, how to do this. Um, 10
milliseconds um, if you program
a timer uh, to, to, to wake up
your task e- every 10
milliseconds you find out that
you’re always too late because
you’re never guaranteed to get
the wakeup call within every 10
milliseconds. It’s either 10, 10
milliseconds or 11 or 12. And
when you start uh, tuning into
the channel you’re too late. So,
what we did is um, we parsed uh,
the packets that came along too,
in the advertisements of both uh
w-wireless protocols. Y- you get
information uh, where the slots
of interest are. For example,
the join slots, uh these are uh,
timed slots where um, a few
devices actually can tune in,
to, to start a handshake of,
for, um uh g-getting onto the
network. Those are of particular
interest. Also from a, attack
perspective. So, yeah what we
started to do is uh, well tune
in advance. So, if our um, uh,
tuning code gets called uh, we
measure okay the, th- the next
uh slot of interest is uh, 3
time slots away. Okay we’ll tune
in right now and uh well the,
the other task will take care of
picking up the packets there. So
that’s gives us some more room.
Like for instance to uh, e-
around 40 milliseconds uh, r-
rather than 10 milliseconds. So
that uh turned out to w- uh work
pretty well. And we’ll show you
how we actually achieved channel
hopping. You can see Z, uh ZB
Wireshark. W- we had to hack in
a non-existent channel. See,
channel zero means that uh we
ex-fade uh channel hopping in
the firmware. And as you can see
we get quite some more traffic
here than in the first case. Why
we were only tuned in to 1
particular channel. And I don’t
know it’s readable but here you
can see that on the left part
that we actually hopped to
different channels. So, what can
you do if you can’t tune on uh
th-this uh intervals of
interest, these time slots. Well
these are a few um attacks that
have been theorized and now we
can execute uh, in practice. Um,
w- one is to just jam the signal
on um, uh b-by sending garbage
uh to uh on a p- particular
channel. And uh you can block
for example advertisements and
if you do this successfully no
new devices can join the
network. Uh because they don’t,
uh they, they are not able to
synchronize with the network. Or
even existing uh field devices
will uh lose at some point the
synchronization with the
network. So in practice that
means that uh the few devices uh
are enabled to send a process
failures and you h- depending on
uh, on what control system you
have uh, you can narrate havoc.
Um, of course being able to
inject traffic you can also
transmit fake advertisements so
you can entice field devices to
join your network rather than
the existing uh network. And, h-
yeah, we’ll give a short
demonstration of how you can
jam. No, yeah. Okay. So, here
is, here you see the victim. Was
happily receiving
advertisements. Now we transmit
the attacker which we start our
tool to jam the signal. We found
the network and on the sides you
see a few packets coming in and
next, it comes to a house.
Silence. So, there’s all, nice
that we can do things without
uh, uh actually being on the
network. But suppose you have
some uh, gather some keys or you
found these in a manual, so you
do it force these. Well you can
do all other nasty stuff. Um,
they way this works is that, the
uh, the encryption actually is
derived from a nonce that has
for last part uh, a predictable
values. So, there is uh, a, in
the advertisement data there is
a counter that you need. And
that can be snipped from the
network w-without it being
authenticated. Um, but even if
you don’t know uh how to, excuse
me, um you can mess with uh this
nonce value because there is uh
replay. Thank you. There is a
replay protection uh in place,
uh that’s supposed to uh, to
protect against obviously
replaying a fake values. Uh but
the thing is, um, if you mess
with uh, th- the th-the, the
nonce and you guess a val- a
valid uh nonce and it will be
picked up uh b-by uh the device,
it is larger. Eh, say it’s much
larg- larger than, uh the time
stamp that is uh g- currently in
the network. It will, you reject
all packets from valid devices.
So you can really bring down
ent- entire sensor networks this
way. Of course if you also have
access to other key material.
For example when capturing a
join process and you have access
to the session keys you are free
to uh to mimic a real field
device and you can really mess
with process failures. And
that’s just a w-where it’s
getting really scary. So, um to
summarize. What did we learn
along uh the road. This uh,
these net- these sensor
protocols are highly unexplored
area. And uh as we uh said in
the introduction uh we suspect
that this mainly due to the fact
that no uh, r-real good, real
good tools exist. So, yeah we
picked up uh the task and hope
that we’ll uh w-we can promote
other researches to uh, t-to to
explore this in- very
interesting area. So, uh yeah we
intend to, to uh to release uh
th-the toolset we, we created.
And uh, yeah another thing we
want to uh, uh to give uh to the
[indiscernible] us, who w-we who
deploy these systems. Um, we see
a change that um that people are
getting very confident with this
technology because it’s around
for 10 years. And, it has never
been hacked. So, must be secure
right? So you see a trend that
uh these protocols are not only
being used for monitoring
systems but also for
con-control. Uh, yeah I would
like to, to, eh, uh probably
that’s not a really good idea.
So, they might want to
reconsider that. Alright, we
have uh some time for questions,
5 minutes I see. So uh, um, this
is e- these are the future
research area of these other
future uh topics we want to uh,
expand upon. So we’ll um support
more attacks that have been
theorized so far but now tooling
exists. Uh, we want to create uh
support for wardriving initial
networks. Uh when we do it the
hard way we were happy to see
that it had the, an uh
ex-external antenna connector
but once it arrived to do us not
on the boards so we were kind of
disappointed. And of course with
the capability of uh actually
interacting with this network
and the capability of injecting
packets. Um, yeah there, we are
free to actually fuzz these
protocols from the radio side of
uh, of these systems. Okay,
thank you for your attention and
we can take some questions now.
[applause]