>> Let’s give Zenofex a round of
applause. [Applause] Alright, Hi
everyone, uh I guess we’re gonna
get started a 2 minutes early
which is great because I packed
in a lot of content into this
period. So, um my talk is
dissecting the Teddy Ruxpin
reverse engineering smart bear.
It’s essentially my experience
taking my child’s toy and trying
to see if it was going to cause
any security nightmares for me.
Um, but uh, we’ll get into some
fun things here on this
presentation. So, a little bit
about me, first of all, my
Twitter handle is at Zenofex, I
go by Zenofex. I’m a security
researcher at Cylance. Um, I’m a
founding member of the hardware
hacking group called the
Exploitee.rs uh, and uh, I’m a
contributing member to a local
community that we have called
Austin Hackers. A little bit
about Exploitee.rs, um, we have
roughly 10 members give or take
a few that, uh, don’t officially
associate with us but they are
pretty much part of the group.
Um, we have Agent HH, CJ, Cody,
Gynophage, Maximus, MBM, Saurik,
Tdweng and, uh, 0x00string or
null string, and of course, me.
So, our general goal is to just
hack things; anything, anywhere.
We originally started hacking
Google TVs and then Google
killed off the Google TVs so
then we just started hacking
anything we could get our hands
on. Um, we have a pretty decent
community and we’re all very
helpful so, uh, check out our
Exploitee.rs site. We have like
60 plus embedded devices that
have roots and other hacks. Um,
we also have an IRC network that
I’ll talk about at the end. So,
a little disclaimer first of
all, um, the data within this
presentation was all stuff that
I reverse engineered. I didn’t
have official documentation or
anything else, um, so a lot of
my attempts were just
essentially trial and error and
reversing what I could, when I
could. Um, I literally have been
working on this for a very long
time. Um, and uh, I, you’ll see
why, it’s essentially a RTOS
environment, um, which can be a
little bit more difficult
because after root you wanna
interface with the peripherals.
So, terminology. Um, you
teddyophyles will uh, [laughter]
will uh, will not or will
already know this but an iliop
is a brown bear like creature
with a kind disposition. You
might think Teddy Ruxpin is a
bear but he’s actually an iliop.
So, the OG iliop. This was the
1980’s, uh, Teddy Ruxpin, I
think a lot of us are familiar
with. Um, it used cassette tapes
on, uh, on its back that you
replaced and you had physical
books that read along with the
cassette tapes. His mouth moved
and his eyed opened and closed
but it was a physical movement
not an LCD screen like the
newest revision. So the new
iliop, um, the new iliop is this
guy. Essentially, oops, uh,
essentially he has animated
eyes, a moving mouth, speaker, a
Bluetooth low energy, a USB mass
storage that is, uh, used via an
internal microSD card, and a
companion mobile app. Getting
inside Teddy. So, I’m about to
show you all what, [laughter]
what this looks like, it’s
terrifying [laughter]. Um, so,
uh, a little, [laughter] so a
little about Teddy, uh, this
particular revision comes with
a, uh, mask that you put on him
so he doesn’t scare your kids
when he’s off [laughter]. It’s
needed too because, like I said,
it’s crazy, uh, but let’s take
his jacket off and uh, get him
out of here. This is essentially
Teddy Ruxpin. This is Teddy’s
skin [laughter]. So, it’s, it’s
pretty enjoyable and here’s
Teddy on. >> Hi, my name is
Teddy Ruxpin. Can you and I be
friends? [laughter] >> No. No. I
actually tried to wear his skin
it doesn’t fit on my face.
[laughter] Um, so, inside of
Teddy we have a logic board and
this is the top of the logic
board. It’s actually stored
right in his eye area here. Um,
there’s this chip called the
Sonix, uh it’s the Sonix MCU I
don’t remember what the, uh,
physical or the, uh actual name
of it was but, uh, there’s a
speaker driver, the Bluetooth
low energy, there’s an SPI flash
and then there’s this, uh, uh,
SD card slot that actually ends
up holding, um, the story books
that are, uh, stored on Teddy
Ruxpin. Um, this is the logic
board’s bottom. You can see that
there are 2 128 by 128 LCDs that
are used for each individual
eye. Um, and then on that
previous picture we’ll go 2
slides back. You can see that
there’s, uh, on the, I guess
right side there is a module
that says Teddy firmware 1 point
1. That module is an MYN822BLE
module which is essentially just
a module for the, uh, Nordic
nRF51822 chip. Um, so here is
the diagram for interfacing with
its SWD port and also all the
other different GPIO pins that
are used uh within Teddy. They
only have, um, roughly 11 GPIO
pins in use of the, uh, 22 or so
that are available. Um, or, the
26 that are available. Uh, and
then of course they have SWDIO
and SW clock hooked up, uh,
which is the d-bug pin out for
software debugging, uh, Cordex
M0 chips. So, with that
particular pin out we were able
to dump, uh, the firmware for
Teddy, um, and also the ram. Um,
you can dump it with OpenOCD but
I had a SEGGER J-Link based on
doing some badge development for
the whole badge life project
and, uh, I just used that with
NRFJProg to dump the firmware
and ram. Um, like I said, you
can use OpenOCD and if you pay
me I can get you a config to
make that work. Um, so, this
particular Teddy, instead of
having physical books he uses a
mobile app. And so, you can see
in the mobile app picture they
have a little cartoon picture of
Teddy and his best friend
Grubby. Um, so uh, the mobile
app works essentially by using a
BLE to communicate, um, when
each page is turned and when the
next story should be ready. So I
took that and I threw it, I took
the APK and I threw it in a JADX
GUI and, uh, it was really
nothing more than a wrapper for
a bunch of Adobe AIR content.
Um, so, within the, uh, APK was
a SWF file, um, and I took that
SWF file and then I threw into
JPEXS. Um, essentially this is a
flash decompiler, um, and all
the BLE stuff was within this
SWF. So, uh, if you are poking
at your own Teddy, um,
[laughter] you can uh, you’re
better off not even looking at
the APK, just unzip it, grab the
SWF and throw it into a, um,
JPEXS. So, I went ahead and I
listed all the BLE info. The
receive and transmit UUID
characteristics and, uh, all the
commands to jump between
storybooks, um, and uh, to
choose individual storybooks. I
didn’t – I don’t plan on reading
you all that. You can look and
uh, reference the slides. Uh, at
the bottom of the presentation,
I didn’t mention this at the
beginning, but at the bottom of
the presentation is, uh, a web
address for our website. If you
go to that website here after
the talk I’ll have slides and
some of my research content but,
uh, I’ve been having trouble
updating it, uh, and I really
don’t want to on the hotel
Wi-Fi. So, uh, just check it
when you get home. So, you take
the firmware, uh, that you
dumped with SWD and you can
throw it into IDA and, uh, it
shows up as just binary data but
then if you, uh, choose ARMv7,
um, LE, and enter in these
settings you can actually go and
look at, uh, the disassembly and
try to reverse some of it
yourself. But, uh, realistically
most of my stuff was done
through visual analysis of the
storybook files and a ton of
trial and error. So, I-I got it
in IDA, a little too late for me
to spend too much time in
that-in this particular section.
So, uh, the Teddy Ruxpin book –
so, um, I showed you all Teddy’s
face and body. Um, on the back
there’s a microSD pin-pin out or
header and you can essentially
connect into that and it pops up
with mass storage device and it
has all the books on it which
are and intro file, an idle file
and then the 10 storybooks that,
uh, they provide. The – I’m
thinking the idea was that they
would release books at a later
point for purchase and you would
just copy them over to the bear
because they don’t provide
functionality to transfer it
over, um, through BLE. So,
within the storybooks, um, the
files that are the container
format, um, for the storybooks
are these SNX ROM files. Um,
since I don’t have the
documentation they could be
called something else but, um,
the-the magic string at the top
of each file is SNX ROM, um, in
white character so each one is
individually null terminated.
Um, the Target exclusive
contains 2 extra stories but it
was always a little more
expensive than I wanted to pay
and uh, I bought 6 of these, uh,
[laughter] so, I-I have way too
many Teddy’s. Um, so the SNX ROM
files. I had mentioned that they
start with a magic string at the
top but then there is also the
header format. The header format
starts with the record stop and
record end. Um, and then the
table itself ends with FFFF. The
data after you use that to
extract the files within, you
end with, uh, the raw image data
first and then the audio files.
The audio files always start
with AU and the raw image files
are all the rest of them. If you
take the image files and you
throw them into GIMP-GIMP has a
feature that you can import raw
data and then you can kind of
play with the settings to see
what the data is, um, which is
on the left. You see the picture
there. Um, you can see that
there RGB656 and then they are
128 by 128, um, sizing. Uh,
and-yeah. So, then the audio
files. This is where things get
a little bit crazier and this
where I spent a ton of my time.
Um, it’s a proprietary file
format used by Sonix, um, and it
actually uses, uh, it uses this
thing called a mark table to
store, um, the triggers for the
data that shows on the eyes, and
then also for, um, the, uh,
mouth movement. Essentially, and
I’ll get on that on the next
slide, but, uh, we’ll get there
now. Uh, so, the header
structure for this format, um,
is essentially the AU string, 2
bytes, uh, a unknown constant
value since I was using a lot of
trial and error and I didn’t
have the documentation or
anything for this format, um,
it, uh – I – there was a bunch
of values that didn’t seem to
impact my tests and I couldn’t
figure out what they were
actually used for. So, the
unknown constant value is the 2
bytes. That seems like – it’s on
almost like every single file
and never changes. Um, there’s –
then the sample right, which is
2 bytes, the channel, which is
always 1, um but is also 2
bytes. Another unknown value,
another unknown value, and then
some, uh, then, uh a 0 or 1 to
dictate if there is a mark
table, a silence table, another
unknown value, and then the mark
table data, sounds table data
and audio data. The actual data
structure – when I say audio
data, mark table data a silence
table data, um, is the mark
table is defined by, uh, 2 to 4
bytes to signify the position, 2
bytes to signify the value of
the data at that position and
then, um, that particular table
ends with OXFFF. It also, if
the, uh, position value is over
8000, uh, hex, um, it takes that
and uses the next 2 bytes, adds
them together and uses that as
the position value. Um, the
silence table, uh, it was OX0 on
every single Teddy Ruxpin file
that I checked and so it may -
uh, I - I know - I don’t know
too much about that particular
table, um, outside of just what
I’ve done for some internet
sleuth thing which is, uh - uh,
which I’ll talk about soon. And
then the audio data, which is 16
bits signed little Indian. The
mark table, so, when - when
you’re looking at the mark
table, how this thing actually
works is, uh, the mark table has
the position value, uh, the
position value and then the
actual value. If the value is a
0 the mouth is closed. If the
value’s 1 the mouth is half
open. The value’s 2 the mouth is
full open. Now, anything after
that that you specify will sit -
will correlate to, uh, image
frames that are within the
storybooks. So, um, if you want
to make, let’s say, a special
logo pop up or his eyes blink or
something you would essentially,
uh, put the value - put the
value of, uh, that image data
and then you would set up
multiples to essentially make it
a moving image or whatever
you’re trying to do. Um, but,
everything you do, let’s say,
your image file is, um, you
know, number 1, well, you’re
still going to have to be offset
by the mouth open, mouth closed,
um, and full mouth open, um,
values. So, whatever it is you
have to offset it by 3. Um, so
then let’s look at the silence
table. So I talked about it a
little earlier but I didn’t
actually mention what it’s for.
The only thing this is here for
is compression. Um, they don’t
use it. I guess the stories
weren’t big enough or it wasn’t
needed but, um, it essentially
just references silent data and
marks the position in the table
and, um, the only reason I knew
that is because of just, random
internet searches on the
subject. Uh, unfortunately Teddy
doesn’t use it. I just know that
the files themselves have that
field, um, and in my tests the
completely broke anytime I tried
to enable it. So, um, then we go
to the audio data. Uh, it is 16
bit little Indian stored, uh,
signed, uh, data that’s stored
after the mark table and silence
detection table. It only
supports 16 kilohertz, uh,
sample rates and then it
supports bit rates from 16, 20,
24, 28 and 32 kilobits per
second. So, what I’ve done for
people who want to hack their
own Teddy Ruxpin is I created
this Teddy Rux Pwn, and, uh,
[laughter] essentially there’s -
there’s no 0-day in this
presentation it’s simply just
reverse engineering stuff. So,
um, I threw together, uh, some
Python code that essentially
takes an input file, it breaks
it down into a folder structure
that contains an eye folder, uh,
an audio folder and it throws
all the eyes and all the audio
into the, uh, folders. You
modify what you want and then
you use that folder as an input
to recreate a new file. Um, so
if you take your Teddy, connect
him to USB, take one of the
files, decompress it or extract
all the portions, modify it,
rebuild it, then you can put
that on the bear’s mass storage
drive, or device and, uh, be
able to see the new content that
you created. This is an example
of said content. Um, it’s been
the background for all of the
slides but I felt like for Def
Con it was important to throw
the Def Con logo into the eyes.
Um, so let me show you a little
demo that I created, [laughter]
which is generally all the fun.
I hope you don’t mind, I know
there’s like a no video
photography, uh, rule or used to
be but I got this 3d camera that
is awesome and I really want to
use it so everyone can just, uh,
deal with me breaking that rule.
Ok, cool. So, let’s make sure
that it’s nice and zoomed in.
Put this guy right there. Let me
get this mic. Hello? Ok, cool.
[soft music starts to play from
bear] [tv static sounds play
from bear] [laughter][applause]
>>woo! >>Yeah. And that’s the
outcome of months of work.
[laughter] So, uh, I hope you
guys enjoyed that. Uh, let me
give thanks to the Expoitee.rs,
uh, one of my ex colleagues Ryan
Smith, the Def Con staff for
helping me on every presentation
I’ve ever done, um, my family,
especially my kid and wife for
tolerating me destroying all of
my kid’s toys [laughter] and
then filling the kitchen with
tons of hardware hacking gear.
By the way if you’re leaving
I’ve got tons of free stuff to
give out so you may not want to.
Uh, [laughter] hack all the
things, uh, we have an IRC, uh,
server where people just jump in
and they tell us what they’re
hacking on and if they have
problems then we help them so if
you are hacking on something,
you’re new, you just want to
chat with like-minded people
jump on Freenode channel
Exploitee.rs. There shouldn’t be
a dot in that channel name, my
bad. Um, so just Exploitee.rs
without the dot. Um, and, yeah,
uh, if you go to the last 3 -
the back 3 doors, uh, I got some
of my, uh, my Exploitee.rs
friends, um, they’re going to be
handing out these SD breakouts
that we created, um, based on a
previous talk but you can grab
one of those. We’ve got some
stickers, um, we have some SAO’s
for your badges, um, the don’t
work but you can just tape them
on or something, who cares.
[laughter] And yeah, thank you
everyone for coming out, uh, and
braving the heat to get here.
[applause]