>>Okay! Lot’s to talk about, so
we’re not gonna, we’re just
gonna cut to the chase. Sigh
Agent X, the stuff’s in the
program. So let’s get on with
it. Surveillance. Why are we
doing surveillance in this talk?
1983 if you said to someone
surveillance this is what they
would think about They wouldn’t
think about the, the global,
technical surveillance that’s
going on at the moment.
>>Facebook >>So! Are you a
target? >> It’s entirely
possible that you are. Some
people that may be in this room
have been targeted. And these,
all these people have been- have
spoken at DefCon, or run DefCon,
uh, and where’s the pointer?
There ya go. So the guy all the
way on the right is actually Zac
Franken who was speaking- who
ran DefCon for 15 years and you
know DefCon might also be
targeting you! This is Michelle
Madigan- you were there- this is
basically a sting reporter who
tried to stung DefCon, so we
stung them with our own
undercover team. [laughter]
Yeah. So, yeah- real physical
surveillance, really good times.
>>In a hostile environment.
>>yeah >>However, if your office
at home looks like this and you
never leave your house, then
you’re probably not a target.
Although it does look a bit like
Major Malfunction’s office.
>>But this is way neater >>yeah
way >>I mean, like, cleaner
>>So, who’s likely to be
conducting surveillance? We’ve
got the obvious three letter
agencies. The NSA, FBI, CIA, KFC
[laughter] okay maybe not KFC,
unless you’re trying to sell the
secret recipe to north korea,
but y’know, a lot of companies
have the ability to engage
surveillance teams if they
require them. A lot of
government departments,
especially in the UK you know
local government can hire and
bring in surveillance teams and
majesty's revenue and customs
are looking for fraud they have
dedicated surveillance teams and
also you as an individual can go
and get trained so this is uh a
UK company run by an ex military
surveillance operator. So you
provide two forms of ID, pay
your money, if you pass the
course you get to formal
qualification so you become
formally qualified in advanced
surveillance techniques for only
two thousand three hundred
pounds. >>So that’s like in
Brexit money, that’s like two
hundred bucks [laughter] >>Yeah,
pretty much. So one important
fact we have to point out right
in the beginning of the talk is
all surveillance operators and
all vehicles involved if in
surveillance have what is called
a heat state, your heat state
starts at ten at the start of an
operation or the start of an
operational day and everytime
you come into contact with the
target or expose to the target
your heat state drops to the
point where for example if you
crash your car into their car
you end up toast. [laughter]
okay? At the end of the day all
of the operators will actually
say what they think their heat
state is, so your mission as a
person that may be under
surveillance is to rate or just
get their heat state to drop or
make toast. Now surveillance
itself, three main stages to
surveillance, the pickup, the
follow, and the housing. The
majority of the talk is going to
be about the follow because
that’s where most of the fun
happens, but we will talk
quickly about the pickup ‘cause
this is important is getting
control of a target at the
beginning of an operation or at
the beginning of the operational
day um and they need to give a
description of the target where
they are and where they are
going and this can be done in a
number of ways, we could use
static observation post this
could be a neighboring property
for example. >>Yeah so this is
uh the big white building that’s
the uh russian embassy in
Washington and uh the building
across the street that’s uh the
FBI static surveillance post
that they’ve owned and operated
for years [laughter] and it’s
very obviously a static
observation post like people are
like oh what’s with the giant
cameras and the skylights?
[laughter] And no one goes
through the front door they
always go through the backdoor
on the adjacent street. >>They
can also use static covert
cameras um again with modern
technology they can fit a
camera, monitor it remotely, uh
and pick up a source as they
leave. Or they can use a mobile
observation post, now I will
cover this briefly, this is an
ex FBI 1989 Dodge surveillance
vehicle, that some guy >>F****d
up [laughter] >>Yeah bought at
an action and then videoed it up
and put it on Youtube now on the
top there that houses the
antennae, each of the lights
were fitted with microphones
front and back, all of the roof
mounts were fitted with cameras
and inside we had a full suite
of video and audio recording a
toilet and air con, obviously
we’ve got to keep him happy
>>That’s a pretty nice van >>So.
Yeah pretty nice van. Obviously
not as nice as this van >>No
[laughter] >>So if you see this
parked in your street you’ve
really screwed up, yeah? >>Yeah
>>Or they can use a surveillance
vehicle now one point of a
surveillance vehicle is a is a
lesser known technique uh and
that’s what’s known as a boot
fit or a trunk fit for you
Americans out there uh this is a
especially adapted vehicle where
uh the operator is in the trunk
of the vehicle, not comfortable,
however they have the ability to
observe, to video, to take
pictures, and it is very
effective in certain
circumstances because a big a**
van parked in this street would
be obvious whereas this could be
boot bit so very limited time
because obviously this the
operator inside is at risk
however y’know it works. Now in
the program we said these
techniques have been around for
years, they’ve changed little,
this is a film maybe 1974 by the
Brits and shared with our
American friends under our
special relationship >>So
special >>So Special. Uh and
this covers the pickup.
Sequences have been shortened
[video music starts to play] as
they say in other words [music
and indiscernible audio] >>I
love this music >>[audio from
video] The escort has remained
stationary. The target passes
the second car who in turn sends
the information that will enable
the third car to take up the
chase. >>From ground now moving
West >>Let’s look at that
sequence again as seen through
the targets mirror he pulls away
and moves off down the road
nothing to arouse his suspicions
and at approximately one
kilometer away from home the
green Magnum pulling out to take
control of the follow appears as
part of the normal traffic
pattern. Although he has seen
nothing the target has been
under surveillance most of the
time [video ends]. >>And a key
point there is under
surveillance they are not
following you they are not right
behind you oooh [laughter] thank
you. Um so within the follow
especially in the vehicle follow
you can lose the vehicle it
doesn’t matter if you lose the
vehicle especially if you’re on
a long operation it’s better to
lose the target than compromise
the operation and make them
aware they’re under
surveillance. Now you heard them
talking on the radio obviously
very old nowadays for brevity we
use brevity codes, this makes it
easier for the team to
communicate it also hides things
like locations and directions of
travel as you will see because
if they’re not using encrypted
communications you can intercept
this and anyone listening might
be aware of what’s going on. So
here we see stand by that’s the
target out of his house wearing
a red baseball cap, blue top,
grey trousers, and black shoes
target getting into his car now
moving off turning left toward
the junction of High Street and
Water lane. Now anyone listening
and picking up on radio knows
exactly where that person is and
what direction they’re going so
we use brevity codes. Seven
seven alpha one from charlie
one, blue on grey, black shoes,
red cap, complete bravo one,
mobile nine one yellow two.
>>Sounds gobbledygook but the
team understands the last part
there is using what we call spot
codes which are on spot maps and
again for ease of reference for
the team to be able to give the
location of a target and a
direction of travel rather than
saying that they’re on this road
travelling to towards the
village of Earl Shilton, as you
can see here, we can simply say,
at red six intending right
committed nine one red five.
Everyone understands where the
target is and what direction
they’re heading. >>So this kinda
gets to something we’ve spot
maps made up for the entire
operational area, every body
every car of how many cars?
Potentially 8 vehicles and 16
operators.So you’re looking at
binders of full of information
rapidly put together with a big
team. It's just not a cheap
thing to do if you’re doing it
right. It involves a lot of
teamwork and when you can make a
lot of toast you can help break
that team up and thus ruin their
effectiveness. >> So what are we
looking for behind when we think
were under surveillance?
Obviously they’ll be needing a
vehicle if you’re in texas and
everybody’s driving pick-up
trucks, they will be driving
pickup trucks. If you’re in a
city they will be in a sedan
car. They will blend in the
environment. They will not be
driving big ass SUVs with
government plates. Except in DC.
>>Here is an extract in a local
paper in Iowa and here we say
just in one state the large
number of licensed plates issued
to cover to work this is because
and a professional team and
agents level team they will hold
multiple licences which they can
change, and again if you raise
the heat state of that vehicle
they think it needs changing
,they will change the license
plate. This can’t be done on the
side of the road because someone
unscrewing the license plate and
screwing another one, someone's
gonna call the cops and you
don't want to explain what
you’re doing. They will to do
this and they will have to leave
the follow while it happens. Now
as we said they will not drive
directly behind you. They will
use other vehicles as natural
covers, they will use 2 or 3
cars behind you. They will use
parallel roots to get ahead of
you but in America you made it
really easy you’ve come up with
the block system in most of the
cities so here we have
outstanded FBI floating box. The
target vehicle is red, and the
direction of travel so the
target vehicle turns the
messages relayed to all of the
team and the next opportunity
all the vehicles turn the target
continues the other vehicles
come in behind and the target is
still within the floating box.
So pulling up to a light and
just as it turn red driving
through will not stop this.
Because there’s someone on
parallel route to pick you up.
So how do we get around this,
how do we conduct anti
surveillance ? now quick point
here. Anti surveillance is what
you do as an individual to
detect the surveillance team.
Counter surveillance is when you
you use 3rd party to do that. Me
as a good guy I have my own good
guy surveillance team to follow
me to see if they can identify
the bad guy surveillance thats
counter surveillance. If you’re
doing anti surveillance you’re
on your own . >> and when you
have 4th team, its counter
counter counter surveillance,
just to confuse things. Throw us
all away down. >>So quite simply
you can do simple things like
vary your route, use the public
transport and I don’t mean from
outside the house, drive
somewhere, park your car get in
a bus. Get in a cab because
busses and cabs in most cities
around the world can go to
places where normal vehicles
can’t so if you’re in a cab or
bus, they will not be able to
follow you down the road, also
they will need to make
decisions, if you get in the
bus, why are you on the bus, are
you meeting someone in that bus
or you’re doing something
nefarious do they need to put
someone over there with you. At
that point you are in control,
you can observe someone that
gets on, and make note of them,
you’ll be able to observe until
the time >>So of course one of
the thing we’re doing here right
is switching up the tempo on the
surveillance team, we’re putting
them them in the back, we’re
forcing them to make decisions
quickly that is awkward. 50-50
decision and if you’re
lucky,they’ll make a 50-50
decision will come up bad for
them and good for us. We’ll spot
them because they’re too close
and or we’ll see them over and
over again. >>And obviously if
they do try to follow you down
here. They’re allowed to be
stopped by this and again they
will again have to explain what
the hell they were doing in the
bus lane. We can use natural
choke points. Here we have 2
villages circled if you drive
around the road, around the lock
here it's about 47 miles, the
roads are really crappy, and it
takes a long time however,
between the two is a ferry,
again if you’re in a area where
these sorts of things like the
lakes area in the york with
coferries use this to your
advantage if you get from here
again, the decisions comes are
they gonna drive 47 miles to
trying to catch you on the other
side or they are going to put
1,2,3 vehicles with you that
point again you’re in control
you can see and look at everyone
on there. Another technique
which surveillance operators are
told to recognize before it
happens is something called the
long look this is where you have
a long straight roads with no
parallel road and when the time
the target hits this road they
have a long look behind them so
they can see lots of vehicles if
they’re in a convoy, specially
if they’re not in a busy road.
Again, a lot easier in the
states this I sat in the middle
of the road took picture one
way. This was 8 mile long this
straight, there were no parallel
roads. I saw one of the car in 4
hours so surveillance team
behind me one this road I hope i
recognize them. >> the other
thing about that is that they’re
forcing the team to also do
resource management they’re
gonna have to put one car down
that road because they can’t put
all of them down on that road
after you because it sticks out
right. It breaks the pattern.
And that’s the thing we figured
out how to choke them and break
the pattern we’re gonna spot
them >> we can also use
technology in our advantage, if
you have someone to assist you.
What we can do is, have them to
choke points say the morning and
they video every car that comes
through before and after you
forbid if 10 mins, the later
during the day it's another
geographic location, again do
the same then you get to list of
license plates, compare the
licenses ends up on both list
potentially that’s surveillance
vehicle. Technology can help us
so the OpenALPR program
automated license plate reader
so this is a bit of footage I
took with an iphone in real
time, there is the image in the
bottom right hand corner. That’s
me running the image file
through the software. Now the
software reads the image file
frame by frame so you will have
multiple instances of the same
license plate so again we can
use technology we can run the
software extract the json
convert that to a sequel file
>>Thank god we recorded at the
demo, and that is recorded. So
the other thing while this is
running there’s other tools that
do this and amazon facial
recognition project. If you can
do it for car you can do it with
faces. >> so out of the box
sequel, sqlite on coli, distance
support, regular expressions so
we download and install pel
regret instructions module
reading the simple file running
standard query using the rejects
here for standard UK license
plates which is letter, letter,
number, number, letter, letter
and here you will see in the
first set of results you get
some license plate that are
quite similar that’s due to the
mysteries in the software where
the images are slightly blurred
and hardly recognize so to get
around this you can just do a
standard sequel count whether
you got 2 similar license plate,
the one with the higher count
will be the real number. So
we’ve now driven to where we’re
gonna meet our contact to pick
up our data and we’re gonna park
and again, parking is a choke
point, you’re in control you
choose where to park, they have
to decide if they have to park
on the same car park with you.
Because you may spot them.
Specially if you’re going to a
multi story park again that is
choke point where you can
observe. Now there’s a
misconception that comes from
law enforcement and the military
, always park your car in
reverse for quick get away
surveillance operators are
trained to blend in, the grey
man, so if everyone's knows you
park because they are here and
you reverse park to someone
that’s surveillance aware,
automatically your eyes are
drawn to that car automatically,
why is that car parked
differently. Again we can see
here to someone that is more
observant than the rest of us
there’s the one that’s parked
wrong and how about that one,
has anyone spot that car on the
opposite direction? Its right in
the middle of the screen dude,
so yeah, again if you’re in a
cab you can get the cab to stop
wherever you want, you can drop
me here, and if there's no
parking what do they do? If it's
in a restricted parking area and
they abandoned their vehicle,
they can lose their vehicle.
Explain that one to your boss,
and so were doing is that we’re
in the tempo right you jump out
of the cab if the unexpected is
on the cross drive which we’ve
all done i hope, this is vegas
and you basically force them to
go from a car tail to a foot
tail and they don't necessary
have assets that close and that
quickly available, its gonna
mess things up for them, it's
gonna make them bad decisions.
>> now when you return to your
car again gives you a chance to
look in the cars as you walk
pass which said that they’re
professionals but they’re also
humans and humans do mistakes
and so if you see maps in there
you may see other paraphernalia
and this is true story told to
me by a friend 2 surveillance
instructors were visiting
students on a covered
observation post course and they
parked their vehicle and went on
foot. Someone reported the
vehicle is being suspicious so
the police turned up. The police
looked in the vehicle and
sticking out from under the seat
was a hampstead, and they waited
and so they came back and yes
explain to them what we're doing
with our special car that says
please don't arrest us, we’re
doing surveillance training. >>
We’re not calling them
criminals, we have a card at
school >>Honest >>One of the
clarification questions when we
submitted that talk is why old
school vehicle surveillance, you
can put a tracker on there, well
yeah you can but they are
technical adversary they can
detect that and if they detect
that they will know they were in
surveillance also yes it's great
he stopped at the mall and I’m a
mile away. So he’s out of his
car and in the mall you get
there, where is he? The main
point of surveillance is to have
enough people in contact with
the target so when he stops you
can deploy on default and
continue to follow. >>The point
of surveillance is not to know
where the people go,but is to
observe their behavior. Were
looking for is that if they’re
doing the deed that made them
interesting in the first place
so technical surveillance,
metadata surveillance is great
you know Jimmy goes to Fry’s
every Tuesday and buys a
hamburger but frankly that’s not
what we care about. We want to
know who he share his emperor
with. >>So we’re out of the car,
we’re walking along they’re out
on foot. What are these people
look like, F*cking bad*sses.
[laughter]. They always look
like this media has told us that
they always are gigantic badass
white males with short hair and
big watches, so if you see these
guys on the streets, you’ll
think oh my god I’m under
surveillance, well they've got
earpieces that I can see this
guy has a wire from his radio
sticking out as should, this
guys has push to talk button
sticking out the sleeve and this
guy has a holster, so he’s
armed. If these guys are
following you, they’re doing
overt surveillance, they want
you to know they’re there.
they’re not there to see what
you’re doing they are there so
you can see them doing you. So
these 3 people where part of a
UK tv show one is ex GHCQ one is
ex MI6 and one is a NEXMI5
surveillance operator. So who’s
who? Not the grey man, the grey
person, they will use female
operators because we’re all
fixated on short big tall white
man you wont pay second thought
to this person sat from the bus
next to you. Also the newbies
into surveillance they fall into
the habit of the unofficial
uniform that they all dress so
differently that all dress the
same wearing black shirts. >>
that never happens, no one ever
wears black shirt and jeans all
the time, were talking about
they have khaki shorts and black
shirts. That’s theirs summer
clothes. On their thought they
still need to communicate, they
will have wireless earpiece you
will not see wires sticking out
their ears. If you have big ears
like me you won't see anything.
You might if you look close
enough see the retractor stem on
the earpiece you need to get
signals on the earpiece so
there’s inductive loop around
the neck this also has a
microphone in it to transmit the
data the antenna is normally
worn of the center of the back
across the shoulders in a
t-shape to the best attenuation,
and the pressel talk switch
doesn’t hang down your sleeve it
will be secluded somewhere
inside your clothing where it
can't be seen. The whole kit is
worn in a vest with the radio on
one side and the battery on the
other side to reduce bulk. So
this is quite a lot of equipment
they’re wearing and ofcourse
they have to wear clothing to
conceal it now talking about
clothing they will utilize
changes in appearance. very old
photographs and >>do love me a
good Stasi archive. This is
where I get all my fashion tips.
>These were taken from manerock
archive from the stasi, which is
the east German secret police
who has a huge surveillance
capability. Even nowadays an
agent surveillance team will
utilize wigs playing glasses
false mustaches you think its a
joke, it works. >>It's all about
breaking out the outline. From
the head up, these two guys are
totally different right.same
shirt but outline are different.
And we are not that good with at
taping all the people around us.
We make little outline about
people around us and that’s
about it. So you just have to
break that outline and you can
disappear on the crowd pretty
easy >> now one of the problems
of the surveillance operator
doing change for the appearance
is you have limited time to do
this. People forget people
operators like goons. Are there
goons in here ? there's a couple
of goons here. We spend days on
your feet so you’ve got a pair
of shoes you like and are
comfortable they’re fabulous,
shut up. There's no place like
home. So they’ll change up
everything else but their shoes
won’t change so remember we
said, you’re in a public
transport, you’re being observed
this is what you’ll be looking
for the small details that
people don't change how often do
you look at mens shoes >>
Watches, people like their
specially ex military nice glow
in the dark watch things that
they forget to change the next
time you see looks different but
with the same watch make note.
Jewelry again, wedding rings
necklaces women with earings. So
they’re behind you so what they
do behind you they will be
conducting most standard abc
pattern so you got the target in
red. Directly behind the target
is the guy that is in control
only one person in control and
has the eyeball in the target.
Behind him is the person that
his backing. He is in the
position to take control and in
the opposite side of the road is
the trail is slightly behind the
target to observe from the
distance. You can't do it this
with one or 2 people so if you
think I’m following that person,
yeah, you’re following them into
a trap. So the target turns the
corner now has the target
continue to walk as the target
stop to wait to see who follow
them on the corner, the trail
being on the opposite side of
the road can see this, they can
pass the message that the target
has continued to walk on the
road. So the guy control crosses
the road to trail and becomes
the control, the guy in control
now becomes the trail. And the
guy behind is now backing. You
still have maintained control of
the target. You are still
imposing surveillance and the
other 15 guys, 14 guys in a
team, they again maybe on
parallel ruse, maybe further
back and can swap and change so
that you can limit your exposure
to the target. Now from our
perspective we want to conduct
anti surveillance against this
guys and girls so we use the
surroundings for example if
we’re doing anti surveillance we
want to identify them without
letting them know we’re
identifying them. Because that
gives away the game. You want to
know they’re there so you can
either lose them to do what you
need to do or do what you need
to do when they can’t see you.
We can use the environment in
subways the sort of mirrors you
see in UK in the underground.
Walking along the street, window
shopping. Window shopping is a
great thing because windows are
reflective. You’re not looking
for who’s on the same side of
the road in, you’re looking
who’s on the opposite side of
the road. You’re looking for the
trail because they may become
complacent not being directly
behind the target, not rotating
as much, and if you keep seeing
the same person on the side of
the road. Potentially that’s
someone that has you under
surveillance. >>So this is kinda
one that things you see. The CIA
training people to do what they
call counter surveillance which
is actually anti surveillance
routes one of the things they do
is that you really have to learn
that urban terrain you have to
learn where those mirrors are,
you have to learn what windows
will work for you. What are the
choke points are, so and so
forth. So they really do invest
in having a lot of case officers
really really well. Know how to
really run their anti
surveillance routes. To the
point where case officers where
like, I have been running anti
surveillance routes for 3 months
now when do I get my job? >> You
are in control here, you choose
the environment, you choose the
place. Again if you’re in a
mall, get on escalators, natural
for people to stand on
escalators, turn around and look
around, look behind them and
talk to their friends gives you
the opportunity to see who’s one
story below coming up. Now we
carry mobile phones so why would
you want to use one of these?
User payphone it gives you a
reason to stop, it gives you a
reason to look around you.
Surveillance operators are
trained, if the target stopped,
they have to have a reason for
being there. So they don’t just
stop and turn they’re back and
pretend they’re not there.
They’ll go into a shop, store or
walk into a phone pick it up and
pretend that doing something
else. But you already used that,
they need to find somewhere
else. >>This is called cover for
action by the way, it's
basically the reason you’re
there. You all know the answer
to this one it's I’m here, I
have a switch and I’m here to
put this stuff inside your
network. You have a cover for
action, it’s the reason you are
in that environment, it is
natural and smooth. So break
that. >>So again we can use
natural choke points while were
out walking, you know the area,
you know this is a one way
street the only thing on the
bottom of this street is a
coffee shop no one goes to. So
anyone else walking down the
street behind you is one you’re
interested in. You could have
areas where there is only one
point to get from a to b that
they have to transit to, again
they will have to take the long
way around or push everyone
through there which will give
you the opportunity to observe.
Things that are less obvious.
Most guys don’t want to go in
here, unless they are with their
wife or girlfriend. So if I go
in here and then another guy
gets in, I’m interested, well
I’m interested in him [laughter]
>> Oh yeah, well played sir,
well played. Indeed. >>but they
have women in their teams, they
can put woman in there and
that’s not suspicious and yep,
but she’s not following men
here. Again,make them make
decisions, why are you going in
here. It may be obvious, but it
may not be. In cold war times,
this were the places where
packages are placed for people
to go in and retrieve and
collect data, because people
don’t want to follow people in
the men’s room. So use it to
your advantage. Again if someone
comes in there it just gives you
the opportunity to make note of
what they’re wearing. Elevators,
first you will not get into the
elevators with these people.
They’re so unhappy, they’re
gonna fight, they’re strange and
again they have to make that
decision, do they put someone in
this small metal box with you.
Which point you’re this far
away, or really get a good look
on them. Also if you get in the
elevator and no one get in
behind you, press, 3 or 4 floors
and get off on your floor. And
no matter what you see on the
films, they’re not gonna run up
15 storeys worth of stairs to
beat you into the top. It
doesn’t happen. It also gives
you a chance to make toast.
Engage with them, if someone’s
right there that’s a bit
suspicious, might be a
surveillance operator, you turn
to them and this is the key
thing, in your best british
accent, you say, excuse me my
good man, mind if I pity you for
a stop, could you tell me the
time please? But why british
accent, but we have awesome
accent too. >>Have you ever
noticed how in hollywood movies
all the villains are played by
Brits, maybe we just sound
right, more focused or precise,
were always one step ahead. I’m
very obsessed by power, we all
drive Jaguars, Oh yes. It’s good
to be bad. >>So we move on to
hostile environments, this isn't
afghanistan or downtown LA, we
use hostile environment to our
advantage. This is agent x’s
favorite hostile environment.
>>no one’s surveilling me, well
they are, but I’m wanting them
to. >> Remember they’re wearing
all this kit, they have to wear
enough clothing to cover this
kit. They get in the pool with
you. >>or the turkish spa by the
way is also really good >>We can
also use misdirection again
they’ll looking for you to have
interactions with people,
they’re trying to identify who
you’re meeting. Use this to your
advantage. If you meet someone
on the street, shake hands with
them, or when I meet my friend
Trevor for milkshake, I normally
give him a big bro hug or, a
fall on Jayson street awkward
hug or stand in front of someone
who’s a bigger target than you
are. >>Yeah That’s a classic
trick, this worked for me for
years. >> Again, use the
environment, going to a cafe you
control the environment, you can
choose where to sit, you can see
everyone that comes in, make a
not of everyone that comes in,
when you read the paper, when to
finish, take that paper, fold it
up and put it on the side and
leave. >>Put it in an awkward
kind of special spot, between
the planters right >>so it
doesn’t entirely the way they
now have a decision has that
paper got something in of
importance, do they leave the
whole team watching that cafe to
see who come and picks up that
paper. >>So awkward, here’s a
pro tip by the way, if you have
ever seen the Big Lebowski you
f*cking Jackie Treehorn them too
so when they do find it, he he
he he. >>Or they split the team
in half, half watch the cafe,
and half continue to follow you.
You have one at that point
because you have now have half
the amount of people operating
against you while you going to
do you your sh*t. You can also
use their techniques and
remember from the start of the
thing we gave description of
what the target look like. So
the surveillance team has been
following you for 6 hours and
all they’re looking for is a red
hat, you can use change of
appearance, while I’m not saying
carrying wigs and mustaches and
sh*t with you, >>which will not
work if you’re not a pro, its
really embarrassing if your face
falls off >>take a bag take your
coat off, take your hat off and
then you’ve changed your
appearance. [laughter from the
audience] >>maybe not your
political persuasion but it
should do it. Now you’re saying
this is old school which is
where we are, this shi*t is not
happening anymore. >>This sh*t
happens in Tuesday everywhere.
>>So here we have Richard and
Cynthia Murphy, So wholesome,
they have barbecues, they have
some more children they have
lived in a small town. And
upstate New York, the neighbors
thought they are lovely they
like hotdogs come on! They’re
actually Vladimir and Lidiya
Gyryev, they were deep russian
operative that’s been in the
country since the late 80’s or
late 90’s, their children were
born in the country, the
Russians were playing the long
game. They came on the radar the
FBI they started an operation
against these people, and as a
result they have identified a
total of 10 deep Russian
operatives. >>Look at how
unhappy these people are
[laughter]. >>That’s because
they got caught and they were
conducting surveillance for
these people for nearly 10 years
surveillance is a long game
because you want them, you want
their handlers you want their
handlers bosses, you want
everyone’s involved in that
team. >>You wanna know how
they’re operating right? Because
everybody on surveillance games
playing from the same playbook.
The way that’s the Soviets
sorry, the russians surveil or
the way we surveil is exactly
the same team make up, same
stuff, because it's really like
a bicycle, it's got an optimal
form where just gonna run with
it, there’s not a lot of change
ups that they run. >> Now an
interesting part of this
operation was afterwards they
deported them all, the FBI have
release video footage of
surveillance they’re taping now
we start with this one, this is
a very strange angle, its a
covered camera in a tree
pointing directly down this is
someone picking up a package
from a dead letter box, when you
pick from a dead letter box,
it's meant to be quick, not
rooting around in the sharpery.
Digging sh*t with a shovel draws
attention now although they use
technology here with a covered
camera, surveillance team that
got them to that point and had
the identified where this was
happening for them to use
technology for their advantage.
And again with the dead letter
box, don’t use the same one.
Because when you go back there
will be camera, so , second one
again, this is totally normal.
We all do this, we all go for
walks, and then we go and hide
under bridges and take something
out of there because that’s
normal. >>Why don’t we put Billy
Gordon for the kids, >>its right
, yeah. In the next couple of
videos, I want you to look how
sloppy they’ve got. We’ve all
seen these techniques. These are
pros, literally their life is on
the line and they’ve been doing
this for 10 years. This is what
pros look like. This is a brush
pass, this is meant to be 2
people carrying the same item in
a busy crowded street [laughter
] because that’s normal right? I
mean I just do that all the
time, I find a tunnel in New
York and say hey man, here’s my
groceries you got some
groceries, that would be great.
Oh this guy, not a spy. >>they
need to go back to school,
they’re not slick. And this guy
is even better, this is a subway
>>Just hanging out >>Not really
acting suspicious, and no, he’s
not coming >>Because we all hang
out in the subways of New York
right? Like you gotta take the
subway, you really don’t want to
be in the subway, anyway. You’re
not gonna hangout there. >>the
FBI got bored didn’t they so
they cut the footage >> they
edited the footage, how long the
guy was loitering in there but
then eventually they started the
footage again and I’m here,
quickly adjust the clothing and
were off to do our brush pass,
again slick in a busy, yeah no,
and again all these camera
angles are taken from covered
cameras >> And remember, it's
the FBI, they’re inherently
bureaucracy right? so somebody
have to fill out a paperwork,
like hey can we put up camera in
a public place and surveil? So
they hire up a lawyer to get
involved and so on and so forth.
A lot of this stuff it took a
long time to set up its pretty
sloppy in the side of the
Russians >> You remember I said
you control the environment,
going to a cafe where you can
say you can observe, you are in
control, so the 2 guys in the
middle are the target of course,
now what they’re actually doing
isn’t overly suspicious in a
cafe passing in between two bags
however, this footage was taken
from a covered camera in a bag
placed on the tabe about 6 feet
away pointing directly at them.
No one does that ever. This
thing about being observant and
looking in an using your
surrounding but it also shows
the length of the surveillance
team will go to get close enough
to get the evidence they need.
>> this is the other thing,
they’re putting a operators
really close to the target, this
is burning distance right. At
this point the person’s leg is
one of the operators and if you
watch the whole footage there’s
other people that has
interaction with the leg. So
there’s like 3 FBI people in
here and they did not spot them.
>>Bad on them >> So I say we
can’t cover everything in 45
minutes so in summary use your
environment, you are in control,
you choose where you want to go
and make them follow you not you
be aware they’re waiting for
you. >> You can set the tempo
because they’re following you,
you’re the leader, change the
tempo and change it on them.
They’ll hate it >> Make them
make decisions, again make them
make bad decisions so they all
showing out they all making
themselves obvious to you as the
target, the best one is if you
can divide and conquer, get them
totally look at the wrong
direction or you get a team to
split so you get half the amount
of people operating against you.
>>Always make toast, that’s the
key thing here, if you do happen
to be a target or maybe doing
things that you shouldn’t be
doing? Not that no one here is
slightly to be targeted
surveillance >>that never
happens >> If you are doing and
you are going to meet someone,
if you are press, you are going
to meet, a source for example
>>combine bath salts with
bitcoins whatever >> if you ever
are in doubt if you were ever in
that position, abort. You may
been to surveillance but abort
so that you don't then drool
someone else into their circle.
Now everything that we said on
this talk is in the public
domain, I haven’t given away
this super secret, I haven’t
knowingly broken any official
secret sect. >>That’s important
for you, I’m not covered by that
>>so please don't arrest me if I
try to leave the country because
that doesn’t happen over here
>>And all this stuff is public,
if you read this book, it all
covers the same stuff. >> So
that concludes the talk. And
we’ve just ran over we will take
questions, but we will do it in
the chill out area so that the
next speaker can get on here,
thank you very much for
listening. Thank you. [Applause]