>>All right it’s about that time
to get the show on the road so
everyone please give a very warm
welcome to Thiago who will be
talking about hacking PLCs.
[applause] >>Sorry I have a
little experiment. Sorry I have
a little experiment here and uh
it took a little longer to set
up than I was expecting but I am
very very happy to be here at
Defcon today and uh I was
honestly expecting like 50 maybe
a hundred people so thank you
guys for taking the time to be
here on Saturday morning and
listen to me. Uh I am Thiago
Alves and a little bit about me,
about me uh I am a PhD student
at UAH and I also work um at the
center for cybersecurity
research and education it’s
called CCRE at the University.
And uh yeah this what I do I
love to hack stuff and I try to
break as many things as I can.
Um and I'm also the creator of
the open PLC project if you guys
haven't heard of it you'll hear
about it a little bit today.
Hands up if somebody have heard
about PLC before. Wow thank you
that's great. Wow that’s great,
thank you. [applause] Also today
um it’s a very important date
for me because this trip to
Vegas marks our 9th year
anniversary. Me and my wife were
together for 9 years and uh
yeah. [applause] I used to have
more hair back then, but she is
still pretty the same way. So
I’m a lucky guy. And uh she
always complain about being like
slowing me down because now we
have kids and I have other
things to focus on but I keep
telling her that if you want to
go fast you go alone. Life is
not about speed. But if you want
to go further, if you want to go
far, you go together. That's why
I'm here, that's because of you.
Alright. And I’m very happy I
invited her to be here at my
talk. [applause] Thank you. And
she has a very important job
actually because I have really
bad jokes and she laughs of all
of them so if you hear her
laughing just please laugh as
well so we have a nice
presentation. Ok? Ok. So a
little outline about today. Um
I’ll I’m gonna um start with
background info, you know a
little bit about PLCs, if you
guys know about PLCs I’ll try to
go fast. If you guys don’t know
about PLCs please pay attention
because I will go fast. K. Then
we’ll go and talk about little
attack vectors, some stuff we
can do to break those things,
and finally we’ll demo if the
demo demons haven’t gotten me
because I did not have time to
set up so hopefully things will
go out fine. So what is a PLC
after all? Uh it is, that’s what
it looks like right, it’s a
brick and uh it stands for
Programmable Logic Controller
and basically it’s a digital
computer, right? It’s used in
automation since 1970 so it’s a
long time ago. And uh basically
it is an embedded system with a
CPU with some RAM, some ROM,
right, some flash nowadays, you
put your program in there, you
run your program and uh your
program decides what to do with
the input data it senses from
the in-in-input modules the PLC
has. So PLC has a bunch of
inputs, a bunch of outputs, um I
have 3 PLCs set up here trying
to heat water and um they’re
doing a poor job doing that. Uh
but then you program those
devices to any logic you want
and it has output modules to
control real life stuff, right?
So like for example in this
setup it’s controlling the
heater based on the temperature
setter that's attached to the
input module. And you will see
PLCs in many different places.
So here I have like a damn, a
substation, a gas distribution
system and a petrochemical
fac-facility. Um PLCS are there.
And imagine what happens if you
hack into those PLCs and make it
crash,k right? Or change a
setting. So for all those
situations disaster will follow
if you break into a PLC because
they’re controlling large huge
stuff that can cause even
physical damage and life loss,
right? So what is the problem
with the current PLCs we have?
First of all they are freaking
expensive. You know if you're
building an embedded system it
shouldn't cost that much.
Nowadays there is some companies
selling what they call cheapo
PLCs. They can uh you can buy
one for like a hundred or 2
hundred dollars but then they
get you on software..Uh there
are companies selling software
programming, software for PLCs,
for up to 5000 dollars per
station. And that is ridiculous,
right? That is ridiculous. And
uh also they rely on legacy
technology. PLCS were built like
40 years ago. That's also a
major problem because this
legacy technology was created at
a time when the internet didn't
exist. So uh they used insecure
protocols to communicate um most
companies rather patch their
devices instead of redesign.
We’re in a situation where we
need redesign and they’re close
sourced. So it’s a problem if
you’re researcher and trying to
figure out how they work. So I
came up with a solution if you
guys know about it. Open PLC,
that’s my thing. Right? Open PLC
is the world’s first and only
one PLC available with the full
source code. They are other
approaches that people try to
develop their own PLCs, but it
is not close to what a PLC
should look like. Uh PLC the
there are many standards that
define what a PLC should do and
how it should bhave and I try to
follow those standards close uh
so that it will look like a real
PLC and behave as much as
possible to a real PLC and make
the source code available anyone
can go take a look at the code
and use it. It is free, right?
And basically open PLC has 3
main components, the runtime
that is the big thing that I am
creating, uh is the that goes
into the embedded system,
embedded device and initially i
started creating my own hardware
but then I gave up and started
using raspberry pi and arduino
and stuff that everybody have.
So you can load the runtime on
you embedded system and have it
read your PLC programs. You
create your PLC programs on the
editor that’s supposed to run on
your computer, right, on your
windows linux machine some
people have boarded it to mac os
as well. And uh the third
portion of it is scadabr which
is a GUI builder that allows you
to build nice animated graphical
screens for your PLC um um uh
programs, right. So for the open
PLC runtime it runs on many
different platforms. These are
the platforms that are currently
supported, officially supported,
like I said raspberry pi,
arduinos, but also there are
some industrial uh devices that
people created that also runs on
open PLC like unipi and pixtend.
Uh this is really cool you can
go and buy those devices and and
install open PLC today if you
want. There are other devices
that are not here that are not
officially supported that were
created by the community so I
have a forum with lots of people
in there and they you know make
all sorts of questions and uh
they also contribute to the
project and they created
unofficial pat-patches that uh
make open PLC run on like orange
pi and other platforms that
basically run linux. This is the
editor what it looks like. Uh it
supports five programming
languages this these are all the
5 languages uh the 5 on the
standard. And this is ScadaBR
right. Uh this is a real nice
graphical screen created on
ScadaBr so it can create many
things. This is the water
temperature control you're gonna
see today. So lets gonna talk
about PLC protocols for a bit.
Uh I don’t know if you touch
what I on Scada protocols before
but what it looks like, there
problems with those protocols um
basically most protocols today
are derived from legacy serial
networks so if you’re old enough
you might remember those RS-485
networks where you hook up a
bunch of devices on the serial
cable and all the devices
receive the same message and
decide if they want to accept it
or not. This is great for
hacking right. Uh you just
listen to the bus and you get
everything. Uh there’s no
authentication of course.
There’s no integrity and when I
mean integrity I’m not talking
about error correction I’m
talking about if someone tampers
the message is that gonna be uh
uh figured out at the other end
or not. So they don’t have any
integrity mechanisms and there’s
no confidentiality so the
message goes um on on-on-on the
field with no um no
confidentiality which means it
it goes in plain text right. So
the most popular Scada protocol
is modbus. It’s about 90 percent
of the PLCs support that.
Actually I haven’t found any PLC
that does not support modbus.
They usually support their own
protocol plus something else
plus modbus. Everybody talks
modbus. And uh in essence modbus
is very simple. There’s nothing
very complicated with that. Uh
it’s of course based on serial
networks and uh the commands
basically how it works is that
the commands for the the
protocol are encoded into
function codes. SO you have
different function codes for
different things you want to do.
And it’s open. That’s probably
why everyone supports modbus
because it doesn’t require any
licensing. You can go and pay
modbus foundation to have your
device certified os that they
make sure your device is
actually following in the full
standards but you don’t have to
do that to support the protocol.
There’s no licensing right
licensing fee. Uh and this is
the modbus frame that’s how what
it looks like. Basically it has
the first byte is a slave ID. Uh
and the slave ID is a unique
address because it was based on
serial networks so you have to
have a way to address the
device. The function code is
what what I was talking about.
It tells the slave device what
to do, it it's like the command
it should obey right. And the
function code varies from
reading or writing to more
memory areas. Data, well data is
data, right. It depends on the
function code you’re using. And
finally CRC uh it is just error
correction verification. Again
this does not check integrity of
the message itself it’s just
checking if there are any
physical errors that happened on
the transmission right. If
somebody can tamper this frame,
change the date recalculates the
CRC and send it through it will
go right it will be accepted by
the PLC. So those are the most
used function codes. Um there is
um function codes to read
digital output, to read digital
inputs, and also to read and
write registers. Basically all
it is is working with memory. So
modbus gives you free access to
the PLC memory you can read
whatever you want you can write
whatever you want with no
authentication. Who loves that?
Right. Uh they updated modbus to
make it compatible with TCPIP
networks, what it mean is that
they added a frame on top of the
modbus frame so basically it has
a transaction ID to keep track
of all the transactions you’re
making so if the host makes a
transaction it makes a random
number on that transaction ID so
when it receives a response it
might receive a bunch of
response from the same slave
device and uh it will match the
transaction ID to make sure that
response is related to the query
it was making. Uh protocol ID it
seems that originally modbus on
TCP was meant to work on other
protocols as well so they
created this field so that
different values on that field
will mean different protocols.
I’ve never seen anybody using
anything different than 00. And
00 stands for modbus so I think
they failed on this. Uh length
is length. [laughs] Right. How
many bytes there are after it.
And after that is just plain uh
serial modbus frame as it was
before. They kept the slave ID
byte on that frame because some
people will just convert between
TCIP networks and serial
networks. So you have all
devices talking serial and new
devices talking TCP so keeping
that byte over there means that
serial devices will also be able
to receive that message, right.
Even though if they are
addressed on TCP. Uh for TCP
only PLCs usually that that bye
means nothing. They will accept
anything. Attack scenarios. What
can we do with this? So you can
create a few a few different
attacks on that. Because the
message is so simple you can
just interrupt the communication
cause a denial of service and
there are many ways to do that.
Uh you can intercept the message
and read the contents because
there’s no encryption no uh um
confidentiality at all. You can
also modify the message. You get
the message you get uh uh bump
in the wire or some sort of
ether cap R poisoning hack and
you you get the message since
its plain text you modify the
contents send it back yeah. That
is pretty disastrous. And my
favorite. Injection. You can
only just send a freaking frame.
The PLC will accept you right.
It accepts everybody. So let’s
demo it. Hopefully it will work.
So I have here ScadaBR. And uh
let me start the last PLC I
didn’t have the time to do it.
Um. Hopefully I will now uh let
me get back to ScadaBR. So this
is ScadaBr for you to get
familiar with it. Uh it’s it’s
an old tool but it works very
well and I incorporated it into
the whole PLC project so so that
we can update it and and
renovate it over time. So here I
have all my data sources. These
are all my PLCs. So here on the
table I have 3 different PLCs.
The first one here is open PLC
running on unipod platform this
is an industrial platform um the
second one is an Allen-Bradley
micrologics 1400 series and the
third one is um a Schneider
modicon m 221. So let me go
ahead and try to turn them all
on. Hopefully they they’re good.
Okay. So let me start this PLC
as well. In the meantime while
this thing is starting let me
show you the graphical screen
and see how it looks like. So
these um this screen shows my my
system my setup here. So what I
have as I said before I have a
cup filled with water and um a
water heater element inside it
and a temperature sensor right.
The temperature sensor is
connected to the PLC. So I have
3 identical setups. And since
PLCs love ladder logic I just
created the same ladder logic
for all the same 3 PLCs. So they
are running identical logic
programs. Of course each
architectural just
inter-interprets that logic
differently internally right.
Some will compile that to binary
code that’s a case for Open PLC.
Some will just convert that to
virtual machine that will just
run uh interpreted instructions.
Um so it varies by vendor but
they all in essence doing the
same logic. I just copy paste
the same ladder diagram to make
sure that they are all running
the same thing, ok? So on that
configuration I have uh
flexibility here that I can set
the PLC for mangual mode uh turn
on the heater if I want manually
so you can see the heater going
up here just a little break to
turn on the PLCs sorry. Um and
uh I can turn the heater off. I
can put it in auto mode so the
auto mode will try to keep the
temperature around 40 degrees
celcius and you know temperature
is a slow thing so it might go
up slowly and go down slowly. Um
but in essence all the PLCs are
trying to keep that around 40
except this third little one
because it’s not on yet. Sorry
about that. Uh let me just log
in here. And in one second I
will turn it on. So my job here
it try to attack these PLCs.
Once I am in in the network I’ll
show you how easy it is to
create a modbus frame and um
attack it. Right? Last click.
Not yet. Uh. Ok. It should be
good to go. Let me start it. Yes
I want. By the way this is
somachine basic this is the
software used to program the
Schneider modicom m221 we will
have a lot of fun with that
software today. Um ok. So let me
start my terminal here. Um. So I
have a injection attack ready.
What this injection attack does
is uh it-it tries to send modbus
packets that will switch the
PLCs in manual mode and keep the
heater on. Right? And this will
this message will be sent over
and over and over again so that
the operator will lose control
of the PLC and will not be able
to turn it off right. So I’ll
start the attack and I’ll this
little attack uh I hate sound.
This little attack has 2
parameters I created this
software by the way everything
is available on my github so if
you wanna get those tools go
ahead you have it. So it has 2
parameters the first one is the
host. So the host is 100 100 100
100 because I’m really bad with
numbers I had to choose a good
one. And uh the other
para-parameter is frequency I
won’t use it the default
frequency is 1000 messages per
second. So let's try that on
open PLC. Go. Alright cool.
Heater is on. Let’s turn it off.
[clicking] Well doesn’t work. So
let’s put in auto mode.
[clicking] It doesn’t work
either! I’m screwed. Right.
[audience laughter] So that’s
probably what the operator will
be thinking. You see the
temperature going up and you
can’t do anything about it. And
all it takes is sending freaking
modbus frames. Right? That’s all
it takes. What I’m doing here is
writing to a portion of the
memory to the PLC that I know
its its storing the setting for
manual or auto mode and the
other area that is storing the
setting for the heater if it’s
on or off. That’s all it takes.
Right. And I can guarantee you
that this kind of attack works
with 100% of the PLCs that I
know of. [Chuckles] Right? Um so
ok. Let’s stop this because I
have boiling water already. And
let me put back on auto mode and
we’ll shut off the heater. Now
let’s start try this same thing
with our friend Allen-Bradley.
It is at the same IP except 101.
I know I’m bad with numbers. So
let’s try that again. Boom. Oh
gosh no. It’s on. [clicking]
Doesn't work. Right. Auto mode
does not work. Temperature will
go up. And uh yeah. It it works
the same way you see different
brand of PLC freaking same
modbus protocol that’s the
culprit ok. Let me stop this.
Auto mode again. Last time last
attack lets try that on the
Schneider modicom please
misbehave. Ok it’s on even
though the temperature is also
over the set point. [clicking]
It does not work either. Right.
So um that’s how simple it is.
You can today start creating
your own PLC attacks. Ok let me
stop this. Now um this was this
was pretty fun and uh I had a
lot of fun creating this but I
have one more thing. For those
of you who are fan of Steve Jobs
this is where the best part
happens right. So let’s talk
about micrologics. Micrologics
is a PLC from Allen-Bradley. Um
and Rocco Automation I don’t
know the history who bought who
but they keep both names and so
I just say both names. But
what-what are the fun facts
about micrologics 1400 series
you should be buying one today
to hack it’s pretty fun device.
Right so first of all it runs
VxWorks. VxWorks is one of the
most popular uh real time
operating systems on the
industry it’s on everything
right including PLCs and there
are a bunch of vulnerabilities
reported for that device. Guess
what? I bet most of those works
with Allen-Bradley as well.
Right? It is one of the most
popular Allen-Bradley PLC uh you
see that everywhere and it
supports modbus TCP that’s why
the injection attack works. Uh
this is my favorite feature. It
can be killed remotely by
sending a bad modbus packet.
This is great. So um let me talk
about this what I called
micrologics deadly packets.
Basically all it takes uh it’s a
trick the memory [indiscernible]
memory allocation algorithm of
the um micrologics PLC. So what
I do is I start a new
transaction ID uh protocol of
course it uh um modbus 00 and on
the length field I say I’m I’m I
will need 20 256 bytes right.
But I only have 6. Uh alright.
So it might try to allocate that
much memory but it’s only
receiving less than that. And
right immediately after I start
a new transaction ID where the
length is the length of the
previous packet and its
incomplete. It stops at the unit
ID. So it makes the PLC confused
with this memory management
system and I cause a buffer
overflow writing that that uh
message on a different area of
the device crashing the device
and making it unrecoverable. So
let’s try to do that. Ok.
Alright. So just to check here I
should have everybody running
wow I left that PLC on for too
long. [laughter from audience]
Alright uh so we’re targeting
Allen-Bradley now it should be
working fine its all just put on
manual mode to prove like the
heater is on, the heater is off,
everything should work
beautifully. Auto mode should
keep the heater off. Let me just
keep that on heater on so that
iwll be more fun . Uh let me go
it’s hard to type when you’re uh
hands are shaking. [laughter
from audience] uh should be
Allen-Bradley exploit. This is
also available on my github um
so all the only argument it
takes is the IP address of the
PLC. So all it does it send
those 2 deadly packets and lets
see what happens when I do it.
Dead. So you’ll see right now
that the PLC is not
communicating anymore. You see
the exclamation point all
around? Ha dead. How cool is
that right? [audience applause]
You can even try to press the
buttons over there it’s
completely dead and you know the
fun fact of it is if you if you
power cycle it still dead.
[audience laughter] I’ll prove
it. I just power cycled it and
it will boot again it managed to
boot again but the fault LED
keeps on for some reason. So
yeah it it it is booting up and
you still see the exclamation
points here you wil see it til
the end of the presentation. So
the point the problem is that
that application got corrupted
so the PLC cannot launch it
again. Uh the fault mode is
always on. The only way to make
it work again si to reprogram it
with the ladder logic. This is
creepy right. So um if you lost
the ladder logic you screwed.
Please don’t send it on uh the
wild. There are too many
micrologics PLCs out there. Uh
alright. Let’s behave. Um ok let
me see if I have something else.
Uh this is um a problem that
affects all micrologics 1400
series. I don’t know about
others because I’m not rich to
buy all the PLCs but I bet it
also affects some other related
series like 1100 and so. Uh I
talked to Allen-Bradley through
ICS-CERT to publish this
vulnerability and uh they are
really nice they responded back
and tried to work with me to
create a patch so they uh they
released recently about few
months ago a firmware update uh
this firmware update fixes this
vulnerability although it’s a
pain to update it. I spent like
half an hour trying to do that
and um I’m supposed to be a
security expert. Imagine people
out in the field what they will
do to try to update this thin
they won’t right. They won’t
stop their factory to update
their PLC firmwares. Hopefully
the new PLCs that will be sell
sold now will have this new
update uh already built in. Uh
there are other mitigations
where please disable modbus TCP.
This is not a fix. Dude if
you’re disabling the protocol
you’re not fixing it you’re just
disabling it uh right. So this
mentality is common for all the
PLC vendors that I usually talk
to. Uh minimize network
exposure. Put PLCs behind a
firewall. So basically what what
they are telling you is the
security is on you right we
don’t provide security. You’re
freaking alone. So try to do
your best. Um these are good
practices but I honestly believe
that a PLC the device itself
should provide any sort of
security. And one last thing.
Alright. Schneider that’s
there’s a special reason why I
brought the Schneider PLC with
me. Um the Scheider has a
protocol that is common to all
the modicom family and I think
other families also use this.
It’s called unity protocol at
least me and some other
researches are working with this
call it unity. Or UMAS you might
hear both names. And this
protocol is obscure. It is
undocumented. It runs on top of
modbus TCP so you have normal
modbus transaction uh but when
you have function code 0X5A the
access decimal over 5A this
triggers the subprotocol that
runs on the data field of the
modbus frame and uh the for the
modbus documentation 5A is uh
reserved function code for
specific vendors, specific um
functions right. Uh and this is
nice part. This protocol is used
to configure and monitor the PLC
down to the operating system
level. You can do a total memory
dump using this protocol right.
You can get the freaking
operating system image using
that. So this is this is crazy
right. Um it’s proprietary and
undocumented um so they try to
make secure by obscurity but
that won’t prevent us from
figuring that out how it works.
So um basically you need to have
a bunch of function codes so
it’s a functon code insde a
function code right. You have
the modbus frame and then you
have the unity frame and these
are uh the function codes you
can play with. And I have to
thank Luis Liras uh he um is a
researcher on the same field we
started talking and
communicating like uh one year
ago because i figured he was
working on the unity devices as
well and we started contributing
to each other and he has a very
nice blog liras en la red dot
xyz if you go if you want you
can go and check it out he has
step by step how he managed to
get those function codes and
reverse engineer the DLLs for
the somachine basic and get that
information so this is pretty
cool and uh basically you can
take a look at some um messages
here um they’re pretty cool like
read memory block. [speaker
chuckles] This is my favorite.
Ok so um but today given the
time constraint we’ll only play
with a few of those so basically
uh we’ll start a communication
an ed communication we’ll read a
project info to reap some data
about the project uh this is all
so cool take PLC reservation. It
means that the PLC needs to be
connected to someone. Someone
needs to reserve the PLC uh if
you take the PLC reservation
you’re taking the other party
down. This is DOS built in the
protocol dudes. [audience
laughs] This is what? Right? So
you just keep setting this take
PLC reservation and I think
nobody else can connect so um
release PLC reservation you’re
uh releasing it because you just
don’t want to communicate
anymore and um um start PLC and
stop PLC will basic main
functions to start and stop the
PLC. Alright. So um let’s play
with it. I’ll just keep this
slide open so we can play a
little bit with how it works. Is
that up? Ok. So I created also a
little software m-modicum tester
I don’t remember the name of the
executable. Ok. So this is
software was created in C sharp
in a hurry. Please don’t look at
the code it’s messy. But the
good thing is it works. Uh and
all I did was created this thing
to help me reverse engineer the
protocols so it basically
encapsulates my messages on the
modbus frame with the function
code 5a so I can send anything
and it will be accepted as unity
messages right. So all you do
you connect to the PLC it’s
already set up with the uh m221
IP address. I connect and then
it gives me the access decimal
output and the access key
related to that. So let’s start
by starting our communication so
every function code has uh 2
bytes. 0001 and I’ll end it with
00. So it just gave me back a hi
I’m here that’s fine. Hello. So
let’s go ahead and uh release
PLC reservation if somebody was
talking to it sorry and I’ll
take the reservation. Ten zero
zero. And now the take
reservation is an interesting
thing. I don’t know if you can
see it sorry I should have make
it bigger but I’ll promise I’ll
read it right. Uh the message is
is sending me back with the take
PLC reservation it-it ends with
a magic byte. In this case it’s
8e. Right it’s even smaller for
me. So 8e means it’s this magic
byte that I need to send before
an message that I want to send
now on now that I have a session
I have a reservation I have
reserved the PLC for me uh I’ll
have to use this magic byte.
That means that um before people
were trying to do replay attacks
so the replay attacks would be
successful just because they
didn’t’ have any session
management so you could just get
messages that the uh the main
station was sending and just
replay that and it will work.
Now you need the session number
but that won’t prevent us from
sending stuff. Right? So now
let’s let’s play with this. I
have 8e as my session number um
you can see here oh urgent
Allen-Bradley’s not talking
still. Sorry. Sorry dude. You
can see that the modicum is
still working fine. Temperature
is 40 degrees celcius I can turn
the heater on manually and off
right. It works. So um what I'll
do here I will send a stop PLC
command so I need to start with
my 8e. And then the stop message
is 41. It ends with FF00. And
lets see. Stopped. Now the PLC
can still communicate but the
heater is off. I cannot turn it
on. I cannot turn it off. I
cannot put it on auto or manual
mode. It’s off. How cool is
that? [audience laughs] So uh
just by sending a few messages,
I can uh have few control of the
PLC. But here comes my favorite
feature of this protocol. This
is really interesting. So I’m
gonna use the somachine basic
here for a second. Let me just
create something new. So I’m
just using their application to
talk to the PLC over here.
Right. And uh when I click here
it already identified my PLC I
try to log in and it’s trying to
log in but this application is
password protected. How come? So
I cannot access my PLC without
the password if I try to type
anything um it won’t give me
access right? Alright. What can
we do about it? Ok. Let me get
back to my unity tester here. So
remember that message read
project info? For some reason
that thing doesn’t even require
a session. So I’ll go ahead and
send this zero zero new session
zero three is the function code
for that and zero zero. Zero
zero is just get the header um
so let’s see what comes out of
it. My header for the project
that is stored on the PLC and
this is the name of the project.
What is this? Yes. The freaking
password. [audience laughter and
applause] Right? So if I were
Steve Jobs and I was working at
Schneider I would say this is
not a bug it’s a feature.
[audience laughter] What if you
forgot the password? The device
needs to tell you that. Right?
So let’s try it. Defcon is my
password. So when I type Defcon.
Boom! I mean super hard. Right?
Now I have full control of the
PLC again using their own
software just because I stole
the password. And it works. I’ve
tried with different uh slightly
different types of modicoms m m
something serious and uh the
same thing works. So yeah you
can play with that uh I can
start the control of it because
I stopped it before and I can
see the programming on it uh
yeah. I have full access. So
this is pretty hilarious. Um now
that’s to show you how secure
PLC is and imagine that those
things are controlling your
nuclear power plants and your
water filtration systems.
[Speaker sighs] I’ll just go
live in a jungle. So Schneider
also they were also really nice.
I submitted this through
ICS-CERT and they talk with me
and we try to come up with some
mitigations and they they
recommended the following
things. Disable unity protocol.
[audience laughter] This is the
best mitigation ever. So again
you see a different vendor with
the same mentality. Just turn
that freaking thing off. It
doesn't work. Right? They also
recommended because of that
password vulnerability and all
all of that they recommended to
store your project files in
secure access re-restricted
locations and encrypt your
project files reputable third
party file encryption tools.
Again they’re giving you the
responsibility to fix stuff, to
to secure your settings. Um and
this is pretty uh it gets me
worried right. And a little bit
about that what I plan to do on
the future um by the way I
haven’t showed you this. This is
what open PLC looks like. This
is a web interface that is
running on the device so once
installed the one time you have
that interface up and you can
see your programs uh you can see
your hardware you can even mess
up with the code live right so
it’s pretty cool. Um and uh this
thing is also vulnerable and
insecure I created it to be like
that because I’m trying to mimic
what other vendors are doing so
we can kinda research about it
but um my PhD thesis is about
creating a secure version of
open PLC that uh will try to
prevent those types of attacks
from happening ok. So it was
really fun to be here at Defcon
today um it was really an honor
to me to be here and thank you
very much for coming and staying
with me this Saturday morning.
If anybody have any questions
[applause from audience].