>>I’d like to introduce first
time speaker William Martin in
his talk ‘One Click to OWA’
[Applause] >>Thank you, Cars.
[Applause]. >> [behind the mic]
Let me see if I can maximize it.
[Pause with mic interference]
cool. >> So as Cars said, my
name is William Martin, and er,
I’m OSCP, I’m a pen tester for
RSM US and I’m based out of
Charlotte, and you know first
time speaker at DefCon so no
pressure. >>[audience member]
whoo! >>Oh, thank you. Ah, if
you can’t see me back there, I’m
the one on the right. [sniggers]
and we only get 20 minutes so so
we’re kinda blow through this.
Ah, we’re gonna talk about
basics on Exchange and the
various endpoints on Exchange .
Ah, we’re going to go through a
little bit of multi-factor
authentication crash course on
how it’s typically set up, uh
which will kinda emphasize some
gaps that some organizations
face. Ah, then I’m going to talk
about my favorite attack, which
is the NTLM Relay attack, uh
we’re going to do a demo and a
tool release and and then we’re
going to talk about how to fix
the things we just broke. So,
overall, organizations have been
doing a pretty kick-ass job in
terms of implementing
multi-factor authentication
across the board for their
externally facing services, like
VPNs definitely, our mo desktop
services, citrix, um web apps,
and email, with an asterix on
email, we’re going to get to
that one. Um, OWA is typically
where we see a lot of two factor
being implemented but there’s a
little bit of a break in
mentality on the goal of
multi-factor authentication on
OWA. Um, I don’t know about most
of you, but, I have email synced
to my phone, I have take a
gamble at least 60 percent, 70
percent of this room also have
that scenario - um, for
themselves. Um, but when I was
working in an organization I
found that I was using
multi-factor authentication on
our OWA portal, but my phone was
syncing just fine with just my
username and password, with no
other, no other factor, no
certification, um, no code,
nothing. So that felt a bit
weird. It seemed
counterintuitive for the point
of multi-factor authentication.
So, to find out why that gap
exists, I realised I had to
learn a little bit more about
how my phone and my Outlook are
connecting to Exchange. And
that’s what we’re gonna talk
about. So, for those haven’t set
up an Exchange server
themselves, Exchange, er, has
multiple roles in which it can
be installed. There’s a mail
server role, there’s an edge
transport role, um and all these
kinda dictate how the server’s
going to operate. The role we
care about it is called the
Client Access Server role. It’s
the one we interacts with when
talking to our email, that’s
things like er auto discover for
telling us how to connect to our
email, a MAPI in which is how
outlook connects in, er and OWA
and ECP um which are the focus
of this. So, Exchange cas
servers run essentially on top
of a IAS server, there’s one
large web app and accessing them
looks a bit like this. So all
over https, all over http, just
standard web calls. Now, to
break down what these little
endpoints do, and the various
ways you can talk to Exchange,
there is PowerShell, which is
used by administrators to kinda
administer the server itself.
Auto discover tells their client
how to connect to exchange, MAPI
is used by Outlook, RPC is used
by old school Outlook, ah,
activesync used by your phone
typically. Ah, OAB provides your
client a way to er download the
global address book, so it
takes, it kinda eases the burden
on Exchange. ECP, is er in
addition to OWA which allows a
user to kinda change their
settings or where you’re going
when changing your signature and
forwarding rules and what-not um
on your OWA and then not to beat
a dead horse, OWA itself, the
web app lets you to access your
email, access your tasks, manage
your calendar, um and what-not
from the web without having to
look, run a thick client. And
then finally, EWS or Exchange
Web Services, if they soap-based
API that allows you to interact
with Exchange and make API based
calls with your mailbox. So,
allows like old school apps or
um, or the ma- the Outlook
client from MAC is based on EWS.
So, the endpoint is what hackers
care about are the ones that
allow access to the email. So
that will be MAPI, RPC, Acce-
Activesync, ECP, OWA and EWS.
Now, as a pentester,
interestingly enough, the ones I
find covered by 2 factor
authentication most often, are
only these two: OWA and Exchange
Control Panel. Which leaves at
least 4 other ways we can access
our email what-not without that
code. So, to find out why, I
mean, not to get ahead of
myself, I’m by far not the first
one to find this gap, other have
been other security researchers
like noblely Black Hill
Information Security that have
found this kind of gap, this
inconsistency on the
implementation of multi-factor
authentication protecting
exchange. And like 2016 20- yes
2016 they reported this to
Microsoft and said ‘Hey, this is
a gap - are you guys going to
fix it?’ Microsoft replied,
saying No. Because this is not
an issue on properly configured
systems. So, I took that as, OK
it’s, it’s the admin’s fault a
check - box wasn’t checked. They
didn’t add a route, um some- you
know it was just a human error
causing this thing, it wasn’t a
technological failure. So,
because it was so prevalent, I
wanted to find out what was
causing such a-a pervasive human
error, um wha- wha- what would
cause all these organizations to
see this gap consistently. And
answer is - there really isn’t
any mention of these other
endpoints in those two factor
authentication ah protocols
implementations. So things like
semantic, RSA, um a little bit
of Duo in their basic
implementation guides they would
cover OWA and ECP both of which
are the only two web app based
protocols. And the reason that
is, is because a lot of these
protocols are authenticating
through something called ADFS or
Active Directory Federation
Services. Will that be ruining
the talk to talk about what that
is? Um, in a nutshell, it
provides a way for users to
authenticate to this one server,
through whatever means they
choose like multi-factor and
then this server will provide
that user with a cookie which
will vouch to other single
silent servers. So when you go
a-a protected OWA you’re talking
to this other server that says,
you know, William logged in,
he’s cool, just trust me. That
trust gets passed to Exchange
and I’m able to log into OWA
even though Exchange didn’t
handle most of the
authentication. So, the issue
lies in that, that whole
exchange happens over HTTP,
happens over like web app based
um protocol, um, but EWS and
MAPI and RCP and those lower
levels can’t handle that kind of
interaction, so that causes a
bit of an issue. This is what it
kinda looks like when you log in
to OWA through an ADFS protected
setup. Um, you try to access
OWA, you get that redirect,
saying No contact ADFS first,
ADFS is actually the one that
authenticates you. It says, hey,
log in, maybe use your two
factor code, or maybe er, give
me your-your certificate, prove
who you are. If using
multi-factor, it’ll path that
code off and say to its
multi-factor authentication
provider, again like semantic
and say, hey, is this code good
and it’ll say Yes or No.
Anyways, after that’s done, ADFS
will pass you back your token or
your cookie, you then take that
over to OWA and you’re good to
go. So, vendors know that
solutions aren’t covering these
underlying protocols. This is
not, they’re not oblivious to
this, um the issue is not so
much on the vendors themselves,
as they’ve stated. It lies on
the environment they’re
implementing their solution on
and to implement their solution
properly, they need something
called modern authentication -
ah, which if you’ve got an
Exchange environment on premises
take a bit of er er overhead to
implement. So, modern
authentication, in a nutshell,
is Microsoft’s implementation of
the OAuth’s protocol and allows
Outlook EWS mapping and other
protocols to er handle OAuth’s
tokens. Now, with OAuth,
Exchange is no longer handling
the authentication phase of it,
even through single sign on like
through ADFS, OAuth just passes
Exchange her token and says
‘clear you’re good to go’. The
OAuth provider is the one that
really implements those two
factor solutions or whatever
else what may it be. Um, but the
catch is with mod
authentication, you need to
implement Azure in some way
shape or form. You can’t just
spin up a DC on prem, spin up an
Exchange server on prem, spin up
an ADFS server on prem and be
good to go. You have to interact
with Office 365 somehow, and
it’s that catch that leaves a
lot of organizations in the
dark. Vulnerable to this kind of
um, lack of coverage. So when
you’re implemented with Exchange
on prem, you need to use
something called hybrid modern
authentication. It requires an
on prem ADFS and it requires you
to use Outlook 2013 or later and
you’re using Azure to perform
all of the token er
provisioning. ER, with pure
Office 365, guys, when you’re,
when you’re using Exchange
online, you already support
modern Auth because it’s all
going through Office 365
anyways, um it just comes down
to what kind of multi-factor
authentication you want to
implement through this now
supported protocol. And this is
what it looks like when you have
a hybrid setup. So, anyways, now
we know that the gap that these
two factor solutions cause is
not a quick, easy fix. And I
love that, because it makes it a
pain in the ass for my targets
to cover theirs. So, while we
can, how can we take advantage
of this gap? How can we take
advantage of this oversight.
Well, looking back at those
other endpoints you can talk to
that are typically unprotected?
There’s a common theme amongst
three of them. Before doing this
research, I didn’t know I didn’t
know that three of them use NTLM
which is my favourite
authentication mechanism. So,
[laughter] that’s my point. So
also the first meme I’ve ever
made. Um, so NTLM attack is my
favourite relay until I pop
maybe 80 to 90 percent of my
internal pentest, um it’s a
terribl- it’s an attack as old
as time itself, um the cult of
the dead clap, uh, the cult of
the dead clap were exploiting
this as early as 2001. So, for
those who don’t know the NTLM
relay attack happens through 3
messages. It works like this:
the victim is somehow tricked to
connect to an attacker. And
we’ll talk about how they’re
tricked in a second. But they
connect to an attack and say,
hey, i want to log in. Here’ my
domain, here’s my username. The
attacker that redirects that
say’s, ‘okay, I wanna login,
here’s my domain and username’
The target server will reply
saying: alright cool, if you are
really so and so, take the
challenge and hash your password
with it. We don’t know the
password as an attacker, so
we’ll pass that right back to
the victim. The victim will
happily oblige and pass that
back. S’now the attacker has the
response we path that on to our
target server, target server
probably says, OK cool, you’ve
now authenticated, you are so
and so. The attacker gets the
session and we kill out victim.
We say No, you weren’t able to
log in. So, the ways to trigger
NTLM authentication are vast, um
some of the common ways and
favourite ways are UNC links and
emails, which if you open an
email in Outlook and you click a
UNC link, Outlook treats that -
it really passes on to Windows
and that - And Windows treats
that a , like you’re trying to
access a network share and per
network shares, it will try to
authenticate, try to login, try
to open that folder for you.
Well, if the attacker’s on the
other end of that UNC path,
it’ll authenticate to them and
that triggers the NTLM relay
attack. My other favourite way
is NTLM, er, ah - sorry, net
bios and O and MR poisoning,
which, does anyone use
responders? Show of hands? Yeah,
fair number of us. So, so it
never fails to get a hash, um,
for those who don’t use
Responder, it’s a tool hackers
use to abuse how Windows works,
when windows asks for a
resource, which isn’t available
through DNS it will then send a
broadcast to the local network
saying , hey, has anyone seen, I
don’t know, William’s share? And
typically there’ll be
radio-silence, but an attacker
will say, yeah, I’m William’s
share. And then the victim will
say, oh cool, alright let me log
into you. And then, that’s how
you get the NTOM hash. Recently
I’ve seen some really cool
wa-ways to trigger NTLM
authentication that I think are
worth mentioning. Er, so
recently there was a CV pushed
out by will Dorman, which he
found that Outlook, you could
sent an RTF, or a rich text
formatted email and when Outlook
received that email, it would
parse it and if that RTF email
had, er I know I’m getting
really technical, but if erthat
RTF email had a remote resource
embedded in it, Outlook would
try to unlikely load that that
and pass it to Windows and then
Windows would authenticate to it
if it’s a UNC path um and this
is all without user auth- um,
intervening without any kind of
warnings. So essentially you
sent an email, they open it and
they - you already get their
hash. Um Microsoft patched that
one, but er we all know that one
patch is everything
appropriately so nothing to
worry about there. So, um, -
there’s a way not patch -
difficult to patch by Mike’s
fell - Mike you’re in the room?
Ah, man, he said he was coming.
Alright, so. Long and short, an
attacker can modify the details
of a Microsoft document and
embed UNC path in the settings,
so when a Microsoft word opens
that document it’ll see a little
UNC path in the web settings, it
treats that a an external HTML
page that you wanna embed in
your document so, as always,
it’ll try and reach out get that
and share it and pass it to
Windows and Windows will
authenticate. This one there is
no user interaction whatsoever
outside of opening a document.
So, if you find that UNC links
are filtered in Kmail and you
can’t get like a map go through,
you might get like a benign
document through their email
system and get them to show HTML
authentication that way. So now
we know these are protect by
NTLM and we can relay to NTLM,
which one do I attack? Well, a
couple years a go, er, SensePost
came out with an attack called
the Ruler attack. Which took
advantage of Outlook rules. In a
nutshell, the Outlook thick
client on a desktop can be
configured to run certain
commands a -upon receiving an
email, sending an email, upon a
certain event happening. And so
Ruler found out that if you
compromise a users credentials
from the outside, you could
create a new Outlook rule, sync
it up with their server. That
rule will then be pushed down to
Exchange Outlook clients and
then that rule would run upon
that event happening. So, um,
naturally I thought: great I can
get RCE with a relay, let’s
let’s use that. That’s what
Ruler looks like. Unfortunately,
one of the creators of Ruler
already had this idea and turns
out, to perform the true, true
authentic Ruler attack, you have
to authenticate to Exchange more
than a few times and NT the NTLM
relay attack is pretty much a
won and done, so you not really
gonna get that far using a MAPi
or a RCP which is what Ruler is
based on. So I just left this
guy, Exchange web services which
I - 5 already? Chr**t! Alright,
which I never heard of until I
built this tool, until I ran
this attack, so in a nutshell,
Exchange web services is just a
way to act as exchange to an API
and the things we care about is
that it’s enabled by default and
by on premise exchange it
supports NTLM by default and
provides access to most things
Outlook provides access to. And
we don’t have to go through
multiple stages of
authentication with NTLM on EWS,
it’s won and done. So I built a
tool called ExchangeRelayx which
has these goals in mind. If we
pop a user we want them, we
wanna to be able to read, send,
delete, you know, manage their
inbox as they would. We want to
be able to download their
attachments, er add forwarding
rules to kinda backdoor their
email. Scrape as much data as we
can from that directory and
launch phishing from inside
their organization. Typically,
orgs have great ah attachment
filtering on prem on the
perimeter but from user to user
from inside the organization
they have that gap, so if you
compromise the exchange of one
user you might be able to send
users BC and D er malicious
attachments without being
filtered through. Alright. Now
try and power through a demo.
[Pause] This demo’s going to a
show a OWA that’s protected with
2 factor authentication but is
vulnerable to the same gaps we
covered. [Pause]. Now being
prompted for the code. [Pause
and interference on mic].
[Cough] [Long pause] Enter
through and there’s your usual,
ah, Outlook web interface. You
got the emails. You can see that
the user we’re on is er William
Martin - that’s me. Er, we’ve
got folder there on the left
called Modern Auth Project.
Going to open the user’s Outlook
thick client just to demonstrate
the same thing. [Pause].
Alright, cool. So we’re actually
gonna launch the attack. Tool’s
called ExchangeRelayX and right
now we’re just going to check if
the system is vulnerable. Right
now it just reaches out to the
mail and says, hey do you
support NTLM? And turns out - we
do. So let’s build a relay to
that NTLM interface, let’s build
a relay to Exchange web
services. [Pause]. Alright. This
is showing sending a sample UNC
link to a victim. And we’re
masking it as a Youtube link.
[Pause] And I’m skipping through
some of the loading times in the
demo because we’re tight on
time. [Pause]. Alright, user
gets the er the phishing email -
that malicious link in there.
They click it and that’s all the
user has to do. The attack is
now done on their end. Over here
we receive the connection, we
relayed it back to their
Exchange server and we see them
popped right there. So, what can
we do with this? I tried to
build a similar looking OWA for
hackers. So, now you see we can
open up their email, we still
got the same er little folder on
the left that they do, and by
the way, as we’re reading email
and sending email we’re not
showing up in their sent folder.
>>Man, you’re killing me Cars.
>>So, I’m gonna release this
tool and you guys can have a lot
of fun with it but we kinda have
to blow through what you can do.
One of the features is that you
can - ah, add forwarding rules
as well as you can ah unlikely
download all of their
attachments, so just cycle
through inbox, sent folder,
everything and just as quickly
as you can, download every
attachment they’ve ever sent or
received. So if you have a user
that’s not super technical,
maybe their CFO and they get
popped, that’s a really bad day.
So. [Applause]. Stop applauding
we have to move through! So, er
how we fixed this you implement
modern authentication across
your organization - oh man,
modern authentication
everywhere, er you have to
implement Azure with that. RCP
won’t be able to support that,
same thing with POP3 and IMAP,
if you have any 20 10s anywhere
this will not work for you you
cannot get modern auth with
2010s environment. Um, yeah.
Implement MFA everywhere, filter
on 1-3-9-4-4-5 and er remember
that split tunnel VPNs and IVP6
are typically a gap. Alright,
here are the contributors. Sorry
for the rush through. [Sigh].
[Applause].