>>Hi! So my name is Alexei
Bulazel. I’m here to present my
research on Reverse Engineering
Windows Defender’s Antivirus
Emulator. Little bit about me
before we get started. I am a
security researcher at
ForAllSecure. You may know the
company from their victory at
the Cyber Grand Challenge 2
years ago at Defcon 24 with the
Mayhem CRS. I also do firmware
reverse engineering and cyber
policy at River Loop Security.
And I’m a very proud almunist at
RPI and RPISEC. They’re playing
over in the CTF right now and I
wanna say good luck guys!
[audience applauds] And this is
my first time speaking at Defcon
so it’s great to be here. Uh,
this work is my personal
research and uh, it is my own
views, not those of my employers
or anyone else I’ve previously
worked for. Before I get started
I do wanna say this presentation
is a deeply technical look at
reverse engineering Windows
Defender’s binary emulator. And
as far as I know, the first
conference talk to really look
at reverse engineering the
antivirus emulator uh, for any
AV product. It’s not an
evaluation of Windows Defender.
I’m not going to tell you this
is a good product you should use
in your network or not. I’m not
gonna tell you whether it
catches viruses uh, effectively
relative to other AV’s or
anything like that. And also
this talk does not address
Windows Defender ATP, or any
other technologies under the
Windows Defender name. This is
about Windows Defender
Antivirus, the traditional
endpoint AV product. So an
outline of this talk. Gonna go
through an introduction. Then
talk about my tooling and
process, how I did what I did.
Then reverse engineering and the
real meat of the presentation. A
bit of vulnerability research,
and then we will conclude. So,
why look at Windows Defender
Antivirus? Uh, this is
Microsoft’s built in AV product
that uh, is installed by default
on all Windows systems. Um,
Windows 10, it runs by default.
Which means that over 50 percent
of Windows 10 systems have
Windows Antivirus running. Uh,
the Defender name now seems to
cover a variety of mitigations
and security controls built into
Microsoft uh, OS, OS’s. So you
have, you know, control flow
guard, EMET, ATP. All these
different things now get lumped
under, you know, Windows
Defender, Device Guard Windows
Defender, Application Guard
Windows Defender, Exploit Guard
and so forth. Again, here we’re
focused on Windows Defender
Antivirus. And it also runs
unsandboxed as NT authority
system. Meaning that if you
found a vulnerability inside
Defender uh, that would give you
initial RCE, if you could
exploit that. It would also give
you a PrivEsc up the system, and
you’d be running inside an AV
process. So the AV would be
unlikely to catch you doing
anything malicious cause it’s
not gonna flag itself say, doing
some malicious writing a file,
injecting another process and so
forth. It’s also surprisingly
easy for attackers to reser, to
reach. I’ve not tried this
myself, but friends of mine at
Google Project 0 have uh, told
me that you can send an
executable to someone who has a
G mail account open, and if they
have that G mail open in a
background tab uh, Chrome, uh,
the Chrome browser will cache
the downloaded file that just
hits the inbox that’ll hit like,
a mini filter driver in the
Windows OS, and then the file
that’s written to desk will be
passed off to Defender to be
rescanned. So you can actually
reach this in a remote fashion
um, even though you would think
this is a traditional host based
uh, protection system. My
motivation came from uh, this
tweet, from Tavis Ormandy at
Google Project 0 who, about a
year ago, found uh, some
vulnerabilities in Defenders
JavaScript engine with Natalie
Silvanovich, also of Project 0.
And I had a background
reversing, in reverse
engineering antivirus software.
Did some work we called AV Leak
with Jeremy Blackthorne who’s
here in the audience, uh, a
couple years ago down at that
black hat and woot. Uh, but I
never actually analyzed Windows
Defender and I always wanted to.
And I also had this interest in
JavaScript engines. So I took on
Defender and looked at the
Javascript engine for about 4
months, then presented that work
and moved on to reverse
engineering the windows
emulator, which I’m on here, I’m
here to talk about today. So our
target is mp engine dot dll.
This is the main dll that
provides uh, Windows Defender’s
scanning functionality. It’s a
very large binary it’s about 12
legabytes large. Um, and again,
this is not the part of Defender
that’s say, doing hooking for
system calls or uh, filtering,
you know, disc rights. This is
the main scanning engine, this
you take a buffer of data, and
you say this is malicious or
it’s not malicious. That’s it’s
purpose. Uh, and inside mp
engine are a variety of scanning
engines. I’m focusing today on
the windows binary emulator,
which is one of many scanning
engines. Before we go into my
work on the windows binary
engine, just wanna quickly recap
what I did reverse engineering
the JavaScript engine. This bit
ly link there will take you to
that presentation. And this was
presented out at RECon Brussels
in Brussels, Belgium back in
February. So, Windows Defender
has a JavaScript engine that’s
used for analysis of potentially
malicious Javascript code and I
reversed it from binary. I used
a custom loader and shell for
dynamic experimentation with uh,
help from Rolf Rolles. So thanks
Rolf! Throughout the Javascript
engine I found AV
instrumentation callbacks that
inform the heuristic antivirus
portion of Defender about
actions that the potentially
malicious JavaScript is taking
that it um, uses to determine if
this is malicious JavaScript or
not. Say, for example, an
exploit. And I also found that
developers seem to prioritize
security at the cost of
performance. So the JavaScript
engine is very paired down,
stripped down, doesn’t have
chitting or many of the other
features and optimizations that
make modern JavaScript engines
fast, on the other hand I found
it to be relatively secure on
the attacks that are supposed to
be relatively paired down.
You’ll see some common themes
like that throughout this
presentation today. As far as
related and prior work goes,
there’s really only a handful of
prior publications on reverse
engineering antivirus software
at all, let alone the emulators
within them. There is of course
the work I mentioned, AV Leak,
which I did with some
collaborators at RPI. Um, some
were for here. Uh, there’s also
book uh, work from
[indiscernible] touching on this
There’s Tavis Ormandy’s work at
Google Project 0. And uh, there
actually are some talks from the
AV industry itself such as, uh,
Mihai uh, Chiriac’s talk from
uh, I believe this was hack dot
lu, uh I think 10 years ago. Uh,
as a AV industry developer
talking about how bit Defenders
emulator works. But really
there’s not been a lot of
offensive work, or work from
people who don’t work in the AV
industry looking at these
systems. I’d also mention that
patents are a great source of
serv, open source intelligence
about how AV’s work. Chris Domas
called that out in his
presentation looking at patents
on X86 processors. Similarly you
can find a lot of patents that
describe, uh, undocumented
functionality within AV’s or how
these particularly complex
mechanisms work. Alright. Moving
in to a background on emulation
itself. So, there’s this
traditional AV model and I think
a lot of people have this idea
about how AV’s may, may work.
Which is that they scan files
and look for known malware
signatures such as file hashes,
sequences of bytes or file
traits. And they might have some
heuristics about, say, imports
or they recognize esthetic MD5
hash, or they recognize a
particular snippet of code
that’s known to be associated
with the given malware family.
Um, but this is really an
outdated model. And this is an
outdated model, you know, 15, 20
years ago this was outdated. Uh,
because malware could evade
these hard coded signatures uh,
with packed code by creating
novel binaries. Um, you know,
packing obfuscation, you heard a
lot about polymorphic viruses
back in the late 2000’s. So the
solution that, again, 15 to 20
years ago, the AV industry came
up with was uh, runtime dynamic
analysis on the endpoint through
emulation. So actually running
these unknown binaries in a
virtualized environment and
looking for signatures there.
This technology goes by a number
of names, you may hear it called
sandboxing, heuristic analysis,
dynamic analysis, detonation,
virtualization and so forth. At
the end of the day it’s all
emulation and that’s what we’re
talking about today. So an
overview of emulators in
general. You begin by loading
the potentially malicious
unknown binary that you can’t
identify with more expensive
analysis, or less expensive
analysis, rather. Such as
hashing or, uh heuristic space
on imports. You’re gonna then
run the emulated, run the binary
in an emulated environment. So
you’re gonna have a CPU emulator
for the particular architecture
of the binary, generally X86.
Uh, you’re gonna run that in
this emulator and throughout
running, uh, you’re gonna click
these observations and you’ll
terminate it at some point. Such
as length of time it runs,
number of instructions that have
been executed, number of API
calls, amount of memory the
malware has used or so forth.
And throughout this you’re
collecting heuristic
observations about the malware’s
behavior that inform uh,
detections. You might also look
for things like if the malware
caused create file and writes a
known malware signature. Uh,
with create file you, you’d hook
that implementation and with
recreate file you would look
for, say, a known malware
signature or known malware hash
at that point. Moving into
talking about tooling and
process. How I did what I did.
Reverse engineering-wise I used
pretty standard industry tools,
like IDA. Uh, and BinDiff for
patch analysis. So as Google
Project 0 was discovering some
vulnerabilities, I was able to
diff uh, updates of the DLL and
find what had changed. How the
Microsoft tried to mitigate
vulnerabilities inside Defender.
Found overall there’s about
massive 12 megabyte DLL. So this
is enormous. Uh, probably one of
the largest binaries I’ve ever
taken on reversing. Um,
obviously people look at
firmwares that are much larger
but this is really, absolutely
monolithic for a single Windows
DLL. What does make this job a
lot easier is that Microsoft
publishes PDBs, and that’s to
basically debug databases that
have symbols and sometimes type
information uh, for the
binaries. Dynamic analysis-wise
uh, AVs are generally harder to
look at than traditional
software uh, and dynamic
analysis does require some work
on the part of the user or the
reverse engineer. In Defender’s
case, it’s a protected process,
meaning that even if you’re
system or admin on your local
system, you cannot attach the
process to debug it, even if you
has, have a CD bug privilege or
anything like that, you still
can’t attach it’s protected by
the OS. The solution to this is
to go into a kernel debugger
and, for example, debug and
entire VM and then attach the
kernel process or the, the
process from the kernel. But
that’s very expensive and just
annoying to do. So, uh,
introspection is also
challenging, actually if you
can, say, pause in a breakpoint,
actually understanding what's
going on the emulator state can
be difficult uh, with a debugger
even though you have the
debugger running. Scanning on
demand can be difficult to
trigger. Uh, if you want to scan
a binary you might have to go
into a gooey interface, click a
couple buttons, select
something, choose it, you know
it’s a pain to do that. You want
an automated command line right
in your face. Just say scan this
file, scan that file, scan the
other file. And code
reachability may be
configuration or heuristics
dependent. Meaning that local
settings about uh, say, how
aggressive the scanning is, what
time limits you allow the
scanner to have, all of these
can get in the way of uh,
effective scanning. The solution
is build a custom loader for
these AV binaries. And it was
nice that I was able to start
with some work that Tavis
Ormandy of Google Project 0 did
on building his own custom
harness for Defender which I
then extended extensively. So
first off I’m gonna talk a
little bit about Tavis’ existing
work, which he called load
library. So Tavis built a PE
loader for Linux. So this is
able to take a Windows DLL on
Linux and load it up, and then
actually run it. Uh, this is not
a full replacement for something
like Wine or any other uh,
Windows simulation, this is just
enough to get Windows Defender
itself running. And shimming out
uh, system calls on windows that
Defender will be making to Linux
implementations. So talking
through how Tavis’ tool works
um, and the link here will take
you to the GitHub project. We
begin with a Linux binary, just
standard user white binary. And
it’s gonna load and resolve uh,
imports for MP engine dot DLL.
So this is just the process of
taking the DLL, relocating it in
memory, doing standard DLL
loading process and putting it
in the redirect execute memory
buffer there in Linux. Then the
IAT, the import address table,
you’re gonna go through and shim
out the implementations of
various Windows APIs with Linux
replacements. So for example,
create file is replaced by a
call to open file or F open and
say, write files replaced to
call to F right. Inside this
engine you have an emulator. And
for now just remember that
there’s a table called G
syscalls, which is a table of
function pointers to various
emulations of Windows API
functions. And on the outside we
have our malware binary, huh,
with your, with the standard MZ
header on the binary. We’re
gonna call a function exported
by Defender called R signal. And
this is the main entry point to
Defender. Uh, when we give it a
buffer of data and it’s gonna
come back with a malware
classification. We then go
through a process of selecting a
scanning engine so Defender may
do some initial analysis with
things like aesthetic hashes, if
those fail and it can’t
determine whether this is a
malicious binary or not, they’re
ultimately going to rep into the
emulator. The emulator will run,
make its determination whether
this is a malicious binary or
not, and then come back with a
virus identification or it might
say this is just benign. So a
quick demo. Going to show you
scanning with mpclient. This is
Tavis Ormandy’s unmodified uh,
harness for Windows Defender.
[cough from audience member] So
here we’re scanning the eicar
test file, this is an industry
standard test file, um, for any
AV. And we see we scan the file
and it comes back and says we
found eicar dot com. So, that’s
kind of a demo, We’re actually
taking this uh, windows code,
running it to Linux and seeing
what happens when we scan the
binary. In addition to using
this harness from Tavis, I did
some dynamic analysis with
customized code coverage tools
developed by Markus Gaasedelen
of Ret2 Systems, he’s a fellow
RPISEC almumnist as well. And
Markus made a tool called
Lighthouse, that lets you scan a
binary or run a binary under
[indiscernible] or a pin,
collect coverage information,
then visualize that in IDA pro.
So you can see here in this
control flow graph, the blue,
basic blocks are those that have
been hit during a given scan.
And I found this to be extremely
powerful and useful tool when I
was doing my reverse
engineering. I did find it
interesting to see how far
flake, uh, just about a month or
two ago, give a keynote at SSTIC
where he was talking about
challenges of introspect ability
with malware. Or, whoops, sorry,
with binaries. And how it can be
very difficult to introspect and
analyze and debug binaries and
how ultimately that’s a
hindrance to security. And
Halvar explicitly called out the
challenges of analyzing Windows
Defender, as one example of this
where because Defender is in a
privileged process on windows
you can’t analyze it under a
tool like pem or dynamorio Of
course we’re running on Linux,
we side step the whole issue of
protected process and we can
actually run in visualized
coverage. Okay. Now moving into
the meat of the presentation.
Talking reverse engineering the
emulator itself. First off I’m
gonna talk about startup of the
engine, then we’re moving to CPU
emulation, instrumentation, and
then the windows environment and
emulation. So first off, the
first thing that has to happen
when we want to emulate a given
binary, is we have to load it in
and initialize the emulator and
get everything started up. So
we’re gonna call the R signal
function which provides this
entry point into Defender’s
scanning and we give it this
buffer of data to be scanned to
be classified. And uh, it will
return the malware
classification. Um, so these
results are actually cached as
well. There’s lots of numeric
stuff going in the back that we
don’t really care about. We
ultimately care about just going
into the emulator itself. So the
emulator has to be initialized.
Uh, we have to allocate memory
for execution, we have to
initialize various C plus plus
objects that are involved in the
emulations uh, process itself.
Various subsystems within
Defender, for example, the
object manager. We have to
create an object manager
instance, we have to set up the
virtual file system and so
forth. We’re gonna load the
binary that’s to be analyzed,
resolve it’s imports and things
like that. And then initialize
virtual DLLs in this emulated
process memory space. These are
kin to the real DLLs in our real
windows system that provide
emulate, or, provide windows API
functionality. Throughout this
process the Defender is
collecting heuristic
observations about the binary.
And you can see these on the
right side here, for example,
things like PEA suspicious
section size. So these might
inform some heuristic
classifications in Defender
because there’s a suspicious
section size, maybe this is
malware. Um, we’ll also be doing
things like in the bottom right,
uh, you can see some min win
resolution resolving API MS.
It’s when the API set DLLs. And
here on the bottom left, uh, I
have um, this example of uh,
when we’re setting up a name for
the binary to be emulated you
can see that if the binary isn’t
windows executable, it’ll be
called my app dot ex E. This is
something you could write
evasive malware that says “if my
name is my app dot ex E,” I
won’t run. I know that I’m
running inside Defender. And
indeed, if you Google this
string you will find malware
binaries online that explicitly
look for the name my app dot ex
E, and chose not to run if they
see it. After startup and
initialization, we’re gonna move
into talking about CPU
emulation. So technically what
Defender does is not so much
emulation as it is to name a
translation. This is a kin to
what QEMU, the quick emulator,
does, which is basically taking
assembly code of a given
language, lifting it up into an
IL, or and intermediate
presentation, and then taking
that IL and then dumping it out
with a JIT engine uh, into
executable code. Um, so Defender
supports a number of
architectures. You can see here
in the enum on the right.
Ranging from X86 of 3 different
uh, flavors to ARM and even
VMProtect. So they can take
VMProtect opcodes, lift those
into IL, and dump them out into
sanitized X86 to be run
analyzed. As well as ARM. Now,
this subsystem is incredibly
complicated and not really a
primary focus of my research but
I’ll give you a brief overview
of it in the next few slides. We
begin with the uh, architecture
to IL lifting process which are
any of these giant functions
that are architecture underscore
2 IL. You can see an example
from X86 to IL translator. Just
an absolutely massive, ugly
switch case. Uh, thousands of
switch cases, you know, IDA gets
super slow when you load this
in. And basically what they’re
doing here, is grabbing a byte
of opcode from an X86 opcode,
looking at that, uh, determining
what it is and then emitting the
uh, coding, or, related uh,
Windows Defender into
representation for that binary
uh, operation. You can see an
example here on the bottom
right, where all push
instructions lift to uh, 13 in
the Windows Defender IL. Those
also, after we lift to IL, there
is an IL emulator that runs in
software so we can actually run
binaries in software. I’ve never
observed this being run during
my research. Did some code
coverage analysis, never saw
this being hit. My uh, intuition
is that this is so that we can
support uh, analysis of X86
binaries on non-X86 host. So,
for example, if you were running
Windows Defender on windows for
ARM, you don’t have to have an
IL to our own JIT engine, you
can just run it in software. Now
as far as the IL to X86 JIT
translation, uh, we’re taking IL
code and then translating a
basic block at a time , similar
the way QEMU does things. And I
did observe this JIT being uh,
used during my research.
Defender will actually uh,
handle unique instructions that
it can’t handle with emulation
uh, through software-bound
emulation. So if it can’t JIT an
instruction out, it’ll actually
generate a call directly into a
function that does that, we’re
gonna show them next slide. But,
just, you can see here uh,
circled in red on the left, you
can actually see the opcodes
being instructed. So they’re
actually constructing a mood,
move an immediate and then call
the immediate, calling directly
into a function handling a
particularly unique
architectural instruction or
event. Uh, over here on the, uh,
right you can see the LEA opcode
actually being emitted. The
opcode in X86 is 8D. So as
you’re dumping out from the LEA
IL instruction down to X86, you
do 8D and then you XOR that with
a register. Um to, uh, register
a value to create a valid X86
instruction. Uh, Microsoft
actually documented this in 2005
at Virus Bulletin with a paper
called Defeating Polymorphism
Beyond Emulation and it’s
definitely worth checking out.
And it’s really remarkable that
Microsoft was experiment with,
experimenting with technol, this
technology almost 15 years ago.
ILs are so hot right now,
everyone’s playing with ILs for
things like binary ninja, or
various program analysis but,
Microsoft was doing this on the
end point, you know, on your,
your computer, your grandma’s
computer, everyone’s computer 15
years ago. They were lifting up
the ILs, JITing them out, doing
analysis on them. It’s very
impressive, I found. So then we
have these architecture specific
escape handlers for these unique
architectural events that we
can’t emulate uh, with the JIT
engine. Uh, you can look at this
offline and see an exact listing
of some of these enums. And an
example of one of these
functions uh, would be this
software-bound emulation of the
X86 CPUID instruction. So this
is an instruction that provides
unique information about given
X86 CPU. And here it’s emulated
in software. So as shown here, I
wrote a malware binary that uh,
does CPUID with this argument
X80001. And when we run this
binary inside Defender’s uh,
analysis engine, we’ll get this
code coverage and we’ll actually
see the little bounce off the
block where that same immediate
is compared, and then we go down
the true branch because the
immediate that our code was
doing matches up with the
immediate here in software and
then they can emulate CPUID by
sending registered date
accordingly. Alright. Moving
into talking about my
instrumentation, which was a big
enabler for the rest of my
research. So the problem with
uh, analyzing Windows Defender
is, again, I said there’s very
little introspections, very
difficult to tell what’s going
on inside of it. All you really
get out of it is virus
identification. And then you
could exploit virus
identification as sort of a side
channel to extract information
about inside the engine. And
indeed, that’s what I did with
the AV league project a couple
years ago, was exploiting
malware identifications as a
side channel to get information
about what’s going on inside
various AV emulators. Um, but
this is really slow and
inefficient. So a smarter
technique, is to go in and sort
of give us a malware-ized view
of what’s going inside, in the
engine. So, MP engine dot DLL
has various functions that are
evoked when various Windows APIs
are called by malware running
inside of it. We can then hook
those, uh, emulation functions
and provide our implementations
so we can create a 1 or 2 way IO
path to share information with
the outside and also, in turn,
inform uh, the malware binary
inside what actions we want to
take. So let me give you uh, a
diagram of that. This is the
original uh, load library
diagram I showed you. This is
Tavis Ormandy’s tool kind of in
an unmodified state, this is how
it works. And I went in, and I
hooked the G syscalls table,
this is the table of about 120
functions providing emulations
for various Windows APIs. I
hooked and replaced those
implementations with my own
connotations of various common
functions. Like Output Debug
String A or WinExec. So now when
these functions now called
malware binary inside the
engine, instead, our functions
are invoked. So, here’s an
example of our Output Debug
String A hook and the process we
have to take on which is
resolving the relative offsets
of these functions and then
setting hooks in the rewrite
execute um, DLL buffer, kind of,
in our Linux process. So what
this looks like is this uh, here
in the top right we have our IDA
Pro disassembly, or
decompilation, rather, of
Windows Defender’s emulation of
Output Debug String A. Basically
a no-op. All it does is retrieve
a single parameter off the
virtual stack and then bump the
tick count. So it bumps the time
a little bit in the emulator.
Here in the center of the
screen, I have my
reimplementation of this
function. So we’re gonna walk
through this step by step. First
off, we have our declaration. So
this takes a void pointer. Uh,
PE VARS T is a mass of about
half megabyte large structure
past all these Windows API
emulations. We don’t wanna know
an exact definition of that
function, so we could just
provide a uh, take the void
pointer, just say we, we’re not
going to worry about it, it’s
just a, a pointer. Then we have
this local thing to hold
parameters to the function. So,
the function has parameters
patched to it in the virtualized
emulated environment, and we
wanna interact with those so we
have to make some space for
them. I’m gonna use the function
internal Defender to pull off
one parameter from the virtual
stack. So we’re going in,
talking, you know, looking at
the virtual ESP and EVP state,
uh, in this virtual memory space
and then pulling off the 4 bit
value that was there. I’m
actually calling back into
Defender from my hook function
to do that. Then I’m calling a
function GetString that’s going
to translate a virtual address
inside the emulator to a real
address that we can interact
with locally. And now we can
just print that string to
standard out. So this sounds
like a lot but let me show you a
quick demo of it in action. So
here I have a malware binary
that’s gonna say “hello defcon”
when we run it. It’s goes Output
Debug String A hello defcon.
We’re now going to scan that
binary inside my hooked and
modified version of Tavis’ load
library tool. And you’ll see
here it says, “hello defcon”
now. Going back to visual
studio, we’re gonna add a new
line, this is a live demo. Of
course this is a pre-recorded
video because the defcon
organizers this year wanted us
to do pre-recorded videos, but I
was doing this live. I just
rebuilt the, the binary, and
here scanning it again. It’s now
gonna say “hello defcon” and
then also, “this is a live
demo.” So this is what’s
happening, is inside the
emulator, our malware binary is
calling this function because
we’ve hooked the implementation
of the Output Debug String A
emulation in Defender, our
function’s being called instead.
And we’re gonna run it one more
time, I believe, with some more
information you can see here uh,
we’ve uh, more rich debug output
and we can see things like the
exact addresses patched to it
uh, from the first memory space.
So this is like, a big enabler
for the rest of my research. The
fact that I had this, sort of,
window into what’s going on
inside the emulator. I can have
my malware binary inside take
observations and then post them
out to the outside world. As far
as my malware binary goes, call
it my app dot ex E. Again,
that’s the name of all binaries
running inside Defender’s
engine. It does this IO
communication with Output Debug
String A and some other
functions. On the right side,
you’ll see a list of factors
that I found could impede
emulation, and then ways to get
around them. So I had to really
massage the linker,
optimizations, imports, in order
to get binaries that were
consistently emulated by
Defender. And I’ll be releasing
some code at the end of this
talk that will have a very
simple, visual project that I
found I was able to get
consistently emulated when
scanned with a library. Finally,
as far as the reverse
engineering goes, moving into
the Windows emulation and the
Windows environment. I think the
most interesting part of this
presentation. We’ll start off by
talking about the user mode
environment. So this is the
emulation of a fake Windows user
mode. So, in Windows Defender
there is a virtual file system.
Um, uh as any real system would
have a file system and files
that malware might look at,
Defender virtualizes 1. And
there’s about 15 hundred
functions on their virtual file
system. And you’ll see a variety
of things in there. Mostly it’s
fake executables that are there
for, um, malware binaries to,
for example, infect or, you
know, do different things too,
that could be indicators that
they are in fact malicious
binaries. So I’ll do a quick
demo of dumping the file system,
again, using that mechanism that
I showed you of posting data out
with Output Debug String A.
We’re able to numerate the
entire file system and dump it
in just a few seconds. I did,
here, actually use a slightly
more sophisticated hook. Uh,
where as doing WinExec and I’ll
show some examples in my backup
slides. It’s not as simple as
just Output Debug String Aing
them. But you can see here in
just a second or 2 we dumped the
entire virtual file system from
inside Windows Defender. We had
a malware binary go inside
there, numerate all the files
that it could see, and then dump
them out. And after we dump them
out, we see that there’s about
15 hundred of them, in this
virtual file system. And you’ll
see things like this, the word
“goat” repeated thousands of
times over, in a file called AAA
touch me not dot ex E. Um, my
intuition is that this binary is
right there on the, the C drive.
And it’s there so that a malware
binary might read that file and
say “send over the network” or
“encrypted” or do some, some
indicator that we are indeed
malware. So maybe, if you touch
it, that might be an indicator
that you’re malicious. Uh, the
reason has the goat. Uh, goat,
the word goat pasted a thousand
times over, presumably it is a
goat file. And that’s sort of an
AV industry term for a
sacrificial file. Like, a
sacrificial goat that you can
like, get infected or changed or
encrypted by malware in order to
have the malware kind of show
it’s true intent. So that was an
interesting artifact. Again,
this is also something that you
could write malware that says if
I see the word goat thousands
times over in a file called AAA
touch me not, I know I’m running
inside Defender, therefor I’m
not gonna run, I’m not gonna do
anything malicious. We’ll see
fake config files. You can see
that these are very clearly
written by a real human, with
comments like bla bla. Uh, and,
you know, generic sequel
queries. We have a virtual
registry that has thousands of
entries and enumerating the
whole registry, dumping that
out, we’ll see things like this.
So for example, there’s a
registry entry for world of
warcraft, presumably there’s
malware that maybe hooks world
of warcraft registry entry and
touches it. So if we saw, a call
to say, reg open key, on world
of warcraft, that might be an
indicator of potential malicious
intent. We’ll see various other
fake processes running on the
system, and these are not real
processes, they’re just uh, when
you call, you know, uh, call
that function to enumerate all
processes it’ll give you this
fake listing. And highlit at the
bottom in yellow, there is our
function, my app dot ex E. Uh,
quick demo of that, dumping the
process listing. Again, using
this same mechanism that I
developed. So there you can see,
uh, real time just took less
than a second, we dumped the
entire process listing. Alright,
back to the presentation. In
addition to this environment we
have Windows usermode code that
runs to provide emulations of
various Windows API functions.
Uh, and there are generally 2
types of API emulations. Um, a
kin to those uh, Windows API
functions, the real Windows
system. There are those that
stay in usermode, which are once
it’s in the emulator. And those
that resolve into a syscall.
Just like a, uh, a trap to a
native emulation here in
Defender. Uh, symbols indicate
that these, uh, emulated virtual
DLLs that are in an emulated
environment are called VDLLs.
And because they are simply
DLLs, once we have a file system
dump, we can just go reverse
that dump, and, or reverse those
DLLs by throwing it on IDA and
their standard Windows PE files.
When we look at them, they’re
definitely not the real, uh,
implementations of things like
kernel32, that you would see in
a real system. So we’ll see
things like this, um, in
kernel32 if we call get
username, it’ll return a hard
code string of John Doe. This is
again, something we can use to
create evasive malware that says
if I see the username John Doe,
I’m not gonna run. We’ll see a
Ostensibly a, uh, Arthur C.
Clark uh, you know, Space
Odyssey 2001 reference. Uh, so
again, you can write malware for
inside Defender. We’ll also see
very simple imitations of
functions like RTL get current
peb. All that function takes is
it needs to just go to the
memory segment at uh, FS18, so
they actually support memory
segmentation at the
architectural level so they can
just do that actual instruction
inside the emulator. Or we’ll
see complex functions like RTL
set sacl security descriptor
just knocked out. They just
return 0. More functions just
stubbed out creating 0, negative
1 and so forth or just
triggering interrupt. So, lots
of complec funct, complex
functions you’re not fully
emulated by Defender. We’ll also
see things like this, again,
more unique strings and
identifiers that we know were
running inside Defender. Uh,
like these German IP addresses
in references to German
websites. Maybe a German
programmer developed this
particular DLL emulation. So
that covers some of the usermode
code, and the very simple
emulations, those that just
return hard coded names like,
the user-kernel privilege uh,
boundary? How, How do we get
into more complex emulations
such as those requiring access
to a virtual file system. These
functions are implemented with a
hypercall like instruction
called apicall. This is, of
course, not a real X86
instruction. With the opcode
0FFFF0 and then a 4 byte
immediate describing the
particular function to be
invoked. But when this
instruction is called and the
virtual CPU, it’s gonna generate
a call into a native MP engine
dot DLL function that provides
emulation of these uh, unique
functions. So these are complex
functions that identify system
state or maybe require
particularly complex handling.
Uh so, in copy file worker, we
have an API call to kernel32
copy file W worker. The virtual
CPU sees that instruction,
generates a call directly into
this emulation of that function,
and then it’s emulated there in
software. Uh, in MP engine dot
DLL. This is great attack
surface if you found any
vulnerabilities in this native
emulation function, so you could
use these to break out of the
emulator and infect the native
host. Uh, this disassembly here,
is provided by an IDA processor
module. And I’ll have an article
coming out in poker GTFO, issue
19, describing exactly how this
IDA process or extension module
works. So, once we have these
apicall instructions running,
they’re gonna trigger a call to
a function looks the G syscalls
table, which is the table of
these function pointers and
these hashes. Let’s go look for
the 4 byte immediate that was
called from the apicall
instruction and then dispatch to
the appropriate function that
matches up with it. So, kind of
a work flow of what this looks
like. Uh, inside the emulator
here, we have kernel32 Output
Debug String A. It’s gonna do
things like log the number of
times it was called. So if it’s
called more than 900 times that
might trigger some unique
behavior. Um, but ultimately
it’s gonna resolve then our,
this function apicall kernel32
Output Debug String A. Which is
then gonna use the apicall
instruction. You can see the
0FFFF0, BB 14 80 B2, and it’s
gonna see that instruction and
then that hypercall’s gonna step
in and basically transition us
into native emulation out of
this managed uh, [indiscernible]
translation context. And we’re
gonna hit the native emulation
for Output Debug String A. Of
course this is what we hooked
when we had our own Output Debug
String A influentation that I
was using to post information
out of the emulator. Enumerating
the emulated functions that have
native emulations, these are
them. The yellow functions are
those that are not found on real
Windows systems, so they’re
specific to Defender. For
example, for debug functionality
or unique backdoor management.
Uh here’s more of them,
including a number of VSF
functions, which are for lull of
access to the virtual file
system. So all these native
emulation functions take a PE
Vars T, a very large, half
megabyte large structure
containing everything about a
given emulation context. And
then we have templated
parameters functions that are
used to retrieve parameters to
the function from the emulated
stack. And then programmatic
APIs for manipulating return
values, register state, the CPU
tick count or time, uh, all that
sort of stuff can be
programmatically managed through
manipulations of the PE Vars T
structure. Virtual memory can be
interacted with with a API
similar to that found in many
uh, emulation engines, such as
Unicorn Engine. Where we can
memory map virtual memory into
our real memory space and
manipulate it there. And there
are wrapper functions for common
operations like reading a single
byte, writing single D word,
reading or writing wide strings
or, regular CharStars. And these
all have uh, kind of these
utility functions wrapped around
them to make them easier for
developers. Moving into kernel
internals. So we’ve talked about
the usermode code, talked about
how the usermode code gets into
kernel mode, or the native
emulations. Let’s look at how
those develop, emulations are
themselves implemented. So, the
Windows kernel provides a number
of facilities to any binary, you
know, this is NTOSKRNL dot ex E
and the associated drivers. And
these are really the core of the
Windows uh, OS or the NT kernel.
Uh, these exa, these are,
include examples of the object
manager, process management,
file system access, the registry
through registry hives, and
synchronization primitives for
IPC. First off we’re gonna talk
about the object manager. This
is an essential part of the
Windows executive that provides
uh, management for handles. So
any time you are opening a file,
a socket, so forth, it’s gonna
go through the object manager.
And Defender supports 5 types of
objects with it’s object
manager. So these are file,
thread, event, mutant, which is
a singular of mutex, and
semaphore. And these are stored
in a big object manager map uh,
here in NT, MP engine dot DLL.
They’re stored in memory as C
plus plus objects and they all
inherit from a common parent
class, object manager object. We
then have subclasses, like file
object or mutant object, and you
can see I’ve made a little
larger for the font the unique
traits uh, to those particular C
plus plus objects. Such as the M
file handle uh, thing in the
file object, or the weight count
variable for a mutex. If various
processes can weight on the
given mutex. Uh, C plus plus RTI
is used to, RTTI is used to cast
between these subclasses to
their parent class when they’re
retrieved. And the object
manager can be interacted with,
uh, programmatically uh, by
these various functions. So if
we open a mutant, they’re gonna
grab that object, then, you
know, mess with it. If we uh,
open a file object, it’s action
call extension object manager,
get file object which will use
our tool to first check the type
then explicitly use RTTI to cast
to a file object and fail if the
retrieved handle is not indeed a
file handle. We’ll also see
things like the pseudo handle
for current process uh, is
emulated as X1234. Again, a
trait of the emulator we can use
to write evasive malware based
on seeing that our own handle is
1234. We have a virtual file
system, provides emulation and
access to a file system. And
this is access through the
standard NTDLL, NT write file,
NT create file and so forth
APIs. As well as these lower
level VFS functions which
provide sort of a back door,
unsanitized access uh, to the
file system in uh, emulation.
Finally, moving into talking
about AV instrumentation. So all
the heuristics and analysis the
AV is doing throughout the
runtime. So they are some
internal functions that are
exposed through the hypercall
apicall interface, and I’ve
summarized them here. And we’re
gonna look at a few of these.
First off, MP report event,
which is used to communicate
information about malware binary
actions with Defender’s
heuristic detection engine. So
these are in some of these user
mode uh, emulations, such as get
user name or get computer name.
Those don’t require strapping
into a full need of emulation,
and that would increase the
attacks of this greatly if they
all did, but we do want to
inform Defender that the given
function was called. So if get
system directory is called,
it’ll report uh, event 12331, or
if you create a process and you
do it uh, suspended it’ll do X
uh, 3018 but it’ll say create
suspended, specifically noting
that a uh, process like that was
created. A MP report event can
be called in more cases, you can
see here, just more examples.
This is called thousands of
times throughout these VDLLs.
And a more concrete example of
how this might play into AV uh,
identification or potentially
malicious binaries is here where
we see that if we called
terminate process on a PID in
the 700 range, which uh, you’ll
note that all these various AV
processes are in the 700 range,
it’ll trigger MP report event
12349. But it’ll also say “AV”.
So if you try to terminate
process on an AV that’s probably
a good indicator you’re
malicious. NT control channel is
sort of a back door interface
for administering the engine.
This is something Tavis Ormandy
hit, and I went here and reverse
engineered the 32 switch case
options of this function and
showed you what they all do. So
these help you through things
like manipulate the uh, rewrite
microcode, uh, manipulate
register state, all sorts of
stuff. Um, create an attack
surface, definitely something
that shouldn’t be open to
malware binaries running inside
the emulator. [speaker burps]
Uh, we’re gonna conclude by
talking about vulnerability
research. Let’s start off by
trying to understand some prior
vulnerability discovered by
Tavis Normandy at Google Project
0. So Tavis discovered this
apicall instruction that I
talked about. And he was able to
call directly into native
emulations and functions, rather
than passing through their
apicall stubs, by just uh,
generating the apicall
instructions on the fly, as you
can see here. And then Tavis was
hitting internal debug
functions, like, NT control
channel. Which when you get
option X12, it goes to rewrite
microcode. And this code here
let’s the user specify the count
in a tight loop. Uh, and with
the user specified count, we
only have, I think, a thousand
elements of allocated uh, for
the new microcode information.
Uh, but the user can give in,
buffer or a flow. Microsoft
patched this by adding a check
that they count, is no greater
turn 0. It doesn’t, doesn’t run.
Tavis also looked at the virtual
file system, and by calling
directly into these unsanitized
functions to access the virtual
file system, was able to uh,
basically get a uh, linear uh,
heap read and write paremative
uh, by creating a file with
these, you know, strange sizes.
And, and this sequence of calls
could crash the engine with an
out of bounds write. Now, I
looked at the mitigations that
Microsoft put in for the abuse
that the apicall instruction,
which were primarily that Tavis
himself was generating the
apicall instruction on the fly
from the malware’s dot text
section. And then Microsoft
added a check that says, is the
call to the API call
instruction, is it coming from a
VDLL page? And if it’s not, it’s
gonna deny the user the ability
to invoke in the emulation
function. This means that these
uh, apicall instructions can
only be invoked from code pages
that are associated with a given
VDLL that cannot be called from
the malware binary. And, in
fact, if you call them it’ll do
MP set attribute, which uh,
will, basically set a heuristic
that, you tried to call the
apicall instruction from your
dot text section. This is
really, really weird. Probably a
strong indicator of malicious
intent. And I found that I could
bypass this mitigation by simply
finding the apicall stubs in
memory in our VDLLs, which I can
reverse engineer. And that could
just bounce off the apicall
instruction, and hit this uh,
interface, these interfaces with
my own uh, controlled arguments.
So this is not good. I did
report this to Microsoft and
they told me this is not a trust
boundary. Kind of a classic
Microsoft response to a lot of
vulnerability disclosures. But
it’s not quite a trust boundary
um, you know, unless you
actually found an actual
vulnerability like, uh, you
know, actual buffer or flow in
there. The fact that there’s
this logical flaw that I can hit
internally, bug interfaces and
do things like stop emulation
right then and there, or change
microcode in the emulator,
that’s certainly not a
vulnerability according to
Microsoft. So an example of a
bypass here, doing something
pretty benign, just hit Output
Debug String A. So I found in
kernel32 the offset of Output
Debug String A and I can uh,
resolve that address and then
treat that as a function binary
and just bounce off this
emulation. And when this runs we
hit Output Debug String A. Now,
more maliciously, we can sort of
hit NT control channel. Uh,
again, that internal debug
interface left in by developers.
Maybe debug or administer the
engine and we can set our own
heuristics like, for example, if
we call virut body found, it’ll
trigger immediate malware
detection. So a quick demo of
that. So in this video you can
see we’re calling Output Debug
String A in the legitimate way,
and then calling it with our
Output Debug String A abuse. Um,
through this uh, unintended
interface kind of left there in
the VDLL code page. Uh, once we
run and compile this binary,
we’ll enroll, so hit NT control
channel as well. And we’re gonna
use NT control channel to check
the exact version number of the
engine, and this was on the
February 2018 build of the
engine. So with our kind of ret2
apicall technique, we run this
binary and we’ll see we hit
Output Debug String A the normal
way. Then through the apicall
with kind of a bypass from
Microsoft’s mitigation. So we
have a controlled argument going
into there. And we also show
that we can hit NT control
channel with controlled argument
as well. Now uh, the, again, the
implications of this so we can
hit these internal debug
interfaces with attacker control
arguments, probably not a good
idea. Finally I wanna talk a bit
about fuzzing. So I was able to
fuzz emulated APIs. Um,
basically working out some more
complex mechanisms to allow our,
our channel to be a 2 way IO
channel, not just an output
channel. Uh, I took MWR Labs’
OSX kernel fuzzer, which
generate random values to fuzz
the OSX kernel. And I folded
that in with my code on
generating random values each
time. And then I pushed those in
the emulator and I was able to
do things like fuzz NT write
file, and actually reproduce
Tavis’ crash but in a unique way
that got around uh, the
sanitization that NT write file
normally does. I reprode his
crash in VFS write, but through
NT write file without having to
use the apicall instruction. You
can see in this demo here, we’re
gonna do that. We’re gonna
resolve the address of NT write
file uh, and then fuzz that. And
this whole mechanism here with
the perams, uh, this is a more
complex interface that I have
for passing information in and
out of the emulator. And
basically on the outside of the
emulator we’re generating fuzz
input to give to inside of it.
Then we’re calling NT write file
with those fuzz parameters and
seeing what happens. So running
this, you’re gonna see this run
for quite awhile. It’s just
gonna keep running. In my
experience, it took about 7
minutes running single threading
second to reproduce Tavis’
crash. Again, this is not a
smart fuzz and there’s no AFL,
there’s no code coverage
mentioned it’s just the dumb,
the random values at uh, Windows
Defender. In order to fuzz it.
There’s the demo. And moving
into the conclusion. We covered
tooling and instrumentation, CPU
emulation basics for X86
binaries and a bit on
vulnerability research and
fuzzing for Windows Defender. We
didn't cover a whole lot of
other stuff. For example, uh,
X86, uh X64 emulation [speaker
burps] excuse me, emulation, ARM
emulation, VMprotect emulation,
the 16 bit emulation. There is a
full DOS emulator uh, aside from
the Win32 in a modern Windows
system emulator. There’s an, a
16 bit emulation built into
Defender. Really interesting
attack surface as well. Probably
not as well looked at as the 32
bit one. Uh we had a look at the
threading model, how you can do
multithreading for binaries
inside emulators. That’s always
uh, a source of problems for AV
emulators at large, so, worth
looking at. We’re also analysis
for dot net binaries. We’re
primarily looking at Windows
binaries that are just compiled
X86 code. Also inside MP engine
we have unpackers, parsers, a
JavaScript engine which you can
see in my REcon Brussels talk,
other scanning engine and dot
net engine. Now, I wanna say
that people love to talk about
AVs and what they can and can’t
do, where, whether they may or
may not be vulnerable. But
there’s not a lot of ground
truth about AVs in the public.
And I think there should be
more. I think they’re a really
fascinating target to analyze,
they’re a lot of fun. I think
this is much more interesting,
to me at least, than looking at
malware. Actually seeing how
malware gets caught and
mitigated and detected, and you
also learn a whole lot about
say, anit-kernel internals and
object managers and things like
that. It gives you an interest
to look at all of these
different technologies. Um, a
lot of claims about AV
vulnerabilities and how they may
or may not be vulnerable are
based on Tavis Ormandy’s work
and a bit on Joxean’s work. But
there’s really not a whole lot
out there. Uh, I really like
this tweet from Joxean where he
said if you Google antivirus
internals, all you find is me,
him and then Tavis Ormandy. I
would say if you like this sort
of work, definitely grab a copy
of his book. It’s an awesome
book and really underappreciated
by people. Um, just come really
incredible work that went into
that. I’m releasing some code
later. Here’s my GitHub, I’ll
also tweet about this so no
worry to, you don’t have to take
a picture of the slide. But I’ll
be sharing some of the harnesses
that I built. Uh, an IDA
disassembler for the apicall
instruction. I’ll also be
publishing an article in Poker
GTFO issue 19 describing more of
this under more technical
details of some of these
technologies. And that concludes
the presentation. I have a whole
lot more slides being released
online after this. This is only
about 50 percent of the material
that I prepared for today. My
JavaScript slides are all there
on that bit ly link. And I wanna
thank all my friends, Tavis,
Mark uh, Marcus, Joxean and then
numerous friend who helped me
edit this presentation and get
here to Defcon. Uh, hit me up on
Twitter if you have any
questions. I have open DMs.
Thanks very much. [audience
applauds]