um just one item before we get started
we ask you to submit your questions for
q
a in the q a section of zoom questions
will be queued in the order received and
with that let's get go ahead and get
started
everyone uses dns these days and i'm
really excited
to introduce our next speakers fatima
security engineer at the university of
delaware
responsible for but not limited to
network traffic monitoring
instant response threat hunting and
managing the theme
she will be joined by chase also from
the university of delaware
who has been involved in research and
implementing
of various things around network
packages for more than 30 years
please join me in welcoming them to
share their findings in dns
that might help every one of you to find
more things in there
thank you so much alex for the kind
introduction um
so hi everyone i'm farmer and i'm not
going to waste
too much of time to get into the
introduction again but just quick note
that i recently joined um es net as a
security engineer
in in berkeley live in uh in berkeley
so uh it's been eight months now so that
was a little bit of change when
i first submitted my introduction to
first conference
so jumping right into the talk
okay so before i actually uh go into the
research and what we did with the
traffic i would like to introduce you
to the basic concept of where exactly
we're getting the traffic so that
in the mind you you know that what are
the end points that we are tapping or we
are monitoring and when i say
that we have these logs you should kind
of like know a little bit of background
of whatever network traffic
profile looks like at university of
delaware so this is a very uh raw
and very um high level diagram view of
uh what the uh what the bordering co
routers look like in universal diver
and where exactly we are getting the
traffic for our monitoring
so we have 10 gig links uh uplinks that
connect over water routers and that
directly
over the internet we have two core
routers that are
the uh backbone of all the uh indeed
all the remaining core routers are
underneath them and that's why we are
getting
the uh mirrors traffic from both the
routers uh
to our network load balancer and then
that network load balancer balances out
the traffic to our
monitoring clusters and one of our
monitoring clusters that university of
delaware is a zeke cluster
so we have four nodes and each node gets
like roughly 25 percent
of load balance traffic our peaks are
around 8 gbps in a very um busy day but
kind of like the average out with the uh
5 gbps
uh link fluctuation and each sensors i
was getting the uh pps rate which is
packets per second
so each sensor roughly gets 300 to 300
000 packets per second which is not a
lot
uh but that's kind of like whatever
network traffic looks like
and as you can see in the in the diagram
that the z cluster
is primarily there for monitoring the
eastward of
minding the knots out traffic which is
the traffic that going that is going
back and forth from the internet to our
uh in universities internal network
so that's what our primarily uh
monitoring system looks like that it
just monitors the north south traffic
i that means the traffic that is uh
coming into the university and then the
traffic that is going out of the
university
subnets
okay so our research problem so
everything started with
me analyzing the logs so i like thread
hunting and i like doing the analysis
and investigation in the logs and i just
keep uh
looking into the logs to see if there is
something interesting there
so what we found uh last year when i was
doing the research uh
i was mainly looking at the dns.log file
that zeke generates that one of the log
files
that is very interesting and very
heavily generated
so we found out that there are some
unique uh
trends and activities that are going in
our dns.log file and we want to
investigate them further that what is
going on and why these hosts are doing
these kind of weird queries
so uh we came up with uh when we
investigated couple of the um
ip addresses that were doing some kind
of like unique activity
we came up with a realization that in
our network that
that there are a lot of hosts and ips
that are doing something um
unconventional with dns i mean it was
not malicious
but it was definitely something that is
that was worth looking at so we kind of
like came up with the two classification
techniques of how we can find out those
hosts
that are using dns for unconventional
purposes not malicious but at least to
know what exactly is going on
so uh we coined the term of label use
because
that those dns queries were completely
fine you
you should not block them but we just
thought that those are looking unique so
we came up with a term called off label
use
for the services and applications that
use dns for unconventional purposes
and when i say unconventional purposes
that means um not the conventional use
of like when we go on the browser and
type www.google.com it resolves to an ip
and then our
uh host tries to connect to that ip
that's like very conventional use of dns
and that is what
primarily dns was uh discovered to use
for as a directorial service
so the two classification techniques to
find out all the hosts that were doing
something unique with dns uh
were these so the first one was we
wanted to find out all the
hosts uh who never utilized the dns
resolution like if my machine is just
my if my machine is taking an effort to
resolve a domain
to get an ip but it is not doing
anything with that ip then that is a
waste cycle right like why
am i machine doing that so we wanted to
investigate all the hosts um
corresponding to that kind of activity
and for that uh we will go into the
detail
of each and every technique of each and
every technique that we have right now
the the two techniques but
just a um just a one liner here that for
uh analyzing that
kind of activity we just chose dns
versus tcp connections and it is very
coarse screen
finding it is not very fine-grained
thing that we map each and every
connection but it's very coarse green so
that's why in overall
we wanted to look into the statistics of
how our dns connections uh look like
versus tcp connections
and then the second classification
technique that we came up with came up
with was uh
we saw and we observed that a lot of ips
that were
our host ips were client types
were using multiple dns resolvers um and
internal as well as external so i wanted
to like
um i want to explain what internal and
external is
so when a host is set up right
and when a host comes up online there
are two ways it can get an ip one is the
static assignment and then the second
one is the dynamic
and in our university network a lot of
clients and majority of the clients we
are trying to move away from the static
assignment
and we are trying to have hosts get all
the settings of subnet
gateway dns servers from our dhcp
servers
so we know that majority of our clients
should be using the dhcp settings that
are sent to them
for connecting to the uh gateway and for
connecting to the
internal dns servers so it was very
interesting to see that
some of our clients were connecting to
our internal dns servers that were the
dna servers that uni has set up for uh
resolving the outside domains
as well as at the same time those
clients were connecting to the
google dns server like 8.8.8
so you were like that if somebody has
set it as a static
then why they would set it like that
that okay four servers are like random
public servers and then the two two
servers remaining are the
ud's internal server so you wanted to
investigate that case as well so these
were the two basic classification
technique we wanted to investigate more
to find out what's going on in our dns
traffic
okay so going to the details of the
first one which is
the host that never utilized the dns
resolutions
it was very interesting though so we
just we were just curious to know what
exactly are the hosts and why they are
doing that
so this is a basic workflow uh to let
you guys know that what we did to find
out those eyepiece
again it's a very coarse coarse grain so
um
just a brief introduction of what we did
so first of all we um we used our zig
data
and uh we there were two sources of data
right so one was a receipt data for
finding out all the
outbound tcp connections because
remember i should
diagram that where exactly they're
tapping or monitoring the traffic it was
like not so
and then the second the the green uh the
green uh
box there which says internal dns
request those were captured by our dna
servers so we were collecting all the
data into one of the same solutions that
we have
so those were the two data primary data
sources for this poc
so we collected and we get a lot of tons
of data so we collected just one hour
worth of statistics
so collect all the tcp connections for
one hour and put them
into this tcp file with just the ips
that are making outbound connections so
all the unique ips
for one hour period of time that we're
making outbound tcp connections
that was our one bucket the second ip5
that we uh
collected was from our internal dns
servers uh log file the queries file
so collect all the ips that were making
the internal that were making the dns
request over internal dns server
and put them in the dns ips file and
then compare those ips for one hour that
do you find
anything in common so they can be three
scenarios right like the first one will
be you will find a lot of ips common
so that is a normal behavior that one ip
resolve the domain
you saw the dns request and then that ip
initiated
initiated a tcp connection to whatever
ip it
it found uh it got from the dns servers
the second one was the ips that were
only in tcp ips
well that it could be that uh they are
not using your internal dns servers
they are using either uh static external
dns servers or they are either using doh
in which case it will not result in any
kind of dns uh query that we can see
because it will be encrypted
and then the last one that is one of the
uh interesting one that
we were looking for was ips that were
only seen in dns ips file
that means the ips are creating our dns
servers
and resolving the domains but they're
not using those resolutions so
we wanted to analyze that bucket to see
what's going on and fight this unusual
behavior
and we want and we tag that as like
these ips are doing something off label
use
of dns
okay so just a statistical scenario
everything was done on our
network traffic so all the uh statistics
are pretty real it's not any kind of
stub data
so as you can see that the first the
first two bars the tcp ips and dns ips
they are pretty uh normal that around 53
ips were found in our tcp outbound
connections
uh around 49 000 were found in our dns
uh internal logs
the unique ips when we compared them
majority of them like almost 90
of them matched so they were common
eyepiece which was good
that normal activity 90 percent of the
time there were some ips that were only
doing tcp
uh connections we didn't see any uh dns
connections for those ips
we tagged it as maybe they are using
external dns or doh
for uh resolution of their tcp
connections and
domains for the tcp connections the the
last bar however the uh
the dns only bar this was interesting it
was almost uh
five thousand six thousand ips and that
it's
that list of ips were only in our dns ib
spell that means that were the only ips
that were making only dns requests and
we didn't see any kind of tcp
connection from those ips
okay so when we uh analyzed that ip5
uh on in which we only had ips that were
doing dns resolution
we found out that the majority of i so i
started looking into
what these dns queries are like why
these dns queries are not getting
used so for some ips i found that
like the first couple of a couple of um
tens of ip we found that they were using
hola vpn and how did we find that there
were a lot of danish queries for
dnstest1.hola.org
smtp testcola.org and those were
resolving to some kind of random static
ip
and that eyepiece weren't used by the
host to connect to anything
so i was like that's interesting so i
did a little bit of research of what
this hola vpn is
it turns out that if you guys don't know
hola vpn is a third-party
free vpn service and the reason it is
free is because it is pretty intrusive
there are a lot of articles um
available online that you can look up
that tells you that there are a lot of
concerns of security and privacy
with hola vpn and they are pretty
intrusive what that means is a client
who is
downloading hola will become a vp uh
endpoint and people on the network they
people on that vpn network can actually
exit their traffic and proxy their
traffic through that end point
and that's what makes its vpn free
because they are not using their own
bandwidth they are using the
customers or the enterprise bandwidth
and we saw a lot of clients who are
using hola and without even knowing that
they're pretty intrusive and everything
is in clear text all the traffic is in
clear
x so what are the implications so
in in general if somebody's attacking
and if that traffic accidentally um
egresses or exits from
a client who is on your network then
that would
that would uh make it look like that
that traffic is coming from your network
and it will kind of like hide the actual
attacker and a lot of times enterprises
have the firewall policies that are
pretty lenient to their internal clients
versus the external ap address
so we found it pretty concerning and uh
what
more interesting was out of those 50
systems
a couple of dozen systems were spamming
so i was
i said that okay now i got that why it
is dns test because hola is consistently
testing your
their clients internal network
connection that how good the network
connection is so that they can use that
endpoint as an exit node so i understand
that
okay they are using dns test to see if
the client can connect to the dns
but i was interested to know and i was
curious that why it is
connecting and testing smtp
so i started looking through the smtp
smtp.log file from zeek
and i found that those ips were actively
spamming
like more than 50 or 60 um
clients like hotmail.com google.com
random random people and they were
actively getting blocked by spam house
so if you haven't taken a look into the
smtp.log file and if you run zeek
please take a look at it because if you
just search for the workspam house or
blog you will see that if your ips
internal libraries are doing something
bad
so that was the bad thing that out of 50
systems
a dozen were spamming actively our
internal network as well as
the the clients that are outside and
unfortunately unfortunately they were
getting blocked by spam house
and there were no notification to us
that hey by the way
we saw these clients who are spamming
you should do something about it
so we investigated that and then we
created a policy saying that
we will not allow this third-party vpn
service on
our network and the clients who are
using it for just the free purpose
should not use it on the
university-owned computers and if you're
on the university network
you should not be using that and we
actually applied that policy and we got
rid of hola in like
it's a long process it took like a month
or two because you have to convince the
client and you don't want to annoy
people
that okay you cannot use this free vpn
service anymore
so we can so that was a good part of it
that after doing this research
we came up with a governance policy to
not uh
allow any user on the network to run
hola vpn
so this is just a quick slide of how we
found on how we detected the uh
ip addresses that were using hola
so the four the first four are the uh
domain names and then
the remaining two are the http uh ioc so
if you want to
check out in your traffic then you can
look for these iocs
the second use case is the antivirus
software so majority of the people would
already know that antivirus are very
noisy and they use
dns for a lot of interesting purposes
i would like to mention specifically um
smackify
they use something called global thread
intel and it is an online database for
their premium users
so they so that they can connect to the
real uh
malware detection or manual analysis
database to find out in the real time
whether a file that they have open is
malicious or not
the same thing is with sofos um so force
uses dns for surface extensible list and
it provides similar kind of real-time
protection to their premium clients
so in mcafee we found that uh a lot of
queries to mcafee.com
were looking very random and weird and i
was like why
these random weird queries and what
sense you can make out of it
so it turns out that uh for having a
quick conversation like if i have a
question that hey this file is bad
you just need to answer it in a black
and white scenario yes or no right
and what is the best protocol to do that
which is like fast
and um it will provide i'm not a
reliable service because it is dns
and udp but it is it is fast right so
they chose dns
and what it does is in gti that if you
open a file which is a local file or if
there is a local file resetting on the
client system if it is bad and there is
no signature
in the in the local database that ships
with mcafee
the client can query it real time to gti
database and then the gta
gt can provide an answer that yeah it's
suspicious then quarantine it and no
it's not suspicious let it run
so they use dns for that and then what
information is shared
it's an encoded query and that encoded
query the first label in the in the dns
domain
is like the uh it has encoded
uh version and product information the
file hash and then some
information about operating system or
the environment where that file was open
we are still not sure what is this is
what mcafee says that they share various
we are still not sure what exactly
are the information shared so this is
just from the
gti's uh website so um
a quick look the mcafee query looks like
that so the first label you can see it's
encoded
and that contains the information like
the file hash and the fingerprint of the
system
that is sent to the gta database uh with
mcafee.com
the only two responses that we saw from
the from mcafee's
dns servers for those kind of queries
where no error in nx domain
our hypothesis is uh that when a client
queries that kind of query
and when the no error comes back it
means that the hash
was found in the database and it is like
a yes
in mcafee's term that yes we have found
this file as bad
the nx domain is uh returned when there
is no match for that
fingerprint or for the file hash that
the host has queried so it's
no answer from the mcafee so those were
the only two responses but that we saw
for those queries
so now what we can do about it right
like we know that this activity is going
on we are we are not able to decode
what is sent to the gta database
like we tried to plot it and we started
plotting it and then
what you can see is like a malware trend
uh that means uh
if there is something new kind of
suspicious files comes around
and if you start seeing an uptick in
that file uh
from your clients that you then it can
show you something that oh something bad
is going on or
there is an outbreak of an attack uh
which has compromised a lot of systems
uh which does not have any uh local
entry in the debt or it does not
signature yet yet
so it's kind of like an unknown attack
so this is the trend of all the uh
files that we saw going uh back and
forth from
our clients to mcafee's dns okay coming
to the classification technique too
quickly
so it is pretty pretty basic like uh
we are assuming that our clients should
be using dhcp and contacting only our
international
dna servers but there can be some ips
that can contact external dns servers
but there were some ips who were
contacting both the internal as well as
external and those were the ips that we
wanted to
look into more so that that's a quick
workflow of hourly construction
dns external ips are the ips that we got
from z clock
dns internal ips are the ips that we got
from our
internal dns um queries log we compared
them
common ips unusual behavior eyepieces
that are only in external
are okay because they had they are they
might be using static uh
assignment and the ips that are in the
dns internal life piece
are are the ips that are using our own
internal dns servers which should be
normal
results uh as you can see the majority
of the ips
found in both the files but the internal
only the external only was very small
percentage
so we were like okay there are still
some clients that are using static
assignment and then there was a bar of
almost 800 900 ips that were using both
so that's the
that's the case we investigated further
turns out that baleena os is uh
an operating system that was running on
most of the clients
uh who were doing both the internal as
well as external
so quickly belina os operating system uh
that
is used for orchestrating and managing
the fleets of ioc
uh iot devices that you have it it it
makes it easier for the
for the managers of those iot devices
to manage them all at the same time
there is another there's another a
setting
in bellina os orchestration platform
that is called dns mask
that settings exclusively used for
bypassing the internal dns server
setting for
for all the uh for all the iot devices
and that was the reason
the clients the pos the point of sale
devices
were actually contacting the google dns
server versus our internal dns servers
for
some of the queries that they were doing
and uh
and the result was that they are
bypassing
so iot devices are pretty naive devices
they don't have been
built in security already you don't want
them to bypass your internal dns
firewall because
that is the minimum layer of protection
that you can provide to your iot devices
and if they are doing that you will get
annoyed right that why they are doing
that and
those are not trivial iot devices those
were the point of sale devices
there are small um kiosks that
university has set up for different kind
of events so that people can go and
buy tickets it is using our like
they should be pci compliant right it is
using credit card information
so a little hack and if they're
bypassing the dns firewall we would not
be able to uh
uh protect them so the result is uh
we checked for the apr.balenacloud.com
and they all were doing the uh
api call for that cloud and we uh found
those poc device pos devices point of
sale devices
we talked to the person who manages them
and then we asked them to turn that
setting off so by default it is on so if
you guys are using bolina os
make sure that that setting is off so
that your iot devices do not bypass your
firewall
and the second again is evast the
remaining ips we're doing the queries
both
the internal as well as external dns
servers avest has something called real
site protection
which kind of like builds an encrypted
connection from the uh
client's host to the dns servers that
avast hosts
and the reason for doing that is they
say that they protect the clients from
the dns hijacking
and but the thing is that all the web
browsing traffic goes to their goes to
their dns
observers but all the remaining
application level os uh
os level dns queries and responses still
go through the internal dns server so
that was the reason
why we were seeing both internal as well
as external dns queries from the clients
who were running avast
um fatima we have about four minutes
left
okay sounds good we are almost done so
and the result was uh we wrote up a
script that detects the at least five
kinds of um
anti-awareness solutions because
anti-viruses are very noisy and you can
easily pick them up from your dns.log
file or any other log file that
they appear in it so i just created a
script and we are we kind of like keep
running it constantly constantly and
whenever we see some somebody using
a different antivirus that is not
recommended by the institution
we just give them a heads up that hey we
pay for this enterprise level
anywhere else you might want to use that
but of course you cannot force them
okay so in conclusion
there is a lot of interesting activity
that you can find by just looking at the
dna.log file
and just the the main take away from
this uh discussion
is that not only the malware that uses
dns for the unconventional purposes but
also there are legit applications
that unknowingly well that knowingly
uses dns for
off-label use but you might not know
about them and if there are some
applications that are bypassing your
firewall just like ballina os then you
should know about them because
there are these default settings that
are automatically enabled and you need
to disable them if you
if you really want them to be protected
by your enterprise level
dns firewall so that was an interesting
um use case that we investigated with
dns.log file and that
i think i have just a minute or two to
see if there are any questions
yeah thank you very much fatima um
there's one question
um for seek notes for analyzing eight
gigabits
per second at peak um that's a lot of
hardware
is the seek rules used very cpu
intensive
it depends uh our hardware is pretty um
rugged so i said 300 000 pps
we have designed our hardware that each
box is capable of doing 1 million 1
million pbs per second
a 1 million pps rate so they are pretty
strong hardware that we use we do have a
lot of custom scripts but again
every script that you turn on in zeek
comes with a penalty of performance
so make sure that there is balance and
if you can upgrade up with your hardware
to support
latest and greatest custom scripts of
that you can run
cool thank you um then james asked um
so if everything is going to be dns over
https
and it's not visible what can we do
about that please
so this everything so what we have dns
for https again is coming it encrypted
we cannot do anything about it and
that's one of the reasons right to
protect the confidentiality of the
client
again if the browser there are
applications that are doing such kind of
videos behavior so it might be a while
for them to switch from using dns to dns
or https
because the reason these applications
legit applications are using dns is for
its fast performance
so it might be a while i'm not sure
whether they are going to
do it do a complete switch but yeah
that's a that's a good point we cannot
do anything about it
but it would be interesting to see if
these applications also move
simultaneously with
using dns over udp for its fast
performance or to dns or https which
might be a little slower
and most importantly browser-based
activity like client typing in into the
browser that activity might be
more dns or https but not like legit
application like mcafield because
these infractions are browser less right
mcafee ballina os
they internally do it there is no
induced interaction so
so maybe there's a there's some time
that these applications might take
to move away from that model to use dns
or https and how they're going to do
that
so until then we have happy hunting with
our unencrypted dns
cool um we have one one last question i
think we can squeeze that in
um omar commented that interesting
research
um did you use any specific tool to
gather or analyze these information
no make sure that you have data sources
it's no
special tool again i said that we
converged everything collected
everything in a seam
but even if you don't have the same
doesn't matter if you have your dns
log file from if you're running z get
that dns data and if you're running
internal dns servers of course you will
have that data you just have to ask for
it
so no special tool um just used zeke for
collecting our north south traffic and
use internal dns logs
cool so with that thank you very much
fatima
carton for for giving this presentation
i think it's a great example of
sharing research with the with the
incident response communities thank you
for that
and i think with that handing back to
josh thanks
thanks everyone