thank you for joining us today
just a few quick uh very excuse me very
quick reminders before we get started
all attendees are muted and if you're
using the event app we encourage you to
check into the session
update your activities and be sure to
complete the sessions survey at the end
this session is tlp white and is being
recorded
recordings will be available within 24
hours via the conference app
and with that i'd like to introduce you
to your session moderator
natsuko annui and i will throw it over
to her
thanks so much thank you for staying
so hello everybody this is mitsuko inui
and i will be moderating this session
today
today you are attending the session
scaling
vulnerability coordination um just one
item before we get started
so we ask that you submit your questions
for q a through the q a section in the
zoom
screen you have the questions will be
queued in the order they are received
and with that let's go ahead and get
started so i will start by introducing
your speaker today
for this uh session so francis perron
is at google in incident response
he is actually from canada but is
currently now in switzerland
he has joined google 2017 and started
out in site-related engineering
site reliability engineering and has
since moved on through several different
roles including responding to
availability incidents
across the google production environment
and to
full-time digital forensics and instant
response role
uh with which is where he has been since
2017.
so with that i think i will turn the
tables over to you francis take it away
thank you hi everybody um
so thank you for joining me and uh yeah
let's see
let's see how this virtual conferencing
uh pans out
so it's gonna be my first preference
first presentation entirely online so
let's see how we fare um so today i
wanted to
present a case study essentially uh
the approach that google took to try and
scale
uh the classic pcert structure
so this is
again a case study because um this is
going to be we're going to
look at the proposal that we made and
how it worked out because
earlier in 2020 this is when we started
implementing and looking into this
so before getting started um a little
a little um a little bit about
nomenclature here
so the word pcert so product security um
the way that i'm gonna be referring and
using it and the material that i have is
really
around these vulnerabilities that are
kind of time sensitive very complicated
very complex
cross product cross pas inside inside
companies
the impact is spread and there's also a
need for coordinated vulnerability
disclosure
so uh the single product impact
vulnerabilities are not really in scope
for
this case study as well as what we
worked on
this is already being dealt with for us
internally with we have a fairly large
security team at this point which
satisfied pretty much all of these
little like one product vulnerability
issues when there's a new cvs
like coming out in the public and so on
we have automation that takes care of
that in general but
the bigger problem arises when we have
coordination
needs across either internally or
external aspects of it
and that coordination actually so
one thing that we have internally at
google is uh this protocol that we've
it's not invented at all it's just that
we've we've reused something called ics
and we've adapted it to our needs
internally
and we call it incident management at
google now this has been discussed and
presented in
other material namely we have a book by
the sre organization that goes into very
much
a lot of details and i won't i just want
to brush up on it because it's important
for the proposal
so the core and this structure this
response protocol
allows us to actually use uh
the scaling methods that we have here
one thing so this the protocol itself
has at the core
the incident coordinator so incidents
and vulnerabilities are very similar to
one another
and we'll get to that but for instance
this
this protocol is shared across
engineering so
the incident coordinator is a role that
basically takes care of the incident
they are responsible to make sure that
the incident is going smoothly
we have enough people we don't have too
many people
and it's also the role of the decision
maker during the incident typically
especially for availability issues you
get time pressure
around decision making the internet
coordinator takes that role
now under that role under that person
we typically have sub-roles or leads as
we refer to them
and the ol the ops lead so
operations lead tends to be the person
who fixes the issue or is responsible to
do so
and that means that they have to and
they're responsible to build a team
that will fix the issue you see the
little periodic
symbol on top of it here this reference
is uh this is just to illustrate the
fact that you can have multiple
operations lead
in a bigger incident for example if you
need to split the incident and sub
aspects or subtactical responses this is
where this would be multiplied
another lead role that is fairly
critical to most incidents
is communications so a communications
lead would be responsible for
communications inside and outside of
incidents sometimes split
as well for press or internal comms
and so on and a little
little star here because this structure
is very simple and very lightweight
we tend to like it allows for scaling up
and down
in the number of leads as well as the
size of the response
if for example an incident requires
a legal person to give advice well then
we would elect a legal lead
so that's what i mean here by like
depending on the incident
you will scale this up as needed this is
for incident
but turns out vulnerability management
is very close to this um
you know it's a very simple very well
it's a big difference but
as far as coordinating it's pretty much
the same
so what we are doing is that we're
reusing entirely the whole protocol
we're just calling it vulnerability
coordinator instead of incident
coordinator
to make everyone happier about it and
at the level of the operations lead for
vulnerabilities this tends to be
per product because you need a certain
level of expertise and knowledge that
one person does not typically have or
can gather for like android and chrome
for example
those are two different beasts and when
an incident or
when a vulnerability touches on both or
impacts both we would have
of like an obsolete for chrome and then
upside for android
but the rest of the structure is
actually the same and
that's kind of the beauty of it because
the whole of the engineering corpus is
trained
in that protocol meaning that when we
have an incident
that impacts them and you know
an incident commander or coordinator
reaches out they know the protocol
they know what to expect and banking on
this
we can actually start scaling things and
by scaling here i mean that how do we
with a small group of people
respond to pretty much all vulnerability
like
all coordinated vulnerabilities as we
see them fly by
now according to the like not official
but the definitions that we see
in the wild namely one of them is
promoted by
the p cert the sir piecert sig at first
there was a document about it a couple
of years ago it basically discusses
centralized versus distributed and
includes an in between called hybrid
p cert uh structures the hybrid is kind
of like in between but the two extremes
are centralized versus distributed in
that case
now for a centralized p
cert this is actually nuts so we looked
into it and
for us at google it does not make much
sense uh the problem that we have is
that we have too many products and
you know we're not unique i mean a lot
of companies
share that problem and it's it becomes
very hard to have a central team that
basically has all of the expert
knowledge
to do security fixes security rollouts
uh
and implement these policies and so on
to so many other pas and products
so looking at this from like
as an implementation problem uh this
isn't something we
we can look into now on the other end of
the spectrum
the distributed model what we have here
is that we have a smaller team
that is part that is the pcert core team
and
next to that we basically interact and
leverage experts
across the various products now this is
actually getting interesting
but it means that we need security
experts or security savvy folks in most
of these products and pas
that kind of happens at google for us so
we're actually in a good place to look
into this
and the small core team is actually
really exciting as well because we can
get started we can pilot ideas much
faster and if we need to hire
a full team of staff expert security
engineers for example
so banking on that again
we picked the distributed approach and
kind of pushed it even further a little
bit
and this is where our implementation
comes in so me bert vert
is our proposal and solution so earlier
in 2020
we designed and started implementing
this
so the rotation itself is a so this is a
vulnerability incident response team now
the name is of kind of a mouthful and
you know we put vulnerability and
incident response team in one word
internal nomenclature rules and so on
essentially
it's a rotation that is staffed by
volunteers
and here these volunteers actually come
from everywhere and
volunteering for us internally at google
means
using this 20 project that we get
so as part of our contract we're
basically allowed to use 20
of our time to do personal projects
personal growth projects
uh that could also include working in
other teams just to help out to discover
things
so using that we're actually
using people's 20 projects to contribute
to an incident response team that
focuses on vulnerabilities
with that it allows us to also have a
very small core team
that is associated with the rotation and
this is again using the distributed
model approach
this we've kind of limited this to just
a little
minimum requirement set essentially
cross site cross time zone
and cross teams just to allow
the core team folks to go on vacation to
take time off to be sick
as simple as that sounds and it's even
more relevant nowadays i find
so we have a small team core team of
experts that have been doing
vulnerability coordination for a while
and are able to actually help and mentor
and assist
and a rotation and a couple of
volunteers so
what does it mean to volunteer and why
would people actually volunteer for this
so we found out that
we did a couple of recruitment campaigns
through email internally
and daniel i'm going to get to your
question in a second
and what we found is that the aspect
of career growth was really interesting
for folks because it's a very different
problem set
to most products most software
development problems that they have to
deal with
and at the same time security is
actually really interesting nowadays
so we see it more and more in the news
and folks actually
there is kind of an uptick in that trend
and
we're using this as well turns out folks
love it
and at the same time the third bullet
point here is really because
since we're dealing with volunteers
uh it's it's kind of hard to guarantee
that they will be around it's
essentially it's not part of their core
job
so the way we work with this is that we
get
kind of commitments not written down
contracts per se but
really a year-long commitment that you
will be a part of this rotation
and you're expected to give this many
hours and we get agreement
uh through the management chain of that
person as well which helps solidify
all of that and so far we've had really
good success here
now daniel's question was how do these
volunteers get trained in the area they
wish to support
i'll get to that in the last section of
the caveats
but essentially training we don't have
specialties
and that means that vulnerabilities are
the products impacted is agnostic to the
situation because of the
protocol that we use the incident
management protocol
it doesn't matter what incident or
vulnerability is being taken care of
and that's that's actually the beauty of
it
so does it work um
i think it does and well many of us
actually do agree here
and it's quite good because we've had uh
we've had so we started the program in
early 2020 recruitment started in
february just about
and we started training folks to like
coordination how to deal with
vulnerabilities and vulnerabilities in
general
what security topics uh mean and
what is it to have an embargo and how to
respect it and so on
so we've built training and we've kind
of gotten that down in the first
quarter and a half of the year i'd say
and at that point in the second quarter
just about
june or just about june
we started looping in rotators and
volunteers
into coordination of these
vulnerabilities
and one of them that actually was a nice
success story is
just about in july there was a
disclosure and this vulnerability called
boot hole
which i don't know if folks remember but
quickly it was uh
there was a problem with secure boot and
grub and the way
that shims could be exploited to
you know work on the white list and get
more binaries trusted which was an issue
so it turns out corporate environments
across various industries were impacted
hours was as well a little bit
so we needed to coordinate across
acquisitions
across corporate and some products who
may be impacted
for example like our google cloud stuff
do we need to loop in coordination as
well in there
so this vulnerability came in through an
usual pipeline and we decided okay let's
do a coordinated response internally at
least
this what ended up happening is a
classic so we ramped up a response with
a vulnerability
coordinator at the top and then an
operations lead who was basically our
technical person
working to help us make good judgment
call we also had someone taking care of
scoping and managing the impact on the
mergers and acquisitions
we also had someone who was basically
owning the communications
uh preparing the price statements and
all that just reactively and so
and we also had operations lead assigned
to each of the products impacted we knew
about
and externally to that there was also
external communication and sorry
coordination
so for example working with the
researchers and stuff like that the
classic
cvd issue and aspects
and when we started this response we
looped in two volunteers
from virt right off the bat who would
sit next to the coordinator
and they would basically get as much
context as we as possible
invited to every sync meetings and
decision making and shared with
documents and all that
and basically at the end of every
meeting that we had
i was a coordinator for that one and i
would just sit down
five minutes past the meeting and just
okay like
let's debrief a little bit do you have
any questions
and let's address those comments and
what went on and so on just
a quick five minute recap at the end of
every meeting turned out to be really
impactful here
towards the end well towards the end as
in close to the disclosure in july
i needed to sadly go on vacation in a
very uh
you know bad timing i guess you want to
call it but this was also a really good
opportunity for us and
what we did is we asked the volunteers
to take over
because they were trained we trusted
they would make a good judgment
and they did so we basically inserted
two volunteers
straight up took over the coordination
role and another volunteer
who was also shadowing during the whole
time took over communications leads
and that worked out real well and then
we kept someone senior
on the cvd aspects of it essentially
to maintain the relationship with the
researchers we did not actually do a
change at that level
but that was also a minimal amount of
communication that needed to happen
any further so for us this was a success
story and
it gave us hope that we would actually
be able to make something out of this
um since then so that was july now this
is a few months later
we've had other instances of these uh
like very similar scenarios uh
sadly a lot of these disclosures are not
possible for me to discuss here but and
but there's still like there's most of
our rotation
has been doing these shadow experiences
at this point
to the point where right now we have
ongoing vulnerabilities
that from time zero have gotten the
rotators to basically coordinate
and this is actually a very positive
outcome for us
now
of course since this is a young program
we're kind of still in the early stages
of it
from a program management perspective so
we're still developing
the whole structure of it and that means
how do we
streamline the training how do we
improve on it and we're doing that right
now we're kind of like working with the
rotation
people to just say like what worked and
what didn't how to how do we
together build a better program here how
do we ensure mentoring
is consistent and high quality and
involves and interests people
working on these two aspects
simultaneously and
um i'm going to get to that question a
second
and maturing this further so basically
what we mean here is
how do we make this self-sustained
sustained of sorts
as in what happens with the recruits
from last year
do we ask them to give their spot to
somebody else or do we take these folks
and make them you know train them into
even more senior contributors
which would actually help out in the
longer term but we
we're working on these on these ideas
and we're going to be exploring this in
the early 2021
uh stage there's a
do these rotators also coordinate with
external teams in case of cross-company
coordination
in some cases yes we've had we've had
successes
where basically when we engage with the
external
companies or researchers we basically go
in pairs
and the main coordinator always stays
basically on the line or as a backup and
drives the communication at first but
always loops in
the rotator who then starts taking more
and more space into that
so yeah we do have rotators basically
managing external or
inter-company coordination in some cases
now there's the other aspect of it which
is um
how do we deal with very urgent
vulnerabilities and
that's actually a legit question
given this is a rotation of volunteers
we don't really
we can't expect folks to do 24 7
contributions to a response
uh google tends to have 24 7
like just we call it follow the sun
response or coverage in general
so if we have an issue oh
if we have an issue and it requires
hourly updates and so on we call these p
zeros so right now the program's not
able
and staffed to handle that kind of
pressure or demand so we are still
working with our incident management
team who has been historically dealing
with these things
so we're working with them still the
goal here is really so that the program
gets more mature develops itself into
something more structured and we can
remove some of these
p0 vulnerabilities from the incidents
the incident management team
but that's not going to happen right now
we're looking at how we can design this
and work with this in the future
that's actually all the material i had i
wanted to
thank you all to attend like for
attending this
little note here there's some
information like some contact
information for me so if you have
questions
that you prefer to send over emails or
discuss privately
just feel free to reach out by email i
do have a twitter account but
don't expect me to be too much on this
um i it's created
it works uh the last point here is that
we are planning to actually try and
write up
and publish a white paper on this as
well so hopefully we'll be able to
actually go into further details about
this and
uh we will also have like
more experience and works uh more
history so that we can actually expand
on some of these things that worked and
didn't so hopefully pandemic willing
as written here so that's all i had um
thank you very much and i'm happy to
answer questions
from here on francis so
uh you addressed both questions i think
that are in
the um uh q and a um
what i was wondering so if somebody
listening wanted to become
involved um and get the
um training and join
uh do they just contact you or is there
something they go through oh you mean
get access to the actual training
material we did yes
at the moment it's very internal because
we do discuss
of vulnerabilities that we've had to
deal with and what kind of impact and
response we've made for them
so this the material as as is is
definitely not
publishable externally but if you're
curious i'm happy to
basically go over the steps like this is
pretty generic in the sense of cbd
training
so yeah if you've had to deal with
coordination with cross company stuff
or if you haven't actually there's some
good resources already on the pcert sig
at first yeah okay
thank you so another question has popped
up so do you plan to publish security
advisories in machine possible format
like ca
csaf
so that's kind of a i think that's out
of topic a little bit
uh i do not know what the plans are
for that like as far as we're concerned
like
these this team or this program
really focuses on coordination of
vulnerability disclosures
uh and also like the internal responses
we may need and
stuff like that it doesn't really scope
out the security advisory aspects
of impacted products and how we
communicate because
the like our the google cloud products
actually
communicate outside through security
advisories so sometimes these actually
make it out
i think those actually follow a very
handwritten format
at the moment if you're asking for like
something that has enough structure to
be processed uh
cves and cpes are pretty much
what i can think of at the moment that
we have like that is very public
chrome also has advisories project zero
also but those
those tend to be manually generated
thomas i'm sorry
i hope that answers a little bit of your
question
thank you so if there aren't
any more questions at the moment if you
had anything else that you wanted to say
but
actually cut out of your presentation
because of time restrictions i think
um you have a couple of moves to go
through that or we can
maybe end early oh one more question
what have you learned so far what have
we learned so far is that um
this idea of using volunteers to
handle like critical vulnerabilities was
scaring a lot of people especially
like senior managers and uh so we went
about it very cautiously
at the end of the day though like six
months in we were
showing really positive results which
even surprised us
so i think what we learned is that it's
surprisingly
feasible to actually train folks in a
very generic
like coordination aspect of things
uh like we're we're really happy with
the results that we've had
and we really want to see how far we can
push this even further
and that's why we're actually having
folks lead full
vulnerability responses up to uh
recently
and again super positive i couldn't have
some better results like inside a year
so yeah so that's excellent thanks for
asking lisa
okay so there's actually one more
question so
um uh i joined late and may have missed
it but
what teams are you inviting to
participate as volunteers how do you
know they can do the work
it's a good question so when we first
did the first recruitment
of emails essentially i targeted very
generic
roles essentially
the for the first wave we looked at
candidates who were
in engineering and in roles of either
program management technical program
management like all of these together
as well as engineering like software
engineering
site reliability engineering we also
have
folks that are a bit more junior on the
tech ladders and we've actually included
some of those folks as well just to
see and we have a lot of variety at this
point we don't actually have
anybody from security on that rotation
so that has also been like something
folks weren't sure about but
turns out if you have passionate people
it actually works well
yes um actually another question
so i have read that you published the
bleeding tooth vulnerability i was just
wondering
why it is not in nvidia yet it's only in
reserve
status is that usual when you publish
such critical vulnerabilities
so this question sadly shouldn't be
addressed to me
so intel agreed and owns the cve
publications for these we
i can ping them and see if they're ready
to issue but generally speaking i think
that they have
a regular cadence of issuing so it might
be in the next
revision or the next push that they have
i'm sorry i don't have a good
answer for you on that one okay with
that i think
we are pretty much just at um our time
so
thank you francis and thank you for all
the lively questions
um lots of comments saying that this is
a very good idea interesting
um initiative for google to do and
i find many people are very interested
in what google is doing
so thank you again francis for this very
interesting wonderful presentation and
thank you
for the audience for participating in
this session today
um so the next session will begin in
just about five minutes
so please i'll jump on to your next
scheduled session
i'll have a nice day have a nice
conference and
see you all soon thank you very much
awesome thanks again everyone
be safe thank you