thank you for joining us today
just a few very quick reminders before
we get started
all the attendees are muted if you're
using the event app we encourage you to
check into the session
update your activities and be sure to
complete the session survey at the end
this session is tlp white and is being
recorded
recordings will be available within 24
hours via the app
and with that i'd like to introduce you
to your session moderator
natsuko take it away thank you
thank you um hi everyone this is
i'll be moderating this session today uh
you're at the session
scan analyze and test data oh my how to
get over the results rainbow
um just one thing before we get started
so
we ask that you submit your questions
for the q a in the q a section
on the q a function in your zoom window
the questions will be queued up in the
order they are received
and with that i would like to go ahead
and get started
and i will start by introducing our
speakers today
so we have two speakers from nvidia
um and they are both um
senior application developer and lead
product security tools team
um so we have jessica and dee
so jessica is a senior application
developer and lead for
nvidia's product security tools team and
she has
13 over 13 years of experience
and earned her master's in computer
engineering from washington university
in st louis
she also has her certifications in java
ruby and cisco's the cna
and d anachae is a senior
development leader at nvidia's security
tools platform team
um she has 14 years of experience in the
software industry and she specializes in
architecting and
delivering reliable and scalable systems
in a variety of areas
especially online services and with that
i will turn the tables over to jessica
and dee for their presentation
thank you thank you
okay welcome to scan
analyze and test data oh my getting over
the results rainbow
i have d today go ahead d if you would
like to introduce yourself yeah
absolutely
really good introductions already so
yeah i know thanks natsuko for a great
introduction but
i will just add i've been at nvidia for
over uh two years now
and i'm really excited to share our
registration and reporting platform with
you guys
and uh i am jessica butler i've been
with the security tools team
at nvidia for a little over three years
um i've had the privilege of being one
of the founding members for the
application we're going to share today
inspect
and actually looking at this picture
makes me a little sad this was
after the last first conference we were
able to travel still
in portugal so hopefully soon we'll be
out again
okay so today i want to talk a bit about
our journey
and kind of how we have landed where we
are and where we are in our journey
and where we started and all the
struggles that have gone on so far
so we'll start with kind of the pitfalls
of a manual process
of working on getting some
scanning applications and all the data
around that for
our product teams at nvidia and we'll
talk about some of the different
um applications that we actually use for
scanning and the data that we are trying
to
make sense of and try to present in a
way that actually is actionable for our
teams
then we'll talk a little bit about how
we are cataloging our software portfolio
at nvidia
and then we'll move on to kind of where
we landed with
how we could actually put the onus back
on the teams for registering
all of their applications and their data
themselves then d will take over
and talk more about how we're mapping
the data so that we can get all of our
information into a single pane in a
place where we can
see everything together and a much
easier way to visualize
the risk that all of our software has or
hopefully doesn't have
um along with that we've learned kind of
along the way that we need to be able to
automate notifications so she'll go into
some of the notifications that we're
sending out to our product
owners and how we can automate
automate the issue management and
getting all of the tickets in a place
where the product teams are used to
finding them after that we'll touch on
calculating risk and we would love to
have some questions and have some
of the audience share with us at that
point
so when i started at nvidia um i had
already been a developer
for about i guess 11 years so i came and
i
was new to security so i came onto the
security team um
wanting to really kind of build an
application around
the scanning process but the way things
kind of
started was we
we already had a tool that we knew we
wanted to use for
um open source vulnerability scanning
and so
we would we kind of let the product
teams know that we had this tool and we
started asking people to have these
scans done
and before we were ready with the
application we had teams that would just
reach out to us via email
or slack or whatever the
i guess choice of communication was at
that time
tell us that they were ready to do a
release and they knew that they needed
to have a scan done
before they could release so we would
gather the source location
um run the scanning tool and then
obviously there was more than one
source code location that was associated
to a product so we'd have to manually
group that data and then we would
would ship that report off to the
requester
and some of the tools that we were using
at that time
or actually some of the tools that we're
using now
show data in a way like this so we're
looking at some of the
user interfaces for the scanning tools
that we use
you can see here this one you can see
the different
open source components that were found
you can see some of the
open source vulnerabilities and the
security risk over here
you can see the different licenses and
then if you drill down into these then
you can get more information
and also we use coverity um and you can
see
basically the id of the vulnerability
that's found
in this case it looks like somebody
needed to scrub this
so i just grabbed a screenshot of one
project um
you can see the impact you can see first
detected
and for check marks you see something
that looks a little bit similar where
you get your kind of your your risk down
here
but again all of these things are kind
of foreign and for you to be able to
understand what each
of the different scan tools are trying
to tell you
and learn how to use each one and how to
drill down into each one
takes time and we don't really want to
push that onto all of our product teams
it's hard enough to get them to start
the security process
alone so
we wanted to be able to grab all this
data together and
display it in a way that makes sense for
not only the owners of each of the
products but all the way up to the
org3 leader or the the vps executives
that
actually own all of this so that they
can understand the risk that they are
shipping
so we started by defining how do we want
to
actually catalog all this information in
our database
so we knew we needed like a top level
product
this is something that is shippable or
deployable we know we need
executive ownership at this level so
that we can drive these
actions and we allow versioning and we
want to make sure that we can capture
end of life after that we need to be
able to break this down into how are
things built how do things go together
how is ownership defined at a component
level and also we know that there are
many components at the or in the
organization that
are shared among many products so we
have this logical segregation
that's known as a component and it can
have
um many source code locations in it so
many source code repositories
it can be found in many products we want
to make sure that we have the ownership
at this level and we do we do marry this
kind of to a build
the next thing that we need to be able
to
show in the database is the dependencies
how things are related
so we know we have internal components
already we can also have external open
source software and external third-party
software
and we know we need to be able to have a
nested relationship with this so we
built this into our database
and then since the the first kind of
service that we
offered was this open source scanning
solution we wanted to make sure that we
highlight the things that are open
source
so we can actually track any
versioning there and the vulnerability
mapping
and then we do have a service now in
place where
we check every night for all of our
source code repositories to see if
there's been any commits and we will
rescan to see if
the fix has been applied so we do fix
verification
okay so we had all the data in the
catalog and we started to actually
um put some of this data in there in
in your own org if you're thinking about
trying to do something like this which i
highly recommend
it would be a good place to like at this
point kind of stop and see is there a
way that you could seed the data for
this
so that you can uh kind of
pre-initialize any level of this
most likely the top level where you have
the the business units and
the organization and who owns each
product we weren't able to actually
um get all the information that we
needed at this point and my guess is
that
you will not be able to find everything
that you need down to the granularity
that you're going to want to understand
how things are built how things are put
together
and be able to easily collate all those
results
into a proper story i guess
so we were still kind of in the mode of
manually entering this data ourselves
and we had the idea of
creating this self-service registration
platform so that
we could actually tell the users you
should go update this
or you should go add in your new program
and we could kind of take the the data
owning and the data
um mining i guess off of our plates so
we could focus on what we really want to
do and automate the scanning and and try
to build a better dashboard for the
security risk
so that's kind of how the self-service
registration tool was born
so how our tool looks right now is we
ask the user to come in and add any and
add the product info
at this point they can add new versions
for that product
they can update anything um in regards
to any of the information that you're
about to see
once we have the product info we have
some required contacts
so at this time we require owner
and direct our bu vp sorry
and then we have some security contacts
that are required as well
um our pcert team works really closely
with us so there's a lot of pcert
contacts that are required at this time
as well
the next step that we decided is
probably the best way to move forward is
to
actually understand how everybody at the
company is building
their projects so we do have at nvidia a
few
um homegrown build tools we also use
jenkins and we use
gitlab so we wanted to actually
understand all the different build tools
that people are using
as well as you know where we can find
the artifacts
once we can start doing some binary
scanning as well
so that's why we're asking for the the
build information we also can refresh
any of the source code locations that
are found in the builds since we already
have this information
so once a week we can go through and
actually make sure that all the source
code locations that we have detected
through the build information
is updated and we're still up to date or
we can contact the team
and let them know that you know we've
got some stale data
at this point when we ask them for the
build information we
we always validate that we can access it
so that's where you're seeing this check
mark right here
if we cannot access it we don't actually
add it to our database at this time
and we'll give them some warning
messages that they can
use to try to go figure out why we're
not able to access it or maybe it's just
a typo and they need to try again
so when they click next after they enter
their build information
we create components in the database and
we actually look
at the build and grab the source code
locations from that
so that's what you're seeing down here
we also allow
teams to enter manually any source code
locations
in case maybe they're using a script for
build that's necessary
that we can't actually parse or if they
don't
have a build set up yet
the next step is linking some services
that as the security tools team we don't
own at this time
so in the case of check marks and
coverity these have already
these tools have already been set up by
other um
teams at nvidia and so we just need to
get the mapping so that we can
add the project information add all the
scan data into our dashboards
we also get check marks here but i
didn't sorry i forgot to grab a
screenshot of that one
and that's it when they click next after
that page
they'll get this summary and it gives
them a little bit more information
about what they can do next we have in
pipeline scanning
as well so using the same
scanning tools that we already use for
open source
vulnerability scanning we can actually
add that to
their pipeline so once they have
finished registration and they reach out
to us
we can add that we're also working on
trying to get some
better documentation so that teams can
add that without having to reach out to
us
but it is a newer thing since we're we
are
trying to get that into their pipeline
after they register they also get a
report
link the next day and then d will go
over some more of those notifications as
well
if there's anything that we're missing
we also add that into these areas to
improve
and then they do get links to the
dashboards at this point
but uh they actually are not populated
until a scan is done
we wanted to make sure that they're not
just sitting here during registration
waiting for a scan to be done
so they'll see the scan and the
dashboards the next day
and i'm going to go ahead and pass it on
to d so she can go over how we're
mapping all the data and kind of how our
dashboards are turning out
yeah thank you jessica so now you have
of your work done where you have a team
that has registered using the
registration portal
about within 10 minutes so how do we get
to the reports
so you have all the data that they gave
you at the registration in our portfolio
database
and then you have these different
scanning services that you're linking to
these programs that are registered
so how do we get to the single pane view
of having all the results consolidated
and married to the hierarchy that they
registered with
so that question is answered by our
reporting platform
um in order to solve this we were
thinking about different routes of how
could we get this information
into one single data source and at that
point we thought that an elegant
solution of doing this for us
could be microservice architecture and
the reason of moving to microservice
architecture was
uh primarily two reasons uh one is
an ability for us to easily scale when a
new tool is added
so say for right now we have these three
services that are being linked
uh to the programs that are registered
one is open source scanning service
other is a static analysis service which
was your check marks and coverity
uh one could be a dynamic analysis
service but say tomorrow we wanted to do
a container emit scanning
we wanted to be able to add uh a service
that could grab data from
that particular service without disper
disturbing the core platform
so what we have here is a bunch of
network of microservices
which are grabbing data from individual
services
marrying it with the information that
the user gave us
at registration and then kind of having
it
into our reporting platform at this
point
the reporting solution that we decided
to use was elasticsearch kibana
so elasticsearch being our backend data
store and we
are leveraging the kibana visualizations
and dashboards
so we have our services running nightly
and refreshing
all the data from the scan results for
all the programs that are registered
and this is the sample of the single
pane dashboard
it's much of a simplified version so
that you can see it clearly
so what you see on your left hand pane
is the results from the open source
software scan
you can see at the top we have
vulnerability is kind of divided into a
pie chart
so that the users can see which ones are
critical which ones are medium
and then we also have kind of divided
them by the packages that that we found
and on the right hand side you see that
we have results from the static analysis
tool so in this case it was check marks
the idea here is that we should be able
to add more panes as we introduce new
services
so like i said if we have a container
image scanning
we would just add more visualizations to
this pane we don't want the product
teams to be going
and chasing down the different tools
that we are using
and kind of maintaining those ui so
this is where they would come this is
where project management would come
and i want to talk a little bit about
that here about the filtering
we wanted to make sure that the reports
are uh kind of dynamic
in sense of say tomorrow we have a team
that is planned to register
uh we wanted the reporting to be
automatic so we are using the dynamic
filtering
so that the email that goes out is
always focusing on the report that is
having the scan results for their team
and this is the sample of um another
kind of report that we have which is
more of a details report
which is targeted towards the engineer
who would be taking
a look at this so like i said all in one
single pane
at the top you can see the results from
the oss scan
which is the open source software and at
the bottom you can see the check marks
and the here they are able to kind of
see which packages were found what are
the vulnerabilities associated with the
package
what is the fix recommended by the tool
that we use
and same for check marks
so now we have the reporting platform we
have registration taken care of we have
reporting
but we still need to maintain that
active communication with the user base
that has
um signed up with us so we have a
notification platform so that we are
more in control of our communication
so i wanted to walk you guys through
some of the notifications that we are
sending
um once the team registered we are
sending an initial report the next day
with the scans that have been linked to
their registration
we also want to be able to have a weekly
email
so that they can plan their sprints
better so i know some teams are more
proactive in fixing their issues but we
thought that it would be good
to remind the teams every monday that
this is where you stand because our
dashboards are
updated nightly so there's nothing that
is stopping from them to
go to their dashboards anytime so we
have that weekly report um
then we have a new cve report so there
are teams who are releasing
uh software um almost every day in a ci
cd fashion
and once they have gone through that
security process and they've released
their software we wanted to let them
know that it's not
really over because new vulnerabilities
are constantly discovered for the
packages
that we found so we want to be able to
let them know that
for this package that is in production
there is a new vulnerability that
was now discovered and you might want to
take a look into that
we also had a requirement from our pcr
team where
they have channels and pipelines where
they are able to
know about undisclosed vulnerability and
we wanted to give them
an ability to create a notification
manually where we could let the teams
know saying that we are aware about this
vulnerability and these are the
different teams
and if you remember now inspect has that
ability to find
for this particular package say five
teams within nvidia are using it so we
have that package discovery alert
and last but not the least uh kind of a
portfolio health kind of a notification
so we have all this beautiful inventory
of builds
repositories and static analysis
projects that we have from teams
so we nightly go and make sure that we
still have the right required data we
still have the contacts
and we are kind of letting them know
that these are the things that you still
need to take care of looks like this
repository was deleted
looks like you have moved your branch
and you need to go back to registration
and update that info
so you have your reporting you have your
notification but how do you really make
sure
that the issues that you are telling
them about
are remediated what is the policy for
enforcing it
so we wanted to kind of uh do this issue
tracking service or
issue tracking platform and here are
some of the things that we needed to
take care before we do that
so when we talk to the product teams
about us being able to create
issues into their preferred tool uh some
of the things that we
came to know is that different product
teams have different policies
so we wanted to make sure that our issue
management platform is able to honor
something like a bring your own policy
because different teams
uh work with different security
architects who know more about
the use cases that are relevant to their
business scenarios
so they could have different policies
and we wanted to make sure that the
issue tracking system is aware about
those policies
another thing we wanted to take care was
a deduplication of the bugs before we
create them
nobody wants to get up in the morning
and see thousands of bucks created in
their jira
so we wanted to make sure that we work
with our pc team closely to make sure
that we create bugs that are more
actionable
so for example one of the metrics by
which we are deciding to open bugs
is by a package and vulnerability
combination
so that we don't open thousands of
issues and we
give we try to give optimal information
in that one issue that is created
we also wanted to kind of look at the
nuance of prioritization
which is a little different from
severity of a particular vulnerability
we wanted to make sure that um the issue
management
um platform um kind of understands
that uh hi i'm gonna give you an example
a high of a vulnerability which has
severe high severity doesn't mean that
it
always necessarily translates into high
priority
for example there could be a source code
within nvidia which is more of a
core component which is shared by more
than 10
business units which are critical to the
business and if a vulnerability is found
associated to that package
we wanted to make sure that the issue
management is kind of customizing the
priority on that issue
and last but not the least the most
requested feature is allow listing
uh we wanted to make sure that maybe in
pipeline
and this is more actually critical in
or maybe with our nightly scans we are
always allowing our teams to kind of
make progress
by having a feature where they could
come in and say that for this particular
package
or for this particular vulnerability we
are aware about it
but it's associated with a test platform
or
it is related to a transitive dependency
that we don't have really control on
um or we are very early in our stages
and and we want to fix it later so we
want to be
able to have our issue management
platform
a kind of allow listing feature that
would let them make progress
and calculating risk now that you have
reports
notification issue tracking the final
part of goal like we say we want to be
able to kind of calculate
a risk for a registered program with
inspect
so here are some of the things that we
are still in the process of ironing out
before we can get to a place where we
have an objective
risk associated with every program so
one of the things that we need to
consider
is that the risk that we associate is
normalized and what i mean by that is
different programs or different business
units
can be at a different stage with inspect
registration
so some of the teams could be coming in
and have 90 percent of their code
register or even 100
and some of the teams might not be ready
yet and have about 10 percent of their
code registered
so when we calculate a risk into our
report dashboard we want to make sure
that we account for that factor we want
to make sure that when we calculate risk
it multifaceted and what i mean by that
is the severity versus priority
discussion that we just had
with the issue we want to make sure that
we are accounting for
custom policies and um shared code
before we kind of
assess the risk for a particular program
we want to be able to take a look at
the vulnerabilities when they were
disclosed how long have they been
sitting into their
reporting platform and we also want to
be able to know that
a particular vulnerability can be
more public and it could uh be more
critical in terms of our pizza than
others
and the severity can be like a plain
measure to us as that
and last but not the least we want to be
able to get to a place like i said where
we want
we have an objective risk associated so
we have been thinking
of ideas like a scorecard which would be
a number
like a percentage number between 0 to
100 that we could assign with a program
but at the same time it should be
explainable or it should be measurable
so our project management as well as our
teams can
clearly assess what is the risk
associated with that program
so at this point i would really like to
open it up to you guys if you want to
share what are the steps you are taking
to get to that pot of gold which is a
risk associated to a program
in your company or if you have other
questions we would
love to take them as well at this time
thank you we have a few minutes i think
and i will try to run through as many
questions as we possibly can
so first question would you think a bank
could use
pcred approach in general and your
specific approach instead of a normal
c-cert
since they usually have many products
for example online services
i am not sure about the difference
between c-cert and p-cert if you would
be able to go all the way away from cser
but i definitely think that you could
organize it in a way that
um maybe allow the products of the bank
to be cataloged and then have
dashboards for them in this way do you
have any other thoughts on that dee
yeah no that makes sense i think uh
whatever we are doing with our
automation in terms of different steps
of registering
reporting issue management and
notification that applies to csr as well
not just pcert okay
so next question i'm just going to fire
these at you so
how do you handle how do you handle
feedback from your teams from the
reports they receive
i'm thinking especially about false
positives and issues
risk acceptance is it just some kind of
filter
on off or something more so it can also
benefit other teams
yeah that's kind of i think the biggest
thing that we're dealing with manually
right now um
so because we have over a hundred and
did you say 160 now products yeah we
have registered
yeah so the amount of source code that
we're scanning
with the tool um compared to the number
of people that we have on the security
tools team
we can't really manually go through all
of them ourselves so
um we were trying to come up with ideas
of how we could build
that sort of thing into the tool maybe
have a way where somebody could come in
and give us like
um you know a rating on how well they
think that the tool did and we would be
able to take that back and actually
use some machine learning to help our
reports
aggregate things better any other
thoughts on that dee yeah no and some of
the tools that we work with
have a way that you can um tell
or remediate a particular vulnerability
by giving them more information about
the version that the user is directly
telling you rather than the one they
discovered
so we are trying to come up with a way
that we integrate that into our ui
by making api calls to the underlying
tools
yeah i think our first approach really
is this allow listing so having
teams open up exceptions with the pcr
team so that
we can still track those but then have a
way to filter those out
thank you next question how do you
identify false positives in scan reports
before showing them in your dashboard
i think that really relates probably to
the last one as well
at this point we don't have a great way
to identify false positives
so it's kind of on the team to go and
tell us what is a false positive so we
can dig into that more
because there's no way that we can
understand all of the source code
unfortunately
at the company yeah i think developers
know about their code the best so we
definitely need to partner with product
teams
although one of the ideas that jessica
and i have talked about is probably
cross referencing between different
tools
so we could potentially build a system
where the source code is scanned by
multiple tools and then we try to do a
union
of there is a intersection of result to
kind of get closer
to reducing the false positives
okay and two more questions i'm going to
try to squeeze in so
uh have you developed criteria to
semi-automate this prioritization or is
this left for manual analysis
uh right now um the way
this is working is like we said we are
taking a lot of feedback manually from
the product teams
uh but the way um this could be
automated
is uh by having features by which we
would allow
uh something like bring your own policy
which is currently under development
so that what we couldn't do is um for a
specific team they could define their
policy by working with their security
architect and our platform would just
ingest that
and then that way the priority that our
issue tracking
system is aware about is more custom to
what they bring in
anything more jessica i think at this
point it is a manual analysis
um but yes we we're hoping to get to it
some sort of semi-automated i also think
that
knowing which source code locations or
repositories are used in the most places
and the components that are used in the
most products will give us
kind of a best roi so we could kind of
drive those down first
so that would be a pretty easy way to
automate because we could just easily
see that
okay so final question so this is a very
impressive process and platform are
there any plans to make it open source
which might be difficult but
overall the platform is great so hoping
for it
well thank you at this point i don't
think there's been
plans to make it open source um
but who knows there have been
discussions to offer it
uh outside of nvidia for other companies
but
uh there haven't been talks about making
it open source
yeah okay so i think
um we're three minutes over so i think
we will
hand it over um hand it over no we land
this session
so thank you dee and jessica for this
wonderful presentation and thank you to
all the participants for
an engaging session with all of your
questions um thank you all so this is
the
last um i think breakout session of the
day and
the keynote will be next in about 20
minutes
so please um i'll take a break grab a
coffee
and join the keynote and i hope you have
a wonderful rest of your day
and a wonderful first conference so
thanks again dee and jessica and
everybody that came
thank you bye