moderating um please submit your
questions for
the q a in the q a section at the bottom
and questions will be queued in the
order received
um so i'd like to welcome
safa and aaron leverett
desiree is a security architect for a
security operations center in the
financial
industry and i think her ultimate goal
is to create
intelligent processes um
aaron is a senior scientist at airbus
operations
co-author of solving cyber risk and
founder of vicinity risks
so the talk is the intelligent process
life cycle of active cyber defenders and
last year
uh jessie uh presented her taxonomy for
documenting
and improving a sock user case quality
it was very interesting and now
they'll talk about how to bring back
intelligence to more first level
security tasks
uh tasks by extending the concept to
more uh first level security
verification disciplines
we establish the state of security that
can help you initiate improvement
steps using in-house information
and this should be something everybody
should be interested in so
take it away thank you very much for the
introduction
so i'm just gonna quickly start into
because it's a lot of information that i
want to transmit here in this short
presentation
i'm uh i'm a now principal security
architect
um for the operational part of uh
finance informatics
which is a german i.t service provider
for the german savings banks so we do
lots of finance stuff
and i'm aaron leverett joining you from
the lowlands of cambridge instead of the
highlands
of switzerland and i'm a senior
scientist in cyber innovation which is
uh you know it sounds like it's a
made-up sort of term but
basically we do r d and my focus there
is on r d in the risk space
thank you so i'm gonna jump in
right with where i ended last year so
for those who haven't seen the
presentation last year
um this is gonna add on the taxonomy
that i published last year
last year all of the information was
pushed to my github
and first actually even sponsored a
peer-reviewed version of that paper that
i
published about two years ago so this
can
all of the links and everything can be
found on that git top
now last year i presented those eight
categories and my main goal was
to make security monitoring a little bit
easier on the analysts and to show where
their problems were coming from because
lots of the alerts that the analysts you
get are like coming from everywhere
and they divided it by if it was caused
by a process problem or a configuration
problem
if the stock can actually do something
about it or if some
member of the company an engineer for
example needs to do some adjustments
and i wanted to get some quality results
on how the products are actually working
and
of course the most important ones were
the confirmed attack with fire actions
and the confirmed attack attempt without
the ir actions which pretty much means
that they accepted the risk that you
don't go further with the alerts
at hackaloo i presented the
kpis or some kpis that i would suggest
that we could take
from those tech from this taxonomy and
this talk was also recorded the link
can be found on the github as well and
at cybercrimecon from group ib
i went on and created some external
thread heat map which is actually based
on only the confirmed attack um with ir
actions and the confirmed attack
attempts without ir action so pretty
much what you should be seeing from
outside and it was combined with some
mighty attack techniques
and critic from the criticality sorted
and i also
created those internal security heat
maps which were more based on the
internal stuff that is going wrong so
unannounced admin actions
and detection device rule configuration
errors all of that kind of stuff
so now we have this update and
this is pretty much caused by the
reasoned and well we all have been going
more towards cloud
and um after um hackaloo i was
approached to actually
translate this whole taxonomy
to compliance and integrity monitoring
just to make sure that we can also
see the configuration of such devices
and
i'm still convinced that detection of
configuration changes especially in the
cloud are also very important
and the stock service quality reflects
overall security quality of state so
i mean if if the stock is the one place
where you get all of the alerts from all
of the company of the things that are
going wrong
and if i'm looking at the last few years
it doesn't look like we
like we did get less to do so what i
actually did
i didn't only translate it to the
integrity and compliance monitoring but
i also looked at vulnerability
management and
what is actually going wrong there
because i'm still convinced that this
was already put in the last presentation
last year
that the stock is really the place where
you see all the errors and things that
are going wrong
and if you don't want to screw all the
analysts then you should be making sure
that they can articulate their problems
in the right way
so this is sort of where um where i came
into the story
uh briefly like um uh desiree had done
all this great work and
you can go back and view some of that
older work but if you haven't seen it
before we're gonna present some new
things here
and the gist of it was that she had done
this great work uh
making a taxonomy for all these
different categories of things that can
and do go wrong and then she was mapping
that into risk
and i i know that a lot of people
traditionally have viewed risk as
a subset of compliance but i want to
encourage you to think about this the
other way around
compliance is one tool for managing
risks and it's certainly not the only
one
i personally got into risk because i was
tired of viewing risk as only a kind of
compliance exercise so one of the things
we're going to do today
is as we go through some of the
taxonomies and some of the details
we're going to try and map those to
risks and treatments
and and clarify some of that stuff about
risk
thank you aaron yes so what i created
and what was last week posted on github
already
is this poster and it looks really
messy probably for many people that
haven't looked at it a little bit in
detail but it should
display all of the categories that i
would came up with
for false positives states and error
types and problems
and you pretty much see the categories
for integrity compliance configuration
monitoring the ones for security event
and incident management so the
security monitoring part as well as the
vulnerability and it was
heavily based i tried to include the
continuous improvement action in this
poster
so the colors um actually should
highlight on where the next action
should be going and this
pretty much was caused because taking
errors for everything would have been
really messy
so yeah but um the focus really is on
this continuous improvement because if
we
highlight and have these categories we
can always go to a next step
and what i tried to include as well was
this paper published by
lockheed martin like a while ago the
intelligence-driven computer network
defense informed by analyzers of
adversity campaigns
and intrusion chains so this
um pretty much they just say that
everything that you try to
um if you can't prevent it try to detect
it at least
and you should always make sure that if
you can't deny the
action completely then you should at
least try to degrade disrupt deceive it
and if you can't detect it you might be
able to discover it so
just make sure that you always have one
of these actions covered so the
reference link
goes to the details but i found this
paper really helpful and interesting
so i'm jumping right into just because
of the time running
this is the categories that i came up
with for integrity and compliance
configuration monitoring
and in this presentation i only added
the follow-up actions
because um really for time-saving issues
and all of this
is already put into a paper like the
last one so
it's pretty similar and also from the
whole way that i created it
and um so on the github you do find
detailed explanation of what every
category is
and how this can be used
and um so for example if you have a
legit violation with mischanged
documentation your follow-up action will
be adjust baseline configuration and
document the change
if you have a configuration error in the
baseline
you your engineer probably needs to
review the baseline
and go on with that so this is pretty
much the category it's divided again
in company problems and what can the
stock soul
resolve themselves and what are the
strategic values that you want to get
from it
so this is pretty much the framework
that you should already know from the
last publication
so i will just go on and jump to the
next wheel
and this is the one from vulnerability
management and
vulnerability management is not only i
mean
if you see this from a perspective of a
sock that is not only
doing services for an internal company
but also for an external one
you usually have a word that is
vulnerability scanner in place that
tells you this is an alert and
or this is a vulnerability that should
be fixed and
um you will most likely get one of those
two responses here you get either that
the vulnerability verification is
mistaken
so your scanner is apparently wrong or
you will get context of the
exploitability is not given eskim
is not given so you have like it's not
actually a problem because your
vulnerability scanner doesn't look at it
at the right angle and you probably have
like a woof or something in between and
you're behind the woof so
it's not a problem well yeah
this is very well possible but um you
should be documenting those things and
what are the responses that you're
getting
and um we are here still with
vulnerability if it was relevant if
they're now with no it wasn't relevant
but if it was irrelevant
then you still have the possibility that
it can't be prevented on time so you
always want
want to make sure can you take some
actions like
right on time or if you can't fulfill
the time then you want to make sure that
you find some other
steps that you can do and um
aaron do you want to jump in on that or
i will sure yeah
yeah the um i think the point here is
that we all know that that
sock workers and defenders of networks
are exhausted they're working really
hard
so if you're scanning for all of these
different vulnerabilities and you're
continually getting pushback saying oh
this one doesn't apply because we have a
waff or because we have
this other mitigation or we're catching
that in the ids or whatever
that's still a question of your scope uh
not being useful
because you don't need to scan for these
things if the context is being discarded
on a more permanent basis
or you might want to scan for them
because you're looking for
when the waff stops working for example
and those are great reasons to do these
things but you still need to document
why you made those decisions and what's
going on this is particularly important
when you're a sock that's dealing with
multiple stakeholders
because you know your teams are
exhausted they're working really hard
and this this is where
um you know dez is a really smart lady
and she's done all this great work i
want to make it clear that this project
is very much her project but that's
where
our conversation started to get
interesting because she would say to me
you know oh this is this is the risk and
this is the treatment
and i'd start thinking about it and i'd
realize that you know there was a lot
going on here in terms of risk
some of which we'll capture a bit later
but the main one there is the sort of
strategic risk of
well vulnerabilities are going out and
if we have more vulnerabilities that's
going to be more patches and more
patches is more
patch management right and i think
everyone's exhausted with that at the
moment and that's why
we need to start thinking about some of
these things and gathering data on some
of these things so i'll let
let dez move on and i'll just uh uh
occasionally chime in to
make a few points towards the end
perfect good
so if we can't install the patch on time
or the engineers actually
then we usually get like one of those
four problems usually just
orally and they don't document it in
another way so if it's a resource
problem they usually don't have stuffing
issues
or budget other priorities and you
should be documenting this
um if you have a compatibility problem
so this usually means that your product
the patch can't be installed on that
version that you have um installed or if
there's some other kind of problem you
want to document in it because that's
actually a risk
if you do have a bad sla with a bad sla
i mean
that you do have an sla in place that
for example for the network engineers
only allows them to install a patch like
four times a year
and they just don't have any way on how
they can install this patch on time for
you
that's something you want to document
because the more facts you create with
this
statistics the more um information you
afterwards have to actually argue
against slas or find out
if there can or should be a contract
adjusted for this
and with the support problem i go
towards partner dependencies if your
partner
or if the partner that you have the
product from is not delivering you with
a patch
and you can't fix the vulnerability you
should be documenting this as well so
all of this will be very important just
towards more greater risks but we get to
that afterwards with the kpis as well
um aaron yeah this is this is a this is
a perfect example of where my curiosity
was peaked right
um so dez was talking to me about how
these these
uh requirements on the sock were to scan
for something and then
you see that you've scanned for it and
you asked them to repair the
vulnerability
but they don't have enough downtime
window to actually do that and that's uh
what you know in economics or risk we
might call conflicting incentives or
perverse incentives
where two different sides of your own
organization in other words
the the salespeople who are negotiating
the contracts and the slas
are now in conflict with your sock
support team
and that is really funny but it's the
kind of thing that we see happen all the
time and it's really interesting because
your sock team's
getting exhausted constantly finding
these risks and then no one's treating
these risks
and it doesn't usually occur to you to
go hey should we look at the slas
and should we find out if the slas have
a provision
for how much downtime is available
there's no point in us asking them to
fix more than they can fix according to
the same contract
and then by changing those contracts you
can realign those incentives and often
when you realign the incentives
you realign the risks and one of the
things that i think many people forget
about risk is
yes it can be mathematical and
relatively objective but it's often very
subjective in the sense that the sock
is facing the risk from a different
angle than the customer
and until you align that view of risk
inside a contract
you're going to have these conflicts so
i guess our point is when you see these
these really interesting entrenched
debates within your organization
look for a realignment of incentives to
help you solve some of those problems
and
and the solution might not just be
writing more intrusion detection rules
or something in engineering you might
have to
get out of your comfort zone and go and
speak to some other people in the
organization
yes yeah because security isn't only
your job but like
there's some governance and security
management team and they have a part and
a role as well
so when we went on and we couldn't uh
just
deny the whole thing happening or have
some other way of degrading the attack
we at least want to try to detect it or
discover it
and if you can create a detection it's
usually via a security monitoring rule
or
more integrity compliance configuration
monitoring or even some hunting action
or you increase visibility by adjusting
some other configuration in the
background so you can do something about
it
but if you can't you usually also have a
few things that go wrong
and um the first four categories here
events cannot be locked detection
pattern unclear
lock event ratio and reasonable resource
problems are usually the ones that i
will point most to the sock
because i think the other people can't
do something about it
so um events cannot be locked is usually
this is a very specific attack
and then you don't know yet how to
detect a specific attack
and then you need to find a close enough
approximate
approximation and this can very well be
that this means more overhead in your
team as well so
um you need to find out if this is
actually a good way or if you
in this case just want to say that the
events cannot be locked in
an efficient matter you want to say
if the detection pattern is unclear i
would usually say that
it's probably more an education problem
that they don't know how to detect it
but it can also be and i don't want to
point this only to the analyst but i
mean
if not even the analysts can get it
right nobody else in the company will
so if you don't know how to detect it
you should be documenting it and take it
as a risk
um then the log event ratio is
unreasonable that's a really economic
problem so
you might want to verify if there's more
economic alternatives but you might not
be able to
please document that this is not in the
current
way you have your setup reasonably
doable
so um this is a different kind of
problem than the others
and with a resource problem at the
detection point it's really that your
stop stock stuff is has like different
priorities or you
just have too little and you should be
documenting this as well
and this is also some kind of risk is if
all of the soccer employees
are too busy with other things um you
want to document this
so yeah then the other categories
are more towards the middle one the like
locks cannot be delivered and research
problem in delivery is usually the
engineers
something in the transmission way
towards you is going wrong
so um it's probably a firewall rule that
you can't adjust and it can even be that
it's your partner at some other site
that is not doing the change so it might
just be that it's not you
but you should be reporting that logs
cannot be delivered to you and this is
why you can't create a detection
and if there's other people having
resource problems that's also something
you want to report a risk to
i mean those people then need to verify
their priorities
and their way they are set up and you
should be documenting it because the
worst thing that can happen
is that someone something happens and
someone comes to you afterwards and
tells you you didn't create a detection
and you didn't document why you couldn't
create the detection
because you have actually tried it
and the last few points here are no tool
for logging is available or no process
demand and responsible for the detection
is available
which is usually a government problem so
security management somebody
in an overall state probably also
security architecture
just didn't think of creating such a
possibility to create to
get those tools in there and this locks
that you need and so
this usually can't be resolved by the
sock themselves so document it
so they do get the data to create such
detections um i would
go on because we want to go to the kpis
and the benefits
um i created a few kpis again
um like the last time for now technical
security compliance monitoring and
integrity monitoring
um so for example um we have here a
number of legitimate
violations authorized by change you do
see that
if you have an alert in the stock and it
was actually
authorized by a change by official
change management process that was in
place
this means the stock wasn't included in
that process and
that's a process problem you want to fix
and
make sure that you are not running after
things and
always because this really should be
like stopped at the beginning
um if you more have like configuration
errors in the baseline
um then it means that the quality of the
security baselines that you have
is probably not that good so you want to
create statistics of that as well
a number of limitations and verification
products found
means that your product that you're
using is probably not that good
so you want to have a look at it as well
um
if you create statistics on it you can
get the facts to
like create the changes that you need in
your infrastructure
and number of activities with no change
required this is a hard one
i mean if no one actually asked to
document
something some change that is done in
the infrastructure so for example if in
the cloud the configuration is changed
and nobody cares the documented
interchange where you could verify it
with you have no
chance of making sure that this was
actually an official change
and this means that the stock is running
after security problems
that apparently the governance team and
security management doesn't think is a
problem because they
never defined the scope to be covering
that areas
so make sure that the security
management
and the governance people know what
should be covered
and if they don't think it's reasonable
to cover it then
i don't i would really question if you
as a stock need to run after those
events
and the last event this is um yes
hey go ahead if you want you can go
through the rest of the slide i was just
gonna
yeah no i wanted to say that the number
of only price changes without legitimate
costs is pretty much
one kpi where you afterwards get a
security
incident from because this is the one
that stuff that you can't verify and
that you need to further analyze
now aaron sorry
no problem no problem it's a little
harder when we're not in person we can't
make any uh eye contact as easily so
um yeah this is a good opportunity to
say you know here's an operational risk
right like if you're
uh you're performing these actions and
you are detecting these things and no
one has ownership of it in your
organization or in another organization
that's an operational risk because
you're not blind to the risk but your
your hands are tied in the sense that
the organization isn't reacting to
anything
and that's a that's a big difference
than a a compliance risk right because
you're looking for someone to own that
risk and do something about it
also you have policy risks uh which
might be you know the
failure of the policy or the way the
policy is designed or the slas that we
talked about earlier
this is a good opportunity to talk about
endogenous and exogenous risk and i know
many of you
will already know what those are but and
keep in mind that first is a very
international organization
some of our non-native english speakers
may not have encountered these ideas
before
so endogenous is a risk that is inside
the organization that flows from the way
the organization
does things i'll use the earth as a
metaphor volcanoes are an endogenous
risk they happen on earth they're part
of the earth's processes
an exogenous risk is one that comes from
outside the organization
and usually is is a big surprise right
so like a meteor striking the earth
would be an exogenous risk there's not
really something inside the way we're
behaving
that we can do to change that now that
doesn't mean that you can't treat
an exogenous risk it just means that the
way you treat it is usually a bit
different
and the way you detect it is definitely
different because
to be able to see it coming you need to
be outward facing a lot of times in risk
we talk about
inside out risk and outside in risk so
most people
i think they think of the inside out
model where i'm an organization
i map my different risks to different
things and i try and keep track of
different treatments
but there's also that outside end view
where i'm looking outwardly to figure
out what risks are coming my way and
which ones are exogenous
so that's uh that's a useful paradigm to
help you think about some of these
things sometimes the solution might be
uh under the things you control and then
indulge in a sense
or it might be in the way you do
business with your business partners or
the way you interact with your
supply chain or the the ways that you um
make the requirements in the software
that you use um so just because the risk
is
exogenous doesn't mean you can't do
anything about it
um do you want to move on to the next
slide and we'll yeah
i guess we also have five minutes yeah
five more minutes so we have a few more
kpis
uh for vulnerability management pretty
much and those are
like i'm coming back now to number of
delays due to unreasonable slash i mean
this is really something you want to
like create into statistics so you might
want to do something in the organization
about else you will always have
engineers fighting against each other's
and this is just not good gonna be the
resolution or the solution for this all
and the number of delays due to resource
problems or average delays
until um things can be resolved this is
also very important i mean
if you're just not having just staff the
way it should be
this is an overall risk that should be
checked and it's probably more on a
contractual level
um yes so the other things are pretty
clear i would say
aaron do you have um something you want
to add elsa would go
to next slide elf because
we're running short yeah sure
just go ahead and move on to the next
and don't forget to launch the poll at
some point when you're ready
oh true yeah so um the goal really was
identify where time is actually being
spent create statistics for
effectiveness of internal security
measures and
architecture so you can have an
evidence-based discussion
and integrate the possibility for
directly initiating continuous
improvement into the process if you
actually are automating all of those
kind of things in the background so
that is a really nice side feature
and this one is about the value at risk
right
yeah so like looking at those contracts
can be helpful to you as well because
you might see
the amount of money that your
organization is making from those things
and how much weight you put on
you know the detection of particular
particular vulnerabilities for
particular clients for example
so understanding that value at risk even
if you're just an everyday engineer
tells you why do we spend so much time
as a stock doing this job as opposed to
that job
and it might be a lot to do with revenue
and and how that revenue is being
generated or
how the value at risk is working um this
also
helps you get a little more transparency
in your risk treatments
so you don't you know when we were
talking about defense in depth earlier
we had a great big list of all the
things that we might like to do deny
degrade
etc and the idea is that you want to do
all of these things and that's that's
great in theory that's like
you know people who have no um they have
an infinite amount of money in their
bank account and they can spend it on
everything they want
i don't live in that world i'm sure you
don't live in that world so
um the point here is how much money and
how much time should we put into each of
those things
and we'd like to both reduce the
severity and the frequency
and then of course you know you can find
these things out by by checking the
contracts or other
um other things it might be that your
customers have a particular value at
risk if you don't meet a certain metric
and so they might be determining the
value at risk and you might need to see
that
not inside your own organization but
inside another one and i think
um now's a good time to hand back to
desiree to wrap things up
and maybe take questions and do the poll
yes we have two minutes two questions
and the poll
yes perfect so um just activate the poll
because
um this is pretty much um i created this
poster i created
um the integrity compliance paper
already and
aaron and i are planning to write
another paper about all of the
vulnerability section
but what forma would you most appreciate
more infos in
um please tell me and then i can try to
include this in the next steps
um just so we know
um what direction to go i think i could
vote myself now hey
yeah i'll take
i'll check the q a the question that
came in was already um
okay already answered okay
so um okay all right good
good do i get the results afterwards or
do we get it now
from the pool
um i believe
i can make you a co-host and you should
be able to see it
okay
thanks everyone for joining as well and
um thank you for your time and um if
there are any questions we're both on
twitter
and um yeah just let us know if you have
feedback i'm
very excited to just share it i'm
actually also really interested in
getting your feedback on it and if it's
actually working
and if we create the change with this
information that we need
so this is really like the key
thanks everyone what a wonderful
audience
all right thank you everyone we're going
to do a 30 minute break
and then we'll be back to the next
session
have a great first everyone thank you
bye