hi everybody thanks for joining us this
is tracy from the first events team
just a few very quick reminders before
we get started
all attendees are muted if you are using
the event app we encourage you to check
in to the session update your activities
and be sure to complete the session
survey at the end
if you are having any app trouble and an
android user please send us an email
at events at first.org and we'll try to
see if we can help you out
just a reminder the session is tlp white
and is being recorded
recordings will be available within 24
hours via the app and the desktop site
and with that i'd like to introduce you
to your session moderator
for this session dr serge rose search
okay thank you tracy and welcome
everybody
tracy's edit my name is serge ross and
i'll moderate
this session and a couple of just tiny
things before we start
uh please add your questions and we hope
there's lots of questions of
to the q and a section of the of zoom
and then i'll then process them as they
come in at the end in the q a period
and uh having said that let's
go ahead with martin ayan the
chief or head of research of mnemonics
talking about lessons learned from
building a threat intelligence platform
i'm eager to hear this i'm building one
myself right now so
without further ado martin
thank you um for the past
three years we've been basically
building a threat intelligence platform
uh called act act and it's tailored for
analysis and automation
and during that work we made
observations on state-of-the-art and
threat intelligence platforms
uh on threat sharing and
some general observations on the field
of threat intelligence
uh we made mistakes uh we found some
issues both obvious and
maybe some more subtle and we tried to
find solutions
that work in the real world so this
presentation is about
all the lessons we learned on the way
and
hopefully some of those lessons can be
useful
to the rest of the community so just a
quick agenda
i'll very briefly introduce threat
intelligence
i'll talk a little bit about why we
built a threat intelligence platform
and what we did and then the main part
will be the lessons learned
and i'll round off with a call to arms
and a little bit about the rogue ad
what we're going to do in the future but
first off
what is threat intelligence and why did
we build this app platform
threat intelligence is something to help
you correctly assess risk
and to help you defend against real and
relevant threats rather than
imaginary ones there are
multiple different definitions of threat
intelligence
they either say that it's the knowledge
of threats
or information about threats the key
difference there is that knowledge
implies understanding and the core
component of understanding
is being able to identify causes and
effects
and as security professionals we
primarily observe effects
we see traces of activity in large files
in network traffic
on endpoints and then we try to reason
about that to figure out what
caused these traces what are the likely
causes
so we went for a definition of threat
intelligence as
knowledge and we built the act platform
to store
our knowledge of threats to try to make
it more useful
being able to efficiently find prior
knowledge about the threat
and relate that to what you're observing
here now is useful
it can help you to get more context and
it can help you make the right decisions
uh making it useful also means to
automate where possible so you don't
waste time
doing repetitive manual work
on this path or request
to automate we found a wide range of
issues with threat intelligence
standards with
terminology and with information sources
and threat intelligence is like it's
kind of like
trying to lay a puzzle with missing
pieces on certain pieces
wrong pieces and even changing pieces
so a threat intelligence platform that
takes all that into account
can help you understand and explain
what you're observing here and now
actually means
as well as how certain you can be about
your conclusions
so the first thing we did was to
investigate all of the available threat
intelligence platform
and try to figure out if they could meet
our requirements
we came to the conclusion that they
couldn't
because at a very high level our goal
was we needed a platform that would
help us to collect and organize our
knowledge
of threats to facilitate analysis and
sharing and to make it easy to retrieve
that knowledge when we needed it
we spent way too much time on manual
processing copy-pasting information
between systems
and a lot of our knowledge wasn't
unstructured form
like human-readable threat reports and
that made it difficult
and time-consuming to figure out if we
had relevant knowledge
that could help us decide how to handle
a security incident or alert
and to break it down a bit goal number
one was to build a knowledge base
we wanted a one-stop shop for our
knowledge of threats
but we didn't want to store all of the
information there we store pointers to
other systems with more details but
this platform should give us the
overview
how things are connected
we wanted to be able to store knowledge
not just information
and that means that semantics matter we
need to have meaningful relations
we wanted to be able to retrieve that
knowledge to find and understand it
and relate it to what we're observing
here or not
and finally we wanted to be able to
quantify
uncertainty that means managing trust
confidence and also missing information
how certain can it be that this claim is
actually true
second goal was semi-automation
we wanted as far as possible to automate
the collection
of threat intelligence and that also
means to be able to extract structured
data information from human readable
unstructured text
because a lot of the relevant
information is only available as
unstructured information
we wanted to automate the rich notes and
that's basically the process of
converting data to information
we wanted to automate analysis to be
able to gain new knowledge from what we
already knew
counter measures to mitigate the threats
that we discovered
and finally lossless information
we want to be able to share information
without losing it on the way
and that's a big problem with most
threat sharing today
and finally we needed strict access
control
we wanted role-based access control
to get access management scalable
but we also needed explicit access
control because in threat intelligence a
fairly common use case is i want to
share this piece of information with
that
individual by no one else
we need support for multi-tenancy that
means multiple different information
owners in the same platform instance
and finally granular access controls we
need to be able to
control access to every single piece of
information
in the platform so that was a short
intro lesson number one
is it's all about relations because
the key difference between data and
information is that
information tells you how data points
are
related to each other and as an example
an ip address is a data point and by
itself
it's pretty worthless from a threat
intelligence viewpoint
the interesting information is
how is this ip address related to other
data points
like have we seen files downloaded from
it
were those files malicious do they
belong to a specific malware family
which organization owns this ip address
which domain names are resolved to it
so a graph is a convenient and useful
model for
describing relations and therefore we
implemented the act platform as a graph
database
that means that it also supports graph
queries automated
analysis by traversing graph
so all of these data points or
observables are
nodes in the graph whereas the useful
information
are represented as edges relating to
objects or object properties
objects are unique so all the
information we've collected on
for example an ip address are connected
to the same
object so if you retrieve that object
and all the relations you get all the
information we have on it
and just a point note that a
graph view is not the same as a graph
database
because you can display any kind of data
even a flat text file
as a graph but you cannot use graph
queries unless you have a graph database
so we designed a low-level
data model to support this and the data
model consists of objects
that are global unique by value
and this is an example it's
write an address that has object type
ipd4
and value 127.001
and that's all information there is on
this object
it's only the type and the value
and it's unique by the title value
convolution only interesting information
is stored as facts
and facts can be connected to a single
object like this
here's a fact of type category that has
the value loopback
it tells you that this ip address has
category
loopback or they can connect two objects
and that's a relation or an edge in a
graph this fact tells you that the fully
qualified domain name through.com
resolves to ipv4 address 12701
the facts and data model are immutable
that means they cannot be
modified or deleted once they're added
to the platform
if you do realize that it's wrong you
can retract it
that's basically adding a new fact
saying that this was wrong
by retracting and every fact is time
stuff and the combination of
immunitability and timestamps
gives you the ability to rewind time so
if you made a decision three months ago
and you're wondering what kind of
information did i have then you can just
rewind time by three months and you can
see exactly what kind of information you
have
every fact as an owner that's important
for multi-tenancy
every single fact supports role based on
explicit taxes control
and every fact can be backed by evidence
and comments
and finally every fact has a region
or source and every source has a trust
rating which you set yourself
it's a value between zero and one how
much you trust the source so if you have
trust in the source then the value is
one and every fact supports
confidence so if the source says i'm 100
confidence that this is correct then the
confidence score will be 1.
finally the product of those two gives
you a certainty
so every fact stories trust confidence
uncertainty
in order to implement this um
we created the scheme our ontology where
we define the
object types and the fact types and
which objects each factor could connect
and this is available on the url at the
bottom of the slide
and this is basically this is just a
subset of the the
ontology but the goal here was to
represent knowledge
and to facilitate more advanced analysis
traversals and to allow us to build
bridges between technical tactical
operational and strategic threatened
options
i'll get back to that bridge building in
a short while
but the next lesson learned was
pivots can be very useful
you can pivot on objects and what that
does is
to let you find related information and
give you more context
the canonical example or a simple
example of pivoting is from dns or
passive dns
you start with a domain name you find
all of the i purposes that it has
resolved to
and then you find all other domain names
that are resolved to those ad campuses
and then you can keep going like that
when you do that you quickly run into
issues because of sinkholes
domain parking shared hosting uh which
can very quickly lead you straight
so for that kind of pivoting you need to
classify and you need to label the
addresses
so that you can filter them out during a
graph traversal
but that's a very very simple example
one more interesting one
is um you can create unconventions
this is an example from urls uh given a
url we split
it so you have the host
or fqdmr ip address as a separate object
you have the path as a separate object
and you have the query parameters
as a separator and that proved useful
when we were tracking phishing campaigns
because
some of these campaigns would reuse
their phishing kits so for every spam
run they would
change the domain name they would change
the path
but they would reuse the query so by
pivoting on that
we could track them over time and
the lesson learned there is try to
identify new
pivot points and exploit them
and if you find a pivot point in a graph
representation
that should be an object because you
need
objects to be able to pivot in a graph
conversion
another observation that we made early
on was that
we built a threat graph and that graph
ended up being a series of islands
or sub-graphs that were not connected
so we had lots of small graphs here and
there and we wanted to be able to
connect with them
and the simple solution to that was
enrichment so you see an ip address you
look up and passive dns
to find all the domains that are
resolved to it and then you add that
information
and we kept adding more enrichment
sources
and the graph gradually became more and
more connected and we could find new
connections between clusters of
information that
initially were separate that's also very
simple one more
maybe interesting or advanced solution
was
using classifiers to be able to bridge
technical tactical operational strategic
threat intelligence
this is an example of using virustotal
to bridge technical indicators to
tactical information in mitra attack
so consider this sha-256 sum it
represents
file which is on virustop
and to the left you see one of the
antivirus signatures
that i've triggered on this file trojan
downloader win32
zebrazy and on the right you see the
software entry in mitre attack for
zebras
so from virustotal
when we receive a file hash we enrich it
using virustotal
so we look it up and we find that this
signature is triggered
we extract the malware family name
zebrazy and we lowercase it to normalize
it
so we end up with an object of type 2
value separate previously we've imported
mitre attacks
which has a software entry for zebra z
we do the same thing there lowercase it
and create a tool object called with the
value
separation now since objects are unique
by value
then these two are the same object and
that actually links the information from
aristotle to the information from
attacked automatically
so antivirus energies on virus total are
classifiers
it's also possible to find other
classifiers and that can be
incredibly useful because it lets you
build bridges between the different
categories of threat intelligence you
can also go from tactical to strategic
for instance
and that gives you a much more
comprehensive comprehensive context on
what you're observing here now
so this is what it looks like in the act
threat graph in the bottom there you
have the
the file hash which is classified as
zebra z
and then there's a link to the threat
director att28 with all of the aliases
so this works very well as long as you
use the same name for things but
in reality there are multiple names for
the same albury family and there are
multiple names for the same threat actor
and that creates problems for this
bridge building so we needed a solution
for that
how do we handle the many different
names
so the solution is obvious and it's like
everyone does basically
use aliases so in this case sophisy is
an alias for a to d28
now the more subtle thing here is that
we started out selecting a canonical
name for each that actor and each
malware family
and then we connected all the
information to that name so
if we got we selected apt-28 as
our canonical name for this protector if
we got information about sophisy we
would
connect that to the apt-28 document
same thing if we get the information
about fancy beer we would also connect
it to apd28
another while later we realized that
that was probably one of the biggest
mistakes we did
because information could be wrong
so if you don't at some point in the
future
realize that sofa c is not actually an
alias for 80.
then you have a huge mess to clean up if
you connected all the information to
apd20
so the way we solved it was only attach
information to the name given
from the source not to a canonical line
so if we receive the information about
sulfusy we attach it to the surface
object
receive information about submit we
attach it to the submit object
then if at some point you realize an
alias is wrong
all you need to do is to retract that
single alias and all the rest of your
information
is still correct
now when we do the graph analytics
we solve this by traversing all
aliases whenever we hit an object that
supports aliases so if we do a
graph traversal and we hit a thread
vector object
before we do anything more we find all
of the aliases
and collect all of the threat factor
objects that are aliases for the object
you
found and then you continue the graph
traversal from the set of threat actor
objects rather than from the single
attacker object and in that way the
aliases
acts as an intermediary bridge
which also lets you correlate
information from different sources that
might use different canonical names for
the same
thread this work on bridge building and
aliases actually uncovered a range of
data and information quality issues in
important sources of threat intelligence
so the first one is about naming things
which is hard
and it's especially hard when you want
to do automated processing and analysis
of information from multiple different
sources
one very useful tool to help you do that
is vocabularies and this is an example
from sticks 2.0 the industry sector
vocabulary
this vocabulary is not perfect like
where do you place a law firm
but it's useful because
it lets you correlate and tailor it on
information from different sources
so if everyone uses this vocabulary we
know that
if it's something targeting the
healthcare industry then it will be
called healthcare
and given our data model that means all
of the information will be connected to
the same
sector objects so one example
this is a really great resource from
tycert the threat group cards
and if you're not using this i suggest
you try
try it out they have collected
information on threat actors aliases
malware families
operations or campaigns
sectors that they target and
geographical areas that they target
now the sectors there with initially it
looked like they were using the stixx
vocabulary but then
when we went into more detail we would
find things like political dissidence
and forbes sector or large domestic
companies a multinational corporation
branches sector
or electronics and journalists
so it's a really great resource but it
could be even better if they
chose the vocabulary and stuck to it
because then it would be easier to
process
next lesson was central aspiration
versus community efforts
in the early project stages we used both
micro attack and miss
galaxy as sources from albert family and
threat actresses
but we found so many
quality issues like sever two different
threat diagrams with the alias apt-17
in this galaxy that at some point we
stopped using it
because it was adding wrong information
to our knowledge base
one reason for that might be that attack
has a very very strict curation
and requires references for all
information
and that might not be possible to
achieve with a commute effort
where you don't have centralized
curation of the information
so
automated consumption of threat
intelligence is hard
and that indicates to us that this
using these techniques to
automatically enrich and build bridges
is not widely used
and we've been trying to figure out why
but
one of the reasons might be that there's
a general consensus
in the threat intel community that we
don't share enough threat intelligence
thus we must remove the barriers to
sharing thus
the standards must be flexible it might
be easy to share
the problem with that is if you make it
easy to share you make it harder to
consume
because if you want to make it easy to
consume this automatically you need to
be strict
you need to represent information
in the same way every time
and for every piece of threat
information
produced it might be consumed hundreds
or thousands of times
so making it difficult to consume to
make it easier to produce
is not scalable or efficient
finally trust and confidence um
relations and threat intelligence are
not binary they may might be uncertain
wrong or missing so to manage
uncertainty as i mentioned we
implemented the trust score french
information sources
a confidence score for each relation and
then the certainty score which is the
product
and the key observation there was that
almost none of the sources that we
imported had any kind of confidence
course
in a machine readable format and
antivirus engines such as their
classifiers
they could have provided the confidence
score but they don't
so that leaves us with guessing
how certain is this av engine but this
is actually not motor family
we don't know oh could you come
to a close end or maybe
yeah i'm almost there so i just hope i
don't come across as
arrogant or bitter or difficult or
anything uh i think that we can do this
better
i think that the necessary changes are
manageable and that the results are
valuable
because given the i platform you can
give it an ip address you can get
using a graph query malware family names
command and control infrastructure
downloads threat directors techniques
incidents signatures
reports that mention it and
the way to achieve that is to share
information as triplets
source object relation destination think
relations when you share information
don't think data and finally the road
ahead
we are also participating in a new
project called socrates where
we develop a security automation and
decision support platform for
uh socks and incident responders
and as part of that we're developing the
act platform
with a focus on tactical threat
intelligence and we're trying to be able
to automatically generate adversary
emulation plans
and currently we're sequencing attack
techniques
by defining preconditions post
conditions so you can create attack
chains automatically
that project has a stakeholder group
we're looking for
interested parties that would like to uh
participate in the stakeholding group
so if you are if if you think that
sounds interesting
just have a look at the website and we
also have the delivery
and finally the app platform is open
source it's on github it's
ic license and we also have a public aws
instance read only with only open source
intelligence
if you just want to test it that's it
for me
okay thank you martin um
there are three questions or rather one
comment it seems
and actually now three questions so
first one is from
woodpendra singh facts should also
be associated with a ttl time to live
yes you can i mean we don't have native
support for it in a data model
but you do have a timestamp you know
when that information was added
and you can handle ttl on the outside so
if you want to export information to a
reputation system or to a firewall
uh that could be handled on the outside
of the platform because you have all the
information you need
okay thanks then the next question is
from andrew cormack
does grinder access control on
individual facts risk
a cutting graph or conversely be
allowing unintended access interferences
across around a cut it feels quite hard
to foresee the effect
of granting or refusing access
you grant or refuse access to
each fact separately so yes in the case
you might cut the graph if you don't
have i mean if you don't have
access to that single fact with bridges
two subgraphs then you will see it as
two separate subgroups
okay then the next question is thanks
the next question is by
patrick forsberg how do you solve name
clashes
if for instance it turns out that
virustotalbin32
sabre c isn't the same as the attack
version we don't have a so i don't think
there's a solution for that
basically if you if you use the exact
same name
then we don't have a solution for it now
okay would maybe be adding
adding the source to the name or
something
kind of the the uh the facts are the
source
so anything connected to that the object
is unique by name
but anything connected to the object
will also have a source
okay so if the oversee has an alias to
another tool object
and that might come from mighty attack
and attack will be the
source or the origin for that fact
whereas if you have a sample classified
as cyber c that has another origin
which could be virus so they're
distinguishable but uh we don't natively
uh handle that name commission
no okay thanks then the next is by
philippe
storchkovsky why did you decide on
confidence scores from feed sources
rather than building your own score
engine based on the threat data context
because our own evaluation is um
they're not mutually exclusive first off
but our
our own evaluation is for each source
we assign a trust score how much do we
trust this source
and then we support that the
source can set the confidence score for
every fact that we receive
and finally we compute the certainty
based on that but
we could have analysis workers that add
new information
and set a different confidence score
given the context so you analyze the
not each single fact that you analyze
this in context with all the other
information you have
but the way you would do that is create
new facts you wouldn't modify what's in
there already
that's kind of falsifying history but
you would create new facts
okay thanks a lot then amit
musad asks can you put some light on
ics slash ot scada specific threat
intel sources well
we're gonna at least import uh attack
for ses
but i mean the threat into a platform is
not
exclusively for enterprise networks or
for ics networks
this um we haven't done the data
modeling for
ics specific things but that's
definitely something
we're looking into in the future
okay so there seems to be a lot of
potential
um thanks a lot again martin for
presenting this as
usual once the questions get going then
the things become
interesting sadly the time is over me
move on to the next session
so thanks to the audience for staying
with us thanks again martine to
present in this virtual conference
bye bye everybody thank you thanks
everybody