- Hey, what's up DEF CON?
This is Cedric Owens, I'm
super humbled and excited
to be here, and I'll be talking about,
basically giving a perspective
of what red teaming looks like
in macOS environments here
in the year 2021.
Some background information on myself,
I'm a full-time offensive
security engineer
on the red team side,
and I've been dedicated red
teamer now for the past four,
almost five years.
Prior to that, vast
majority of my career's been
on the blue team side
doing incident response,
threat detection, threat hunting,
both in the intel community
and in the private sector,
and so even as a full-time red teamer now,
I highly value
collaborating with blue team
just to help uplift
each other's trade craft
and move the needle forward
in our organizations.
I personally enjoy macOS post exploitation
as an interest area of mine,
that and infrastructure automation,
so whenever I do have free time,
I'm typically working on projects that fit
into one of those two buckets.
Also as an early '80s
baby, I do enjoy '80s
and '90s nostalgia such as what
you see here in the picture,
just reminds me a lot of my childhood,
and it's even cooler now
to see my kids playing
with a lot of these same toys
or watching these same shows,
and just kinda cool to see the legacy
of these things live on.
I am on Twitter, handle @cedowens
where occasionally I'll post blog posts
or tools that may be of interest,
so check that out if
that's of interest to you.
So what I plan to talk about
today, first one being,
why do we even care about macOS,
especially in a Windows-centric world?
Why are we even here for this talk?
Overviews of common tech environments
and what the tech stacks
look like in organizations
that are heavy Mac users.
Options for macOS payloads
and post exploitation,
and I look at how the
different options you pick
usually will have a pro and
a con associated with it.
We'll also look at other attack vectors,
so things in macOS environment
that become attack targets
that may not themselves
necessarily be macOS,
but you'll find them often
in macOS environments,
and then we'll end off talking
about detection opportunities
to look at from a blue team perspective.
So again, first question
is macOS, why do we care?
And to your point, if
you're asking that question,
most Fortune 500 companies
today are still Windows shops,
and you may find there that maybe 90%
of their endpoints are
Windows, maybe five Mac,
five Linux or Chromebooks, but in the,
there's a sliver of companies
in the San Francisco Bay Area,
your Silicon Valley companies
that are basically the opposite,
where you may find 80 to 90%
of the endpoints being Mac,
may find five to 10%
or somewhere around there
being Windows endpoints
and you may have Chromebook
and Linux mixed in,
so essentially it's the
flip of what you'll see
in your Fortune 500 environments.
It makes it for an interesting
environment to assess
from an attacker's perspective
because there's often a mentality,
well, if we're not a
enterprise Windows shop,
then we're more secure, and
I can understand the line
of thinking there, but it really depends
on how you implement your
Mac/cloud environment.
In other words, if you
have keys laying around
that are in code repos
or other easy places
for an attacker to find,
you may find that even
though you've migrated off
of a Windows enterprise environment,
your environment can still
be easily compromised,
so we'll talk about that a
little bit more as we go.
It is a slowly growing trend that,
at least that I've been seeing,
where newer companies are adopting more
of a quote unquote non-Windows
enterprise environment,
and what I've noticed
is that Active Directory
is typically gonna be there
because it usually is
the best LDAP solution
for enterprises, so even
in these environments,
you will have Active
Directory which will be used
to back your authentication,
but just your typical
end-to-end enterprise rollout
of Windows will be different here.
And I like it too because
it allows, as a red teamer,
it allows you to point
out different vectors
that really have nothing
to do with Active Directory
and compromising domain controllers,
but other very interesting vectors
that can still be impactful
and in some cases devastating
to your organization,
so I think it's a very
interesting environment
from a red team perspective.
So first we're gonna look
at common tech stacks
and what you might encounter
in a common tech company
in a Silicon Valley area.
First thing is there's a concept
of realms or environments,
and so you may have a
corporate environment,
a dev or stage environment,
production environment,
and so here's an example,
we'll walk from left to right
where you may have employees
that remote in using an
identity as a service solution.
Two common IDaaS solutions
are Okta and OneLogin
where the employee authenticates
with their username,
password, and a 2FA token
which is usually gonna
be a Okta verify push
or a Duo push to their mobile devices.
Once they log in, they're
now inside of their identity
as a service portal, and
they have access to a lot
of different productivity
applications like email,
you may have Atlassian products like Jira,
you may have Salesforce, internal Git,
even custom application servers,
all accessible to the
user based on their roles
in Active Directory.
Then you also, on a production side,
you may find a combination of
cloud-based production hosts
and on-prem, and you may find a lot
of different things there,
but typically in production,
you're gonna find your customer-ready code
and maybe even customer
data that's stored here,
and you're gonna find things
like your build hosts,
your CI/CD pipeline, you may
find some cloud-hosted services
and servers there, you
might find HashiCorp
for managing application secrets,
and of course you may
have some on-prem stuff,
you may have Jenkins on-prem
or even in the cloud.
We have some Windows servers,
segmented environment of
Windows servers there,
so a lot of different things going on here
and it makes it interesting
because of course there's
a lot of complexities,
and sometimes
with more complexities
comes more opportunities
from an attacker perspective.
Another thing to point
out is on the bottom left,
I have rough percentages
over the different endpoints,
so I'm showing macOS being
80% and Windows being 15
and Google Chromebooks
being 5%, just a rough,
rough numbers there.
Some organizations you may
actually find Mac being higher
or closer to 90%,
and the Windows population
being even smaller,
so it's interesting
because with Mac being
such a high percentage
of endpoints in tech environments,
and engineers using their Macs often
to either do dev work locally on a Mac
or log into a cloud-hosted server
or an application server or a jump box,
or from other places
that they can do their
development work from there,
you typically may find that
there are sensitive keys,
tokens, credentials, things
like that that are stored
on the endpoint, so really end-to-end,
this makes for a very
interesting environment to assess
from an attacker's perspective.
Next, gonna talk quickly
about some different ways
that macOS is deployed from
an enterprise perspective.
One option is custom deployment
where you hire your own team
and they build out some
custom solution to manage
and hook into Macs and control
them and push policies,
et cetera, and basically loop
back into your LDAP solution.
Organizations that do that custom tend
to be maybe like your big five in tech,
so something like your Apple
or your Facebook, Google,
may all be custom, where
they have the money,
the resources to throw at that.
But typically what I find
is outside of the big five,
most organizations in
the Silicon Valley area,
most companies there
tend to use a solution
that they purchase, such as Jamf Pro
which is really the most
common that I've encountered,
but I also notice products,
other products that are
up and coming like Kandji,
and so we're gonna take a look at those.
I also wanted to point out
Calum Hall and Luke Roberts
and their Black Hat talk this year,
did a really good talk on abusing
Jamf for remote management
and how an attacker can
leverage that to control
and compromise managed Macs
in an enterprise environment,
so highly recommend checking that out.
So here's a very high-level overview
of common Jamf deployments
that you may see.
You have, typically have an admin server.
If you're in an
environment that uses Jamf,
you can run Jamf, check JSS
connection from Terminal
and that will return the URL
to your Jamf admin server.
You also have your endpoints,
which have the Jamf agent on them
that receives the configuration
for the admin server.
You also have self-service
that runs on the endpoints,
and allows users to
install software versions
that their IT department
has already vetted,
so essentially they don't have
to open tickets for these,
they can just install
them from self-service.
Really nifty way of doing things.
Also, Jamf does include the ability
to have remote management,
where admins can remote
in to do screen sharing
or other troubleshooting on the endpoints,
and typically that is
through an admin account
that has SSH access into the endpoints.
Often times from what I've seen
in enterprise macOS environments,
SSH is enabled on the endpoints,
and the IT team will use
an account that can SSH in
and it has pseudo-rights on the macOS host
where they can perform administration,
so that's a very common thing
that I've seen in
environments, and of course,
one thing to be aware of
is if that is how your
environment is set up,
because very similar to the problem
on a Windows side years
ago about dealing with SMB
and local admin passwords
and LAPS coming out being a solution
to randomize those passwords,
well the same thing would apply here
if remote management's being used,
is it a static password
or is there random passwords being used,
and of course if it's static password,
then that means if you get that password,
you can now access any Mac
in the environment over SSH
with pseudo-rights, and the
SSH has full disk access,
so it bypasses privacy protection,
so that could be really
bad for the environment,
so just something to think about there.
Another thing, another aspect
to look at here is if you run,
as a red teamer you
run a phishing exercise
and you target Jamf admins,
which is usually a Active Directory group
in your environment that
limited people have access to
that that organization has
identified to administer Jamf,
and you phish them,
you gain access to their
Active Directory credentials,
and then you use those credentials
to log into the Jamf management
server, Jamf admin server,
and depending on the environment,
that admin server may be behind Okta
where 2FA push is required, or it may not,
may just be locally in the
environment without 2FA,
and you can get access that way,
and then from there you
can start to push policies
and scripts to run on the
endpoints, and really,
there you almost, you
essentially do have full control
over your macOS environment,
so this is something,
an attack path to think about as well
if you're in an enterprise
Mac environment.
But now, even when it comes to Jamf,
there's really so many different
ways to implement Jamf,
there's really no one way to do it,
so we're just gonna
look at a few examples.
First example is probably the simplest
where macOS hosts are
bound directly to AD,
and in that case, you
can run different DSCL
or LDAP search commands to
pull AD information directly
from the domain controllers,
just as you can on the Windows side,
like for example with net
user commands like that.
You can do the same here,
and tools such as MacHound,
which is a macOS port of Bloodhound,
or Cody Thomas's Bifrost which
does Kerberos manipulation,
those tools would work and apply
in this environment since the host,
the macOS hosts are bound
directly to Active Directory
and can query it directly.
Another example is via, access
via a tool called NoMAD,
where in this case, macOS
hosts are not bound directly
to AD, so if you try to
query Active Directory
from these hosts,
you won't be able to reach
it directly that way,
and essentially the user logs in locally
with a local account and then
they do network authentication
for access to resources,
which is where NoMAD comes in,
and that, NoMAD then performs
Kerberos authentication
on our behalf, and so, and this,
if this setup is how your
environment is configured,
then there are files
that you can read from
that you might find
interesting on an assessment,
such as different plists
that I have mentioned here.
Also things like klist, KCC,
Cody Thomas's Bifrost tool
that does Kerberos manipulation,
those tools would still work,
since Kerberos is still
happening from your endpoint,
so something to think about there.
Another example, same
setup or similar setup here
where your macOS endpoints
do not have direct access
to Active Directory to query
domain controllers directly.
In this case they have
Jamf Connect on them,
and Jamf Connect is synced through Okta,
and Okta does the syncing
with Active Directory
when it comes to authentication.
And so a federated model there.
And what's interesting here
is, just in this example,
the Active Directory controllers are,
domain controllers are
walled off by firewall rules
or VPN access, maybe a specific
VPN profile that you need,
so again, if you try to query
directly, this would not work,
but if this were how your
environment's set up,
there still are some interesting plists
and files on the system
that you could pull from
to learn more about the
host and the environment
that you're in, such as what's your,
the two files highlighted above.
So as I mentioned, AD is still present
in macOS environments,
but it just looks a little bit different
from what you see in your
enterprise Windows environments,
and I enjoy it because it
gives me a chance to focus
on something else outside
of Active Directory.
And of course when you're in
these types of environments,
they're heavy Mac and
cloud implementations,
so a lot of interesting things to look at,
so let's talk about that.
First thing we talk about, initial access,
in this case targeting our
identity as a service portal,
so the two most common
are Okta and OneLogin.
A tool that is pretty
popular here is Evilginx 2
by Kuba Gretzky, and what
it does is you point it
to a target login portal,
it clones that portal,
and as, and you basically send out a link
to the fake portal, and as
people log into the fake Okta
or fake OneLogin portal, it
captures the username, password,
and it authenticates
it to the actual site,
and does the same thing
for your 2FA token.
So then the attacker's able
to grab the token for Okta
or for OneLogin, import it
into their browser using a
plugin like EditThisCookie,
and now you're the compromised user.
And what's so interesting
about this attack path is,
once you're inside of someone's identity
as a service portal,
you have access to a ton
of different productivity
apps, so you got Slack,
think about the credentials,
configuration files, secrets,
things that people have shared in Slack
that may be pinned in different channels,
think about Gmail or Google Drive,
people may email themselves passwords
so they don't forget or
sensitive information,
you have access to search all of that.
Imagine, your Confluence,
your Jira tickets,
things that may have
interesting data there or Wiki,
all sorts of juicy information
there, and as a red teamer,
you may opt to take this path
and essentially meet your objectives
without ever even needing to land access
on a macOS endpoint.
So this is definitely worth
running in your environment
from both a red and a
blue team perspective,
and one of the big wins for,
from the blue team side is allowing,
basically running through
your procedures to see
if you have visibility into
this attack path, and if you do,
do you have the ability to
revoke compromised tokens,
because in this case,
password resets are great,
but if you don't revoke
the compromised token,
you're not gonna be able
to boot out the attacker,
so a good way to test your detection
and response procedures.
So I mentioned a lot of interesting data
in your productivity portals,
and there're some tools
that people have written
to actually automate
this if you're using this
from a red team attack perspective,
one being a colleague
of mine, Antonio Piazza,
he wrote a few different,
what I call thief tools of GD,
GDir, and Conf-Thief to simulate
or speed up downloading sensitive files
from those platforms.
Also a colleague of mind,
Brad Richardson over at
Credit Karma wrote a tool
called Slackhound that
does a similar thing,
if you find a Slack token
on a host, you just feed in
and it uses API calls
and things of that nature
to pull down data, as well as SlackPirate,
so a lot of different and
interesting attack paths
on this vector.
So now, we talked about
identity as a service briefly,
I'm gonna pivot over to the
macOS side of the house,
and talk about some of
the basics around macOS
from a security perspective.
I like to break it into three
different areas, prevention,
detection, and removal.
Gatekeeper, on the prevention side,
is essentially the engine that, or the,
I guess you'd say the service with,
since Policy D is behind it as the engine,
it evaluates certain file
types like application bundles,
installer packages, Mach-Os, et cetera.
It looks for files
that have a com.apple.quarantine
attribute appended to them,
which the operating system
appends for any files downloaded
from the internet, so if
a file is of the types
that Gatekeeper evaluates,
such as Mach-Os, apps,
installer packages, et cetera,
and it has that quarantine attribute,
then Gatekeeper enforcement kicks in.
It checks to see if it's
signed and if it's notarized,
and if it's not, it will
block it from running.
If it does, it still does a popup,
but what's of interest here
is that even for a non-signed,
non-notarized, like app packages,
installers, Mach-O binaries, et cetera,
they usually can still right-click open
and click through one other prompt
to run it despite Gatekeeper.
On the detection side, you have XProtect,
which is also a part of Gatekeeper
and it's really more of
the malware definitions
and blacklisting that I
guess you could say comes
from Apple intel, from
real-world malware resources,
or malware sources that
they have analyzed,
and then you have the
malware removal tool,
MRT.app that does the remediation.
From a red team perspective,
the prevention side of it
really is the hardest hurdle
to overcome.
XProtect and MRT.app usually are not much,
usually not big factors for red teamers
because we tend to write
our own stuff for macOS,
since it's kind of a niche
space, and since XProtect
and MRT.app tend to
look at existing samples
for their intel, usually when
you write in your own stuff,
those two aspects become less of a factor,
it's just really Gatekeeper
that becomes the pain
and headache from a red team perspective.
Other things to think
about is the concept of TCC
or privacy protections, so, and that,
essentially you have certain folders
or certain places on
disk that TCC protects,
so you have things like the
user's desktop, documents,
downloads, all sorts of
other places on the system
that TCC protects.
What's of interest though are
things that are not protected,
so the home directory itself,
and within the home directory,
certain other subdirectories
like a .ssh or .aws directory.
Both of those would contain
credentials, and the ability,
if they're captured, to
provide lateral movement,
a temp directory is also not protected,
which is why malware
typically is dropped there,
so just something to
think about because again,
if TCC is enforced, a popup
will show up to the user
where they can allow or deny
if that directory's requested,
but for not protected folders,
there's no notification to the user
and access is not prevented at all by TCC
if it's not protected by TCC.
TheEvilBit and Reggi
did an excellent Black Hat talk this year
on 20 different ways to bypass TCC,
so definitely check that out.
They'll dig way more into what TCC is
and different methods for
bypassing, so check that out.
From an initial access perspective on Mac,
a lot of different options here
and they all have different pros and cons.
You have your Mach-O binaries,
which are checked by Gatekeeper,
but you typically need a delivery method,
because most of the time your Mach-Os
are not gonna be double-click friendly.
I mean there are some tricks you can do,
but just generally speaking,
you'll use your Mach-O as
a second stage payload.
Apps are checked by Gatekeeper.
They're pretty
remote-friendly, because again,
they're app packages and
they're double-clicked usually,
and so they are remote-friendly,
but they are checked by Gatekeeper.
Installer packages are also
checked and remote-friendly.
They allow a user to double-click.
You got weaponized PDFs,
shell script trickeration
which we'll talk about later.
Essentially that is a bug that I found
in Gatekeeper this year
and reported to Apple
and worked with them to get it fixed.
You also have your scripting languages
that are not checked by Gatekeeper,
things such as JXA which is
JavaScript for automation.
Cody Thomas did an excellent
job a couple years back
of highlighting how powerful JXA is on Mac
and how it's essentially like
an AppleScript alternative,
and some, it's kinda interesting
because sometimes I'll
view JXA as the replacement
for AppleScript, but
they're both still around
and they'll probably both
be around for a while.
Of course Python is not
checked by Gatekeeper, however,
Mac or Apple will remove
Python from base macOS installs
at some point in the future.
Don't know when, but from
an attacker's perspective,
it's just something to keep in mind
if you're heavily relying on Python.
Office macros are not
checked by Gatekeeper,
but it is sandbox, meaning it will be,
if you gain access
remotely via Office macro,
you'll only have access to
certain parts of the disk
and certain binaries, et cetera,
so a lot of different options here.
Got AppleScript browser extensions.
One thing I wanted to point
out was that on macOS,
D00MFist Leo Pitt wrote a
really neat tool called Mystical
that is a payload generator for several
of these types of payloads
where you can provide
in information that will
generate the payload for you.
I also wanted to point
out Mythic by Cody Thomas
at SpecterOps, is what
I consider at this stage
to be the king of macOS
command and control
because of its innovative use of JXA
and has a lot of other cool
features with how it's built
and how it's managed, so
definitely check that out
from a red and blue perspective.
Quickly gonna jump into
some different examples,
so the first example
being installer packages,
and I'm gonna briefly
talk about script only,
because they're the most common
and pretty simple example here,
but you have a pre-install
and a post-install script,
and both require the shebang
at the top and exit at the end
in order to run successfully.
They run as child processes
of the installer packages,
so whatever scripts you have running,
and it runs elevates as root
from an attacker's perspective,
which is a nice plus because
any installer package
that a user detonates and, to install,
they end up authenticating,
and usually in macOS environments,
the user is the local admin,
so when they authenticate,
that installs with elevated
or root access on a host.
As I mentioned before, this check,
installer packages are
checked by Gatekeeper,
but they can right-click and open,
and that's a common technique
that's used in the wild
with real-world malware samples,
so Patrick Wardle
and Objective-See have
a lot of good examples
of real-world malware samples for macOS,
so you can look through
their Mac malware reports
of 2020 and 2019, et cetera,
and look for different
examples for how these types
of things done, like an image is included
and the user's instructed to
right-click and press open
in order to run a non-signed,
non-notarized installer package.
Here's an example of pre-install script,
so we talked about
pre-install and post-install.
This is an example on
the pre-install side,
and it essentially just
pulls down a unsigned,
non-notarized Mach-O binary,
writes it to the temp folder
and sets the executable bit.
On the bottom is a example of,
with us being remote these days
and so many employees being from home,
this is an example of how you
could add a guardrail in there
to check for the host name to ensure
that it's not running on
someone's personal machine
but on a corporate machine.
If it's found to be running
on a personal machine,
it will exit, if not, then
it will perform the pull down
of the payload and set the executable bit.
And here's an example of
a post-install script,
where it just runs the
Mach-O binary backgrounded.
So once you have that set up,
you can just run this
package build command here
to generate the package,
host it, get it to the user,
they detonate it, they
authenticate, right,
or basically double-click and authenticate
through the installation, and it detonates
in the background, and as you
can see at the bottom here,
this is my Mythic, I
screenshotted my Mythic C2 server,
and the payload detonated
as root level access.
Another example, you have app bundles
or app packages where you have the app,
the name of it with content/macOS
and then a Mach-O binary
at the bottom, and so to
do this, a very simple way,
you could go into Xcode,
create a new project,
in my example I'm using Swift here,
and then you would design a
window with buttons, icons,
text, et cetera, for a
user to interact with.
Once you have that
designed and ready to go,
you go into info.plist for
any app transport security,
so app transport security
are restrictions on Apple
to limit the types of outbound connections
that app packages can make, so
if you're trying to talk out
to a non-HTTPS server, so just plain HTTP,
it's certain entries you have
to put in there to allow that,
and even if you're
talking to an SSL server,
it does not like self-signed certificates,
so you actually have to get
a valid signed certificate
for that to work.
And then of course you set
your sandbox accordingly,
or the settings there that you need,
and then you can add code like here below
that uses a dispatcher,
and gain access Swift
as a background task to
execute a JXA payload
that's hosted on a server.
And here's an example of the
window that you can design
for the user to interact with,
and as you can see it
can be very convincing.
When the user clicks Update
now, then the Mythic command
and control server receives
a callback from the user.
So again, app packages
are checked by Gatekeeper,
but as you can see here, as I mentioned,
same with installer
packages, same with here,
you can right-click and
open, so here's an example
from a Shlayer which is a
common macOS malware family
that's been around for a while,
the simple image to
social engineer the user
into right-clicking and
opening to run an unsigned,
non-notarized app package.
Of course you have
Microsoft Office macros.
They still work, they've
been around for a while,
and even today, when you,
I like to do tests with macros
where I just will attach it
and see, let the email system's
antivirus filter scan it
and see if it detects it as malicious,
and one thing I've noticed
is that simple string
concatenation is usually enough
to get it around those filters,
so if you're taking the word exec
and doing E plus X plus
E plus C for example,
that will get around a lot of the filters.
We'll look an example a
little bit later for that.
No Gatekeeper concerns,
but as I mentioned earlier,
it is sandbox, meaning you
have limited disk access
and limited functions or binaries
that are available to you.
You can still access things
such as osascript curl,
screen capture, Python, so
still a lot of potential there,
and Adam Chester who's currently
at TrustedSec did a blog
post a couple years back
where he looked at entitlements
that Office products had,
and he found that they had one entitlement
to drop files outside of the sandbox
if the file name was prepended
with tilde dollar sign.
So really good research,
and that technique still
works where you can drop files
on disk outside of the macOS
sandbox using that technique.
A colleague of mine, Madhav Bhatt,
who's also at Credit Karma,
he recently published a sandbox escape,
where essentially you create a zshenv file
that executes a payload.
You zip it, and for that zip file,
you prepend the tilde
dollar sign in front of it,
you drop it to the user's home directory,
you add it as a login
item, and then on reboot,
when the user restarts,
the login item extracts the zip file,
drops the zshenv file to
the user's home directory,
and then when the user opens the Terminal,
you have non-sandboxed
callback to your server.
So definitely check it out,
a very informative blog post
and does still work.
An example, Office macro
generators for macOS,
MacPhish has been around for a while,
and honestly that's where I learned,
I took a lot of my cues for
how to write macro generators
from MacPhish.
It's got a lot of cool options
where you can generate
Office macros that use Python
or curl or osascript or
combinations of them.
I also wrote a couple
macro generators as well
for Mythic that uses curl and osascript,
and I did my own for
MacC2, which is a command
and control tool that I wrote for macOS
that leverages Python.
I did highlight Python
in red, because again,
Python will be eventually taken
off of base macOS installs,
so just, I like to highlight it in red
so you can be prepared when that happens,
which is why things like switching
to JXA for example is a good option
because that will be around for a while.
Also, when it comes to Office macros,
AutoOpen subroutine is useful
so that when the document
is double-clicked,
the Office macro can be executed,
and here's an example here
of how I concatenated the
word Python and the word exec,
and you see long strings
of base 64 characters,
or I guess in this case
hex characters, excuse me,
long strings of hex characters,
and what those do is,
in this payload that I've
written, I basically read from a,
I read the actual payload from a file,
read it into a long hex string,
and now it's just breaking that hex string
into smaller chunks.
So now I'm gonna quickly
talk about CVE-2021-30657.
This was the bug I
reported to Apple this year
that was Gatekeeper bypass
around the March timeframe,
and kinda where the
idea for this came from
was I started thinking about,
well, here's the typical
structure of app bundles on macOS.
You have the app name, you
have the contents directory,
macOS directory, and then
there's a Mach-O inside of that,
so when you double-click an app bundle,
the Mach-O inside of it is what executes,
and it just has all these
other wrappers around it
like info.plist, et cetera,
so I started thinking,
what if we put something else here,
something that's not
checked by Gatekeeper,
because Mach-Os are checked,
which is why when you download
an app from the internet
and try to execute it,
Gatekeeper will pop up,
like if you just try to normally run it.
But in this case, what if
we put something like Bash
or Python in place of the
Mach-O binary since neither
of those scripting languages
are checked by Gatekeeper?
So I did that.
That's kind of what led to the bug,
I found that it worked and
it did bypass Gatekeeper,
and I reported this to
Apple March, I believe,
of this year and they
fixed it in short order
in Big Sur 11.3 and in Catalina updates.
From the Apple Security Bounty website,
they have a section there for
user-installed applications
and access to sensitive data.
$100,000, all right,
really big bounty payment,
but they have a very,
you see the two asterisks
there next to that first line,
I wanted to highlight that
because Apple has a very narrow definition
of what they consider sensitive
data, and in my opinion,
it's much more a consumer
focus versus enterprise focus,
because they only consider
contacts, mail, messages, notes,
photos, or location data to
be sensitive information,
which makes sense from an
individual consumer perspective,
but when you're starting to look at Macs
in an enterprise like what
we're talking about here,
macOS environments where
organizations have thousands
of users that are using Macs
and they're doing development
and engineering work
with sensitive data on the host,
this definition certainly
should be expanded.
And in my case, my app
detonated, got remote access,
and then I was able to
access sensitive data,
which is things like SSH keys,
AWS keys, Azure, GCP keys,
other files in the user's home directory,
the user's shell history
that contains sensitive
information depending
on what they've done, so
a lot of different pieces
of sensitive information that
this payload had access to,
but because of Apple's very restricted
and limited definition, kind of consumer,
individual consumer-focused
definition of sensitive data,
I received a tiny bounty
payment in this case,
nowhere near that 100,000 there,
so just wanted to point that out.
For researchers, if you're
submitting things to Apple,
to just be aware of that, and
the reality is Apple may say
that this is the small breadth
of sensitive data we care about,
but from an attacker's perspective,
you may have a bypass and
you're able to get things
that are outside of that window of Apple,
in terms of their definition
of sensitive data,
but it's still sensitive
data, and so that can happen
in your case as well
where you receive a small bounty payment,
so just wanted to give
you a heads up with that.
Some interesting things
about this payload,
so I mentioned it does bypass Gatekeeper
and app transport security
that we talked about earlier,
where the system restricts what
websites an app can talk to
or what types of protocols
it can talk over,
those things don't apply,
also you'll have access
to non-TCC folders so
you'll have the ability
to grab things like SSH and AWS keys,
et cetera off the host,
and it's very convincing,
so as you can see here,
just by copying icons over
to my fake app and it's
got the OneDrive logo
and it looks pretty close.
And so serves as a really good payload
that a user can just
simply double-click a DMG
or a zip and double-click
the app inside of it,
and that's it, so it's
not, no need to right-click
and do all these other things,
which made this a very powerful bypass.
And I, in my tests, I did both
with trying a shell script
at the bottom of the app
bundle as well as having Python
at the bottom of the app I'm doing.
In both cases they work,
because neither Python
or Bash scripts are checked by Gatekeeper,
so I was able to get a
callback in both cases,
and here's an example,
just kinda walking you through
what the payload looks like,
and I'm just showing you here
that Terminal does not
have full disk access,
it did not have any folder access as well,
and Gatekeeper's set to App Store
which is the most restrictive level,
so just wanted to show that
there's no trickeration going on
in the background.
Here is the payload that pulls down curl,
or uses curl to pull down the payload,
and runs it backgrounded,
and then there's an
osascript message there
which is a fake prompt to the user,
saying thank you for installing this app,
so you'll see what that looks
like a little bit later.
Next, I'm using this masquerade script.
It's a slightly modified
version of a tool called Appify
that's been out for years, that
basically took shell scripts
and put them in the bottom
of an app bundle structure,
and so that's what I did here
is just ran that masquerade
script and created a fake app
that has the structure of an
app, but instead of a Mach-O,
it has the shell script
downloader at the bottom
of the bundle.
Now what I'm doing is taking
the icon from OneDrive
and I'm copying it over
to remove the default logo
in my fake app to make it look
a little bit more realistic,
and notice that the operating
system labels both of them
as apps, even though in my case,
I don't even have an info.plist.
Just there, it just kinda
follows the app bundle structure,
so now that I have my
fake app with the logo,
what I'm doing now is
copying it over to a folder,
and then I'm gonna go into Disk Utility
and essentially create a
DMG file to host the app.
So that's kinda what I'm doing here.
I just moved the fake app over
to a folder called hosting,
and now I'm saving it there
and I'm gonna give it a
new name called RealApp,
so it'll be saved as RealApp.dmg.
So that's what's happening
here, so now that that's done,
you'll see RealApp.dmg was dropped there,
so the next step will be
to show that when a user,
basically to simulate a user
downloading it from the web,
so I'm gonna host the RealApp.dmg
to a local web server here
using simple HTTP server,
and that way I can click it, download it,
and when I download it,
it will have the same quarantine attribute
that a user would have if
they had to download it
as part of a phishing
exercise, for example.
So I just hosted it.
Here's me accessing it here locally,
and you can see there's RealApp.dmg,
so just single-click it,
it downloads to the Downloads folder,
and now we'll just confirm
that the DMG file does have
the quarantine attribute
that Gatekeeper checks.
We'll take a look at that now.
And as you can see,
it does have the com Apple
quarantine attribute appended
to it, so now we're
ready to take that file
that we just downloaded and detonate it
and see what happens.
So you detonate the DMG,
outside the DMG is the fake app
that we created here in the
demo, we double-click that.
Notice no Gatekeeper popups
anywhere, and as you can see,
you got the fake popup
there that says thank you
for installing this provisioner,
it fakes to be from the IT
team, and in the background,
I get a callback from my Mythic
command and control server.
So again, Apple has fixed this,
but I just wanted to show you
what the bypass looked like
when I submitted it to them.
Other things to keep in mind from TCC,
a lot of this we've already talked about
of what's not protected.
Another thing to mention is SSH is often,
kinda touched on it early,
but in enterprise macOS environments,
SSH is usually running by
default on the endpoints,
and SSH daemon was recently pointed out
in the Mac security community
that the SSH daemon actually
has full disk access,
so if a machine, if you're on a machine
and you have credentials of the
user and you SSH in locally,
using those, that set of credentials,
you now can have full disk
access and bypass TCC,
so something to point out there.
The quarantine attribute,
using curl does not append
the quarantine attribute,
just downloading through
browsers or through Bluetooth,
sharing files from one
machine to the next,
which is AirDrop, things
like that will append it
but using curl does not, so
that's something to keep in mind
because I used that in
my Gatekeeper bypass,
and from signing and
notarization perspective,
you could totally sign
and notarize your payload
if you want in order to get
around some of the controls,
but in my personal experience,
I found that it was pretty,
a pretty painful process,
and when I did sign and
notarize my red team payload,
I had about a week before
Apple retroactively found it
and deactivated the developer account
and revoked the certificate,
so just something to think about.
I personally believe it's
probably not worth the time
since real-world malware samples
are often using unsigned,
non-notarized payloads
and social engineering
that right-click open
execution of the payload.
Once you're on a host, lots of
different things you can do.
You can, again, you can
grab the system credentials
from the host, so like
AWS credentials, GCP,
Azure credentials, you can look
through users' Bash history,
you can look for maybe
sensitive files on the system,
sometimes users might save
tokens or passwords to a file,
MangoPDF did a really good
blog post on cookie crimes,
things you can do there
with, for Google Chrome,
so definitely check that out.
I have a link in the
resources section later
to that blog post.
Course you can prompt
the user for credentials,
you can do it via osascript
or you can do it programmatically
to not leave any command line artifacts.
You can also search for other
interesting files on the host,
and even this file here on the bottom,
this login data Chrome database,
contains a stats table,
and that stats table contains
the username and the login URL
for various sites, and it's,
of course it's unencrypted,
and you do not need root to
read it, and it's not protected
by TCC meaning any non-sandbox
payload can now read
from that table, which means
if you already have the user's password,
considering often times
passwords are reused,
that table now provides usernames
to try that password
against for different sites.
Also if you have root access,
you can grab the keychain database
and take it offline using
forensic tools like chainbreaker,
and so you can gain root access
via either installer package
which we talked about,
that gives you root access
because you use authenticate,
or if you get normal
user access, you can use,
you can basically prompt
the user for credentials,
and once you get those
credentials, you can then,
through tools like Mythic,
you can run elevated
commands since the user,
via the username and password,
that user is usually root on their Mac,
so then you can use that
to run elevated commands
and pull of the keychain, so
something to look at as well.
When it comes to persistence,
lots of different options
beyond just launch agents
and launch daemons, which
are probably the most popular
for macOS.
TheEvilBit did a really good
long-running blog post on,
titled Beyond Good Old
LaunchAgents, which goes,
it's like the Mac version
of Beyond Good Ole Run key
on a Windows side and looks
at all sorts of interesting
persistence options on macOS.
Leo Pitt or D00MFist also
has a PersistentJXA repo,
looking at JXA implementations
of a lot of the techniques
that TheEvilBit talks
about in his blog post.
I also then took a subset
of D00MFist PersistentJXA
and did some Swift implementations,
so I have a repo now
called Persistent-Swift,
so you have a lot of different
resources there to play with,
different, to look into
different persistence options
and different implementations for macOS.
Lots of other options here
like Vim plugin persistence,
SSHrc persistence, profile
persistence, Xorrior, Chris Ross,
he has a really cool
authorization plugin that,
he did a lot of research there,
so a lot of different options
to look into for persistence.
So some other attack vectors
beyond Mac that you'll,
typically will see in a macOS environment,
one being the build pipeline or also known
as the CI/CD pipeline,
and the way I like to describe
it is this is the process
that an initial concept
for code goes through
from the initial draft,
thought, or concept,
all the way through to
being customer-ready,
and it hits various stages
and checks along the way,
and what makes this so
interesting is there's a lot
of interconnections here
across different hosts,
so if you can access one of these hosts,
chances are you'll get a lot of access.
And sometimes your build environment,
your CI/CD process will
traverse environments depending
on what you have implemented
in your organization,
and as I mentioned, a lot of integrations,
like there may be some
internal Git integration,
and of course internal Git
becomes a target internally
because there tends to be more
trust for your internal Git
than your external Git, meaning
that since it's internal,
people may feel like posting
or committing secrets
in your code is not as
damaging, but ironically,
that's gonna be one
of the first places an attacker will look
in a tech environment is
looking through Git repos.
Jenkins is often commonly
part of the build process
and is usually misconfigured in some way
that will allow easy access,
and often times Jenkins will contain a lot
of different secrets on it, given that,
given its role in the environment,
and then of course you have workstations
where engineers may be doing
development from their Macs,
and there you'll have local
keys stored there as well.
Quick look at Jenkins, two
common misconfigurations,
this is the first one, allowing
unauthenticated build jobs
to be executed, so if this is
present in your environment,
you could hit the view default newjob URL
in your Jenkins host, and
it will bring you to a page
that will allow you to
run a new build job,
where then you can add a
single step to executor shell,
and you put whatever shell
command you want in there,
could be running a remote
shell, reverse shell payload,
it could be catting
out files on the system
that are sensitive, it could be querying
for metadata service IAM credentials
if your Jenkins host is
in a cloud environment.
And so you execute it
and you can see the console output there.
So essentially, this will allow compromise
and access to secrets which
can then be used to pivot
to other parts of the environment.
Another misconfiguration for
Jenkins that's pretty common
is the script console page
allowing unauthenticated access.
So if you, if this is
configured in your environment,
you can just hit the script
page of your Jenkins console,
Jenkins host, you'll be
brought to the console,
and then here you can run groovy script
and essentially get reverse shell access,
you can cat local files, query
for IAM metadata credentials
and the metadata service,
so all sorts of different
things you can do here as well.
A few other juicy targets,
of course internal Wiki,
so thinking about all the
organizational information,
system environment information,
credentials that are there
that can be leveraged
by an attacker,
thinking about your
internal ticketing system.
Imagine the environment information
that can be learned there, or processes
and architecture information.
Slack, of course, we mentioned
that earlier, credentials,
keys, VPN profiles, all that
stuff can be found often times
in Slack.
Another one, if you have
Docker in your environment,
if Docker's configured with
unauthenticated API sockets,
then those hosts can be
hit on port 2375 or 2376,
usually default ports,
but those hosts can be hit
and shell commands can be
run unauthenticated on those,
and potentially extract secrets out
from your containers there.
Of course we talked about internal Git,
so a lot of different
juicy targets once you're
in a macOS environment
outside of just macOS.
And of course you have cloud-hosted.
Usually if you're in a macOS environment,
there's gonna be a good
amount of cloud there as well,
and so the entry points
for cloud keys often times
can be phishing payloads
like grabbing cloud keys
off a compromised endpoint,
maybe code internal repos
for your internal Git,
so finding secrets that've
been committed there,
of course your build hosts like
your Jenkins as an example,
sometimes even build logs
will write the cloud keys
that it used during the build,
so that's a misconfiguration
to check for as well.
And it's good I think to also test
from a blue team perspective
to see what your cloud visibility
and detection posture is,
so can blue team see things
like accessing secrets
in the environment and using
those secrets to pivot,
different post exploitation
examples, like on the AWS side,
like looking at secrets
manager or parameter store
for additional credentials
which may provide access
to another environment or
a higher level of access,
assuming into other roles, so maybe,
let's say red team has
access to an AWS role,
that role has the ability
to assume into another role.
The role that they can assume
into has higher privileges,
so that would be a form
of privilege escalation
or lateral movement, to see
if blue team can see that,
attaching policies to users or roles,
all sorts of different
things here that can be done.
And I think it's worth
running through these types
of scenarios proactively or even looking
at the MITRE ATT&CK matrix
for a cloud that they have.
I'm looking at some common
privilege escalation
and lateral movement techniques
for different cloud environments.
So other recommendations
on the blue team side
is I definitely recommend leveraging
the Apple endpoint security framework.
It's good both from a personal standpoint,
so let's say you have
a payload, a red team
or a real malware sample payload,
you wanna understand what it does,
you can take Patrick
Wardle's process monitor
or file monitor that he
wrote and you can take it
on a sandbox macOS system, detonate it,
and then you can look
at the endpoint security framework logs.
It's almost like the
equivalent of Sysmon for Apple
or for macOS, so
definitely check that out,
and then you can look
for things like suspicious
command line executions,
persistence methodologies,
we talked about repos
that you can use there,
parent-child relationships,
so things like an Office
document spawning VEN SH
for example, that would
be something to key in on.
Course, network detection,
so looking for one host
accessing one or many ports
on multiple hosts over a short period
of time might indicate
scanning or sweeping activity,
course identity as a service
abuse, we talked about Okta,
OneLogin, so being able to
see if you have the ability
to see compromised tokens, and if so,
do you have the ability
and procedures in place
to revoke those tokens?
Of course Jenkins abuse,
so getting visibility
into script console abuse,
or build jobs running
suspicious shell commands,
and then within a cloud itself,
like AWS or GCP for example,
looking at your common post exploitation
and privilege escalation
methods, and auditing,
you could even proactively
audit your roles and see what,
like you can work with, I guess,
if you have a cloud security team,
you all can work together
to see what the state
of your current IAM roles are,
what roles they could assume into,
and look for easy
privilege escalation paths
and see what can be done
to reduce those paths.
Lots of different resources here,
lots of cool people I've
done a lot of awesome work
in the macOS space, so
this is not all-inclusive,
but just wanted to shout
out some good resources
for people who are
interested in delving more
into these topics.
Definitely check those out.
So thank you all for
listening, appreciate it,
and if you have any questions,
feel free to reach out.