- Hello to everyone.
Is a real pleasure to
be part of DefCon 29.
My name is Salvador Mendoza
and I'm a Security
Researcher at Metabase Q.
And I'm proudly member of
Ocelot Offensive Security Team.
Today, I'm going to talk
about the Pinata attack,
or PIN Automatic Try Attack,
regarding EMV technology.
So let's start with the agenda for today.
We're going to have an
introduction to terminology.
Also we're going to talk about
the EMV transaction flow,
which basically is how the card data goes
from the terminal
to the bank institutions,
and how it's processed.
After that we're going to talk about
the inadequate implementation
regarding this attack.
How someone could exploit it.
Finally we're going to have a demo
implementing a internal tool, named Elma.
And after that,
we're going to have some
conclusions regarding
this research.
Let's analyze some terminology
that we're going to use
throughout this presentation.
Some of them are going
to be very important
for the demos, for example,
or to understand a little
bit more in depth, how,
how the issue, how the bad
practices are implemented.
So let's start with a
secure element, or SE,
which is basically a responsible
to sign the transaction,
but to keep the secrets in the
card, on the physical card,
to sign the transactions,
when is processing it.
There's CVM, is the cardholder
verification method,
which could be different, right?
It could be that you verify
the transaction by signing it,
or it could be by PIN entry mode.
Also, we have the APDU,
application protocol data unit,
is a protocol in charge to communicate
or to conduct the
communication between the card
and the terminal.
Also, we have the ICC, or
integrated circuit card.
We know these cards, as well
as smart cards, for example,
but we're going to talk specifically
to the EMV transactions.
That's to be clear.
The PRC is the PIN retry counter.
One of the most important
terms that we're going to use
during this presentation
and also the ARC or ARPC,
authorization response code,
how the bank institution
responds back to the transaction
into a terminal.
The EMV contact payment
is one of the most common,
un-secure technology that we implement
and use every day to make transactions.
Because it implements a secure element.
The secure element is in
charge to sign the transactions
or to sign the challenge
that terminal is sending to the card.
Basically a contact payment.
It's when we insert the
card into a terminal,
and we'll leave it there
until the transaction finish.
Sometimes the user will require to insert,
or to enter the PIN, for the transaction.
Sometimes it will require to sign a paper
to verify the transaction.
When the card is in
inserted into a terminal
is going to be detected
and after that is going to be reset.
Is going to be the list applications,
and is going to be
different the steps until
the transaction is complete.
During these steps.
One of the most important
is if the transaction
is going to be processed online
or is going to be processed offline mode.
It will depend on different factors.
And of course,
is going to depend on
the verification method.
If we take a look into different details
regarding the terminal
on card communication,
we can see in the protocol phases, how,
how this transaction goes through.
For example, we have
the card authentication,
we have the cardholder
verification method,
and also we have the
transaction authorization.
It is going to be the last phase,
after the verification in the transaction.
When the terminal starts
sending commands to the card,
the card must answer back
for that specific command.
But for example,
let's say if the terminal sends a command
that is not properly right,
the card will answer back that
that command wasn't right.
So the terminal is going
to prepare a new command
and send it back to the card.
So basically, it's when
you're typing something
to a terminal and every
command you're getting
a response back, it's the
same thing with a terminal
and the card.
It's like a, sending a command
and getting a response back
very quickly.
One of the most important
parts and this protocol phase
is the cardholder modification method
that we're going to implement
for the Pinata attack.
Many people think that the
communication between the card
and the terminal is encrypted,
but is not, sadly is not.
And they use the ISO 7816,
which basically, many other
technologies use it as well.
Such as NFC, for example.
NFC implements the application APDU layer
to communicate with a terminal, as well.
And also the same technology
that we use for our cell phones.
This chip that you put in cell phone,
it communicates implementing
the same APDU layer
with a cellular phone.
So it's not encrypted the communication,
but you need to follows a format
and we're going to analyze
what is the format? What
is the APDU command format?
And also what is the APDU answer format?
So how they know how to answer back
and which format is going to be.
And take a look into the
different details of parameters
inside of this, of this APDU protocol.
So let's analyze one of
the most important parts
in the APDU protocol,
which are the commands and the responses.
So basically let's start
with the APDU command,
which is literally different
from the card response.
We have a header,
and we have a body.
And the body we have the
length of the command.
And also we have the
data from the commands
or the command, basically.
On the response, we have the
data and we have the trailer.
The trailer basically is the status
of the previous command from a terminal,
which basically that
it tells if the command
was secured correctly, or
if there is something wrong.
Something in the answer
is going to be in the
status of this trailer.
So to have a better idea,
let's analyze a APDU command example.
This one on the, is going
to be the first command
that the terminal sends to the card.
We analyze it separately.
We can see what is a class,
what is the instruction,
we have a parameter one, parameter two,
and we have the command length
and after that, we have the command
that is going to be sent to the card.
The same way, we have the card response,
which basically is the data.
And after that is a trailer.
So in this particular example,
we have the data and the
trailer is going to be 90 00,
which basically is that
the previous command was,
it secured correctly.
So now to analyze the data,
for example, in this response
we need to decode it.
To decode this data, we need
to use a TLV decoding method.
Or we can use the
emvlab.org, decoding tool,
which basically you put the APDU
is going to break apart each,
each command or each answer
that they print to the card,
which is very straightforward.
For this type of responses,
or commands we can analyze
very quickly to see what is
inside of the APDU protocol.
But essential to understand the process
and to understand the
communication between the terminal
on the card.
As a security researcher,
sometimes you need to find a way
to test some implementations,
but sometimes even when you have the idea,
you need to design or
create hardware or software,
depending on what you want to test.
This was the case
when we need to design a
tool to analyze APDU protocol
between the contact card, or
EMV card, and the terminal.
Because we know that these security cards,
but one thing is, what they mentioned
saying that they are security cards
and another thing very differently
is the implementation.
So we decide to create or to
design the Elma technology.
This Elma tool is a EMV
Laboratory Middleware Assistant,
which basically is what it does.
It assist to analyze the EMV
protocol between the terminal
on the card.
We're going to go into it tells about
how we design this hardware
and what are the capabilities
that we have in the laboratory
to analyze these technologies.
So this is the Elma board.
Is based on Simtrace 2, which
is a open hardware project.
Is specifically designed
for the same technologies
implemented in the cellular
phones, or the GSM network.
So the idea of Simtrace
2 is that you can sniff
or emulate traffic using the
same adapter on the board,
or using the USB cable connect
to a client in the computer.
On the other hand,
the Elma board is specifically designed,
using adapter, flexible
adapters, on both ends.
But also it has a capability
to implement the USB,
to feed the board or
to analyze the traffic
between the terminal on the EMV card.
Also, it's capable to connect to a server,
implementing the wifi
connectivity, using the ESP 32.
And it help us a lot in the laboratory
to understand the protocol
and to understand the features
in the EMV cards.
These are some of the
characteristics of the Elma board.
We have the USB-C connector,
which basically is for,
for flexibility.
Also, we have the ESP
32 that we implemented
for wifi connectivity to the server
or to external server
where we can send data
from the board, process it.
And after that, send
them back to the board.
So the board can emulate
it directly to a terminal.
Of course, where you have
different adapters to connect,
like for example, EMV cards or SIM cards,
we have different modes
that they could be, eh,
sniffing modes, fuzzers or
emulation specifically for,
for a task.
Let me show you how it looks a,
a connection for the sniffing traffic.
We have the EMV card in one side
and we have the Elma in the middle.
And after that,
we implement another connector
with a physical physical board
that simulates a physical
EMV card to the terminal,
which basically, it sends
the data through the Elma.
And it simulates a transaction.
Let's say, for example.
Basically this idea is to
sniff the traffic from the card
to the terminal and read
the responses from the,
from the card.
The idea of seeing the
commands from the terminal
and seeing the response
from the card is to analyze
how they interact with
each other and after that
we can analyze their responses.
And to see there is something where
putting this communication process.
So let's analyze the Elma tool set.
Elma has different
capabilities in the client.
And also in the board.
For example, we can use a sniffer
or emulator depending on the task.
Let's say for example, that
we want to sniff some traffic.
We can run the sniffer,
the sniffer platform,
or the sniffer firmware.
Or we want to emulate something
we can use the emulator
for that task specifically.
Inside of the emulator,
we have different features
like man-in-the-middle.
The man-in-the-middle can alter the CVM,
or basically the cardholder
verification method.
Imagine that we have the list
of the cardholder verification method
that in this list, depending on the order,
it could be the verification method.
So we can change that implementing this,
this type of man-in-the-middle
emulation mode.
Also we can change the terminal commands,
we can adapt the card response,
but one of the most
important parts is that
we can modify any EMV type value.
This is to test the
environment, basically.
Also, we have APDU fuzzer
is to send random data
to a terminal or to the card
to see if we can break something. Right?
Of course, we have the Pinata attack.
And in these, in these features,
which is basically this
presentation is based on.
And above all of that,
we have the option to implement a relay.
This means that for example, we can have,
the Elma board and one computer,
and even the physical card
could be in another location.
And we can start data from that card,
implementing the client
for, for this, for this Elma
is my work.
So the virtual smart card
is the core of the Elma technology.
Basically, I can relate
it to a software emulator
of smart cards,
but you have the capabilities
to connect physical card
readers to your computer
and move the data between these,
virtual smart card readers,
change the data and send it back.
And it could be sending back
over a relay for example,
or you can send it back
locally to another device
that is connected to the device.
It's very easy to use it.
And we implemented a
lot in the Elma design.
So after we analyze the APDU protocol
and how we design the Elma
prototype, or Elma technology.
Let me talk a little bit
about this inadequate implementation
to reset the PIN retry
counter in the EMV cards,
or bank cards, let's say.
So let's talk a little bit
about what is a process
in the protocol
when a transaction starts in the terminal
Initially, we have the
card authentication.
After that we have the
cardholder verification,
and then we have the
transaction authorization.
So let's start with the
card authentication.
In this step,
the terminal start sending commands
to list the applications.
Basically this point the
terminal knows what kind of card
you are using. Let's say visa,
MasterCard, American express,
something else.
So in the next, in the next step
is going to be the cardholder
verification method.
It's where the terminal is
going to prompt to enter a PIN.
Or it's going to ask you to
sign, to sign in terminal,
or is going, is going to depend,
depending of the terminal technology.
And of course, comparing
to the card technology.
All this process is going to finish
with the transaction authorization.
And this part, the terminal sends,
all the data to the backend,
to the financial institution.
And the financial institutions,
the financial institutions
sends back the IRC,
which basically is the
authorization response code.
And this is applied to
the card or on of course,
applied to the, to a transaction.
So at this point,
the transaction can go through
or it could be declined.
Is going to depend in all of
these, all of these forms.
So let's focus in on the
cardholder verification phase,
which is one of them,
one of the important
steps in this research.
Do you know how many
cardholder verification methods
do we have,
to make a transaction, for example?
So let's focus and read a little bit about
how many this verification
methods, implements,
in the terminal on the card,
when you're making a transaction.
So we have a kind of
list inside of the card
that it tells the terminal,
what kind of verification
methods is capable of.
Some of them are like,
no CVM required, signing the paper,
plaintext PIN by ICC,
plaintext PIN on paper,
also encrypt PIN by ICC, or
encrypt by ICC and sign paper.
And one of the most
important is encrypted PIN
and is verification online,
which is one of the normal verification
when you're using an ATM for example,
the verification is encrypted PIN
and verify online all the time.
So this some of the most common
cardholder verification
methods that we use
with the transactions.
So let's analyze this card response,
where we need to take
a look at the CVM list,
especially putting attention
to the 8E tag value.
So the first step is to
decode it, to see how it's,
how it's implemented
or what kind of value
the 8E attack contains.
So after we decode it,
we can see the cardholder
verification method list.
Inside of the list we have all the values,
all the possibilities
that the physical card has
to verify a transaction.
Specifically, I'm talking
about the 8E EMV tag.
If we split the values we can
understand them individually.
So let's do that.
So we have this list and
we are going to separate
each value to understand what exactly,
what exactly means.
So we have encrypt, encrypted
PIN, in the first row,
if terminal supports CVM.
The second row, is encrypted PIN by ICC.
And the third row is plain PIN by ICC.
And the next one is a sign.
Under that one, is no CVM required.
You can see this list is in order.
Do you might what happened if
I flip the values, let's say,
if I put the 1F03 on the top of the list?
That could be another
attack of another research,
but let's say we're going to be focused on
the plain Pin by ICC.
What this verification method does?
What exactly does is
that you can verify a PIN
against the ICC.
So for example, I want to
verify a PIN 1, 2, 3, and 4.
So I can send this 1, 2, 3, and 4
to the card implementing this command.
On the EMV card has different
possibilities to respond.
Let's say if it is that the right thing,
you're going to be a 90 00,
which is going to be the trail
of the EMV card response.
But also they have no more options
like 63 C2, which means
there is a wrong PIN,
but you have two more attempts left.
And after that is going to be 63 C1,
which means is a wrong PIN,
and one more attempt left.
And 63 C0, which means wrong
PIN and no more attempts left.
So you imagine, this is a
counter, PIN retry counter,
which basically it counts
how many attempts left
inside of the ICC.
So if this counters goes to zero,
that means that we don't
have any more possibilities
to attempt with another PIN,
which is a mechanisms to protect
against brute force attacks.
So to be able to send
these commands to the,
to the card, or to the EMV card,
first of course, the card has to support
plain PIN by ICC.
And another thing is, if we
go through the EMV flow chart,
we can see that to send PINs to the card,
we need to go through
the card identification.
And after that, we're going to be
in the cardholder verification.
At this point is where is,
where we able to send
commands to the card.
So let's say that we start sending
to check their retry PIN counter.
And at this point,
the retry PIN counter has
three more attempts left
to try different PINs.
So we start sending the PIN 07 18.
We got a response back, which is 63 C2,
which basically means is a wrong PIN.
And we have two more attempts left.
After we sent the last PIN,
which is going to be the 07 20,
we can notice that we got the 63 C0,
which means the PIN retry
counter is equal to zero.
That means that we don't
have more attempts left.
We are not able to try more, more PINs.
So here, the question is,
how can we reset this PIN
retry counter to three, again?
We have two common ways to reset the PRC,
or the PIN retry counter.
One of the most common is
when, do you remember the PIN?
And you can go to any ATM from the,
from the financial institution.
And when you insert the card to the ATM,
using the correct PIN,
the ATM internally is
going to run the scripts
specifically to do the card management.
And it's going to reset this PRC
to the value that it has before.
Another way to do it is when the card
contains the encryption key
on the MACE scripts
inside of the card.
So when the terminal basically generates
the application cryptogram
and response with the ARPC,
basically for online approval,
the financial institution
is going to response
with the ARPC,
which basically is for the approval
or rejection of the transaction.
But inside of this data,
we're going to have the CSU,
which basically is the card status update,
which contains some data
that could update the,
the card internally,
which could be a command to
reset the PRC specifically.
Let's imagine that we have a card
and we already try three different PINs.
So we don't have any more
attempts left in the EMV card.
That means that we need to
try to make a transaction,
to see if the financial institution resets
the PIN retry counter.
So how we can do this?
We can try to make a transaction
with no CVM required,
or we can try to make a transaction
implementing the signature CVM.
We can do this in different ways,
but normally, like the mobile POS's,
many of them implement no CVM
or signature CVM here in United States.
So the idea is that after generating
the application cryptogram,
the financial institution
returns the ARPC.
We can verify if the PIN
retry counter is set to three,
for example, or to five,
depending of the configuration.
And we can notice this in the last step
of the transaction when the
ARPC is applied to the card.
After this step we can
verify the PIN retry counter
is sets to the back,
to the previous value,
which it should be three or five,
depending on the implementation.
But, of course, this is a
inadequate implementation,
bad practice to do it.
The best way to reset
the PIN retry counter
is by using an ATM in the
financial institution,
or by calling a representative
from the bank, for example,
to assign a new PIN to the card.
And after they used that card in the ATM,
they are going to reset
the PIN retry counter,
but doing,
doing this type of reset
after a transaction,
it could be very dangerous,
I'm going to show you why.
So let's imagine that we
have a normal ARC from the,
from the bank, which
basically I can see some,
some changes between each responses.
So this one is a normal transaction
when you didn't receive
any order to change the PIN retry counter.
But in this slide, we can see a different,
different bytes that I can relate it to,
to the PIN retry counter, basically
to change it to the to the previous value.
So to be able to use the Pinata attack,
the card has to implement
two different features.
One is the plain PIN by ICC
cardholder verification method,
and also the PIN retry reset by the user
when the PRC is zero.
With these two characteristics,
we can run the Pinata
attack against the EMV card.
And we are going to show
you how I did my setup
to do this and to run this Pinata attack.
To run the Pinata attack we need to
make a special Elma set up project.
For this specific case,
I'm going to use the GPD
pocket 2, a small computer
or pocket computer is one
of the most powerful devices
in this size specifically
to do different things.
But I mean, you can use
any, any other device
that you have available
to do this type of setup.
Also, we're going to use
a cheapest card reader
that you can find on the
internet, is the SCR3310,
which basically what is going to do is
we're going to extract
the original EMV data
from this reader. So our
card, our financial card
is going to be inserted in this reader.
So basically with the pocket computer,
we're going to start reading the card
and we're going to process the data.
And after that, we're going to send it,
send it to the Elma board.
So ultimately we're going to
need the Elma board, of course,
and we're going to need
the SumUp payment system.
Basically is a, is a
payment system that you can,
that you can run implement
in a cellular phone.
So you have an application and you can,
you can make payments directly
to this, to this device.
The idea to have this device is to,
to be able to control the
payment environment, basically.
So the idea of the Elma at
this point is going to simulate
a real EMV card to SumUp,
but it's going to process
the data that we are going to
extract from the card reader, basically.
Because we're going to use
a mobile payment system
and we are going to have this application
for the SumUp payment system
in our cellular phone,
we need to implement the
Auto Clicker application.
The Auto Clicker, basically,
what is going to do
is going to play an
important role to make,
or to help us to automatize
different different tasks.
For example,
let's say that we try three different PINs
and we need to make a new transaction
to reset the PIN retry counter.
So the Auto Clicker is going
to that automatically for us.
So that's one of the most
important parts in this,
in this Pinata attack.
So this is my set up.
I have the Pocket 2,
basically in the middle,
we have the card reader, SCR3310,
where from where we are
going to strike data,
the original data from the card.
On the other side, we have the
Elma board connected by USB.
This could be a relay or
an internet, but for this,
for this demo, we are using a
locally, locally connection.
The Elma is going to
simulate the transaction,
implementing the, the
connector to the SumUp.
So when the SumUp sends the first command,
Elma is going to process it,
is going to send it to the
client in the pocket computer.
And the pocket is going to
send the last command to the,
to the card.
What's going to do on the client side
is going to start checking
for some kind of flags.
Let's say, if I activate the Pinata attack
is going to detect when we are going to be
in the verification mode.
And after that, we're going to start
making the brute force
attack against the PINs.
After we have a zero on
the PIN retry counter,
we're going to start a new transaction
to reset this PIN retry counter.
And after, we have another
three attempts in the counter.
We are going to start the process again,
to make the brute force
attack against this EMV card.
Internally in the computer
is going to be running
a virtual card reader, which
is going to expect data
from the card reader
or the physical reader.
And it's going to send this
data to the Elma board.
Basically is to process
the data internally.
And after that, to present
this data to a terminal.
the idea of implementing
virtual card reader
is to be able basically
to emulate a card reader,
but simultaneously to be able
to modify data in real time.
To visualize that Pinata attack.
So what it does basically
is after a transaction,
it checks if the plain PIN
by ICC verification method
is available. If it is, it
checks the PIN try counter.
If it is greater than zero
means that we have possibilities
to make a brute force attack.
If we couldn't find a PIN,
basically we repeat this cycle
until we get the correct PIN.
So mentioning this, we can go
directly to the demo slide.
So first I went to run the client software
to start to make a first,
the first transaction.
Here is a where the Auto
Clicker is very handy.
So it's going to help,
help a lot with all the transaction
that we are going to need.
After we, we made the first transaction,
we are going to check
the PIN retry counter
to see if it's greater than zero.
If it is, we're going to
try to brute force the PIN,
implementing a list of
possible PINs to try.
If we couldn't find any correct PIN,
we're going to make a new transaction
to reset the PIN retry counter.
And after we reset, we try
to make a brute force attack
against the EMV card.
If, we couldn't find, we'll
repeat the cycle until we,
we are able to, to find the correct PIN.
And in this last try, we
find we'll be able to find
the correct PIN. And is the 07 22,
which basically is the PIN that we can use
to make a transaction
with the card, basically.
On this point, we can
use this card in the ATM,
or to make a purchase in
any store implementing,
implementing the correct PIN.
I want to say thank you to these people.
They helped me a lot in this research,
especially the Metabase Q
team for all the details
and support.
Thank you for being part of DefCon 29.
Hope you guys keep enjoying this event.