- [Presenter] Hello everyone.
Another year to see you
in this special mode.
Welcome to our talk, "Caught You:
Reveal and Exploit IPC
Logic Bugs Inside Apple."
First, a self-introduction.
Zhipeng Huo is a senior
security researcher.
He's a member of EcoSec Team
at Tencent Security Xuanwu Lab.
His research focuses on macOS, iOS,
and Windows platform security.
He has found and reported
many vulnerability
to Apple and Microsoft.
He's a speaker of Black Hat Europe 2018,
and DEF CON 28.
Yuebin Sun is a co-author
of this presentation.
He's a senior security
researcher of EcoSec Team.
His focus is on macOS and
iOS platform security.
Chuanda Ding is also a
co-author of this presentation.
He leads the EcoSec Team
and is a speaker of Black Hat Europe 2018,
DEF CON China 2018, and DEF CON 28.
This is the agenda of our talk.
First, an introduction to
IPC and logic vulnerability.
Then we talk about the IPC
mechanisms on Apple platforms.
After that, we will share some interesting
logic vulnerabilities we found
in Preferences and App Store.
And finally, we'll give a conclusion
on IPC logic vulnerabilities
on Apple platform.
Let's talk about some
background knowledge.
What is IPC?
IPC means Inter-Process Communication.
It's a set of techniques
provided by the operating system.
It allows stand-alone processes
to communicate with each other.
The communication could be
about process notifying,
and then the process about some event
or transferring of data
from one process to another.
The processes involved in
IPC could have two roles,
client and server.
The client request the server,
and server may respond
to the client if needed.
The OS kernel provides the IPC channel
to allow the client and server processes
to send or reply to messages.
There are three advantages
that IPC provides.
First, modularity.
Modern software is more and more complex.
With the help of IPC,
developers could divide the complex system
into separated modules
and reduce the complexity of software
and avoids re-inventing the wheel.
Second, stability.
If all data and code
are inside one process,
a little error would probably
crash the entire system.
By dividing a complex system
into separated modules,
a module crash would not
crash the entire system,
which makes the system more stable.
And third, privilege separation.
With IPC, developers not
just separate functionality,
but also separate the privilege,
isolating sensitive operations
into separated processes,
giving the processes the least privilege.
Then if part of the system is hacked,
it will not compromise the entire system,
and increase the security
and protection from attacks.
Let's see an example of IPC usage.
The web browser.
It's nearly impossible to
build a rendering engine
that never crashes, and hence,
it's also nearly impossible
to build a rendering engine
that's perfectly secure.
To solve this issue, modern browser
mostly use a multi-process architecture.
For example, it may divide the components
into rendering process
and networking process.
So different processes of browser
would communicate with
each other through IPC.
And all of them also needs to request
the operating system's system service.
You may not feel it,
but IPC is everywhere.
The using of IPC divides the entire system
into separated processes.
Different processes have
different privileges.
Process may have low
privilege or high privilege.
A process may be sandboxed
or non-sandboxed.
There is a security boundary between them
and IPC may break it.
IPC is a bridge between
different processes.
So it is also a window
between different privileges.
IPC vulnerability is a
key to high privilege.
So it is one of the most valuable targets
for privilege escalation.
Logic vulnerability is different
from memory corruption vulnerability.
We do not want to play
with memory corruption
since they are boring to us.
We like to find logic flaws.
There are two kinds of logic flaws.
One that is introduced
during design phase,
and one is introduced
during implementation phase.
In fact, most of the time,
abusing existing features
are enough for us to
compromise the entire system.
Apple's new MacBook and iPad Pro
have been combined with
the new Apple M1 chip.
The new chip brings many
additional security features
such as system integrity, data protection,
and Pointer Authentication Code.
The Pointer Authentication Code or PAC
is a hardware-level security mechanism
against the memory bug,
which makes memory games much harder.
Logic vulnerability is not
playing with memory corruption
and may not be affected.
So is the Spring of logic
vulnerability finally coming?
Before introducing the
IPC logic vulnerabilities,
let's start with some
fundamental knowledge
of IPC on Apple platforms.
Apple IPC has different
specific implementation methods.
This includes shared files,
shared memory, and sockets,
which other systems supports as well.
There are also some that
are unique to Apple,
such as Mach messages, Apple events,
distributed notifications, and so on.
However, the latest and the most advanced
IPC methods on Apple platform
currently are XPC and NSXPC.
Apple implements them
on top of Mach message.
Next, we will walk you
through the principle
and usages of them.
Mach port is an endpoint
of unidirectional communication channel,
which is one of the fundamental parameters
of XNU kernel for messaging.
Messages can be sent or received from it.
Users of Mach port never
actually sees the port itself,
but access it through
a type of indirection
called Port Rights.
The sender of the message can
send the message to Mach port
through the SEND right.
The receiver of the message
can get the received message
the Mach port or through
the RECEIVE right.
The message transmitted
through the Mach port
is called Mach message.
The system trap level API,
mach_msg and mach_msg_overwrite,
can be used to send or
receive Mach messages.
The structure contains a header,
optional complex data,
and message buffer.
The header contains the sender
and receiver of the message.
The optional complex data
part can transfer complex data
such as a file handle,
shared memory, and Mach port.
Message buffer is used
to send binary data.
Mach message is low level and powerful,
but it is also ancient
and poorly documented.
Developers needs to construct
entire structure to transmit data
and handle different
data type by themselves.
It is difficult to use,
and Apple also does not recommend
developers to use it directly.
Instead, Apple provides
high-level IPC mechanisms
that are easier to use.
On top of Mach messages,
Apple built another communication
mechanism called XPC.
XPC is managed by launchd process.
Launchd is a naming server.
The XPC server register with launchd
and declares that it will handle message
sent to its endpoint.
The client looks up an
endpoint name via launchd
and sends a message request.
The server will receive the request,
handle it, and reply to
the client if needed.
Behind the scene, launchd
starts and terminates
the target server process on demand.
The message sent through
XPC is called XPC message,
which is a more structured
dictionary format.
XPC users do not need to
pay attention to the details
of the underlying Mach message processing.
Through the xpc_dictionary_set APIs,
we can easily construct
an XPC dictionary message.
Besides supporting the
transmission of basic types of data
such as typical string
integer and Boolean,
XPC message also supports
complex data types
such as file descriptor and shared memory.
XPC message is serialized
into Mach message
and transmitted to the
other end of the IPC
via the XNU kernel.
The received Mach messages is
unserialized to XPC message
and then can be used through
the xpc_dictionary_get APIs.
At the API level, the XPC server
calls
xpc_connection_create_mach_service API
with the
xpc_connection_mach_service_listener
flag set
to register itself to
launchd as an XPC service.
And then the client can
connect to the XPC service
through the same API.
The message sending is completed
by the xpc_connection_send_message.
After the process
received the XPC message,
the registered message handler
via xpc_connection_set_event_handler
will be called to process the message.
The mainstream languages
for app developers
are the object-oriented
Objective-C and Swift.
So Apple has encapsulated a layer
of object-oriented implementation
on top of XPC called NSXPC.
NSXPC provides a set of remote procedure
call interface implementations
instead of caring about the
underlying message like XPC.
After establishing the connection,
the client can directly
call the open interface
of the NSXPC server across processes,
just like calling local methods.
Apple provides many NSXPC
classes for developers.
The server registers
the service with launchd
through the NSXPCListener,
and specifies a NSXPCListenerDelegate
to handle the connection request.
The connection between a client and server
is managed by NSXPCConnection.
What method can a client call in a server?
The NSXPC server defines this
through the Objective-C protocol,
which defines programmatic interface
between the calling
application and service.
In interfaces definitions,
common arithmetic types and basic types
such as strings and arrays
are directly supported as parameters.
The interface also supports
custom defined class objects
to be parsed as parameters.
The custom object needs to implement
the NSSecureCoding protocol.
Here is an example.
Here is an architectural
diagram for an app.
The server registered the service
through an NSXPCListener.
The app establishes a
connection with the service
through the NSXPCConnection.
In this process,
both parties can directly
call remote methods
across process boundary
without caring about
the underlying implementation details.
We will now share some
interesting logic vulnerabilities
we found and exploited on Apple platforms.
We found and reported three logic bugs
in Preferences components.
With these vulnerabilities,
a local user may be able to modify
protected parts of the file system.
What are Preferences?
Preferences are user-defined settings.
They are persistent data
stored in Preferences file.
Its format is property
list also called plist.
The service, cfprefsd,
has the responsibility
to manage Preferences.
It would read from or
write to Preferences file
according to client requests.
Apple provides two kinds of
high level Preferences API.
Using the Foundation APIs,
apps could use the NSUserDefaults class
to access its Preferences.
Each app has a single
instance of this class
accessible from the
standardUserDefaults class method.
Through the shared user defaults object,
apps could get and set
individual Preferences values.
Apps can also use many of the underlying
core Foundation APIs.
For example, CFPreferencesSetAppValue
and CFPreferencesCopyAppValue
could be used to get or
set the Preferences data.
After reverse engineering cfprefsd,
we found it create the XPC service
named com.apple.cfprefsd.daemon,
which runs with root
privilege and without sandbox.
When the client requests cfprefsd,
the event handler will be
scheduled to handle the request.
As a foundational service,
Preferences could be accessed
from almost everywhere.
Even the most restricted process
needs to access Preferences.
Here is a sandbox profile
for Safari web browsers.
It allows the sandbox process
to access com.apple.cfprefsd.daemon.
Because cfprefsd is an XPC service,
we could also request it by
sending XPC message directly.
It is a low level method
that could control
the operation more precisely.
Here is a sample request.
First, we use the
xpc_connection_create_mach_service
to create a service connection.
Then we create the XPC
dictionary and set the key value
that is used to control the operation.
Finally, we send the XPC message
through the
xpc_connection_send_message API.
Where does cfprefsd save
the Preferences data?
The Preferences file path
is constructed from multiple components.
Part of it is a fixed value in cfprefsd.
Parts of it come from the
client through XPC message.
First, let's see the Preferences Directory
where the Preferences file is stored in.
There are some predefined
locations to store the file.
PreferencesDomain is a value
that is parsed through the
CFPreferencesDomain key.
By default, the file path is composed
of PreferencesDirectory,
PreferencesDomain,
and the surface string .plist.
How is the file path constructed?
There are two main components.
First, format the file path
with CFStringCreateWithFormat
which concatenate the
PreferencesDomain with .plist,
then
using
CFURLCreateWithFileSystemPathRelativeToBase
to generate the full path.
The baseURL is the PreferencesDirectory,
and the filePath is the
path returned above.
Logic vulnerabilities always
combine some features.
And we found that
CFURLCreateWithFileSystemPathRelativeToBase
have two features that may be abused.
First, this function has
path traversal feature.
If filePath contains ../,
the returned filePath could
traverse to any path we want.
The second feature is that
if the filePath is an absolute path,
it will return the filePath
no matter what the baseURL is.
We could use the path traversal feature
or absolute path feature to
control the Preferences filePath
and return any filePath we want.
What if the controllable filePath
does not exist on the file system?
The function name,
cacheActualPathCreatingIfNecessary,
is very interesting.
Seems it will create the file
path if it does not exist.
Firstly, it will try try to open a file.
If the file path exists,
it will return path.
But if the file path does not exist,
it will get the directory
part of the file path,
and it will create the directory.
After it created the directory,
it tries to open the file path again,
and then return the file path.
The CFPrefsCreatePreferenceDirectory
is the function
used to create the now
existing directories.
It first split the path into
multiple sub items by slice
and then creates them
recursively with mkdirat.
After the directory is created,
its ownership will be modified
through a file change owner.
But where does the user
ID and group ID came from?
The owner of the newly created directories
is determined by several factors.
By default, the owner is the
identity of the XPC client
and cfprefsd get the
identity of the client user
through xpc_connection_get_euid
and xpc_connection_get_egid.
However, the XPC client can
also specify the expected user.
Therefore, the ownership of
the newly created directory
is also under our control.
We can let cfprefsd help us create
any directory with controlled owner.
There are many ways to convert
arbitrary directory creation
to code execution with root privilege.
Here we share a method
mentioned by Csaba Fitzl
through periodic script.
Periodic script is a mechanism
to schedule script execution.
The daily directory does
not exist by default
but the operating system will periodically
scan and execute the files in it.
By exploiting the vulnerability,
we can create the daily directory
and set the owner of the
directory to the current user.
And then we can write any
script to the daily directory.
Wait a day, and the script will
execute with root privilege.
The patch for the vulnerability
is simple and straightforward.
It can be explained even by
looking at the function name.
The cacheActualPathCreatingIfNecessary
function
has been replaced with
cacheFileInfoForWriting.
There is no creating anymore.
In fact, cfprefsd will
no longer help the user
create the non-existing
Preferences Directory.
If client parse in a directory
which does not exist,
cfprefsd will ask the client to create it.
How does cfprefsd read
the Preferences data?
When the client wants to get the data,
the client needs to request cfprefsd.
By default, it will read the data
and then return them
in the reply directly.
But if it decides that
the file is too large
to fit in a XPC message,
it will just return the file descriptor.
To avoid subsequent changes to the file,
it will clone a copy before
return the file descriptor.
This function is the
implementation of cfprefsd
to process large Preferences file.
First, it gets the file path,
then it determines whether the file size
exceeds one megabyte.
Then it generates a
random temporary file path
according to the rules,
and then clone the original
file to a temporary file.
Finally, open a temporary file,
and return its file descriptor.
It calls clonefile to clone
the file to a temporary file
with a random name.
The temporary file and the original file
are in the same directory.
The path of the temporary file
is generated by mktemp
according to a rule.
The rule is that the file path is spliced
with .cfp and seven random characters.
So the final temporary
file name is random.
But can it guarantee it to be random?
The mktemp will replace the
seven X at the end of the row
with random characters.
The space for random
characters is very large.
Is there any other way to make mktemp
generate a fake file name?
One key point is that snprintf
specifies a maximum length as
0x400 for generating rules.
If plist path is very long,
what happens if the
splicing row exceeds 0x400?
Snprintf will overflow
and the characters exceeding 0x400
will not be written
into the written buffer.
To be more precise,
if the length of the filePath pass
the cfp string is exactly 0x400-1,
the rule generated by snprintf
will not contain X at the end.
And mktemp will generate a
fixed temporary file path.
Before clonefile is called,
there's a file check.
In exploit code,
we can first parse in a normal file path.
This will ensure that cfprefsd
can successfully pass this check
and enter the subsequent
clonefile process.
After the file check and
before the clonefile,
there is a window for race condition.
Before we replace a controllable file
with a symbolic link during this time,
cfprefsd will call clonefile to help us
copy arbitrary file to a
temporary file path we control.
We've got a fixed temporary file name,
but can we link it to another place
ahead of mktemp function?
No, this file name is
guaranteed not to exist
at the time of function and location.
But after the mktemp return successfully
and before the clonefile,
this is also a window for race condition.
We could replace the temporary
file with a symbolic link.
In this way, we can achieve
arbitrary file write.
In the patch, Apple added
an overflow checking
and the subsequent clone
file will not be executed
if overflow occurs.
The previous method of
forcing fixed file name
no longer works.
How does cfprefsd write Preferences data?
When cfprefsd saves Preferences
data for the client,
first it extract key and
value from the XPC message,
then it reads the original
data from the target file,
and it generates new data based on
the incoming key and value data,
and writes to the new
data to a temporary file.
And then it renamed the temporary file
back to the target file.
When saving data, cfprefsd verifies
the client has write
permission to target file.
The client needs to parse
in a file descriptor
with write permission.
After the previous check,
cfprefsd would generate a temporary file
and write data to it.
Then it will rename this temporary file
back to the target file.
Can normal user replace the source file
if the rename was a symbolic link?
No, this temporary file is
in root-owned directory.
A normal user does not have permission
to write to this directory.
Can a normal user
replace the rename target
as a symbolic link?
Normal user has write
permission for the target,
but the target file will be deleted first
when the rename is called.
So even if it can be replaced
with a symbolic link,
it will not work.
Regarding this feature,
the rename API documentation says,
if the final component of the
target is a symbolic link,
the symbolic link is renamed,
not the file or directory
to which it points.
But wait, the document says that
if the final component of the
target is a symbolic link,
rename will delete it first.
What if it's not the final component?
What if the middle component of plist_path
is a symbolic link?
Suppose the path of Preferences
is /tmp/test/hello.plist?
If we replaced the directory
with a symbolic link,
pointing to the LaunchDaemons directory,
then the hello.plist is used
as the target path of rename,
what will happen?
The symbolic link will be followed
and the temporary file will be moved
to the LaunchDaemons directory.
Before renaming the temporary file,
it verifies the caller
has write permission.
However, after the file check
and before the rename function,
there is a time window to
replace the middle component
of file path with symbolic link.
In renaming files, it will
move the temporary file
with controllable content
to arbitrary path.
The patch for the rename
vulnerability is very simple.
Rename is replaced with renameat.
Renameat locates the target file
according to the directory descriptor,
to ensure that the final move target
must be in a certain directory.
So even if we replace the
directory with a symbolic link,
it will not work anymore.
Here is a demo.
We used the vulnerabilities to achieve
arbitrary file read and write,
and then we put get
root privileges on macOS
and read privacy data on iOS.
First,
we used Preferences vulnerabilities
to achieve root privilege.
We could see the system
integrity protection is enabled.
The current user is a
normal user, not root.
We could get the root
privileges very quickly.
Next, we use Preferences vulnerabilities
to read privacy data on iOS.
You can see our demo
application is not allowed
to access photos and contacts.
However, when we take a photo,
then the open the demo application.
Our demo application can steal the photo
and send it to our server.
Last year, we found and
reported an interesting
logic vulnerabilities in
macOS App Store component.
An application could abuse it
to gain elevated privilege.
The vulnerability exists in NSXPC server,
com.apple.storedownloadd.daemon.
The server is implemented in
storedownloadd application,
which runs with root privilege.
Fortunately, this process
is run in the sandbox.
But unfortunately, as
an app download service,
it must have the ability to write
to some sensitive locations.
For example, it is allowed
to write to applications
and keychains directory.
As an NXSPC server, it provides
many interfaces for client.
Here we listed the setStoreClient
and performDownload interface.
The performDownload interface
is very interesting.
This interface performs
downloading jobs for the client,
but what can it download,
and what is the SSDownload parameter?
For NSXPC, the Objective-C
object and implements
NSSecureCoding protocol
could be used as parameters.
SSDownload is such an object.
This object only have
one property, assets.
And it is an array.
The element in the assets array
is SSDownloadAsset object.
It is also an Objective-C object,
and it has three properties.
The URL, download paths, and hashes.
The SSDownloadAsset object is
passed from client to server.
The properties of SSDownloadAsset
will be serialized in client.
The function, encodeWithCoder,
will be called
to serialize the specified
properties to XPC message.
At the server side,
the XPC message would be
unserialized with initWithCoder,
and construct the SSDownloadAsset object
with specified properties.
The properties of the object
would be fully controllable.
How does storedownloadd
perform downloading tasks?
It will perform download
task according to the URL,
then it verifies the response
contents based on the hashes.
And finally, it writes the contents
to the specified download path.
There is a hash verification
in the download logic.
This function will calculate
the hash of the response content,
and then compare it with the
hashes the client specified.
But it's not a security check,
just a data integrity verification.
Because we can control the download URL,
the content hash and download path,
we could write arbitrary file path
with the storedownloadd's privilege.
Attackers could say,
"Hi, it's storedownloadd.
Please help me download
the file from this URL.
Its hash is this...
and then write the contents
to this download path.
Thanks!"
Then the storedownloadd would do
all the jobs well for the attacker.
How did Apple fix this vulnerability?
"The issue was addressed
by removing the vulnerable
code," they said.
To be more precise,
they completely removed the service.
There is no
com.apple.storedownloadd.daemon anymore.
Here is the demo of App
Store vulnerability.
We just downloaded the
test.keychain in tmp directory,
to keychains directory,
with the help of storedownloadd.
There are other interesting
logic vulnerabilities
we found and detailed in our blog;
an XPC service implementation flaw,
which is a logic bug inside launchd,
for managing the XPC service;
and NSXPC vulnerability in
Adobe Acrobat Reader for macOS.
There are many security
mechanisms on Apple platform
that tries to make
vulnerabilities harder to exploit
like DEP, ASLR, PAC and so on.
But you probably noticed that logic bugs
are not affected by
these security features.
That's just awesome.
Logic vulnerabilities has many advantages.
Though it is hard to find,
it is easy to exploit.
The exploitation is always stable.
The logic vulnerabilities
exist across platforms often,
so one exploit could rule them all.
Logic bugs in core
frameworks like Preferences,
let us rule whole Apple platforms,
Intel and Apple Silicon alike,
without changing one line of our exploit.
Apple is also working
hard to try to reduce
the IPC attack surfaces.
For example, by adding more
restrictive sandbox rules,
it reduced the IPC services
accessible to applications.
They keep deleting the unnecessary
high privilege services,
and they are adding more and
more private entitlements
to make many high privilege services
only accessible to Apple applications.
It hard to make sure
everything is perfectly secure,
so Apple is also trying
to limit the damage.
For example, they are putting
IPC services in sandboxes
and give them the least privilege.
They are also using Rootless
to limit the root privilege.
In this presentation,
we talked about the latest IPC mechanism
on Apple platforms, XPC and NSXPC.
Then we walked you through
some of the interesting
IPC logic vulnerabilities;
three logic vulnerabilities
in Preferences,
and one in App Store.
We detailed the design logic
and the implementation
of these components,
the flaws inside them
and how we exploit them
to elevate privilege.
And we also talked about the advantage
of IPC logic vulnerability,
and the state of Apple IPC security.
Logic bugs are always fun to hunt for.
We think you will love it just as we do.
We would like to thank Csaba
Fitzl, Ian Beer, and Zhi Zhou
for their previous work and shares.