hello everyone to the original nomas I
am responsible for the technical sector of
eyes on
today I will quickly present you
who are the new scenarios that
are currently found in the field of
cybercrime and those who are and how to already
acquire everything by explanation
on those who  it is the various methods
of personnel training said that
cyber security ctf normal let's say ctf
precisely high that makes because we are
specialized and that which
nationalization of a cyber you know
of an attack type and he thinks how it was
organized was implemented
implement it later  the final purpose
of this operation from that of
measuring the cyber place to
actually understand where the weakest points
of those who participated in this
type of activity were I do not anticipate much
for which he wants to go a little quickly
addressed to the area is a
consulting company  main spa turin then
another office in italy milan rome genoa
bologna at various markers  i in australia and
north america and we have specialized in
all class ad consulting activities
plus a sector of always securid
we operate with activities that are two
cents gross of the center for ethics
intends but also the realization and
development of different types of
products we do  also activities
of prevention warners for customers
we teach there is attention to robberies
you all know that
a little the hand is the classic thing she has
ensured especially before but the
infusions a company 94,000 in the usa
plus the fact of 20 cents at the level
of  new technologies
now let's talk about the functions of signaling
this amis or as in the special
perhaps evolved behavioral rising
part-time personnel to the question of making
automatic scenes of what is
simply human and making him believe that
he is in the environment he wants
in the nature of the facts he takes
regularly viewed but noticing
or humanitarian assisting negative
because they will  or to read the
sanremo
this summer the engine failed both a
recipe of practically hanging techniques
used above all to make the 20th
traction then carry out scans
analysis attacks on the insane hairpin with
agent systems chosen to make all
envious suffers went to the fields for
the origin of the flight  at christmas
we also build msd traders
to make sure that I never am this one
from modena help a company that has not
been simulated the super explicit
information and effective efficient operator
and what we see around the
world we would have believed they do not go to
seminars  it is given made us working
on the defense motion we come to
sacred repetition usually thank goodness those face a
militant strate to do precisely on
tripoli
the activity of selling the state in
quotation marks
in the middle we have been acquitted deep
of various acts various groups that are found
alive  for some months
new competition in arm hardware capabilities
that had interested  o the
ceramic museum of all criminals are
always crucial healthy you have seen the
life walls the various pc campaigns of
attacks in general for the dust that is
those that a sharon hom commodities
is instead more however Italian in
terms more control the game and
starting again to speak also in eruption
endowed seems alive with the May of so
Italian material of quarry ii of cerano
and then move towards the opposite one
that would like to be of the series of the
exploded attacks no cross or a
saleen of real identities actually
armed when all the formations
passport of the  driving license and quatar the
revolution knows how to do exhibition forms
I want to attack a certain esteem in
themselves they already give me everything done to
build a game system
for control heaven there is no
back of mass of fortune in rice already
like a blacksmith  attacked and we use it
insert a phase will be rendered in
as ridiculously
I need to fight but from the market
of everything that can
be used to accomplish myself I also have
the over having to do it comes much more
complex I can do that
I was pleased with the services but there are
the impact in terms of costs of the cyber
loaded worldwide and an estimated 6 million
pato dollars the cost of power I
know what management for
information retrieval no one may in the state
screamed but in fact
actually taken the measures are a
little different
everything always the events use what they
had exponents I do one
however somehow brings home disagreements
someone who pays is there hoping to
actually free himself from activities
convince orange rooted even not
only maldolese of five file managers
italy of blackmail in general more
technologically aimed at blocking
particular systems spoken illicit activities
in london in various
kinds points of intellectual power but
ricardo about between saturday at home
meeting has never lied about everything a c  dare
instead more interesting to ask yourself
how polyclinic and passages from a dear friend
you will want South Tyrolean mind to a friend at
immediate need centers I would like three
wagons as I am amazed by the
carnet listen to
a part basin habits own
function of 303 investments
final tenth a reinvestment unfortunately the
technologies way the parks investments
particular excess of drugs
valuable type the ease I do not know if you do not
know how to avoid that a product in any case
in private with the recipient and
capitulates to the welfare state in the
sense that I show that doing these
truths perhaps takes the theses all done
the collaborators seem to be only carlo
cafiero to separate beautiful name says
that he sells data considered talent and
the alleged 2000 strips forward
compared to rooms space
also become working as it was but I was there to
train to give space even serious spaces
of a double between  they sing and therefore
all states not to be organized
go to awaken you for walls exalted
any exercises using to the
sacraments or carry out of seven
robbie arrest raised to read in the
military field that I have done only of
projects fat says that this field develops
the fork technology and above all from
what we have to sound
operated requests  Neapolitan or the souls are
national who are interested in doing almost
13 years of development that is the born that is the
state graph without the earth is always
skyrocketing even the European Union as
the age of fiat and rosary is admitted
within the  crazy about the development of
innovative technologies in the context
of the defense attack faced by the
dictator that failing what we
feel industrial very great merits
the intelligent car that thank goodness are
suitable systems or totally bears
from the estimates scandals that happening
somehow open about why  admits
the problem of lori systems usually
theorized pageant drop in which
new thing and rubles in security
which will then be normal in this
post transplant mountain but not
enough so that the systems
produced are not always longer usually
to pay so that more standards notice
a very important thing and to train
the saiwa  stomach of three people in
understand what is needed if this is already
difficult but we will also make national
the usual try to provide some
kind that is to put new
mindsets also to be against because
in the end
tell us most to
secure the building  activity comes the
rules and regulations issued by the state
of the leaflet law declares that
the position of the other privacy
has resulted in both there was therefore good or bad
in these movements they pass to
bring new technologies closes in
a competence relate six minutes
what they are  distinct two there are the
products we produce less and less but the
same fourth antivirus mayor if he wants
seg  uire the senate has a certain sequence
of never maybe to understand if we are all
chp and the most behavioral word
if you wanted then that is launching is
trying to do something more than
looking if in the morning the new
production fix the bandages that
obviously no one intelligent other
talk  there are no books that in the
end are the ones that the management
a china in 300 euros
I also teach at the master and sales
ponente in genoa teaches an accident
ending
ranieri sends when I talk about an accident
I always say that whoever does the
centers gets away  talk with
young minds in defense of peace because
existing help we
buy Indians what happens but
then the life of the human being is able
to activate the procedures we have
modified it is a foreseen decline found
in front of the new attack and to do
something and efficient to the scope you
wanted to the bucket the video what I
would have lost more systems to say but
why the shower and goods  ssimo therefore what
weight of the high data flows month for
such data is different and
actually processed to a reality even
remember accustomed to this extended you
cannot demonize them and you after having them
zavoli when then after milan and already
successful genoa for with two sonatas by
who do lassad in italy it would be
wounded they smell rome because they
realized that they are behind without having
suffered an attack and this is already a
very positive thing because very often I
take the facade that at this point
I have to put in place somehow it is
already seen  of the norm but now we can
prepare ourselves to look for accidents
such as systems of her competent who
look so now it is more visible
inter attacks to marry her and this
then is happening as we help you to
do this they go ascent of the service and
whatever else we work on  those who only
realization in gym systems
which ones to choose as the country says is
right so
football by the rest are only the
set dates of the sections of the
instruments somehow in which down there to
notice attacking let's say someone the
preparation you wanted the machine
to be followed find a play 40
load your part breaking it the
profit in fact there is not
actually usually a ugly  that there is really
someone who
defends himself even in national salvation
there is a minimum of a situation in
geneva it is a little difficult
it is not a very realistic situation
functional ardent you learn many
nice things he has no other things we are
first months indicates how hello on those
who are the chickpeas terni of how much he must
first will have the time of coutinho
left-handed 1 technicians more elastic evening
hair arestrup armament quarry well
you should also have a week of
play perino very much
the aim the usual and with of l  'ontario
five photos because in the end there is not
only the
typical university obviously the times
are specializ  zati on the power of
delayed operations and what is the
theater and the scenario of reference in the
end the volunteers also behavior
the application as among the rookies is
communicated it is like who attacks do
they medicated and there are also to the
further process
who attacks and who intends but immediately
also of the others entrance we will see
social word are impossible
what is a theater a theater in this case
is for example also the very
famous corporation localized research company
the possibility of another in
montoro and precedes terni realized
within what does not hold up
the chemical production plant in
Italy in this evil in exercises
they have tested clean I can talk about
blue team and he must have been the one who
should have defended this diet against
possible attacks by other
malicious people.  I pass with all systems it loads
into the system of this kind which ctf
attacks in delta and what you aim
was  verismo therefore all systems
contain material data old
disused site thing room where life happens very
often a new system
built in a hurry to replace
the old one and also some
problems known to us it should be noted that
these systems we create are
built from day zero  that is
practically whoever has to prepare the food
or the exercises says ok scene at the
theater which diana cielo to the companies
search ok on an equal network series
of components start all the others are
built from scratch installed is
operational used the components less
presence of the components are loaded
date  therefore system tends put
integrated in the systems have found the
peoples had defended itself as a match lech
the insertion of ns then the jato disc is
completely the new scenario
all the deaths based on what those who
receive reconstruct to build for
example that assigns large di  researched the
theater ball and composed held
f  uori you will go there in which the salting but
certain questions wlan legend
but as a winger against them
included sprinkles to be
reported in defense both of ps service
could be allocated or not
depending on who organized the game
decidedly to create me cabbage as well as
the targets  but there are other extensions a
new expression of voip so the
attacker can also listen to the
phone calls that having among the players
vote that within the realization of
mario quite complex scenario of
all systems with deployed displays
there are similarities are the cameras
that do  see the situation
we are trying a scenario digging in
which there is this company even a small
but professional company with all the ferries
all the objects that appear on
the assembly line
the controls decide the owner of a
style redemption that lowers
integration so I am afraid to work  and
integrate and talk with coordinated anas
by the typical autom years  ation and
nico on the diamonds of such are the weather sensors
the sensor the activity tank burglar alarm
the hygienic elevators
I feel activated
the mode let's play
scientific fact this company and on the floor
minus two
all the plants on each floor writer
of the sensors that are looked at us  for
at least two there is a card singing genes
to vote different evening of the famous
ufo crash
we talked to toro not the aliens
within 15 employees of
structures what decides and where to
attack is better than particular and
complicated in this world
in the end it is attempted first and foremost in
general they ended in general
also because the allocated in addition to
payment in alloy always a little more
complex to manage it is not clear if
an ancient product but a series of crm
nas feel like where the cotton windows
obviously  false seeds of peace
red that is a hundred of all pine the
simulation made rope cristini are
made with let's start for example these
studies of  other manufacturers who, according to
mourinho, simulate texas instruments
so I eat if components
that the initial simulated as I ruin
your house are present, it must be corrected
with respect to what is the open product
and I still feel sic society year there is the
most industrial part  that these older ones
have been then it will be edited by m then
in the end a whole series of
undernourished components of natal mind of the
ocean which are the teams
involved usually center tim that what the
run team that due to the cost all
absolutely having  husband franco
charbonneau to become let's face it
we could funds for example igt
the employed have been victims state
the system is a fundamental component
these because their language you do not have to
call them trying to load from
success
n download it from the race but real to
do his  nas automatically and on and on
like what I'll try goes to storm
but everyone saying this thing when
merging and who g  ioca blu are depreciated
in the desires are to analyze them
only the attacks occur block the attacks
but you also find the internal users they
begin to say that if they do it it
works when not full inside and
therefore a warning they only have a
structure
it also allows you to present
some  machines that time even the cities
of Parma type of strength and other
sectors
and already happened obviously so of
the voice archives ok I feel the machine
the wrong natural prize condition
for example Juventus attention that they
are ready nearby but contains here they
have become objectives  of tournaments on
targets and with an excellent of 20 in the case of
white intestines the possibility of
starting the natal presence of sight
then start a transversal system on
those facts in which those who make the gup also have
to red let's say they should look for
all safe says the nation tribe  it is
a union of two worlds parties
drum sales that already attacks the knowledge
of the competences  and and tasting I am
at all defender and they use it the ways they
almost like it in the head they are interrupted
on all sides however
positive gluten are themed precise to
train on the flyer equiteam they are
automated
so when you see a certain
sound fragments available it is having
success had success a  last
automatic can block can do
the operation that reasonably all the
usual instead the work portals loaded
rich business and mail chat the
routine systems played in holiness scores
with all the collaboration tools of the
company so year exceeds let's say to
be conferred whole with  a voip point
of paul between them they can communicate
is called mary mandate the relative to the
website therefore to a virus that
indexes systems that it sees
approaching there is a dense sun that must be
searched enlarged fabulous download
first what its part of really  there is a
dense generic young gmail tithe
ahead so the future er  existing
because it usually serves to be able to make
a turn that accuses between collaborating
with the other free line colors
obviously of chat and organizing
Levantine instead it is particular because the
last possibility, for example, to be
projected of infrastructure outside
then appear painted internet
enumerates a site  internet not even the
possibility that it builds of mirò
deflector to be able to make kisses
with age who the year of the in verse and
anything else that seems the two forwards but
also the way to be out of pato
within the company
then  you can simulate design a faithful
who attacks or who has certain hundred of the
system he does in things and
is usually given to seven goals in the
mentan cup that yesterday z from the clear position
he serves seemed system that there are
signs in the elevator systemic initiatives
I find active  and anything else
private citizens this is what he said
in exercises in which all were
many university students
who have already participated from the cdr and
so on and have been made for
this type of exercises two teams
one two linked to the management one can
be from the passer network
the first the walking game and the
contact from yesterday has reasons of
protocol  warning of the kind
applicative fairies 20 c managed applications
present there had been a healthy
network structure where structural or
to understand there was a person who was
responsible denier tense and from
what goes to talk to management
from agricultural etc etc
during the phases  attack because when
you are in reality it begins you draw from it by
suggesting clothes but if I spend what
happened
montaldi is responsible for
technical formations because it touches as the
sled in case it should stay with
it can be some kind of problem
and then inter obviously not
questionable stop advanced bring the officials
your services then avoid but call
siri more interested for example if they
blocked the ac  process to the system to
receive with a special
machine that is managing the
active services will turn off the thought of the inter
do it in actions by the parties is
therefore digestive report what happened
and see to be requested this year it seems
machine score difference with
function above all related to the
possibility of testing from the outside with
a first fraction to understand how a
fairy system of architecture a
basic value conceal
occupational and behind passion and
anything else
the boot in time before had the idea
of knowledge of all  components
that climb the terror found
inside the system so he
already knew that there were first pappa pappa pappa with
tom calcerà are not at all so to
what was
done so that day
return of the situation at least
had the basic skills  who could
put the trading systems
come in system productions
the machine pills designs he
uses neither  the step to the system
integrator traces and anything else obviously the
certain half of the team had been made in short
weighed by classes factors first thing the
baila wines of the services of the press release the
system will have to remain on somehow
each service involved a penalty and
if we make a mistake something and neorealist
it had to be brought which although it turns
founded obviously because it will see an
initial period in which it could real
there is about to change a rule the
system finalized when undergoing an
attack by the part or one went
entirely border had also been brought to
suffer place and of the two ports that  that
relative modality demonstrating from chapter
going on and the teachers present
for someone is in full fact that is
that to the serians to be able to extend the
prestigious machines to activate a
channel 60 that draws a third doing
there was a system that the fake story must be
what was happening at
the nation-wide management
game sessions in general and al  in the end
what is religious was a pin up
familiarization with killing every
too close
we will see in connection on the
game network armored defense consumption 90 minutes
very few families and anything else is
opening the representative doors made
immediately first phase attack in line  90
minutes
bombed a phase of the second
attack phase 40 minutes in the second phase
of the mobile with debris it was
done very fast which gave
results
the Parisian defense we had the
time to try to do it
obviously knowing a priori all  the
companies have available it could
be the shower cooperation how much
harley league aim enough
center must be ready there are
booty lit florentine pasture era
of coffee quiet did nothing
you can use the tools
it says it has the blue settings with
above to serve  all councilors on
turi districts with 16
use choice will be made by his
indiv  Same as Italy goes how to
build abstention step
invented all this wine
there is also for some time what to
understand are the hunting scarf that
divided the criticism and then beaten
configure any defense because they
must be configured by paolo
average gap of  'automatic security in the
bottom 19 the machine however and a simpler method
then from an online attack aiming to
achieve specific objectives
in the meantime the loot to try
to run for cover somehow by making
the team united indexes while pushing to
root some operation belly stone
and to coordinate especially on the part of
life that they are strong in Calabria but
threatens as happened with those who
remain at the attack of empathy ignited the
promises of to try to mitigate the
defense to make me ports technician that will
have to be program we returned to the subject a
line point  nation organized at paci
point ie in the jury garden of
this also of that time there not  there is
never for ahead mainly a year of
time at the end the
west fantasy has a hole this and
this other and on like this work of
telereggio crociano has arranged
situation awareness so they could see each other
on the multi we obviously hope what
we are in cameras for example  the
aid system where there are the
austere did not go out here system of
inserting the balance on which judges
the extraordinary mantia that was
ending also remember the alarms
launched by the cynical film so thank
goodness there is a scheme make pieces
that clean functions
this information was moved at our disposal
it is easy what we are
at measuring that sacred place of we
will see each other vividly because barge [ __ ]
the fully expert actress
what is important for us was to
evaluate the degree of security of the
infrastructure
people and software came to believe this  not of
explained how it was employed to
seek them active but they will seek  together
defense but above all it has the
response the result as they are treated
with because a part there were reds and
waste in the titanic
then maybe it has not already done by itself
what they meant in the panic car that
we have seen almost a little worse for
the lack of experience but it is what
will happen to companies when they
attack not via
then so in a series of operations
to be able to change the country
because I understood something it was not
those who make the game to always do
technically
for the injured  that we
made with technical or less complex
communication home there was but empty inter part
that had available to coach
and reactive and wanted and the
application part that of a very
popular application did not say to run
all the traffic that having a  these
ends on him or he can not let them
affect external who is running
therefore also an activity had to be
made created inconvenience ne red  they had been
made able that coincidentally the reds will
more or less be the parables they do not know
that
so if it happens by chance they have long
done that you breathe where I am set
aside from doing an important thing when
born so massive a
particular technical structure that to understand  what does
the attacker do what he wants to do
in short there are no accidents we are a
little 20 gasoline on the technical part
indeed subtitled they knew what he does
certainly genius of the soils sold
let's say separate skills I knew how to
do what they for all mystical
bribes that he wanted facts seen that in
that of pine and the fauna of
defense phrases the tools that can
become a company as a structure are
the extension of human capabilities it is me who
wins the opportunity in Ticino to do
certain operations and also in
Italy decide some things that are perhaps
showing cianni  based on the part
of the communication companies did not take
into account the adults so one thing let's
change the passwords  unofficial ok but
we don't say no and we close it out and
we amaze them carmine valentino that
works no more no answers anymore so
even the italian soldier how to make them
start contact there was a
fair exchange of information between a and
philip k then they were hit and  dropped
everyone talks tried to cover the
machine of the machines to be managed did not
look at rosaneri as foreshadowed
levels of people understood general
seeing an important thing they knew that
the service volume of having voted
all germinative did not get off
which one that had brought more
the  negative impact of the dog day at the
end the administrations are useless
where to the thousands you reserve you can
protect everything not the same as
security because it could not and
technically maybe not suffer
comically it is therefore not certain things.
but
important thing in the never-
ending gorge was trying to decide
ra  idly or know how to operate
the rosanero's flagship lamon did
this he
had noticed it time is not 90 minutes
to work to create you understand that if you
always find yourself succeeding sounds not
imported commercial allows ours
have therefore given down risked
life machine is not  also important
this type formation also must be
above all improvement not only with
technical trusses that affect tests
are not 33 developments in anything else but
above all to understand it at all no
I make the classic but the most used championships
I did not know well that they load in
optimal form for  agents do not resonate they
did not know of the capacity could be at
a water they declare therefore the stability
of the mister who by now arrows could
be the students could not be
someone was joke ventilated
consequently to a we will understand I looked at the
type of the attacker's kato rates of
what  he used it this moment
venezia uses almost tight linen stitch
if instead of waist l  eons packages to
scan if not malformed packages
caste four times but I have to download
attacking is already a better club
the low level the body a dentist
who happened during the attack they
realized that they have not been hired to
remove the password the same too
let's put American price lists
general city of lawyers that is a magic
inside they have cleared up the
cosenza somehow the
crus passed for each personal car has been removed a step
because they are but finendo nostrum and the
family makes a fund that some
clarification said the  experience of the
arid but milan I am very happy between
what organized the reasons de
ski remembered about
salvation accident management even there you just need to
know it about protection
you have to learn the game to do 16
rights because even today
safety skills but something especially
always knew this accident
practically  without the offense design football
and keep it successful eventually for
thwarting  re salvio dogs are the salt of the
new skills of
natural methodologies that there are a little
different from the usual
because in the end it is important in the
same city a ctr-type collection system
ability of a speed to
have groups other than regional that I have
with very serious and exchanges of information
on directors and edited mattato something that
usually companies do not already do
rome there was not met as this
is taken for granted what do not compete with
the past regime and the formation of 20
all cursed more and more fundamental
let's say levels  on average now on
those that are
with this the writing thanks disappeared
[Music] we
thank a renowned
president for very interesting for
having been widely on
schedule and we start with and
first ask me to do it is something that
interests us because we want then  in
this sector you can play with the
team
you want some honest if you have put in
how many resources s  they are used to be able to
create this in nature phrases that from the
point of view of the data it seems it is not
because anyway as ireland and zanella
current several things fixed
automated that an unsubscribed polish
the author chosen among the users
configure the gear in terms of
data services  matrix is all what you find
here are skills I don't know that being
security we say how
a machine must be made what they are but
also to systems engineering so we have a
series of
windows linux experts in the scale field you
will say
we build as components the
competitive centocelle
le  specifics must be all some
satisfaction
the young Ligurian type that obviously makes it
easier for those who have to defend and
then there is an object artists myth
always something that only federica used I
recommend recently we have a double
twist of windows phone enters with golf
new burst of  distance of five
we have to hold up more complex have to
look for the scene you are f  you use with the
homeland machine
the time version we played it
well but merit work people with
experience of the issue salient
stupid doctors at anas the figuration
the controller matera times it happens
that you have to do it disappeared we
looked for the minutes they did not go before
the three seats of the  things all with
experience a hairpin
service information that the questions if someone has to
participate in the CDF and is in this
room I would recommend to go immediately they
are bringing the food directly the
three big ones accompanied if instead now
more quiet
other questions
thanks
if gazeta you can know the  level of
information of the Trentino people, that is, what
was their path
[Music]
they are Italians
so the joint center dottor house
recycly Italian then had to
be trained at the school of java where
I drew it I did it about some
on the date of genoa bojan  in this case
but it is obviously special costs  zati in
the born area
now I am touching and we see the
special faction of cianni especially account
of the mobility square meters poured by
the hard one
yes exactly even more than a hundred
we made transport and study
of the questions
I would still be
[Music]