hello thank you very much for joining
our talk today my name is Leanne
Galloway and this is Tim or Eunice
yunusov and we're going to be talking
about payment technologies and the
security risks associated with them so
the reason why we came up with this talk
is because we both work with payment
technologies every day and all of us in
this room we interact with payments
every day as well and we realized that
for something that we all interact with
so often it's actually quite a complex
ecosystem which is quite difficult for
most people to understand so we thought
it would be really great if we could
shed a little bit of light on what's
really going on in payments and the
security risks associated with them so
with that in mind I thought I would
mention a few reasons why we are
qualified to do that so the first reason
is that we were both born in the 80s
which means that we were born
approximately 20 years after the first
cash dispenser was installed in London
by Barclays Bank that also means that
we've suffered through the introduction
of many new payment technologies along
the way last year we bought an ATM and
deconstructed it completely and when I
say completely I mean right down to the
safe which was a very interesting
experience for us so we work actively
with payment technologies and we're
really interested in carrying out
research in this specific area but like
you we also interact on payments every
day so as I mentioned we started from
the idea that the payment ecosystem is
an extremely complex per place and if
you look at this image here you can see
that it seems quite overwhelming but all
this is is representative of a number of
different payment systems and what those
do were they simply just facilitate the
ability to transfer funds from one
individual to another and for the
purposes of this presentation we're
going to be talking about regulated
money so we're not talking about
cryptocurrency
but if I break it down into three
components it makes it quite a bit
easier to understand so first of all we
have payment instruments so that's
things like paper money and cheques then
we have card payments so anything from
chip and pin swipes keyed entry of the
pan number then we have payment system
operators so that's banks clearing
houses and credit unions and then
payment delivery methods payment
delivery methods are really the endpoint
of these systems and they're they're the
part that we interact with most every
day
so that's points of Sales terminals
payment gateways so if you're making a
payment online and ATMs so for this
presentation we'll be primarily focused
on the endpoints of these systems and
the reason for that is in security as
security researchers this is the first
point of interaction for many of us
because it's relatively easy for us to
obtain access to these devices it gives
us some information about the system and
payment system operators like banks
essentially operate like a black box so
it's quite difficult as a security
researcher to begin man unless you
happen to work in a bank another thing
is that criminals typically focus their
attention on this area first so that's
what we will be focusing on ATMs
point-of-sale terminals and we'll also
be focusing on card payments themselves
yes how even really first ATM was
installed how we heard like 40 51 years
ago not too many things significantly
changed in the last 50 years even though
now it's like almost four million CTMS
operating all over the world and by
changing I mean from a security
perspective so just quick overview of
main ATM parts for interactions for
criminals and like from customers
perspective so three main part is three
main parts service area which contains
computer monitor or card reader and
cryptic keyboard so main point of
interaction with a customer then we have
vault which contains cash dispenser with
from four to six different castles for
each types of notes and behind this
there is a network which which work to
communicate ATM Swiss bank and so on and
really interesting that the fact is that
cryptography is probably the major basic
thing in all payment technologies in
every bank for example in ATM may be
cryptic keyboard is the most secure part
of ATM in the end as well as for example
encryption encrypted connection to visit
network but sometimes even bank does not
understand properly their ATMs ecosystem
how complex it might be for example not
every bank will understand that if
hacker will get access to one ATM he
could get access to our ATMs in network
and control them and spit out money from
all of them or for example in fact who
banking network yet their access to
internals and the
Nell's as well as vice-versa for example
when hacker can in fact some end point
computer in a bank like operator
workstation it's just a question of time
at what time he'll get axe he could get
access to every TM in this particular
Bank so let's make an overview of modern
ATM attacks and I will not be speaking
about how to cause brute force yeah so
will not be speaking about gas dynamite
and so on will speak about more
sophisticated and logical things so
first of all is interaction with
operating system-level which brings us
to attacks well known as Jack Putin when
hackers run their own malware to spit
out money second is about hardware
attacks also known as black box attacks
when hackers communicate with directly
whiscash dispenser without any
communication with computer insert is
kind of Miss configurations and
vulnerabilities which could be contained
in network ATMs Network so this is a
very great example for us here is an
instruction available in dark web which
says where exactly hacker have to drill
small holes to get direct access to USB
port and insert their keyboard and mouse
for example and which means if we are
speaking still about Windows operating
system here which is a great like 95 90
% of ATMs all over the world it's like
you know you can be even a cat to get if
you have access to keyboard and mouse to
run your own piece of malware yeah if
cats can do this of course that's why
there are typically several layers of
protection yeah for example not every
ATM will allow you to plug in your
keyboard and mouse next it is some kind
of restriction which calls kiosk mode
which which restrict operators to make
to get full access to Explorer for
example to shell itself and even to farm
manager which surprisingly installed on
like 99% of ATMs and some other
protections but in the end if you will
be able to bypass this protection grain
oh I screen you will see an ATM all I
need to do is utilizing some keys on the
keyboard is I can use some key
combination to gain access to the
operating system so here we run our
crafted piece of malware and yeah
getting our notes so it's pretty easy
and of course it made complete sense
because computer should send these
comments by default to peripherals to
catch dispenser to get money by
especially crafted most of the time API
which calls domestics FS surprisingly
created by Microsoft and that's why when
these these attacks started to appear
majority in vendors implemented next
level of protection mostly it is
application control tools presented by
major vendors like Kaspersky McAfee
Trend Micro checkpoint so instead of
normal antivirus which works with
signature based or behavior analysis
they create whitelists and blacklists so
after install after being installed this
software create whitelist of
pre-installed applications on this
moment and ever seen which want to be
launched afterwards which is not in
whitelist will be blocked but there are
several problems first of all this
software will
not work from the box it will not work
it should be very slightly setup it
should be configured and configure it
very properly for every specific atm
and this happens almost never and second
in the last five years you all might
seem that even major security vendors
which creates security software they all
make mistakes for example in the last
couple of years we found like around
five zero days in all type of these
products and of course not only us our
colleagues as well so black box yeah
instead of drilling holes and plugging
in keyboards and Mouse's hackers can
drill in in other places also house and
connect directly to catch dispenser
instead of computer yeah and send
comment Viacom or use B to get money for
this purposes you may need specially
crafted hardware these Arduino for
example on board or you can use small
laptop and hold it inside of service
area if you get access to Kies to
service area which is surprisingly also
not very hard
this attack first was described in 2013
by Barnaby Jack and since that all ATM
vendors implemented their own security
which was surprisingly cryptography
which means they build secure layer of
connection between computer and cash
dispenser but they did not do this very
well so first we send this attack to
answer in 2013 of their poor
implementation of the security mechanism
and in 2017 they still met
a lot of problems in this year on the
black hat will present presentation
about breaking black box security in
major vendors like in CR and vim core
but I will briefly describe what
happened so in in summer we sent we and
our colleagues from other security
companies sent several emails to NCR by
saying guys your encryption is not very
well it contains a lot of problems but
they were saying us now we all write
videos yourself you you sending us looks
like fraud
until in September of 2017 incident
really incident that happened in Mexico
when hackers actually used this Miss
configuration this vulnerability or I
dunno this backdoor wherever and get
access to money in one bank and
surprisingly afterwards in February of
2018 NCR presented new completely secure
version of protection against black box
but in the end that means that even the
major solution for from ATM vendors
against black box is you need to buy
completely new ATM and throw out on all
your 5000 ATMs park of old ATMs it will
not give you 100% guarantee against this
attack and what story you all probably
seen this somewhere in your life when
you see stuck in out from ATM some rj45
cables ya go in somewhere to network
devices and somewhere else which means
hackers for example also can connect to
these wires and for example use
vulnerabilities of Windows yeah which
would be probably instant
in India TM or in worst case scenario
basically just substitute the answer
from a processing center by saying give
me a don't give me a notes from Castle B
give me C nose from Cassidy
yeah and in theory everything should be
of course protected with controlling
controlling checksums with cryptography
but honestly it works very well when we
are speaking about outdoor ATMs
installed on the street somewhere else
but when we were speaking about ATMs in
a bank branch this might happen not all
the time and I will share one very
interesting story which happened with us
like two months ago we had ATM security
assessment project and network
connection were working why GSM
industrial modem which were held in
service area and after project we after
the main part of project we were
speaking with band by saying guys do you
want us to make assessment to check out
this vector yeah how we can actually
compromise use one compromise DTM we
should compromised in the end and get
access to all your network and they said
oh no we all right you know we have
everything we have all security policies
firewall will not allow you to do this
everything is isolated from each other
and like we said okay let's let's go for
it then and 48 hours later surprisingly
what happened it turned out that this
gsm modem using were using its own
proprietary VPN which was working like
end-to-end tunnel with their own two
binaries the same identical binaries on
the server and client side and these
binaries contained remote code execution
and 48 hours later we got access to HT
page which said us here is operated ATMs
you can choose and get access to this
ATM remotely was very good until we
realized that it was not the network of
bank it was a network of engineer
company service provider which were
maintained in like 12 banks in a very
big city so we were able to get access
to ATM every ATM of these two banks in
this big city yeah why why this happens
and all over the world yeah of course
I'm not speaking about Asia about
Eastern Europe this happens a lot in
Europe in West year Western Europe in
London in England and this year is this
also started to happen in USA for
example
so why attacks on ATM growing up from
year to year yeah well first of all as
lien already mentioned sometimes it's
quite easy to buy your own ATM yeah and
start to build your own hacking camp for
your criminal things and end up with
being one of these famous hackers who
actually steal money from ATMs and
second hackers are pretty lazy still
yeah criminals are pretty lazy and they
wait until this market will appear until
you can just basically go to dark web
and buy and download step-by-step
instructions how to in fact in any ATM
in in your city until they wait this
piece of software will we will appear
which helps them to make this jackpot in
attacks which will allow them to use
even second factor authentication
against Muse who wanna rob them more so
this is the major problem that this
market dart market gives a lot of
possibilities to criminals these days
okay so next we're going to talk about
card payments and we're gonna focus
specifically on cardholder present
transactions so those are chip and pin
chip and signature keyed entry of the
primary account number and any
contactless payments as well so although
contactless doesn't have additional
cardholder verification it is considered
a cardholder present transaction so what
happens when you make a transaction so
typically you might go into a shop or a
business and you'd be paying for some
services of goods and you'd over hand
your card to the business holder or they
would ask you to touch the terminal at
that point your information is sent to
their acquiring bank they don't know who
your bank is at this point so they asked
your card brand to then determine who
you're issuing Bank is they will make
some initial checks just to see if you
have enough credit facility and to see
if they're happy with you making the
payment they'll then send this
information all the way back along the
chain so it seems relatively simple so
far but if we look a bit deeper so in
this case this is a representation of a
NFC payment you can see that it's quite
a bit more complicated but honestly for
the purposes of understanding many of
the security risks associated with card
payments you don't need to understand
the exact steps that a transaction makes
so firstly let me talk about chip and
pin so chip and pin isn't so widely used
in the US but it is used for almost all
transactions in Europe and it was hailed
as a security solution to many of the
issues associated with swiped
transactions I think we all know that
it's relatively simple to clone a clone
the magnetic stripe data of a card and
then to forge someone's signature it's
almost child's play in fact so Chip and
PIN was meant to be the most secure form
of authorisation
so the most secure version of
authenticating the cardholder but
unfortunately there's quite a number of
issues with them so in 2010 researchers
from aperture labs in Europe they found
that specifically for SDA cards if you
were to make a transaction in offline
mode with a terminal there are two
possible outcomes the first is that you
could intercept the pin in clear-text
not very good so far and secondly is you
can bypass pin verification altogether
so that does away with the cardholder
verification it also means that you can
steal someone's card and for a limited
period of time before the bank blocks
you you can make transactions in what's
considered the most secure form so that
doesn't sound very good but actually
from a criminals perspective there's a
much easier target
and that's NFC so if we look at NFC it
was first used for transport system so
it's first used by the you passing
career and then in the early 2000s was
adopted by their Transport for London
system and then slowly it's been
integrated into payment technologies and
now it accounts for around 40 percent of
all of our non-cash transactions so why
is this so attractive to criminals well
there's quite a few interesting points
about contactless the first is that it's
considered an acceptable risk by banks
so they know they're going to suffer
some losses from this there's no
cardholder verification so you can
intercept someone's tokin or take
someone's card and quite easily make
payments with that for a period of time
before you're blocked also quite
interestingly sometimes you can have a
higher limit in the country with which
your card was issued and then make a
payment in a country where the lower
there is a lower limit associated with
transactions and you can actually bypass
that and then lastly it's pretty much
everywhere so for that reason it's very
very attractive but if we look at the
kind of attack vectors that
facing contactless payments will see
that there's actually not so many
confirmed cases in the media or by banks
around this area so in 2015 this is an
article by SC magazine and they're
talking about one of their journalists
was affected by a type of fraud but
there's not really very much that's
happens between 2015 and 2018 in this
space except of course that many
researchers started publishing
information on the many different issues
associated with it such as replay and
relay attacks but in the early part of
this year in the UK they actually
announced that there were significant
losses associated with contactless
payments which is very interesting
because mostly banks don't like to admit
that they have a problem so if we take a
look at the NFC attack surface area you
can see that there's lots of points of
interaction if you are an attacker so
first of all we can interact with
enrollment then anywhere between the
token being issued and the terminal and
directly between the terminal and the
acquiring bank as well
so let's talk about tokenization
tokenization is meant to be a more
secure way of making a payment so what
happens is when you enroll your card
with a mobile wallet it's replaced with
a virtual representation of itself
you're also issued with tokens that have
a limited lifetime you shouldn't be able
to use them again but last year Tim
actually found that there were some
issues with Apple pay specifically that
for certain kinds of payments of making
payments through applications or
websites you can actually reuse the
token and make another purchase secondly
the research of Salvador Mendoza he
found that there were a number of issues
associated with sampson pay specifically
that the tokens actually have quite a
long lifetime associated with them so
what this means is you can intercept a
token and you don't have to use it
straight away you can hold on to
of tokens that you've harvested from
people so if we look at what that first
point of interaction looks like between
the phone and the terminal the easiest
way of attacking this is really through
what's called a relay attack so in this
situation what an attack is trying to do
is they're just trying to intercept your
token before you use it
so NFC uses inductive coupling all that
means is that I have to get really close
to you so one way of doing that in a
very simple way is that I could have two
phones and the first phone could act as
a reader I could intercept a token from
your card and from your phone I could
then send that information over a public
Wi-Fi connection to another phone which
would emulate your card and make a
payment but there are more complicated
ways of doing that as well so here's an
example of a more complicated version of
doing that so this is a project I was
working on with the research of salvador
mendoza and what it does is it uses
dedicated hardware an RF channel to
transmit the information so with this
you don't actually have any issues with
using things like public Wi-Fi networks
any lag associated with that and you can
see here so in the first instance we are
reading the card on this side so you can
see the cards been read and then i'm
going to walk to the place where the
card has been read by a another piece of
hardware so this is about 30 foot
and I'm just going to lift that up and
you can see the card that we've read
so how have payments and fraud evolved
so firstly as I mentioned there's been a
greater focus on contactless payments
it's a new form of technology and it
doesn't have the limits doesn't have
very high limits associated with it but
it's really easy to intercept tokens and
make payments with them but secondly
we've seen a growth in something called
authorization stream attacks or
authorization anomaly and what this is
is really attackers looking at the
different physical devices in the system
as well as how the bank responds to
payments that they're making to try and
work out how to carry out fraud so what
they're doing is they're just trying to
abuse the logic in the system so if I
give you some examples of that it will
become a bit clearer so in the most
simple form what that looks like is
imagine if you went into a bar and you
handed your card to the bartender but
instead of having just one terminal they
also had a fraudulent merchant terminal
they could touch your card against both
terminals very quickly and both of those
payments would go through and they would
both be authorized by your bank that's a
completely legitimate way of making
payments but that's not how the system
should be used as an attacker I also
have the ability to intercept the
transaction information between the
terminal and the acquiring bank with
that I can do things like modify the
transaction values I can modify my
merchant code and I can also do things
like issue credits rather than debiting
from an account now you might be quite
familiar with the concept of fallback
but I'll just go ahead and explain that
so when you make a transaction in a shop
ideally your bank wants you to make the
most secure version of that transaction
whatever that is assuming it might be
chip in signature or Chip and PIN that's
the ideal scenario as an attacker what I
can do is I can just
the card and terminal to try and make
the transaction in a less secure form
and it's much easier than you think so I
can just insert my card upside down
sometimes once sometimes a couple of
times and then it typically will ask you
to swipe your card at which point you
can swipe the card and fake the
signature another interesting example is
that it's possible to intercept the
track to equivalent data from a
contactless token and write that
information to the magnetic stripe on a
card you can then use that completely
legitimately to make a payments then we
have another interesting use of the
terminal itself
so for you to go into a shop and make a
payment if the merchant gives you the
terminal in your hand there's typically
a short window in time between the
actual synchronization of the
transaction to the acquiring bank and
actually the transaction being made so
what this means is I have the
possibility to manipulate the terminal
itself and you can actually reset the
operating system which means that you
would be issued with the receipt it
looks like you've paid for the goods but
the transaction actually never takes
place and lastly so this example of an
attack actually occurred for for real in
2016 a bank in the UK was hit by
something called a credit master attack
and they lost 2.5 million which is a
significant amount so banks are really
terrified by this form of attack
primarily because it has the ability to
just completely financially cripple them
so what this is that attackers are
looking to predict and brute force the
entire bin ranges of cards sometimes
before they've even been issued so that
sounds like it's quite complicated
because you would also need to
understand the information associated
with the cardholder things like the name
and address the expiry dates and the
security code but as it turns out it's
not quite as complicated as that because
typically if you're trying to make a
payment
with this kind of information you'll be
doing it through things like websites
you won't be doing it in person and
often those websites won't check all of
that information so immediately you have
less information to guess and
researchers at Cambridge University
actually found that if you distribute
the guesses against different websites
different merchants web sites it is
possible to do this within a few
thousand guesses yeah and as for the end
let's try to quickly also find an answer
for the question why hackers will try to
steal hundred dollars from thousand
people if they actually can just steal
100 millions a time right so in 2018
hackers probably all of them already
understand that it's quite easy to get
access to banking internals network by a
phishing or compromised ation of
compromising of web servers or other
network devices and afterwards if
hackers are already inside it's just a
matter of time and a matter of final aim
they can get access to ATM network and
as happened in Thailand and Taiwan a
couple years ago they can get access to
banking processing get access to all
track to data and start to do things
which Liam described couple minutes ago
or in this case scenario they can get
access to interbank in exchange network
called Swift so in the last five years
the bohr around ten attacks on different
banks all over the world with a lot of
money were stolen where maximum was
around 80 billions 80 millions a time 8
million dollars but the
question is that Swift actually says
guys this is your problem this is Bank
problem that you don't have completely
air-gapped Swift infrastructure against
rest of internal things you got hackers
in get into your system compromised your
servers what do you expect from us our
software is completely secure our
terminal does not contain any
vulnerabilities our network also secured
with VPNs a lot of layers of protections
and things like that this is your
problem that like after infection of
some of your terminals and points by
phishing is just a matter of time yeah
how hackers just mitigate pivoting via
networks and couple months later somehow
your Swift server and Swift terminal was
infected what did you expect afterwards
of course two months is later you will
be compromised this is just an example
from one of our security investigation
in one of our bank remember how I told
you that hackers are lazy yeah and they
are lazy like 99% of them car but it is
a small amount of criminals black
hackers who actually do all their own
security researchers here they buy ATMs
and in this case they somehow get access
to Swift server via I don't know fired
employees yeah
they get access to Swift internals made
some kind of their own research and
create their own malware dynamic library
of Swift network which allowed them what
they allow them to do they allow them to
substitute to tamper the correction of
signatures so operator on the screen
sees that yeah all operations were
confirmed by me or by someone else
checksum is all right we can send it
next to Swift Network as well as they
can even tamper information on a printer
sent on a printer for visual
confirmation and the same result will be
achieved and of course afterwards
hackers would easily get access to that
hundred millions and easy steal them so
let's try to find an answer what to do
with these interesting stories so we've
talked about quite a few different
examples here many of them are just the
tip of the iceberg really for what we're
working with and one of the main reasons
why this happens is because we are
seeing many different technologies that
are layered together and banks don't
typically understand how these things
work in practice
so the only real solution to all of the
security issues we've shown you is that
live testing has to be carried out in
many of these environments and that's
just simply because theory is very
different from practice so you might
understand something via a standard but
when you go about testing that it's you
might actually end up with completely
different results so that completes our
talk if you have any questions please
let us know and thank you very much for
listening
[Applause]