so my name is mark Arnold I provide all
security leadership at a multi cloud
company called nav a site that's who I
am but today I'm gonna be two people
because my co-presenter could not make
it at the last minute so what was going
to be a conversation that started out at
blackhat maybe two years ago will be
kind of a silicate between myself and
myself kind of pontificating points that
he has around hacking intelligence now
just four preliminaries I've come at it
from a CSO practitioner or leader
leadership and also from an academic
side as a linguist I'm trained in Middle
Eastern languages he's coming from
coming from the same topic as a military
trained intelligence person and we've
come together to say can you hack
intelligent hack intelligence or can you
not do so I say you need to hack it out
of out of necessity he says it cannot be
had so that's kind of framing the
conversation that that I'll have with
myself today okay just a few
introductions I already told you who I
am will has a credible bio he's known
out there worked at a number of
companies McAfee damballa saundra
digital shadows and most recently
digital Guardian he's got a book out go
check it out
he may be watching somewhere remotely
now we want to start off by saying you
know if you're not watching or not
reading the intelligence then you're
flying blind does anyone have anyone
know where this comes from or seen this
so this the context for jay johnson's
comment has to do with you know one of
what has to do with our leadership
around you know daily reading of the
intelligence you know regardless of what
side of the political aisle you fall
down if you're not reading the
intelligence you're you're flying blind
well what does it look like anyone
recognized security wizardry hands some
of the old schoolers yes just one person
what Wow we must be little bit old but
it's okay
it was the genius of Andy Cobb he
thought about this concept maybe about
14 16 years ago and a bathtub in the
bathroom and now folks all over the
world are using it
I used it back in the day I must confess
to make sure my IDs signatures were
up-to-date and I also made sure to look
at it to make sure my in map version was
up today I don't know it might be you
know something to target but there are
some other more Mardin dashboards I
won't call out who these belong to but
if you look around the intent you
understand who these are is intelligence
it doesn't really look like this right
when you walk into the office office you
know what should it look like I'm coming
up this conversation from the side that
many of us in the room don't have access
to the Intel that would be relevant for
us but to protect our particular
organizations I borrow from mark
Orlando's talk at RSA 2015 typically
when you look at getting the Intel
that's relevant it's going to cost you
money would you say yes if you look at
it from left to right open-source is
typically free community projects are
free low-end dollars you're talking at
commercial you start to shell out more
money to get vendor-specific
moderate targeted intelligence and then
on the far in internal when you're kind
of have a closed internally source
system it's gonna cost you money because
you need people you need resources you
need trained individuals who can not
just gather and collect the data but
also makes sense and analyze the data it
only it's not only about economics but
it's also about Bureau
see so there are bureaucratic barriers
if you're not on the intelligence side
how do you get at the data that's being
collected and at the agencies there's
competition around whose data is the
best date of the right data cultural
differences how do you handle the data
you know have a database data handled
from one agency to the other and then do
you have a security clearance can you
get at the data what are the pre
conditions under which data is shared
okay and so not just cost but
bureaucracy and red tape typically if
you're on the outside of that
conversation and you need access maybe
sharing is the way to go so friends with
benefits how many of you know about the
opens right exchange just raise the
hands behind just one say huh so only
that many people about otx okay this otx
Facebook has it has it has exchanges
common I mentioned today has been showed
and that's just probably look at that as
an exchange for for collecting scans
zmapp others intrigue at i/o by jonathan
planet at Kenna are ways to kind of get
at this but look what this user says I
mean it seems like otx database as a
crowdsource list of suspicious sites but
as with a lot of anti-malware software
or sites like this it provides little
insight into how severe the threat is
because of lack of context there's
something missing there so you can you
could have all these disparate pieces of
data but if you don't have the context
then is it meaningful or relevant for
your particular organization there are
local and regional agencies like Eric
Allen Austin but again does this get us
around the barriers of getting into the
the relevant Intel that we need to
protect our orgs this was a comment on a
website reviewing orgs like Eric saying
fusion centers
typically in the beginning are tasked at
helping us share our data to bring data
together to collectively solve this
problem around getting at the right
Intel but at the end of the day
sometimes it gets it gets fused in with
other intelligence or local enforcement
priorities and so forth and so forth
such that it gets watered down and lose
its its impetus and then there are those
who who determined to for themselves to
use closed source methods so I was also
an optimist current company I walked
into a well-known help ensure health
provider they didn't want to have
anything to do with our sales pitch you
know because vendors are saying you know
if you take our solution you're going to
have the best threat intelligence the
best relevance for your in particular
organization they said no we're going to
take this internal because we want to
make sure that the data that we're
seeing that's relevant for us has
impetus has has impact for our
particular business an org ice-axe
I'm sure of one of the room knows about
is X high barrier high in cost but for
many C sales and I was like what the
group of seats was about two weeks ago I
sacks are highly valued because it's
close pretty pretty much close group of
orgs and you have the ability to begin
to foster trust among the various
providers of various shares in that room
but for many of us getting into that
room cost money emphasized that cost a
lot of money in H I said not so much
money but it costs money to get into
that room to have access to that data so
the economics is quite involved in that
particular instance how many meeting the
real know about apt dot threat tracking
comm I sieve couple hands so this is an
attempt to gather intelligence
from various sources I don't know if you
have to barter with a vendor a
compromise assessment provider that
would say if you want this level of
taxonomy you've got to paid the gold
standard if you want an additional level
of text items you have to pay platinum
costs
this site is run by have or a flake and
if you go in there you'll see all the
apts you'll see all the Russian hackers
the Chinese the the Chinese threat
actors all lined up with the various
compromised tactics that they use to get
into organizations if it's live right
now you can go out go out right now
you'll see number of people in there
kind of adding data to this particular
document but this is a way for some to
get around the barriers of cross the
barriers of bureaucracy if we'll were
here standing next to me and I'm going
to start the conversation there will
will it say this is not prudent it's not
responsible that someone would be
collecting this data in an open forum
and sharing that out but however has
this disclaimer attribution is a very
complex issue this list is an intent SiC
to map together the findings in a single
internet analyses and so if you can't
get at the data and you're curious about
the taxonomy
you can find them here but is that a
responsible way around getting a way of
getting to a data that normally cost
money to get to these resources for me
there's also bias when we talk about
Intel sources so we had a clicker here
first one basically there's political
bias Lucifer and the Bears this notion
of hacking political process east the
second one is kind of near and dear to
me I'm from Boston when the the Boston
bombing happened there was a lot of
image image Intel on the internet and so
what happened what happened is a crowd
sourced
kind of sleuthing took place where as
this gentleman Sunil Tripathi was
incorrectly and correctly picked out as
deep as the bomber and caused quite a
great great of grief upon his family and
so even actually collecting all this
data all this Intel in some instances we
have bad outcomes based on who's
actually handing panelling the Intel
then finally there's semantic bias in
our artificial intelligence that's the
big thing here in LP national language
processing it's it's helping us to get
at the resource problem but as Arvind
professor narayan at Princeton would say
it's also easily able to be impacted
through bias and we have situation where
these artificial intelligence systems
may be ingesting a lot of bias now I'm
going to kind of pause here to give you
an example of what that might be so in
the book waters 2016 they use what's
called named entity recognition
recognition to extract information on
orgs people and places out of Facebook
think about the recent troubles with
Facebook and how hackers and reddit
threat actors are extracting bits of
information out of out of those social
media repositories and kind of using
that as as as weapons or weaponizing
that data to attack certain groups and
so with named entity resolution you see
here kind of four funded here locations
times persons organizations money
percent and data hopefully after this
talk I'm going to be releasing some data
where this is applied on some social
media platforms but one thing that this
does not do very good is provide context
so you have the data extracted but you
need context and so this example on the
end
is the very first verse because in the
same book waters uses the biblical
examples I pull one of my own this is
the very first verse out on the Bible in
Hebrew right you probably can't read it
unless you can read Hebrew it says in
the beginning God created the heavens
and the earth I dropped this Hebrew and
Google Translate and Google Translate
gave me back the wrong translation and
so what I suggested to me is and
supervised or unsupervised national
language processing systems you can
basically poison the data I could put
anything back as they asked you google
responds back give me a good translation
I could have thrown anything in there
what we what we are doing in the
background is taking similar examples
and poisoning the data and inducing bias
as it were into these systems and it's
very easy so you can get a text extract
the data out but is it the right context
you can impact the context by poisoning
data with bias and an essence corrupt
said data
NORs anyone know about Norse and I want
to cached Norse were former Norse
employees are here but a well-intended
company at this particular time there
was an article or a white paper released
about this attack on Iran Krabs kind of
commented on it said you know if you
look at the looked at the document
looked at all the data basically it's
full of bias and so as a consumer of
threat intelligence and consumer of such
that data and embroidering with Varner's
back and forth about what to purchase
how much bias can I detect you know in
this situation this is probably the
worst of the situations where this
entire particular article was supposed
to field with bias and not intended
without the intended outcome was not as
as it was ought to be
took this conversation will and I will
who's not here today we took this
conversation on to security weekly with
Paul acid Orion and John strand John
strand was on the was on the call kind
of sitting back the entire time which
we're having this conversation about can
you hack it can you not hack it John
said this conversation makes no sense at
all why are we talking about that
intelligent most people don't even know
about their own environments and so
basically he keep held us at ass
because you know yes we're we're
concerned about the hype cycle and what
vendors are trying to sell us but at the
end of the day or the buyers of say it
threatened tell or the collectors have
said threat Intel or they do they know
anything about their own environments
and basically if do you know thyself
right the best best practice is that the
best path forward to kind of circumvent
what's happening from the outside in
attackers those stories yes I see one
hand and then nightmares of a pen tester
anybody if you've not read these two
sides or these are these are these
commentaries on knowing your environment
I would suggest that you read these two
as you think about threat Intel note
basically if you follow the
recommendations in these two decks you
will basically wipe out 98% of your
threat surface I guarantee you I think
there's also the dirty dozen by the
Cloud Security Alliance just released
that talks about growing threat activity
in the clouds and how crowds are being
attacked in certain ways that you ought
to know about so this is all from me
very important because you've got to I
think know yourself before you can
really engage and thread Intel and I say
that because of this one quote here from
Danny wood at cyber reason we were
conversing about this about
two weeks ago and basically she told me
threat intelligence received yesterday
is already irrelevant now what does that
mean
I don't do a lot with props when I'm
giving talks but I wore this shirt in
particular as you see my shirt I have
duo I was in the throes of a
nation-state attack and the Assessor on
site at the time said to me mark they
attacked you and three other folks at
the same time if you had do or something
like duo you might have slowed down the
attack now the fact that he told me you
know was enlightening to me but it was
already irrelevant right excited oh my I
didn't know my environment well I knew
the environment I knew them apart I mean
be transparent environment was crap but
and so we got what we deserved but if we
had known ourselves and had the threat
intelligence at a pet irrelevant you
know time perhaps we would have thwarted
or slow down the attack and so hacking
intelligence I'm not sure that that was
my point - well I said you know it's
cross its bureaucratic it's knowing
yourself to get around some of this
resistance or impedance to understanding
how to protect oneself with threat of
intelligence so yes these are kind of
will slides here so do we really know
what intelligence is right and then you
keep using that word I don't think you
know what it means so how do we answer
the question of what threat Intel is so
him coming from the military community
would suggest that we've defined it
improperly and so how do we course
correct the conversation by providing
the right and definitions around what
intelligence is most of us that are
concerned with intelligence are we doing
it the right way are we pursuing it
because it has a net effect on our
organizations our partners
and people are we pursuing it because it
has become fashionable to do so and then
why is it you know why in the last
decade is there an uptick on doing
intelligence as it become important
because we're being told from marketers
or our enterprises you know
understanding that is something that we
have to do or is it just you know the
thing of the day and then do we
understand what intelligence tradecraft
is our organization's understanding the
core of the fundamental rudimentary
tenets of what trade practice are we
equipped and capable of conducting in so
there there are two foundational
definitions from the field one from the
dictionary of the United States of
military terms for joint usage would
suggest that intelligence is the product
with resulting from the collection
evaluation analysis and integration and
interpretation of all available
information which concerns one or more
aspects of foreign nations or of areas
of operation and which is immediately or
potentially significant to planning and
then in the training handbook it writes
intelligence is the same thing as the
product resulting from the collection
evaluation collation kind of similar and
we'll kind of added his own twist to
this by saying intelligence is the
collection of information unqualified
which is then processed vetted tested
for veracity deduplicated normalized
enriched and analyzed for military or
political value for domestic and foreign
applications and as a part of CI
operations in other words intelligence
is information data that has been
collected via a variety of methods from
a variety of sources understanding of
events individuals orgs movements and
governments it is both process and a
consumable action or product so process
and product I mean it's not threat Intel
if it's just a product there's got to be
a process it's going to be process and
product we typically talk that it's a
product but it's a process and product
some of the tenants that he raises are
these if we look at this list if you
just peruse it for just a moment which
of these did we normally hear when we're
talking to vendors and I'm not trying to
cached on vendors I'm just trying to say
this is this is the the larger list of
intelligence components that are at the
foundation of threat intelligence so at
this list which ones normally are are
talked about
I hear toast I hear I listened Oh sent
sick singing and right those three right
what about the others do they normally
come up do when you think when you're
thinking about do we think about the
others that are on this list and so will
points us out as as a challenge to the
conversation and in that we basically
have a conversation around a portion or
a smaller percentage of what the overall
disciplines of the tenants that underlie
the disciplines are typically focused on
those three and I said to will when
we're talking to vendors or talking to
each other you know can we I don't know
that's like many of you go to RSA
whatever you walk the floor
I see vendors and my bashing vendors too
much today I'm not trying to bash
vendors but I I get concerned when I see
you know threat intelligence but then
last year you were you were you were you
know selling me something other but then
paren intelligence needs me to the booth
but what kind of threat intelligence is
it is it is it Oh assent is interment is
it Cygnet is it sideband is a defendant
I mean kind of kind of pulling back the
onions and having these larger
conversations and then from from the
linguistic side of this conversation can
I inform the underlying tenants with
things like name into the name entity
recognition NLP we're talking about
about machine learning and data science
to kind of make this conversation more
fruitful for those who are faced with
barriers are getting
right thread Intel more conversations
more questions that will it ask the
group why are we doing threat Intel
today for those of you in the room how
many actually have mature threat Intel
programs
I'm agent I see couple hands how many
would like to have mature threat Intel
programs how many you're not even having
the conversation me too at this at this
cloud company say oh my my manager says
to me is threat intelligence something
that we should do I'm like okay that's
that's the wrong question that's the
wrong question
for those of you who are doing that
until those of you are trying to mature
threat until what are the drivers is it
miss Korean behavior is it the evolution
and maturity of cyber criminal criminals
ABT's is that a bad word yes or no
nation-state proxy nation-state over
aggressive marketing entities if I had
to pull the room which ones would be top
on your list
I am apt nation state some certain mark
marketing it depends on what what or
you're actually in so that's I like what
you what you say when I was with those
group of seats those two weeks ago they
said as you're embarking upon this
conversation around threat intelligence
don't look outside for the inside story
that was Mike towers from allergen a lot
of us may be going back to knowing
thyself do we know what or we are in are
we basing our conversations based on the
org or the verticals that we reside in
typically it's been aggressive marketing
or you you find yourself in a
compromised I've been in both situations
where now it's like okay we should have
had we should have had these items in
place or these particular staples in
place to mitigate some of the some of
the challenges but it's it's a murky
it's a murky market or murky story but a
conversation that has to be had
we talked about military definitions as
a pope in comparison to our current
definitions when we talk about threat
intelligence do we think about
tradecraft and so will says you know
most of us are or are down the PAMP or
down the path incorrectly because we
don't understand tradecraft when we talk
about threat intelligence do we
understand what tradecraft means
techniques methods technologies that
were that were used in an espionage and
so in that sense if you look at the
circle to the right there's planning
there's collection there's processing
and exploitation there's analysis and
production again there's that word
produce something dissemination and
integration circled by evaluation and
feedback so the you know the feedback
loops that would enrich the conversation
directed at espionage but when you look
at it from an information cyber security
perspective it's kind of similar
techniques methods and technologies use
in defending organizations personnel and
their interests against adversaries
internal and and the link does this
sound close to what the definition
should be like we have these we have
these underlying tenants again that
should be informing the process and the
ways that we're going about in such
programs will suggest that in any
program that understands the underlying
tenet of tradecraft we when you
translate that into an information
cybersecurity context that it should
have similar bullets as a part of that
program so understand the intelligence
of the lifecycle collections again
collections hunting hunting is the big
thing now at Masseria profiling looking
at organization personal profiling again
understanding the inside story before
looking outside for analytics production
and workflows I don't want to read
through all this but these are be
available but when you're looking at
defining the program it should have some
elements
these as a part of the program what is
the future then of intelligence or you
know what's happening right now I'm
liking what Rick Howard is saying over
at Palo Alto the norm for us is sharing
we're always you know trying to get
around this through sharing there was a
gentleman by the name of Serge Sergio
Acosta
Kyle stone that grow who wrote on his
blog that sharing in essence is
enriching the collectors and not so much
those who need to benefit by that but
sharing is typically the way that we go
about this most of us Rick says no have
no idea if we have multiple controls in
place down the kill chain for specific
adversaries we can kind of treat
security controls as a giant set of
things to prevent and detect instead of
focusing on the adversaries that we're
buying things we're focusing on controls
instead of focusing on the adversaries
so I'm not sure if any of you in the
room have seen this yet but the play
books from unit 42 in the room anyone I
have one hand unit 42 play books take a
different approach to this so typically
we have one or two run books but what
what would what would organize what
would it be like to have multiple run
books for multiple adversaries so if you
if you know who's targeting you or or
and it's not just one active but it's
multiple actors or two or a handful of
actors Rick Howard and the folks at
unifor to was suggesting that you have
run books for each particular tenant
adversary and so even the controls that
you have today the controls that you
have today may not be the controls you
use tomorrow may be a modular set of
controls based on the actors that are
happening so if you look at this
particular example there is one
particular thread actor sofa see and
then the various things he should have
in place for this particular actor how
many campaigns are out there what
exploits are they're using what should
you have or be looking at in your
environment
for this particular actor and so the
tendency has been to you know bye-bye
for all the actors as opposed to taking
a more modular approach because the
actors are different content potentially
each day for your particular organ a
particular time and so to move module II
have multiple run books be pliable in
the approach the desired outcomes of the
conversation having talked to will last
night would be these there are barriers
many in the room are trying to get to
some modicum of threat Intel or
something that resembles that for their
orgs how do we help people overcome some
of the barriers to getting to the route
the relevant Intel for their particular
organizations and then expand the
conversations you know some what I want
to hear more you know from from will
side of the room about the underlying
tendency fundamental definitions that
ought to be impact are influencing the
conversation we only talk about three of
the ants there may be eight we saw on
the board maybe others from my side of
the house using other disciplines to
inform the way those individuals
fundamental tenets have framed the
conversation around threat Intel
extracting it from from the military
context and putting it into these
information security context building
will we have a I would believe to build
Intel practice almost foundational
attendance and then weave into
transparency I can speak I can speak
from that position because I used to be
a vendor I used to sell the Intel we
just wanted to get you know fuck me let
me back up let me back up don't throw
stones don't throw bricks or anything
and since some some days was about
getting the PIO
but for me being a consumer a
practitioner and a seller if the vendor
and consumer conversations could be more
transparent more open peel back the
onions what is it that you're actually
selling me and when you sell it to me
does it do exactly what it needs to do
for my particular environment
from my particular reference frame of
reference can I talk about the multiple
run books is it pliable for my
particular organization or vertical and
so with that what kind of flew by
because I'm by myself up here but thank
you for listening to the conversation we
have a lot of time left so a few
questions or I have a question here yeah
I need that term but yes you're correct
we didn't come up in the curtain and the
initial conversation but it is in the
back back to the background of the
conversation about it being actionable
being not just collecting because we we
can define the process we can unearth
the military definitions but at the end
of the day after that process that loop
is complete is it actionable question
I absolutely I absolutely I do know what
it is I absolutely love it
I think with I'm sorry so he asked about
miners attack framework if you're you
can go out there and look look look that
up but it's it's a framework that that
kind of talks about how attackers are
using what particular processes or
techniques and tactics in various
situations so he's he's asking if if
that would be something useful to help
enhance our detection in response and I
would say emphatically yes and then I've
worked with a few vendors who are
already under hood you know ingesting or
using that framework in terms of
enhancing their product for public
consumption but I also see it making
sense in what unit 42 was doing for me
it's for me that's the one of the most
innovative changes if they get there it
made me and it's not probably something
we can all do but be pliable can I have
them can I have multiple sets of
controls maybe it's not maybe it's not
cost-efficient to have it but being
pliable enough to say maybe I use
product eight from September to December
but I see we've got some predictable
analysis down down the road that
suggests that we flip the switch and
start move over to another set of
controls typically we have a static set
of controls if there are no other
questions thank you
you
[Applause]