okay so it's been a couple of years
since the last time I got up in front of
you guys to try a live demo a couple of
slides first basically at last man log
in st. Louis a bunch of the backbone
operators got together to talk about
tools and what kinds of tools would be
useful is was a little meeting called by
Doug Mon from HS ARPA and there were two
things that came out of that one was
what you're about to see now and the
other was a live RSS feed of who is
changes as they happen which also got
worked on and mostly done about a week
after the last nanog but then ran into
intellectual property issues around the
who is content so we'll be working on
that as well but anyway so this one
basically the goals here were to get a
tulip that would let provisioning
engineers sanity check the lists of
prefixes that their customers want to
announce out through them so if you're
running a backbone customer comes to you
once the BGP session says you know here
are the fifty prefixes who want to
announce out through you a senior
engineer could probably look at each of
those and tell you if there was
something wacky about one of them but a
senior engineer probably doesn't have
time to go through all 50 of them for
every customer and if you hand them to a
junior engineer who does have time at
least for the lists of 50 if not the
lists of a thousand the junior engineer
may not already know off the top of
their heads what a lot of different
prefixes are so the idea here was just
sort of automate that and be able to
pick out the weird ones for a little bit
more scrutiny and what people will save
some of their time by not looking at all
the ones that were as
affected and then obviously the next
step is to crank out a properly
formatted prefix list that can be dumped
into a router so as you might expect a
lot of the work in this goes into the
input parsing because people you know
have all kinds of weird formats that
they want to dump junk into this tool in
obviously the easy one is just cider
right and end end end / mask length but
you know if you look old who is stuff
you've got pre cider ranges you've got
stuff people are dumping in from cisco
and juniper configs from output from
display commands on routers stuff coming
out of other kinds of provisioning
systems lots of stuff out of our IR and
irr who is so we were trying to parse
all of that stuff as rationally as we
can and I think you'll find we're doing
a reasonably good job but we'd be very
interested to hear about any exceptions
that you find then we do a little bit of
analysis of it a lot of database lookups
into the different databases that we
keep of different kinds of
infrastructure so we flag all the bogans
and critical infrastructure like
exchange point subnets and root and TLD
name servers we flag long prefixes so
anything longer than a / 24 right now
but you'll be able to dump in a table of
your own preferred maximum prefix
lengths for each range out of the v4
space then we draw a little map of the
world and show on the map where these
prefixes map tues so that you know if
there's one that's different from the
others you can spot it easily we grab a
little malware incident to address ratio
statistics from Rick wesson's outfit
support intelligence and we kind of sum
that up into a ratio and then we put a
lot of this stuff up in a table so that
you can sort of sort at different ways
and look at it and make sense of it and
then the output we do Cisco prefix list
juniper prefix lists and juniper set
commands so time for a live demo ah just
just kidding okay all right so I'm going
to have to do this kind of over my
shoulder here so somebody want to poop
where's cursor there we go somebody'll I
give me a couple of prefixes that
they're going to be able to recognize
whether we've got them right somebody
Mike RSL hell all right this is not a
plant somebody else can come up after
our sure 192 okay 148 1 48 to 50 20
space 0 0 1 255 ok let's see how that
one works and any others come on
somebody here on it's not dangerous
harmless come on guys hello we'll start
selecting volunteers don't get him yeah
okay try 146 stop 188 dot 0 dot 0 okay
so I'm not bothering with a mask on here
we'll see if it gets it right Ted how
about you one years later all right okay
so to show you the kind of stuff that we
can digest successfully I'm going to
dump in some other things here as well
so we've got we got those two then we've
got a show IP bgp show IP route some
show run the route statements and route
map statements and then some who is down
there so let's submit it and this is
going to take a little while because
this entire thing database and
everything is at the moment running on a
single little mac mini which is why i
have the URL hidden up there at the
moment because I'd really rather that
only me and a few other people be using
it right now what we do the demo and
then you guys can all start playing with
it the moment the demo is done so we're
grinding through some database queries
here and rendering a map which yes will
only take another few seconds there we
go okay so this is probably easiest to
see if we sort it look sorting is not
working there
okay there we go because it was taking
yeah oh well okay so there's the map you
can see that most of these were in the
US we've got a little bit in Mexico a
little bit in Canada and a little bit in
South Africa here so right off the bat
if we're writing a prefix list for an
ISP in the u.s. we might want to look at
that South African one and say hmm you
know maybe that one isn't right so let's
sort by country and go find that so
there's the South African one you can
see it's just a normal prefix checks out
ok so it's checked by default so we
might want to uncheck that to say no we
don't think that one's okay we're going
to take it out of the list that we're
going to the prefix list we're going to
generate now let's go back and look at
the others so this one we've kicked out
because it's the it's got the dns server
for the TT country code in it turn it up
trinidad and tobago but you know I
happen to know what that is and know
that that one's okay so we'll include
that then we've caught the one here 198
32 dot 176 which many of you may
recognize that's packs so we probably
shouldn't include packs then we've got
another one here 206 to 20 to 30 / 24
but that's already included in another
one that was already in the list so we
don't need to include it again here's be
rude and look cursor down there and then
here's one with a whole bunch of TLD
servers in it that I also know is okay
and we've got a bug on 192 168 and then
a bunch of stuff that you know I know
belongs to various customers whatever
also we can
and hit show errors here and see what
the parsing errors were right so prefix
0000 is to general and then a bunch of
things where we looked at the line and
there just wasn't anything that looked
like prefix in it but anyway so we we
have that show airs button anytime we
had any parsing errors so it shows up
some of the time all right so let's say
we want to go ahead and generate a
prefix list for this and I want to call
Luke sorry we scroll down so you can see
all this a little bit better say I want
to call this Bill's list and let's say I
want to add this onto an existing prefix
list that has goes up through 300 right
now so let's start that at 310 and let's
say I like my increments in fives so
this is all just you know copy and paste
able off of here let's say that actually
I want to pop it into a Juniper instead
got juniper intercept commands you know
various ways of popping us stuff out and
we're happy to add more the the output
side of this is actually really trivial
compared to all the parsing and database
so there are other things that we can do
here aside from just submitting lists of
prefixes and generating prefix lists
like I said set maximum prefix length if
you want to give us a table of maximum
prefix lengths in different ranges of
the v4 space again happy to take those
that feature is not quite done yet but
will be shortly custom exclusion lists
also not quite done yet but should be
shortly where if you have things that
you want flagged in input that you see
but you don't want that to be public for
other people so like your own internal
infrastructure that you don't want to
hear from customers that kind of thing
you can put it in and we'll save it
for your use but other people won't see
it report critical infrastructure so if
there's something that you think that we
don't know about that you think is
critical infrastructure you can report
it to us and we'll figure out whether to
add it into the general list of things
that get flagged with a lot of the stuff
we have links with definitions here so
if again you want to throw a junior
engineers at this you may not quite know
what we're talking about we try and be
as helpful as possible and then lastly
of course the future and bug report
there in case you run into anything
please let us know so let's wrap up the
slides here so future features like I
said the custom acceptable prefix length
stables custom prefix rejection tables
guess rejection accept tables so if you
want us to flag things based on a esas
that you don't want to see in the path
or that are automatically okay in the
path we're going to have both of those
features another trickier one previous
transit is uniformity checks so if you
give us a list of prefixes we'll look
through and see whether those prefixes
mostly have the same a esas in common
that they were getting transit from
before and if so we'll be able to flag
ones that don't have those in commons so
if a customer a new potential customer
comes to you and says you know all these
guys are my customer will be able to
flag ones that look like maybe they
didn't have that guy as their service
provider in the past also suggesting
potential aggregates so if you give us
you know something that includes 16 / 24
s in the list that could aggregate up
we'll be able to suggest the aggregate
for you if you want to put just one line
in instead of 16 lines into your final
list next ml API for integrating this
into your provisioning system so if you
want to just fire something off for
your existing provisioning system rather
than logging in in the web interface
you'll be able to get the same data back
in XML and do whatever you want with it
I RR submission generations so another
output format aside from the juniper and
cisco prefix lists is a template to mail
in to an IRR so we want to just do that
for you automatically as well again not
quite done yet and lastly ipv6 we
haven't actually had a request for v6
yet but a lot of people have mentioned
that they think other people would want
it soon so again we didn't try and get
that done for version 1 but we will soon
and obviously this is all driven by what
you guys actually want to use so just
let us know terms of known issues like I
said the main one is just performance
we're doing fair amount of caching and
so forth to make the responses come in
as quickly as possible but right now
it's all running on one a little mac
mini and we'll try and scrape together
some money for more hardware to put on
thank you very much to all the beta
testers we got a tremendous amount of
feedback over the last couple months
about this as well as of course in the
original meeting at the last nanog and
that's where all the ideas here came
from we didn't have the smarts to dream
any of this up ourselves and to HSR PO
who called the original meeting that
came up with this and there's the URL
where it will be in perpetuity as long
as we're around so please have fun with
it and let us know what problems you
find we love the feedback and if anybody
has any questions right now I'm happy to
take them that looks like I'm off the
hook no questions no Collins all right
and I guess we're on to lunch guys and
you want to take it over stever