hello can you hear me so good morning my
name is stefan suru yo I'm faculty at
the University of Toronto in the
computer science department university
of toronto is just a couple of blocks
north of here so unlike most of you who
get to only spend about three days of
winter in toronto i get to spend the
entire winter every year one good things
about research talks is that there are
15 minutes only so hopefully they're
going to be short and sweet so i'm going
to try to do that as well before I begin
I want to give you a little bit of a
very high level view of the research
project that I'm doing this is joint
work with Troy Rhonda with my graduate
student so what we're doing we're trying
to understand the prevalence of certain
internet security attacks in particular
you know how when people receive
phishing emails as spam emails and half
when do people really click on the links
in their emails why does this thing
thing still happens and why do people
still feel forms and online and buy
viagra and so forth so to do that we
said we're going to trace a network
traffic at the University of Toronto now
in research Rana is a large school it
has three campuses the campus downtown
which is the one here if you go on in
verse 11 you can see the campus is
called the st. George campus and it's
the biggest and there is a campus on the
east side of the city and there is a
campus on the west side of the city the
one on the west is called University of
Toronto Mississauga and we are tracing
all the traffic going in and out of this
campus University of Toronto Mississauga
so in this talk I'm going to just tell
you about what are some of the concerns
that we had to deal with in order to
protect the users privacy when we trace
network traffic so just kind of to take
a step back about eight months ago unit
we went to University of Toronto and we
said to the ethics comedian we said we'd
like to actually look at everyone's
emails and they said no so it took us
about eight months to kind of convince
them that we are going to offer some
privacy guarantees and the role of this
talk is to tell you what we've learned
okay now one thing I want to I want to
give a little bit of motivation so a lot
of people actually are doing network
tracing and today in today's day and age
all these networks racing in order to be
in
thing it has to you have to look at
packet payload a lot of people talk
about packet headers collecting them
analyzing them understanding what's
going on that's great but all the good
stuff and the interesting stuff
especially from a security standpoint or
cursing the packet payloads not in the
headers anymore now when the moment you
start looking at packet payloads now the
privacy concerns escalates right because
you're looking at people's traffic and
typically when you look at the research
projects and how they deal with privacy
they pretty much all of them deal with
what I call a three-step process let's
gather data we're going to write it to
the disk then offline some time later
we're going to anonymize it and the way
we're going to anonymize it is using a
hash function and there's a whole bunch
of very smart hash functions some of
them are what what's called prefix
preserving in other words if you have to
IP addresses that share the first two
octaves even after you uh naanum eyes
them the anonymize numbers the hash
values are going to share the first two
octaves and that's very nice and finally
after we analyze the entire day that
we're going to throw away the raw data
and we're going to do the entire
analysis on the anonymous traces and
because we you don't like to actually
disseminate our faces in the research
community we're going to post these
faces online on a public website
somewhere for people to download them
and run their own studies because that's
very nice we get a lot of citations that
way ok now the message of my talk today
if there is one thing I'd like you to
remember is that these three step
process is completely inadequate from a
privacy standpoint you cannot go with a
straight face in front of an ethics
committee and say oh we're going to
gather all the raw data is three
somewhere on the disk and sometime in
the future going to remember to erase it
that doesn't work especially when you
start talking to people telling people
you're going to look at their emails
okay so why is that now for the next two
slides I'm going to give you a couple of
attacks that could actually be mounted
against your traces and can expose a lot
of privacy first of all I was called
mapping attacks now mapping attacks
actually map from anonymized data back
to the road data and there are two types
of magic mapping attacks there are known
mapping attacks and there are inferred
mapping attacks now what does it mean on
mapping attack so let's suppose you know
that the president of the university's
IP address doesn't share any pre
nobody no other IP address within the
university of toronto now even if you
wanna minimize that IP address looking
into that on my straits you can figure
out the IP address of the of the
president of the university that's bad
the second one are inferred mapping
attacks inferred basically means you
don't really have knowledge but you can
make educated guesses so let me give you
an example if you if you look at the top
10 most popular URLs okay most popular
websites in your trace yes there are not
in my so you don't know what they are
but you can take some educated guesses
so for example chances are google com is
one of them okay and then you can try to
break the keys of the hashing functions
that way let me give you a different
interesting example you'll work up a
peer-to-peer traffic and you suddenly
see that on november 30 2006 suddenly
there is this new file which you've
never seen before you don't know the
name cuz is not only mais but it's very
very popular and then you look actually
on IMDb and you realize that this is the
same date when the borod movie is being
released and then you can say hi i think
i can take a pretty good guess as to
what that file actually is okay and
things like that third type of attack is
data injection attacks so on attacker
knows that you're tracing and it
basically construct traffic you know
carefully in a careful manner and it
tries to inject this traffic in your
face then it goes online you download
your trace and it tries to look for
those carefully constructed patterns in
the in the hash trace and it can learn a
lot of things that way as well they're
also crypto attacks playing all crypto
attacks whenever you talk to a crypto
guy he will tell you are you remember
that md5 hash function I can generate
collisions in about eight hours on my
laptop really easily and you know
collisions are not particularly bad when
you trace and when you are non mais
things the real question in my mind is
the moment you make these trace is
available yes they're going to be hard
to be breakable from a crypto point of
view today but you know how are they
going to be are they going to be able to
be broken 20 30 years from now very very
easily because if they are people don't
like to know that you know two years
from now everybody can read their email
there are even more attacks and on this
slide I have what I consider the war
mode the worst attack the most worrisome
their attacks on the tracing
infrastructure your have a machine that
looks at all the traffic online and it
has access to it
how do you know that I'm machine is
gonna is not going to be remotely
exploitable some guy somewhere is going
to actually hack into your machine there
are also unanticipated attacks we can
just not be able to foresee the kind of
attack somebody's going to be able to
mount on these traces and the example
that I like to give a couple of week
uppal of years ago somebody show that is
very easy to fingerprint the operating
system of a host by looking at the
timings of those particular packets in
the TCP streams there are all kinds of
clever ways to actually attack that you
can really foresee so that you can
protect yourself against that and
finally the worst one in my mind is what
I call legal complications some smart
lawyers somewhere thinks that it's a
good idea to get his hands on your trace
and it's a penis and we're a publicly
funded research group at the public
institution will be able to have so if
you get subpoena to actually you know
give access to our tracing
infrastructure and if you have raw data
on the tracing infrastructure and that's
particularly bad and let me tell you why
I'm really worried about this isn't that
all these attacks that I presented so
far if they could reveal some
information okay but the one will you
actually have access to the raw data you
revealed whole identities actually then
powerful information of all the users
whose traffic you're monitoring and
that's particularly bad so we scratch
our head and we said okay we learn two
things they're here two things we're not
going to do first of all we're not going
to write plain text or raw data to the
disk ever okay because like I said you
can actually if somebody gets their
hands on that data you can get
subpoenaed well you're right running it
and you haven't write it and you haven't
erased it yet and that's it's a very
serious attack because it reveals fully
information about the identities of the
people who are tracing and the second
thing we actually learned and we decided
not to do we said we're not going to
make these traces publicly available
we're not going to post them online if
there are other researchers that have
interesting questions or studies or
queries they would like to run our
traces will be happy to accommodate them
we're not going to make these things
available somewhere online so that
people can download them and archive
them and break them 30 40 years from now
or anything like that okay so um how are
we how are we doing this thing so I'm
gonna actually give you a picture here
kind of like a
mental model of what we're doing now in
this slide you see three clouds on the
left you see the Internet cloud in the
middle you have the main cloud which is
the st. George campus the biggest campus
in University of Toronto and on the
right you have the campus at mississauga
which is the one we trace traffic to and
from there are two things i wanna say on
this slide first of all that Mississauga
the campus at mississauga is connected
to the internet via saying George okay
so it has it doesn't have its own
connection and second and the most
important thing is that this picture is
not up to scale when I'm not claiming
hear that university of toronto is as
big as the internet in terms of traffic
or anything like that okay i'm just
making these clouds big enough so that
we understand what's going on of course
the internet is much much bigger than
the traffic we're looking on here okay
so what is that we're doing well we have
a switch on the link from Mississauga to
st. George and it does port mirroring
and it has a one-way linking to our
tracing machine now the dotted frame you
see on the slide that's one machine and
we basically split it into ram or
volatile memory and stable memory or
stable storage and that's 13 C machine
and we have a one way link what does it
mean to have a one way link well you
take basically a fiber cable which has
an impound inbound and outbound channel
and we only only put the inbound channel
into the Machine and we do not connect
the outbound channel in other words we
make sure that there is absolutely no
wire or fiber optic cable or anything
like that that can take packets and
route them send them outside of this
machine we basically disconnect our
tracing machine from the internet
because to my knowledge this is the best
way we can go in front of the Ethics
Committee and tell them we're pretty
darn sure nobody is going to break
remotely into this machine over the
Internet there is no wire coming out of
this machine okay okay so what is it
that we're doing well we're getting
packets on this one way link and we're
basically doing everything in around
there is no kind of you know secret
sauce here it's kind of like bad news in
some sense so we're doing we're
capturing the packets online we're doing
TCP reconstruction HTTP reconstruction
we're doing more application level equal
construction in particular we're looking
at hotmail mail that you actually
receive with hotmail and gmail and
things like that we also run spam
assassin
and we do everything in RAM and then
only after we're done we are naanum eyes
the data and then we write it a stable
storage okay so what does this mean this
has these nice property which is if you
unplug the machine from power all that
thing is gone because it's in volatile
memory so if you get the peanut and I've
unplug this machine from power there is
no raw data on this machine whatsoever
okay and you might wonder how do you
know there is really no raw data what
about the swap file right i mean you can
get and we said yeah you know we're
going to disable swap file but the kind
of the good news is you know if you're
tracing a line spins and if you start
swapping things in and out of memory
you're probably too slow anyway and you
lost so you should crash rather than
continue okay so we're starting we're
writing everything to stable storage
that's basically our answer and that's
how we reveal we're able after eight
months of discussions with the ethics
community to get to be approved to
actually look at the people's webmail
for for fishing so in summary our
infrastructure protects against
intrusion attacks and the way it does
that is because it's disconnected from
the internet there is no traffic coming
out of this machine it protects against
legal attacks to recover raw data
because all the raw data manipulation is
done in volatile memory RAM and it
protects against mapping crypto on
anticipating the data injection attacks
because we're not going to make this
trace is publicly available however the
inside here is that some of these
attacks like the mapping creeps are
anticipated attacks are still possible
if somebody gets their hand on the
anonymous traced one way to do that is
to be subpoenaed and we really don't
know very well how to protect against
that other than saying that you know
even this anonymize traces will make
sure to permanently destroy them as
quickly as we can and that's our best
answer so far now I have this is my
summary slide I have one more kind of
it's kind of like the lamest sliding the
whole talk and this is kind of like some
preliminary statistics about fishing the
reason why these are very very
preliminary is that we're basically
tracing as we speak like I said we do a
lot of things in ram our tracing
infrastructure is really not rock-solid
the longest race we've collected so far
is about 56 hours okay because after
that we crashed because of all kinds of
bad bugs and things like that we do
everything in RAM so only tracing about
honey megabits per second this was the
traffic over the weekend coming in and
out of this campus we could probably
trace up to about the gigabit per second
with the machine we have so far but
there's this is a smaller campus and it
has a only about five thousand users now
we look at hotmail for now only when
we've seen 200 people 200 people using
hotmail and they have read so these
slices we see but they have read is not
received they clicked on their emails or
700 times so they've read about 700
unique messages and about 3% of them are
spam seems pretty low the reason why
it's low is because hotmail does a
fairly good job of filtering and
classifying email as spam as well so we
this is Pam after that has escaped the
hotmail filters another statistic that I
want to kind of finish with kind of like
kind of like you know that I found very
interesting this is again very
preliminary so I did not put this on the
slide because you know take this with a
grain of salt here's an interesting
thing we found that I found very kind of
counterintuitive it turns out that if
you look at clean emails emails that are
not spam many of them don't have links
that's great but but many of them do
have links and the interesting thing is
that the number of links in clean emails
is actually higher than the number of
links in spam emails or phishing emails
and we believe that the reason of why
this is treats because the bad guys
really want to make you click on a
single link they don't wanna give you
too many links and options you can click
on because that's not good did we want
to click on this link as if you click
there then good things happen to them
and bad things happen to you and that's
the end of my my talk I you know this
this code that we're actually developing
is going to be and it is actually
publicly available and open source and
so forth so you can actually download a
copy and play with it thank you very
much
can we get the next presenter come up
here while I ask if there are any
questions Joel yay glee I'm just a quick
observation if you actually need disc or
swap it's it it's pretty easy to
generate random key every time and have
temp or swap file systems that are
encrypted so that every time the
machinery boots you get new file systems
and it's actually quite convenient and
we use it in some collectors that's
great i will actually looked at that
also and i think it's a good solution as
well and it could be probably be done
the thing that I'm worried about I'm
worried about what's being swapped and
what's not being swapped what if I want
to make sure that the key that i have in
RAM is not going to be soft on discover
but you're right i think i think the
nice solution i'm not saying absolutely
yeah right well i mean if you want to
talk to me about it later shut around
wonderful thank you yes sir mike hughes
links um thanks Stefan it was me who
press can give into doing this just one
another question was the machine that
you're using at the moment um how much
memory here physical RAM and how much
storage have you got on the back of that
machine so we have only four gig of ram
and here is one thing I kind of learned
doing this is that you know having more
rameez nice there is nothing wrong with
it but the reason why you're running out
of RAM is because you probably have a
memory leak somewhere and if you have
eight gig instead of four gig of 12
games of the four gig rather than
tracing for three days your trace you're
going to be tracing for five days or
something like that so we're better off
trying to go after that bug and try to
fix it yeah that that's quite a useful
point because I know I mean we've been
doing some work with things like s flow
data and one of the things that we have
is trying to handle this much stuff and
it you're always doing things in RAM
disk and then having to commit stuff
later and so you can actually make the
thing fast enough because you've got so
many Mac to Mac pairs for example in my
application but that that's really but
you're right the biggest bottleneck we
have is RAM and the second biggest
bottleneck is CPU storage is not really
an issue
okay thank you thank you very much