so this is a presentation about s flow
it is a standards-based protocol for
exporting information about packets
traveling through a router or switch
it's like net flow which a lot of people
use simple premise you can't possibly
have a tap port or any way to record all
the packets go through your data all the
locations but you may be interested in
some portion for statistical sampling
and you may want to gather data the s
flow protocol was designed by the Inman
corporation 2001 they did an RFC for the
original versions and then they haven't
done our FCS for updates but there have
been a few new versions since those
published the design of the protocol was
was intended to overcome limitations of
the traditional net flow protocol
specifically the fixed header format you
know every time you need to add a new
type of information you have to release
a new version and it became difficult
for people to support so it's very
flexible extensible you can change add
update new header formats
to various things like I said it's
intended to enhance or replace arm on
net flow the usual type of things and
there are a few vendors who are very
prominent with it specifically foundry
extreme and forced n are relatively well
known for supporting it Cisco and
juniper however do not they still go
with net flow a quick recap on why to
use any type of export protocol you know
you are interested in your protocol port
application statistics you're interested
in tracking denial service you're
interested in capacity planning one
interesting thing that sflow adds is the
ability to do layer 2 support so a lot
of folks use it for analysis on layer 2
exchange points so you can tell how much
traffic is going between any particular
member without everyone's gear having to
do max
mack counting which a lot of equipment
out there doesn't support or even if it
does it's flying car dependent or it's
very limited or it's some feature that
you lose when you turn that on so for
the exchange point to do the polling is
beneficial for everyone you get a nice
webpage and it displays how much traffic
you're doing to every individual appear
some folks have rolled this out already
Equinix was I think the first and links
and AM six I know have followed up with
their own versions and it's proven to be
very popular there are some concerns
about data privacy but in general folks
like it and find it very useful so
here's the sFlow version of the history
of flow export which is probably neither
thorough nor accurate but it shows some
of the progression through time of
traffic levels and various forms of flow
like I said the version that you're
probably all aware of is net flow which
was Cisco dependent it's been extended
many times and the latest version is
NetFlow v9 which not many people have
rolled out from what I've seen but its
goal is to copy a lot of the features of
s flow whereas s flow is release much
earlier v9 tries to replicate that with
a lot of the extended format so
basically the limitations that you are
facing when it comes to sampling data is
how much data are you pulling the sample
with traffic rates growing at the rate
that they are it's significantly
difficult to get all the packets or
anywhere approaching all the packets so
there are two methods that are used to
reduce the amount of data that you have
to monitor the first is sampling which
is simply looking at one out of every in
packet so you know sample one out of
every thousand packets multiplied by a
thousand and hope for a statistically
correct average and the other method is
aggregation which is to collect all the
data but
then consolidate it on the device before
exporting it so for example say you're
not interested in every destination IP
of every flow but say you're interested
in destination prefix you might do the
aggregation on the device itself before
exporting data and that reduces load on
your collector and load on on traffic
that you have to export usually sampling
is the winner and the reason is you
don't have to maintain state for a lot
of networks complex networks with lots
of flows there just isn't enough
DCAM in the world or whatever resources
being used as RAM whatever to track the
state to build the flows so a lot of
folks face this on platforms today where
if you're trying to track net flow even
if you don't want it to be stateful you
can't turn it off and you're going to
quickly exhaust your router resources so
the problems of net flow it is
originally based as a flow based system
you know it was designed so that if your
router saw 10 packets about a flow but
before they say the 30 second export
cycle or whatever the case may be it
would summarize that data and export
information about that specific flow
that requires state so like I said
frequent state memory exhaustion and the
sampling that is available is an
afterthought so there's no mechanism
inside the protocol for example to
communicate what the sampling rate is
you have to know what you've configured
the device for you generally can't
configure multiple sampling rates across
different cards different architecture
types things like that and support for
all versions and features is sporadic
NetFlow v5 is probably the most commonly
used today that's the generic net flow
it doesn't include support for
aggregation that's in v8 which is less
commonly used the most commonly used
versions don't support layer 2
information they're not extensible and
that's something that NetFlow v9 has
tried to fix but I guess
it's an afterthought and it's basically
adapting the features of sFlow back into
NetFlow so the features of sFlow it's
specifically designed for sampling there
is no flow data there's no attempt to
track flow data and from the ground up
it's built to do sampling so it
communicates this type of data inside
the packet and makes it much easier to
maintain correct and accurate data like
I say here you can configure lower rates
for 10 gig cards versus hundred Meg
cards if you want more data more
granular data inside things that you
don't necessarily aren't passing that
much traffic there's currently 23 types
of data bearing message formats that's
extended all the time but it includes
everything under the Sun from your
generic type of net flow information to
information about the BGP path selected
MPLS paths and various things it fully
supports layer 2 fully supports MPLS and
BGP like I said and it also supports
passing the first 128 bytes of the
packet and that lets you get into a lot
more interesting detailed analysis with
the header and writing custom code to do
whatever you want and one of the other
interesting things that no other NetFlow
has that I'm aware of is a push base
counter so instead of having to go out
and SNMP query a box and then get the
results back it will actually push the
usual SNMP type data out for each
interface it makes it really easy to
collect at a high rate of speed
interface data so it's it's kind of
useful said that turns out to be very
useful and there's a lot of benefits to
getting down into the ten to thirty
second range as opposed to like a five
minute average or whatever you really
see a lot more denial of service you
really see a microburst a lot more so
it's very useful once people are
interested in that the issues with s
flow generally speaking the issues are
all in the design of the protocol so
when I first looked at this thing I
thought oh wow this is bad it's got some
interesting formatting to say the least
and you can obviously see where they're
trying to keep everything 32-bit word
aligned the issue is that you have very
inefficient use of space so for example
you may have values that are only going
to be one through four like say bgp
version and that's gonna be a 32-bit
value and then later on they will have
separate message formats where they try
to take something that is legitimately a
32-bit value like say if index and they
say well if it's less than 24 we'll add
in some other 8-bit value at the end and
it results in extra message formats and
all kinds of complexity but fortunately
that's just an issue for the people
writing the libraries to parse the
packets the other issue is that at least
in the the original v2 and then the v4
versions there was no TLB encoding so
what this means is you have to know your
parser has to know about every type of
packet or you know if you receive a type
of packet which you can't correctly
parse if someone has added a new
protocol or new export message which are
not aware of you can't just skip over it
you become D synchronized with the
stream and you end up losing the entire
packet and corrupting your data
potentially so that's been at least
somewhat fixed in v5 they've gone back
and added a few new features generally
speaking is transparent to the end-user
once you get around it then like I said
there's a net flow v9 which adds the
flexible fields which is comparable to
all the different s flow format types it
adds the layer to information
it adds the information about MPLS paths
you may be traversing about BGP routes
various other enhancements so it's
really intended to catch up to s flow
and then there's been a recent IETF
standardization attempt on IP fix aka
NetFlow v10 which is based on that flow
v9 they had a couple more things some
some enterprise specific formats but
roughly the same thing kind of the same
features I haven't played with it
personally so I can't speak to it but
for people that happen to operate
foundry extremely important networks
you're still gonna be interested in s
flow because that's the only only thing
supported so even if if not flow V 9 or
IP fix get around to adding all the same
functionality the still interesting
stuff it currently as far as I'm aware
is only supported by Cisco and that's
bee-nine
I'm not sure what universe plans are for
it
it doesn't replicate the push based
counters which I personally find very
interesting so there's a couple ways
that you can do this and I apologize I
had a more current version of the slide
which I don't have here the folks at
am-6 had worked hard to develop their
own tools and I wasn't able to get any
information on whether that was
officially released or not but you may
want to harass Niels there's the
official sFlow site there's a reference
collector that they give away for free
there's commercial products that they
sell obviously it was written and
developed by a commercial company
there's some specifications online for
the actual protocol and like I said and
I'm not sure if they have six tool has
ever been released but they did their
own stuff actually needles can tell me
right now well maybe not they probably
have to turn it on because it's called
the nets s flow and it's on Sipan okay
so I also for the purposes of this
worked on another implementation which
is my own high speed C library I split
this up into two packages one which is
the generic library which
anyone can use to parse the packets and
fairly efficient given the limitations
of the protocol and I also split it up
into a reference example code I'm sort
of right now the documentation isn't
that great so if you know what you're
doing you can probably figure it out if
you don't you may be confused or try to
get around to adding more documentation
shortly but there is a reference
collector which implements the two most
interesting features that I'm aware of
which are the push counter information
writing that out as the equivalent of
replacing SNP polling and the layer -
Mac - MAC address mapping so anyone that
runs an exchange point that's interested
in s flow data is probably going to be
very interested in this it's the kind of
thing that users seem to like that's
basically the gist of it
so questions
and Chris Whitfield internet also in
your list of applications supporting and
I wanted to add that the latest versions
of n top also will collect us flow
although I think the latest release
version has a bug that breaks sample des
flow but there's an RC that was released
today that fixes that bug Matt Rangel
Tufts University one thing was very go s
flow is so you could not actually
construct total traffic passed by just
taking a look at all the STL samples I
mean yeah there's plenty of other ways
to do it but you could not do it using s
flow specifically right you can't well
you can reconstruct the total data one
of the fields that it does pass is the
amount of data that was originally there
before it was sampled so more than just
knowing about the packets if you happen
to get for example your one out of a
thousand packets happened to be the
small packet it still has the counters
for the the original data that came that
was sampled from the thousand packets so
you can at least reconstruct total
utilization from that alright thank you
anyone else I think we're good