hi everyone welcome to ovas app check
and today we're here with the builder
sessions and for the next 45 minutes you
will have tadmavi today to actually talk
about the topic abusing Cloud apps 101
command and control before I introduce
the speaker I just wanted to give you a
few uh things to go about for the next
45 minutes I'll be the moderator for
this session so I will come up back
again after he's done so if you have any
questions you can post it down
on the Google platform on the right side
of the video and we'll be taking those
questions once after the speaker is done
with this session and uh you know
there's no chat options available for
the attendees on the zoom so if you want
to post in any Chat thing or any
questions you can use the Hoover
platform for the same I'll be looking at
down all of the comments to bring it
down to the speaker and we can discuss
that at the last 15 minutes so we have
the topic here as abusing Cloud apps 101
command and control and we have a great
great speaker here he's a threat
researcher at netscope threat labs and
is focused on cloud application views
and cloud enabled thread detection
so really I welcome you to Mommy today
and over to you for the session
thank you very much Samana that was a
great introduction I hope everyone is
having a great time here at Olaf's
global app SEC 2022 and we have a very
exciting talk prepared for you today so
let's get started
um like saman said I am a currently a
threat researcher here at uh netsco
previously I've held positions as a
researcher a software engineer and as a
developer at multiple companies I have
my masters in cyber security from Drexel
University and I also have an oscp in
various Cloud certifications as well my
interest range from capture their Flags
exploit development to the study of
cloud application abuse as well which is
a really nice segue into what we're
going to be talking about today
so it is my hope that everyone attending
this session today takes away four key
takeaways with them firstly what is
cloud C2 what is cloud Community Control
what does that really mean secondly what
cloud applications are abused for
command and control in the wild right is
this even really happening is this is
this tactic occurring thirdly if this is
happening how can you simulate this in
your corporate Network so that you can
see if the controls you have in place
can detect this tactic
and then lastly if you do have gaps in
your security posture what defenses can
you put in place so that you have a more
complete Security posture and you can
identify this tactic being used in your
environment right so those are the four
takeaways let's get started
first start with talking about what
cloud C2 is what do we mean when we say
cloud Community Control
before we Define command Cloud command
and control however we need to take a
step back and talk about what community
control is so command and control is a
stage in the Cyber kill chain the Cyber
kill chain maybe for those of you who
aren't familiar is a set of steps uh an
attacker uses when compromising a Target
system and this was developed by
Lockheed and Martin and it typically
starts out with the attacker performing
some reconnaissance you can see this on
the right side of your screen or the
slide I mean it starts out with some
attacker performance and reconnaissance
they'll gather some information I'm
going to gather some information they'll
try to find any weaknesses they can
weaponize on malicious payload against
once they've weaponized this payload
they'll deliver it and then exploit that
weakness once they've exploited that
weakness they will install a particular
piece of malware on the target system
that will phone back home and pull for
additional commands so this traffic
where a compromised device is pulling
for additional commands is what we refer
to as command and control
traditionally it has involved this you
know compromised device polling for
commands via mediums like https and DNS
directly to the attacker controlled
server if you wanted to simulate
Community Control you would have used
Frameworks like Cobalt strike and
Powershell Empire to simulate this in
your team engagement or penetration test
assessments so that you could see if the
controls you have would identify this
so now that we've covered what command
and control is what do we mean when we
say cloud command control or Cloud C2 so
traditionally what we've seen attackers
do is they'll set up their own
infrastructure their own servers their
own domains and their own hosts to
Tunnel traffic through and you can see
this on the top right a compromised
device is going to reach out
to the attacker-owned infrastructure
that's set up by the attacker which will
then pull commands from the attacker
machine right so this is what the
traditional setup was like this this is
tough to detect but the security
Community has done a pretty good job of
using threat intelligence Feats to
identify the sort of infrastructure so
the attacker uh sorry the security
Personnel would identify a server that's
used for C2 they will take this IP
address or this host they'll feed it to
a threat intelligence feed that other
security Personnel can consume and then
defend against the DC traffic to their
Network
what attackers have done is recently
they've started using or I should say
abusing Cloud applications as a medium
for Community Control right so instead
of these infrastructure we'll see
Dropbox instances Google Drive folders
right slack channels S3 buckets as a
medium to Tunnel their commands back and
forth now why would an attacker want to
do this well firstly it's very minimal
setup it's very easy to kind of get set
up and going into these Cloud apps right
secondly they're very uh they're cheap
if not free so they're very cost
efficient and thirdly it's even tougher
to detect this traffic since everyone
uses you know they're so popular and
ubiquitous you blend in with the
existing traffic that much more so it's
that much more enticing for attackers to
use these Cloud applications as a medium
for C2
so what we are refer to as C2 is
actually categorized in miter attackers
also miter attack those of you that
maybe aren't familiar with it is a
framework for categorizing the tactics
and techniques that you see
um that attackers are performing in the
wild
C2 is categorized as technique 1102 or
abusing web services for command and
control and it's broken down into three
sub techniques the first sub technique
is bi-directional communication and this
is really what we're going to focus in
for this talk right it's where the
attacker is sending commands to and
receiving output from a compromise
system over a cloud application so both
the forward and the reverse
communication is happening over com over
a cloud application instance now while
we won't cover the other two however
it's important to mention them because I
know they exist because they are
important the second sub technique is
one-way communication this is where the
attacker will send commands to the
victim or the compromise system without
receiving any output back so it's just
the forward Direction this is
um if you can think of it as another
level of adding stealth from the
attacker's point of view you know they
want to blend in and you know lie under
the radar that much more
the third sub technique is dead drop
resolvers
um for those of you maybe that are
familiar with like spy movies and
Espionage right you know what the
concept of a dead drop is so you can
think of a dead drop resolver as a
digital debt drop right this is where
the attackers abusing the Cloud app to
host information that point to
additional C2 infrastructure so the
communication doesn't actually occur
over a cloud application but the end
point of where that communication should
occur to or should
communicate to is reaching out is is
hosted on a Cloud app so here you can
see a YouTube comment right this is an
instance of a dead drop resolver where
the attacker has left a message that
says my keyboard doesn't work some
gibberish but then at the end of the
second line is a b64 encoded endpoint
that the compromise system will pull
down decode and then reach out to for
additional commands
so that's kind of a quick introduction
of what cloud community control is what
we you know we say cloud C2 now let's
talk about how thick how often is this
happening in the wild right what are
attackers doing how are they abusing
these Cloud applications
so here in this slide it's a little bit
of a busy slide but what we wanted to
show is the malware samples and the
cloud applications they've abused for
commanded control so we can see
boxcar Nimble Mamba and crutch of abuse
Dropbox graphite and blue light have
abuse OneDrive a-clip has a b slack
we've seen GitHub abuse Google Drive
abuse Twitter abuse Tumblr Blogspot
Google Docs Google script paste and one
Hub telegram right and this is a select
list the list goes on a much more
detailed list can be found on miter's
page right there's a
there's so much variety here and so much
application so many applications that
have been abused that we really want to
have you guys take away from this slide
is that no Cloud app is immune to this
attackers have abused Cloud apps or have
a bees the Cloud app or they are going
to abuse the Cloud app right it's it's
either happened or it's going to happen
right they're they're kind of uh
diversifying and kind of getting depth
that's what we really want to show here
so in the previous side we kind of
showed the the instances of of malware
and the cloud applications they're
abusing what we wanted to show in this
slide is how we could um can we get some
aggregate insights from these uh from
these from these instances so we looked
at our 23 known and reported instances
of cloud community control over a
two-year period from April 2020 to April
and these are just new and reported
instances right so there's like a lot
more that are not known or that have not
been reported but if we just look at the
ones that are known and reported we can
see we can we can
get some insights one of the insights is
which Cloud applications do these
attackers prefer you can if we take a
look at that chart we can see that um
Dropbox is by far the most preferred app
but eight instances of the 23 OneDrive
is a second at five and then Google
drive four instances and then and then
after that you have telegram at two and
then slack Google Docs Google sites
glitch GitHub Gmail Cloud film Cloud
front all at one instance
so these attackers are kind of
preferring these top three Cloud apps uh
the most you know Dropbox OneDrive in
Google Drive in this preference is even
more apparent if we go ahead and
categorize these Cloud applications
based on the services they provide to
their users so if we categorize uh
Dropbox Google Drive and OneDrive as
cloud storage because they're cloud
storage applications
we can see that
cloud storage app is by far the most
preferred by these attackers right at 17
instances of the 23 then you have uh not
so very close second social
collaboration and CDN maps at two
instances each web design platform as a
service development to the Webmail all
one instance each right so when we see a
chart like this when we see that cloud
storage is by far the most preferred app
it's 17 instances of the 23 we ask
ourselves why is why is this the case
right why why are these Cloud apps
referred
um this way and while we can't really
know the answer until we sit down with
these attackers and Survey them and ask
them why they made the decisions what we
can do is infer
and further reasoning based on the
actions we took in the cloud
applications so we we see that there we
came across three reasons that might
likely explain what's happening firstly
how easy is it to get set up in Cloud
applications right these these Cloud
apps make it super simple to get set up
three to five minutes and you have a
fresh account you're ready to go right
secondly how popular in ubiquitous are
these Cloud applications right if you're
trying to uh everyone has a Google Drive
account right everyone has a Gmail
account if you're on a compromised
system and you're trying to blend in
with to the existing traffic you have a
better chance of doing that if you're
targeting one of these Cloud
applications
or sorry if you're if you're using one
of these Cloud applications right
thirdly and this is a trickier one is
how easily does it integrate to the
existing workflow right we know that
attackers are lazy and they're going to
choose the easiest way to get to the to
get to the goal right that's where
they're the attackers
but when we take a traditional C2 type
of setup that's been around for a while
and how how does that work they'll take
the data they'll encrypt it and encode
it this is um malware seeing Planet
victim right it'll take the data encrypt
it and code it and they'll HTTP post it
to their server
okay well if they wanted to use a cloud
storage app what would have to change
they'll take that data encrypt it encode
it write it to a file and upload it
that's three to two to three lines of
code that needs to change that's not
that much at all right versus you look
at an application like slack maybe what
would they have to do they would have to
take that information create a slack
Channel post it reply you know post it
as a message reply to that message
delete that message right it gets a
little bit more complicated and we've
seen attackers do this as well
but we also see uh we also tend to see
these attackers kind of choose the
easiest way to get to their goal right
and that's that's kind of why uh we
believe cloud storage app is the most
preferred
next what we so we looked at the
categories and which categories the most
preferred but what we also wanted to
look at is what features in each
category are abused right
so when we look at cloud storage apps
like Dropbox and OneDrive we've seen
uploading files downloading files
deleting files with social apps like
telegram we've seen bot usage right
you've seen reading messages writing
messages with collaboration apps like
slack we've seen creating channels
reading messages writing messages
replying to messages
CDN apps like cloudfront we've seen
proxy traffic via CDN Network web design
apps like Google sites you've seen
dga-like algorithms to pass data to
different URL every day platform as a
service apps like glitch we've seen
creating custom applications and then
uploading files to those custom apps
development tool apps like GitHub we've
seen creating repositories adding commit
deleting commits right Webmail apps like
Gmail you see the writing draft emails
adding attachments right so the reason
we have this table here is you can see
that these attackers aren't taking their
existing
methodology and kind of shoving it into
the Cloud app no they're actually
leveraging the features in the cloud
application to kind of make their
offensive workflow better right they're
using channels in slack they're using
repositories in GitHub and they're kind
of reaping the benefits of using these
Cloud applications as well
foreign
so
we act let's talk about what we covered
so we talked about what cloud C2 was
right we defined what cloud C2 is and
then we looked at some trends that are
happening in the wild with regards to
Cloud Community Control now we want to
do is take a closer look and see how we
can simulate this in our Network so that
we could see if the controls we have can
identify this tactic being used
we're primarily going to use three tools
to do this Empire C3 and Covenant and
we'll cover what those are in just a
second
we're going to focus in our two
applications here Dropbox and GitHub so
Dropbox is a representative for cloud
storage and GitHub as a representative
for
um development tools and for each of
these apps what we'll do is we'll talk
about what is the Cloud app meant to do
why would an attacker want to use this
Cloud app or abuse This Cloud
application we'll go over a real world
example of abuse of this Cloud app and
then for the bulk of it we're going to
go through a detailed walkthrough of how
you can simulate this in red team
engagement and then finally we'll
briefly take a look of how this Cloud
application is being abused
so that we can um
kind of see what's happening under the
hood right
so the tools we're going to use are
Empire Covenant and custom Commander
controller C3 Empire is a Powershell and
Python 3 post exploitation framework
it's open source and maintained by PC
security it's a Unix based so if you're
kind of a a Linux shop maybe you want to
use that tool Covenant on the other hand
is a collaborative.net C2 framework
it's also open source and it's Windows
based so if your windows shop maybe you
want to prefer that one
um C3 on the other hand are custom
command and control isn't um it's a
little bit different from Empire and
Covenant while these other tools kind of
focus on the command execution and
interpretation portion C3 kind of
focuses on the medium the command is
going through so the definition is it's
a framework for rapid prototyping of
custom C2 channels so it lets you kind
of quickly get set up with new uh
committed control channels that you want
to use and it provides integration with
tools like Cobalt strike and Covenant so
that you can kind of offload that
command interpretation portion off to
them to develop their maintained by
f-secure labs they are you know great
all of these tools are very well
maintained they're really a blast to
work with so if you have you know some
time and you're trying to learn a new
tool I highly recommend you take a look
at these
so first let's take a closer look into a
Dropbox so Dropbox is a very popular
cloud storage application and since it's
a cloud storage application right it
tends to be abused by uploading
downloading and deleting encrypted and
encoded files it has a highly flexible
app development interface and it's very
easy to get set up in Dropbox it also
exists as an Enterprise and a personal
cloud and this kind of entices attackers
that much more to use it since you know
the corporation they're targeting or the
company they're targeting might be you
you know an Enterprise level client of
the of Dropbox already
so let's go over a real world abuse of
Dropbox so uh threat actor by the name
of mole rats was founded abusing Dropbox
for Community Control earlier this year
in January this threat actor is known
for being stealthy and they've
previously used this tactic of abusing
Cloud apps what's really interesting
here is that they actually used multiple
accounts in this exploitation workflow
on this uh offensive flow right and we
can kind of see this flow along the
right uh malicious Office document gets
downloaded by victim executes some
Powershell code this Powershell code
download and execute the dot net
backdoor this backdoor talks to the
attacker communicates to the attacker
via these Dropbox instances right and
the attacker kind of segmented or
segregated these
um Cloud applications based on their
responsibility so you had one drop one
dropbox instances just for C2 another
Dropbox is just for file infiltration
Etc right so you can kind of see that
they were separating these
responsibilities out based on the based
on the account so if one gets burned
they can still talk through the
compromised machines
so how can we simulate this in our
Network right where you can do this
using tools like Dropbox C2 C3 or Empire
for us we're going to use Empire below
but that's somewhat arbitrary you can
really use any of the tools and achieve
the same um same result
we're going to follow a four-step
process to do this we are going to first
create an attacker control Dropbox
account then we're going to go ahead and
set up an Empire server an Empire
listener with an access token from the
Dropbox account so we're going to
connect to the Empire server with the
Dropbox account and then thirdly we're
going to generate a malicious payload
from Empire and deliver it directly to
the victim kind of simulate a compromise
and then once we have a victim the
attacker communicating by the Dropbox
account we're going to interact with the
compromise device by tunneling commands
through Dropbox so
um let's get started
so firstly we're going to go ahead and
create the attacker control Dropbox
account and generate an access token
here we've signed up for Dropbox and we
can go ahead and create a new app on the
platform we're going to give it sculpt
access we're going to say uh you know
you want full access to to Dropbox or to
the Dropbox accounts rather we're going
to give it Empire C2 and then give it
you know full read and write access one
thing that's not captured in the screen
cap below is there's a place where you
can download these you can copy the
access token it's not shown on the
screen cap but we've grabbed that access
token as well
and also you can kind of see a little
Legend on the top right that shows you
where we are in the attack flow so you
can kind of see
um
right now we're in the Dropbox portion
right that's what we're setting up
once we set that up we're going to go
ahead and set up an Empire server an
Empire listener with these with this
access token so we have a Linux machine
here where we've installed Empire we're
going to set up Dropbox and give it that
API token if uh you know pass it the API
token and everything's gone well we can
type in the execute command and we
should see that the listener Dropbox has
successfully started so we've connected
this Dropbox sorry this Empire server
this Empire listener with the Dropbox
account
so what does this do
um behind the scenes right so this is
actually going to go into the uh Dropbox
account and create a folder here it's
new Empire that's the default we didn't
really change it but you can change that
to whatever
um you know you feel like is appropriate
here we've uh it's created an Empire
folder that has three subfolders results
staging and taskings and this is really
kind of
um laying the groundwork or the
foundation for that communication leader
so that that you know the compromise
system can
um reach out to the attacker and the
attacker to the compromise system over
this uh over these folders or over this
application that's been set up
so now that we have the Dropbox account
connected to the Empire server and
that's you know fully functional and
running
um what we're going to do is we're going
to generate a malicious payload and
deliver it directly to the victim to
kind of simulate a compromise normally
in a red team engagement or maybe a pen
test assessment what you'd follow is or
what would typically happen is you'd
have a phishing campaign that you
download you know malicious document or
a malicious link file that then would
download this as an XT payload we're
kind of skipping all of that here just
for the sake of brevity we're just going
to copy this payload over and kind of
simulate what you know compromise that
has happened right
so we're going to use the Stager module
in Empire we are going to set the
listener to Dropbox and generate uh you
know that payload as a Windows batch
file uh we're going to name it
launcher.bet we're going to copy that to
the victim and we're going to execute
that once we execute that we should see
a Powershell process start up and this
Powershell process is going to fold back
home to the attacker and register what's
called an agent right so this agent is
going to have you know agent name it's
going to have the language information
about the AP address the username that's
running out as the process name process
ID the delay the last time we've seen
and most importantly the medium it's
communicating through which is uh
Dropbox in this case
so we have
um once you set all that up we can
interact with the compromise device we
have a quick video here see if this will
uh play for us
okay cool
so here we can see um
so what we have is we have the victim
machine set up and we've copied this uh
batch file or this Windows batch file
over to the victim machine we've named
it launcher.bet and we're going to go
ahead and execute that on the victim and
see what happens
so once you execute that we should see
two Powershell processes have spun up
right and we go to the attacker screen
what we see is uh
this agent will check in right and
they'll have a unique agent name
since this is a multi-stage deployment
it does take a while for the agent to
get uh fully set up so if we kind of
list it out it's still not kind of
completely set up yet just give it one
or two more seconds you can see that
um
we can see it's now fully set up we have
all the same details as before you know
the agent name the language IP username
process name process ID the delay last
time we've seen in the medium right The
Listener so we're going to go ahead and
interact with that agent we're going to
type two commands we want to see
um
we're going to see who we are in the
list of the processes one thing to note
here is that the victim operates on a
polling architecture
which means that it reaches
um out to the Dropbox folder to look for
new convenience at a specified interval
this interval is
um you know specified in this delay
column here so here at 60 seconds so in
um
so this means it's going to check
commands or the victim's going to check
community in the Dropbox folder for 60
seconds this is important to note
because if you set this to know for once
a day you might not see the result of
the command right away
so here we just have to wait a little
bit until the agent checks in but if we
look at the Dropbox account in the
meantime what we see is how this
communication is happening right you see
that the attacker is going to upload
these text files
the victim is going to download them
delete them and then upload the results
of uh these operations as different text
files right and then the attacker is
going to pull that down and then Parson
uh show the results in that in that
console
and it's also the agent names kind of
lines up to the the name of the text
file in this case
all right well that kind of happened
quickly but you can kind of see do we
list of the processes that just came up
right you see the process uh name the
process ID the architecture the username
it's running ads and some some memory
information right
so now what we want to do is if we go
back to the victim
um what we want to look at is so this is
an application called Fiddler maybe
those of you that aren't familiar with
Fiddler Fiddler is a web proxy that we
have running on the victim machine
that'll show us the processes and the
web connections that's originating from
these processes right
so here we can see that this Powershell
process is reaching out to
dropboxapi.com and it's you know
Gathering some information
on
um you know these these uh encrypted
encoded text files and if we try to see
what the contents look like at one of
the
requests we're trying to download these
files you can see that it's not legible
right it's it's
completely gibberish at this at this
level
awesome
so what did we just see right we saw how
this interaction is happening between
the compromise device and the the
attacker's machine right this
interaction is happening by uploading
and downloading these um encrypted task
files you can see on the left side of
our screen these text files if you try
to download it open one of them you can
see that there's really if they're not
legible at all it's encrypted and if we
take a look at the code we can see that
the the portion of the code that's
actually doing this is using an advanced
encryption standard algorithm to kind of
encrypt that
um that data that's going back and forth
so let's summarize what we just talked
about right so Dropbox is a cloud
storage app that's similar to you know
OneDrive and Google Drive it's abused by
uploading downloading and deleting these
encrypted files if you want to simulate
a threat actor using this technique you
can do that using tools like Dropbox C2
C3 and Empire
and one thing to note here is depending
on maybe the sophistication level you're
trying to model you can you can use
these tools differently so if you're
trying to model a unsophisticated threat
actor a threat actor of low
sophistication you can use the default
configurations the tool like Empire or
C3
if you're in a Model A moderately
sophisticated threat actor you could do
that easy you know you could take these
tools and comp customize their
configurations a little bit so that you
can kind of fly under the radar a little
bit better
and if you want to model a highly
sophisticated threat actor you know the
kind of attacker that we've seen
targeted attacks in the real world what
you might do is use multiple accounts
with segregated responsibilities so that
the you know the data transfers
separated amongst them right you might
also really tune your traffic to match
what's happening in the network so if
you hop onto victim Network and you see
that there is one person that uses
Dropbox a lot and you know that person's
in HR or whatever maybe you want to use
that person's machine to kind of tunnel
your commands outside of the outside of
the network so it kind of Blends into
that traffic a little bit better right
cool
so now let's take a closer look into uh
GitHub abuse right we're going to follow
a similar structure here as well
um GitHub maybe those of you aren't
familiar is a code development platform
it's primarily a source code repository
platform but it's grown to be much more
than that at this point and since it's
really a source code repository platform
it does tend to be abused by creating
repositories and adding commits
similar to Dropbox it also has a very
flexible application development
interface that lets you kind of quickly
get set up and get going and kind of use
this app as as you might need right
if you take a look at a real world abuse
of this app when we saw uh Lazarus aptr
very sophisticated North Korean apt it's
very famous
um leverage GitHub for C2 earlier this
year so the attack flow it's very
similar to what we're seeing at that
given time uh malicious Office document
gets downloaded it you know does a bunch
of other malicious processes stuff right
it spins up folders it does some
malicious link stuff malicious dll stuff
but also communicates
um out to the attacker via a GitHub
repository right and what it does it
retrieves the files present in the image
directory of a GitHub repo and then it
grabs the commands from those files
executes the command from those files
and uploads the command results uh the
command results are committed to the
repo Under The Meta files directory
where the file name denotes the time at
which it was executed so it kind of
really gets its money's worth from from
the GitHub account it has set up
so if you wanted to simulate this how
would you go about doing that you we did
this using
um C3 and Covenant and we followed the
steps that were outlined by f-secure
great set of steps we kind of slimmed
them down and kind of summarized them to
that same four-step flow we followed for
Dropbox
um these two these four steps are
firstly we're going to sign up for this
GitHub account and we're going to create
this access token or create a personal
token once we have that we're going to
set up C3 and Covenant with a GitHub
channel right and we're going to use the
steps again outlined but if security
steps are kind of much more detailed
right there like hole in this repo set
it up this way past these configuration
framers Etc right we're gonna follow
those steps instead of C3 and Covenant
once we have those two set up we're
going to generate a malicious
um we're going to generate a malicious
payload that contains this GitHub token
and we're gonna
um run this on the victim machine to
simulate a compromise
once we have uh simulated this
compromise we're going to interact with
the compromise device by tunneling
commands through GitHub and you kind of
see this in the attack flow the chart at
the bottom right the C3 server the
Gateway is going to upload those
commands to GitHub
the malicious process or the relay
that's running on the victim server it's
going to pull those commands down
execute them upload those task results
to GitHub then the Gateway is going to
pull down those task results parse them
and and show them on the console
so let's follow the first step and sign
up for GitHub account sorry so we'll
sign up for a GitHub account we go ahead
and create a personal token we're going
to name it C3 and we are going to give
it full access to this account right
once we have that GitHub account fully
set up we are going to uh set up C3 and
Covenant with um
we're going to set up C3 and Covenant
with a GitHub Channel using these steps
right the steps that were we referred to
earlier that were outlined by a f-secure
one thing to note here is that C3 and
Covenant are you know two separate
repositories that are being contained at
different pieces so if you um
if you set these up together uh we found
that there might be some compatibility
um gotchas we so to solve that we found
that the best commit hash is as that
commit ash from covenant that works uh
pretty well for all our use cases that
we mentioned here right but we're going
to set up C3 and then we are going to go
ahead and generate that um once we set
up the Gateway we're going to do is
set up the GitHub Channel as as that
medium and if we have that set up we can
see that on the screen on the bottom
right that's what it should look like
right you have the Gateway which is the
C3 service connected to the channel
so what does this do right similar to
how we saw with um
Dropbox and the Empire folder being
created in Dropbox in GitHub this is
going to go ahead and create a
repository to be used for the C2 channel
in the GitHub account right so this
repository is named the e5j you can kind
of see that it resembles any GitHub
repository right it has a readme etc
right
so we're kind of laying that groundwork
here similar to how we did with the
Dropbox account
so once we've set up the GitHub account
and it's communicated to
connected to the C3 Gateway we can go
ahead and generate the malicious payload
it'll contain that GitHub token and
we're going to download that and run it
on the victim machine so here
um
C3 has this really amazing interactive
UI that we can go ahead and create and
download what we call a relay so the
relay is kind of that malicious payload
we're going to download that relay copy
it over to the victim machine again
we're going to skip all those other
important steps for the sake of brevity
right and we're going to run it as admin
on the victim machine
so what this does once you run it on the
victim machine it's going to spin up a
process that's going to phone back home
through GitHub and it's going to like
kind of set up that um the connection
that we need to kind of tunnel commands
back and forth once we have this set up
we can type commands like who am I uh
that'll tell us who we are and then get
the current directory which is going to
give us details around uh where where we
are in the in the machine in the file
system right so how this kind of flows
you can kind of see on the right side
the Gateway or the you know the C3
server is going to send those commands
through the channel so the channel is
like those two squares in the middle
um the purple and the black square and
then the victim on the far side is going
to pull those commands down execute them
and then upload the results back through
the channel through GitHub right so both
the victim and the C3 Gateway they're
both on internal networks so they don't
communicate to each other outside of
GitHub at all right
so we said that the abused GitHub or the
communicate via GitHub but how exactly
is this happening
from the GitHub side right like what
what are the steps it's actually
following well it's very similar to
Dropbox in that there are encrypted and
encoded files but in this case they're
going to get added to a local repository
that's going to get pushed up into
remote into the remote
um
the remote copyright and get in GitHub
so you see the attacker commits these
files to the repo then the victim is
going to download and delete these files
and then push those changes up right and
the victim is going to execute those
commands again upload the results from
those tasks then the attacker is going
to pull those down and delete them and
then they're going to repeat all these
steps for every command that that
happens right so that's how that
communication is happening via uh via
GitHub
so let's summarize what we just talked
about we saw that GitHub is a code
development app a source code repository
app that to bees by adding commits that
contain these encrypted and encoded
files if you wanted to simulate the
threat actor using this technique you
could do that using tools like C3 and
Covenant
and depending on the sophistication
level here as well you might use these
uh tools differently so if you want to
model a low sophisticated ER attack with
low sophistication or unsophisticated
they're actually you just use the
default configurations using a tool like
Empire C3 and see uh See if your
controls can pick that up if you want to
Model A moderately sophisticated threat
actor you can customize those
configurations a little bit and if you
want to model a highly sophisticated
threat actor a targeted attack in the
real world then you might go ahead and
really tune the existing traffic to
match what's in the network so maybe
tunnel your commands through
the development department instead of
the you know HR department that way the
likelihood of them using uh GitHub is
more right there's a higher likelihood
so while we didn't mention these other
tools because we don't see them as much
they're also very important to know
um you know they know they exist right
is your outlook C2 abuses Outlook email
address for C2
um gc2 abuses Google sheet and Google
Drives to execute command on its victims
so the commands are actually written as
in the cells in the Google Sheets and
then call it a C2 abuses Outlook won't
Nook on one note in Microsoft teams for
C2 so these other tools maybe the the
corporate corporate system you're
targeting uses these other tools uh uses
these other Cloud applications that you
want to kind of blend in with maybe you
want to use these other tools as well
so let's talk about let's take a step
back and kind of talk about what we
covered We Begin by talking about what
cloud C2 was we defined Cloud C2 and we
kind of saw some standardizations that
exist in in the industry today then we
went ahead and looked at some trends
that exist in the wild right what are
attackers doing is this even really
happening you try to answer those
questions right then we finished talking
about how we can set this up in our
internal Network so that we can simulate
the threat actor using this tool so that
we can check our controls and test our
controls and see where the gaps are say
we did identify a gap what defenses do
we need to put in place right first of
all why don't the existing security
controls pick this up right it's hard to
detect
here we have a screen cap of Fiddler
running so Fiddler is that web proxy
application that runs on the victim that
we saw earlier
in
while while this was running on the
victim machine we also had the malicious
relay that was connecting to C3 and we
also had the GitHub desktop application
running right and we just looked at the
you know the endpoints these URLs that
these applications were reaching out to
and here you can see the the two
processes and in the endpoints right so
firstly both the malicious and benign
traffic right the benign and Cloud C2
traffic is going to the same domain
api.github.com
this domain is a valid cloud provider
domain it's github's domain and the
traffic to this domain is encrypted
using the cloud provider certificate
that could that could would otherwise
right this is why this is challenging
because these server these IP addresses
associated with API github.com the
hostname api.github.com you can't put
that into a signature feed into threat
intelligence feed because there's just
so much benign traffic going there if
you can't block this out right so you
need other methods to detect this
particular technique
so what can what can we do to detect
this firstly
um identify and block known malware I
know this is silly to say but don't even
let it get to the Cloud C2 or the C2
stage
um if you can because once it gets to
the C2 stage it's going to be uh pretty
challenging to detect so if you can
block this earlier on
um definitely try and do that secondly
um oh well this shut down on me
sorry about that you have to kind of
move around
um
okay secondly if you want to um
if you don't see any Court any use for
uh certain Cloud application in
in your corporate environment you know
disallow communication to that
non-corporate cloud application maybe if
you can't disallow all communication
maybe what you can do is
um
uh monitor usages of that cloud
application so you can investigate what
happens right thirdly
um adequate logging and monitoring it's
so important to make sure you see all
the endpoints your processes are the
processes on your networks are reaching
out to and this is an oauth top 10 issue
right make sure you have
um you know adequate logging and
monitoring in place
fourthly uh regular beaconing Behavior
maybe this isn't
um
necessarily malicious but if you see a
certain process beaconing back out at a
certain interval that should be
something you um you'd want to
investigate a little bit more
um unsigned application making network
connection should be a big giveaway so
if you see that happening in your
corporate environment make sure that you
kind of block that it should not be a
common use case right make sure like you
know when that happens user agents that
are associated with known malware so the
Empire user agents kind of it's a little
bit static and it doesn't there aren't a
lot of benign users that use that uh too
often so if you see that make sure you
kind of block that out
the last two are actually um we got from
f-secure's blogs and they're really
they're really good detection so we
wanted to note them here as well
um f-secure monitored all of um the
processes and the network connections
from these processes across time and the
across time the model the packets that
were transferred outside of the
corporate Network and you see when an
endpoint is compromised that traffic at
that instance of time is going to kind
of stand doubt so make sure and this is
kind of at the bottom right right so the
screen cap at the bottom right you can
kind of see that this compromise
endpoint kind of stands out and you want
to use that to identify
um endpoints that might be potentially
compromised
lastly um the C2 stage is followed by
um
actions on objectives which is the last
stage in the Cyber kill chain this stage
is
um
if you're maybe not able to identify the
C2 stage because the attacker is low and
slow and you really it's beginning out
once a week and you can't identify it
usually
um action on objective stage is going to
require them to it's typically data
exfiltration right and they're going to
do it over the C2 channel so if you see
large amounts of data moving off your
corporate Network to an application that
you don't see any corporate use for that
should warrant you know a lot of alarms
going off and you should kind of dig
into that a little bit more
so let's go all the way back and kind of
talk about those four key points we
started with
what is cloud C2 we defined Cloud C2 as
command and control via Cloud
application we saw that um
we saw a few uh definitions and a few
categorizations that exist in the
industry today and then we went over and
talked about which Cloud applications
are abused with C2 and we saw a vast
majority of them can be abused and we
saw some Trends and some insights and we
even categorized these apps and saw some
features that are abused in each
category
then we went over how you can simulate
this in your network and we went over
two example applications Dropbox and
GitHub and we saw we can do this with
four steps when using a tool tools like
Empire C3 and Covenant and then lastly
we talked about what defenses can be put
in place and we saw there's numerous
controls that we can put in place to
identify and detect quality to both at
the endpoint at the network level right
and we can use these uh defenses to kind
of help our security posture from a
defender's standpoint
awesome so that brings us to the end of
the talk and I have a few more minutes
to go but uh and I'll be happy to start
taking questions but in case uh kind of
ran out my Twitter handle is at dog Lulu
and my LinkedIn is
um D Mula geta we have a bunch of
research on cloud application abuses on
our blog so feel free to kind of follow
us there or
um if you just really want to talk
anything cyber security I'm always open
to having uh you know these discussions
please reach out to me I'll be happy to
kind of answer any questions you have
borrowing that you know thank you very
much for attending this talk and if you
have any questions I'll be happy to
start taking them now thank you thank
you very much like Mario it was great
presentation so much interesting content
and thank you very much for sharing it
uh so I wanted to ask the first question
that I have here are there any patterns
you have noticed with Cloud applications
features and abuse frequency
yeah that's a really good question yeah
so
um this is kind of going back to that um
slide where we saw the
maybe I can go back really quick
yeah so here
um we have seen some patterns right
these these uh attackers are kind of
preferring uh certain categories of
cloud applications a little bit more and
they're attacking them at a higher
frequency and these
um the reason for these cloud storage
applications we kind of went over a few
reasons that might be the case you know
they're easy to get get set up and get
going a lot of people use them so
they're very easy to kind of blend
um into and then lastly they're they
integrate really so the integratability
factor is important to integrate really
well into the existing flow they have so
attackers are kind of more enticed to
use these category of cop of
applications more in the in their
attacker flow but we um we will see in
the near future and as time progresses
that a lot of these other other
categories are also going to start
seeing some traffic as well
thank you very much great thank you and
the second question this is not
something that cloud providers should
deal with is it why uh is this something
I as a Defender have to worry about
yeah that's a that's a really good
question right um
if let me answer that in two parts so
firstly the cloud providers are doing
you know what they can do to detect this
there's a lot of instances where they
have abuse portals and everything where
if you identify abuse of the particular
Cloud app you can kind of reach out and
let the provider know they'll bring it
down they have some
processes and police automation please
kind of identify abusing of their
platform
um but you have to imagine what it looks
like from their angle right if you go
back to the Dropbox example the attacker
is really uploading a file downloading a
file deleting a file from the Dropbox
point of view there's really not much
you can do there that that's that's
exactly what you want the application to
be used for it's only when uh you know
someone says this is using this
application is being used to move data
off my system that that becomes a
problem right so there's a visibility uh
problem there that it's it's difficult
for the cloud provider to see especially
in targeted attacks right so this is why
as a Defender we kind of went over that
list of defenses that might help you
identify the sort of traffic in your um
in your environment
yep
thank you very much for your answers uh
is anything else you would like to share
is there any communities that people may
uh join to get more information
yeah absolutely so
accidentally touched on the link
so I uh I have this slide here
so um these are my uh these are this is
my information that's my Twitter handle
my LinkedIn those are the two best
places kind of get additional
information on this so if you uh kind of
reach back reach out to me and get um
I don't think we're going to give these
slide decks out but if you reach out to
me I'll personally send these slide
decks over to you so that you can have
the links and the references Etc uh and
also if you go to the my research team
is the netscope threat lab research
teams we have a Blog where we talk about
all this stuff on a weekly basis so we
have a bunch of additional not just
YouTube or additional Cloud application
abuse as well so if you want the latest
and greatest in that space that's uh you
know that's the best place to reach out
to it's a great question so Lana thank
you
it was so good it was a very interesting
presentation I am sure that people will
reach out to you and will ask more
questions
thank you thank you very much and
thank you for being the active part and
speaker in this conference thank you
very much for having me
appreciate it I'll stop sharing now and
I'll um give that a throw back to you
thanks