it is 9 A.M
um my time it's almost certainly beer
o'clock your time so I will keep this
nice and short
um thank you for joining us at the last
keynote at the OAS Global appsec EU
virtual next year
um the global appsec virtual will no
longer be a virtual it'll be an
in-person event at Dublin in February
next year so please do come along RSVP
in your calendars today we look forward
to seeing you there and I can't honestly
can't say how excited I am to be able to
finally be able to go to Ireland so
please do
come to the in-person event next year
along those lines we have a virtual
Global appsec Asia Pacific it actually
has a native Japanese track as well as
English tracks we also have the cfp and
CFT are extended at the moment so if you
want to actually present at that
particular conference please um have a
look at our website and see how you can
get going
in November we're actually going to get
back to in-person events yay so we're
looking forward to meeting everybody
again at San Francisco we will try our
very hardest to make sure that there's
many of the Keynotes and primary tracks
will be
um
let me just turn this out down there
um we'll be broadcast for a hybrid but
in person is where to go we look forward
to seeing everyone there that's in early
November
lastly we need to actually review and
renew our bylaws and to do so requires
all of the members to vote and in fact
we need 50 of you
so 3 000 out of six thousand to vote for
the new bylaws we've never had more than
1100 people vote before so that's going
to be excitement please keep an eye on
your email as the vote goes through for
the bylaws please vote it's really
important that we can replace them and
we actually get your settings into the
bylaws and we can keep them that way for
many years to come
and I'm now pleased to announce Dr Alan
Shulman pelik she's the managing
director of cloud cyber security and
Ernst Young and the Americas
she's going to be talking to us today
about Cloud attack service management
typically cloud and infrastructure
platform teams are separate and
with the way that the world is going the
infrastructure side of cloud
implementations is infrastructure is
code so we should be bringing them
together and that's what this talk is
going to be about
Dr Adam Alex Shulman peleg is the
managing director of the cloud cyber
security Consulting Services events and
young she helps multiple clients secure
their public clouds and contain
Technologies addressing the involved
risk cyber security and regulatory
requirements in her previous role she
was the director of cloud security at
Citibank
and prior to that she was at IBM
research
she holds Decades of technological
leadership and holds a PhD in MSC and
BSC in computer science she holds
multiple patents and has more than 36 30
scientific Publications with thousands
of citations I can only imagine your H
score
mine was accidental I'm sure yours is
not accidental at all
and with that he here you go thank you
take it away
thank you Andrew and thank you everyone
for joining good afternoon in Europe
good morning in the US I'm super excited
to close this week of amazing what was
talks and sessions with this wonderful
topic of cloud attack surface management
and today we'll talk about how to manage
the attack vectors that we're seeing in
the cloud and how they are changing our
cyber security posture posture and
practices and what Caesars should be
doing to protect the organizations
against these new attack factors
first let me start with the disclaimer
that everything that I will be
presenting is based on my 14 years of
experience in Cloud security and not
necessarily representative use of
everyone in my organization
during the talk we'll go through the
following first of all start with what
are Cloud attack vectors why cloud is
different from what we know in our
traditional environments then we'll take
several examples and we'll analyze
deeper what are the attack factors who
is responsible for them and what are the
techniques that we are seeing from the
application security standpoint which
means how can someone exploit these
environments then we'll go to protection
and prevention what should we be doing
how can we mitigate these risks what
organizations should be doing to provide
the holistic view over this attack
surface
and then our last topic will be the
cease of you
what should ciso be doing how can Cecil
reduce the risk
um across all the environments but from
the application and Cloud security
standpoints
so let's start with some definitions
what is attack surface a type surface is
defined as a set of points on the
boundary of a software system its
elements or environments when an
attacker can try to enter affected or
extract data
in simple words what are the entry
points for an attacker to exploit our
system
then what do we mean when we're saying
when analyzing the attack surface it is
actually an assessment it's an
assessment of the exploitable
vulnerabilities or weaknesses that can
lead to a potential system compromise
foreign
cloud is different let's look at what we
had in our traditional environments
in our data centers we had
infrastructures and platforms that were
provisioned by dedicated skilled system
administrators these were responsible
for the provisioning of the firewalls
for the provisioning of the service
for the provisioning of platforms like
kubernetes
and then developed developers were
operating inside this well-established
perimeter protecting the applications
from lower level misconfigurations
they were operating safely without
managing any lower level dependencies or
infrastructures for example in our
traditional environments developers
cannot impact the configuration of
firewalls but in the cloud things are
different because Cloud native
applications are forcing the developers
to provision and manage multiple lower
level dependencies
let's maybe think why this is happening
because the entire promise of cloud is
to simplify the management the
infrastructures and platforms
so we're getting everything
transparently as a service just with one
API call but are we doing this API call
right
can we misconfigure it
so these are the new questions that
developers should be asking
and even more than that resources and
platforms are deployed now as code
and they are deployed over the public
internet
and there is no network perimeter to
protect from services misconfigurations
now let's analyze let's take some
examples and go deeper in what we can
see
yeah
let's first look at this from the layer
standpoint
and this is how we're managing this
today we are looking at layers we have
infrastructure as a service we have
platform as a service and we have the
applications which may be containerized
services or Cloud native each layer has
its own attack vectors
let's start with infrastructure when
provisioning the infrastructure there
are so many misconfigurations or
mistakes that people can make it's also
with firewalls that in the cloud and
people may misconfigure them but any
misconfiguration of identity and access
management instance instance metadata
service policies permissions anything
can be exploited
as an attack Vector to compromise the
entire system
and this is why wave Cloud security
posture management tools addressing
exactly this layer and this type of
attack
now let's look at the platform we have
platforms like kubernetes SQL Server
Jupiter lab and many more each platform
once again may be miscon misconfigured
so people who are provisioning this
should be aware of all the requirements
they should be provisioning them in the
secure way and we have dedicated tools
once again kubernetes posture management
and other products that are helping us
to prevent these misconfigurations and
manage this layer of our tax service
and then finally we have workloads we
have containerized applications or
serverless applications that operate the
platform and the infrastructure
and today we address we are looking at
them as applications so we'll do
application scaling at the Java level we
are not always looking at them
as they interact with the platform and
the infrastructure
so what is happening today they're being
scan phone a little bit from the
vulnerabilities they are scanned for
supply chain but today I would like to
focus on the interaction between all
these layers because our serverless
applications some are interacting with
the platform in the infrastructure they
need to provision buckets they need to
provision certain services that are
needed for this application to operate
and this is what we call Cloud native
because in Cloud native applications are
using and benefiting from the wonderful
services and the transparency of using
them in the cloud
but these are also the new risks that we
should be considering so today we'll
look at interaction between the layers
and let's start with who's responsible
for what
and let's look at the attack surface
from the standpoint on who is
responsible for this part of the attack
surface
how it is being managed today and how
can we do better by combining all these
roles responsibilities and layers
so most of you are familiar with what is
called the shared responsibility model
that was announced by cloud service
providers
in this model cloud service providers
are responsible for the security of the
cloud
well Cloud users are responsible for the
security in the cloud which means Cloud
users are managing the attack surface
from their side from how they are using
the cloud and cloud service providers
are managing the effect surface of what
can happen to the infrastructures
but let's review some of the examples
most of the cloud breaches today are
starting with some type of
misconfiguration exposed credentials
open buckets Network misconfigurations
public IP addresses improp
authentication authorization and of
course application vulnerabilities
so obviously users of the cloud should
be managing all of this but are they
influenced by other things as well let's
look at several examples so first there
is the supply chain these packages that
everyone is using application developers
are using them and Cloud providers are
using them one of the most if
unfortunately famous examples recently
was the log4j library this is the Java
library that was vulnerable and the
vulnerability is called log4j
when this became public in December
everyone became vulnerable because
everyone
was using this in the applications so
for the cloud users they had to quickly
fetch their part right where the
applications are using this library but
Cloud providers also had to patch this
very quickly and some of them for
example unfortunately if I applied
automated batches
uh that didn't go very well and actually
introduced new attack vectors like
container exploitation and privilege
escalation
so Cloud users at the same time and to
manage what their vulnerabilities as
well as with additional risks that cloud
providers added to the mix
and so obviously Cloud users need to
take all this into account when planning
their protection a tools environments
and layers for their Cloud applications
let me touch on an additional topic
and these are the CSD bugs and Witnesses
we don't call them vulnerabilities now
because these are misconfigurations that
may allow exploitation
but because these are not public
libraries we're not designing cdes to
them
some of the examples even in the Capital
One Bridge what causes is actually a
design issue
which allowed exploiting temporary
credentials for the metadata service
the cloud provider updated this and
release the new version
but actually the old one was still
available
for backwards compatibility
but we're still not calling this
vulnerability uh and there is no CB
number sign it is a design issue that
was resolved
but still Cloud users should be aware of
this because there are so many
organizations where developers are not
reading all the blogs about breaches and
they do not know that they need to
update applications to the new version
and there is no one driving for this and
our traditional vulnerability management
programs are now checking for this
let's look at some additional examples
of such bugs and Witnesses
and there are two Israeli cspn companies
that recently jointly each of them
separately but all together it boils
down to eight very significant Banks and
weaknesses that were discovered in the
infrastructures and platforms of the
cloud providers
and it is it and there was an excellent
collaboration so Cloud providers are
resolving all these issues but let's
just review them for us to better
understand the attack surface and what
should we be doing to better manage this
there are two we can actually Define two
categories of this uh newly discovered
weaknesses
first of all of them are breaking the
multi-tense isolation which means these
companies have demonstrated that the
exploitation code allowed going from
there a
account or their service
to the service account or date of
someone else
which means breaking the multi-tenant
isolation because Cloud providers should
be isolating and separating between the
data of the different Cloud users
but then there are two types of of these
exploitation techniques one allows
exploitation just for the specific
service which means if this is being
executed on the behalf of let's say one
user of a certain cloud service it
allows accessing the data of another
user but it is still limited to this
specific service
um so we call this cross-service day
program
but there is also another type that
actually allows going broader to any
service of any client so this is cross
account cross-service takeover which is
which was shown to be possible
um through exploitation of weaknesses in
deployment mechanisms or similar nature
because this is what allows
to go broader so once again these are
not uh real attacks uh this is just
researchers finding these weaknesses
reporting and resolving them
but what we're learning from this
exercise in a way that multi-tenant
isolation can be broken
this this is why we need to have several
layers of Defense
so that if something bad happens we can
still manage with the situation
and we also need to start treating these
design issues and weaknesses is
vulnerabilities because we need to
ensure that our application developers
are aware of them and they're improving
their code and addressing them and
they're always using the most recent
design the most recent version and they
are updating everything that the
application needs to actually consume
the solution the resolution of these
weaknesses as soon as possible
from the application security standpoint
let's look at the exploitation
techniques
oh no this is very similar to what is
typically published by a wasp
um
the most probably the most common
technique is server-side request forgery
where an attacker can make out arbitrary
web requests from a compromised server
to some other targets and this is what
allows actually cross-account
cross-service exploitation
and then extraction from environment
variables third party exploitation as
well because it was shown that actually
a there are many companies that are
unknowning they're just not aware of
this and when they're consuming such
services such services and requesting
certain access to Cloud environments and
they're just granting this access so the
these overprivileged SAS Services is an
is another attack Vector that we've seen
um but we're putting this in a category
of credentials because there's a
overprivileged roles or tokens or
exposed credentials that may be used to
attack the environment
then another
technique is a cloud deployment code
exploitation
but uh injection of code
for example through weak access controls
on repositories of buckets objects
actually storing the code itself for an
attacker can update the code and inject
malicious pieces
all the techniques as XML external
entity and this is these are the
techniques that we've seen both in
breaches and research projects showing
and demonstrating various effect
scenarios
and then obviously there are SQL
injections that can be done also via
functions
and no SQL injections because no SQL
databases may still be exploited
via techniques that are very similar in
nature to SQL injection techniques but
essentially getting the data through
these queries
um and remote account access takeover is
also something that we've seen repeating
throughout this demonstrations of attack
vectors or the bridges that were
published and we could analyze the data
so now let me summarize what we've seen
first we saw that cloud can be exploited
the application exploitation techniques
then we also know that cloud management
code is accessible via internet and
exposed application exploitations
so in a way the situation is
we have more risk than we had we had
before because the same application
exploitation techniques can now be
applied to infrastructures code and it
is over the Internet so overall the
risks in some cases are higher
and then we're coming to this conclusion
that application security processes and
approaches should be applied to Cloud
code and environments and this is what
we'll be talking about today
so let's move to the next topic what
should we be doing to protect our
environments to prevent all this from
happening because obviously new attack
vectors will be occurring all the time
and it may also be pause to explain that
we need to accept this
this is the nature of our modern
environments we do need cloud cloud is
not a question it's the reality of our
modern applications
it we need this to deliver business
value uh companies need us to build
their businesses so it's not a matter of
choice that's the reality we have the
cloud we have these effect vectors and
we need to to establish processes for
the solicit management and prevention of
Paris
so first of all defense syntax most
probably all we've heard this so many
times
still it is not always happening so
let's review this on the example Vlog
for Shell which was announced in
December
and suddenly everyone became vulnerable
so all the applications are vulnerable
the cloud provider itself is vulnerable
so everyone can be exploited through
just one issue
in a library that everyone is using
so many organizations were able to
quickly manage with this issue through
things like graph so even before they
managed to patch all the environments
what was their first solution let's just
block this let's let's prevent this from
being exploited through web application
firewalls
and and many of the providers were very
quick with supporting this and many
organizations were very very happy okay
at least we we have this additionally
protecting us and now we can remediate
uh the local social vulnerability
but still as you saw even some of the
issues
for example the cloud provider that did
the right thing automated the patching
but suddenly became vulnerable
allowing because of the mistake allowing
um a bigger the option of privilege
escalation then we need to present
prevent this as well we need to be ready
for this
what's the solution
we need to have both path and
segmentation so that if there is there
are some issues for example exploitation
through
uh breaking domestic tenancy of the
cloud provider this cross account
cross-service
um attack Vector that I have described
if we have segmentation it will prevent
the attacker from propagating further it
was scope and reduce the blast radius of
what may happen so that's another way to
mitigate reduce the risk and entitle the
situation
then additional tools cost-based
intrusion prevention and other Solutions
like runtime application self-protection
that can add additional layer of
protection and there are always new new
and emerging Technologies adding more
and more layers and it is important to
emphasize yes it is important to have
layers of Defense we cannot realize just
on one tool just on one provider and it
is this little approach that will help
us to manage with what we discussed
before
but then there is also Cloud native
because look at the cloud native system
as ecosystem in itself when applications
are using multiple services and it
mentioned containerized serverless so
this this mix of application and
underlying platform and services from
the cloud provider and we need to
properly manage and control this
so these are the three points that we've
seen as the most critical ones to
actually reduce the risk first use
policies code and have processes
to harm them all these environments put
Guardians and patterns helping other
application developers to be more secure
don't rely on just on application
developers give them these patterns and
give these guardrails that will protect
them from making mistakes and
misconfigurations and still be ready to
respond the Cyber response piece is very
critical what happens if if a certain
weakness bug or vulnerabilities being
exploited how should we respond into
this
so now let's go deeper into all these
aspects and we'll see some examples
but first let me also Define how we
should be looking at this let's think
think of ourselves as Caesars
we cannot just think about one weakness
or one but is this major problem because
we need to cover everything it is the
coverage it is the holistic View and the
metrics that will give us some
indication of our going to good are we
doing bad can we improve can we improve
our time and this is the goal of CSO
programs
traditionally with Cloud security
program and application security program
working together and they may remain
separate or maybe combined but let's
review the roles of both
so what application Security Programs
typically doing in in large
organizations first ensuring that there
are these gates to scan the applications
um static code analysis Dynamic code
analysis all the application security
best practices developer training of and
awareness they're also initiating threat
modeling for the most critical
applications pen testing and running
these programs for the detection and
resolution of vulnerabilities and of
course adding devsecops practices
for the application itself
adding all the application security
tools to the devops processes
now let's look at the cloud Security
Programs and what are they doing today
and the way they are augmenting
application Security Programs and they
have a very similar in nature typically
but instead of for example scanning the
job application they're scanning
infrastructures code that is managing
the cloud environments
the initiating threat modeling exercises
both on the cloud service provider
services and applications that are using
these services in the cloud
focusing on cloud native
attack scenarios and attack vectors that
we've been reviewing today initiating
pen testing and monitoring for
misconfigurations and then driving for a
solution
and of course doing this developer
training but Cloud native developer
training is slightly different from
traditional developer training so Cloud
Security Programs today are building an
exactly this what should developers know
in addition to what they know today
they need to learn how to secure the
operate cloud
when the application is using the
underlying Cloud platform platforms and
services what are the risks and what
should application developers be aware
of so all of these on the agenda of
cloud Security Programs
and these programs May remain separate
only be combined but there is a need to
cover for all of these aspects
let's review this graph actually shows
the life cycle of such a program
and let me explain this on the example
of a cloud security program
uh typically many systems are initiating
this please come and check how are we
doing what is Alpha Security posture
what is the amount of misconfigurations
vulnerabilities that we have in the
cloud and help us to analyze our attack
vectors
so when we're coming to to do this
assessments typically uh we're expanding
uh divisibility bring more tools or
adding more policies to get visibility
into the environments and then typically
we'll see more so you will see this what
you can see in this graph is the wire
access these are the findings so
typically if we initiate
um additional search additional tools
for visibility mapping of
misconfigurations we'll see more
but the secret is actually how to
resolve them and how to keep everything
green and secure over time
let me give you some examples
it in almost every case we can see that
for example instances are not properly
encrypted that's never a common mistake
of
application Developers
obviously the solution is not to go back
and change this manually for thousands
of instances the solution is go back and
remediate the deployment code
and this is the way to get to the screen
State actually resolving the issues
analyzing what's the root cause and then
going back to the code typically it's
about one or two lines of code that if
result will impact the entire
environment
but it is critical to do two things one
this root cause analysis and second
addressing all types of findings as I
mentioned we cannot look just as at
vulnerabilities with this assigned CVA
number and risk because there are just
so many misconfigurations there are bags
and weaknesses and they're also Opening
Our environments and they are also
putting us at risk
so this is why these three things of
cdes misconfigurations and then products
and weaknesses are so critical
sorry what should we be doing with this
what I've seen it is this combination of
visibility and addressing the root cause
and there is this balance because we
can't do just one of them we need to do
both and we need to do both in parallel
getting visibility seeing all these red
items getting to the root cause and
updating the code resolving them through
these preventative controls and
preventative guardrails and this is how
we're resolving this over time
what are the metrics for Success so let
me give just a few metrics of course the
amount of metrics that we should be
measuring is much higher but this is
just file remediation efforts first
visibility and scanning coverage
when when this graph of findings that we
got thread items
are we looking at everything we should
be looking at or maybe there are
additional environments that we are not
looking at
then for prioritization of high risk
items because everything may be right
there are just maybe too many issues and
we cannot resolve everything at once so
we need to prioritize and we need to
detect these most critical items that
should be resolved first
and there's there are actually two
things two attributes that uh that are
useful to look at first the criticality
of the item and then also the impact for
example if there is this one line uh
with unencrypted volumes and all of the
instances are deployed from this code
not encrypting the volumes if we fix the
slime all the volumes will be encrypted
so by fixing one line we impacted
thousands of instances
and that's a good high priority item to
start with because it is easy to fix the
impact is Big the risk of
exposing the data is
an additional metric is also around life
cycle and gates are we scanning through
the entire life cycle or are we looking
just pre-deployment or just run time
typically it's not enough just to look
at one of them
because if we're scanning just at
runtime
it's it may be too late if if we're
scanning just pre-deployment then still
if there isn't an attack or exploitation
after the code is deployed we'll
completely miss it
so measuring these scanning Gates and
life cycle management is very critical
and then the last phases are actually
how we're responding
because typically the amount of issues
is bigger than we can resolve manually
so having systems for tagging and auto
ticketing assigning the priority and
then resolving the issues is very
critical and without this it is almost
impossible to remediate these findings
and finally and finally
once we are fixing the issues what is
the speed of redeployment let's back to
our example of our encrypted volumes
we detected the problem we fixed this
one line of code if the instances are
not redeployed we didn't really resolve
it so measuring the speed of
redeployment and mean time to resolve
for each and every issue is very
critical and and this is an important
method metric for the success of these
programs
and let me maybe finish this with one
additional example of what a cloud is
different
and where are we talking about Cloud
security combined with application
security
it is about the management of the life
cycle of public cloud services
if we're looking at this every service
may be misconfigured most of these
services are defined as multi-tenant by
nature which means let's take object
storage as an example
it is one service for all the clients it
is not deployed in this dedicated way
just for each account it is shared
between everyone
so if someone is misconfiguring it
then no network can can protect against
us it is just policy misconfiguration
and the bucket is exposed
so this management of the life cycle how
we hardening the services
and what's the life cycle how to secure
the foundations how to secure the build
of the application creating this bucket
foreign
time and then how can we improve over
time
so this uh what many organizations are
doing today they are defining this uh
baselines for each and every service
that they're using in public clouds
creating these rules for example uh for
instances the volume should be encrypted
in this way for storage buckets these
are the policy these are the default
policies inside our organization and
this is a deployment code that should be
used
and then there are monitoring tools to
detect if something is misconfigured to
generate events and then handle them
and do the remediation that we've been
discussing
but we need to do this for each and
every service
and this pipeline is actually very
similar to our traditional abstract
pipeline
sorry
because it should start with threat
analysis exactly is an application
security what are the tax scenarios then
how the service should be configured to
prevent this
then what are the guidelines for
developers what is the deployment code
how are we monitoring this and what are
we doing if something goes wrong
many organizations are going in this
direction but let me emphasize maybe one
of the most critical
points of how to do it right
it is the policies code piece that is
very critical a policies code has many
meanings
essentially it's policy written as code
and it may be implemented at various
stages
in this scenario these are the
compliance rules
that before we're deploying a certain
service we can scan
is it according to what we Define and if
not will not allow the deployment
the same at runtime we can have policies
code monitoring and if something is not
aligned with this Baseline definition
there will be an alert
and Remediation procedures
so let me finish with highlighting
what's how this policies code is helping
us and what's the meaning of it and all
of you are familiar with the concept of
Dev seconds
it's the essential integration of
security tools in our devops processes
through the entire life cycle of our
applications
policy as code is actually a mechanism
to make our Dev Cyclops processes better
by defining the rules by defining these
Gates and saying this is the policy
this is the the gate has brought about
that secops process but it is the
policies code that defines these are the
rules of the road
if you're not following them you will
not pass to the next stage and this is
why devs checkups and policies called
actually complementing each other and we
need both
so let me summarize with what we've seen
today
we saw that cloud can be exploited by
application exploitation techniques so
Cloud security and application security
are coming together
Cloud management code is accessible the
internet exposed uh
to potentially malicious attackers that
can use traditional application
exploitation techniques
that therefore application security
processes should be integrated with
Cloud Security Programs
to check for all these issues and then
finally from the ciso standpoint cloud
and application Security Programs are
essential they should cover attack
service management depth of checkups and
policies
I know this and thank you for listening
and all positive questions
thank you so much and uh I'll give you a
couple of ticks there to get um you know
a little drink going
um
okay we do have a number of questions so
the uh Dorothy dixa which is what we
call a question that we've asked
ourselves
um there's actually four of them that
aren't that come from the audience so
the first question with four votes is
what are the recommended tools for CSP
threat modeling
uh
I wish I could give you a name of
products unfortunately this space is
emerging most of the threat modeling
methodologies were developed
a very application
security Centric
I think this space is still evolving
indeed many organizations need to do
this manually so
okay and I I hope that soon I will be
able to recommend the product
unfortunately I think we're still not at
this winning phase right now
but would love to continue for it if any
of you will hear about this Technologies
please share with the rest of the group
today
yeah I mean we're an open source
organization if there's a person in the
audience who wants to get going on such
a tool we actually do have a tool called
threat Dragon we also have tools called
um that
um the folks to do Iris risk through
Stephen DeVries and others you may want
to just have a look at those and see if
we can extend them to include CSP threat
modeling
um obviously in Microsoft threat
modeling tool exists as well but if you
are interested in doing this work it
doesn't have to be a commercial tool and
I think realistically our goal is to
help developers all over the world so if
this is this question had the most
number of votes so there was obviously
an interest if you are interested please
do contact Harold Blankenship who's a
the technology and projects director and
let's see if we can get some
improvements going okay yes thank you we
would love to continue to be part of
this forum and indeed there are many
improvements that we have solid
foundations inside modeling so it's
about taking this to the next level and
an excellent question and definitely a
great initiative to push forward
absolutely okay so the next most popular
question is due to limited knowledge of
cloud security how to make sure
developer or SB I'm not too sure what SP
is but who manages
who managed to do the rack configuration
so
um I'm not too sure what they mean by SB
but um
I'm not sure but anyway um how do we
make sure that the right person has
actually done the right configuration
who manages it
yes it's
a service maybe a space service provider
ah lots of this because indeed if we're
talking about our application
applications let's say I have developed
an application I'm putting this into the
cloud I would use cspm or other tools to
actually check for misconfigurations and
other things but sometimes there are
service providers and third parties that
that they're responsible for actually
implementing this
and and indeed this is actually a an
excellent question and many many
organizations are really worried about
this because they're consuming software
access
but actually it's just another company
another service provider building these
applications of a public cloud services
and a many clients of these service
providers they want to know that this
application is secure and not exposed
exposed to the attack factors that we've
been discussing and so what is emerging
right now still is a discussion I still
did see this fully forced but this is
something to discuss as part of the
agreements with the service providers
for them to bring these attestations
some of the decisions are provided as
part of soft to processes or others but
it will not go very deep into this
emerging attack scenarios and how to
check them and so discuss one option is
to discuss this as part of the
agreements with the service providers
that will be that they will be providing
these more advanced statistications from
more advanced tools or agreeing to
periodic audit processes
so the decline will actually ask to
periodically audit the service provider
and check for these issues so these are
the solutions that I've seen in this
place in the space hopefully this
answered the question if not then brings
that additional details on the wall
Trust
sure okay so the next question is are
you aware of any regulation or
compliance
um uh standard that prevents using cloud
and multi-tenant setup and requires a
customer to have a dedicated hardware
and the example they give is PCI DSS
which I'm reasonably certain doesn't
prevent that but are you aware of any
other standards or compliance
requirements that require dedicated
Hardware
yeah I think honestly I'm not a lawyer I
think there may be cases where this may
be required for some specific use cases
and
some defense related scenarios or things
like that and
it is of course it will be more secure
but I think also today
um
in many discussions about compliance
people understand that if they will be
too strict in these requirements they
will be preventing Innovation from any
companies
um so this is why there is this a gentle
balance right can we
actually say no to the cloud can we
force people to say no to the cloud
because in many cases they don't have a
choice there are so many solutions that
are available today only over
Cloud environments even
if we're thinking about blockchain or
other applications many of them are
available only over the cloud so
organizations that need to integrate
this they actually Force to go into the
cloud
and but but this question I think it
will apply certain organizations yes may
have based additional requirements based
on on their use cases but but there's a
the situations I think are just
handled separately and and many
organizations honestly are still very
concerned to go to public to public
clouds so many organizations are still
having data centers not necessarily
because
um Regulators are saying you cannot do
this but they're concerned that if they
will go maybe they will not fully
satisfy their part of the shared
responsibility or the cloud
the multitant isolation may be broken
and then they they will expose actually
their clients so there are organizations
that are still concerned with us
yeah I mean honestly a lot of this stuff
comes back to the people who believe
that data has a special place
um on this planet instead of just an IP
address
um ever since the 1960s and 1970s where
IBM were running lpars for various
clients and that is the underpinning of
the world financial system
this is a ridiculous question but there
are some ridiculous compliance
requirements out there so there are
plenty of firms making a lot of money
from people implementing these
ridiculous requirements it really should
be about whether or not it's secure or
not not where it's located or who whose
other computer it's on
um I think if most banks were required
to host their own mainframes
particularly for BCP or Dr purposes they
would fail this compliance check and
therefore it's a ridiculous compliance
um I'm extraordinarily unimpressed with
anybody who thinks along those lines
because it's not about security it's
about job security or making sure that
someone gets paid
rather than up time or security or some
other non-performance sorry not a
non-functional requirement I feel very
passionately about this and um
to me I'd I'd take tangible security
over pretend hand wavy security
physio security every day of the week
um just because it's a dashed line
somewhere as it says this is our private
virtual Network
hackers don't care they really don't
anyway let's just move on I as you can
tell I'm very biased against the actual
question
um
and um just for the record I also am not
aware of any regulations that do that
I'm sure there are some
um this is the Dorothy Dixon have you
got any examples of firms or
organizations that have actually done
this convergence and what were the
challenges or successes that you know
that they had
yes thank you so I'm maybe I'll just
share from my personal experience
because as part of my role at Citibank
and I I built the C so-called security
program but day one it was built in this
close collaboration with application
security program because we already saw
these interaction points and they need
to actually combine our approaches and
um and have this as one holistic view
scanning applications and scanning
containers and scanning infrastructures
code for example so we started this at
Citibank now is Ernest and Young it we
started with two practices called
security practice and application
security practice and just throughout
projects to clients we saw that a most
of our projects are combining both and
we need people who are skilled in both
for both no application security and no
Cloud security are familiar with all
these attack factors and how to prevent
them so internally we merged in our
practices we have we call it attack
surface management now and we have a
team of trained professionals looking at
cloud and application Security in this
holistic way so we have actually
implemented this and this is the the
mission of our team
cool the next question is do you know of
any blogs
um oh actually it just switched over
I'll ask someone I was originally going
to ask do you know of any standard that
is planning to Define policy as code
oh that's an excellent question
um
I think a oppa is becoming very popular
as an approach to policies called
management as this architecture where
policy decision point is separated
so I think we're converging not as a
standard not as
compliance tunnel but as an
architectural standard
um and Architectural concept
but the mechanisms to the policies code
is very different and we have and we'll
continue to have many ways while
actually doing policy as code and we
should continue doing this let me give
you some example examples what we
mentioned for the deployment of public
cloud services we can have
pre-deployment policies code checking
that what we are deploying aligns with
our roles for example checking that
there are no open buckets and all the
volumes encrypted
through our pre-deployment code this can
be done as policies code another example
of policies code is defined as part of
cspn tools right so we want to align and
have exactly the same rules now
monitoring and alerting if things are
violated
but we also have for example policies
code even as part of network management
or network segmentation tools even the
rules how are we doing Network
segmentation these are also policies and
we should have them as policies code so
right now the situation is that and we
have actually many also ways to do
policy is called it may be policy in the
platform policy in the product policy
organizational policy that we're now
extracting to offer a so today we have
many many policies called initiatives we
should continue progressing with all of
them we should not be stopping this
automation effort because there may be
better ways to consolidate but there is
a need to have a holistic view on this
places of policy is called just ensure
that we're defining the same rules
across all our environments and places
so maybe bottom line policies code may
continue to be distributed although we
do want to centralize it so we need to
accept that in spite open inspired
architectures will still have some
distribution of policies code so we need
to continue both trying to centralize
and then still have this beyond all of
the decentralized instances and still
continue to automate so the most
critical thing is not to stop the
process automate
transition from policies that written on
paper
to policies written as code and can be
aggregated and reviewed in this
automated way
hopefully this answer the question
I think it did thank you the last
question we've got and then we'll wrap
it up is are there any tools or blogs we
can follow to find these CSP bugs or
configs obviously you might want to put
a URL or two in is do you have social
media like a Twitter handle that they
could actually go look at and you can
paste there
yes so so first person I'm very careful
and we'll always need and and the cloud
provider Cloud CSP typically these are
published by cspm companies so you can
follow the blogs of cspm companies
typically they're publishing because
they're the standard responsibility
they're publishing this only once these
things are resolved
but looking at Cloud native forums for
example there is a community called
Cloud SEC uh through which you can see
some of these Publications
and and also just reading the blogs of
cloud security companies
they and the most critical thing is
actually not just to read and say wow
that's a problem hopefully in most cases
the cloud providers will continue
quickly resolving these issues so the
clients are not impacted by this and
once these are reported or discovered
they're doing whatever they can to
quickly resolve the issues but what is
critical actually for us to keep in mind
that it is possible and we need to
accept this and we need to design our
architectures in a way that they will be
able to manage with us and we need to
design our cyber security processes to
be able to quickly scope the event and
respond to it
okay
um there is actually one more question
that just snuck in
um are there any recommended tool or
services for Asset Management
oh that's an excellent point
because what we've seen there are
sometimes excellent tools but they will
be just for one cloud provider because
you need to speak the cloud native
language to actually get all the assets
so there are certain open source seven
tools for cloud native asset management
but they will not always have all the
environments
so what we've seen organizations today
sometimes they will use let's say one
open source tool in one environment but
then they need to implement something
similar by themselves in other Cloud
environments
and in a way this is also on the agenda
of CSO Cloud Security Programs
to check that there are processes doing
this Asset Management
actually even just reading the apis from
the cloud provider
doing this kind of by themselves doing
all these API calls mapping what are the
resources that they have and keeping
this as a registry on-prem because in
case of the incident it's very critical
to know what was imported what is the
scope of event and without this tools it
is very difficult to manage so excellent
question I hope this space will continue
emerging and once again maybe
um as part of the WASP organization and
there will be initial additional
initiatives to help with Asset
Management in the cloud
I have some questions
exactly the the most critical topics
where we need additional investment in
the industry and we need more tools and
moralistic solutions so both threat
modeling and asset management
topics and
maybe as part of our last we can invest
more in this
and with that we are at time thank you
so much for a great talk and I think we
had a lot of questions which sort of
demonstrate the the relevance and
interests that people have in this
particular topic and so we do hope to
see you again at a future conference
thank you so much for being a keynote at
ours
no worries thank you