hi everybody this unfortunately already
our closing keynote for the first day of
our global Earth virtual upsec 22. this
one is shiran Saban technical expert is
a focus on cloud security
is as co-founder and CEO of solofo the
first application we had Cloud Security
Solutions but I don't want to go wrong
because he said she will introduce
herself she's professional certain cyber
security has been military in an
intelligent unit stronger believes in
empowering women that's what you see on
her t-shirt as he showed to me
um
she's very represented in the community
and Technology world she is volunteering
election monitoring she's a
a very industrious and devoted Over uh
volunteer globally and in Israel
so without further Ado ladies and
gentlemen
this close yours
thank you so much Martin uh for this
introduction and hi everyone thank you
for having me today
um good evening to all of you in Europe
uh for me this is good morning from San
Francisco I am at the RSA conference
right now I hope I'm sure you had a very
good day today at apsec EU and hopefully
um you will find some some interesting
topics today and in the rest of the
conference as well
um so let's get started
so as Martin mentioned I am Shira on my
day-to-day life I'm CEO and co-founder
of solvo solver is a platform that helps
developers devops and security teams to
keep a least privileged Cloud
application automatically
uh and if you want to learn more about
it we can talk about it later it is not
the topic of our conversation today but
other than Cloud security I'm also the
co-chair of OSP Israel but I have to say
that my greatest achievement in life has
nothing to do with cyber security a few
years back I was working for a company
that got acquired by a large corporate
and thanks to to this acquisition what
happened was that the corporate made a
change in their policy and they became a
dog friendly company thanks to my dog so
I definitely feel like this is my
greatest achievement in life yet that
made the difference for thousands of
employees worldwide
uh but now you know everything important
to know about myself so we can get
started and talk more about business and
about Cloud security
uh always top 10 uh I think most of you
are familiar with this project uh but if
not I will just say that this is a
community project uh that started many
years ago actually almost 20 years ago
uh where the community and the Security
Experts point out at the most common or
the most popular risks and security
issues that we're seeing in in
applications in web applications
um because we want to raise the
awareness and help developers and
everyone else in the process to adapt a
smarter and more secure way to deliver
those applications so that for it's for
us for the end user to feel more secured
about it
um now in 20 years the world has changed
20 years since OAS was established and
the applications that we create
changed the technologies that we're
using changed so obviously in the top 10
risks that appear in those
um in the document that is being
published every few years
also update and change over time for me
as a cloud entrepreneur I was curious to
take a closer look at the impact that
the cloud made to the applications
security landscape
I want to remind you that when the cloud
burst into our lives and it was kind of
a Data Center Alternative it wasn't
supposed to uh be what it actually be or
I don't know if it wasn't supposed to be
but we didn't dream the cloud would
become what it is today
and I will show you my thesis around it
but I think that there is a very thin
line today between application security
and infrastructure security they
actually go very well together
so in this talk we're going to go back
in time 15 years back actually to look
at always top 10 and how it changed from
a 2007 I will be starting from the top
10 of 2007 until today the last hours
Pro 10 was released in 2001. so this is
a 15-year perspective
later I will share with you my
predictions
or my assumptions they are all mine not
and always official opinion about uh the
future of our top 10.
so one other important thing I have to
say before we move forward I'm going to
share here the top 10 from 2007 until
today I did some digging into the uh um
documentation that is available to
everyone on the online
and occasionally I found some
inconsistencies in the order of
appearance of the risks
so during this talk I will not be a
referring to the ranking of of the um
the risks so don't look at the order of
appearance if something appears on the
top that doesn't mean it was number one
that year uh let's just focus on the
risks themselves that appeared in um in
every year that we will be talking about
we're not going to talk about each risk
specifically I just want to look at the
overall trend in 2007 we had some new
and newcomers some new risks that showed
up this year
I will be highlighting in green the new
risks that came in this year so csrf
insecure communication and malicious
file extension were new at new 2007.
it's interesting to see how those things
are still relevant
um today now in in general for the sake
of our conversation today I will be
grouping the risks in into two
categories uh I did this uh dividing it
is not an always a terminology and I
look at two groups today one is the user
and application interaction category and
the other is backend and infrastructure
related
um risks the user application group is
looking at the interactions between the
user or and the malicious user and the
application so that could mean code
injection that could mean URL
manipulation and this kind of things so
in 2007 we saw um
four risks that belong to the group of
uh of the user application interaction I
will I will be highlighting that in
yellow
throughout the entire talk so green for
new risk yellow for the user and
application uh risk so
um in the back end and in the backend
group of vulnerabilities of the risks we
have the encryption we have the
authentication and we have the network
and we will see how this evolved over
time but this is 2007 and this is where
we are starting
now the next thing I want to do after we
talk about the vulnerabilities is what
happened in the cloud world
from the day of the uh
this document they all document was
released until the next one was released
what happened in the cloud world so
really important stuff to talk about uh
between 2006 to 2010 is first of all
first of all you know an important
reminder always puts here before the
cloud uh also started early 2000 and AWS
was born in 2006.
um a year later our good friend S3
bucket came to the world still very
popular to this day and it's pretty
amazing to to think about how popular it
is and how we can't create any
application without using it in 2008
Google released the Google app engine
that later became what we are familiar
with as gcp so this is when these guys
came to the world
moving forward in our journey in time to
2010 two new risks made a first
appearance that year the security
misconfiguration and I unvalidated
redirected and forwards uh by the way
according to the 2010 documentation
misconfiguration was also include a we
refer to misconfiguration as also
unpatched packages exposed admin pages
and server configuration so today when
we talk about misconfiguration very
often we relate to things like leaky S3
buckets we size three buckets only 2007
so when in the OS documentation we
talked about misconfiguration we still
related to more uh traditional and
classic misconfigurations and not to the
cloud misconfigurations as we know them
today
um so another fun fact is that security
misconfiguration was a part of os top 10
of 2004. it had a little the name was
slightly different in Secure
configuration management it was dropped
out in 2007 because it wasn't considered
to be a software issue however from the
organizational risk
perspective it cleared it was clearly a
part of the top ten and this is why the
team that built that document decided to
put it back
so let's get back to my classification
of risks and in the um user app
domain uh and the risks that we have now
we have four of those uh the previous
year we had four now we have five uh in
my world again in my definition these
risks have to do a with the interaction
between a user and things that between
the user and the application a a
malicious user as well
so they when we're talking about things
like uh getting access to unused pages
and patched flaws unprotected files and
directories
um if they're unauthorized to do so and
in the backend group we are still mostly
talking about encryption and networks so
no massive changes over there yet but
let's move forward
what happened during this time and in
the world of cloud
in 2009 the cloud infrastructure is
becoming more dominant it is the go-to
for startups and for Enterprises that
are creating new applications some of
the Enterprises are still in their
on-prem and Legacy Technologies but just
wrap your head around it in 2009 the
cloud Market size was 58 billion dollars
recently in 2001 it was over 300 billion
dollars
Microsoft for a little late in 2010 they
introduced us to a Microsoft Azure as
you guys and girls probably know Azure
today is the second most popular a cloud
vendor so they uh they beat a Google in
the race
we're getting closer
to to to nowadays uh we're now talking
about the OS top 10 of
2013. uh this year we only had one new
uh entry maybe not exactly a new entry a
more of a merge between insecure
cryptographic storage and insufficient
transport layer they both became
together sensitive data exposure
um so not a lot of news
in oasp this year but on the other hand
we had some very interesting things in
that period of time in the world of
cloud
um in 2013 a company named dot Cloud
released Docker as an open source a tool
aimed at simplifying the usage of Linux
containers and making them accessible
for everyone if you're not familiar with
DOT Cloud this is because today we just
know it as docker
so think about it this is a 2013 that's
almost 10 years ago it feels like only
today we are really getting the hang of
it and how to use the uh this technology
well and securely
2014 Google launches kubernetes as an
open source container orchestration
system to automate application
deployment and scaling and management so
again these are things that are now very
very very popular but back then that was
just the early beginning uh 2013 we were
also introduced to AWS Lambda the
serverless
so no doubt that this period of a
2013-14 was very very interesting in the
world of cloud and I think that at this
point we're also seeing a Tipping Point
in the top 10 risks at oasp we will
start you using thing less a user
application kind of risks it's not that
they don't exist but we're seeing more
risks in the world of backend and in the
world of infrastructure and how
infrastructure is becoming more relevant
to our world of risk management and the
popularity of those risks
um
where in 2017 we are almost
we are almost now
and so we're almost over with our
journeying time uh always top 10 brought
to us five new risks uh one of them was
emerged broken Access Control uh was
insecure direct object reference and
missing functional uh function level
access control so these two became one
risk
insufficient logging and monitoring in
my opinion is a risk that definitely has
a lot to do with Cloud the place where
we became dependent on third parties to
provide us with services that we we must
keep track on and make sure we are on
top of every event in every incident and
we need to make sure which data went
where and how come this event happened
this way and not another uh made us
desperately need logs coming from other
products or other services that we're
using
um logging was also important in on-prem
days don't get me wrong but this time we
need them even more because so many
things happen that we might not even be
aware of so I think that logging became
an issue because of the popularity of
Open Source Code multiple Security
operation products uh just the the
multiple products all over the place not
to mention uh using multi-cloud and even
hybrid cloud and of course uh
more open source and different
Frameworks that we're using
um
according to my classification another
thing that we see
this year we only had two user
application
risks the other ones the the back and
the kind of risks are exploitable or
Martin corrected me that we don't look
at them as vulnerabilities but at risks
but they are exploitable
of course but
from other levels of the application
they are not really in the user
interface at least in my classification
the way I see it so we're moving away
from the user application interface
going deeper into the application the
back end of the application the third
parties and the different services that
we are using in order to make this
application functional for us
um so this is where I'm taking this now
so the back end is related to the
vulnerabilities that now have to do with
data with access to data and different
resources and with authentication and as
we mentioned before the logging so this
is getting interesting we're living at
the area of the users and getting closer
to the back end of the application
closer to the technology
um
at this point I when I was looking into
the history of the modern history of the
cloud it was getting harder for me to
identify
groundbreaking events
for for the cloud domain I think it's
because it became such a mainstream and
such a such a popular technology and
natural technology to use in our life
that
maybe we take things as granted but when
I wanted to to look badly for you know
more groundbreaking events it was
getting harder
now we made it to the always top 10 of
2021 that's the light latest release of
August top 10. this year we had three
new entries or three new risks one of
them was a renaming and expanding of of
the existing definition
it's interesting to see that in 2007
client signed request forgery was a new
entry and in 2001 the server side
request forgery was a new entry so you
see where I'm taking this right we're
moving away from the user closer to the
back end
um again if we take a look at my
classification of the risks we will see
that we grew further apart from the user
basically all we have left in the
um user application a group is the
injection the other risks we have to do
with uh have to do with the code of the
application the component uh the
components the application is using and
basically this is a area I like to call
it Plumbing uh Plumbing means that we
connect different components together
that we didn't build
uh making sure that all the different
parts work well together they enable
small a smooth flow of data and the
functionality of the application even
though we didn't build each part
specifically by ourselves and this time
it includes Access Control
authentication and encryption and this
is why the last version of the WASP top
10 we only have a one user application
related risk again this is my my take on
it and the take on on how the cloud made
us move apart from the user interaction
and closer to the infrastructure and
backend
um so this is again in my opinion the
biggest change that the cloud
infrastructure brought to application
security the fact that the
infrastructure is an integral part of
the application and we can't do
application security without taking a
very close look at the infrastructure
the cloud infrastructure and to make
sure we use it correctly it is well
configured
it doesn't expose our data and uh not
our data and not other people's data not
data of the application and only the
necessary entities an entity can be a
user or it can be another Cloud
component or an external cloud account
only the necessary entities get the
necessary access that they need in your
Cloud application on average you have
dozens of third parties and other SAS
products that are connected to your
application and you want to make sure
that they only have access to the
specific data and resources that they
need it's really easy right I know you
can do it
so
we went over a the office top 10 from
2007 until uh 2021 but what does it mean
for us
um to sum up the going back in time this
time this part of our journey
there are a few things I want to share
with you
uh we saw that from focusing on the code
of the application and the user
application interface interface the OS
top 10 is showing more risks that have
to do with behind the scenes so we no
longer uh
it's not that we no longer manipulate
URLs to get access to the to the hidden
data but we can find it in a
misconfigured S3 bucket so today we just
have more ways uh to do some nasty stuff
we no longer need to exploit broken
authentication we can see that you are
saying an admin role to an
internet-facing ec2 machine so we can
take over that
these kind of risks existed in the past
but they certainly exist today but they
just made some adaptations into
um into the cloud world
in the past there used to be a part of
the I.T team to to make sure that the
servers are not exposed to the Internet
so the developers wrote the code handed
it over security was a silo and we
didn't do we didn't have to do anything
about it but today it's a part of the
cicd process where we actually have
developers and devops and security team
involved in the process so it's a flow
no more silos and everyone has to work
together so all of us need to make sure
that it's a joint effort
to secure our application and our data
no longer separated teams but now every
everyone is actually working together on
this
um in the 2017 report the writers
created a very nice infographic of the
previous
risks in previous reports so I took the
liberty to create an updated version of
this
chart please feel free to take a
screenshot if you want to get a kind of
a
overview of how the OS top 10 changed in
the last 15 years I will also ask Martin
later if we can publish this as some
kind of a white paper or put it in the
always
um website for everyone to use
so feel free to dig into this and see
for yourself how different risks went
out of the OS top 10 that doesn't mean
these risks don't exist anymore but we
you have to prioritize right so
theoretically we could have had over top
100 but when we had to choose the top 10
these are the ones that made the cut and
it's really interesting to see how they
changed and adapt over time based on the
new technologies that we see getting
into our lives
um
so I promised you uh I will talk about
my predictions which again are my own I
don't think I have a lot of news here I
didn't come up with risks that you're
unfamiliar with but I try to maybe look
at
what I'm seeing the events and the
incident and the breaches that I'm
seeing today and kind of guess
where is it going to hit us and what in
my opinion makes sense to see in the
future
of us top 10.
um so in in a way we finished going back
in time and now we're going forward in
time
um and the bottom line in my in my
opinion is that there isn't a lot of
news
uh we previously didn't see
um any specific API risk in the OS top
10 in the previous reports
even though please remember that there
is a dedicated project at OAS for API
security
uh I think that API risks and
vulnerabilities are going to grow bigger
and bigger on us uh and other than that
I think we keep on seeing the same
things generally speaking over and over
again
same mistakes guys leaving credentials
in text files putting it in Dropbox uh
not rotating Keys giving everyone admin
access these are all things we keep on
seeing over and over again we have to
stop with this relying on code we didn't
write remember the chaos we had a few
months ago around log4j
remember that just a couple of months
ago OCTA the service that all of us are
using got hacked and through that hack
their customers got attacked so this is
a
sadly a good example to using third
parties this
is this is crazy but this is the world
that we live in
misconfiguration and architecture to me
they mean that we just have to plan
ahead and threat model
and we also have a dedicated OS
resources on that that you can feel free
to use
um now
where are we going with this you're
probably wondering what does this mean
to you and what can you do to improve
your application security posture in the
cloud so here is my take on this first
of all shifting left
we talk about it all the time but still
we find it very very very hard to
implement we'll be seeing more
developers finding themselves touching
the infrastructure not because they want
to replace the devops but because they
want to move faster and if we want them
to move faster and to deliver faster we
need to enable them with the security
with a secured way to do it so we will
need to implement automated
devsecops and infrastructure security
tools to make their life easier and to
make our life the security people life
less stressful
um I mentioned the term Plumbing before
this is a the terminology that I like to
use in the case of talking about
different services and components that
we didn't write we connect them together
and call this an application uh the more
we use the cloud the more we use managed
Services the more we use SAS Solutions
as a part of our application this is
more Plumbing that we are doing and we
need to learn how is the data flowing
exactly where to filter it how to
identify a leakage how to make sure that
only the necessary access is granted I
think we'll be seeing a lot more
Plumbing issues so to speak in the
future so prepare yourselves and prepare
your team for this mindset of becoming a
security plumbers
uh last but not least we are all using
third parties all the time at the end of
the day
if I if OCTA got hacked so who are we
and through through OCTA their customers
so actually no one is immune to these
kind of things no one I don't rely on my
vendors and I don't rely on my external
products to keep me secured this is our
responsibility to make sure that our
infrastructure our backend our data are
all secured we're not going to QA the
other products we are not going to pen
test the other products while we go
through an audit I mean unless you
really want to I don't think it is our
job to pen test the other products
um so always remember that you are
responsible for your own application and
keep in mind that those third parties
might and might not be secured and the
fact that they are compliant to
something doesn't mean that they are
secured and secured enough and securing
the standards that you would like them
or you would hope they are secured
um always prepare yourself for a
potential breach or potential hack
and I think that this is not news to you
security is like an onion you have
layers and layers and layers you can
never have a hundred percent
um so keep in mind that you should also
know in which layer did you keep the
data and what kind of layers did you put
around it and where are the third
parties around those layers and what
kind of security layers are you putting
around them to mitigate
potential future
um risks
so at this
I would like to thank you today for
joining me to a journey in time
from OS 2000 from OS top 10 2007 until
uh I will be taking some questions now
and if anyone wants to reach out to me
later over LinkedIn over Twitter please
feel free to do so
thank you so much sincere so I hope
everybody so we have some questions from
the customers I haven't attendees uh one
is the first one is
um over the years there are mobile top
10 the API to ten the docker top 10
shouldn't this be considered
consolidated
or other guidelines that tell
what to follow for What on how to avoid
confusion or increase awareness uh I
think that this is the challenge that
any security practitioner is facing I
can tell you that I'm here at RSA right
now and you look at you work at the Expo
you have dozens of security
companies telling you about the
importance of the risk that they're
going to mitigate and resolve for you at
the end of the day you know your
application and you know your crown
jewels and you need to work your way
around it it always has
very good and very up-to-date resources
for example if you go and take a look at
the other OS projects not only the top
10 but the API top 10 the serverless top
10 you will be seeing some commonality
there are some mistakes that repeat
themselves and we see them in every
project right so authentication is
something that we see everywhere so if
you decide and I think that you should
tackle authentication and make sure you
do it correctly
if you do it once uh it it covers a
other security aspects as well so there
I I wish there was one single source of
Truth for the top 10 things everyone
should be doing in their application but
it really differs you know some
applications are on premise some in the
cloud and some also have a mobile
application and some don't have any pii
so their risks are totally different
their potential of damage is totally
different
um so I just think that you need to
analyze your application threat model
your application and then start
obviously with the most with the things
that could cause the biggest damage and
can give you the quickest or maybe not
the quickest but the biggest impact on
your security and start with that
yeah if I may add so it's indeed we have
about risk in the context and of course
in several contexts you have the same
risk but I would like to point out it's
an OS Project it's the open cre the open
common requirement and variation it's
kind of linking the requirements where
they come from by conduct so it's not a
one-on-one mapping but the mapping like
we have there for example authentication
you can see where the requirements of
authentication come from by what
standard or which version of what's that
not I will put it at the answers as well
it's nice one to add
right okay the next question was
perhaps about the future uh the
prediction perhaps insecure software
supply chain will be on the list in the
future what do you think
I think that uh um
it's there it might be so I think that
any third party that we use software
supply chain but also you know also a
cloud infrastructure I look at it as a
third party it's not exactly software in
this in the sense that we copy and paste
from stack Overflow and put it into our
application but if you think about a
using AWS Cognito for example the
authentication Service that AWS has for
you what's behind it there is some code
that someone else wrote so I look at it
in a way just like you mentioned a the
third party a software
supply chain I look at using a managed
service the same way because this is at
the end of the day a piece of code
someone else wrote so I think there is
definitely room to put in the field
future always top 10 using any kind of
third-party Service as a part of your
application this is a supply chain issue
I might mention one very interesting
incident that happened a few months back
AWS someone at AWS accidentally I
assumed it was an accident anyway it
made a change to the security
policy for S3 bucket for the support
role they accidentally added a
permission to read items out of S3 so
for some time if you used the support
role for S3
AWS employees were able to read items
out of your S3 bucket
so this is to me it's a third party big
issue and
when we talk about mitigating the third
party risks thinking about the roles
that you have enabled in your account
and maybe not allowing the service
support for AWS to be active all the
time is an interesting layer in the
onion and you don't have to enable it
all the time you can enable it just when
you need it
now I I like the security onion uh just
think about that it's a mems about the
security onion I also when I uh to this
point is when you say talk about supply
chain I was wondering when it came out
because I know that many years ago Josh
Coleman of iron Curry talked about
supply chain cleannessness and headed
with uh alignment of the car industry
where one uh brand has less suppliers a
much more external part the other one
has less external Parts but more
different suppliers so the one that goes
for Quality the other one the the
pricing and then you see the differences
so you have to have what do I import and
that's for also 10 2017 as you showed it
they had a using components of
non-vulnerabilities and now it's the let
me see it's the A6 it's vulnerable
outdated components so definitely supply
chain and this external components it's
more on the radar now definitely for
attackers open source right yeah
everybody is allowed to contribute and
we all did this for the best and now
people will use it for the worse
definitely another question we have is
is the current release cycle of the auto
10 three to four years enough for the
future what do you think
it's a great question uh
um I think that
in theory we could have updated it maybe
every year or two but would you run a
very thorough assessment every year or
two I think that organizations don't do
it that frequently uh
um
so at the end of the day the OS top 10
is kind of a mirror
to what we are seeing
um maybe maybe three to four years is
too long and we can shorten it but I
don't think that every year is uh
necessary in the sense that are we
really going to take action based on a
new hours top 10 every year I'm not sure
about it
but Martin what do you think yeah I
think we usually take actions I'm always
worrying about people demanding like hey
we always have 10 and now I was checking
all of our application security posts
whatever it
augment people get it's not a complete
list it's an advanced document and if
you base your security portion also 10
it's like you trust one tool for your
security validation right on your
Instagram you want to call it I was
scared about people calling this because
it's an awareness document use it it's
not a choose it's not a complete set of
requirements but you know so yeah it's
like
cringing my teeth when I hear people
like I think that say something about
the maturity of the most companies
um another good question I heard is like
what do you think about a single biggest
concern for organizations running in the
cloud
I
um so we talked a little bit before
about the plumbing and connecting
different components very often in our
Cloud application we connect we not only
connect components from the AWS
Marketplace the the different services
that are available there but we even
connect external Services external
vendors external SAS products external
AWS account and we do this connectivity
in the cloud using uh roles and policies
and not policy like I don't allow it to
connect to the internet but a role in
the policy is a part of IAM identity and
access management and I think that today
the really nasty AWS or Cloud native
hacks but also the really good security
mechanism to fight it is identity and
access management and this mechanism
exists in AWS in Azure in GC in in gcp
everyone should make sure
that their Provisions don't have too
many holes in them or don't have any
holes in them if if possible
I think that the biggest failures that
are Cloud native not I forgot my
credentials there in my code in GitHub
but the cloud native incidents happen
because we have enabled too much access
to our Crown Jewel and resources
the example that I gave before about
giving the ec2 machine admin permissions
I have I know someone in their company
I'm not gonna say who that for all of
their Lambda functions they use the same
role
the LA each Lambda is doing something
different if you use the same rule for
all the lambdas I can take one of them
exploit it create myself as the attacker
with admin permissions you will never
know about it
so the cloud gave us this great power of
creating an identity for every cloud
component we are using it the wrong way
so theoretically speaking I can take one
component in your Cloud application and
help make it assume a role that can
assume an admin role and I can take over
the entire account people are unaware of
this and it's very very very simple to
fix and to prevent
so I think that this is the single uh
point of failure but also the the place
that would give you the best security
value for your time
I think it's a perfect loopback to our
opening keynote about the inside stress
because of what Lisa said back then she
sees companies they fire somebody or
somebody will be laid out for whatever
reason and they said oh everything is
good because PA disabled account or the
accountability password will be reset
anyway after several weeks and they
forget they have the non-profit the
non-personal in the service accounts
externally right oh we have the shared
account on this external service they
haven't thought about it and it's an
interesting one yeah
yeah
um
let me see
I have to seen many companies that do a
lift and shift so they're taking
applications as is and do it loud
because I already cost a lot of money
right what do you think about that
it's funny I a while ago I was talking
to someone from one of the big cloud
vendors and they shared the statistics I
was not unaware of they told me that
about 70 percent of uh the compute power
today is still on-prem not in the cloud
I thought it would be the other way
around I thought most is in the cloud
and a little bit is still on-prem so I
think that first of all lift and shift
is still a big challenge I thought that
I mean I was under the conception that
now the challenge is cloud native lift
and shift is still a problem it's a big
problem and
yes there is a challenge because if you
lift and shift the architecture and the
technology from the on-prem and just
make it run in the cloud you are not
enjoying the benefit of the cloud and
I'm not even talking about Security even
the cost is not optimized if you just
lift and shift I know that sometimes you
have no choice and you have to start it
this way and
re-architecture and rewrite the
application later on yes it happens and
I think that when thinking about lifting
and shifting and migrating to the cloud
always remember there is no place for
you to connect your firewall anymore it
works differently and you have to if you
don't have the knowledge in-house you
need to bring in a the consultant that
will give you that will give you again
the the in the the things that will
quickly give you the value of just you
know making sure that what you have here
that you just lifted and shifted is
secured I think that the cloud vendors
can give some help in that extent uh
it's difficult consider uh rewriting the
application if it makes sense in your
organization I think that sometimes it's
not as difficult as you think you put
some things in a container put your data
in a in a cloud database and things are
going to work smoothly from now on
um just remember that if you lifted and
shifted some things you had in the
on-prem like code and packages that you
had over there and sometimes people
migrate to a global applications to the
cloud it doesn't always make sense so
think carefully before you do it
okay yeah I think that's also a good
question is when you look at the clicks
and shift so you said what is the
overlapping of the application Security
in Cloud security
um
the overlapping look the code is code
right if your code is vulnerable it is
going to be vulnerable in the container
in the cloud or in the basement in your
office and always is still about
applications right so the code that you
write or the code that you copy and
paste
you need to make sure it's not uh
vulnerable and that you understand the
risks that you put inside
remember that there was an company that
tries to have this hard environment
whatever how bad your code is you can
deploy it and the environment will take
care it's more secure and unfortunately
it didn't work out I would have loved to
see the word but it was kind of awkward
anyhow there's one more question it's
like on the principle of police I'm
sorry and the principle of least
privileges on the plumbing which
strategies do you think work best in a
dynamic environment
for example a principle of police
privileges in a secure groups for the
kubernetes
okay so list privileges is a it's a very
important principle if you're building a
cloud native application the the cloud
vendors came up with it as a part of the
shared responsibility model they tell
you hey we are responsible for bare
metal you're responsible for everything
else and you make sure that
permissions are always reduced so I
think there are some even open source
tools to help you
um
try and look where you can reduce
security permissions and
for example Netflix released some open
source tools that can help you see which
permissions are being used and which
ones are not and
statistically you might be able to to
reduce them
um and and it makes sense if you want to
um make your application list privilege
or Lister to take a look at one of these
open source tools I can look for my I
have a list of the open source tools
that I had good experience with so I can
publish it
later on Twitter so you can take a look
um and see if if either one helps you
okay that's a Fairgrounds
she has so much thank you for that nice
talk and Q a uh long q a sorry for that
thanks everybody for listening the whole
day I hope you had learned so for the
morning the very nice opening sessions
from Lisa 14 now we have said Shira
Saban for closing session tomorrow
morning I'm again here to open the
conference with a keynote from Astrid
ozenberg it's a 9 A.M in Ireland UK time
and 10 a.m and you settle European Time
sure thank you again thanks for all you
doing hours and your company has reach
the best have fun in California and I'll
see you soon in person I hope thank you
and thank you everybody to everyone have
a good day