good morning good afternoon hello to
everybody wherever you are welcome to
our hopefully from time being the last
version of global appsec we're doing to
the coffee pandemy I'm looking forward
to the next in-person one and the end of
the year in San Francisco but now we go
on the virtual one and welcome to you
all
I cannot say how much oh enough how much
I misspelled and happy to announce the
first opening keynote speaker Lisa 14 14
I think uh it's a cyber security expert
and who doesn't know she started her
career in securing or trying to secure
uh stock pirates from taking ships in
the club Somalia she has been in the UK
counter-terrorism intelligence before
moving into the UK cyber crime units she
founded her own company Red Gold cyber
security in 2017. Lisa is a professional
speaker trainer entrepreneur a
documentary personality and vlogger I
think I could go on for take all the
hour of uh of the space for announcing
here she has uh it's a she's an expert
in Risk Management Insider threats and
social engineering
uh she has founded
um sorry she's founded a cyber for good
movement called cyber volunteers 19
organization provides pro bono help and
advice to help them protect Hospital
hospitals around Europe from cyber Tech
during the pandemic she also founded
respect and security and I think that's
on our heart for everybody a
volunteering organization
helping to stem out ahead and harassment
in our industry so I think that's a big
thing what she has done as well
uh with no fur video Welcome to this
conference and here you go Lisa Forte
the stage is yours
thank you very much I just share my
screen
hello everyone
um welcome I'm Lisa Forte um that's
quite an introduction that he gave me um
I'm a cyber security professional
um and I specialize in training
um designing sort of programs and risk
management programs and then running
cyber crisis exercises for companies
around the world
um and I'm really fascinated generally
by risk and how we manage risk at
different levels both human technical
um and and how we sort of manage that
and that's very much reflected in my
personal life so if any of you
um happen to follow me online in on any
of the platforms you'll notice that I'm
a climber mccaver
um and I explore abandoned Minds for fun
um and all of that involves the
management of risk in difficult
environments potentially constantly
changing environments and so all of that
plays into my sort of general interest
in this area and how we manage risk
and the talk I'm going to give today
is how we manage risk from the inside we
talk a lot in security about how we
manage risk from protecting against
nefarious actors who are outside of our
organization how we stop them attacking
our organization and the assets that we
have but we also have to be mindful that
sometimes that threat can come from the
inside especially when we're dealing
with
things like developers when we're
dealing with IP when we're dealing with
any sort of r d or commercially
sensitive information
this can be really really attractive to
Insider threats
so I'm going to start by asking who are
insiders because I think this is a
concept that's largely misunderstood
um most of us would say an Insider was
an employee
and that is correct but often what we
forget is insiders can also be
contractors who work in our business
they can be board members they could be
suppliers who maybe have a lot of access
into the company and into the business
they could be interns or volunteers as
well who work again inside the business
an Insider is just somebody who has been
given authorized access to the things
that the company does that's all it is
and they can actually pose a really
substantial risk to the business
potentially because they have not only
been given the access legitimately to
for example uh source code for something
or
um you know intellectual property or a
chemical formula for a drug or whatever
is the business does
not only have they been given legitimate
access to some of those assets which in
itself delivers a bit of risk
they've also got the knowledge of the
business they've often got
a knowledge of how the business Works
what security is in place who's
responsible for
um delivering that security or enforcing
that security
there's been loads of cases of fraud for
instance inside large organizations
where they know how the audits are done
so they know how to avoid being detected
by those audits so they can pose a
really really big challenge both from
the perspective that you've got the the
access that to be honest a lot of
attackers would dream of having
and then you combine that with the
knowledge potentially to avoid or
obfuscate what you're doing and avoid
detection and those two things combined
make it a very difficult threat to
manage and to
um sort of mitigate I suppose
now another thing that always comes my
way in when I talk about Insider threats
is people say to me what is an Insider
threat who are they what do they look
like are they men are they women how old
are they what's the sort of profile
and if you look at the data from U.S
cert there is no one single demographic
profile of an Insider threat we have
seen every possible gender age race
religion everything
um becoming Insider threat so there's no
sort of one profile of person it's not
more likely to be an older person or a
younger person
it very much depends on job role
and I'll come on to that in a moment
when I talk about the different types of
attacks that we see from Insiders
so the first thing I want to tackle is
the difference between
an unintentional Insider and an
intentional Insider and from an
unintentional perspective we're talking
about people who maybe make a mistake
who click on that link in a phishing
email or who are maybe negligent in
something that they do or they send
something to the wrong person or they're
reckless in what they do
in all of those situations they don't
intend to cause harm to the organization
they don't intend to steal something
they don't intend to commit fraud
it's an accident a mistake
I actually don't like calling people
insiders who have made mistakes inside
of threats because I sort of feel that
it puts a really horrible
um sort of title on someone who's
essentially made a mistake which is
something we all do on an almost daily
basis or something I do on an almost
daily basis anyway
however these people are unintentional
they are just going about their daily
business trying to do their job and
something that they do causes uh the
manifestation of a risk
we're not going to talk about those
kinds of people in this talk we're
talking about the other type which is
intentional insiders so these are people
who within the organization whether
they're a contractor an employee a board
member whoever it is
they intend to do the thing they do so
this could be intentionally taking
um sensitive information this could be
intentionally planting a logic bomb or
creating a back door
all of these things are done with intent
and that that's the topic of of this
talk today
now people often also use the phrase
malicious Insider which is also really
misleading because malice is one
motivation for doing these things but
it's not the only motivation
intentional insiders intended to do what
they do but they don't necessarily do it
because of malice sometimes they do it
because they're in a really difficult
financial position and this is a way to
make quick money to pay for a health
bill or to to do something like that so
they're not Melissa they're not being
malicious necessarily they are doing it
for a different reason so we see money
being a motivator fear blackmail
sometimes
sometimes revenge and Malice there's a
whole spectrum of reasons why people do
these things
um so don't just reduce it down to
malice
so there are three types of intentional
Insider attacks that we see we have
theft which could be
um usually sort of this the the
um the theft of intellectual property or
research and development or things like
that so you'll usually see it
um in roles where you have for example
scientists engineers
um developers anyone who's doing
something that's creating something I
suppose you could say within the
business those are the rules that are
the most at risk for theft because if
you think about it let's just use an
example of a pharmaceutical company
if you've got a scientist who's working
on a drug a brand new drug he's got
access to really sensitive information
the HR person probably wouldn't have
access to the formulas for that drug
that they're working on
so they have less opportunity to commit
theft than than the scientist does in
that situation
so that's theft we also have sabotage
this is usually committed by techies
unfortunately by our kind of group of
individuals so it's usually techies
Security Professionals people like that
privileged users or some description
um just purely because everything we do
is is digital so they have the
opportunity to sabotage stuff delete
accounts
um interfere with code stuff like that
so sabotage is usually done by by
techies
and finally we have fraud
um and this is usually committed by
lower level employees people who work in
sort of data entry roles predominantly
who can change details on bank accounts
or insurance policies in order to
um financially enrich themselves I
suppose
foreign
so the next argument that people put
forward and another myth I suppose that
I'd like to dismiss
is that people who do these things are
what we'd say in the UK bad apples or
inherently evil bad people
and I hate this argument because firstly
I think it's rather naive and I think
it's also an argument that can really
put your organization at risk
let's take an example let's imagine for
a moment that your life is taking a turn
for the worse
your partner has left you
you're going through a divorce you're
very very stressed you're fighting a
custody battle
um let's say money's really tight the
you know your bills are adding up you've
got this financial pressure you've just
found out that your mum is really really
ill and you know you need some money to
help with her care you can't even really
afford to run your car at the moment
you're in a really difficult situation
and at work your manager is just not a
nice person they're really difficult
they're making your life hell
um then they're putting up all these
barriers to your job you thought you
were going to get this promotion but
that gets given to somebody else who's
nowhere near as experienced as you
if you imagine being in that situation
you're probably pretty close to Breaking
Point you're probably feeling pretty
isolated you're probably feeling pretty
desperate you're probably feeling really
disenfranchised with your life and with
the things that are happening
and let's imagine that a foreign
competitor to your to your employer
contacts you and says well here's 10 000
Euros as a golden hello
come and take a job with us just bring
along some of the code you've been
working on bring along that report
you've been working on and we'll give
you this money
all of a sudden when you're in that
desperate situation and things are
really really bad for you
that looks attractive that looks like a
good option that looks like a life vest
to get you through this difficult time
and this is the problem we reduce it
down to these people are evil but more
often than not and in almost every case
I've looked at the people who do these
things have been in a difficult
situation
and it's just sort of snowboard to the
point where eventually they do this
so this has become such a big problem
um people being contacted online usually
on LinkedIn but not just on LinkedIn
and encouraged to give information over
about what they're working on or share
things they shouldn't share and it's
become such a big problem that in the UK
MI5 one of our intelligence agencies uh
worked with the center for protection of
national infrastructure to develop an
app which you can download from the app
store which is all about educating
people how to spot suspicious profiles
online how to to to make sure you're not
handing over confidential information
MI5 came over a hundred thousand Brits
have actually been targeted
um in order to get confidential
information on what their company is
working on
and fake profiles are so easy to make
online you can quite easily make
something super convincing that you look
like a recruiter or an HR professional
or whoever it is
and you can contact people and try and
get information about their business and
what they're working on and what the
sort of projects are that they're
working on
for example in the first quarter of 2020
Facebook claimed that they took down 4.5
billion profiles just in the first
quarter that were fake in that same time
frame LinkedIn claimed they took down
7.3 million
Twitter estimate that between five to
fifteen percent of all of their accounts
are fake
so this is a really big problem and this
is a problem that as a society we're
going to have to really look at tackling
because some of these attacks can be
really convincing and I'm going to tell
you an example of how some of these
things could manifest
so
this gentleman will call him Rob is a
scientist let's say
he works in this company
he's a really good scientist he's been
going for a bit of a difficult time he's
been having a divorce he's you know it's
in the pandemic he's he's working hard
and he's a bit lonely like a lot of
people got during the pandemic and one
day he posts on LinkedIn and someone
comments on his post
and this person is a woman and she asks
a question that says something about the
nature of his post
so he's really intrigued and he replies
back to her and he decides to send her a
direct message to explain further what
he was meaning
so he writes historic message to her and
they started back and forth
they start talking about science it
turns out she's a scientist as well for
a different company
they start discussing all sorts of
things and the relationship turns a bit
more romantic let's say we become really
close friends a little bit romantic
relationship going on
and she starts asking lots and lots of
questions about his job he's working on
a very very sensitive project at the
moment he works for a big company in a
lab and she's asking lots of questions
about what he does and he's really
flattered so he's sending her lots of
information he's telling her lots of
stuff that he's working on
she wants to see what he's doing and
wants to discuss the science behind some
of those things
and obviously he's really flattered by
this whole process
so the relationship progresses and
as covid was locked down she's saying to
him regularly you know oh I've taken up
dancing and I'm getting really good at
him I want to post some videos and
create a YouTube channel would you mind
reviewing some of my dancing videos
so he's pretty flattered she's a
beautiful woman a beautiful Bulgarian
scientist oh sorry
um and
he says okay yeah sure so she sends him
some videos and she he watches them and
you know he sort of replies with the
expected responses that you just you'd
have thought he would
and then one day he's at work in the
office
and she says to him oh you know I'm
about to upload this new video
um would you mind if you just quickly
reviewed it
yeah sure send it to me
so she sends it to him it arrives on his
phone
he tries to click on it doesn't open
sensor response saying try to open it on
my phone won't open
she says oh no no that's because it
won't open on a phone it it just doesn't
like the operating system you have to
open it on a Windows device
okay so knowing that he shouldn't do
this he forwards the email from his
personal email to his work account
he goes into the open plan office goes
into the email opens the email
clicks on the video
still doesn't play
replies to her again and says look it's
still not playing I don't I don't know
why it's broken but it's broken I'm
sorry
so she replies oh yeah I had that
problem too
turns out that on the newer laptops and
the newer Windows devices it just won't
play I don't suppose you have like a
really old device a really old laptop a
really old computer or some description
it's running some sort of really old
programs
um I think some of the new software
interferes with the video
so things like eight there's only one
place in this organization where we have
really old devices and that's in the lab
so they're running really old software
for reasons that they need to to run
that software
so into the lab he goes
and he's got the file that he's
downloaded onto USB stick goes into the
lab plugs it into one of the lab
computers which he knows he shouldn't do
goes to open the video
still doesn't open
so at this point he's getting frustrated
and he said look I'm really sorry
um you know I've tried to open it I've
done it in the lab where we're running
sort of really old window software
and it's still not opening
um I'm sure it'll be great just post it
on YouTube I'll watch it later
and it turned out that the video was a
little bit less MP4 and a little bit
more malware
and thankfully the company discovered
this and no damage was done
but this person had managed to convince
him to break security rule after
security rule after security Rule and he
intentionally knowingly did all of those
things because he met this person and he
thought he was reviewing a video that
she was
wanting to Post online
so insiders are valuable I mean if you
think about what I just told you that
example
it's very common that they'll get you
talking about your work and you'll and
you'll be quite happy to do so because
you're relatively flattered that someone
is that interested in what you do
um they'll ask for proof of things that
you're working on documents files things
like that
um we've seen people who have actually
managed to get confidential reports
screenshotted and sent them as well
um and I think there was a social
engineering side of it which I won't go
into which is the people who are
creating these fake profiles
contacting you are under a pretext
and getting you to hand over information
or to do something
but you have to also see that from The
Insider perspective these people are
these insiders are breaking security
rules passing information they shouldn't
being sort of I guess lured into the
promise of
Financial enrichment or or whatever it
is so insiders are incredibly valuable
now in security we love a kill chain
kill chains for everything every type of
attack let's map it out like this so
typically
um the way we kind of see this work
is that whoever it is whether it's a
nefarious actor like an attacker whether
it's a competitor whether it's a foreign
State whoever the actor is behind the
the plan to get the information
they'll obviously do some reconnaissance
on the business
maybe they'll have targeted specific
businesses especially for theft specific
businesses that
um are developing really interesting
software or developing sort of uh really
interesting interesting engineering
projects or the vaccine for example
during covid
there'll be a first Contact so it will
usually be something pretty innocuous
it'll be something a bit
um
usually quite friendly nothing massively
um to raise any alarm Bells
over time they will build some rapport
with you to make you think that they are
a recruiter or whoever the pretense is
that they are they're coming to you from
then they'll usually test that Rapport
so they'll ask you for something really
little to just see whether you'll do the
thing that they're asking you to do
then they'll do the attacks or the
execution of the orders what they
actually want to achieve which from this
situation is usually to steal
information
um the other Insider attacks are a
little bit more personal
um and we'll come on to those in a
moment but from a theft perspective
usually if you're looking at sort of
corporate or industrial Espionage or
you're looking at state-based Espionage
um this is easy to steal information
sometimes it's to sabotage the company
as well but that's usually pretty noisy
so it's it's more about acquiring source
code or acquiring chemical formulas or
whatever it is
and then they'll usually extract from
the engagement pretty swiftly and this
will usually be that the profiles that
they had online get deleted really
quickly
um sometimes they'll have a whole story
of why they need to sort of disappear
and that's usually done so that they can
re-enter again and contact you again
later on if they need to and sometimes
they do genuinely offer people jobs give
them money to steal the information and
then those jobs do in fact exist and
people go on and and do those jobs so
it's not always that it's it's all a lie
but it's definitely got some intent
behind it that perhaps you didn't
realize
so some of the things that we see as
like the approaches or the reasons why
people might approach you especially for
theft specifically to get you to take
something from your company that you
shouldn't take and give it to somebody
who shouldn't have it for whatever
reason
so we often see this from recruitment is
a big one
in fact in the MI5 campaign they talk a
lot about recruiters people claiming to
be recruitment Consultants
or HR people in a company
who are recruiting you
I have actually had some conference
invites where people have invited me to
speak at events and let's just say that
some of the invites have been incredibly
suspicious I've had a few friends who've
also had this happen to them where
they've wanted information on things
that you just suddenly think this is a
bit weird I'm not sure this is a real
conference at all
um we can we've also seen it from
romance and friendship like in the
example I gave
um that woman starting a romantic
relationship also you know friendship as
well can also work
business opportunities consultancy work
investment in your company or your new
business Promises of business
Partnerships and all of this sort of
thing
um is is really really common as reasons
that they might contact you in order to
to get you to do something
so we've talked a little bit about how
this can be done
from the perspective of an outsider
manipulating you on some level to do it
but this can also happen from people
themselves in their own organizations
and there's two kind of examples that I
want to give you from a sort of techy
space I suppose
so start with theft
so in this case
um the person in question was an
engineer they worked at a sort of visual
simulation software company
and they resigned and at their exit
interview they were asked have you
returned all of the devices have you
returned you know do you have any copies
of any of the code blah blah blah
and
um they said they sort of lied at this
exit interview and they said yeah I've
returned absolutely everything there's
nothing I have at all
so they leave and that's all sort of
tied up from the company's perspective
and they decide that they're going to
become sort of self-employed a
consultant and it turns out that
actually they had stolen the source code
for this new product
they then over the next year actually
spent time coercing people who they'd
previously worked with at this company
to give them more information and more
um
sort of
interesting pieces of of r d I suppose
you could say related to this
so that happened over the course of
probably just under a year
and then they accepted a job for another
company so they decided to leave the
consultancy space they accepted this job
where they went to work for this other
company that was a competitor of the
company that they'd stolen the source
code of
so they go and work for this company and
obviously
develop this stolen this stolen code
into another product and they go to this
conference and they this company that
they're now working for they do this big
launch of this product
and it just so happened that
representatives of his previous employer
were at the same event and saw that the
product that they were launching was a
hundred percent
a stone product from their company put
two and two together and went oh my God
they've stolen all this stuff
so in this particular instance actually
the the company was really lucky because
they actually reported it to the
authorities and the they actually found
evidence that this individual had stolen
this source code and then they'd taken
that and given it to this competitor
developed this product launched it the
whole sort of chain was proven
um and they got I think it was ten
thousand dollar fine and I think they
got two years in jail as a result of it
this individual so in that particular
case
in some ways they were too noisy about
it maybe with the launch I don't know
um but they got caught
and this individual actually was put in
prison for it
so it is a crime we have to be aware
that that is a crime
um and sometimes companies do actually
have the ability to prove that someone
has stolen these things
so that's theft that's stealing of
something
in some ways sabotage is
harder to understand
um and this often happens because most
of the situations were sabotage happen
because someone is angry with their
employer they're disgruntled they are
um usually either planning on leaving or
actually handed in their notice
and they want revenge sabotage comes
from a feeling of anger a feeling of
sort of Beyond discontent really
disgruntlement perhaps and the need to
sort of exact revenge on this employer
that you think has done something bad to
you
so in this case
um there was a software developer and
they actually were terminated from their
job for poor performance
and they they left the company and they
actually got a job
their next job with a subsidiary of that
same company which was a bit odd and
that was about a month later or so
but what happened was the company that
had fired this person
hadn't deactivated his accounts so he
managed over the course of a few months
to access I think it was something like
30 odd user accounts he got into
people's emails he managed to review and
change code that was being used within
the organization
um deleted like software
um modification notices uh created
accounts he actually deleted or removed
both the CEO and the cfo's accounts at
one point completely disabled them
um there was a assist admin in the
organization who
actually would log into her account and
see that someone had logged in an hour
ago and he was logging in and doing
stuff from the sysadmin account so he
had all this access and they hadn't
disabled any of it they hadn't
um changed anything and he was really
good at deleting logs hiding what he was
doing
um and sort of just generally being a
nuisance
and it wasn't until they actually
changed some employees around within the
company that they did a review of all
the accounts and this was a long time
afterwards
um that they realized what was happening
and this gentleman was sort of having I
suppose in English law terms going off
on a Frolic of his own and sort of doing
all these sorts of things so again he
was sort of interfering and and
sabotaging and in that case he didn't he
didn't do an awful lot of damage it was
more
being a nuisance really more than it was
causing huge damage but we have seen in
sabotage cases people planting logic
bombs we have seen people creating back
doors we have seen people creating
accounts and then selling them on the
dark web or defacing the company website
has happened a lot
um
so we've seen a lot of these things
happen and again like I said at the very
beginning because all our businesses are
run digitally now almost all the cases
involving sabotage are techies because
we are privileged account holders
we are pretty much the only people in
the business who could really do
a lot of damage when it comes to
sabotage
um and if you think about it from your
own roles if you wanted to sabotage the
organization there's a lot of ways you
could do it that would be hugely
damaging
so those are sort of a few more examples
I suppose
of
how insiders have as I said at the
beginning the access to the crucial
things so account modification codes IP
all of the sort of crucial systems
applications and assets that a company
might have insiders have access to those
legitimately they also have the
knowledge of how to hide things
especially techies especially people who
work in I.T security
you know how to hide your tracks
you know how to cover things up you may
even be the person responsible for
spotting these things
so you have an ability to cover Your
Tracks very easily which an outsider
doesn't have the same capability as an
Insider for doing that
so Insider threat
can be a huge huge problem and
specifically they are a massive problem
for any company that's working in sort
of a high r d space so things like
businesses in the new economy market so
anything to do with technology but also
sort of scientific based Industries as
well especially for theft really very
vulnerable to Insider attacks
so what do we do
well one of the kind of key things that
I've been working on recently is
developing
um an awareness of everybody into
creating Insider threat programs and
feeding into internet threat programs so
in the US they tend to be a little bit
more advanced on this concept than in
Europe and and the UK
um
but we should all have Insider threat
programs operating within our our
organization just like we do for all
other elements of security
and I argue that there's four elements
that need to go into that inside the
threat program
the first one is training
so
stripped back down recognize
potentially malicious profiles online
people who might be trying to contact
you because you are working in the absec
space you are an attractive Mark
potentially you're going to have access
to things that are interesting that are
valuable financially valuable
so because of that you have to be a
little bit more aware of what
potentially malicious profiles might be
like
so if you have an opportunity go and
download the cpni app on the App Store
free to download
um was created by MI5 and cpni go
download it and and just go through the
training program it's really quick
really easy gives you a bit of an idea
of what these profiles look like
um so training is really good to make
sure that we're aware
of what this sort of thing looked like
but also if you're having a conversation
with somebody online
and just just look at the way the
conversation is going and what I mean by
that is if you're having a conversation
with someone who's pretending to be a
friend or a recruiter or whoever they're
pretending to be and you don't know this
person
look at the conversation and think is
this normal does this look like a
conversation I would have with other
friends or other recruiters or other
business people
because the chances are
if they're trying to get information out
of you they are probably asking you
questions and you are probably doing all
the talking
and generally in a conversation it's
pretty balanced it's pretty 50 50. if it
doesn't look that way just allow that to
trigger some alarm bells in you
and then think about how you would
report these things if they happened or
you know if you spot somebody within
your organization who you think might be
doing something they ought not to be
doing how do you report that
so that's training support
um one of the things I talk about a lot
is that actually one of the best ways to
stop Insider threats happening within
your organization is for employees to
feel supported and to feel like they've
got someone to turn to if they've got
problems
so using the example of sabotage for
instance
as I said before we know sabotage
happens because somebody is angry they
are taking Revenge out against their
company
so if you have a situation where you can
detect that this person is really
unhappy in their role that maybe they're
going through financial troubles maybe
they're having a hard time personally
maybe they're having mental health
problems gambling issues or whatever it
is that's happening to them that's
affecting their life
um you can put in place
as organizations can put in place
Employee Assistance programs to help
them
to stop them from getting to the point
where they are angry or in financial
trouble and thinking about potentially
taking something and selling it to
somebody else
we have the ability to provide support
for our staff and employees to the
degree that actually they're not
vulnerable to being manipulated they're
not vulnerable to being approached and
offered money because we are there to
help them and support them if they need
it and that is a real real key point if
you're going to have an Insider threat
program that works it has to be based
off of that
we also need ability for people to
report stuff so we need to have an
ability to whistle but I mean on my on
my website red red hyphengo.com there is
a white paper research paper that I that
I did a few years ago
um free to download
um go and have a look at it it talks
about how reluctant we are to report
people who are doing something and in
this piece of research we looked at we
gave all of the participants
um a set of scenarios of things that
they saw somebody in their organization
doing and some of these things were
outrageously bad
and it turned out that in fact the only
people they were happy to go and report
and say this person's doing something
dodgy this person's doing something bad
the only category of people they were
happy to do that for were contractors
nobody else colleagues they didn't want
to report
if their boss was doing something bad
they didn't want to report that either
and it turned it was actually quite
surprising that people felt I can't go
and report on a colleague I can't go and
report on a manager who's doing
something they shouldn't be doing
so you have to think about that as well
how can we encourage people within our
companies to say oh I don't think
something's right with this person I'm a
bit concerned about them or I saw them
doing some this thing that they
shouldn't be doing and how can we do
that in a supportive way that doesn't
penalize people but also doesn't create
this culture of
um oh you went and told on me so now I'm
going to sort of
um in you know sort of impede your
progress within in the organization
so reporting is another really important
thing
and then finally monitoring so we do
need some monitoring on some of the key
key job roles within our organization so
as I said before going back to those
three attacks theft going to be people
who are developing software developing
um scientists maybe who are developing
chemicals or drugs or things like that
Engineers who are working on projects
the people who are going to steal stuff
are going to have access to the
stealable information right so we could
monitor that group of people
sabotage we know almost completely
committed uh by Security Professionals
techies developers so some monitoring on
that group of individuals
fraud which was the final attack we know
low level data entry roles so we can put
some monitoring on that group of people
we don't need to monitor the entire
organization
aggressively that's not necessarily
appropriate in fact
um as most of us are in Europe in the EU
um the European courts have been really
really clear that any monitoring you do
on your staff has to be proportionate
and has to be necessary and has to be
restrictive I had a company the other
week who was talking to me about an
Insider threat program they were trying
to put in place and they were talking
about their monitoring and they said to
me is it okay if we can just turn on the
webcams of the the laptops the personal
laptops of our staff and I thought no
you you can't you can't do that that's
not that is not restrictive that's not
that's not okay so we do need some
monitoring but we have to make sure that
that monitoring is reasonable
it's as small as possible don't do more
than you have to
um making sure that whatever monitoring
you put in place you can actually use
because in a lot of situations you will
collect logs on things and then you have
no ability to review them so there's no
point in collecting them
um so making sure that you're doing you
know a bit of monitoring but not too
much and making sure that that's really
just open and honest with your staff so
making sure everyone is aware of what
monitoring is on them
and why I think is is kind of a key
point
so the final thought I kind of want to
leave you with is
I have this sort of general theory with
Insider threats that someone who is
Happy satisfied content enjoying life
doesn't turn around and steal stuff from
their employer doesn't turn around and
sabotage their employer there's no need
to commit fraud because you've got money
you've got lots to lose you've got a
nice life
so the more we can think about creating
a work environment that's that looks
like that for our employees the more we
reduce the threat and I tweeted the
other day that if you're inside a threat
program is just monitoring monitoring
monitoring you've probably increased
your risk of an Insider threat
so it's really important that we send a
message to all of our colleagues
our staff that actually you're not alone
if you have problems if you have
troubles if you're going through a tough
time if you hate your job within our
within the organization we are open to
having a discussion about how we improve
that situation for you
and then you're reducing your
vulnerability to people being paid to
hand over information you're reducing
your vulnerability of people being so
annoyed with your company that they want
to sabotage it
and I think that's the best way to
reduce the threat
so I hope you enjoyed the talk I think
we've got a few minutes for questions
hopefully from Martin
um but before we tend to that I just
want to quickly give a shout out to uh
respection security which is a volunteer
organization that I co-founded with a
bunch of other people and I really
recommend you go and check them out
follow them participate in the
discussion
um it's a voluntary organization we
created to try and Stamp Out hate and
harassment in the sort of tech
um security industry and there's loads
of initiatives there that you can get
involved with but it's all about trying
to stop bullying and trolling and all of
that sort of thing that goes on in our
industry sadly so please please go and
give them some support it's a really
important message
thank you waiting for Martin
thank you so much Lisa really great
presentation as expected and uh yes we
have several questions well first one I
want to ask how common are those Insider
threat attacks
Insider threats are
they're not hugely common thankfully the
problem with them is when they happen
they are really really really serious so
it's one of those things that they don't
happen a lot necessarily
but we've seen it with Tesla for example
they had a really bad one not not too
long ago we've seen it with lots of
other companies that have had this sort
of thing happen they are really usually
really serious and actually really
publicly embarrassing when you have to
say yeah that was one of our developers
that stole that sorry that's a really
embarrassing thing for a company to say
it's also uh types of companies that are
more vulnerable to those attacks
yeah I'd say probably
um companies that operate in sort of new
economy markets so tech companies would
be really vulnerable because it's such a
high r d space we're developing new
stuff all the time and the other one
that I've seen recently actually is the
gaming space as well so people who are
working in developing
um sort of PlayStation games and things
like that that's actually a really
um aggressive Market where people are
getting paid a lot of money to hand over
things they're working on
okay another question is uh as you
mentioned uh for the threat or tampering
was told the question is what is the
share I think the speed of internal
threats versus external threat when it
comes to code tempering theft from what
have you seen during your assessments
for in a lot of these situations
sometimes it can be quicker and easier
to get in Via social engineering by
talking to somebody who works in the
company and getting them to hand over
information
um and again it comes back to that
position so there was a gaming company
recently I forget what the name of it
was you had this situation and it turned
out one of their developers was a pretty
young person I think there's been a lot
of talk in the gaming industry about how
overworked people are who develop games
um and this particular person was not at
all satisfied with their job was hugely
stressed
um and I think they were paid 40 000
Euros to hand over a little bit of
information of what they were working on
now this person I think was like 26 27
they were really young
um 40 000 Euros and a lot of money
it's a lot of money if you think you're
not going to get caught right so they
did they handed it over and I think you
see that's where the line kind of blurs
it's not necessarily just only outside
people inside people it kind of
um the share of it can sort of yeah
change but I think you know a lot of
these things unfortunately they're going
to benefit competitors it's not
necessarily for organized criminals it's
for people who compete with your company
right
oh yeah another question is so between
the theft League sabotage or other types
of text
which one was the most popular in the
past 12 months
uh theft big time yeah and I think it's
because
um generally I I don't know if some of
you might have heard of this uh they
talk about the great resignation that's
happening now globally right because of
covid and everything that's happened
um and because you've got loads of
people moving jobs it's a perfect
opportunity to take a few copies of some
of the things you've been working on and
go and sell them so I think theft is the
biggest problem because
um also people you know it's difficult
with the cost of living issues the
increase in gas prices the increase in
in lots of our bills
um people are struggling for money as
well so if someone comes up and offers
you 40 000 Euros
starts to look a bit more attractive
doesn't it
the next second part of the same
question is what are some of the
forecasts for the next 12 to 24 months
some of the forecasts and that's
interesting
um so I think one of the big problems
we're going to have is this hybrid
working I think hybrid working is great
for a number of reasons like I work I
work in a hybrid working environment my
company employs hybrid working
um but I do think the problem is you
don't have the visibility as you did
when they're in the office and the
problem you have with that is that it
does
um allow people to take copies of things
that you might not notice I had um a
company the other day who was an
investment bank and they had people
working from home and they said there's
no way they'd be able to steal any of
these documents and send them out and I
said to them but they're working from
home so of course they can and they said
no no it's fine they can't we monitor
all of it they wouldn't be able to do it
and I said well I can do it by doing
this
take a photo on my phone done and then
they thought oh yeah they could do that
couldn't they that would that would work
we wouldn't notice that so I think
that's one problem that we are going to
see that hybrid working
does give more opportunity to people
being able to do things that they
probably might not want to do in an
office environment so I think we will
see more theft
um I do think that with sabotage again
there's a lot of people who are going
through tough times at the moment and I
think as soon as you start putting all
these different pressures on people
food crises cost of living crises
um all of this pressure that's going on
different people I do think we might
start to see people becoming more
agitated and that might also go up
yeah thanks though one more question
um yes reporting can go the wrong way if
people trust can report or colleagues
they don't like or are competitors in
the workplace how you afford that
problem
so I think you need Anonymous reporting
to try and encourage people to report
genuine bad behavior but as you say the
other problem is well if I really hate
my colleague I'm just going to put in a
report to say that she's doing all these
horrible things right
um and that's not necessarily true and
that comes down to then your security
teams and your Insider threat teams
being able to go through it and actually
establish whether it's true or not
um and that is it is complicated you see
this happen with policing right there's
it's the same sort of thing
um and I think yeah so I think that the
way you investigate reports has to be
really fair I think it has to be
thorough it has to be evidence-based and
you have to sort of have those processes
in place to ensure
that if you do get people reporting on
people they hate just for fun or
whatever they're doing you have a
process that they don't get disciplined
um but it is a yeah it is a genuine
concern and that's why sometimes I think
we have to accept that there isn't one
good solution it's just a choice of not
very good Solutions
I remember several years ago I was at a
conference in the Netherlands and there
was one guy he called himself he's not a
security uh role he has a he's
transparency uh you know transparency
officer because he wants people to be
able to work transparency and then very
transparent way to report so it was
Anonymous or by name and of course
beginning when you could report
everything on everybody
and the whole following up was very
transparent to the one who is Accused he
said by making it very transparent you
suddenly have a environment where it's
not blaming but just asking like why are
you well having two laptops carrying out
it's just a very normal things like this
normally don't ask but it was really
interesting one and they were only
hidden those who did something wrong I
said not even on purpose but just have
been tricked by uh this you know
tricksters
went on the videos and explained their
case so I lost my job because I didn't
saw those signs and because they were
system spelled and not just goodbye we
have to fire you but also help them to
continue with them outside
to be even so that I come up the video
they do recording tell their style Story
how they have been tricked I think
that's very impressive yeah yeah and
yeah and ultimately you can help them
right if
and get involved early enough you can
help them before they've done something
that they can't undo
yes definitely so thank you so much for
being here uh thank you for everybody
else enjoy the conference I am happy to
also be the moderator for the closing
keynote for today so enjoy the
conference thanks again Lisa and I
really like uh appreciate what you do
with respect and security uh I think
that's what we all do uh need respect
each other and have things are happy and
joyful went for a conference thank you
thank you very much thanks bye everyone