hello and welcome everybody to the
Builder strike my name is Tatiana
balendir and I'm a principal security
architect at Diamond track and today I
will be moderating this session
in the next 45 minutes
um Matt will talk us through the
landmines in the API landscape
at the end of the session we have 10 to
15 minutes to address your questions
please put these questions in the text
form in the window close to the on the
right of the Hoover
a streaming panel and we'll be watching
that and addressing this
and the please note that the chat
function in Zoom is blocked for
attendees so use the Hoover app chat
and Q a pain for addressing questions
and with that said
Welcome Matt and
let's enjoy your talk
yes thank you very much let me get my
screen shared
we'll get rolling assuming you're seeing
my screen which should be all good
so as Tatiana said welcome to land mines
and the API landscape let's get started
I this is a bit of a gonna be a bit of a
fire hose I've got lots of lots of
material for you
so quickly just going through the what
we're going to talk about I'll do a
quick intro a little bit of background
and whatnot I'll go into why attack apis
and what makes them interesting and why
they're well I mean I guess it was uh
Gartner was saying that they're going to
be the number one attack Vector in this
year which is probably going to be true
and then I'll talk about finding
landmines where the problems are and I'm
going to take this from the perspective
of both an attacker
what an attacker would do as well as a
Defender and what the defender sees when
those types of attacks happen and then I
have a conclusion a couple of key
takeaways Etc
so who am I I'm Matt tesaro I'm a I call
myself a reformed programmer and an
appsec engineer at my first job out of
college was writing
php3 which tells you how long ago that
was
I currently work as a distinguished
engineer for No Name Labs I've got
14-ish years with the OS Community my
main core maintainer of defect Dojo I'm
a co-lead of the appsec pipeline oh I
need to put it I'm also doing the
podcast now so I should put that in
there too and oswg is kind of dead so I
should probably take that off I'll
replace it with the podcast for my next
deck
I've got 22-ish years of using free
Libra and open source and Linux I'm
currently when I write code I write it
in go and that's a picture of me doing a
dual front kick board break to get my
second degree black belt and I also am a
founder of 10 security
so why why attack apis well apis are
simple right it's it's just you know you
read the Wikipedia definition an
application programming interface is a
connection between computers or between
computer programs right so your program
written in say Ruby makes a rest call
say to my program written and go and I
sent you back some stuff over HTTP
straightforward super simple no biggie
well actually it's much more complicated
than that when you get down to it and
you actually have the setup kind of for
real these end up being very complicated
if you have say a web application here
backed by a bunch of apis you'll usually
have an API Gateway in between that web
app
and the apis you'll have a web
application firewall in place you might
have a mobile app that talks directly to
the API Gateway those first level of
apis may end up calling back to other
apis that are within your uh DC or maybe
off in some other cloud or it could even
be a third-party provider that you're
getting services from so these things
get really tangled really quick when you
do them at scale
okay
so let's say you do have an appsec
program in place and it's pretty solid
and you're pretty happy with it if you
look at the circle on the left that's
kind of the general app set tooling you
would have right you might have a WAFF
and SAS and dust and SCA threat modeling
developer training some kind of anti-bot
in place
um hopefully you have an app inventory
right if you have all those things in
place and you add API security tooling
or well if you consider the API security
tooling you need there is some overlap
like SAS works the same for an API in a
normal application threat modeling same
maybe different questions but generally
the same sea can work for both desks
maybe works for both if you have a
decent Dash tool although Dash tools
generally don't do all that great with
the traditional task tools don't do all
that great with apis but then you have
all these other things that are very API
specific that are probably not in your
tool belt
uh in a traditional or a normal or you
know whatever appsec program that hasn't
seen apis before so there's a lot of Gap
and this this this large gap is I think
where a lot of the issues come from
so you may have a great app set of
controls but API security issues won't
get caught by all of them
and it's all about the data like if you
think about the what was that uh Clive
humby I don't know how to say that for
British band's name
um but he coined the term the data is a
new oil right and if you're moving the
new data around you're going to move it
around in pipelines and in Tech those
pipelines are apis that's how you move
data around
and so now you have the value of a lot
of businesses being the data they hold
and how they move that data around being
apis
and then the flip side of the coin is as
over the years we've had browsers that
have got continually and incrementally
gotten better and better and the
controls we have in place
be they a ton of different security
headers now you can use for web
applications as well as MFA and captchas
and
uh tons and tons of browser
hardening mechanisms that we now have at
play those don't exist for apis and apis
haven't had the years and years of sort
of field deployment at scale that
browsers have had and so in a lot of
cases you'll see that if the same
functionality exists on a website or an
API as an attacker the API represents
something with far less controls or
security guard rails around it so why
wouldn't I attack that API
and then just quick talk about different
types of testing because I'm well I'll
explain why I need that in a minute
right you can have black box where an
attacker has zero knowledge it's you
know quite literally I'm sitting down
with a laptop in a coffee shop somewhere
and just poking at IPS
a gray box where you may have uh limited
information on the target use is usually
for like a penetration test where you'll
have maybe an IP range so at least you
know where to focus your attacks but
they don't give you much more than that
uh white box where you have full
knowledge and a lot of times the some of
the controls like I said a web
application firewall or some kind of
intervening device will be turned off
and then crystal box where you have full
knowledge including source code right so
these are different levels of attack and
the reason I talk about these when I get
into the landmines I'm going to talk
about them from the perspective of Black
Box because that's the least knowledge
you can have hopefully if you're working
at a place you'll be much more white or
crystal box but I wanted to give you
kind of the more full overview of what's
there
and then you cannot forget my favorite
pro bono pen testing otherwise known as
somebody hacking you right this is what
happens when you put an answering port
on the internet somebody starts poking
at you so this is always
in the background uh free with any
internet connection is somebody poking
at your resources
and then finally when I talk about API
security I think there's three major
areas or pillars or categories whatever
you want to say
that are worth talking about
um one is API security posture and and
this is just understanding the inventory
and all of the apis that you have all
the endpoints as well as who's calling
that API are you where is that call
originating from is this an internal you
know API to API call or is this coming
from public internet and then probably
most importantly too what what data is
set and received right am I sending out
pii or some other kind of personal or
gdpr type data is it just public data
what is it right how how sensitive is
that data and so if you have that
inventory and a categorization of how
sensitive the data is you have a very
good sort of map of your apis and you
can make some good decisions in terms of
how much effort is worth putting behind
securing those different apis
and then API runtime security so this is
watching the traffic that goes to and
from your apis through some mechanism
and and getting an idea of what normal
traffic is and then obviously doing
anomaly detection to find out what is
abnormal traffic and doing alerting or
detection or whatever it takes to sort
of let the security team know hey
there's something wonky going on with
this API
and then API security testing so this is
just to get an assessment of the
security state of your API now since
API the the source code that makes up
API and the source code that makes up
applications
are going to be tested the same for SAS
I don't generally include SAS in API
security testing because that really is
just the normal part of what I would
consider appsec
um so really this is generally speaking
dast testing of apis
um and then you need to take those
results that you get and feed them into
whatever makes sense for your business
that's usually something like a jira
backlog or whoever your developers
track issues with the software and
hopefully get them fixed
so it's posture run time and uh testing
and then finally I think one thing from
a security perspective you need to have
a slightly different definition of an
API I think the term apis almost become
like the term website it's so broad that
it kind of means nothing so I I am very
specific when I say API what I mean by
an API particularly in regards to
security controls is three different
things you have a host name right what
what DNS name is that API running on
right you know I don't know
uat.bigport.com
you have a path right slash API slash V3
slash users or API V1 slash cart show
items whatever the the path is
and then you have an HTTP method right
post put git patch delete
Etc
and why you need all three of those is
to make a good security decision you
have to have all three because you can
have only one of those variant very
radically different uh security postures
can exist
for example doing a get request to V2
users all in other words getting a list
of all the users is very different than
a delete request to all users right it
may be bad to go for an attacker let's
say to get a list of all users but it's
even worse if they can delete all your
users
so here's an example where only the HTTP
method changed but the security
ramifications and controls we need Etc
around it are radically different and
then in that that second example we're
posting to uat.example.com
uh user admin
here I'm adding an admin user to a uat
environment may be kind of interesting
not super scary in the second example
we are posting to production and adding
an admin while adding an admin in
production is a very interesting from a
security perspective
something happening so this is another
case where it's just a single method
name change everything else is the same
but the security ramifications are
radically different
okay let's go find us some landmines
so I'm going to start in a traditional
sort of uh pen testing perspective let's
do some Recon let's find apis to attack
from a black box perspective
so the first thing you'd want to do is
just do passive Recon right just gather
all the information you can about your
potential targets and even if you are
internal I think doing this exercise
either at your desk or maybe from a
coffee shop if you want the true
external perspective and a nice coffee
um isn't such a bad thing
but in a passive Recon you're going to
have no direct interaction with the
target this is just to see what is out
in the public internet so to speak for
your apis what can I find out now this
may be a lot if your API is a public API
that's meant to be used
such as like the GitHub API that's very
public they don't hide the documentation
for that Etc right that's by Design if
it isn't internal though API you
probably don't want to find much of
anything about it so this is where you
just want to know what the world sort of
knows about your API you can do things
like Google dorks the oasma mass tool is
fantastic for DNS enumeration you might
look at things like showdan
um programmable web and apis.guru are
two great sites to find lists of
publicly known apis which are yours or
may or may not be listed depending on
the the background
if it is a public or open source thing
this is where GitHub issues and PRS can
be very interesting to find potential uh
security issues and then if it is a
public API there may be stacked over for
overflows or something like that where
someone's trying to get help within a
particular API call
from the defender side
you really can't do much it's public
info now you can do things like I've
seen vendors put the API docs behind a
customer login page right and that may
make sense depending on the use case of
your API and that certainly can sort of
make it harder to find out about your
apis
um so you may not want to advertise them
at all but you may also want to
advertise them because you make money by
people using your apis like if you're a
stripe you want your apis to be as easy
to use as possible so you will have a
getting started page you will have
public documentation so this may or may
not be something you can actively do
something about but in the case of the
tooling posture runtime testing they're
not really in play here because we're
not even sending any kind of traffic to
your API so and you can't really test
your API to see if the dots are public
so this is more just of a human exercise
and so you've done your passive Recon
now it's time to go active and this is
where you gather public information all
that you can from your targets by and
also playing nice right as opposed to uh
not sending any traffic now you're
sending traffic but you're not trying to
be malicious yet you're just sort of
getting a feel for things
so the idea here is to do basic
um Recon do things like you can look at
the robust.text if particularly if
you're completely blindly looking at
this if you're looking at a API backed
website this is where the dev tools the
network Tab and all those different tabs
that you have in your browser Dev tools
will give you great hints at what's out
there obviously local proxies like zap
or burp are fantastic for this either
for API back mobile apps or websites
um you can do things like brute forcing
URLs with something like dirtbuster
Derby Go Buster they're all the sort of
popular uh directory uh
directory brute forcing tools and Kite
Runner is a API focused brute forcer
that's very useful but and maybe even an
nmap scan but
at best for the defender
it's pretty hard to see this this
traffic s attack traffic right if I run
an M app against your
IP range you could probably see that but
honestly if you have an open IP to the
internet everybody's in Mountain
everybody but you're getting enough nmap
that I'll just get lost in the shuffle
um if you have a single page web app or
a API backed mobile app you can't do
anything about Dev tools they're built
into everybody's browser you just have
to deal with that
I have seen interesting things with
robots.txt before where uh one
particular client I was interacting with
had
their CPU intensive Pages listed in
robots.txt because when they got crawled
it was actually spiking CPU usage
on their website and my position to them
was you probably need a better way to
handle this because for as an attacker
that robots.txt is almost like a guide
to doing a Dos of your web application
um
and then for
um the three types of tools posture in
this case really just helps you focus
your limited resources where it needs to
be the most the most risky of your apps
run time can discover active recount if
it's noisy enough certainly something
like durbuster or Kite Runner will be
rather uh obvious particularly if I'm
trying to if you have a non-public API
and I'm trying to Brute Force Brute
Force Uris for that API those will stand
out pretty blatantly and then testing
this is Recon there's not too much you
can do about testing from a recount from
a testing perspective
so we're done with Recon let's move on
to Discovery
so I've got targets how do I use them
legitimately
right so this is where it particularly
if you're first seeing an API and
testing it you need to just understand
how to legitimately use that thing how
do I make legitimate calls how do I
authenticate how do I do whatever the
use for that API is right if it's stripe
how do I make a transaction
if it is something like stripe that's
very public there will be API
documentation getting started guides
blog posts the whole nine about it
um if not it may be kind of interesting
if it's an API that is not publicly
known
this can be really challenging to figure
out how those things work you may be
able to find a Swagger file a lot of
times there there's a URL or yeah URL
that'll have the Swagger file posted for
you or uh raml whistle waddle all those
different ways to specify uh specs
for the API
um I have had cases where the
provider of the API also provides
something like a command line client
even though their apis may not be
publicly known if you put something like
burp or zap as an upstream proxy to that
client
suddenly you can see exactly how those
API requests work I've also had once
where the documentation was so terrible
that I had to use a client just to find
out how to talk to the API
um and then you you once you get those
particularly when you're doing a blind
attack where you don't have the list of
API endpoints you can start to manually
create a list of those either by brute
forcing finding them in in the dev tools
Etc but you do want to start to
enumerate a list of all the API calls
that are available to you
and then on the flip side as an attacker
um
[Music]
most of the traffic just looks like some
excuse me newbie right uh trying to
learn to use your API they're going to
make some bad off calls but it's going
to be a onesie2z kind of call maybe
there might be some curl requests or
something but it won't look too weird
and it won't be all that pronounced
now if you do have an API backed mobile
app or a single page app
our web application right these May
stand out right if you're only expecting
API calls from your mobile clients like
say Android or iOS and suddenly curl
starts calling your API that's a little
weird right that shouldn't happen and
that can stand out from a Defender point
of view
um and if you have an undocumented
non-public kind of API you're going to
see a lot of
failed requests as the attacker is
trying to understand like exactly what
your API looks like
um
so there's a couple cases where these uh
these Discovery uh attacks for lack of a
better order the discovery activity will
will show up and look pretty pretty
obvious so from a posture perspective
obviously you can use that to focus your
your resources but it's also good to be
able to know like this is an internal
only API I should never see a public IP
hit this thing and if that happens you
get some kind of network issue that's
pretty hairy that you need to jump on
quickly or if you have an API Gateway in
place you should only have requests
originating from the API Gateway and
then suddenly they don't then somehow
someone is able to bypass their API
Gateway
runtime you can certainly discover
some of this traffic if it is things
like I said where you expect a very
specific client only to be talking to
your API and you get some Oddball
requests like curl or you know the
request library from python or something
or if you have undocumented apis you'll
probably see a lot of failure so runtime
can definitely help you here
and testing it's proactive it also
doesn't really help you much for
Discovery hopefully you just won't have
issues to begin with but they're still
going to be discoverable
oh and if you are doing this from a
testing perspective and particularly as
a blind test or a non-public test a
discovery can
seem easy but you can spend loads of
time trying to find there's got to be
another API endpoint here there's got to
be
um so be warned if you're doing the
testing side of this uh don't don't let
this be a time sink
okay let's go on to the active side of
things like let's get malicious now so
as a black box tester I found some apis
I've understood how to to talk to them
legitimately and I have a fairly good
idea of what's out there now it's time
to see if there's some vulnerabilities
and just to be to give some structure to
this and not just sort of randomly talk
about things I grabbed the oh wasp API
top 10 and I'm going to walk through all
of those and explain the attacker and
Defender side of those two pieces
so the first one broken object level
authorization
uh in this example right we have
Benjamin here making a request to an API
with the token a bearer token as well as
his user ID and he gets back Benjamin's
information now there is some pii in
there but hopefully Benjamin knows his
own date of birth and his phone number
is SSN
um but
this is actually a valid request this is
how it should look right this is a good
request
however if Benjamin gets a little
nefarious with us and he keeps his same
token and he keeps the same
name but he changes the user ID to a
different numeric value
he now gets Charlotte's information and
her dob and her phone number in SSN and
this is of course a bad request from a
Defender point of view great request if
you're an attacker
um but this is Bola this is what Bola
looks like
so
from an attacker's perspective how do I
find Bola you can look at how resources
are structured and try to find any kind
of IDs or unique values within API API
calls these can be numbers like like we
saw in the previous example or these may
be non-numeric right these can be simple
like strings right they don't have to be
numbers generally they're numbers but
they don't have to be
um
and then you make calls to those
Resources with your same existing token
however you're authenticating
and you just modify those numbers and
see what happens it's really not too
hard you can also do things if you have
two user accounts create something as
user one
and then as user two try to request that
something and this depends on the use
case of the API if the API has resources
isolated to users then this would be an
example of a bull attack if everything's
public obviously this this is not a
whole lot attack
and then as you're doing these look for
response differences kind of like
fuzzing honestly if there's a different
response code 404 means it doesn't exist
generally speaking if apis are well
coded
um 405 means you're unauthorized so that
tells you 405 does tell you hey there's
a resource there of this not going to
let you see it
time to response can sometimes give you
some clues about existing or interesting
IDs and like the response very very
seldomly happens but sometimes it can
from a Defender
unfortunately detection takes a fairly
deep inspection of those API calls right
in the example I showed a minute ago it
was only that one ID string that changed
otherwise the request was the same and
the good and the bad requests so from a
a looking at the HTTP even the the
payload perspective a lot of laughs are
probably going to fall short here
because it looks like a normal
well-structured bit of Json it doesn't
look weird just one of the data values
inside of there isn't doesn't match what
it would it was expected for your token
right your Bearer token in that case
so
this is really kind of tricky for sort
of more web app focused
intervening devices like Wax to find
so you really need a deeper inspection
to be able to understand that this bear
token is generally associated with this
user not this other user
so this is where you kind of need a
specialized tool or API specific tool I
should say for this
um if you if I'm an attacker and I'm
looking for Ebola you're going to see a
lot of failed requests or authorization
issues so this is a great way to sort of
uh
to find those attackers before they get
to do anything interesting with your
apis
if you see two similar requests with
different ID values in them from the
same client in a short period of time
that is a huge clue and this is
something where if you have decent
anomaly detection with AI or ml or
whatever you want to call it
um but they can point that out right
that's something that that a computer
can find very good very well for you
a posture here really tells you the
areas that have that most their most
risk for Bola runtime can detect Ola and
if you have a decent bit of testing it
can find that whole hopefully very early
in the production in pre-broad whatever
whatever you call your early not quite
to production yet that's where you'd
like to find these things
um broken user authentication this is
where you have the ability to log in
basically username and password into an
API to to generally get a token back
that you then use to do the rest of your
requests
as an attacker I can Brute Force
credentials I can do password spring
um apis don't have the nice things that
browser has like MFA or captcha
this can also be the places where
there's no uh anti-automation on
password resets particularly on API
backed uh web apps
you can do the the whole thing of of
playing around with um base64 and and
sometimes uh they'll base 64 things and
thinks it helps it doesn't really or
there can be issues with the tokens
themselves either they generally have
low entropy or there may be some JWT a
jot specific weaknesses like a the none
algorithm attack if you don't know that
do a little bit of reading that's a
that's an amazingly hilarious thing
um you can have weak
uh passwords for jwts you've got people
to crack them there's this nice tool
called JWT tool that'll do some of that
for you but
generally speaking this is uh an
attacker trying to get
authentication bypass so they can get a
valid token to then make requests as
that user
and if they are brute forcing
credentials or doing password spring
this is going to be very noisy so for a
Defender it's not hard to see
um password Springs noisy if crypto is
used incorrectly you can usually find
that more statically than dynamically
honestly although decent API runtime
tools will see that and tell you that
you have weak Secrets there's a great
RFC the JWT best practices RFC if you
are using jots I would recommend looking
at that
um and then some companies have actually
removed often from the API altogether
because they get so many so much better
protection from a traditional web app
they make the human log into a web app
get a token and then add that to
whatever their API automation is
uh GitHub does that actually now
currently which is pretty interesting it
didn't before
um posture this is where you can
identify any kind of offend that exists
in your API so it's very useful to sort
of focus on removing this problem from
your plate
uh obviously brute forcing passwords
bring those things are noisy yeah
manipulating jwts is noisy if you have
deep inspection those are things that
runtime can help you with
and testing can identify those poor
practices with authentication before you
push stuff out to prod
excessive data exposure
this is where you have apis that are two
verbose and their responses this is
generally caused by a developer using a
like a two Json method right that takes
a data structure jsonifies it and then
they just add it as the response to an
API call
generally that'll be the full data model
and it won't be just a subset and in
that case they rely on the clients to
sort of filter or just ignore the extra
data that they send and if you're only
using your client say your mobile app
that's great in theory because the
mobile app will ignore that but as an
attacker I don't have to use the mobile
app I just have to use something that
talks HTTP and I won't ignore that extra
data particularly if it's interesting
so from an attacker's perspective you
want to look at things that generally
will have a lot of data around them this
is like a profile page or a an inventory
page or if there's some kind of linked
like you know friends kind of users
um you can make guesses to where there
might be internal metadata where this is
a different like a role may be implicit
but not shown in a profile you might be
able to get that role out
um as excessive data exposure
and this can be very time consuming if
you're looking at a big API there's a
health care API I looked at that had
like 435 methods
or endpoints I should say
um and then you add the HTTP methods on
top of that they had lots to do there so
this can also kind of be a bit of a Time
sink
now from a Defender unfortunately if you
have excessive data exposure my request
is just a legit request you're just
sending back more data than you should
so this will look like normal traffic
um and this is a place where SAS or
static analysis can help you find or
like uh sem grip can help you find those
two jsons or whatever it is for your
language right where you're having
developers directly dump a data model
out to the response
um and this is where you need to find
out if your clients are relying on
filtering up data because that's a
that's a warning sign if nothing else
and in the better designs you actually
have separate data objects for internal
storage versus what goes out over the
API so maybe you have 15 elements in the
internal representation of that data but
the API only gets six of those and you
have two different data objects in the
language whatever programming language
you're using so that it I have to
consciously as a developer add a new
data item to that API only data object
and that I can safely use those two Json
things because I've done that
segregation of data explicitly when
creating the API data object
a posture can show you where sensitive
data is
um to to know that those are the sort of
spooky Parts potentially shows you large
data responses
um runtime can show you large responses
but you may have those on purpose so
that may or may not be useful to you but
it can definitely detect
the what happens with data exposure from
an attacker perspective is I'll find it
for one user and I'll try to get it from
the rest of them lots of telecoms have
had this problem or they had a
problematic API and I figure out if I'm
going to call it once I can get one
person's information but if I call it 10
000 times or it can help you a million
times I can get a million people's
information so
where this will generally show up for
runtime is I might be able to get the
first requests out and steal that data
but as I try to steal data in Mass it's
really going to show up for runtime so
runtime can definitely help you here and
then testing can find those verbose
responses early in your pre-prod cycle
lack of rate limiting or resource lack
of resource and rate limiting this is
where you don't because apis are meant
to respond quickly to multiple requests
you kind of need to right limit them so
they don't fall over also does that you
can if you're having an API that's used
like say strike by multiple clients you
don't want one client to sort of eat up
all of your resources
so as an attacker this can be fun if you
have a method
or an API call that lets you add items
of some sort like I don't know my
favorite songs addicts several million
songs and then ask for your list of
songs and if they don't have pagination
this is a great way to have a sort of an
application Level dos so sort of lack of
pagination it's a giant clue this is
getting much better but in the early
days I found lots of those
um
the fuzzing and brute force can find
some of these
this is where you're just going to do
interesting things like play around with
the headers or the you do
um different IP requests or just
anything to try to get around the the um
rate limiting you can play null
Terminator K switching games anything
just sort of confuse an intervening
device that's right limiting you if
that's an API Gateway a wife or some
other network device
um
and I have found cases where they did
have rate limiting but it was set so
high that I could already start to
impact their performance before the rate
limiting kicked in so as an attacker
even if you find it that may not
necessarily mean the API is safe
from a depender perspective
most of these requests going to look
normal they might have
um larger responses I've done sort of
stupid API tricks by there was one XML
API where I injected 32 bags of space in
between two x XML elements and sent it
to the API and it fell over so that
would obviously show a very very easily
in runtime
also runtime can see a lot of unusual
headers or weird encoders or null
Terminators that you don't expect so a
lot of the the techniques you do to try
to get around rate limiting end up not
looking like normal requests and
therefore can be spotted with runtime
protections
um and if you have observability decent
monitoring you can see usage spikes a
lot of this I'm testing this I'm going
to be poking things that are CPU or Ram
intensive and this will show up so as a
Defender you can see these odd spikes
and if you're quick enough Nimble enough
you can actually take action against
them
um so posture will help you understand
what things need limits and where it
makes sense to put in limits
a runtime can definitely see the Oddball
traffic that is trying to bypass or get
around any kind of limiting device
um and then fuzzing can sometimes find
data issues these rate limiting and
resource issues early particularly for
app level doses
uh broken function level authorization
this is where you have
um multiple groups or roles for an API
and I can make a a
legitimately tokened request for one
role to another roles method and it'll
it's allowed that's broken function
level authorization
so as an attacker I want to find apis
that have multiple roles or groups
sometimes I think this is poor design
but you will find that backplane or
admin functions are also exposed in the
same API that sort of normal user
functions are exposed at
so those are great places from an
attacker
and then there are I've also seen
instances where the documentation will
not lists kind of dangerous or
state-changing methods like delete put
post patch
um but the API will actually accept
those requests so if you're reading the
docs and only doing the legit thing you
don't try them but there's nothing to
say you can't throw a delete to a
resource even if it's not in the dots
and see what happens
and to find this out usually create uh
items within one roll and try to access
those from a separate role and this is
very context
context dependent on the API you're
testing
um you can use brute force and some
other techniques to try to find those
back plane or admin type operations
and you can play around with headers
request data Etc to try to to try to
originate as a trusted IP
usually by header manipulation like
exported four Etc
um to maybe get access to those admin
functions
so from a Defender this is obviously uh
critical for things that have two or
more roles if you have a single class of
user across your API then you sort of
can't have this problem
um
and you will see lots of Errors when I'm
trying to discover these issues because
I'll I'll send a post request to
something that doesn't support post and
you'll get an error right so that can be
very useful
um you can also see the same client do
multiple roles within a small period of
time this is another great way place
where ml or AI kind of automation from
runtime can help you find a tax
failures if you get failures or requests
either failures to the back plane or
failures to requests that look like
backplane paths that's another great
sign that somebody is being naughty with
your API and then if you see funny
requests headers or bodies where
someone's playing around to try to
bypass
or to try to get around
um the level of function level
authorization that's another great sign
so posture can definitely help you
determine apis with groups or different
privilege levels so you know where to
focus your efforts to try to get rid of
this particular category of problem
the unusual and failing requests can
easily be seen by run time or changes in
a role with with a single client within
a short period of time is atypical
traffic generally speaking for most apis
so that's very detectable
and then obviously testing you can run
this kind of testing early in pre-prod
to find those issues and hopefully not
let them go out to prod
so Mass assignment this is where I'm
sending data data payload into an API
and I'm adding additional data in there
and if I have the the opposite of the
two Json but I read in Json and I turn
it into a data model automatically I can
then change data values that aren't
supposed to be exposed by your API
and so from an attacker's perspective
look at areas where it feels like there
should be more data this is almost the
flip side of our previous uh
previous issue
and you can find issues where there's
differences and responses and requests
for different privileged users right if
you notice as an admin user I have an
admin equals true and somewhere in your
Json We'll add that to a normal user and
see what happens right a post to that
normal user
this is where you can guess in Brute
Force values a lot of apis will simply
ignore additional data and just Dev
Nolan so there's nothing to say you
can't add 10 possible admin issue admin
ish key fields to a request and just see
what happens and maybe you'll get lucky
on one out of those 12 you added right
it can't hurt sometimes you'll get error
messages and other helpful information
when you're trying to to sort these out
from the API so thank you API developers
buzzing can sometimes find these and if
you do have broken function level off
authorization
this can get really interesting because
then I can change
email or some other like like
particularly like a password reset email
or something sensitive
about another user from my existing
users account and this might allow me to
say compromise One account and then go
and compromise multiple others so this
can be very powerful if it's combined
with that broken function level
authorization
so if you have deep inspection
of your API traffic you can see these
additional Fields right because I know
that this API request on every other
normal user has 10 fields and suddenly
there's 27. that's that's very easy for
runtime to find that and
alert you to that an anomaly
you'll see a large number of failed or
invalid requests depending on how your
API will handle that additional data
added
the API sizes will increase you'll see
um
apis with different roles oh that's
you need to watch this board
particularly for apis that have
different severities it's going to
increase the severity if you have
different rules or privileges let me put
it that way in other words if you're
subject to Broken function level
authorization
or you have that multiple role in the
API that you're looking at that makes
this even more of a problem if it exists
and then posture can focus on rules with
sensitive data or
um multiple roles
runtime you can see a lot of this if you
have a larger request add fields that
don't typically exist or all that's
going to show up fairly broadly or
easily for runtime
and then testing can show the additional
um
fields very early in Discovery and
hopefully get that done in pre-broad
[Music]
security misconfiguration this is just
basic stuff TLS you have headers with X
powered by that leak information about
your API
I have default creds if it's a like say
an open source project or something
where the default credits are known you
might be able to upload an icar file if
it takes in files icar is a test virus
file this is where recounted Discovery
can kind of give you an idea
for most error messages or another issue
that you can find as an attacker that
can kind of help you target other
attacks
um there may be misconfigured things
like Django has a debug mode that is
very verbose if there are issues and if
I can trigger an issue and get a ton of
information about say that Django
install
um you can find things like intermediate
devices like API gateways Etc they
usually add
um headers somewhere
and then you can play games like doing X
remote Adder to try to call internal
functions
if they only trust the headers and don't
actually look at the truly true
originating IP
[Music]
and from a Defender this is kind of just
to be blunt running like nessus or the
whatever kind of network traditional
Network scanner can find a lot of these
basic mistakes
um also passive traffic monitoring can
find a lot of these things like weird
header issues API Gateway bypass if I
have an internal
um an internal API getting public IPS
hitting it all those things are very
easy just just by watching the traffic
to see
um if you have clients that have lots of
erroring or malformed requests that's
another sort of indication
posture can show you weak configurations
or API bypass particularly if you have
things like the data classified to where
like I said this API should only receive
internal requests and suddenly I'm
getting public IPS
um and I kind of put passive uh passive
traffic monitoring under posture
although it might be done by a runtime
piece of uh Tech depending on what you
buy Etc
um runtime unexpected traffic multiple
errors these things kind of show up
fairly easily malformed responses
and then um testing it just this is just
the basics you could do fuzzing for API
specific things or hopefully you're
running some kind of network scanner to
find these issues
um injection this is traditional
injection
um in any kind of places and tokens
headers any of the body or the request
Recon can kind of give you an idea where
it might be interesting to do injections
um there's tons of different great
um places to find injections there's
loads of fuzzing lists
um you can go to the Lost testing guide
will give you a lot of these there's a
bunch of cheat sheets for this
um but one interesting thing is second
order injections a lot of apis will take
in really focused data
um and it may not take it may not have
effect within the API but it can be used
by Downstream or internal systems and
then pop up somewhere else and I saw
this for real at Rackspace been years
ago we injected into an API a xss string
and that exercise string went through
seven different systems before it popped
up on an internal admin panel so second
order injections really do exist they're
really hard to tell when you're black
box testing but if you are internal you
can find these things out
um from a Defender point of view
obviously the the 101 thing to do is
input validation and output encoding but
from a runtime perspective you're going
to see lots of failed or malformed
requests and the traditional fuzzing
strings are very well known by both the
attacker and the defender if you have a
decent run time so those will stand out
right or one equals one stuck into a
request is probably going to be found by
even a reasonably good networking device
this watching traffic right you also can
see
a large number of requests that have
validation errors to a particular apis
I'm trying a fuzzing string because I'm
basically brute forcing a bunch of
fuzzing vectors
so those will stand out
um and one area where this can be really
problematic is if overly trusting east
to west or internal API to API calls
where if I can get an injection into one
that passes to the second and it's
overly trusting because it's an internal
API calling another internal API even
though the data came from outside you
can have some really interesting things
happen there
um posture is good to understand which
APS have sensitive data which would be
something I'd want to inject into as an
attacker and then East West API so it's
internal only apis
for runtime you're going to see a surge
of errors or weird valid mail form
requests or fuzzing strings show up very
blatantly if you have even a reasonably
good runtime detection
and then obviously you can do those same
fuzzing vectors in your pre-prod testing
if you do that you can hopefully find
those before attackers do
we have 10 minutes to go okay oh okay
I'm gonna go really fast these these
last ones are luckily not that hard
improper Asset Management means uh
improper Asset Management means you
don't have a handle on what apis you
have out there and honestly from an
attacker I can sum up all those bullet
points into that bottom line my pen test
was really easy if apis are unmanaged
and unloved and unwatched as an attacker
I'm gonna have a productive time
as a Defender I need to know all those
apis and to classify them probably have
an API or something else in place
whatever you should understand your
landscape
posture that's what it's designed to
solve this very top 10 issue so that
should do it for you if you have good
run time it'll update your posture so
that as you add apis to get added to
your inventory and testing honestly not
very useful here
insufficient logging and monitoring is
also one as an attacker you just kind of
have to infer that because Chuck gosh
I've been spraying crappy traffic to
this API for three hours and it hasn't
reacted but it's really hard to tell
from external
from internal you don't see attacks like
if you don't have walking and monitoring
you may be getting attacked and you have
no clue unplanned downtime is a resource
that you really should have better
monitoring and logging
um in the diagnosing API issues is is
difficult this is just a general idea I
mean this is more of a SRE kind of thing
but if you can't diagnose API issues you
probably have insufficient logging and
monitoring
um posture can tell you how much logging
you should have
obviously runtime this is what runtime
is supposed to do monitor so if you need
you know if you have a run a good
runtime tool you can kind of knock this
one off your list and testing can kind
of tell you what's logged but it's not
that useful
look at that I made it bonus material
I'm going to quickly cover this and we
should be good on time
fuzzing
um well this is covered in the the
testing guide I'm going to kind of go
quick here because I'm running short on
time but obviously from a Defender
fuzzing is very very loud and this is
where runtime can find it for you
um one thing I did want to point out is
there's two different ways that I like
to think about attacking apis you either
attack the structure or I have valid
data but I fiddle with the how the data
is laid out in Json or XML or whatever
the whatever the API takes
versus data attacks which is I have a
well-structured
data payload and I just modify the data
elements inside of that payload and I
found some really interesting things
doing structural attacks where I add
three of whatever it expects only one of
or a dozen of them or you remove one
right so don't forget structural attacks
when you're being naughty with apis
I'm graphql it's pretty much the same
for graphql except for graphql it's a
query language if it allows
introspection I can get tons of I can
pull the whole schema honestly for the
graphql API but to be honest with you
graphql is a huge area so I'm leaving
that as an exercise for you guys
foreign
four key takeaways if you know how to
test web applications you're really far
into being able to test apis yeah
there's a couple things you need to to
know that are different but honestly if
you're if not if not go read the Lost
testing guide that's all I got started
years ago
um but if if you know how to test apis
you're really far ahead into testing if
you know to test web apps you're far
ahead into testing apis because
basically an API is a web app without a
UI
um
there's special knowledge and tools
needed that are definitely for API
testing I'll give you more on that a bit
and there are definitely gaps in API
security controls if you have a solid
API shop API security shop you probably
don't have what you need for apis and it
might be time to sort of do a a sanity
check on what you have in place in terms
of controls Etc
um I created this webpage of API
security tools because I kept finding a
bunch of them and I wanted to put them
in something sensible
um you can find us on the community
pages on the OAS website I'm happy to
take PR's there have been several that
people have added or you can hit me up
on slack and I will add them and I do
categorize them into those three types
of tools if they're posture runtime or
testing and I have open source versus
commercial Etc so I I I hope this is
useful to you and if you have some
additions just let me know
and then very very quickly
here is a places where the API the three
different tools and the top ten tens
where they're weak and where I have week
they really support but they don't
directly Impact versus where they have a
direct impact
and then in some cases
um like a mass assignment or testing or
testing for logging and monitoring Etc
they may not have any impact or like the
the up Arrow uh arm on improper assets
management for posture that's what
posture does
so I apologize for the fire hose and I
have six minutes per question
thank you very much Matt it was
extremely enlightening and I think it
covered so many topics and it has to
sink in first however there is one one
specific question regarding the best
tool recommendation is there anything
that you can recommend
oh uh wow that's a hard one to answer
because it's all over the place
um it so here's the trade-off you need
to think about I'll tell you how to
think about it and then you can solve it
for yourself it's money or time right if
you have money
likely a good commercial tool that's
going to save you time but you have to
have budget to make that happen right
versus open source work very well
generally speaking like zap does a
decent job of testing apis if you have a
good Swagger spec and you feed it to zap
it could do a good job of testing apis
and it's zero dollars so that may be a
great place to start I tend to like to
try a couple of Open Source free tools
because it's kind of a I trade off a
little bit of time to understand if
they're useful and then
depending on what kind of coverage you
get you may or may not then decide it's
time to Pony up or ask for Budget to get
a to get a commercial tool and in
because the commercial tools will do a
lot of hand-holding for you they'll make
nice output they'll be updated regularly
you know there's just I mean it's a time
or money question unfortunately and and
zapdo is not a bad way to start and if
nothing else get use a free tool to
understand sort of get a smell test for
your apis if the free tool is really
noisy maybe you just need to solve a lot
of problems before you pay a vendor to
fix issues or maybe that might scare
management enough to give you lots of
budget and you go buy a tool so it kind
of depends
the usual security answer it depends
like a lawyer I know sorry bad me
you said in the beginning there and
nothing yet formalizing sand of API
hardening
but what is
the best practices that you would
tell us to watch for and go for in the
priority yeah that's a great one so
there's several things you can do that I
think are just kind of fundamental and
almost design time decisions which are I
think better to fix than bugs obviously
so
I I like the the for lack of a better
term the auto magical data binding from
say a DB table to a post or a response
to our API request right you have these
to Json like I mentioned earlier
functions that will just take a data
model internally however that data is
represented in your app and turn it into
a Json and then send it over the wire
now from a developer like uh
productivity perspective those are
awesome those Rock from a I don't want a
leak data perspective those are horrific
and on the flip side if you have a read
in data and magically turn it into table
data I have mass assignment problems so
although it is more work which is always
an interesting uh conundrum to sell to
management
having specific data objects for the API
that are different than your internal
objects I think is really important
because it it makes it explicit right
instead of it magically happens
because it could be the developer one
used it to Json right and then there are
three jobs later where some new person
who inherited Legacy code is told to add
a field and they add a field and
suddenly that's exposed and and it's
really kind of well it I mean I guess
maybe it's somebody's fault but that
could very accidentally and
non-maliciously happen but if you have
the explicit objects I have to add that
very very you know explicitly to make
that not happen
um the other big area is authentication
or authorization excuse me and actually
the whole token management can be really
interesting for apis
um
this is where I think having an API
Gateway makes a lot of sense
because if you have 12 apis behind an
API Gateway and API Gateway is handling
the like say jwts for you
you don't have 12 different potential
potentially different implementations of
JWT handling you have one and it's at
the API Gateway so this is one of those
kind of rare cases that if you do it
right you can get more security and have
less work for the developers now granted
you if I can bypass that API Gateway
things get really interesting
um so that's it's not without its cost
but that's another great area to get
some benefits
unfortunately we have to rub our book
here thank you very much Matt for your
talk and the input you gave