hello and thank you for attending this
session we will be listening to ATP the
electrician
um talk about the owas snow project he
is a senior security consultant with
security Compass
um if you guys will notice there is an
option to ask questions to the right of
your screen if you're in the huba app
that has been disabled in Zoom um but go
ahead and feel free to and ask any
questions and we will be taking a few
minutes at the end of the session to go
ahead and answer any of the questions
that you have so um with that I will
turn it over to ATP who is ready to
present thank you
thank you thank you Christina thanks
everybody for joining
let me share the screen I hope all of
you are able to see the screen
uh today I'm going to talk about uh new
OS Project called Avast snow and we will
discuss how obvious snow can help you
active slightly more priority there's a
reason why I'm saying slightly more
privacy because this tool cannot
obviously give you 100 of privacy
the website for us now is
privaciesnow.com and this is the logo or
mass code for the project the project
name is avasts now
a short version of what this tool does
before actually getting into the final
details so a short version is snow is a
software
version of a privacy screen guard I hope
that gives a high level idea of what
this tool is going to do
uh if you don't it's okay I'm going to
discuss that in detail in the upcoming
slides
all right the before going ahead I have
a question so the question is you can
see a picture on your height right hand
side there's a person sitting uh and
doing something on their laptop maybe
they are checking their emails social
media or transfer making some
transactions or whatever and there is a
person behind standing and they are
looking over there the sitting person's
shoulder onto the screen and this the
standing person is performing some sort
of an attack the question is what is
this attack called
the you have four choices
a password guessing C cyber stalking C
Shoulder surfing
the credential surfing so if you if you
can uh guess or say what's the answer
I'll I'll take a quick look into my
whole app to see if I have any responses
shoulder surfing that is the correct
answer the standing person is performing
a shoulder surfing attack
now the second question I have is what
does the lecture c stand for in the CIA
trial we all know Cas seen as one of the
core principles of cyber security so
what does the letter C stands and say hi
your options are a continuity b
consultancy c Central the
confidentiality I will wait for the
answer
right so if you have answered C
confidentiality that is the correct
answer so shouting sort of Surfing
results in compromising confidentiality
one of the core principles of
information security or you can say it
affects privacy of the person so that is
the short resourcing attack now the
second question is like how can you
defend from shoulder surfing attack
right there are lots of different
solutions available based on the type of
attack so if say for example when you
walk into a store and you're purchasing
something with their debit card and you
have to enter a pin at that time you may
Define yourself from somebody from
stealing your PIN by covering the number
pad with your hand while typing the pin
with the other hand so that that is a
production mechanism so similarly there
are lots of different mechanisms you can
use and we will we will look at into one
of the option so this is a privacy
screen guard you can purchase them from
the uh from store like an online store
or I think you can go walk into some
stores and you can get from there as
well what it basically does is that you
you have a
film are available you basically apply
that film on your laptop monitor or or
phone and that will help you access some
privacy by limiting the viewing angle so
somebody needs to sit right in front of
the screen and they have to be facing
right uh right the screen from the front
to actually see the screen so if you
move the spawn a little you won't be
able to see the screen what is going on
in the script
so like I said there is a mobile version
also available
uh these are the four main issues when
you use these type of physical privacy
screen types one you need to spend money
all these privacy screen guards are
after market Solutions I haven't seen
any mobile phone laptop or uh monitor
manufacturers giving these privacy
stream cards in their package right so
you have to
you have to go ahead and purchase these
credit cards by spending extra money
the second thing if it affects viewing
angle for me personally that has been a
big deal deal breaker because
yes I want privacy but there are some
there are times when I want to say share
a video or something and and watch it
together with my friends or spouse and
and at that time they won't be able to
see what's going on the screen and
unless I give my phone to them and they
stand right in front of it right or say
when I'm in office if I have a privacy
screen card on my laptop if one call
colleague walks over and they want to
work with me on some things if they are
sitting on a chair next to me they won't
be able to see what is on the screen so
that that has been a problem of course
you can peel that off for that time and
that brings us to the third problem
which is it is not easy to install every
time the thing of privacy cards as
whatever that template glass protector
you have on your phone right if you
remove that and stick it on again yes
you can do that but maybe it will create
more bubbles it can easily get that
these are these are very prone to this
creating Bubbles and air air bubbles so
you have to be really careful and have
to be an expert in it to install it
properly so yeah it is not easy to
install then the fourth one is it can be
tough to get the right size so if you
you we have monitors laptop screens and
mobile phones available in various sizes
and privacy screen guard protectors
those manufacturing companies can't uh
they they they they will create screen
guards for some phones or devices which
are popular but if you have a special
size or if you have a new model of a
monitor all of you like I say have a new
widescreen monitor or a new phone with a
different aspect ratio basically you
have to buy something bigger and maybe
cut it with your with the scissor and
that's not ideal right so you get the
idea it's not easy with these physical
ones and that's why I thought hey maybe
there should be something a software
version right of the Privacy Street gun
and that is what OS now is basically
when you enable snow and just like uh
when when you you must be knowing dark
mode right on the websites if you enable
dark mode suddenly it changes colors
similar to that if you turn on snow the
under tree screen will get blurred back
stack pictures will get uh illegible you
won't be able to treat them but then if
you move your mouse cursor on top of it
of the elements that you want to read
whatever immediately underneath that
cursor becomes visible so you would be
able to read that portion over there so
someone looking over your shoulder they
would even if they are looking at the
screen they they need to see where the
mouse cursor is moving and read and what
is underneath that so you have some
protection so say for example you are
logging into your bank account and you
already know what your bank balance is
so you don't have to hover your cursor
on top of fact so somebody standing next
to you wouldn't be able to read how much
balance you have so a similar same thing
goes for say an email ID a phone number
displayed on the web page right so all
of them we become blurred and nobody
would be able to read that
so the advantages of
using a software version is faster snow
is free you basically enable this and
you don't have to actually go ahead and
purchase it second it won't affect
weaving angles so you can turn off snow
easily uh as well so if you want snow
you you just click a button if you don't
want to snow don't not to be on it's
again you just click on a button that's
it also Size Doesn't Matter the snow
software is like it is it is basically a
JavaScript so basically uh whatever your
screen size is it it can shrink or
expand so viewing uh the size of the
screen is not going to affect the
experience of the Privacy right so that
those are the those are the advantages
of using a software version in this case
Oslo
now now you know what uh East of West
snow you also know what are the pros and
cons of using a physical version of
privacy screen and also uh what are the
advantages of using uh the software
version which is our snow I will quickly
post here before moving on to the next
section of the presentation to see if we
have any other questions on whoa whoa
okay looks like I don't have any
questions so we will move on to the next
part
I want to say that snow we won't give
you 100 privacy so even if you have this
snow chained on
it is not 100 right if you are in a
coffee shop and is connected to a random
Wi-Fi which is controlled by an attacker
or random insecure Wi-Fi
snow can protect you there so snow is
just protecting what is on your screen
even on the screen when when you talk
about the screen say for example you are
talking to somebody uh okay you're
chatting with somebody and you're typing
something on the keyboard and somebody
the only your screen is protected so if
somebody looks over your shoulder to see
what you are typing on your keyboard
they can still based on your finger
movement they can see what you are
typing and the snow is not going to
protect you over there so those are the
issues with us all with the with the
with snow
similarly some if you are entering a pin
or something you still need to hide it
right other other orders if somebody is
recording what you are typing or or if
there's a CCTV camera somewhere just
grabbing your screen or then they would
be able to go back Zoom it up watch it
slowly and see what was underneath your
cursor and would be able to read those
content right so in those cases no it's
not going to help you if it was a
physical screen privacy card
uh it would have protected you from CCTV
attacks because
CCTV would be in a different angle we'll
be looking at the screen from a
different angle and since privacy stream
cards is going to reduce the viewing
angle it can protect you there so that's
that's the difference between a software
version and a physical version
now third question what is this ancient
equipment
I'm looking for the answers there are
four options it is a phone B it's a
morse code machine three it's an
encryption device encryptor or it is a
music player I will see if anybody have
any answers
I'll pause for a second
if you know the answer just type A B C
or D
all right so if you have answered it's a
phone you are correct it's an ancient uh
telephone I I see the right answers in
the uh so thank you Eric so yeah this is
a telephone
why we are talking about telephone I'll
come I'll come to that in a bit
now fourth question what are these two
people doing
you again you have four options they are
making a new thread
be they are waiting at the fishing
finishing point for a runner so there is
a marathon or Sprint happening and
they're beating in the finishing line so
that somebody can uh hit those uh Ribbon
or thread right
third option is C uh they are talking to
each other
fourth option is D they are talking and
thinking
okay so uh I have a right answer again
see they are talking to each other so
this is called that they are
communicating right they are using what
is called a tin can telephone or a lover
phone most of you have the same thing
you see uh paper cups and uh some
threads when you were a kid maybe you
still do so the the the the those those
are very familiar to us why I'm
discussing about that is that uh is is
another that leads to another question
what does both of them have in common
from a privacy standpoint
uh so what does an ancient telephone
and this Tin Can telephone Lover's phone
have common from a privacy standpoint
so the answer is
they have privacy built into it there is
a reason the telephone has an ear piece
instead of a loudspeaker even with the
lovers phone one has to place it on over
their ear to hear what the other person
is saying it is not like uh you uh put
it over there and everybody around you
can hear it right so they have privacy
built into it and those are ancient
stuffs
um how about the software and Hardware
we Define these days right they don't
have many of these software and Hardware
are not designed uh are defined with
privacy mind uh there is a comment that
says you could easily intercept the
course with the action telephones and
even with uh Lover's phone yes that is
correct so the the
they have those issues and I and sadly
we have those issues even now uh with
latest technology and stuff but yeah we
at least we have
we have some controls right so yeah it
is good uh we are there so uh what I'm
saying is that uh
we should be having uh a shoulder
surfing protection built in in our
software or Hardware that's what I'm
trying to say
now now you know uh we already discussed
what is a West now so now you know what
is no uh you know the difference between
a physical privacy screen and wasps no
and you know how we used to design
technology with privacy in mind and then
you now you know also know what you
think bottom soft privacy in today's
software right I will quickly check who
out to see if I have any other questions
before moving on to the next section
within the presentation
right I don't have any other questions I
will go to the next section so right now
who asks now is available on web Windows
Chrome and Firefox
so if you are
developing a website and that is the
first portion if you are developing a
website we have a snow JavaScript
available I will give you more details
in the upcoming slides if you are using
a Windows laptop or desktop then you can
you there is a nice soft chairs now
software it's an experimental version
but it is available on Chrome and
Firefox so you can we have a browser
extensions or add-ons are available all
of them are free and open source for
sure
so one thing I want to plug it here is
that initially when I developed August
now it was only uh on I it was just a
vibration at Chrome version I present
before presenting in Virtual absec
virtual apps against the conference I
wanted I presented it in a small
conference near my home in in Canada and
one of the attendees said hey I can Port
the Chrome extension to into Firefox I
can create a Firefox extension formats
now and I was like yeah great go ahead
and do it and Tobias who was an attendee
went ahead and he created that Firefox
extension that's how that's how we have
a Firefox extension uh similarly my
brother said hey I I I like this project
I can't create one for Windows and he
created the windows version uh so that
is the beauty of us and open source I
think when I I basically obvious to know
was a was my need I wanted privacy when
when working on my uh laptop or or when
I'm surfing web on my phone or whatever
and I I would have I created that
extension and I was using it personally
and at one point of time I thought hey
maybe I can publish that maybe some
people will get uh
it will be useful for them right I open
source rate but uh but not it was not
getting anywhere and I was like hey
maybe I should promote it to uh so that
people will know such a project access
and I presented it in novice Vancouver
and that led to a nice Firefox extension
and that led to a window special so
that's why I love ovac so if you have a
great ideas like this I think you should
at least put out the idea somewhere so
that people can contribute to it right
there are lots of talented folks here in
novas band and actively available in the
information security industry so
absolutely of it and I I just want to
mention that
now obvious noise not available in Mac
iPhone iPad Linux or or an Android and
maybe if you are a developer on any of
these platforms maybe you can help this
project by plotting uh or creating a new
ask Innovation for any of these
platforms there was also one requirement
that August snow currently Works based
on a mouse cursor right where you move
your mouse mouse cursor and that means
somebody needs to move their cursor to
read what what is underneath that cursor
and it raises accessible issues some
people may not use
track parts or Mouse they may maybe they
will use keyboard or they will just use
touch screens right so in that case I
have can we can we can't say hey we are
not entitled to privacy because you are
using a keyboard to navigate now we
should not
so that is one thing that I want to
address so if you have any ideas for
that uh you are all welcome I I I'm open
to hear those ideas
um this is that is the next thing I'm
going to do I'm trying to see uh what
are the accessibility softwares are
available out there and I can integrate
snow with them uh so yeah so that that
research is still going on
basically
I want now to be the next dark mode when
when I see dark mode being interrupted
by lots of softwares out there lots of
phones hardware and a software every
everyone is jumping into the dark mode
bandwagon and I want not to be there
because our privacy is is of utmost
importance
now I talked about the web fashion so if
you are if you have a website and you
want you really care about your
customers privacy and you want to know
available to them
there is a privacy snow extension sorry
JavaScript available you can go to
privacysnow.com and you can get this uh
piece of core code you just
add that to your website included using
script SRC then you can have a button
somewhere on your website with on click
private system or something of that sort
and that function will trigger start to
be on and off so maybe you can use that
on your website uh after heading back
from this session
or you if or if you have a website that
you wish it had of us know maybe you can
talk to them and see if they can
integrate snow
now if you are using Google Chrome or
Firefox we have super snow and small
light two extensions available you once
you installed them
you can see this nice little icon on top
if you click on that uh snow will depend
on everything will get blurred if you
click on it again it will be turned off
if you are on Windows download our
Windows station and run run it and it
will go to the tray it will get
minimized many people have said that hey
I have run the tool and nothing is
happening right so when you run the tool
it is going to start uh
and go to tray you have to go to tray
and right click on it and turn on the
snow then snow will be on and if you
want to turn off you can turn it off one
nice thing about the windows version is
that it unlike the browservation it
gives slightly more uh features I it
gives you more granular controls the
other problem with web version is that
if you are using Google Chrome or
Firefox and you are using snow it is
available on Chrome or Firefox right and
if you are using some other desktop
software so it's not available there but
if you are using the windows version
every every app is covered right so that
that is the advantage of using the
windows creation it is still
experimental so you may face some issues
here and there the source code is
available if you want to modify it but
if you report that back to me my brother
is working talking about that so maybe
I'll ask him to fix it and uh so yeah
let me know
now you know uh where all you can use
now or or where you can't use now
and you you also know how Avast and
collaborate collaboration can help us
right in improving privacy or improving
information security I will take a quick
click and who are to see if I have any
more questions before going to the next
section within the presentation
no questions yet all right thanks so
where all you can use snow uh that
that's uh that's something uh
which is obvious say for example if
you're at home and you are buying a
surprise gift for your spouse and you
don't want supposed to know it then then
you can use snow even at home or if you
are at work you are creating some a new
uh groundbreaking technology whatever
stuff and you don't want your co-worker
to know or some competitor to know you
can use snowy on your on your laptop
if you are commuting to work using any
public transport chances are that
somebody may look over your shoulder to
see what's happening on your phone or
tablet or laptop or whatever so if you
can use snow over there
there's an interesting piece there why
why I created OS snow in first place
right so when I started my career I I
used to work in Delhi and I used to take
daily Metro every time it's a it's a
metro train and I used to go in the
morning to the office and we'll head
back in the evening to home uh and it it
is usually rushed there are lots of
people and sometimes you'll be sitting
on your chair and looking at your phone
because you have a lot of time and you
are going through the phone at some and
many times when I'm in the train I can
see that people are looking over
somebody's shoulders it is easy when
somebody's sitting and some uh and
checking their phone somebody standing
can easily look over the other person's
shoulder and see what is on the phone
screen right for tablet or laptop so I
have seen people peaking and Performing
shoulder surfing and I was like okay
there should be a solution and I've and
then I did some research and I came
across all these privacy screen guards
but then I was not uh I did not like the
idea of installing a privacy screen I
don't need to affect the viewing angle
so much I wanted something easy there
something you can easily turn on and off
and that led to the creation of how fast
snow even though it was not immediate it
took me eight or ten years because I was
like hey I know this solution but it's
it's a silly Solution that's what I
thought because somebody is going to
come up with that so maybe I'll wait and
maybe I will I should search and find it
and I I did lots of search on Google and
Bing and I did not find any other active
projects I uh doing this right then I
was like okay oh fine I will create
something so I created it I open sourced
it and now we have more people
contributing to in do it I'm creating
particle to different platforms so here
we have that
all right uh so before
looks like there are no other questions
so I think I will move on to the final
conclusion of this presentation which is
you deserve privacy so you deserve snow
please head over to privacy snow.com and
download snowflier mobile
via browser or whatever
thank you Abby that was great I'm going
to tweet that actually so that we get
more eyes on snow
um and thank you to everyone who
attended if you have any questions we
are still in the huba app um accepting
any questions
um otherwise thank you so much for your
time and thank you Epi for such a
wonderful presentation that was very
informative and I loved seeing
um snow and hearing about all the future
plans for it it would be great to see
some developers working on a Mac version
for it sure sure we all deserve privacy
yes absolutely so thank you again
everyone have a great rest of your
afternoon