hi everyone welcome to the Builder track
I am Muskan mangla I volunteer in the OS
Community I'll be moderating this
session during the next 45 minutes
you'll be listening to Geron and Ben
present over strong secrets we have a
secret for everyone please submit any
questions you have during this session
in the QA tab just to the right of this
video in the Huawei platform I'll be
asking the speakers your questions in
the last 10 minutes of the session
please note that the chart function is
disabled for the attendees but you can
leave comments and chat using the chat
tab in the Huawei
so well I'll introduce the speakers
briefly Geron is a typical security jack
of all trades as a Hands-On security
architect with a knack for or to
Automation and risk management Geron has
been involved in the various obas
projects now focusing on obas uh wrong
Secrets Ben is a freelance security
consultant and engineer when specially
specialized special Specialties are
architecting and implementing Cloud
security and building secure cicd
environments in agile devops and SRE
cultures
now handing over to you uh Jaron and Ben
uh for forgive me if I pronounce your
names uh wrong so yeah over to you guys
you did awesome thank you so much for
introducing us let's start sharing some
screens see the Technologies with us
all right all right all right I think
you can see it now so welcome everybody
um to oval from Secrets
um we hope to uh entertain you a little
bit with our project in the upcoming 45
to 60 minutes
um and with content I think we can be
very short about um about our
introduction for ourselves
um
so I'm Joan
and here right next to me is uh
[Music]
yeah Ben
that's right
and uh let's move ahead so we have more
time for awesome content
so
um
let's start with a little bull uh this
side of the screen at least for me I
hope it's also for you when I write
inside the screen there is this
beautiful uh pool uh where you can fill
in uh where did you find secretive in
the projects you had access to
um and well I can't access it on my
computer and show it live because then
we get the funny audio loopback but
right now I'll refresh it again I see
about 34 responses answers
right over here
um let's see if I can show it like that
okay this is a bit funny I don't think
that works very well
um but basically what we can tell is
that a lot of people found secrets in
git
um uh a lot of people found secretion
and farce in secret managers in Cloud
vendor Solutions but also in the cicd
pipeline and a few of them found them in
Docker containers and libraries
executables or in workload schedulers
all right awesome well that information
I think we all touch stuff a little bit
let's get ready to do stuff
so
um the first question of course would
then be if we go to this poll is hey hey
but um
what are secrets what can be a secret so
here's a few examples of possible
Secrets right again there can be plenty
of course
um you can think of uh uh various things
like uh uh uh um your password which
makes total sense private Keys whether
for TLS configuration gpg
um I am access keys for your Cloud
vendor
um
um but then of course also API keys or
um a little bit less easy OTP seats
um MFA backup codes uh 2fa code for as
long as they're valid uh QR codes to
sign on easily and stuff like that and
all of a sudden that it starts to grow
and grow and grow so apparently there is
quite a few Secrets out there
so
um then the next question would of
course be
um
if you had to rotate all your
organization secrets
would you actually know where they are
um and not not just what you know
well your team lead decided that it
should be or where your season decided
they should be or your lead architect or
whoever books you're voting your
organization but also where everybody
else eventually puts those Secrets which
might be in different places basically
um and they actually know their purpose
remember how um uh Jack from the other
unit basically just um uh committed this
password thing do you actually know
where this is for
um more importantly
um can you rotate it timely when you're
compromised so if you know earlier
secrets are get and rotate it and do you
actually know well lots of other things
about your secrets who lost touch them
stuff like that so
for this it's again time for a little
poll again at the right hand side of
your screen there is a second bowl which
asks you do you know the location for
the secrets in your organization
so this pool has been on for quite a
while and we have quite a few responses
from what I can tell as well
um oh it's still growing pretty cool so
let's jump in at 30 responses five
people said that they know the location
of all the secrets in their organization
I'm very impressed by them because I've
never worked in an organization where I
knew all the secrets or where all the
secrets were located because there were
always too many people trying to be
quick and stuff and Ben Walsh will show
what quick means in that sense uh during
our demo but that's really let's not
steal the standard for now
um uh but 26 respondents this far has
responded no and I think that's really
an honest response because it's very
hard to know where your secrets are
so that's about the location of things
in the context of Secrets but apparently
there's more to this than just that
right so
um
yeah
can you tell us when your secret was
lost Borrowed by an ex-colic or an
active colleague
you know because some administrative
tasks need to be done or because he was
he or she or it was sect
um and tried to uh take a few items home
to have different licenses for instance
um we can all say that it never happens
but we all also know that this happens
very often
um
more importantly can you also tell when
a secret was not working anymore so this
we often can tell because then all of a
sudden our service is added right
because then the whole service goes down
if it's integrated with some other
server for which it needed a secret that
is apparently not that hard
um unfortunately we're often very much
just too late because the audit started
and we eventually find out that it was
because the secret was no longer working
and then there's this funny guy from
Despicable Me
um that tries to present something for
us as well on the slide so let's assume
we found out where our secrets are which
is great we start monitoring them we
make an alert when they when they're
grabbed and then we look on the entry
that they are grabs another question is
do you looked it correctly or do we end
up having the the data uh of this given
Secrets writing your audit law or in
tomorrow where too many people have
access to
okay
so apparently Secrets management is
special
um by now we know that many uh of uh the
things that we present with the novel
conferences are considered special
otherwise we'll be talking about it but
secret management by itself
unfortunately needs some attention
um and that is why we introduced uh
projects over strong secrets
all right what is it tell me more let's
go
um so it's basically a vulnerable app uh
and a secret detector despat you'll see
when Deb demonstrates the app in the
larger portion how that works and you
can find in our readme how the secret
detector test bet Works what we
basically did is we have a bunch of
challenges
uh where you need to find a secret
within the code or within some other
asset that we created for you where some
people Miss have funny beliefs about
that's a secret over there is safe
um and next to that the secret detector
does bad basically
um has a few additional Secrets inside
git so you can let the your secret
detector run through and see if it
detects the things
um that are out there but by that you
know how effective your secrets detector
is and whether it's configured correctly
we have a few goals about this so by now
you understand we think Secrets
management is special
um so yeah we would love to educate
people on secret management and
spitfalls
and we would like to help people reflect
on the secret management strategy so
while you're doing these exercises
in our vulnerable app ask yourself hey
are we doing something similar here or
are we at risk doing something similar
or have I seen somebody in my
organization doing something similar
should I improve my strategy
um and there and of course you know
trying to promote secretary management
that's an important facet of security
um all of this could never have happened
without the tremendous support of our
volunteers
um so these are most of them some of
them we they didn't want to be mentioned
but still huge shout out to the
anonymous people helping us as well
um special thanks to Nana Tibor
um uh Josh Mike and yours who did quite
a lot of cool stuff to help us out and
special call out to Dave and Martinez
her tester is also helping us out a lot
in other things
um and of course
um a special call out tomorrow Kula who
has done a tremendous job on helping us
to promote a project correctly
um and Bjorn for being an inspiration
with uh many things he has already done
for all for such a long time and helped
us along the way of uh little tidbits
having that set and of course reach out
to bed amen finally presenting This
Together apologies gentlemen for take
and ladies for taking your time on that
one so
um okay so what did we built of the
volunteers you might wander by now right
let's have a look at our architecture so
the vulnerable application is basically
spring boot application that um uh uh
sits in a Docker container and a Docker
container you can run on your desk on
your machine directly but you can also
just uh visit our website in Heroku
which is uh wrong secrets.airoko web.com
which you can also find in the project
readme or we can load it as a bot and
run into the kubernetes platform uh
right now we have scripts to support
mini Cube AWS which is completely
terraformed for you but you can also
tear it down correctly gcp in azure
um as well as a mini Cube actually so
you can also just run the kubernetes
exercises and evolved exercise locally
and in every layer we basically add more
secrets so if you just run the docker
container locally you get a bunch of
Secrets but if you want to enjoy the
fill flavor of it use one of the cloud
providers noted in this slide to have
fun with it
[Music]
um
having that said giving us a lot of
space for Ben to uh start showing some
awesome demos over to you yes we'll uh
thank you will do let me share my screen
as well
there we go
all right
um so
you can find wrong secrets on GitHub and
like you and also said on Heroku and
that's the easiest way to
try it out in in a uh well
easily
please don't run any testing tools
directly on Heroku there's not really
any dynamic
uh challenges going on so using things
like a wasp sep well while they're in my
YouTube some results that's not really
the goal of our Challenge and also
hiroku notes freed Heroku notes don't
really like it when you do that
so be gentle with it you can of course
uh just walk through all of the
challenges that are supported by this
environment
once you go to wrong
secrets.herokuapp.com you'll be greeted
with this screen it's both available in
a light and a dark mode
and then there's all the challenges
listed below we currently have 18 there
are some more in the works on which I'll
share later
um but there's like you don't say that
challenges at every layer here
and you'll also see that some challenges
are disabled so uh depending on the
environment you're running in you might
might need to
do something else to get working or we
require some dependencies Etc so of
course challenges for specific to a
cloud environment
don't work on Heroku so those challenges
will be grayed out for you
now this is all nicely responsive or at
least it should be and you can even do
some of this on your phone as well if
you so desire for some hacking on the go
what we also want to do of course is not
only show you and teach you how things
go wrong but also point you in the
direction of how you should do things so
not only have we included some resources
on the home page uh but when you
actually go to a challenge
um you can also look at hints which will
provide you with a step-by-step guidance
on how to retrieve the secret
and for some of the challenges we've
actually had remarks okay
um I'm doing this but why is this a bad
thing so we decided to also include a
section on on what's wrong in this
approach
So speaking of uh this Challenge and
what's wrong with uh centralized
hard-coded password
um let's give it a go
so what's happening here and the
description gives us a brief primer so
people write a proof of concept I'm
going to start with a hard-coded secret
for instance a password in code
but you may end up pushing your code to
production and forgetting that you had
still this hard growth thing going on
so this is one of those things that
would be very easy to detect of course
if you have access to the source code
and uh one of the easiest ways that's
probably installed on uh well nearly all
machines uh is grep
um so what we could do is just grab for
password and now if we do that on our
repository we'll get a a ton of results
uh for for different reasons hopefully
you will have
maybe only somewhat less meaningful
results on your own projects
um let's see
but let's grab in the repo and see what
comes up
so there's a lot of things here and a
lot of them
are a centered around documentation of
course but there is also some
interesting things that may be what we
are looking for I know uh out of
experience of course that it should be
this one
so let's go ahead and I've already
create uh completed this challenge in
this session but
there we go we found a centralized
hard-coded password
and
of course for an open source application
this is especially bad uh don't do this
don't put your secret in code
um
it gives I'm sorry earlier the entire
world access to it and it's also quite
hard to erase this from internet memory
so everything that is behind this
password should be considered
compromised the second lead lands in
GitHub
right let's go to a
it's a different challenge that is
related to Docker in this case I wanted
to say a somewhat more complicated
challenge but I I wish it's it's maybe
even easier to figure out uh where this
secret is
so
um
going here there's the docker argument
based password so you know maybe if you
use Docker that you can provide command
line arguments to set different things
uh not necessarily hard coding them in
the code but you supply it a password
for instance in the command line
and thus this password is now in your
batch history probably or you may have
passed it in in a somewhat more
sophisticated way and it's a bit harder
to retrieve but
um if you use darker arm means there's
still ways to retrieve this thing quite
easily
and
[Music]
um
we give a brief primer again on how this
is done
so in this case
uh we can easily spot What's Happening
by looking at how the layers are
constructed
now if you put your image on Docker help
there's this nice overview of the layers
and of course there are different tools
to dissect this but in this case we
don't even need to do anything special
we just go to Docker Hub and go to wrong
secrets
there we go
look at the most recent one
and uh here we have this interesting
command
image layer 14 where there's this
arc-based password
hello Global appsec this is just a
temporary password
oopsie Daisy
so again this is public for all the
world to see
and you may for your own environment
think of ways even if the Stocker image
is private that this is probably not a
desirable thing to do right
so let's go that's it
all right
um now one of my favorite challenges
actually
um is more related to cicd we've had the
docker container we've had uh the the
code and
um another place to store Secrets would
be your CI platform but of course if you
have a CI platform that stores secrets
then you also need to consider the
access to that sequence
um and if you have for instance GitHub
actions then GitHub actions needs to
interact with this Secret in some way
um maybe 2x there's a cloud environment
for example
and
if someone creates
uh a workflow that accidentally spits
out the secret in the log
uh or even
uh this might be a malicious thing going
on where uh it's it's not some error
accidentally logging it
um it's it's pretty easy to exfil sorry
these things
so normally you may know that GitHub and
other CI systems mask their secrets in
the logs
so here we see a sample workflow
in GitHub and and what's happening is
that there's a bash script that loads in
an environment variable where we have a
secrets so the the challenge 13 key
and
um it will just Echo out the key
um and and that will be masked
and then
even if you encode it with base64 Once
then it will probably still mask this
output in the logs but if you encode it
twice or Thrice or you can go several
layers deep depending on what you need
then
um
your mileage may vary but you will
probably end up with the secret
so running this command
first we have the the plane output where
we just load this thing and indeed it
seems like it's masked and now
there's the
double encoder thing and there we have a
double encoded base64 Secret
now if we go to our tournament terminal
and
decode that thing
we end up with this nicely random string
which we can put over here
and there we go we have successfully
exfiltrated a secret from GitHub and
sold our challenge
so
the final thing that I want to show you
is also still somewhat related to code
which is challenge 15.
say you have Aus access keys and you
accidentally hard-coded them but
you were smart and removed them again
but only after you had already committed
your secrets
so
um one thing we can do
is
use truffle hog to detect secrets that
are in
um
in the git history
and
for our projects naturally that yields a
lot of results so I I had to get a bit
funny with trufflehog uh and and do
specifically a grab for the thing we
want but you could just run troughlog 3
on our gits Repository
and then grip for AWS
and there we go in a second or so
it's probably
checking out right now
[Music]
processing the results
there we go
so as you can see there are some
different entries related to Secrets
uh
these secrets
they they uh are then again like in code
easily exfiltrated but there's a neat
thing about this so say these keys were
not put in there accidentally
but rather
on purpose
in the sense that once you use these
you know that someone has been going
through your code and uh checking out
whether there are any secrets so
I can result
I'm not sure if you're familiar with the
concept
but what we could do
uh
is check out one of these keys
let me access key ID
and then do this
I don't really care about the region I
think
and then do AWS SDS get call or identity
profile wrong secrets
and now in this case
uh let's see
probably use the wrong
one did I
configure
I didn't sacrifice to go to the demo God
sorry
there we go
yes
so I used my canary token whoops and now
I've landed on a tripwire on which uh
as a hacker you would probably know by
this stage that your activity has now
been uh yeah is being monitored and is
now being alerted on so as a Defender as
a builder this is a useful thing to do
to just leave Cannery tokens here and
there
um
if someone is rummaging through your
code or whatever
and maybe even your your local machine
leave one of these on your local machine
as default AWS credentials
that if they are used
you know you are compromised
now we also have this uh stats thing in
our wrong Secrets app and
um this also shows us uh a a web token
that's uh that's uh
again a gallery token and it shows us
what
uh uh generate token will be received
and the last one last entry was just
shown uh this is probably me then
going to a specific URL
so that's a nice way for you to know
that their
well is an attacker maybe accessing your
platform and if this secret is located
close to your other secrets
it's probably high time you start doing
some incident response and maybe
rotating Secrets or closing access to
some parts of your system
to contain
okay
that's it for this demo part
um let's
progress
now
we have
18 challenges as of now and we're also
working on more like I said so what's on
the roadmap
now first off we probably want to
improve the development experience a
bits currently it's quite cumbersome to
add a new challenge and go through the
testing Loop go through the verification
again
so we want to make this easier for
everyone working on our project and and
Implement a nicer development experience
for instance with live reloading
we also want to do
some Secrets management yeah secret
hiding in in binaries for example so
hard coding something in code is one
thing but you could also hard code it in
a binary and then
um what would happen is that it still
often quite easily detectable and
there's various degrees of course in
which this is easy to detect you can go
from some simple string to something
that's obfuscated Etc so that's another
area that we are exploding exploring
one thing to note
is that all of these challenges that we
have here are things that we've seen in
the wild
so if there's any scenario that we
discover or you hopefully you have seen
something interesting as
potential contributors uh you could flag
it and and say okay I've seen this
interesting thing and maybe it's a nice
idea to make a challenge out of it
you're welcome to uh do something for
that yourself of course but you're also
welcome very welcome to just post it as
a potential challenge in an issue in our
GitHub
another thing we're working on is like a
multi-user CDF or cdfd support various
UI improvements
um we want to have foreign secrets uh
additionally available as a secret
detection testbed so that various secret
detection tools can use it as a sort of
Benchmark of how well they are at
detecting things or
and how good they are at not detecting
things that are false positives and
there's much much more for that please
check out our GitHub at commune wrong
Secrets slash issues as well
so having said that back to you uh
all right sorry that was technically
stuff not helping out thank you so much
ben really awesome demo
um so now you might ask yourself okay
this is tons of ways of how not to do it
so how should we do it
um like Ben already mentioned uh you
wrong she gives us a secret detection
Benchmark to find out if there's
anything inside that um that you're not
detecting yet in your Pipelines
um and of course make sure you're also
prepared for having the detector
actually even as a pre-commit hook
instead of just in your pipeline because
hey you rather want to find out whether
something is violating before it hits
gits in a lot of other places
so
um
um there's a bunch of resources we
picked in that in our application which
you can visit uh like a Blog about
Secrets management references to open
Sam which is also being I thought being
presented this uh this conference as
well an awesome talk to check out
um and then of course a secret detection
Topic at GitHub where you can find a lot
of tools other examples and other
resources you might want to jump into to
find diff out and to learn of about
Secrets management then there's almost
Secrets management cheat sheet that is
really recommended to ever read through
thank you so much jamanico for governing
that and then there's the open cre
project where our project is integrated
with that the moment you go over there
you basically find out all about Secrets
management the different uh standards
like the asvs and other things so
anything always predict and understand
it as well by the way
um this Friday there will be an awesome
presentation by Robin Spiros about open
Theory and if you're really done with
scrolling through hundreds of resources
and to Google your every day you
should watch it and see how you can
contribute to it because I think it's an
awesome growth to where it's a better
standard to interact with each other
all right
um so having that said
um the next very next question would
that be I suppose
um yeah what can we take away from this
so if you're watching right now or
watching this afterwards it's recording
what would be the takeaways from our
projects in general
um and of course still you know try it
out give it a test and learn from it but
let's let's have a look at the takeaways
anyway
first of all never hard code anywhere
that means anywhere in your
configuration whether it's the metadata
of a binary or something else anything
really
um or in your Cloud configuration or in
um
uh in uh in your cicd pipeline in a way
that you can't really rotate it anywhere
where you where it can be yet make sure
it's not just hardcoded and easily
detected
and whether you're use your advanced
technology user or not make sure you
don't trust the defaults because many of
the platforms that we're using today to
generate create software to integrate it
with our pipelines and to basically
deploy to production have a set of
defaults that are mostly tailored at
making sure you can start deploying ASAP
so if you have a few lines of code then
you magically have an application you
can do stuff of course it's not magic
it's depending a lot of configuration
defaults and those defaults might
actually hamper you if it comes to
secret management
rotate Secrets often and if you can use
ephemeral Secrets where the secret
generation and deletion basically shows
an intent to use a certain service but
that the secret will only be there for
as long as you have basically use that
service for a given request
um reduced to Blossom radius of your
secret so if a secret is somewhere
somewhat hard-coded or if a secret is
easy detectable within your
infrastructure or somewhere else make
sure that the secret Is Not An Almighty
password to your complete Cloud
environment and anything else you
possibly could attend to
make sure that that given secret is then
only allowing the servers consuming it
to do exactly what it needs no extra
writer whatsoever
and make sure you reduce exposure you
don't have to so the easy thing
everybody would think of is okay let's
make sure all of our you know company
repositories aren't public
but maybe we should go a few steps
further and thinking of hey do really
everybody in your organization need to
have access to all the assets within the
organization or can we take it down a
little bit
similarly issue we have maybe policies
in our secret management solution to
make sure that some people can access
some of the secrets they require but in
most cases possibly nobody needs access
and it's just a computer thing you'll
need to see the main the data of a
secret
um and have logging alerting in place
not like the guy from The Little Disney
movie
um but make sure you really can tell uh
when a secret is being accessed and more
importantly make sure you're able to
tell from the uh
resource required that is basically used
as the place where you authenticate to
with the secret or the place that will
basically generate materials with the
secret that
um
um that really shows locking and
alerting to see like hey where is the
secrets consumer coming from is that
from the place it's supposed to be or is
it somewhere completely different
um you haven't that set
um we can really use your help
um so if you want to uh have a drive of
our of our project promote it if you can
give feedback whether through a wolf
slack or project wrong Secrets um and
try to improve your project with PRS if
you feel like hey this is something I
can do I would love to contribute a
little bit and of course we'll list you
as one of our contributors then as uh uh
um and promote you in any of our
sessions
and that sort of computer session a
little bit earlier than expected so we
still have a little bit of time left are
there any questions
I think
um there are no questions so far from
the audience and it was really uh
amazing and wonderful session from you
guys because we have covered all the
aspects of from the attackers point of
view and to the defender's side how to
um how to find the secrets and how to
secure the secrets to reduce the attack
surface and the major key takeaways from
this session is like we should not uh
store the secrets in a hard-coded way to
reduce the attack surface and always
keep logging and alerting in place very
insightful and very great session thank
you so much again
yeah I do have some questions so what is
your favorite challenge of the project
and why
you want to start doing it yeah sure so
my favorite challenge is let me share my
screen on that one
because
um is I think
uh sorry is 14. so 14 is special to me
because when I try to explain our
project to a friend of mine who's a
driving instructor so it has nothing to
do with it he was like hey isn't this
the same as my colleague who just has
one two three four as his password to
his password manager and it has all
these awesome passwords inside but it's
just one two three four and I felt like
that's stupid why would you do that and
we figured that is awesome that needs to
be a challenge and this challenge
basically shows that Secrets management
is not just some corporate infosec thing
or whatever or or a unicorn let's do
this right type of thing but it's in our
daily lives um in every person that
needs to you know secure access to
whatever Services you dare he or she is
using uh you end up
um having to protect your secrets so so
this is to me is one of the most awesome
challenges uh um because it has a
beautiful story behind it
[Music]
thank you for answering the question so
the next question from my end is like
like uh it is awesome to hear that
you're running a multi-cloud application
but what was your experience with
building this application for multiple
environments
right yeah
um
I having bills all through the the cloud
environments
um or well three of the major public
clouds I should say
it's it's it's quite painful to
um to do this even though we were using
kubernetes and theoretically that's
something that's quite portable right
you go from from what to uh to the other
um
but uh there are always implementation
details associated with a specific cloud
and
especially learning Azure for example
and how that interacts with our an
environment was uh quite a pain
um not even going into
the updates and say uh there's some life
cycle management update you have to
upgrade a major kubernetes version and
then that's different per Cloud as well
so
um there are quite some things
um that are yeah painful in in
maintaining three separate clouds and I
think it's it's
really good to keep a bit of focus if
you want to do things well
um before you go multi-cloud and there's
actually because of this there are some
challenges in there uh specific to some
of the clouds
um that are
pitfalls
um and if you want to do things in a
generic way like put things in terraform
and put things in a terraform state for
example uh you might end up with a
secret entire form State and and that's
also
um one of the things that we then
highlighted as a challenge
um
uh so that you can learn from that
okay thanks for answering this question
uh one more question from the audience
is it life project could we expect or
new challenges to pop up in the future
so I'll I'll take this one so
um yes it's a very live project we have
releases almost every two weeks at least
that's what we attend to whether it's
maintenance releases because uh GitHub
is telling us that our resources are
outdated again and to make sure you can
use this we are updating it on a regular
basis
um we this morning just announce the
upcoming of the first binary search
challenges and I don't mean buying a
research tree like algorithmic fun stuff
but you know reverse engineer binaries
to find the secrets inside which will
start with releasing a sea level a sea
based challenge then C plus plus golang
rust and maybe even Swift so we can
virtually show it doesn't matter which
language you use or how you go to
machine goat
um you'll end up in trouble basically
um so that's that's the one list
um similarly
um uh uh there is a few challenges being
worked on by a few volunteers already
um which are assigned issues um and we
have started some of the preparations
for ctfd which is going relatively slow
because there's a lot of integration we
need to make sure that will work
properly
um and the test bed is continuously
extending and we already hooked up with
one of the organizations that publicly
said hey where that skid guardian and
git Guardian if you're watching this
thank you so much for your support and
Shout out in your blog we basically said
We are Becoming ovos member because I
want to do this and a few other things
um we are in touch with them to make
sure that we add more and more secrets
and we hope that other security or
Secrets vendors will follow
um to you know uh test their stuff the
test bet and at the same time we're
extending it continuously
so not just challenges but also uh
Secrets hidden in one branch to see if
you can basically find them
project shows mostly what is not a good
idea in terms of handling Secrets can
you share a few good ideas as well for
the same
sure sure
um
so um uh so
um uh there's a few things so of course
there were the takeaways right let's
let's quickly dive into those so that we
can easily still see them
um so these are the basic takeaways as
they never hard code if you don't have
to don't trust default of the platforms
make sure you rotate or use it for
Emerald secrets and once you start
thinking about rotation intramural
secrets you automatically end up with
one of the more major secret management
platforms that are designed to do this
well which can be any of the known Vault
projects basically
um and of course reducing the blast
radius of a secret which means actually
not specifically handle Secrets
management but really reconsider your
identity and access management strategy
so not one account to rule them all but
multiple accounts for different reasons
um and good luck with managing those
um
and of course
um uh you're looking alerting is
something that is also very important
what we often see in the wild uh uh is
that um
teams often say like Hey we're never
hacked or um uh we sure secrets are
secure but there is no law showing when
when a secret has been used for
authentication for instance or when some
resource that can only be accessed after
the sequence is being used that that the
access to that given resources being
lost so
um make sure you get your looking
alerting in place not just about from
your secrets management tool but also on
those ends uh where uh we basically
um uh are waiting for the secrets to
land in order to be able to do
actionable items
so in that sense yeah um that's uh um
that's uh um that can be very valuable
um and the other thing really is the
resources we showed earlier
um and those resources still need to be
extended a bit and that will be let me
see if I can quickly pop that up
um that will be basically going over
these resources where it opens here we
link can be really recommended because
you get tons of resources from the asvs
and other things in terms of actionable
items they can really help you as well
as the secret management cheat sheet
that more verbally tries to explain what
you should do or shouldn't do in
situations with the CI CD and stuff like
that
I'm definitely gonna have a look for
this resources and thanks for the
amazing session and the wonderful
session I really appreciate the session
and yeah
so I think we are over and
okay bye
thanks a lot
thank you thank you so much bye-bye