hi everyone good afternoon welcome back
welcome to OAS appsec EU and the
devsecops track
um my name is Nathan Britton I'm an OAS
volunteer I'm an earth chapter leader in
Birmingham in the West Midlands in the
UK and uh pleased to help
um today's session
um so we're gonna talk today all things
devsecops and the importance of getting
security into your Ci City pipeline
so during the next 45 minutes you'll
hear from Joe presents his talk on
Securities code at devsecops approach
that'll last about 45 minutes and then
10 minutes we'll have the Q a afterwards
so please within your Hoover app or the
Hoover browser please locate the Q a
session uh and add your questions there
and I'll keep an eye on them and at the
end we'll we'll Grill Joe with all those
uh with all those questions
um but that's all
that I need to say enough for me I'd
like now to hand over to Joe who's part
of GitHub security lab to begin his
presentation go for it Joe
thanks so much Nathan hi everyone
welcome to my presentation I'm sharing
my screen so we get started
so welcome everyone hello from the
GitHub security lab my name is Joseph
a bit about me is that first of all I am
doing security from my early teenage
years because it was my own way to
provide dedicated and ethical service to
organizations and the society as as a
whole
through the years I studied software and
I focused on cyber security I've worked
as a consultant for IBM advising
directly caesos and CEO on pressing
security monitors and for the past year
now I'm part of the GitHub security lab
because I want to help software
developers directly in the open source
to secure the open source software that
we all depend on uh some carrier
highlights include a zero day
vulnerability for a top 10
cryptocurrency back in 2018
I showed through my thesis a way to post
legitimate transactions randomly
uh as a result of attaching directly
blockchain Innovations so that we secure
them and other career highlights lately
include the YouTube series that is
called security bytes that you can find
in the GitHub Channel
in this series I focus on uh common
mistakes that software developers are
making so that these are avoided and
everybody is coding securely
um The Gap I found in the market let's
say and I introduced this series was
that normally you see videos that
hackers are trying to exploit code and
trying to show you how to
um make benefit of bugs I chose the
other way I I use code that I see often
online and I show what is wrong with it
foreign
other Publications I have lately include
blogging again in the GitHub official
blog like for example today's most
common security vulnerabilities
explained alongside how you can get help
for free from GitHub to avoid those and
I'm writing all this content because I'm
part of a team with the goal to secure
the word software together with you
we are doing two things towards that
direction the first one is to produce
educational content like the one
um I just described but also we are
doing security research
which includes
331 zero days over the past 26 months
that we publish and we explain in our
Twitter and in our blog and at the end
of the presentation I'll speak a bit
about the future and what we are going
to publish because many people are
finding those uh very useful it has to
do with free consultation on how you can
secure your open source project and
content on security for actions and all
these nice features that you have has
so today
um she has to speak about security ask
code which is a new deaf second
methodology that I'm gonna explain how
we got inspired form and show you how
you can apply in your code starting
straight away after today's session
first of all I want to start with a
little story that is real it doesn't
come from a Netflix original scenario or
from anything like that 10 years ago
when NASA tried to go to Mars to explore
the sacrifice of Mars they use a little
Rover called curiosity
so that rubber would land in the surface
of Mars using a little parachute but in
the same way that some of us when we are
going like in a trip with a family you
have a family member asking 20 minutes
after you left home if uh the heater is
turned off and if you are sure that you
locked your door
someone in the NASA team asked are we
sure that everything will be working as
expected do you want to make a final
check do you want to make a final code
review
so there was a snippet of code very
similar to the one on screen right now
that the NASA Engineers took a look and
they found a potential
vulnerability about
so I don't know if anybody has spotted
that already but in the first line you
have a method that is expecting an array
of 12 elements
but an array of three elements is
actually being created in line seven
which can cause a random memory access
leading to random Behavior in line two
because the array is gonna be looped
correctly until the third element and
then you are going to have the elements
4 to 12 accessing random memory
this means that the Rover could crash in
the surface of Mars and on top of that
the NASA Engineers did something smarter
they didn't just fix that specific
vulnerable instance of the code but they
wrote a generic query in the language
I'm going to introduce in our demo to
find instances of that vulnerability in
the rest of their code base
so they wrote a generic code ql query in
order to pick similar issues in the code
and they found 30 other issues
these 30 other issues could together
lead into the Rover being crushed so
this would be a very very late fix in
production it's a costly one it causes
effort time and potentially money in the
case of damage
the smart thing that they did was that
they fixed all of them with a single
query
10 years that was 10 years ago one year
ago NASA sent another over to Mars This
Time called Ingenuity but they learned
from the mistakes of the past they used
a collection of our products alongside
code 12 that we are gonna see in today's
demo
and they shifted security left by
picking up problems like that or others
very early in the software development
life cycle and not just at the end when
the part when the Rover is literally
mid-flight which is very late in
production
so
if I would end the presentation here
today it will be just some oh today I've
learned about a very good feature that's
called codeql I can't enable it in my
code
um as well and I could benefit from the
same security as NASA and other teams in
the world today's presentation is about
showing you how you can write your own
code URL code towards devsecups
I'm trying to make you an actor instead
of a passive user of course
um it's open to you to turn it off to
turn it on I'm gonna show you how you
can enable code ql later
but the point I want to make is that we
are working as a community when NASA
Engineers write a query to pick up a
vulnerability in their code this query
is also available to you to me to
everybody really when the security team
of another team in another Enterprise is
doing the same then this query is
available to everyone and in that query
set you have my team contributing which
is the team with 351 zero daily
vulnerabilities and we also have back
bouncers back Hunters
um that are contributing queries to pick
up zero level abilities that they find
so that they get paid paid bounties
so we are all working as a community
here
and now I want to introduce security ask
code
we were inspired for security as code
through the lessons learned from devops
and quality assurance
so traditionally
we believe that historically actually
devops succeeded because the developers
didn't need to open tickets to
infrastructure teams and they got their
hands dirty with infrastructure they
could write manage change and control
their own infrastructure
in the same way
they could Now read execute and
understand readable code without the
need to get involved and lose time with
other teams internally
in the same way you have called the
assurance
in the pre-orderline days teams will
work in silos so you have the testing
team making sure that the code is
functional but also secure and providing
the
developers team with potential changes
in the code that they want and some
let's say recommendations
today I think that this approach will
not resonate with the vast majority of
people because we shift towards a more
deaf second way of doing things that
people want to have the control in their
hands
we got inspired from that and we want to
promote security as code which is the
methodology of codifying security
decisions that are then shared with
other teams
we therefore expect the Security Experts
of an organization to codify their
security knowledge in readable and
executable form and then socialize this
knowledge with the rest of the company
so that developers can read understand
change and execute security decisions
that are codified this way
we believe that the speed of devops
would not be affected and Security will
be a seamless Observer just for when
there are security alerts that as I'm
gonna show you later in the demo they
are very readable very understandable
explained very well with references and
security can become
uh not a stopper because traditionally I
know that especially in the past we were
seeing as people who say no and stopping
the progress and the speed of an
organization
the way we propose to do securely as
code is via a new language which is
called code ql
cultural is a language that allows you
to query code as if it was data by
describing what you want to find and not
how to find it
this means that is a declarative
language
but it's also a logical language so that
you can use operators like and and or
to show relationships uh between what
you are looking for
the way that it works behind the scenes
is through creating an abstract abstract
syntax tree for your code
which is called a database so this
database is relational and it can find
what you are looking for in a very fast
way
culture is an object-oriented language
which means that you can benefit from
features like encapsulation and
inheritance composition but also the
object-oriented nature which is like
relationships in the form of
lions are animals so that you can talk
as generic as possible in the same way
as NASA spoke as generic as possible and
they pick vulnerabilities across their
whole code base
code Trail is free for open source and
uh it it's also on on a paid license for
Enterprises
I'm gonna show you how you can enable it
in a bit but like I said before the
point for today's presentation is to
show you how you can write in control so
my goal today is for everybody to live
with knowing the basics of this language
I started as a beginner myself around
five to six months ago and I got very
fast with it very easily and quite
quickly because I could benefit from
templates there are so many templates
and ready-made code there that is just
asking for placeholders in order for you
to find what you want
I don't reinvent the wheel in the
language and I don't expect people to
invent their wheel either
NASA or other teams around the world and
back Hunters they don't start from
scratch but you are also very welcome to
start from from scratch if it's gonna
help you we start from a very good level
from the existing queries in the code
base in the database and we are building
on top of those
another another thing I want to say
about code 12 is that internal supports
JavaScript Java python go brust C C plus
plus C sharp Ruby is coming in the next
year as well as kotlin and many other
languages are in the road
so before going to the today's demo
I want to make sure that everybody is in
the same line I'm gonna show how I can
pick an SQL injection vulnerability for
a tailored code base so imagine that
this code base is private to me I want
to use code 12 to pick up SQL injections
and I want to pick it up in a genetic
fashion like NASA did with the
vulnerability we've seen
for those that are not familiar with ski
injection just have a look in the meme
and I'm going to explain the
vulnerability in 20 seconds
so this movement is very famous in the
cyber security industry it's from XKCD
the root cause of the vulnerability is
input sanitization really that is either
not happening at all or happening
incorrectly
so behind the scenes you have codes
similar to this one which is written in
SQL
where the developer is expecting
a student's name to be added into the
database but the problem is that the
developer here assumes that the user is
very innocent and the only thing they
can pass is indeed
a student's name they trust the user
really but in reality if we can see in
the SQL code below
someone that has malicious intentions
can can indeed close the quote that is
expected above
to close naturally because you just pass
a name add a semicolon and through that
semicolon are the malicious command that
can be to drop the students table or it
can be to create another admin user that
will have access to the students
database personal data
card information
etc etc
the possibilities are endless really
with UNESCO injection vulnerability I
just want to make sure that everybody
understands where the vulnerability
occurs here
so it occurs in the way that the
untrusted user input enters into the
database
and just before start writing on codeql
I want to introduce some terminology
that it's going to help us with the
templates of the language first of all
we have sources
sources are vulnerability sources that
are places in the program that receive
untrusted user input
in the example I've shown you the source
is this one is the execution of
the ins is a call of the insert into
methods where you have untrusted user
input entering the code base
and then you have six things are places
in the program that the malicious user
input is actually being executed
if you don't have malicious input
execution you have an unexploitable
vulnerability
in our example if the untrusted user
input never reaches the sync we don't
have a vulnerability so we will suffer
from many false positives that my demo
is gonna Focus to lower
the sync is actually the place in the
program that the SQL command is actually
being executed it can be the query
execute command
you do have a vulnerability when you
have data flow from sources to things
in no other situation that's the only
situation where you have an SQL
injectionable rabbits now let's go to
our demo to start writing code ql
together
I'm switching to my code editor which is
the vs code
here on the left I have installed the
code ql extension
and I have made my
the code base the intentionally
vulnerable code base that together we
are gonna find vulnerabilities on I
create the abstract syntax Tree by using
a command from the code ql
um command line which is here it's the
mobile Shepherd from o wasp it's an
Android mobile app that is intentionally
vulnerable
so if we explore the database the code
base a bit
just an OTR if I use the where code base
or database they are interchangeable
because the code base is transformed to
the database here
so if we have a look around I want you
to consider a mobile app like that's my
phone here
you enter in the mobile app and you have
a normal application that is asking for
your username and your password to log
in Imagine something very similar the
code behind asking for your username and
your and your password to login is here
line 98 and line 99.
in line 98 and line 99 we can see that
we have the method get text which is
responsible for getting the user input
into the code base
you need to remember that that's the
room for error it's the place where a
malicious user like myself can enter
something malicious in the code base
uh or a user that is trusted can enter
something which is not malicious but
that's the same place that's a place we
need to focus our attention
so if we plan a bit now and I'm back to
my slides
the source is essentially the get text
method
the way code 12 works is similar to SQL
you need to find all the methods in the
program and then filter just those that
are the get text method
so the way that we are going to write
this code today is that first we are
gonna find all the methods in the
program no matter what they are doing
and then I'm gonna specifically restrict
those methods that are accepting user
inputs
so if I switch to my code editor
starting from scratch I'm gonna import
the standard library from java
which is gonna give me all these nice
out of the box ready made functions so I
can be productive and I can write code
faster
some important Java
and then like I said similar to SQL I
can use from where select close like for
example from all the methods of this
code base give me some methods that meet
some specific criteria and return those
methods by the select
let's first start since we are beginners
now and uh in a few moments we are going
to be knowing all the basics let's start
from
to
keywords the from and the select in
plain English I'm gonna ask the language
to give me from all the methods in the
program that are being invoked those all
those methods
so I'm gonna use a type which is called
method access
which is going to return all those
access methods
and if I hover on top of it I can get
some nice help here a method access is
an invocation of a method with a list of
arguments
I also want to have a variable which I
can name call or I can name c i can name
whatever I like and I want to have all
these methods that are being invoked
returns
I'm gonna run this now
and in fact on the right hand side I
have all the methods that are being
invoked in the program
so if I click in here or here you can
see where each method uh lands so by
this I can also say that
I can use codeql just to search my code
and get get myself familiarized with the
code not necessarily to pick security
ruler abilities
so let's get a bit more of help here uh
let's be a bit more specific
by restricting the invoked methods to
just those that are receiving user
inputs
I can use
the code completion functionality of my
ID and get proposals of what functions I
can use
system I'm looking for an argument sorry
I'm looking for a method that is
specific method I can use get methods
so if I hover a bit
get the method gets you the methodox
test by a specific methods it expects
something specific so I can use further
methods like the Hast qualified name
which is expecting a package name a type
and a method name
so when I hover over you can see how I
get the help here
and until I complete the package which
is Android dot widget here
and the type which or the example with
the animals where a lion is an animal we
have the generic type of edit text
and the specific method I'm looking for
is the get text
before I run this I just want to
emphasize the chaining functionality how
expressive it is and how I can use
inheritance composition to get from one
place to another
so I just run this
and I came up with the three invocations
of the get text method in the program it
doesn't mean that they are all
vulnerable I just want to emphasize but
where we are now is the the we know the
places of the program that receive
untrusted user input it can be malicious
or it can be okay
so if I go back so far we have all the
methods of the program that are
receiving user input
let's now find the sink
the sinks are the places in the program
but you have S12 being executed
specifically is the raw query method but
the first argument of it by Nature
because the rest of arguments are like
decoration to the query being executed
so if I go back to the code
and I go to the line 147
we can't see here that we indeed have
zero query methods with the first
argument being passed
and that's exactly our Sig normally in
my day-to-day job I would then go to the
code and search for their query method
manually because I will use code 12 to
do this I will just familiarize myself
with the language which is Java with the
Android package and I will then know
what are the pain points and what to
look for I just want to show you where
everything is invoked so that we are all
more clear on the same page
so the tactic that I'm gonna follow to
pick up things in the program
is the following
I'm gonna start from all the methods in
the program I'm gonna further restrict
my input to those methods that are the
raw query methods specifically
but because I want to avoid false
positive reduce the pressure to the
security team and to the time that
security Engineers would spend to fix
stuff and developers etc etc
I will be more specific and I will only
ask for the first argument of the raw
query method if that first argument is
actually being set I know that I have
things
so if I go now back to my code and I can
code this
on top I have the same functionality
like before for example we get method
has qualified name you see some change
here
um we are not on the Android dot widget
we are looking for the net SQL Cipher
database
the sqlite database is the
hierarchically higher methods and
specifically we are looking for the raw
query but like we said we are looking
for the first argument of the raw query
method so we avoid false positives
so I can use
The Logical features of the language
here by using the end operator
and further restrict
um the call so I can say
that's what we are looking for is the
argument in the first
uh position before the comma so I'm also
introducing another variable here which
is the variable argument which is of
type expression because anything that is
passed inside a method like get argument
or there are clear methods is of type
expression and it's an argument
so I want to be more specific here so
I'm looking for calls in the Raw query
methods
where
the argument is the one
in index
sorry uh we are the argument
is the call to that row query method in
index
zero
because we are software Engineers index
0 is the first argument
so in plain English this query here says
get me all the invocations to the raw
query methods that are having the first
argument being set
so far so good we have sources the sinks
what we are looking for is confirmed
data flow from sources to syncs
without confirm data flow there's no SQL
injection vulnerability happening
and now I'm gonna show you the real
power of the language
by showing you the data flow template
I didn't write this code this code was
ready-made from the language maybe the
NASA team wrote this code maybe my team
will this code or someone else from the
community
well it is asked from me is just to fill
the students here in line 15 and line 19
with the functions that we've done
before for search tests and things
if I explain the code a bit here
on top you have some metadata that are
coming with the language you don't need
to bother with them then you have the
Java Library being push that alongside
some other libraries that are going to
help with the data visualization
and the data flow which is going to help
us to find confirmed flow from data
sources and seeks
then you have the real power of the
language which is what we bring on top
of SQL which is
the object oriented nature you have a
class here a class that extends its
super type getting everything from its
super type so it can make you more
productive less errors much easier to
write less for more
um in here you see
The Constructor that you can use to
initiate further classes
and then I want to speak a bit about
credit Gates credit Gates is the same
thing with functions in other language
or methods
it allows they allow you to reuse logic
they can encapsulate portions of logic
and create functions that are reusable
so since we have time we are 33 minutes
past
let me show you how I can create how I
can transform this to be a predicate so
I don't write the same code over and
over again
uh and I give my team reusable code so
for example if I create a predicate here
and I made I name it sync that is
expecting a method access and also an
argument
I can copy and paste what is in the
where clause
like that
be
and in here I don't need this I'm just
gonna use
the predicate from above passing inside
the call and the argument so if we run
this
on the right you are gonna see that we
arrive at those raw query invocations
that the first argument is being set
so back to the
code here I also want to introduce
another keyword that I find very very
useful and very readable which is the
exists keyword
um I like to joke a bit about it is less
context is more so for example I'm gonna
delete
the fact that we have method calls here
because at the end of the day
vulnerabilities start with method cost
so I'm completely deleting the method
code here
the sync is not expecting an argument
and I can use the exist keyword which
goes like that there exists
a method access
such that
this and this happens
so in plain English here we have
a variable that
lives and dies inside the context of the
methods which makes your code much
faster much readable much more readable
way less confusion for a team to
understand what is this guy talking
about
so if we run this code
we expect to have the exact same results
as before
so having said this let's go back here
and fill that through this
so I'm gonna use the same tactic as
before there exists a medical
such dots when this method is the get
text
I know that I have untrusted user input
entering my code base
so if I copy and paste this
here
the final thing I want to show you from
the presentation is this idea for notes
uh and you see that notes is a special
type in the library data flow here
because if I switch back
we'll present data flow by nodes you
have this idea of a node a having a flow
to another node node D so in the
specific template I show you we need to
represent everything under the node type
in the same way before I use the
Expression type and the method access
type I now need to use the node type so
that I speak the same language with my
template which what I mean is that
well there's a method access that is the
get text method access
I want this node
to equal
but
method call
so if you imagine that on the left here
we have the get text expressed as a node
on the other hand side for the sync we
are gonna have a specific argument the
first argument of the rockware method
uh being the low destination
so if we express this in the same way
there exists a metal access
such that something happens which is
more specific it's ready from here
actually
for coping and paste that
the only change I need to do is that
here we don't have the expression
argument we have the node expression
which is like that okay
if I run this code you are gonna see the
real power of code 12 which are are
confirmed SQL findings with specific
Pathways without any
um false positives
so I just run a code and on the on the
right you can see we have two SQL
injection vulnerabilities to confirmed
findings let's break them down
the first finding has two paths
so a security professional I need to fix
all the paths but from my experience
from before I can guarantee that the
best teams I've seen in my life can fix
one or two
paths at a time they need to run more
tests and they need to fail more to fix
everything
if I go here and I click on the path
I can first click on get text to see the
first let's say uh
half of the journey that this
vulnerability starts from so the first
is where the first untrusted user input
is getting to the language which is here
line 98.
let me zoom out a bit
let's follow the flow
if we click on check name you have that
this check name is now passed into a try
catch block where we try to understand
by using the login method
if the user has passed credentials that
are indeed part of the database I.E if
the username exists in the database and
if I now follow the login method
I go to the signature of the login
method that is expecting a username
Etc
and then these specific flow continues
into the raw query where you have the
place in the program that is being
uh pass to the Rock query method which
is going to execute
an SQL command
that's the very first flow
the next flow is this one
which is actually the exact same way of
doing things but instead of checking
that the user has passed the correct
username and password so the login
method
equals true it now equals false so I
want you to notice the difference
between the lines 102
and the lines
116. you have the exact same flow but
the one equals true the other equals
false in reality they are both
vulnerabilities
I've seen many teams fixing just the one
of the two but in reality you need to
fix everything
so SQL the code 12 will give you all the
pathways
to that place
and in here we have another confirmed
finding that is now the password
following the exact same Journey
to uh
the database
and here that's the one for the password
so I now want to highlight that
okay this is a very simple example but
in a real code base
with a flow between tens or
hundreds
of places you will need something very
powerful like code 12 to give you all
the confirmed flow of the data so that
you don't have to follow manual in
general what you do manually is very
error prone and in cases specifically
when you have this kind of
um let's say equals true equals false
and all these flow between the codebacks
if I go back to my slides
I promise to show you how you can enable
codeql passively so that you can use out
of the box all these queries that my
team is writing massage writing other
Enterprise teams are writing in the back
counters
it's very easy it's a few clicks if I
head to my personal profile
and I pick one of my open source
projects like for example Matthew paxos
you can see here that I can just
navigate to security
code scanning alerts click setup code
scanning
configure scanning tool
and I can choose code URL analysis which
is here
so I click configure
and there's a yaml file being created
for me I can just commit this file and
every time I'm gonna commit and push
code uh I'm gonna get alerts I'm gonna
show you how they look I can specify
which language I want to pick Alex from
and I also want to specify how vocal is
the language like for example I want the
language to touch I want the alerts to
touch on quality stuff or be very like
uh conservative and just give me back
from findings
uh so back to the slides the next thing
I want to show you is how alerts are
looking
so if I go to another code I have
another project I go to security
I click so here code scanning is already
up I click oh sorry not on the secrets I
need to click on code scanning alerts
few alerts
and I can see here that I have nine open
alerts and five that I've closed
um if I click on one of the alerts
you have the explanation here I have use
of protein or weak cryptographic hashing
algorithm on sensitive data
you see exactly where the others are
carrying
you have some nice explanation that is
clickable and also on the right you can
see the pattern CW is that you can click
and understand more about them
uh
that's how another Earth is looking
and finally
to start your journey these are some
resources that I found useful in my own
Journey
codehere.com security lab help come get
involved some ctfs that we run
some time ago in general like I said you
don't start from scratch
you start and build on top of code that
already exists
and uh
you can be very productive very easily
with the templates like the one I use
for the demo
finally
there are some new initiative that my
team is has started over the past two
and a half months where we open our
doors in in a project called Community
office hours we welcome open source
maintainers
we sit down with them for an hour or
more through different meetings and we
can discuss the security surface of a
program
um what there are security problems are
concerns often maintainers come to us
and they don't know what they don't know
in terms of security
so we have helped them in defining their
security policies we help them to
understand how they can quickly
and effectively
notify the community about the potential
vulnerability in their code base and
this is something that the community has
embraced and when we open some more
slots you can find about them in GA
security lab in Twitter
we publish our research there we publish
our educational content there and I
would love to have more open source
project so that our impact is
um is growing more and more
so I would like to thank you on exactly
45 minutes uh I was upsetting you for
having me and you for listening uh to me
let's use the remaining time for
questions and if you think about
questions later I will be more than
happy uh to contact me in in my own
media like for example Twitter at jkcso
or you can add me in
and that was it I'm open for your
questions and let me stop sharing my
screen
thanks Joseph great talk
yes we've got we've got a couple of
questions coming in I'm going to start
off with a couple of simple ones
actually before we get to those so a lot
of people may be more familiar with
sast dust SCA those kind of kind of
terms so could you just clarify the high
level is it a dust tool is it a SAS tool
um is it neither of those just yeah
start off with that one that's a great
question Nathan and thanks so much the
audience for asking uh code ql is a SAS
tool
um I know that those two are very
helpful they can help you find things uh
out when you run real variables on them
and find things on the way cultural
doesn't run the code it doesn't is not
able to pick variables it's a SAS tool
but
um something very useful that I've seen
from clients in the community is that
some code URL alerts we are not 100
let's say
um correct at the time but through
specific data that they found with dust
tools they were indeed true code ql
alerts this means that the false
positives are very low and it's a it's a
product that they can it can complement
Your Dust a lot
I assume therefore that you can use the
output of Das scanners to then perhaps
Drive some queries within code ql for
other projects that you might have in
your organization exactly to reduce
their false positives and to have a more
data driven approach in you tailoring
your queries
okay so a specific question about
um advantages perhaps so where would you
see are the key advantages then between
something like code ql and a traditional
SCA or SAS tool that that you know
people on this are watching this video
or or viewing this will or perhaps
having their own organization today
that's another great question
um I think the three main
differentiators of code ql uh in
comparison to other tools is first of
all the 10 tracking functionality
um as we've seen in the demo in the data
flow we had at the end that's something
that other SAS tools are not so powerful
on
um which is very useful for security
vulnerability research at least
for someone who wants to follow a change
across the way see where data flows
where exactly in which situation like
when something is true or when something
is false is something that can save you
a lot of time and can make your fixing
process much much easier the second
thing I want to touch on is the open
source element of it
someone can enable code ql for free for
an open source project and benefit out
of the box for all these Collective
knowledge we've built all together as a
community for the past 10 years the fact
that teams like nasas my team with the
331 zero day ruler abilities other teams
that are public and we have spoke
publicly about and you can find our
interview and YouTube is the one for
Mercado Libre which is the Amazon of
South America
um they can also contribute queries
trust so this is very powerful when you
are an Enterprise or someone who wants
to have private repo you can build on
top of that
and finally the other thing that I think
differentiates us is that the amount of
time and the resources I don't want to
say resources and speak about people the
teams we have that they focus on
reducing false positives no query is
gonna make it to the database unless we
absolutely
that's Siri unless we absolutely reduced
to the uh minimum false positives uh
some people joke in my team and they are
like oh it's much easier for you to like
achieve this super amazing thing that is
I don't know once in a Million
van a query getting into our database
that is not polished for the minimum
false positives so these three
okay thank you and actually we've got a
follow-up question really around around
the time and around uh the maintenance
to create the tests especially if you're
in an organization which has some pretty
big applications that they've built
perhaps over a number of years and even
ones that perhaps haven't had code ql or
even any security scanning previously
what's the kind of
you know practical maintenance elements
that you could um you can give us your
experience about
I would say that it doesn't have a huge
overhead like you see on my demo iron I
specified specifically I specified the
get text method as the method where
untrusted user input is coming in
but anybody could just be way more
generic and just say all those methods
of type edit text that's if you remember
when I've used the hash clarified name I
use the package android.widget the
generic type edit text and then instead
of saying get text I will say any so an
organization with rapidly changing code
to avoid fragile queries they can be as
generic as possible they can use the
object-oriented in hrf code 12 by using
the generic types and then they can use
the keyword any so that they can get
started quickly without the false
positives and the overhead that an
organization will need
okay thanks um another question actually
is regarding
um
these other possible it's a very
powerful tool it's very obvious for me
from the demo how powerful at all it
actually is what else could we use it
for right you know we can obviously find
vulnerabilities I'm thinking whether
manual code reviews could possibly use
it peer reviews of code but what else
where else can we use it
I will say to that's another great
question I would say to to set your code
so
um I've told you about the zero day
vulnerability I found in 2018 I wish I
knew about codeql at the time uh the way
I found this vulnerability was by
reading the whole code for Bitcoin
that another project has support and I
found the vulnerability for that top 10
cryptocurrency that was uh for for
Bitcoin I didn't have or I didn't know
about coach at the time so I had to like
um manually go over the code and
establish mental relationships I go from
X to Y I could use code 12 for that I
could write a few lines of code to go
specifically to that method understand
um or Express in code where I want to go
next what I want to find instead of how
to find it and in general I'll search
for all those pain points in the code
um it can be just to familiarize
yourself with a code base not
specifically or necessarily for
vulnerability research
it's a method of querying your code as
if it was data
so how long does Coquille been around
then
um it's around for 10 years uh more than
that it's around 12 years originally
being created by semol a small startup
in words by 29 and then after 10 years
of implementation and working with
Enterprises it was acquired by GitHub in
late 2019
and GitHub was previously acquired in
2018 by Microsoft so think about uh code
12 being the code scanning feature of
GitHub and also for Microsoft
okay and just going back to actually
understanding element we talked about
SCA the dependent we didn't find
dependencies or insecure dependencies in
your code
[Music]
um I love this question uh because it's
so pressing many organizations are
suffering from Supply chains attacks
they are so prevalent these days
that way I will do it is the following
I would use 100 code Trail to scan the
dependencies I have if those are open
source
if those are not open source I will use
dependables in order to which is another
uh feature we have another product we
have to get notified about secure
versions so that I can update
um on the spot really
so to summarize here while code 12 is
a tool you can use to search for
vulnerabilities in code or general to
query your code you can query your
dependencies for vulnerabilities in if
those are open source in the same way
you will query your own code
okay thank you and can you just run
through the languages it supports as
well it's quite a long list and I think
it's been added to as well so of course
so uh My Demo was in Java other language
supported this subscript python go rust
C C plus plus C sharp and it's always
um
how can I say culture is always under
development there are huge software
engineering teams that are introducing
new features in the language based on
user feedback and new languages that are
coming is Ruby uh actually very soon in
a few months from now kotlin as well is
coming in many many languages are
underway that I can't really
publicly disclose unless they go on the
public roadmap
Okay cool so we're running out of time
we've got about a couple of minutes I
think trying to squeeze in perhaps
another one or two
um so if people were starting from
scratch can you just remind us how they
would get it onto their projects just a
very very quick overview of how they
might enable that
sure so
um
let me can I show my screen
yeah we've got about a minute so
yeah that's vs code you just go to
extensions which is here by clicking
extensions you write code 12.
that's the official code ql extension
when you install it you are gonna see
code ql being here and you can connect
uh with your with the code base you want
to query by passing in a GitHub URL
that's pretty much it
uh otherwise you need to compress create
an abstract syntax tree for your code
base and connect it to the
vs code it's very simple it takes one
click and from there you are going to
have all the queries that exist from
before all this Collective knowledge you
can either run the queries out of the
box or you can double clicking on
existing query like I did with the data
flow template and you can code a bit on
that if you want you can start from
scratch in the way we started with the
source great that's great Joe what a
great session really appreciate your
time I really appreciate you coming on
to appsec EU
um and once again
um yeah yeah thanks thanks for me and
everyone else for your time today thank
you so much for today and
um thanks so much it has been amazing
the organization was superb I'm very
looking forward to hear back from the
audience and to help everybody let's
keep in touch