hello everyone so welcome to the Builder
track so I'm Muskan mangla volunteer in
the West Community I'll be moderating
this session during the next 45 minutes
you'll be listening to Dr Luca and
Shiraz present web developers Beware of
the topics for SAS in your code please
submit any questions you have during
this session in the QA tab just to the
right of the video in the harbor
platform I'll be asking Dr Luca and
Faraz your questions in the last 10
minutes of this session please note that
the chat function in Zoom for attendees
is disabled but you can leave your
comments and chat using the chat tab in
the huaweba well I'll introduce the
speakers briefly Dr Luca is a part of
the security research team at sap where
he is contributing to the research
strategy and to the software security
analysis area in particular
Faraz is a PhD student at sap University
doing his research on the web security
domain in his work he focuses on the
static application security analysis to
point out to the difficulties of these
tools and the solutions to have better
coverage of the source code now handing
over to the speakers for this session
and over to you Dr Luca and Shiraz
thanks a lot for the introduction
um I hope you can hear me well good
morning so a pleasure to be to be here
uh yes I will share this presentation
with farasa we start with the short
introduction context Etc then for us we
go into the technical details and then I
will take over for a few conclusion
remarks this work is also a
collaboration with other security
researchers Julia was a former
internal sap security research Fabian is
a chief scientist she threft and David
balzaroti is professor at a curriculum
um so I end all this work is really uh
let's say applied the research work you
will see today and is uh under under an
European project it is called testable
that started last September and uh what
you're going to see here are first
results coming out from that project so
if you like the results please follow up
on the let's say on the news in that
project uh first if you can move to the
next slide please
thanks a lot yeah okay this is the
agenda I already said I will start with
some context and for us we'll take over
with the technical details because this
is really uh something he did during his
PhD that is still ongoing but it's
really one first good Mission he
achieved in this PhD and so for us we
present a motivational example why it is
important what we are doing the approach
that we developed we developed and then
I will take over for some conclusion and
Next Step next flight to us thanks okay
so the context is really fast static
application security testing so I don't
know who is in the audience but I would
suspect that there are some developers
among you web developers and so perhaps
some of you has used these tools uh but
let me quickly say what these tools do
so essentially imagine you have an
application it can be a web application
but it can be also any software
application right well if you have the
code what you can do is to use a static
analyzer so a SAS tool in order to
analyze this code with the hope of
detecting some vulnerabilities so the
code will analyze the code we will
analyze the the source code of your
application tool will analyze the source
code of your application probably
creating a kind of internal structure
initially abstract syntax 3 with some
additional relationship maybe control
flow also some data flow whatever and
then they will start navigating in these
internal structure to discover
vulnerabilities like cross-size
scripting SQL injection others
however I mean
you you get findings from these two
sometimes you get false positive uh and
uh perhaps you you analyze your audit
all the all the findings you fix the the
two positive that were also reported uh
at some point you reach a verdict that
everything is fine so you get the
traffic light
that is green
okay so now what is the conclusion I
mean can we really say that everything
was analyzed in your code and that there
are no vulnerabilities so are we really
sure there are no false positive false
negative sorry in that in that
application uh so this is the kind of
question we were
investigating uh knowing that SAS tools
are widely used in industry so I'm from
we are from sap sap is a large software
company and we use SAS tools internally
uh to let's say during our software
development life cycle to verify to
analyze a program before shipping right
so it's not the only uh tool that we use
it's not the only approach we also have
some Dynamic analysis inside but static
analysis is for sure one of the means we
use in order to ensure that our products
are more secure
and especially when it is about
injection vulnerabilities these tools
are believed to be pretty pretty good
and actually also in the OS code review
guide there is a version two uh I don't
remember when it was delivered but you
have a link just below and if you go on
figure one and figure two of that guide
you will see a kind of survey that was
done quite some time ago in 2015 but I
don't think the let's say really the
mood of developers that were
participating in that survey changed and
they were really saying that yes he did
such tools they believe is a good weapon
against injection vulnerability
uh for us can you move to the next slide
but so as I was saying before so was all
the code analyzed I really sure that
there are no bugs no uh let's say
undetected vulnerability so Force
negatives that are just under this Gap
and this is the kind of question we have
investigated uh to understand let's say
how good or how easy or how hard it is
to do testing with the sustool and how
can we improve the testing if if we can
of course so and this is what we call
testabilities amount testability for
sust so how easy is to test an
application with the SAS tool what is
that makes really difficult for a sus
tool to to analyze an application what
makes it easy
etc etc so now I leave the first for us
to go into the technical details
thank you Luca I hope my voice is clear
so as Luca mentions that uh
what we are missing or is the static but
what much confidence can we have with
that with the static tools
and with you I would like to go through
an example sorry I went to this an
example so here we have an old cve and
with this old cve there's a
vulnerability and the tool we are not
able to discover is a vulnerability
inside but let us go to understand the
path of this of this code and then we
will go more in more details
so here actually we can see that there's
one line of code which is required one
so here is a PHP code and the required
ones in just including a file and we can
see the file it's it's a variable so if
this variable is controlled by an
attacker he can control which which file
will be included he can do some
manipulation here so he can he we will
have a file inclusion vulnerability
so for this we call that the sync so we
have the thing that we need to to check
if this thing there's a value coming
from a source a source as meaning as a
value coming from an external so the
user can control this this variable then
he can control which file will be
included and then maybe the the user
will it will be an attacker which will
manipulate here and we will have the
vulnerability
so if we go backward from this from this
line we can see that the ACT file is
coming from this from this variable act
and it's coming from this GPC get string
inside GPC get string we can see this
there is this called user Funk array in
PHP called user function array is just
to call a function dynamically
so then the name of the function can be
inside a variable or in in our case the
name of the function is just defined
here statically so from this line the
function GPC gate will be called
sorry
so if you go to the function GPC git
which is as we have the the post
which is the source so we can see now
that there is a path from a source to a
sink
where the source where the user can
enter something and then he can
manipulate which file will be included
and that will call the for a firing
query
it's important to understand the
the
vulnerability here
to check then
with a static tool so we just take this
we just take this
vulnerable codes that we already
discussed and we scan it with static
tool and the static many of the static
tools they didn't discover the
vulnerability
what is the main reason of that
we have a doubt that's okay this call
user Frank array we are calling the
function dynamically what if the tool is
not able to understand this line and how
we can check that
to check that
we just called we'll just use something
called the testability pattern
actually the distributed it's just it's
accessibility better it's very simple
code it has a source and it has a sink
it's the same as we explained it before
the source is an input is coming from
external user and the thing in this case
it's an equal for for the values that
will cause an xss but it's not really
important to understand what type of
vulnerability here but we just say okay
we have a source and we have a sink and
there's a path between this source and
sync
so now we will try to play around try to
make it a bit more difficult inside we
will inject our targets between the
source and sync to check if the tools
they are still able to handle these
targets or not
and now in our case we have the case of
cold user function array
and we want to to test the code user
Frank array what we do
just we just simply we tried with our
patterns we try to be straightforward
cover only the the topics that we want
to cover minimize the code so here we
can we can see that we have the call
user function array
we are calling the function f passing an
input returning the input and then we
are printing it so here's also the
vulnerability
and we are sure that we don't have
another Target only we have the code
user Frank array
what about the static tools
when we run when we scan this code with
the static tools we can see that 4 out
of six
in our Arsenal that's the awareness of
not able to handle this code and
discover this vulnerability
and one of them is the commercial tool
we have two commercial Tools in our
Arsenal one of them is a commercial tool
just didn't detect the vulnerability
here
what we do is we try to transform the
pattern so here actually we are just
calling the function we are using call
user function array a built-in function
to call the function GPC gate but
actually we can call the gbck directly
we don't really need to use this this
line
and then in this way we are fixing the
the targets and there is no targets
anymore
but how we can be sure there is no other
Targets in the past between the source
and the sink after doing this
transformation
we scan the code again and then we found
that the commercial tool is able to
detect the file inclusion vulnerability
in this code
that's meaning now the the volume is
solved and we are detecting this just
the stable Target
it's important to point here the effect
of the testability target it could be
just a simple line of code or multiple
line of codes that they are blocking the
flow for the static tools and the static
tools cannot cover what is after
in this projects that we are discussing
the cve actually this function which is
called GPC gate strings it's called many
many times and every time the the tool
will and it's always returning a source
every time there's a call the tool will
consider that as a safe value that it's
not coming from an external user just
because of one line of codes as it were
not able to hunt
so we discussed the effect
uh also after creating our pattern as we
already already so we create different
instances we try to make it a bit more
difficult and check different cases
between between the tools so we already
discussed showing the function is
defined statically what if it's defined
as a constant inside the code and if we
apply constant propagation we can know
which function will be called so it's
the name of the function is inside the
variable with instance 2 but actually
this F variable is already defined
before
and with nss3 just we can know a part of
the name of the function so we can have
like for example here the function is f
underscore then there's something so I
can have a set of possible functions
that can be called which is F1 or F2
so that will help us to reduce the
search space and maybe we can focus only
with these two functions
so now I will want to to go so after we
discuss the how the effect of one when
the stability with arbit I would like to
go through our Research into theology
our work is is divided on three phases
we will go deeply in each phase but let
me say that in the first phase we create
the patterns and we check them with the
static tools
with the second
uh we want to to find their prevalence
and the real projects and in the third
we want to transform this pattern and
see and see their impact on real
projects
so let me begin with the pattern
creation for the patterns we didn't want
to be a language specific we want to our
approach to be generalized for that we
choose two different languages which is
PHP and JavaScript
for many patterns there is a lot of
intersection between the two languages
but it's also it could have one one
language have more features than other
depending on the features that is
providing depending on the dynamicity of
the language or demanding also how the
tool is is provided behaving with with
this language maybe the tool will be
better with one language than other
language
and because we want to be a
systematically
with our creating for our patterns we go
through the documentation of the
languages
we read the documentation we check the
corner cases we check the discussion of
the community about the difficulties of
some of of some cases for the language
and we were creating the patterns so we
create 120 patterns instances for PHP at
115 instances for JavaScript
after creating the patterns
we measure them with our static units so
we have
some of the research tools and some of
commercial tools
we can see that the commercial Tools in
most of the cases they are behaving
better
but overall for uh for PHP there's no
language support more than 50 percentage
of our patterns while for JavaScript
they reach the 60 percentage
uh meanwhile if we take the combination
just like how many patterns that is not
solved by any tool so the combination
can cover 66 percentage of the patterns
in PHP and God can reach for 82
percentage percentage for JavaScript
so like that we create our the stability
the our patterns library but what if our
our patterns are just Corner cases or
just fancy features are no one used some
something just is not really exist and
maybe it's just like okay we can we can
just ignore them
to answer this equation we we went to
check the prevalence of this project of
this patent and real projects
so we try to create a diverse data set
of projects we went to GitHub and we
clone a low popular projects 1000
projects that they have between 20 and
70 Stars medium popular between 200 and
700 Stars High popular 1000 projects
that they have more than one thousand
stars also we found the website it's
called source codeester that is offering
for the community an open source
websites that they can use a part of the
code or they can use the world code
so we combine this data set and we
create we have in our data set 3
340 projects
after after collecting the projects we
begin to use our patterns as a query
inside the source code to search the
occurrence of this of this pattern in
this project
and we found that our targets are highly
prevalent
actually we will experience
yeah we will have 21 unique patterns in
average per project
and we will experience one pattern every
20 line of of code
just to explain here the the graph that
we have so each point is representing a
project
the colors that's representing the sets
that we have as we said it's a high
popular medium popular low popular and
the source code Ester
the Y will represent the number of
unique patterns per project while the X
it will more make me understand how many
line of code I will pass until I will
experience a pattern so in for that the
x is the number of line of code divided
by the occurrence of all the patterns
so here is the patterns for for only for
for all the for all the tools in our in
our work
but we already saw that the commercial
tools are behaving much better than the
uh the research tools so we focus on the
tool to uh commercial tools for PHP
and we take only the type the patterns
that that was not able to be solved by
these tools
and we all we again see that our our
targets are highly prevalent even for
the commercial tools
so the commercial tool will will have an
average certain unique pattern in a
project and we will experience one
pattern every 47 line of code while the
other tool is a bit better that it we
will have 8.5 unique patterns in average
per project
and we will experience one button every
203 line of codes
so now we see this
the the projects are highly privileged
as the patterns are highly prevalent and
we already saw the effect of one targets
how much it can make difficult for the
static tool to handle so now we can see
we can estimate that how much we are
missing uh for negative
when we are using the static tool and we
see that the tool has cannot handle all
the situations
what will be the main message of this
higher prevalence I will return back to
this point but before I just want to
mention that
we have a table in our in our paper
explaining all the details about the
patterns the name of the patterns the
dimensions the tool the answer and their
prevalence
between the four sets in our that is it
and we have this example actually when I
create this pattern I was saying okay
who will use this call user function
array for calling a function statically
like if they can cause a function
directly but I found that
this
target it's used in 208 projects are for
out of 1000 projects in high popular
projects that they have more than one
thousand stars
and to take to take the
the message from from the higher
prevalent prevalence of our patterns it
will help the user to make them aware
about the area of the code that can be
confusing for the static tools instead
of doing the manual work everywhere they
can focus manually as their manual work
in specific areas as the tool is not
able to handle
or maybe it could be possible to
transform some of these patterns and
then it will be reducing the manual work
for the for the developer or the
security team and we will have more uh
we will reduce the risk of having Force
negative
so how we will do this transformation
and how how is the impact of these
patterns that's what what we we
discussed in our last phase of our
experiment
in this phase
we have the
we we have the manual and the automated
experiment
I just want here to say that okay we
have the just just to to have a a brief
idea before we go in details so I have
the project
I I scan it with the static tool and I
have my reports then I will do some
transformation in the middle and I will
have another version of the project I
will scan it again I will have a new
another alert I will compare between the
old and the new one and I will check the
new one because the new one happened
because of my transformation and then I
will have the alerts the tool will give
me okay this path is possible to be
vulnerable
but in my side I have to check if this
path if it's a true positive or if a
false positive
so the manual pattern transformation
I went to an old CD
I I scan it with a static tool if the
tool couldn't find the vulnerability in
this in the static tool then I will
discover the patterns in this vulnerable
path
after I point point the patterns I will
transform them
in the world project
so it's an old cve so we return to the
version of the old version of the
project when was this this problem
exists and we take we take this version
and we do the transformation on this
version
after doing the transformation we run on
the static tools and we check the new
alerts manually
at the same time
we went to the latest version of this
project
and we do the same transformation and we
run with the static tools
so
is the is a problem or the vulnerability
is already discovered before and it's
already solved so if we think about it
it shouldn't be it shouldn't be now
vulnerabilities in the latest version
but is that is this correct I will
answer this question in few slides
but before I will go to that slide I
just want to say we did the
transformation and we experienced three
type of transformation
in the first one we already discussed
this one it's semantically preserving so
actually the code is the same I'm not
changing anything I'm just going instead
of calling the function using colluder
function array I'm calling it directly
in the second approach in the second
transformation so
I need to apply over approximation
and here in this example actually it's
just like we are forwarding the user
from one PHP file to another PHP file by
using a JavaScript
and the tool is not able to understand
and parse the JavaScript to understand
this flow from one file to another file
what I do simply is that I delete this
this
redirecting and I didn't include a
normal PHP
they are the same almost
but in PHP when I have when I Define a
variable in in file one I can use it in
file two
so there's no problem here but when I do
a redirect and I Define the file as a
variable in file one and I will come to
use it in file 2. it will be not defined
it will be an error
while in the third
type we need a developer helper here I
need to explain a bit this pattern so in
this pattern we already speak about the
source and the thing but here's the
topics here here it's a built-in
function it's called extract extract
will take an array and will generate
variables from this array the keys in
this array it will be the name of the
variables and the values in this array
to be the values of the value
so here
the a actually will carry the value of
AAA which is a which is the source so
here we have an exercise vulnerability
and when I was doing this manual work I
experienced a code like that
extract post and then an SQL query and
then I have username and password from
where this username and password even
for maybe a person who is reading the
code is difficult to know so how the
static tool will deal with that actually
this username and password are coming
from the post
so here we need the developer to do
annotation to say okay this username and
password are part of this post
then if we look to the code
it will be very simple for the static
tool now to discover the SQL injection
in this in these cases okay I have
variables coming from the post going to
SQL query without sanitization so here
we have an escape we have an SQL
injection
so
uh
in our paper we work on five cve for PHP
5 cve for JavaScript
we have all the details on the paper we
put the cve number the vulnerability in
gcpe the pattern that we transform and
the new alerts as we discovered so for
PHP
we transform nine patterns and for
JavaScript we we transform 17 patterns
adding the vulnerable version actually
after doing the transformation
we found 300 204 through positive real
vulnerabilities or exist in the
vulnerable version after transforming
these nine patterns
the static tools were able to detect
them
and 20 uh in JavaScript
so that was about the vulnerable version
while
in the latest version we have we
discovered six and new conferent
vulnerabilities from compared by the
developers and gain the cve about them
it's an old cve it we have an old cve
and the problem is already known
and uh till the moment we are
discovering these vulnerabilities
because of these targets so actually
it's important when we receive a call
when we receive a report from from bug
Bounty or someone to tell us okay you
have a vulnerability here it's not
enough to fix this vulnerability
I need to search for the reason why this
vulnerability was exist and I didn't
found it before
if I'm using static tools and the reason
that I is the targets so I received I
received the report I go to the main
reason which is the target I try to
transform it and then I run the tool
again and I will have a better coverage
I will have less less risk of forcing it
so
this manual transformation done on just
10 projects
but actually this results give us the
motivation
to go to automatic pattern
transformation
for this for that we choose we choose
five pattern that we say okay we will
transfer them manually automatically
sorry we transform them automatically on
the data sets as we discussed before a
300 300 projects inside and we will
compare the the alerts before and after
and we will check the new alerts
manually
so here just a table to explain that we
have R1 R2 to R5 is is the pattern that
we choose and we have their occurrence
in each state in our data State
depending on the occurrence and the
number of separations
then we have the number of new alerts
that we found and out of this new alerts
how many true positive we have
so in this experiment
we refactored a
1170 project with the occurrence of 32
000.
we had nine around 9 000 new alerts in
72 applications
overall we discovered
370 new vulnerabilities in 43
applications
out of this 370 370 new vulnerabilities
55 vulnerabilities in high popular
projects thus they have more than one
thousand stars
so we can see that it's just by
transforming five patterns
but as we have we have already around
the where we have 120 instances for PHP
says we could have this coverage so
it's it's giving us uh it should be
giving us an alert just how to how to
work with the static tool and it's it's
of course it's reducing the manual work
a lot but still we cannot really say
okay we are safe after using the static
tool and the targets will help us and
help the static tool to have better
coverage
so we already discussed as we have many
discoveries depending on two different
uh
experiments manual and automated as we
did we did the responsible disclosure
for all the vulnerabilities and we gain
the CD is all the details actually about
about the manual and the automated
experiments about the cves
about about the the patterns everything
is the is inside our repository on
GitHub so please feel free to to go to
there and and check all the resources as
we have over there
now I pass again to to Luca
sorry just the time to unmute thanks a
lot for us
um so yeah indeed just to wrap up and to
take the main takeaway messages out of
these so you saw that we created the
stability patterns and we created those
for PHP and more or less more than 100
more than 100 also for JavaScript 150
whatever we saw that these patterns this
that that capture what we call targets
so things that might confuse static
analyzers
uh we saw that these targets are real
that uh if you if you search for them in
real application you find them and
actually I think this is also a very
good added value of our war because why
we create a pattern that is a small test
case for a SAS tool we also create what
we call the discovery room so what
allows us to discover the pattern in
real application that discover the tarpy
in the tarpet area application
and then we saw that by transforming
them it's not always possible
and feras mentioned that there are these
three types of transformation we we
identified so far so it's not always
possible perhaps sometimes we need help
from the developer if the developer
wants to you know to help but at least
the developer will know that that part
of the code will not be analyzed by the
tool so that is already quite important
information because it provides
awareness right
and we saw that by doing transformation
so by Transforming Our top it's by
removing our targets we were able to
discover to detect a lot of
vulnerabilities uh that was a very huge
amount of work especially for feras he
mentioned about 9 000 new
findings from the static analyzer he
didn't analyze all of them of course he
analyzed I think 2700 and out of time he
was able to discover
317 new vulnerabilities and if you count
also with the manual experiments is more
than 400 and by doing the responsible
disclosure developments of this project
confirmed that essentially what we were
let's say auditing as true positive was
a real true positive I mean not in all
what what this transformation show is
that by doing that work we can really
increase the testability of the
application when the application is
tested via sas2
uh there is also something nice that we
haven't done in our in our world that
perhaps uh can be can be done and I
think it we believe is something uh
important for the community
um so essentially our targets are
available for the community
and if SAS tools wants to use them in
order to measure what they support and
what they do not support and to see also
what can be supported in the new release
perhaps that is something that can be
done so what I'm what I'm saying is from
one side you can try to improve the
testability of an application by
transforming by removing the target from
the other side you can try to improve
the tool by making them supporting more
targets
um so what are we working right now and
what are our next steps uh so we are
trying to enrich our catalogs one thing
that we are doing is to focus on the
Java language also because this is a
language that is very widely used but
overall in the world but also sap uh and
also we are uh let's say maturing our
research so we can see that our pattern
schema uh can be improved we can add
other features to the pattern that are
that are important uh I I cannot provide
the details right now we don't have the
time we are also developing a framework
to operate this pattern so
we want I mean it would be kind of a
database
or file system based but it doesn't
matter so we can create buttons we can
add those patterns in our catalog we can
measure those patterns against an
arsenal of static analyzers and we can
discover those pattern in real
application and perhaps then we can also
you know have operation for transforming
some of them in an automated manner
what we want to do uh in the context of
these European project called testable
is to have let's say a tie with with
obasp and we're going to propose a
novice project so that we can involve
the ovas community we would do this by
by the end of this year I think and what
we would like to do is our part our
targets are already available to the
community but we would like to uh to
make them more specific to the ovas
community uh because I mean the web is
the area we are we are targeting and we
hope that by doing so the obas community
can also uh you know participate create
perhaps some patterns on their own and
help us and the entire Community to
improve uh the the results of the static
analysis side
so if any of you is interested to to use
already now the patterns get in touch
with us because the link that for us
provided that is in the slide is about
the target we had at the time of paper
that is let's say six months ago more or
less so we have definitely updates that
we didn't push yet because we are still
refining the scheme of the pattern Etc
but if you want to use them get in touch
with us but we can provide anyhow the
latest version so that you will not to
work with let's say an old version but
as I said by the end of the year with
the OS Project I think we will deliver a
good stable version of this these
targets can you move to the next line
for us
to us
can you yeah thanks okay so get in touch
with us you have the emails here I
already mentioned this is a joint work
with other researchers funded by an
European project uh there is a Blog that
we um recently wrote if you want to have
a look you have a link in the slide is I
mean is a short blog you can get a bit
more details if you if you continue
reading but I mean I think I think also
if you if you want to say explain our
work to others that could be a good
means and if you have if you want to
have really full technical details then
I would suggest to go into into our
papers or just come back to us and with
that thanks a lot for your attention and
we are open for questioning
for the wonderful and amazing session it
was so insightful and very deep about
the sast and how you analyze the
patterns how you automated and how you
compare the tools very insightful
session all together now jumping to the
Q a uh if audience has asked any of the
questions
uh yeah one of them has has asked like
are you providing the slides where do
you publish the paper or do you have a
link or any kind of information so that
so that they can have a read of your
paper
foreign
having those links
um so uh just if you if you go in these
two links you will find the information
that you are looking for if there is
anything else that that you need just
get in touch with us I mean not the
problem at all
absolutely sure and the rest uh I do
have the queries so I just wanted to
know basically how do you discover your
testibility targets
okay maybe I can take this question so
as we mentioned at the beginning we have
a joint work with the shift left and
actually they provide to us a
framework that we can generate the code
property graph about the source code if
someone doesn't know about the code
property graph it's a way a data
structure to represent the source code
when they there's the AST that is uh the
flow between between the data flow and
the control flow and the code flow it's
a it's a bit complicated data structures
but it's a it's quite famous for
representing the graph and then they
have this their query language to to to
to run on this code property graph and
that's what we used actually to to to
search inside the big amount of of
projects and to search for our
testability targets inside
thank you that is really awesome and how
do you transform them can you transfer
everything or like uh yeah
so as Luke I mentioned that uh till the
moment it's not really possible uh or we
don't have enough mature in in this
direction of our research to say okay
how we can transform all of them this
would be very interesting for the
community for the upcoming work maybe to
check more how they can to do the
transformation
the five Autumn the five automatic
Transformations that we used we used use
them from the T1 type which is a
semantic preserving and that's uh help
us to not produce a huge amount of uh
false false positive when we if you
apply the overall approximation so it
does help us to give a specific number
of alerts and out of this alerts we
could find the species like we can't
find the true positive inside
okay thank you for answering and the
last question uh so how OS Community can
take advantage of your testibility
patents
maybe I can take that one
um so yeah as we mentioned before we uh
okay the the patterns are already
available so if anyone wants to use them
it can do that I would suggest again to
come in touch with us because there is
an ongoing version so it could that the
person could just get this ongoing
version rather than the the oldest one
um the other one
um however I mean we will definitely try
to add this OS Project uh to
um let's say advertise and to make our
patterns more tied to the to the overs
community and I hope we hope that by
doing so
um we will have yeah more people uh
let's say helping us in this work and
perhaps making so web application more
testable for SAS at the end of the day
yeah okay okay for sure thank you so
much and the last question so sorry uh
from audience that I somebody has
mentioned that I would be interested
what was the response from the
commercial SAS tools vendors if any
record regarding missing so many Targets
in the code
so okay it's a good question um I mean
we are in touch especially with the uh
those providing commercial uh static
analyzers and we had a few discussion in
this this respect uh is not something
easy I mean some of those topics do not
require much work to be supported I must
say and so indeed that can be uh pretty
easy for some of these sus tools to you
know to release a new version where some
of these patterns are supported but
something we saw um is something we we
are we we are we thought about very
recently is that for many of these tools
you can also provide what are called
kind of modeling rules so essentially
you can tell the tool how to interpret a
function that they are not able to
interpret at the moment
so
um that is something that is pretty
interesting for us because we have the
pattern that capture a Target that makes
something difficult for the tool okay we
have the discovery rule so we we can
discover this target inside the real
application and now what we could do for
some of them at least is to provide this
modeling rule that will tell the tool
how to solve the target so how to
interpret the target so that is not a
Target anymore so somehow the one
developing the target the creating the
target creating the pattern can provide
these three information and by doing so
the tool immediately should be able to
cover that pattern to to not to support
the Target and so to increase the
coverage and the testability of the
application so this is something we we
uh just started and I hope we will have
some results
I hope and I believe I'm sure about that
that has totally answered the question
and thank you for you so much for your
session it was really wonderful and
amazing to hear you guys and shortly
we'll be moving to the next session in
another 10 minutes so let's wait for it
yeah
thank you very much thank you very much
thank you bye
bye