high security has an image problem this
is not exactly news of the people in
this room right this is one part of that
problem we're seen as a roadblock to
most organizations I've spent a lot of
time doing the compliance work in the
last couple years and even within
security the compliance people are seen
as obstructionist pedants where the
pariah within the larger security pariah
just like coming upon a road full of
goats the reaction to security measures
and often the people who are proposing
the security measures it's not usually
look there's all these cute goats it's
oh for God's sakes I do not have time to
choose a new password that's at least 14
characters long and contains two
uppercase and two lowercase and three
special characters and doesn't repeat
any of any of the last 15 passwords I
had and doesn't have more than two
repeating characters and doesn't contain
my mother's maiden name and how do I go
around this I will bribe people so I can
get my actual job done it doesn't of
course help that the security industry
is also perceived as being unresponsive
to questions as Taylor Swift recently
pointed out when people ask questions of
security people this tends to be the
typical response right maybe not from
every single security person but if it's
the responsive user gets from one
security person it creates an
expectation in that user for the next
time and unfortunately people tend to
share their negative impressions of
security people with their friends and
to be clear like hashtag not all
security people right but also hashtag
enough security people that we should
actually be concerned about this problem
we can't which is too long for Twitter
by the way we can't do our job if this
is the reality for our users more
concerning Lee for the nice people in
this room we can't do our job if our
users think that this kind of thing will
be our response even when it actually
won't it turns out that chilling effects
of having our users think that we think
that they're stupid and evil are in fact
chilling and then users don't come to us
and we can never help them so I saw this
tweet the other day and it really
resonated with me I've worked for
organizations that had major shadow IT
problems because the response were
mighty for every user requests for the
last three years had been closed won't
fix including for things like I actually
need this to support a
customer requests it's just like I don't
care go away your troubles don't bother
ya I don't bother me at all and even if
that's not your response if you just
come from other places where that was
the typical response you have an image
problem that you didn't make but
ultimately one for which you are
responsible making our problems worse
security people have a huge amount of
access and this will mentioned in more
depth later even good security people
with all the rights with the right goals
and duties and ethics in mind treat this
access is kind of a perk of the job
right the issue is that when the public
perception of IT and security staff is
all the staff who abuse their power to
spy on normal users it makes it harder
for us and the nice people to do our job
our access is a trust and a burden and
we need to remember that but a slightly
harder problem is that we need to make
it clear to the users that we remember
that this is a trust that we protect and
a burden so the simple answer to all of
this is well we may be security people
should be nice to people like really
nice so that they like us and that's
true we should be nice to people that's
also not enormous ly helpful for most of
us it's way too general to provide any
kind of specific advice and it's also
impossible to be nice all the time with
a few talented sainted exceptions one of
whom is sitting in the room who despite
crazy people always seems to be like
smiling we need something that has a bit
more structure than just be nice in a
way where yes as Douglas Adams suggested
nobody has to get nailed to anything but
ideally a strategy that's designed for
the real world
where we have a ton of power and ton of
authority but we need to interact with
users who might see as obstructions or
even just be scared right and this is a
common problem when people see hackers
right they see the CNN coverage oh my
god all the hackers are in Vegas and
they have blue hair and they read about
the power that we've accreted either
from normal operations side or just the
red teaming side it's terrifying right
the first time you've told a
non-technical user about something as
simple as a Wi-Fi pineapple what was
their response oh but it wasn't that
seems neat I'll bet it was that's
incredibly terrifying and the problem is
if you know you have people in your
organization with that level of power
even if they seem nice most of the time
you're worried about the larger thing
this is similar to Canada's problem
right there are nuclear weapons in your
backyard most of the time the Americans
seem nice I wonder if they're going to
turn orange and not nice and then do bad
things with them right this is the
problem with security operations so
before getting on to what the solution
is let me introduce myself
hi I'm Brendan I'm security researcher
I'm a security consultant I'm also an
attorney with a deep academic computer
science background I do a bunch of
different things I'm admitted to the bar
what Canadians awesomely call called to
the bar which is a wonderful expression
in my home state of Montana but actually
live in Seattle and I'm looking for a
new opportunity so if you like what you
see in this presentation let's talk
later if you don't like what you see in
this presentation harass me on Twitter
so what everybody else does it it's
great moving swiftly onward it turns out
there's a good historical precedent for
the situation of a small powerful group
needing to interact peaceably with a
larger society I'm not an incredible
student of history partially because
lazy partially because typical American
so I first came across this while
reading halting state by Charles Stross
which is a near-future sci-fi novel and
if you haven't read it you definitely
should it's a novel about augmented
reality alternate reality games and
distributed security in the MMORPGs it's
kind of like the Internet of orcs if you
like and like the Internet of Things you
can still use the Internet of orcs to
attack Brian Krebs which is helpful so
not a joke you should have read the book
in the teen teens in the 1820s London
which had been like let's be clear a
big-deal City I'm not gonna say well
London was a hamlet until the 1820s no
London been a big deal for like 900
years but in 1889 1820s we have the
beginnings of the Industrial Revolution
and beginnings of the modern kind of
urbanization trend and so London was
growing ever more massive the police
force was not there's a huge variety of
detail to what I'm gonna say next so I'm
gonna basically hand wave over all of it
but the summary of this is that policing
in general in the whole world was mostly
handled by local constables right
there's not a lot of order - constables
there's no constable Constabulary
Academy there's none of that right there
is pretty much the kindly old guy who
locks up
the drunk and lets him go with the next
morning right more problematically than
that London then as now was a metropolis
composed of a ton of small towns not one
enormous city so to give you an idea
this is London just a little red
outlined area this is the city of London
these days the city of 1 is basically
just huge financial building towers
nobody actually lives in the City of
London or almost nobody so it stands
that since this city is small and filled
with no houses Greater London must be
bigger right well how much bigger is it
well we can zoom out and then we can
zoom out you can still see the little
red area and then we zoom out again and
this is modern Greater London it's
essentially bounded by this Ring Road
the m25 they're not going quite that far
in every direction and this immediately
headache-inducing slide is all the
little tiny towns inside Greater London
right and if they're all doing the
individual police scene it becomes let's
go with tricky to ensure that the laws
work the same way everywhere not to
mention jurisdictional issues every
three blocks or so right stop or I'll
run after you and then you hit you know
you cross a road and now you're in a
different town and now you're out of
luck so obviously then like now there's
some cooperation between constables of
neighbouring Hamlet's but cooperation
isn't the same thing as unified
jurisdiction and this makes things
complex so at this point the Home
Secretary who's the guy in charge of
domestic affairs for the UK was a
gentleman named Sir Robert Peel and this
guy had an amazing resume right he was
in power out of power in power accreted
accreted way too much power he actually
became both Prime Minister and Home
Secretary at once which is a really bad
idea for the same reason you don't let
developers push code into production and
eventually he was like out of power for
a little bit minister of the loyal
opposition and then back in power and
eventually out of power again as he
retired so to handle the issue of
Greater policing policing across all of
Greater London which is actually what
it's called by the way Greater London is
an actual like census boundary he wanted
to create a London Metropolitan Police
Force and at the time the population was
like not in favour of this there was
only one other major European city with
a unified police force and it was Paris
and there's two different issues here
one is
that it's Paris and the UK never been a
big fan of any proposal that starts with
let's do exactly what they do it in
France right and that's before you get
to the fact that they've been fighting
at war with Paris for basically the last
50 years most of the last five years but
in addition the Parisian police were not
police they were not the kind of like
friendly happy police they were what we
usually think of today as secret
political police well with all of the
intrigue and terror that you'd expect
from secret political police so this is
not a good model the population is not
in favor of new secret police in London
so what was the fix to this this
fundamental principle the people are the
police and the police are the people and
the police are simply paid to give
full-time attention to keeping society
intact which is the job of every citizen
in some philosophical sense this either
sounds radical or nonsensical I think
you'll go with radical as we go through
the implications of each of the nine
principles particularly with regard to
the relationship between the police the
public and the last-ditch use of force
of which the principal spent a lot of
time on as an American of course I feel
like our police could take a lot of
pages indeed all of the pages from this
idea but they don't listen to me on the
strength of this proposal then peel got
the metro police bill through Parliament
and the unified London Police were born
with this unified ideal we're going to
be very different from the French which
is served them well they might have said
it's you know a sense of like of the
people by the people and for the people
but that was still ticking people off in
London at the time considering the White
House it just stopped burning and thanks
for that yes the UK embassy to the
United States recently tweeted in
response to the White House post in the
anniversary of the burning awkward which
is among the greatest tweets of all time
I note in this slide by the way that Sir
Robert Peel almost definitely didn't say
this originally and in general didn't
lay out the so-called pelion principles
though he did discuss some of them as a
kind of general philosophical statements
like what would a great police force
look like both before and after the
Metro police were established so he was
the Home Secretary made it possible but
the people who actually wrote down these
principles were Charles Rowan and
Richard
so like a lot of advances in history
particularly in science and mathematics
the wrong person got it named for him
and not just the principles the London
police were at first derisive Lee now
someone more fondly referred to as
bobbies after this Robert so why am I
talking to the history of cops in London
for a whole five minutes because the
issues that the police were facing then
are strikingly similar to the issues
that security people in much larger
organisations face now we have a lot of
power and a lot of ability to peer into
things that most people can't this
population
Early's mean the population knows this
and is not therefore real predisposed to
liking us they've seen groups like us
before that abuse their power
we're tasked with keeping the peace any
slip-ups will be our fault but our
successes register is nothing right
nothing terrible happened today that's
fine basically because it's not about us
right the order the general populace
shouldn't really need to know that we
exist
but we do need the leadership to know we
exist because otherwise they won't hire
us anymore so it's a weird balance right
we need to stay invisible to the public
and close to the heart of the leadership
and yet not be creepy secret police and
inspire fear and terror and revulsion in
the populous most fundamentally though
we're not the point of what's going on
we don't exist for our own sakes and
everyone else will continuously tell us
that the organization does not exist for
our comfort we have to integrate into a
larger society and we need their
cooperation to make that possible so to
make this work we're going to apply
police stuff to nerd them just like in
this photo it won't be a shock to you
that they learned that the rest of this
presentation is my proposal for a way to
solve it based on peels nine original
principles of policing I do want to make
a few things clear however because
you're gonna hear a lot of ideas that
sounds somewhat familiar in a few cases
at least I'm not pretending that nobody
has ever thought of any of these ideas
before I'll try to point out major
organizations that have done a few
things well in fact but even when I
don't please don't assume that I think
that this is all like poor and new what
I think is a value about using peels
principles as a strategy for security
organizations is that it's an ordered
way for security to work within a larger
organization or society
simply shouting be less terrible to each
other hasn't worked so far so we need
something with more like actionable
goals the fundamental principles that
rather than simply saying suck glass
peels principles are a framework to
guide you in sucking less so it's not a
random framework secondly look this is
maybe all terrible quite a few people in
this room have significantly more
experience than I do I have some and
I've had the privilege to work with a
lot of great people who have agreed
experience some of whom I'm privileged
to call friends and I've tried very
consciously to apply this to my own
client work and as I go through old we
point out things words worked really
effectively so it's been much better for
me than what I had before and hopefully
it'll will work for all of you and if
you want you're welcome to come back in
a year or three and ask hey do you still
like that or is that a terrible idea
and I'll tell you if it was a terrible
idea but for now it's working for me
better than what I had before and it
seems kind of reasonable so the
principles and we'll go through all nine
in order because they all have a lot of
applicability to security today so I'm
not gonna read each one of these by the
way because I hate it when people throw
up quotes on the slides and then read
them to you so that's the general idea
so the first principle is the basic
mission right and right off the bat we
have two major items to apply to
security operations the first major idea
here is that prevention is the mean
order of the day this is not a shock to
security organizations right yes do not
look into laser with remaining.i right
if we can prevent at least one eye from
going to waste then that was good there
are a few great nuances to how we you
know what we do for prevention and what
we don't do for prevention that we'll go
into later but obviously the basic goal
is always let's make sure bad stuff
doesn't happen but the second idea is
also very important so I live in the US
and as you are no doubt aware the United
States has completely lost its
collective mind or the subject of risk
we cannot see him at a math
psychological level to understand risk
or even to compare risks in any kind of
reasonable way right like we freaked out
at people who like their underpants on
fire and now we have naked scanners in
every airport but we hand guns to
toddlers we take elaborate hand wavey
cargo Calton precautions and bling blong
regulations or the lawyers and then we
drive loud fast
cars with no speed limits and we yell
and plaintiffs attorneys who do things
like well how dare you sue a teddybear
manufacturer well you know that the
teddy bear had an iron rod in its back
right and then he turns out that when
kids trip over it they die cuz that's
bad
yeah actual thing that actually existed
in America in the 80s teddy bear with
iron spike because this is why we need
plaintiffs attorneys for right but we
hate the lawyers because they're
terrible so we're told that the only
available success is no attacks no
breaches no insider threats no nothing
victory at all costs but by all costs to
be very clear I mean no costs you can't
spend any money and you certainly can't
spend an infinite amount of money
because nobody has an infinite amount of
money so the way to fix this is to point
out that defense and cleanup are in
effect alternatives but that like police
prevention and police response more
defense will help prevent the need for
cleanup but will not eliminate the need
for clean up and this is the same
solution we already used in other areas
a great example of this is the if you
want to add another nine of uptime you
need to double your infrastructure
investment kind of rule of thumb you can
using this spend a lot of money and make
an outrageously available solution that
will work very well Mike say Amazon Web
Services right if you look at a region
each individual region is outrageously
available and it will still go down
sometimes like yeah but some Web
Services does right it'll do so in some
unexpected or complex or completely
random way right I recall one
post-mortem from a few years back where
they had as they were all as they always
do they had tested their ground fault
interrupters for the whole datacenter
and one that they had tested just a week
before and it worked with flying colors
just said oh my god there was a
lightning strike and during a clear day
and cut off power right and tried to
switch over to battery and the battery
thing failed because that hadn't been
tested recently so basically the data
the data center our Auto Darwin aided it
was just okay and this was not really
preventable right Lee had done the
prevention things and it just fell over
in Calgary in 2011 one of my other
favorite data center failure stories an
explosion in the battery room of a major
datacenter destroyed the equipment that
cut
back and forth between the mains power
and the backup power so even though only
the batteries were damaged the data
center could no longer figure out that
it was plugged in and so therefore it
turned itself off it's like all the
power is gone what am I supposed to do
these kinds of complex failures don't
happen often in a well engineered system
the prevention wasn't worthless it did
buy you something for all that money but
bad things will still happen and so at a
certain point that key is to explain to
management that you can spend enough
money to prevent all the preventable
things and what will remain will not be
nothing it will be chance occurrences so
how to explain this well is going to be
very situation dependent I did have one
client called little over a year ago
that maybe laughs the client wanted
security and compliance solutions that
would quote make sure we don't get sued
right
and he said this like over and over this
was a repeated thing and that's not how
security works of course Security's not
in the business of making you get sued
but eventually had to step in to point
out that that's not how lawyers work
either
right lawyers are not vampires and
compliance is not garlic you might still
get sued right or your data center might
just fall over what we can do with
security work is help the is make sure
that when you get sued you are at least
right and therefore have the best chance
of success or for spending on
infrastructure we can make sure that
when bad things happen you had every
backup system reasonably available in
place and sometimes that will have a
cascading failure is this a perfect
answer no it's actually a deeply
unsatisfying answer right because like I
want things to just stand up and work
for a thousand years and they don't
that's annoying but it's not an answer
that stops the conversation it's one
that guides the conversation towards one
about risk tolerance and risk management
and eventually acceptance right it's
like the stages of grief and so we're
going to come back to that ideas we go
through the rest of this presentation
about guiding the conversation rather
than just stopping it this is the second
principle and the core idea here is
we're dependent upon public approval and
public respect to do our jobs
and there shouldn't be like a shock
right but it sure seems like a problem
I've actually watched organizations that
were at war with their internal
organizations like their subgroups right
they're at war with internal IT or at
war with HR or security or anything
really it can actually happen any group
I watched one company I was doing some
work for transform an internal political
struggle between two essentially
co-equal managers into an internal
technical struggle who struggle where
these groups hated each other so badly
that they built software that couldn't
interact with the other side of the
company which caused actual measurable
harm because politics became engineering
failure I'm sure there's like civil
engineers have a lot of stories like
this but I'm not that kind of an
engineer so I didn't do it beyond edge
cases right there just horror shows
there's a deliberate call to action on
this point again security isn't the
mission of the organization it's a
critical part of that making the mission
happen but it's not the goal it's not
even the goal at security first
organizations like since our keynote
person mentioned it 17 times open
whisper systems who make signal security
is not their number-one goal security is
like their goal 1.5 a messaging system
is their number-one goal that is usable
as an actual UX that people want to use
because otherwise it doesn't matter how
secure it is no one's going to use it or
only extreme edge nerds are going to use
it and for a perfect example of that of
course we have PGP which works pretty
well right there's metadata set but
setting metadata aside the security is
quite good on the messages what's not
good is everything that surrounds it to
make an actual messaging ecosystem which
is why you have problems like people are
applying with unencrypted text and
unencrypted reply text to an encrypted
email which is bad right and makes
security people sad so even for security
first organizations security is a
critical part of their value proposition
but it's not their only part and it
can't be their primary part so given
this remember that you're the support
organization and that while they can't
win without you you can and will lose
much more quickly if you lose their
respect they don't need to have an
entire marching band saying how awesome
you are though that is cool right we
tried it at Wisconsin and it's kind of
neat
I mean you all need to be on the same
side no that is not a cheering party for
the security Oregon Wisconsin by the way
that would be cool as a follow unto this
it's easier for our entire industry to
have the approval and respect of the
rest of the planet if we act like mature
adults and when prominent conferences
that are clearly not Sektor advertise
themselves as drinking first at in
conference second and I actually don't
mean the Vegas cons they're not the
worst ones about this or when
information in the industry is held
hostage by people with a sexist axe to
grind it makes it very hard to claim
that security deserves a seat at the
adults table it also makes it hard to
get approval to attend conferences which
is not an incidental problem for at
least me we've you know we don't all
need to have the respect and excellent
judicial robes of the Supreme Court
campus is the Supreme Court of Canada
but we do need to be the industry we
actually want to work for and yes I do
have apologize on behalf of our late
Justice Scalia who insulted the judicial
robes those are amazing just by the way
every lawyer in the world thinks those
are great so this is the third principle
on lien cooperation there's no need to
name and shame anyone on this slide but
I will point out that there are many
prominent security people from have a
great deal of professional respect whose
approach within the Seri within
companies seems to be to shame people
who aren't security experts for not
being as paranoid as professional
security expert which bugs the crap out
of me and also hurts our report the
users I'd not found a single person in a
professional setting whose response to
daily abuse is well I should just do
everything in my power to get better so
that this person likes me in fact when
we see that in other contexts we call it
an abusive relationship right and if we
have an abusive relationship with the
other support organizations nothing
works well so why is it okay for us to
say well how dare the support staff
member do something foolish like plug in
a USB key that came from my insurance
company except didn't actually right but
it was silkscreen with the insurance
company's logo it came in the right
envelope it had my name on it all these
things it just turns out that none of
those things are hard to fake right we
would all just say well basically don't
plug anything USB and if that point
wasn't mean to you before today's lunch
talk then certainly was made for you but
today's lunch talk never plug anything
in the internet is filled or dangerous
but most people don't think of the bad
USB exploit right or the power usb
exploit or the Turner USB key or a
printer wire into a radio antenna thing
that came out of the research University
of Tel Aviv a few months ago so it's
human nature to vent about things right
I've had clients come to me with
exquisitely self-inflicted wounds things
that are kind of bad and yet so funny
that it's hard not to laugh at them and
it's perfectly fine and human to want to
tell these things to your friends right
you can have a drink you can unwind you
can tell stories we're all gonna do that
at like 5:30 you can even do so in a
public forum right the DEF CON Comedy
Jam popularly known as the fail panel
which apparently rides again tomorrow
afternoon used to be excellent at this
before they ended at DEFCON 22
remember however that when you rant
about how awful non-technical or non
security people are in public and I
don't just mean telling stories but the
kind of abuse of users like those people
should never be allowed to touch
keyboard which yes I see on a daily
basis on my very security oriented
Twitter feed you run the risk that
you'll make it more unlikely that users
will bring things to you and it's not a
direct thing it won't necessarily be the
user you're ranting about or even the
company are ranting about if you're a
consultant work with a bunch of them but
if your public reputation is that you
have no empathy for mistakes then people
will stop bringing them to you and it's
bad right I've learned incredible things
about really bad breaches and regulated
corporations from low-level employees
whose job was not security their job
wasn't even tactical right they were a
people person they liked people and
there's two people laughing no one else
gets referenced that's fine but this is
actually very important right we need
their trust a story that's not mine but
which blew up the internet a few months
ago so you might have seen it came out
from a financial institution with
extensive internal controls due to the
information they handled right a random
user following their monthly security
awareness check box send out a security
newsletter to remind people right either
good to send out a security newsletter
are you good to have the loose lips sink
sink ships posters so they went with the
newsletter option and they've been doing
this for a while and one month a random
user reached out and said hey you know
I've always felt kind of odd about this
thing but I'm probably just wrong like
you techie people are all very advanced
and it's not my thing but I just I just
wanted to kind of understand why this
was a good idea I'm sure it is but I
want to know why it's a good idea well
tell us what's going on well every six
weeks when we change our passwords my
manager comes around and makes us write
all our passwords down on a clipboard
and when we go on vacation she makes us
give her our proximity cards that go to
her individually locked offices because
again regulated financial institution
and she says she needs this to make sure
that her organization could be super
efficient right and this that making
sure this happens is part of why our
group has such high bonuses compared to
other organizations because we're super
efficient so like that seems odd but I'm
sure it's all for the best tell me why I
shouldn't be afraid of this and their
response was to fire basically everyone
but this person in the division right
because this is
gramm-leach-bliley act this is bad this
is a reportable breach that goes to the
SEC from a non-technical user who had
the actual belief true or not for the
actual subjective belief that if he went
to the security organization he wouldn't
be taunted right
he might be said you know basically
they're there it's all fine here's why
that's fine that's what he expected that
wasn't what he got I believe they
mentioned the thread that he got a trip
to Tahiti instead while they fired if or
when else in this organization um but
again it's about setting up this kind of
thing and it is an instantaneous right
if you go and just say I'm an excellent
person you should all love me
people won't it's a long-term prospect
but eventually these breaches just start
coming to you before you get called by a
blogger who says by the way I have your
whole core database do you want to
comment we ultimately need people to
point out that this is not a
fortification anymore if it once was we
need people to point out that some
Emperor's are in fact naked these people
will mostly not be security people and
security only happens when everyone
cooperates and even if abuse feels good
ultimately it hurts your ability to
cooperate with your users so keep your
rants to your friends the ones who buy
you beer this is the fourth principle
cooperation diminishes proportionately
to physical force now let's just set
aside physical force if you are using
hitting people as part of your standard
security practice you have many problems
either you work at a very niche industry
which we're just gonna move right along
from or you have many problems I'm not
gonna be able to address within the
scope of this talk as I said in the
intro part of this talk is this time
nobody should have to get nailed to
anything so let's talk about compulsion
instead right which is the general thing
like whether or not you're like slamming
someone into the ground compulsion is
that you can't go we're going to
question you type thing that police do
or eventually arresting you in a
somewhat more sane less American way so
please stop that is it natural part of
security
please stop plugging things in please
stop clicking things if the other things
that we told you to click because we're
bad about clicking please stop emailing
that etc it's not inherently bad right
in most cases it's the equivalent of
please stop hitting yourself and not on
the grade school
only way where I'm just hitting myself
with my own fists right like actually
please stop hurting us the problem is
that if every time somebody asks a
question the answer is no people stop
asking even if you are right in every
one of those cases and all the questions
they asked are in fact terrifying
I don't think seeing though is wrong or
bad or unreasonable but it chills our
ability to participate in the larger
business because they're just gonna say
you know what every time I have one of
my brilliant ideas Brendon tells me it's
a terrible idea right and I've gotten
that before right usually from engineers
who really do only have terrible ideas
right they're like the clock that is
wrong every time a day is not right
twice a day at all we don't have a plan
for everything because we're not
everything right we're part of a larger
team so when we people come to us with
questions if we're honest and if you
didn't want this to be known to your
clients that don't show this them that
this video we make up our answers on the
fly right of course we do based on our
training and based on our experience
everything we know we make up whatever
the answer is we said well I've never
seen your specific problem but here's a
lot of related problems the answer is
probably no because it's going to kill
you so we should use the same technique
that another group uses for the same
reason improv groups and if you've seen
improv or if you've taken an improv
class you know what's going on here the
answer whenever if somebody asks a
question no matter how ludicrous is
always yes and okay so it's usually yes
and something like yes and I'm not just
wearing a top hat I'm also writing a
leopard or whatever right you continue
the story so I've spent a few months
trained this very consciously with one
client and it is hard when an engineer
comes to me and says hey can I shoot my
own eye out it is very hard to say yes
the and is critical on the whole
shooting your eye out thing right you
can say yes you can do this dangerous
thing let's talk about how to make it
safe let's give you some goggles for
instance and if the goggles work maybe
you'd consider operating like a full
face mask great kind of big like
surgical face shield things also I'm not
sure how good you are with the shooting
yourself and the eye thing let's give
you some body armor and keys who miss
and shoot yourself in the torso and
he'll handle delicately this kind of
that's right leading them down the
primrose path can work very well right
hey he helped me do what I asked right
he showed me how to do what I asked for
safely but it turns out there's a lot of
protections we need to do what I asked
so maybe we should redesign this feature
without the IUD out chief howdy part
that doesn't always happen right like
that's victory right they didn't do the
dumb thing you didn't have to say no but
sometimes they'll keep the IUD out apart
but now they have all these layers of
protection that hopefully will keep at
least their remaining eye intact
sometimes they won't user safety gear
either but they least be more aware that
failure is an option and they'll be more
looking for failure which will enable
them to now switching my metaphors jump
clear of the car after they've driven
off the cliff but before it explodes in
midair for no reason except Hollywood
all of these outcomes are better than if
you just said no please don't do that
for the 11th time and they decided that
merely all you wanted in life was to
crush their dreams which is most of what
I want in a relationship but not
everything so over some time of actually
trying this myself
and this is hard for me because I am NOT
nice I was able to change how I thought
about these questions from how do I make
your new stupid idea as painless for me
personally as possible to how do I help
you achieve your goals in a way that
protects everybody and that's the
developer perspective right if you've
done software dev you know that your
features don't usually come from you
unless you're just developing your own
software they usually come from on high
and you're not tasked to say your ideas
stupid you write just has to finish it
the business wants what it wants in your
role and security is to enable that you
can terminate individual truly dangerous
ideas probably if you have built up to
enough political capital you can
probably kill the really bad one
remember that that's a gun you only get
to fire a couple times if you try yes
and you can usually steer them back onto
the path this one is a huge wall of text
right and this one highlight bits and
Oren's that are super important I also
highlighted this one bit in red right
the idea of without regard to the
justice of ended justice or of
individual laws or policies right that's
actually really dangerous for security
people because we design a lot of them
which is not something the police
usually do and I'll talk a little bit
more at the end about the justice or
indeed justice of individual things well
let's talk about the rest of it right
the individual service and friendship
and courtesy and good humor and
sacrifice so again I hate to see just
don't be a jerk cuz it's somewhat
reductive right but when you think of
like the London police force you have
the nice guy who poses with the tourists
idea right not just a jerk so think of
this as a challenge can you make people
who you dislike cuz you know this
happens not notice without giving very
much away I think I can safely say that
one of my proudest moments in the last
ex period of time was when I got an
unsolicited letter saying how great I
was from a client who I had what I will
summarize as a difference of opinion
with this is not easy this is perhaps
the most difficult thing for me
personally in this presentation it's
hard to keep up appearances when things
are being dangerously mishandled but it
is worth trying beyond this we have this
idea of individual sacrifice and this is
a critical part this is right in the
middle of the pelion principles and E of
individual sacrifice is weird right
because with the exception of the weird
stories with the guy with the shotgun
and the Katrina disaster it's not like
security people are ordinarily being
asked to defend data centers with
bullets right it's the way I think of
this in terms of security is yeah you're
not expected to defend your networks
with a shotgun but you are expected to
go to the extra mile or the extra 1.6
kilometers in Canadian to make things
work right this goes with the fourth
principle don't just say no and the cool
thing is we have all these conferences
as a security industry right and you
meet people here and some of that is
British professional networking I'm
looking for if I make my new charlie I'm
done with this job where should I go
next right what are cool companies to
work with but the other thing is in the
kind of war stories telling stories of a
beer thing you learn who's working with
what technologies and you can see hey I
have never worked with X random thing in
X environment well I know this guy at
the University of Toronto who does all
sorts of amazing things right the
University of Toronto has an IP v5
network and if you're going wait wasn't
there a jump yeah there was but the
academics have preserved the middle one
for
reasons I have no idea it's like I know
know a guy that if I want to really
troll firewall operators or if I have a
really odd Network I can call to tell me
how ipv5 works well enough to secure
stuff nearby at at least this is an
amazing thing right figure out a way to
do the research even when it's a pain in
the butt because you're the support
organization and yeah it's not like
you're not busy enough I'm aware of that
we'll talk more about that next it's the
important part here is again about that
use of force right we're gonna do it
when only we've tried persuading and
advice and warning and then that worked
then we're gonna use coercive force and
again we're gonna set aside physical
force because that's a whole other area
the street thing that strikes me most
about this principle is that security
and IT have a huge amount of tools that
creep people out as I discussed at the
beginning and increased people out badly
right the first time a non-technical
user hears about the wall of sheep or
possibly more horrifyingly about
driftnet what you said of just showing
you usernames and passwords actually
shows you all the images loaded live on
your network which is fun for about 10
seconds and then you hit the point of
you cannot unsee that what you have seen
and then you put away driftnet for the
rest of your life but you also have just
simpler tools right their IT people who
I know who like to just watch the list
of host names scrolling up on their
network right just every host name it
just drops a log into their log file
right coming off of their border
firewalls and they do that for not bad
reasons right they're doing that to make
sure that the usual pace of activity is
going right if they dead stop
something's gone wrong at the border if
they drop dramatically at an unexpected
time maybe something that's gone offline
it provides them a kind of heartbeat
pulse and they're not really looking at
it sometimes they might go who's going
to urban dictionary at lunch right that
kind of thing but mostly they're not
looking at it but this kind of thing or
another great example of this is
exchanges on demand remote wipe of
phones scares the heck out of
non-technical users and it should it's
an enormous coercive power right I can
reach out a nuclear phone because you
get your email from me what why would
you do that how could you do
that how do you live with yourself all
responses have actually heard because
this scares the heck out of people and
if you're the kind of person who tells
me that good users should have nothing
to be afraid of because after all what
do you have to hide I have a lot of
things to discuss with you after the
presentation like how do you live with
yourself so a lot of security and IT
people see again this kind of being able
to use this level of monitoring and
control as a perk right not as an
abusive perk but as a standard way that
I think of my workflow and using things
like automated monitoring is not
optional anymore for network security
but it's not a reasonable to present
human eyes watching us constantly for
the same reason that we resent human
eyes watching us move right even if it's
not doing anything if I just sit and
stare at somebody for hours on end and
follow them around they're gonna be
creeped out even if I'm not breaking the
law I'm not disturbing the peace I'm not
anything
I'm just really creepy and it annoys
people so how do we solve this
I had actually this issue at another
client and it was in particular the
exchange remote wipe thing right they
were just terrified by this concept
right it was an organization that was
very nice and they didn't like this
power so what we did is we clarified
right the next time around when we're
talking about this kind of power we said
look yeah we have the ability to do
remote wipe here are the circumstances
in which we can do remote wipe right
like we can't do remote wipe unless you
use exchange to access our server right
like if you use IMAP taxes our mail
server that isn't a thing right so it's
only this cut-down set of users and if
you don't like it you can switch over to
IMAP or you can stop using your work
email in your personal phone and we'll
give you a phone and that's fine too and
even with that here's the times of which
were going to use it we've created
basically a rules of engagement document
right and in some groups this will be
more formal than others I would have
suggest if you want to do this yourself
make it very formal add it to your
policy kit and then if your IT people
are abusing this if they're using it
outside the rules of engagement fire
them treat it like any other major
policy because this is again part of how
you build trust with your users you say
yeah we do have big nuclear weapon type
tools we don't just use them
and that will hopefully work until you
turn orange this is the seventh
principle and this is what I talked
about at the beginning right the
security people are the police are paid
to give full-time attention to what is
everyone's job and I could say you know
this is the you know you are all part of
security right thing that we all do at
the end of security awareness training
all those you're going to hope god I
hope I don't have to do that from there
ten months yeah now what I'm gonna do
it's not the most important part of this
the security team is the organization
and the organization is the security
team and I don't know if it's just human
to organized into teams then be a jerk
to the other team it sure seems like it
just look at any given football match
but it sure as heck a problem in
security right we do this with normal
users in our organizations and that
hurts our ability to serve the
organization we're not better than the
rest of the organization and it's
critical to remember that so how do we
get over that barrier what helps me but
may not be directly applicable to you
you'll have to see is to get in there
and pull right like actually going and
work with the developers if you're
actually a developer you could in fact
fix a bug try it just try fixing about
any bug final the level bugs it won't
harm anything and then hopefully will be
relatively small and see how it is to
build up their workflow right especially
if you have developers who are saying
that your security thing is hurting
their workflow which depending on your
organization might actually be a problem
it could help to just say you know I
know enough Java not to be deeply
dangerous this is a typo we have to fix
on a JSF file or something I can fix the
typo and learn about how the developer
workflow is you'll gain a few things one
you'll find out first of all if your
security things really are hurting the
developer workflow which may or not may
not be true secondly you'll learn if
their developer tools are hurting your
security workflow for instance if you
work in an organization that uses
vagrant how many of you guys use vagrant
or know what vagrant is right nobody
knows we'll be okay like ten be a little
bigger news for the rest of you vagrant
is a way to automatically spin up
virtual machines for developers okay
it's a very common developer tool it's
really great because then you can just
say here's a vagrant file think about
like a chef's recipe right or a puppet
configuration file but it's for local
virtual machines so it's a quick way to
just go Shazam you've got to develop our
environment that we know we're
vagrant just introduced a new feature
relatively recently called vagrant share
and what vagrant chair does is it
punches a hole in your firewall and lets
anyone who can pick it they do kind of a
cracked horse battery staple idea so if
you go to correct - horse - battery it's
only three words dot i think vagrant
share com you now have access to all of
the systems from the perspective of the
virtual machine sitting on the developer
laptop for all ports so you can do SSH
out of that machine you can do port 443
out of that machine and you're supposed
to use it to access what's running on
that server but of course if the virtual
server is configured or if it's just a
default installation you can do anything
and I can see several horrified looks or
people in the audience who are now about
to go say wait have I turned this off
yet no you probably happened right it's
an outgoing firewall punching tool there
are actual developer things that this
actually fixes right this is not just an
insane tool so if your developers are
using this they probably have a reason
they want to use it that reason is
probably not good enough from your
perspective and that's fine but now you
you're going to crimp their workflow and
what working through the developer
environment will help you do is figure
out how you can adjust their workflow to
not cause a raging ball of pain in the
middle of your environment which vagrant
share unless you were fully like Jericho
tear down the firewall level compliant
you this will probably cause a raging
ball of pain right if you're not a
developer or if you actually fixing a
bug is simply an insane request and I
understand it can be insane or can be a
violation of separation of duties and
either one of those legitimate help
developers to threat modeling or help
developers with even like feature design
or documentation just be another
engineer that they can at least bounce
an idea off of something where that they
know that you actually care about their
existence it doesn't have to be a
constant thing but do we knit once in a
while particularly in an organization
where this is significant either
cultural divide or off an age difference
between you and the developers and I've
actually been in organizations
terrifyingly on both sides of major age
difference right when where I was twenty
years younger than everyone else and one
where I was five to ten years older than
everybody else both of those horrify me
because I'm not that
so in all these situations it helps to
make everyone feel like you don't think
you're better than the developers right
or better than the whatever and
including you which is nice and again it
also helps you show you where all the
developer pain points are because the
developers aren't coming to these
solutions and saying hey I'm gonna
destroy your fire one every way possible
they're trying to fix a problem and
maybe you can help that problem giving
your vast security knowledge and
networking knowledge and all these
things you can say actually if all you
need is be able to access this one
service why don't I spin up a virtual
machine for you so instead of punching
directly into our and core network let's
push like as a testing or QA environment
somewhere else it's a little bit less
crazy
one other note on this principle the
police are the people and the people are
the police a corollary to that is
necessarily that the security
organization should be like all of the
people I continue to be horrified at
this small but loud faction the security
industry that openly discriminates and
they openly discriminate sometimes based
on protected classifications or I like
race or gender or appearance and a few
months ago I heard a c-level officer of
a major security company a really big
one say that his presentation in a
conference was quote not for the
beautiful people end quote
because they don't really get security I
don't know why we're having trouble with
that thing we don't Lord knows we don't
have that trouble at sector which is one
of the reasons I love sector but it
needs to end not just a sector but
everywhere else anything right now but
beyond that there's a more pernicious
kind of separation that's less just
obviously horrifying Security's agreed
fielding is no small part because it
doesn't take a PhD to get here right
I've worked and I've seen people on
stage here at this conference with
people who had only a high school
diploma or people who had PhDs right the
flip side of that however is how often I
see how many people post in that they
don't look at resumes of people who have
college right who went to college
because man college ruins your brain man
you get put inside a box and you can
never think your way out again and this
is more common than I would have
believed before writing into it about
ten times in a week it's not a more
helpful bigotry than saying you'd never
hire someone without college so let's
quit that as long as we're quitting that
was also quit only hiring people who've
hacked
birth I know prominent technologists
some of whom are speaking at either this
conference or other major conferences
for whom second the security was a
second or third vocation right there's
one major female technologist who came
to security out of a ph.d program and
applied philosophy and now she's a huge
deal security person right all of the
different paths are all security paths
and we need to embrace that kind of
thing
let's also drop the certification hatred
but I'll come back to that later if
we're gonna see how progressive and
diverse we are we should make sure that
we actually include diversity is the
summary here the eighth principle is
mostly about the judiciary the important
part is never usurping the powers of
people who aren't you this comes up for
security people kind of often right we
find major security violations that are
ongoing right you know people are using
technology that's not only not allowed
but it's expressly forbidden cuz it's
deeply dangerous right and what that's
gonna mean for you could be anything
from Dropbox to using online PDF
converters which is one of my favorite
ones that I found in bad places and so
the question it comes to the security
people or it doesn't come but is you
know offer it up by the security people
a lot of person should be fired they're
deeply bad right not our call and it
makes people scared again about the kind
of power we'd naturally agree because
we're the adults in the room those of us
who act like adults so I find this one
helpful to remember that I'm not the CEO
and that the culture for what's
acceptable from the way employees act
the way policies are implemented to
security strategy ultimately goes to the
chief executive the CEO or the Board of
Directors and security should have a
seat at that table right and hopefully
with a service-oriented approach to
running security you can earn one but
remember that if the CEO is prudent you
make your case well you'll get your
strategy through and if you don't and
this end it's actually a problem and the
strategy is imprudent and you're
actually hurting users you do your best
to make your case and if they're hurting
users and you can't live with that then
it's time to find a new position and
that's also a rational response but
security doesn't run the organization
again even security first organizations
she doesn't actually run it cuz it's not
our thing right we have a very specific
niche the ninth principle we are coming
to them to this I promise the test of
efficiency is the absence of crime not
us so I love this photo right it's a
great about how security can blend in
this is my group of ham radio examiner's
at DEFCON 22 and we look just like
normal people we totally blend into a
crowd at DEFCON you can barely actually
it's bad even at DEFCON we're kind of
nerds because we all had glowing
callsign badges but yeah we totally
blend into a normal crowd right security
shouldn't be about itself
ideally users should go throughout their
days without having to think about
security per se we know from study after
study that when they don't when they
have to think about us a lot they hate
it and they just disable things they
tell they can go back to their job my
favorite recent study on this came out
two or three months ago was a hospital
where the IT staff had implemented
passive IR sensors so that when a doctor
walked away from a workstation the
workstation would automatically log out
this is for lots of good HIPAA reasons
we can assume the solution from the
hospital staff was very simple they put
a Dixie cup over the infrared sensor so
the infrared sensor would always
register presence and therefore would
never logout because they had to get
their job done we don't win in
situations where we the users feel like
we're always spying on them like if
we're watching it live or like we're
always trying to prevent them for
getting their job done we win when users
actually get to do their jobs and that's
how best to look at excellent to
management as well and it's also how
best to make sure that we can change the
cultural narrative of security as
roadblock so we need a new narrative and
what that's gonna be comes next the
first part of my kind of call to action
thing we do a call to action because
first of all all the cool kids are doing
them now and secondly beyond simply
applying these principles in your own
roles because a few more specific things
I'd like you to do it's an obnoxious
cliche that the perfect is the enemy of
the good right
unfortunately the security as a
roadblock thing often comes from this
precise problem well that solution
involve risk so it's bad and awful right
this is another facet of the risk and
tolerance I discussed the beginning of
this but it has the amazing ability to
stop forward momentum
lower-risk solutions well saying well we
can't move to the cloud if there is risk
as I guess but our servers are old and
unpatched and terrible there's much more
risk there but I want you to find a
risk-free solution no that's nonsensical
right ultimately this resolves down to
well we shouldn't move a forward out of
our house which is on fire on to the
street because the street might catch on
fire and that's true but there's
definitely less fire on the street than
there is currently in the house and if
we're on the street we can continue to
go down the street and be chased by fire
right and being chased by fire is a
suboptimal solution but it's definitely
better than remaining in the house which
is currently again see above on fire so
this is the hecklers veto right your
solution sucks cannot cause paralysis
for your organization so end that with
him yourself and again for those of you
who are thinking you know Brendon does
this yeah Brendon does do this Brendon
would like to stop doing this Brenham is
trying really hard so ended in yourself
and try not to tolerate it from others
explain how risk works talk to your
local risk person they have their own
conferences too and that summit is
inevitable and then move forward second
this is a CSP it's not my sis be do I
have one as far as I can tell nothing on
the CSP which and this has all the you
know the nice fancy words on the bottom
nothing as I can tell on this piece of
paper requires it's bearable its bearer
to be terrible it is a piece of paper
that means you took a test it's not evil
please as an industry can we stop
treating the city people as evil please
do not say every time you've seen
something dumb on the Internet
well I'm sure this is totally compliant
right I'm sure at least twelve sippie's
approved this which yes is something
I've actually seen from major security
people the same goes for the sisa right
which is the auditor grade thing or for
graduate degrees or for undergraduate
degrees or for GE DS or for Liberal Arts
degrees or for technical degrees and
double for community college degrees
interview for skills stop screening
based on having a credential right this
is part of the skills gap issue we can't
find anyone to hire because we hire same
well you've got a liberal arts degree so
therefore you must be bad
you must not have spend your entire life
hacking but some of the most talented
hackers I've met one of the other hacker
lawyers actually had things with like
undergraduate degrees in Russian
literature and then went on from
agrarian Russian literature and founded
a pen testing company and sold the pen
testing company for a bajillion dollars
right and now he's a lawyer in life is
grand it takes all kinds and in fact if
you look around at this conference and
ask people about their backgrounds
you'll find that we have all kinds so
let's stop hating on all these different
ways where someone has chosen a
different path to better yourself then
better themselves than the one you took
I don't know why this needs saying so
much but it certainly seems to well
we're doing that if we could stop hating
on compliance it would be nice like I
understand it does seem like we have a
lot of boxes and we need all of them
checked but honestly compliance does a
lot of great work you'll be cool if we
could not be the whipping children and
finally speak up there are a few people
to whom I truly look up in this industry
and the common thread that runs through
each of them is that one can count on
them to speak up on behalf of people who
need it and who can't speak for whatever
reason usually they don't get a real
seat at the table if you see your
company doing bad things not simply
technical decisions was that you don't
agree but things that are in fact wrong
and have measurable harms towards users
speak up if you see a company that's
hurting users privacy whether it's
deliberate you know what kind of an evil
overlord thing which is not all the time
or just negligent or behaving in an
illegal or unethical fashion you have a
duty to speak up we have to move beyond
this attitude even though we're a
support organization of just bull hey I
just work here we're not the only thing
in the company we are - charge days
security people with protecting the
trust of our fellow employees and
protecting the trust of every user of
whatever it is that your company makes
what you do protects users from
embarrassment from harassment or even
from violence depending on what it is
you do and that's a huge responsibility
and it's our duty to live up to it we
only get to be the adults in the room if
we act like it when it's hard that's
something we should look to take from if
not perhaps the typical police officer
who are unfortunately humans then
perhaps
the paragon of policing right the idea
that we do our job in service to all
regardless of when it gets hard thank
you questions at all we've got a couple
minutes left
they're real questions
okay well I'm bright in purple and
stripy so if you want to talk later I
will be around I will be less purple
tomorrow but still relatively striping
thank you all very much for coming