[Music]
the whole fact that we have to do
security awareness training is the
challenge we've designed systems that
are not safe they're secure when
operated properly and so unfortunately
in order to have secure systems we have
to do a lot of training to have people
operate them properly and know when
things are going wrong I'd hope in the
future we don't have to have that but
today security awareness training is
necessary we can take all the problems
we have in the world of security and
roughly half of them are technical
problems but the other half are people's
problems people doing stupid stuff there
is no patch for stupidity some people I
think you look at security awareness
training is a way to create the human
barrier between malicious things and
them infecting or our computer
environment the research is showing that
that's not terribly effective I do think
security awareness training is broken
and I don't think as a whole I think
with some great organizations that
really offer some great training but i
think it's not focused in the right way
so what we've seen over and over again
with organizations that have like
internal security program but they're
just they're boring and nobody wants to
take them and they want to click through
there they're overly complicated they
don't draw connections to real-world
activity and so the end user who you
want to educate and elevate the level of
side of security knowledge is clicking
through the vignettes as quickly as they
can just so they can get back to their
job security awareness training is good
as a concept and it can work in
organizations an important part of
compliance efforts but if you approach
it as only a compliance thing I'm going
to check this box I'm going to read a
thing from 90 minutes then you end up
with no success permit users get nothing
out of it because all they heard was a
monologue for 90 minutes what we want to
do is create a culture change that takes
time and that takes buy-in but we know
how to reach people to do sessions that
engage them empower them have them own
their stake in it and then watch it go
forward but we need to find a way to
make sure
purely awareness a thing that is
pervasive an organization by making
security part of people's job instead of
making it something special to have to
pay attention to on top of a regular job
find a way to engineer intern and on the
workflow so that security happens by
default otherwise you're going to ask
people to do something they're going to
remember for three days and then they're
going to stop doing it as I go back to
whether they use for them part of the
physios role in improving cyber security
training is making it entertaining right
we all read books and we all love
watching movies because they tell
stories so we have to incorporate that
entertainment factor any to the training
so that you can teach something that's
both technically accurate that's going
to raise the level of awareness but it's
also going to entertain your audience at
the same time well I feel currently the
security awareness training is largely
focused on my computer based training in
which you tell people here's how you
better security systems but it's dry and
it could be boring so I think better
ways is hands-on hands-on labs hands-on
ways which you show somebody here is
actually how your information was stolen
and here's one of the fact it can do
with it and then once we increase the
awareness hopefully we can have people
who are more sensitive at how do we
better secure our computer machine what
we need is an approach to security
awareness training that involves
connecting with users and explaining how
the security organization serves the
corporation as a whole and how the
security organization can serve
individual users in respond to
individual needs to do that we have to
move away from the lecture format we
have to move away from online security
awareness training we're the only
requirement of a user is that they stay
barely sentient for maybe whole business
once we get to something more in person
you're more focused on the actual means
while still covering the bases to ensure
that we can meet our compliance
obligations as an organization then we
get effective security awareness
training that makes a measurable
difference in the success of an
organization
you
[Music]