[Music]
sectors an event by the community for
the community it's put together good by
myself in the advisory committee larger
because we get to go to lots of great
events south of the border and nothing
like those existed here good
opportunities for professional
development that you frankly don't get
anywhere else unless you're willing to
jump on a plane and go to Las Vegas or
Barcelona or Amsterdam so its budget
friendly and the content is frankly
fantastic
it has great content a love sector
probably my favorite conference that
honestly that I get to go do it has
great speakers level of the audience the
enthusiasm the tier i come to sector
because it's canada's premier security
conference and it brings everyone
together all at once makes it very easy
to meet everyone in the industry where
it's not always so easy just because of
its nature
I'm tweeting dad have a problem they
need to deal with today they want to
learn something to help them progress
make career we want to connect with the
community that's around them and those
are the sorts of things that really
drive people to sector
[Music]
this is actually one of the only ones
i'm doing this year mostly because
that's where I get treated the best free
to challenge another Congo er maybe if
you're a vendor challenge of competitor
to a pic deathmatch I can go much more
in depth into the material and cover
things that I wouldn't get to talk about
a lot of other places because people
seem to really pick it up very quickly
sector is great because it has a large
diversity of people and one of the best
parts is it has a great community feel
to it so as a presenter I get to meet a
lot of different people but I get to see
again each year it's good to be able to
talk to them about where the industry is
going but also hear back from them about
what's changed in these years
[Music]
really try to bring the best from all
over the world into Canada for this
event
you