so sex is here today with Ian Patterson
managing director of sukira
in Kusa been talking about data breaches
and incident response so explain what
you covered in your talk so my talk was
kind of a 101 fundamentals about how to
manage a security incident how to
identify security incident pre breach
during a breach in post reach okay yeah
what what are some of the common
mistakes that companies make when when
trying to respond to a data breach
incident yeah I think some of the bigger
things are tactical stuff that happens
on the ground initial preparation is
great but during a breach one of the
fundamental problems is people trying to
run their team's too hard for too long
people burn out during these incidents
especially your technical stars they
need time to rest so you have to think
about how am I going to utilize my
resources knowing that people have a
limitation on how long they can work for
is try and remediate these problems
while you're still trying to balance
your business recovery objectives so
it's kind of like intensive short-term
project management because you know
people are limited resource energies a
limited resource and you have to manage
it properly exactly and it's it's a high
pressure type of situation because you
may not be able to transact with your
customers you may not be able to
transact as a business right and those
concerns obviously weigh heavily on the
month senior management but the incident
handlers have to balance the realities
of the team and their capabilities and
they the longer you try and push the
more you're likely to make mistakes
he's never kind of standard playbook
that can apply to most data breach
incidents or do they differ enough that
you kind of need to pull different play
books off the shelf to cope with
different kinds of breach yeah
when you're building an incident
response plan there's a series of
activities that you would put in place
so identification of an event initial
discovery of the indicators of the event
and triage containment and then recovery
and then post breach right so all those
are standard
how you react to each breach though and
the strategies you use to react will be
unique depending on the type of breach
and the organization and what their
recovery objectives are all right okay
so you have to you have to think about
multiple disciplines it's not just can
take technical containment and getting
the business back online you've got to
think about things that legals and
forensics as well yeah so part of what I
talked about and it doesn't get talked
about enough how to communicate
externally and internally things like
bringing in external legal counsel and
establishing privilege super-important
depending on where this is gonna go if
there's gonna be a class-action lawsuit
or something having that privilege can
be huge for the holy discovery process
and I think the worst thing you see in a
lot of breaches is a failure to properly
manage external communications if you do
get it wrong if you did watch it more
the worst ramifications I mean what's
the worst thing that can happen to you
financially from a reputation
perspective itself
yeah reputationally the brand damage of
a breach can be pretty severe it's
interesting that it's not always
reflected in the stock price of these
companies if we look at target for
example their stock prices back up to
over what it was before they were
breached
so reputation will take a hit initially
in the long term though depending on the
scope of the breach if you have many
class-action lawsuits that take effect
if you have regulatory failures you may
fail to continue exist as a business in
the long term particularly if you're
managing for example healthcare records
or something like that the fines
associated with that and the regulatory
penalties would be tremendous for most
companies so that's kind of the worst
case if you screw up your Incident
Response and don't inform the right
people and don't manage the
communications and manage the event
properly it could be the end of the
business okay so yeah so wise words to
sort of to think about Incident Response
in advance I guess the stitching time
really does save night absolutely okay
well lovely thanks so much for coming
onto sector this year we really
appreciate meeting thank you so much