hi
i'm christine ging and today i'll be
talking about our paper
usable sex security studying people's
concerns and strategies when sexting
so first we approach consensual sexting
as
a normal human behavior not something
that's deviant
in fact about 26 percent of american
adults have sent
nude or something new photos of
themselves to someone else
however it can come with risks such as
coercion to sex in relationships
receiving unsolicited sex and revenge
porn
one study shows that one in 25 online
americans have been a victim
or of or threatened with revenge porn
and these risks are higher for younger
women and queer individuals
so we have the question of how can
platforms better support sexual
privacy and this is a type of privacy
that requires being able to secure
autonomy enable intimacy
and protect equality
with the goal of answering that question
in mind we came up with three research
questions
so for adults who have sex did before
what are their experiences with sexting
their concerns and their mitigation
strategies
answer this question we conducted a
mixed methods online survey
using prolific we recruited adults who
sexed or have sexted before
and our study was irb approved
on to our results so in our paper we
describe
sexting frequency platform usage sharing
storage concerns and strategies but for
the sake of time i'll only be talking
about concerns and strategies
so the top five concerns that came up
around sexting for participants
included sex getting around to other
people
sex being used as blackmail receiving
unsolicited content
the receiver's devices getting hacked
and shoulder surfing
with regard to receiving unsolicited
content
we found that women and non-binary
people were significantly more likely to
receive unsolicited sex
and be concerned about this than men
now i'll talk about strategies both
technical and
non-technical so some of the technical
management strategies that our
participants talked about
including included disappearing messages
and password-protecting stored sex
the latter of which um one example
is the my eyes only private album
on snapchat in terms of non-technical
strategies
these included getting to know the
person first and communicating rules and
boundaries
some of our participants use a mix of
both strategies
so for example one participant wrote i
sucked with
i sexed with my partner who might trust
and we had several conversations about
sexting before we started
when to delete photos if we were at risk
of revenge pointing each other
we're not and from there we talked about
several different platforms and
ultimately chose an encrypted platform
it's not completely safe
but it's a calculated risk
on to our discussion
so in terms of how platforms can better
support sexual privacy
we broke this down into policy
suggestions community moderation
and interface design suggestions so in
terms of policy
community guidelines can be written to
encourage asking for consent before
saving images
and to not allow harassment such as
unsolicited sex
the latter of which is common amongst
dating apps
in terms of community moderation there
must be sufficient enforcement
of policy changes like the ones i
suggested
another suggestion is to automatically
detect and blur unsolicited needs
which is something that developers are
already working on
in terms of interface design one
suggestion is
not allowing photos to be sent unless
both people in a conversation enable the
feature
or for dating apps have a profile
disclosure like grinder
so they allow a user to
edit whether or not they accept not safe
for work picks
so in conclusion our results cover
sexing frequency platform usage
sharing storage concerns and strategies
and platforms can support sexual privacy
by considering consent through policy
moderation and design thank you very
much
you