welcome to this afternoon's session
we're going to be running it
logistically as follows
Wolfgang will kick off with a
presentation of about 15 minutes and
then we'll open for Q&A
straight after his presentation directed
to his presentation because Wolfgang has
to leave for the airport at 1630
precisely to get an aeroplane and rather
than wait until the end for all of Q&A
we will take the Q&A for him then so he
can make make the airport in time so
from about 1610 roughly will then go
over to the other two presenters first
christina and then and then Theodore and
when they're finished with their
respective presentations will then open
up for a more general Q&A directed
primarily at their presentation so from
probably around 1630 1635 so I do
encourage all of you to think about
questions and comments it's often that
part of a session that is the most
instructive the most rewarding for all
concerned it's the great pleasure to be
here this is some I'm fortunate to be
here for the second time at a saikhan I
was here in 2015 the sunshine was on I'm
back here the sunshine is still on so
Estonia must be the land of internal
sunshine so very good so Wolfgang crime
vector is almost an institution in his
own right in the area of Internet
Governance he's been a very important
policy entrepreneur in this area for at
least the last three if not four decades
and it's a great great honor and
pleasure to have you here to address us
who have gone please
having me here you know at the right to
freedom of expression right to privacy
right of association all these are
fundamental human rights which are
relevant in cyberspace but all these
rights means nothing if we live in in
stable and insecure cyberspace so the
question of this session is really to
find the relationship between security
and individual human rights does it work
yeah yes you know I remember 15 years
ago in particular after September 11
there was a debate whether you have to
pay with the loss of privacy to enhance
security so there were two camps
one cam said okay you have to give up
your privacy if you want to live in a
secure we have to control saying and
then we will have 100% security if you
have privacy and the other can argue the
other way around and this approach
proved to be wrong because you cannot
back security by giving away your
privacy even if you free way all your
nobody can guarantee that this
will lead to a secure cyberspace so that
means what you have to have is the right
balance between privacy and other
fundamental rights including freedom of
expression freedom of association and
security and this was more or less it's
the outcome of a debate in international
fora and this was laid down in the
so-called Geneva declaration of the
United Nations World Summit on the
information society which said to build
a people centered inclusive and
development oriented information society
where everyone can create access utilize
and share information and knowledge
enabling individuals communities and
people's to achieve their full potential
in promoting their sustainable
development in improving their quality
of life premised on
the purpose and principles of the
charter of the United Nations and
respecting fully and upholding the
Universal Declaration of Human Rights
that means the information society as it
understood by the world community is
based both on the charter of the United
Nations which guarantees security and at
Universal Declaration on Human Rights
but it means you cannot play one thing
against the other Bose has to go
together and this was more or less
repeated in the netmundial principles
this was the big multi-stakeholder
conference organized by Brazil in the
year 2014 the most advanced document on
internet governance principles where
also it was repeated that human rights
is the basis for the information society
and security can be treated as a human
rights and again this interrelationship
was also reconfirmed on the review
conference on the World Summit on the
information society in New York in the
year 2015 so what does it mean for the
future so already four or five years ago
the former president of the European
Parliament Martin Schulz came up with an
initiative and there too we have to
strengthen fundamental rights probably
we need a new charter to strengthen
fundamental human rights in cyberspace
so we the European Parliament was
discussing not only Snowden but also you
know the role of US companies and there
was a feeling in the European Parliament
by some members of the Parliament that
yes we have to stretch the fundamental
so that mean throats started the the
process then a German foundation did
site fundraise a foundation entered in
and created a multi-stakeholder group of
28 intellectuals mainly from Germany and
they worked on a draft for a new
European charter for fundamental digital
rights which were presented to the
subcommittee of the European Parliament
in December to 16
and a second craft was presented just
recently to the new German government in
the Minister of Justice madam Bali and
discussed at the year Republic hi in and
if you want to go deeper into the text
see the the website
ECM so the problem was and and this is
the core of my talk is do we need really
new fundamental digital rights yes or no
there was in this group there was a
debate and said okay on the one hand
people argued so we have already
fundamental rights we have to European
Charter on fundamental rights from the
year 2000 and we have to human rights
declaration which was reinforced um it
on the information society that means we
have existing rights and as I said okay
yeah that's right but all these texts
were written in the analog time so that
means we have to have now a digital age
and we have to see this rights in a new
light and probably we need new rights
like the right to be forgotten and as us
we are referred which we are constituted
by the European Court of Justice so what
we agreed finally was an understanding
if we want to move towards a new
instrument probably the new instrument
would not be a new charter but a
framework of interpretation then one
thing is it's it's clear that the world
has changed and probably a number of
these fundamental rights which were
described either in the United Nations
Declaration of Human Rights from 1948 or
in the European Charter on fundamental
rights from the year 2000 has to be seen
now in a new light and if so far the
conclusion from this initiative was we
need an enhanced understanding of the
existing human rights in a digital world
this was the conclusion and we also
concluded that while the existing
mechanism of Human Rights is
concentrated on the relationship between
did this
the government and the individual so we
concluded that now a lot of things are
done by at the private sector so and the
question is you know what has the
private sector big corporations do they
have also obligations quote-unquote to
guarantee human rights the guarantee for
human rights is in the hands of
governments mainly so but what about all
this as a big companies which handle our
data which enable us to enjoy our right
to freedom of expression so this where
the two open questions you know if we go
deeper into the role of the DES future
of discussion of fundamental rights we
need an enhanced understanding and we
need a broadening of the debate with
regard to the various stakeholders we
came up with order you know to summarize
this and also to conclude we identified
in particular three issues which we're
further discussion is needed and I think
it's not a surprise that the first issue
was we have to have an enhanced
understanding of the right to freedom of
expression and I think the debate this
morning when Alex Thomas spoke about
from from Facebook about the
complication you know how on the one
hand to guarantee freedom of expression
on the other hand to do something
against the pollution of our
intellectual environment against fake
news and some other things so this is a
delicate issue which needs further
discussion so we have in this Charter we
do not propose already a final solution
but I think this needs further
discussion personally I think if you're
compared with with the the car traffic
you know if you clean the highway from
drunken drivers this does not interfere
into the freedom to drive a car so and
it's a it's a delicate issue because
it's extremely difficult to have the
borderline where say okay here freedom
of expression stops
normally this can be decided only by
independent courts on a case-by-case
basis so insofar you know we are really
entering here
slippery territory but we have to have a
discussion so that the sensitivity of
all stakeholders is growing and and you
can develop a certain feeling you know
what is right and what is wrong you will
never settle this issue but I think this
is one issue for further discussion
the second issue it's also another
surprise is the right to privacy in the
digital age so we have a lot of new
discussions around test the GD P R is
probably the most important new legal
instrument you know that in the Human
Rights Council the Rapporteur on privacy
in the digital age hedonic II is
proposing new instruments including the
instruments against mass surveillance
and and things like that so this is a
the second line of discussion and the
third and last line for discussion is
artificial intelligence and I think this
is will will affect the fundamental
rights fundamentally in the future
yesterday in the Munich Security Summit
the general petraeus who was also the
chair of the CIA made very clear that
the passion in a debate about less
autonomous weapon systems that at the
end of the command train there has
always to be a human being which can be
made accountable and I think this is
really important if we discuss
artificial intelligence you it's nearly
impossible to regulate it in a classical
way that it means here also you have to
look for innovative ways how to handle
this probably stumbling forward on a
case-by-case basis but I think this is
an important point that at the end of
all this change will machine to machine
is communicating you have to have a
human being which is in the final
control how this can't be implemented
this is not easy but this has to be
discussed and we need more public
awareness so that this issues freedom of
expression privacy
and the future of artificial
intelligence is discussed and this is
not enough because we cannot discuss
these issues in isolation the decipher
tet1 internet there is one cyberspace
and we have at the moment different
streams of intergovernmental
negotiations where the negotiators are
sitting in their silos so we have
cybersecurity this is negative in the
first committee of the General Assembly
and in the United Nations in the digital
economy the World Trade organization's
is discussing a digital trade pact and a
regulatory system for e-commerce human
rights issues I mentioned already in the
in in in the freedom of X in the Human
Rights Council of the United Nations and
artificial intelligence is discussed
elsewhere the g7 will organize a huge
multi-stakeholder conference later this
year in Canada under the Canadian a37
presidency and probably the outcome from
the g7 conference will be an agenda for
the future of artificial intelligence
but you know if we have one Internet
then you cannot negotiate this
separately like privacy and and security
this has to go in hand-in-hand and we
have to find the balance and the GDP is
a very good example that if you regulate
one field like privacy this has economic
consequences this has implications for
the security and certainly you need the
technology but it means you have to have
a holistic approach which brings the
security cyber security issues the
digital trade issues the human rights
issues and the technology issues in a
certain balance with this I say thank
you and if you have some questions I
have still two minutes for Q&A big
thanks for much for long
well in fact we have more than two
minutes for Q&A while some of you may be
preparing or thinking about a possible
question or comment I might just come
with with something myself I'm intrigued
by the the initiative that you flagged
earlier on in your presentation about a
European sort of high level principles
code and I'm just wondering is this
thought of as something by Europe for
Europe or is it thought of as something
which would be in conformity with the
latter part of your presentation that is
meant to also operate for the benefit of
the wider world that's one question yeah
you know that was when Kurt started the
initiative there was on to like always
you know you had first enthusiasm and
then you had a skepticism said you know
we have so many instruments do we need
new charter the source was also the
candidate for the Chancellery in Germany
and he negotiated in the coalition
treaty that the German government will
take this project sooner or later and
will table it in the European Union so
that means the the future of this
initiative residence will be a charter a
statement or I proposed a framework of
interpretation so this is open but the
discussion will continue and I think
these three main issues I have outlined
freedom of expression privacy and our
different intelligence will probably
drive to discussion how far this will go
it's difficult to say it was a German
initiative so that means we I go
tomorrow to duplicity to the euro tick
we have a similar session there how many
other Europeans are interested in
bringing this forward remains to be seen
Lucas Elvis for the relic for now my
relevant had as I share the Council of
Europe's expert group on the human
rights dimensions of artificial
intelligence
so first the advertising plug is we're
working on
the interpretation of the Council of
Europe's human rights and how the court
should interpret it on automated
processing of data free expression so
we'd love to pull you in and have we
have a lot of stakeholders behind the
table but we'd like to have you on board
the question I do have though is if I
read the Charter most of the questions
that are raised are addressed in a
fairly strong in particular way by a
fair bit of European law GDP are sort of
primarily among those bits but also a
number of decisions by the European
Court of Justice other bits of law that
are being negotiated right now like the
privacy regulation rules we have on the
books so do we need to have a broad
discussion in Europe or is it that we
need to figure out what our message is
to the rest of the world because it
seems that we've had that debate in
Europe over the last five years but we
don't necessarily in the conclusions
we've arrived that share the same
outlook that the rest of the world does
in some of the details yes I guess so
that means it's never enough discussion
in Europe so these are the circles which
have this discussion but even now in
Germany Vista GDP are any percent of the
German public is surprised that there's
a GDP our so that means if we have to go
out of the silos and to bring all this
experience which have been collected in
the discussion to the broader public so
that's it's really limited circles in
the Council of Europe in the Commission
in the parliament in expert service but
you are absolutely right while the big
cyber battle in the economic field and
probably also in the military field will
be between China and in the u.s. what
the Europeans can bring to the table
they do not have Google orbital they do
not have Alibaba or Amazon they do not
have $0.10 or Apple so what the
Europeans can bring to the global
process is the rule of law and insofar
the GDP is a very good example we are
now you know this has triggered the
economic model of a lot of big
corporations even Facebook has now big
advertisements in German
papers that really pay us a good thing
for a good reasons so and I think this
is the way where the Europeans can
really contribute to the world and my
understanding from the blend for mr.
karnaki is that he is looking in the
Human Rights Council if he talks about
new instruments to use the GDP are also
as a source of inspiration probably for
a United Nations Convention on data
protection so this is open for
discussion nobody knows at the moment he
has different plans but and it has to be
seen you know how to treat impair our
works but I think for me that's only a
first step where you can use special
European regulation as a model for for
other parts of the world and then
because Europe in this field has not
such fundamental economic interests like
the Americans or the Chinese so they
have also their interests but European
is seen as it I would not say a neutral
party but so this reflects more or less
a common sense and a general
understanding I was King so I have more
of a tactical question building on the
last question and the eternal problem
with Internet governance right so your
last slide just showed all the different
silos and for AI for example the OECD is
also doing an initiative in addition to
the GSA etc etc so how do we convene as
a you know multi stakeholder group how
do we convene the right people in the
right place and right people meaning
everybody in the right place to have
these coherent discussions instead of
running around you know as you know to
Brazil and I'll see you in Tbilisi
tomorrow and and those kinds of things
so how do we actually make that happen
so that there's more coherence yeah this
is the proposal for the so called
holistic approach and this is difficult
to to plan because you have this
established communities with different
cultures the trade people are so
different from the security people and
the Internet Governance people are so
different
from the human rights people so but if
you want to have sustainable results
they have to talk to each other some
people have proposed ok let's start a
process like this climate change which
leads to Paris agreement for cyberspace
as I have said ok like the law of the
sea which is also very complex
convention so my proposal would be to
get inspiration from the Helsinki
process in Europe we had different
baskets the baskets were negotiated
individually but we're interlinked so
that means the Internet is a
decentralized mechanism so that you
could have liaisons among the various
silos so that decision in one baskets
are taking in the light of the
experience of the other baskets within I
can you know I'm more for more than 20
years with ICANN we had it so called
IANA transition where we had a rather
different communities for the names
community the numbers community the
protocol community and all they
negotiated individually but came
together in a so-called cross
constituency working groups we as I
informed what they decided in their
field of competence so that means the
proposal is not to create a world new
world conference on the Internet and
remove tower to world convention in
cyberspace but to have a decentralized
systems where the various negotiation
strings are interlinked by a liaisons or
representatives or whatsoever so but
that this could lead to it I call it a
multi-layer multiplayer mechanism and
enhance communication and cooperation so
you have to give the baby a name though
but this you know and I repeat if you
continue in isolated ways you will not
have sustainable results thank you good
thanks very much again Wolfgang so
Wolfgang mentioned briefly the role of
privates gatekeepers and private
platforms and that was quite a nice
bridge over to the theme of the next
presentation by Christina
so Christina without further ado the
floor is yours thank you very much thank
you I am very very pleased to be here
and I look forward to the discussion
today I am going to talk about the
factor content regulation by social
media platforms in the context of the
fight against terrorism and violent
extremism looking into issues raised
from a human rights perspective with
particular focus on the right to freedom
of opinion and expression and
interlinked rights such as the right to
participate in public debates now I
think it has been well established in
the past years that internet
intermediaries who provide a platform
for and curate online content play an
extremely important role in facilitating
the public's access to information
communication including in facilitating
discourse on issues of public interest
and this has revolutionized the way
individuals governments groups wide
variety of actors communicates and also
how public debates are conducted it also
resulted in the spaces where individuals
exercise their free free speech as well
as seek information to allow them to
form opinions being increasingly
controlled by private entities and for
this reason did the argument that some
online platforms have become the digital
age equivalent of public squares has
been gaining traction and there is an
argument to make that due to their reach
use and level of interactivity some of
these platforms at least to some extent
do play a public interest role and why
is that of course studies showed that
people have been increasingly getting
their news from social media social
media platforms have been instrumental
in disseminating information
about human rights violations and abuses
about political developments about
humanitarian crisis and so on and in in
certain countries and provinces some of
these social media platforms are
actually so dominant that too
at least part of the population they
represent the Internet itself and
especially as in these cases offline
information frequently flows in a
restricted manner this platform
constitute constituted the main source
of information and that includes
information that is of public interest
now if we if we look at how social media
platforms regulates the functioning
they're functioning they work on the
basis of standards that are pre
established and that are unilaterally
imposed and that provides them with a
quasi normative power they're also the
ones who of course execute and enforce
these rules which gives them sort of a
quasi enforcement power and they also
have this quasi adjudicative role and
frequently required that disputes that
arise with their users are settled via
internal or alternative dispute
mechanisms and of course having my
having in mind the role that these
entities are some of these entities play
the question arises whether the exercise
of this private sovereignty should be
subject to some form of checks and
balances to view to avoid arbitrary and
abusive use of power but of course while
the Terms of Service and community
standards that that the functioning of
this platform is based on should be in
line with the laws of the states where
they operate which in itself can be a
very big challenge for companies the
companies do not have any formal human
rights responsibilities arguably under
the UN guiding principles on business
and human rights they do have
responsibility to respect human rights
and and
to remedy in case they abused them but
of course this is soft law it's a
resolution of the Human Rights Council
it is not binding and not unimportant
Lee it is not something that has been
formally agreed with companies and I do
not suggest that companies are
insensitive to issues related to freedom
of expression and many of them are
actually quite sensitive to them but
what I'm trying to say is that there are
many underlying issues and this is
reflected among others in the fact that
community standards frequently go beyond
but humor by standards allow and what
states could enact as as binding rules
for example a number of platforms
censored nudity in general because they
wish to facilitate the creation of a of
a space that fits their business model
that is more miner friendly or family
friendly this is something that states
could not do however as as we are well
aware there has been increasing pressure
on platforms and internet intermediaries
to monitor and the police content
generated and disseminated by users on
behalf of the states in the content of
the fight against terrorism and violent
extremism and this is a trend that is
very much driven by the use of ICTs by
terrorist groups as a tool for
recruitment financing planning and so on
and many states have been considering
sanctions and fines to be imposed on
online platforms who they think are not
doing enough to counter this phenomenon
and because of that platforms have a
course taken a number of individual and
concerted measures which did not provide
for a comprehensive solution and it is
not really something surprising
considering that one of the very
important challenges that is faced by
companies who are addressing terrorist
and violent extremist content is that
there
no universally agreed definition of
either States defined by terrorism and
violent extremism in their domestic
legislation and they are very
significant discrepancies between the
different approaches that states take
and in addition there's there's been a
tendency in past years to criminalize
conduct that used to be in the pre
criminal space before such as
glorification of terrorism apology of
terrorism praise and justification of
terrorism and similar concerns go
actually for violent extremism as well
many states don't even focus on
countering violent extremism but
countering extremism and radicalization
and disassociate the concept from
violence this has actually triggered a
lot of criticism on part of Human Rights
bodies both from international
organizations like the the office of the
High Commissioner for Human Rights of
the UN or the Special Rapporteur as well
as NGOs because under some of these
definition there is a threat that almost
any kind of views that deviate from
social norms accepted by the majority
may be suppressed as measure and and the
measures may actually target thought and
belief an opinion rather than actual
conduct then again some companies
respond to these developments by
developing their own definitions which
is something that Facebook has done and
Facebook has recently published a blog
post where they define terrorist
organizations as any non-governmental
organization that engages in
premeditated acts of violence against
persons or property to intimidate a
civilian population government or
international organization in order to
achieve a political religious or
ideological aim it is very commendable
of course that a company who must be at
least in part struggling with the
expectations on them to deal with with
terrorist and violent extremist content
at the same time it also raises some
questions and some red flags because if
one raises this definition it can read
as including in the category of
terrorist organizations any non-state
armed group that is involved in a
non-international armed conflict with a
state which is of course problematic and
in addition to two issues related to I
mean in addition it's actually linked to
issues related to definitions and
forcing all these different standards in
different jurisdictions comes with very
real challenges especially for those
companies that operate in many countries
or that operate quasi worldwide the
other aspect that I will right I would
like to raise in addition to the
substantive criteria that is used by
platform 2 to deal with content that may
be criminal in nature or that that they
are expected to censor and remove is are
the procedures that they employ when it
comes to assessing content and this is
generally when it comes to to terrorism
and violent extremism this is an
exercise that requires a rather
sophisticated legal analysis we
unfortunately have insufficient and
income prehensile information on how
platforms make such determinations
including on what are the circumstances
when artificial intelligence is used
what are the circumstances where their
human oversight what are the
circumstances but there is a combination
of the two of course the use of
artificial intelligence to deal with
large volumes of content is something
that is encouraged by some states and
the European Commission as well so it is
something that is likely to be a lot
more prevalent in the future also
because there is no way to deal with
horrendous volumes of content with human
moderators now the problem with agar is
of course is that they are not foolproof
and that may lead to to screening that
is over or under
inclusive for example algorithms are not
necessarily well-equipped to understand
context different forms of humor may not
pick up certain nuances and suppli T's
and need to be trained for different
languages and contexts and what is
particularly important in the context of
terrorism and violent extremism they are
not necessarily very well-equipped to
assess intent on part of the person
posting
I mean criminal intent and also the
threat level as the result of a certain
post now the problem is even if we if we
employ human expertise that is not
necessary a silver bullet either for for
many reasons doing it right with require
social media platforms to employ a very
highly trained and specialized workforce
reports that we have indicates that it
is more frequently low paid and
insufficiently trained moderators that
are the de facto gatekeepers of freedom
of expression online for example we are
reports in German media on Facebook
moderators employed in Germany by a
third company who do content review for
Facebook allegedly have on average 8
seconds to decide on the legality of a
certain post because of this
shortcomings and this is my final point
it is very important that there is due
process and there are adequate
safeguards in this content regulation
and moderation process and this is
something that so far is largely lacking
or it is definitely not adequate users
generally have very limited options at
their disposal to receive information
about processes to challenge decisions
or to or to get redress while the the
social media companies the platforms
have their own challenges first of all
the volume of content
and secondly onerous intermediary
liability frameworks imposed on them
applications included in the laws such
as the the German Network Enforcement
Act they also received very little help
and guidance from public authorities and
considering all this it is very likely
that in case of doubt platforms were
error on the side of over censoring so I
think that why there there is much to be
said in favor of self-regulation and in
favor of regulatory restraint on part of
the state when it comes to these issues
one has to bear in mind that the human
rights obligations of states include the
obligation to set up a framework and to
create the conditions that makes human
rights compliance possible including on
part of other actors non-state actors
that very much includes businesses and
this would definitely mean ensuring that
there are effective safeguards that the
relevant rules that underpin content
regulation and moderation are accessible
and are foreseeable and there is a
possibility to meaningfully challenge
decisions there is an access to remedy
and there is a meaningful independent
oversight this is very much to ask and
very extremely extremely far from this
however I think that if one - if we want
to safeguard freedom of expression
online these are the conditions that we
need to be moving forward in the future
thank you very much and I look forward
to questions later on
great thanks very much Christina and
hopefully we will have a fairly seamless
transition over to the world of
PowerPoint we do okay thank you very
much
I have I would like to thank very much
Torsten and the organizers for this
invitation I have a huge challenge which
is presenting to you in 15 minutes
something that normally needs about 15
hours to explain adequately which is law
enforcement cross-border access to data
and human rights the big issue is that
there is absolutely no doubt about the
fact that law enforcement police justice
need to access data in this digital age
but the big question is how to do this
in a way which will be compatible with
human rights so this will be my outline
during this 15 minutes the starting
point was the USA versus Microsoft case
and although these cases this means
today there are some very important
lessons to learn from this case the
second point in my outline will be the
cloud act a little bit lost in the
clouds since its adoption
the third point would be the evidence
proposal proposed recently by the
European Commission and I will discuss
the important challenges for not only
the months but the years ahead so let's
start first with the first point I guess
you're familiar with this important case
in front of the US Supreme Court the USA
versus Microsoft case for those of you
who are not familiar let me explain it
very quickly
Newton might think Europe I will be the
United States and the point in this case
was the following the FBI requested
Microsoft the data the emails of a
suspect in a drug trafficking case
Microsoft examines this it said well we
are sorry we cannot give you the data
because
the data you're asking for are in our
data center in Dublin in Europe very
safe hands exactly with GDP our hands
and so Microsoft said if you want let's
imagine that this is what micros said
let's imagine that you were asking for a
book that this guy left in Dublin what
who you were supposed to do you are
supposed to go through an omelet mutual
legal assistant treaty sent a request to
the doubling authorities which will go
take the book and send it to you in the
United States so this was the position
of Microsoft with data we should do
exactly the same thing as for a book
sent requests to the Irish authorities
but what is very interesting is that the
United States government did not have a
total same approach and this extremely
interesting thought provoking about the
stages of data today the United States
said will not at all well both states
both both parties in this case accepted
that low the American law and the basis
of which the warrant has been issued
which is a stored Communications Act had
no extraterritorial reach so the US
government did not question this they
said there is no extraterritorial reach
to this old law drafted in 1986 six well
before the cloud but the US government
said there is make certain
territoriality here come here mister
Microsoft come in Washington DC Seattle
we give you a computer and you can
access all that is that you want so the
data are American there is no
extraterritorial reach you can imagine
what there's a huge problem I drafted a
study at the request of Microsoft which
was published and you can find on mice
around 8:00 last December and I heavily
criticized this approach of the American
government because you can imagine
beyond all things that every government
in the world can use it most you can say
that all data Russian Theo yang can say
that all data if they are accessible for
preparing well technically it could be
more difficult but they could be for
North Korea
could we consider that the argument of
Microsoft is better and that Microsoft
said that what is relevant is the place
where the data are stored is it more
relevant in a digital world well in my
study I discussed also this extensively
of course it's not the only relevant
criterion who have plenty of other
things that have not taken into
consideration but it is relevant first
technically the data has a much greater
materiality than it is often suggested
when we view you download your emails in
reality what you do is that you request
a specific data center somewhere in
Ireland or in Tallinn or elsewhere to
give you access to this so this is very
much relevant and also legally because
after the relevation of certain
companies like Microsoft invested
hundreds of millions of dollars in order
to build data centers in places like
France for example Germany the
Netherlands and elsewhere so that they
will send this message that well what is
done in Europe remains to Europe your
data will be stored in Europe and will
be protected by the GDP our and European
law and this was also the position of
what became very recently since the
entering the first of the GDP are the
Data Protection Board will European Data
Protection Board which in last November
said that their silk convention of
existing media legal assistant treaties
by third countries law enforcement
authorities an interference with the
territorial sovereignty of a EU Member
State so all this is very interesting
because as a matter of fact we could ask
ourselves now the case is dismissed we
were expecting the the decision of the
US Supreme Court in June but the
adoption of cloud data and coming to
this immediately render the case moot it
was dismissed but nonetheless for me
Microsoft won the argument the case
because Microsoft argument was that
American law did not have an
extraterritorial effect and so the
Congress had to adopt a few months ago
in March this bill
the cloud act in order to give clearly
an extraterritorial reach to the cloud
so I come to the second part what is the
cloud act the cloud actor is two things
first what we call the Microsoft Ireland
fix their solution to the Microsoft
Ireland case please read clockwise with
me the main points very quickly about
cloud that well was this a fix yes
surely from the point of view of US law
it was a fix
Microsoft argument was that the Congress
needs to legislate in order to give an
extraterritorial reach to American law
this was done it was not the case before
it is clearly the case now but of course
the other solution was given only from
the point of view of America no not at
all from the point of view of a European
law conflict of laws etcetera
the second thing in the cloud that is
that it introduced a procedure which
permits a company like Microsoft Amazon
Google or any other to file in case of
such a request to give what is stored in
the cloud to file a motion to quash or
modify to the American judge very good
but no novelty it was possible also
before absolutely no novelty here and
what is a very preoccupy is that the
cloud Act provides for no obligation for
the US judge to follow this to quash or
modify even if the US judge finds that
there is a conflict of laws for example
with a European law or any other there
is absolutely no obligation to accept
that this petition why because the
American judge could say that we have a
national security considerations in the
United States which are absolutely
preeminent and so we must give priority
to this even if there is a conflict of
laws you don't matter we will not modify
this warrant so the third problem is
that the problem of conflict of laws
remains and especially the huge issue is
the incompatibility of such a request
with the general data protection
regulation especially article 48 I could
talk for hours about this but what is
very clear is that we need the European
Union to come out and say
there is clearly an incompatibility with
the gdpr and that we have to follow some
conditions and some procedures in order
to lift this incompatibility so that
things will be clear my other point is
what will happen with the reactions of
other states now all states know that
American law has clearly an
extraterritorial reach what are they
going to do are they going to accept
this are they going to accept that the
data stored produced and stored in their
territory will be given to the American
authorities without even than knowing
nothing at all
so what will be their reaction this is
interesting to see and we could also
make a parallel with other issues of
laws American laws which has an
extraterritorial reach let's think about
the ranch actions and the whole debate
and others and finally there is a
concern about the fact that the Cloud
Act does not take a sufficiently into
consideration interstate and reciprocity
issues which brings me to the second
part of the cloud duct I still have some
time which provides for bilateral
agreements as the possibility to
conclude blattar agreements with several
governments in order to give a solution
to this conflict of laws not all
governments it's just with qualifying
foreign governments just an elite of
governments if they need some strong
American human rights requirements and
if there is no veto from the Congress in
which case all the Europeans will be
happy they will finally have access to
some data stored in the United States
directly using the same procedure but
attention not all data there are very
strong limitation a very limited number
of data that they could have access if
there is such a be lateral agreement but
this is the novelty that we live there
is a lift of some of the blogging
features of the ECPA nonetheless major
questions remain including the issue of
reciprocity and human rights
requirements that could be for example
European Human Rights requirements how
we're going to introduce them are we
going to be able through this bilateral
agreements to resolve all this is
let me go now to e evidence to the
European cloud duct presented just a
month ago
by the European Commission well the idea
is the similar instead of going through
this
I'm sorry through this blood procedure
which very time-consuming I cannot
explain to you here but the ideals to
have a shortcut like cloud act instead
of passing through International
Cooperation between states to request
directly Microsoft or Amazon or Google
or any other to give the data to the
authorities through what we call the
European production order an order given
directly to a nice speed provider I
don't have the time unfortunately to
present you all the issues in cloud act
but in evidence but at least very very
clear quickly I would like to say that
what is interesting is that first of all
the evidence makes a clear distinction
between four types of data with
different with different settings if you
want and procedures for each one the
more the data becomes sensible the more
we have human rights and other
requirements we can use this procedure
only for serious crimes for example not
for any kind of crime and we have also
what is very interesting we have both a
project of a regulation about all this
the European production order especially
but also it directive on legal
representatives we ask all companies to
have a legal representative voice where
we the states will be able to address
these issues what are the futures very
very quickly because I'm running out of
time
when first of all there is an
extraterritorial reach in a evidence
extremely interesting the Europeans
criticized heavily the Americans for
their extraterritorial rage of their low
of Cloud act and at the same time their
response is to introduce an
extraterritorial reach any evidence so
that they can they could play on the
same level field if you want during the
negotiation second issue eeeh Venus
takes very well into consideration
extraterritorial reach
yes but taking very well into
consideration the protection of
immunities and privileges of foreign
states with a possibility to go in front
of a judge if you find that there is any
kind of problem concerning privileges
and immunities in other states has an
obligation
not to - well - to cancel the order the
European production or the same things
we take into consideration adequately
the protection of the fundamental
interests of foreign States and this is
very important and the contrast once
again to cloud act and there is also you
can read this regulation of dozens of
pages or as always you can see that
there are very strong human rights
protections there is room for
improvement and the part of my work now
is precisely to try to define what we
should improve so that we'll be able to
meet the requirements of European no but
you will see that there is a very good
quality of this despite this there is a
criticism of the i-gos I will not be
able to discuss it because I'm running
out of time I just have one minute and a
half left in order to talk to you about
the challenges ahead what are the
challenges ahead well first of all
logically adoption of the evidence it's
a very good legislative package there
are things we prove you can do it
quickly the big challenge is when are we
going to be able to adopt this state's
need this evidence and for me it's a
very important step towards the
conclusion of an agreement with the
United States and with other states so
are we going to be able to adopt a
evidence before the end of the current
mandate of the European Parliament
especially which means still March
because we have elections in June in
March of the you'll enter into
legislative mode of the European
Parliament this is a big question it
could be good to adopt here evidence as
soon as possible second challenge is
that we need to start negotiating an
agreement a data sharing agreement with
the United States the United States
already started doing this with a UK
there is this myth about this data
sharing agreement between the United
States and the UK that nobody has seen
if somebody has it here please give it
to me I would like to read it but the
major issues now is that we have the
evidence they eat you clearly affirmed
this competence in this field so
logically speaking we should have an
agreement between the United States and
the EU and this should resolve the issue
big
problem the united states are not at all
willing to conclude an agreement with
the European Union and this is white
cloud duct only it speaks about the
possibility to conclude lateral
agreements with governments not with
international organizations why because
they are fearful the United States of
the human rights protection is some of
the EU member states especially the ones
of the east and this is the big problem
so what are we going to cover we're
going to have a framework agreement
between the United Sensai EU and
agreements also with member states this
a very huge issue on which I work
actually and finally I promise this
agreements whatever either EU US or
bilateral with States will definitely
need to address adequately all the human
rights issues in order to pass the
control of the European courts and it's
especially notable Bassel but also
Strasbourg we have seen what happened
with safe harbor we have seen what
happened with the recent PNR agreement
with Canada there is absolutely no doubt
about the fact that the Parliament
European Parliament will submit this
case this agreement to the European
Court so it's absolutely necessary to be
able to have enough human rights
protections in order to pass this test
thank you very much
[Applause]
thanks very much Theodore thanks very
much Christina we've got now 18 minutes
roughly to have discussion questions
while some of you are thinking I see one
hand up already I've got a very sort of
quick question for you Theodore when you
were talking I was intrigued by the
omission presumably because of lack of
time of reference to the cybercrime
convention and I'm just wondering what
sort of role that might play because
interestingly that's the Council of
Europe instrument that has been ratified
by the u.s. a quite extraordinary and
one I just wondered could that be some
sort of bridging normative framework in
this in this way ahead with respect to e
evidence yeah this is extremely
interesting of course I cannot enter
into details we're negotiating right now
an Additional Protocol to the Buddhist
Convention on cybercrime which precisely
has for a certain object to address the
issue of evidence let's say evidence in
the cloud it's interesting to read the
European impact assessment study 250
pages but there is a part about the fact
why this is not contradictory with other
existing instrument instruments or with
the project of the video person I think
that basically the short answer to your
question because with there are many
answers but the short answer is that
within the Budapest Convention will
never be able to go as far away with the
Budapest confession we'll post some very
basic rules and let's not forget that we
have more than 50 states newcomers a lot
of African states are our Japan is part
of the Buddhist conversion Australia and
several African states are coming into
the Buddhist convention and of course we
will not be able taking into
consideration this situation to go as
far so it's not it's an important
project but certainly not as ambitious
as what these bilateral agreements want
to do ok good general down the back
first thank you very much
and thank you to all three speakers now
we just have to hear for your wonderful
contributions my name is kuba magic I
teach international law at the
University of Exeter in the UK I have a
question for dr. who's the urban if I
may you know you started your talk by
saying that social media platforms now
have this cosine normative cause I
judicial cause I executive roles so
let's drop the cause I and if we talk
about normative judicial executive what
are we talking about we we were talking
about states and so is is the argument
is the consequence of the argument that
social media platforms are slowly
becoming quasi States nowadays now this
question is sometimes posed to their
representatives and for example Mark
Zuckerberg when he was asked this very
question he said oh no no no no Facebook
is not a state Facebook is a community
but then it's a strange community isn't
it one that doesn't give its members any
say in how they are governed so maybe
you know professor client vector was
talking about Internet Governance maybe
we need to talk about social media
governance and I wonder if that's the
consequence of the argument that you're
making so that members of these social
media platforms must be given some say
in how they are governed it's not to say
that it hasn't been tried Facebook tried
it and failed in 2009 but I wonder what
your thoughts are on that
are we moving in that direction or is it
an impasse completely thank you thank
you it's a very interesting question
thank you very much I would not say of
course that social media platforms are
becoming States but you I fully agree
with you that in certain respects they
are taking over tasks that have been
traditionally associated with States and
at least in that respect I feel that
they should be taking up more
responsibility that is akin to the
responsibilities that the states have
when it comes to for example
guaranteeing freedom of expression
states are not very well placed to to
guarantee freedom of expression on
Facebook and Twitter on most of these
platforms at this point and I agree that
ideally
there should be some sort of if they are
a community obviously you should consult
the community and your your rules and
your governance should be a result of
that community's wishes considering that
the community for example a Facebook or
many of these social media platforms is
very very big as much bigger than the
community forming most countries of
course this would be an extremely
difficult issue which is why in a way
for me the easier but not really option
is to go via the existing obligations of
states to ensure that within their
jurisdiction human rights of people are
respected even by third third parties
and that's the complications of that of
course come from the fact that when it
comes to to these platforms it is very
difficult to think in terms of
individual countries and one country may
legislate and it may have limited effect
it may even become disruptive so ideally
of course you would need something that
is binding in a way as a state could
legislate but that goes beyond the the
national level I think that's not
particularly likely to happen anytime
soon but this is how I would see
probably a meaningful solution to these
problems okay my name is a soft ovum
from Yale Law School one of the last
comments the wolf game made in his
presentation was a need to break the
silos that exists across this space and
I want to argue that your papers have a
similar siloing
in the sense that we ran an event that
the information society project at Yale
Law School
titled extraterritorial informants
enforcement and information society and
we argued that M Ladd people are not
talking enough with access to data
people and with data control people in
the sense that the same conflict of laws
problems arise when you want to access
data stored by an intermediary or when
we
- sensor data stored by an intermediary
be hidden Germany to a day in a store by
Facebook in the US or be it Microsoft
want you to access the in a store by an
Irish and so the problem isn't that we
need to look at a cloud attack the
problem is that we need to start
thinking about a private international
law treaty that deals with conflict of
laws in data and intermediaries and so
it's not a solution that is
state-by-state basis through domestic
extraterritorial laws but rather through
a private international law treaty I
know curious to hear your thoughts about
such a proposal quickly as far as my
presentation is concerned if we have a
treaty between the EU and the US this
will immediately resolve the conflict of
law issues you can call it as soon as
you want is it a private international
law human rights or whatever that offeri
call it as you wish the issue is that if
we have a treaty this will immediately
resolve the the problem because on the
basis of article 48 49 of the GD bear
there will be no clearly no more
conflict of laws because this will be AB
faith done on the base of a treaty so
solution as I indicated before I do
think that a real solution would be at
the international level because
everything else sort of at least in the
with respect to the issues that I've
been addressing everything else would
just provide for fragmented and and
probably temporary solutions I'm sorry
you meant Universal because a treaty
between the EU and the US is an
international treaty of course okay okay
but if the International will go back to
the question about the Budapest
Convention protocol this is exactly what
we're trying to do there or that it's
not really Universal yet will not have a
Russia or China or but still it's a very
multilateral initiative but the problem
is that if we want to go far in this
cooperation of data sharing we cannot
this do this at this stage with
everybody because you really need to
have very good human rights guarantees
from both sides
presentation about extremism and
tourists on social media and how to how
the platforms are dealing with it and
the one thing that I'm curious about you
hear anecdotal reports from law
enforcement saying that it's actually an
incredibly valuable source of
information for them when there's this
public communication there's not the
issues of warrants it's out there in the
open so when it has there been any
research from when the platforms start
to crack down on this content as to what
impact it has on law enforcement and
really overall the cost benefit when
there is more restriction of the public
facing content I am not aware of any
such studies that have been conducted if
if anyone here is working on anything
related I would be extremely interested
because one of the issues that that is
raised when you look into censoring
content I do when I do understand that
there is certain content that needs to
be removed everything that is incitement
to hatred and violence that comes with a
certain that triggers a certain threat
level that a crime may be committed
obviously it should be removed but then
when one looks at again anecdotal
evidence of the kind of posts that are
being removed I think much of that
actually would be protected under
international human rights law under
freedom of expression because with
freedom of expression you can publish a
lot of questionable things unless they
hit a certain threshold they should be
left there one thing that that came to
mind when you asked your question and
again anecdotal evidence from law
enforcement that when overeager
platforms censor
contents that may be of terrorist nature
actually they're not really helping law
enforcement and they're not really
helping persecutions because then
evidence is not properly contained and
it cannot be used in in a court setting
anymore so in that that respect it's not
necessarily something very effective and
something very useful but I take your
suggestion to this as to the study
because I think that would be that would
be extremely useful for everyone who is
interested in this debate good
so more empirical work necessary good
and then hello my name is Sophie Kooskia
I teach international law at Yale
University in Krakow Poland and my
question goes to professor Christakis
with regard to one specific issue that
you briefly touched upon namely article
48 gdpr
which says that you know any transfer of
data on the basis of a decision of a
public authority has to be only on the
basis of M lot or other international
agreement now my question would be or I
would be interested to hear your views
on how this would play out in a future
possible case I mean let's imagine
Microsoft - we have an new person now
the US wants the data of this EU person
requires Microsoft or Google or whoever
to hand it out and now we have article
48 and so what would be the European
reaction on that B I mean what what's
the toolbox apart from the legal tags
that we can use to block that and what
would be the consequences I would be
interested in hearing you thank you
great question
we could discuss endlessly about it I
think that the first step is to ask this
question not to me but to the Microsoft
people or to Google Amazon and all the
others are they going to challenge a new
warrant or not the second point is it
could be eventually useful to have the
EU come out very clearly and say that
such a thing will be incompatible with
article 48 because you know the
travelers or article 49 there is no
ambiguity and this ability
fortunately for me was not erased by the
amicus Curia that the EU Commission
submitted to the US Supreme Court in the
Microsoft Ireland case they remained
voluntarily I'm being used in discussing
article 48 49 a little bit disturbing
for a researcher like me who seeks some
kind of clarity on this issues probably
it could be good to suck up some
guidance before answering your question
from the EU if we have such a guidance I
think that things are very simple
because if we request for example the
know Microsoft or Amazon Cloud or Google
if we request them data which are stored
in Europe and this is contrary to the
gtp are you know that we have this huge
sanctions in the GDP are so they will be
exposed exposed I'm sorry to to all
these sanctions which could go up to 4%
of our annual overall return so I think
that there are other issues to discuss
of course but these are probably the
steps in order to give an answer to your
question thanks very much
interesting when you say this you'd like
some guidance because it brings us back
in terms of circle drawing to vote gongs
call for a framework of interpretation
and that could be one of many many
elements of such a framework of
interpretation so we're not quite at
1700 but I also have a plane to catch at
1805 so I do note that the adrenalin
levels are starting to rise within me
and would be I think probably now quite
appropriate that we start to bring this
to a close would you like to say
something to conclude Torsten all right
yeah thank you on behalf of the
organizers it's a great pleasure to have
all of you here on our panel and to let
us have some insights and
some very detailed opinion on that
cutting edge topics and as a expression
of our grateful thank you for being here
I want to hand over some little presents
and hope to stay with us for the rest of
the conference at least the two of you
and okay thank you and please applause
for the panelists and moderators
[Applause]