thank you for your kind words it's
always a pleasure to be back at saikhan
see many familiar faces in the audience
one thing that we don't hear too much
this year or maybe I just haven't been
paying attention is a reminder of the
theme of the conference and so the theme
of the conference is maximizing effects
but I will put it to you that not all
effects deserve to be maximized and so
if some cyber operations because we will
be talking a lot about cyber operations
if some cyber operations have
detrimental impact on the rights of
other states then perhaps there is a
duty of states to mitigate to stop such
cyber operations or even to prevent them
and so this principle or this protective
duty is sometimes referred to as the
principle of due diligence now how far
does this Duty go how far should it
perhaps
evolve further and what are the gray
zones in this area is what we are going
to explore in this panel now I hope
you'll agree with me that we couldn't
have a more qualified and a more
interesting panel than we have today
because all of the bios of all of the
speakers are online and because we don't
have too much time I'm not going to do
long introductions but I will just tell
you very very briefly who are our
speakers today so the one who is staring
the most intently at me at the moment is
probably figure out if you're the Kubo
guy from the animated cartoon are you
that Kubo I'm going to show you my two
strings later right yeah thank you for
that so professor Mike Schmidt is also
very well known to this crowd he's also
my colleague at the University of Exeter
I'm very pleased to say and his other
affiliations include the u.s. naval
Naval War College and of course the
center here now Mike will be speaking to
us today about the talent manual and
it's and the position that the
international group of experts took on
the principle of due diligence where
many of you will know two rules rule six
and seven were dedicated to this
principle then the second on the panel
will be mr. Peter stock Berger who is a
senior managing associate at Denton's
and now a Peter will also be known to
psych on
here he presented a very good paper
about how the law of attribution could
evolve and today he is also going to
talk about dislikes varanda aspects so
he's going to explore whether the
principle of due diligence in
international cyber law should also
evolve further than it perhaps is at the
moment and then on my very very left is
Professor cutting vanilla from
university Grenoble out who has also
very many publications in the area of
international cyber law and one of them
that I would like to highlight today in
particular has a very interesting
subtitle and it's called who is afraid
of cyber diligence and so I can see many
faces around here so I hope none of us
are afraid of the topic that we're going
to face today we have not that much time
left so we agreed with the organizers
that I'm going to I can I'm allowed to
be myself today so I'm going to be a
very rude moderator and I'm going to
enforce the time limit very strictly so
all of our speakers have exactly 15
minutes to present their papers and then
we will have some time we have
altogether 75 minutes so not too much
we'll have some time for Q&A so with
that enough from me and Mike you have
the floor thanks q-ball I'm just nervous
because the clock hasn't started is this
because I work with you good afternoon I
think I know probably 50 or 60 percent
of the audience so it's good to see
everyone again what we're going to be
talking about today or what I'm gonna be
talking about today is the approach that
was taken by the international group of
experts during the seven-year tall and
manual project to the principle of due
diligence now there has been at this
conference an awful lot of talk about
the issue of sovereignty of sovereignty
of rule of international law or merely a
principle of international law whatever
the correct answer to that question
whatever that answer may be nonetheless
if it is an obligation I'm sorry if it
is a a right then it has corresponding
obligations because an international law
when states have rights other states
have obligations to respect those
particular rights so due diligence is
one of those rules of international
law that come from the principle of
sovereignty so we're gonna move the
discussion from sovereignty now to due
diligence it's been around for a long
time the paper by Paul Paul Peter Peter
the paper by Peter I don't remember his
name but I remember the paper it's
excellent I encourage you to read it
lays out the history of the principle of
due diligence and I commend that piece
to you to look at the history of due
diligence but if we start in relatively
modern times we start with the first
case before the International Court of
Justice which was of course Corfu
channel and Corfu channel was in fact a
due diligence case a case that involved
the requirement of due diligence with
respect to Albanian control over
territorial waters had to do with
British warships the facts aren't
horribly important but what you need to
know is that the very first case before
the International Court of Justice dealt
with this particular principle and it
was based on an arbitration island of
Palmas based on statements set forth
that an arbitration between the United
States and the Netherlands in which the
arbitral panel the famous Max who burr
told us that the principle of
sovereignty remember the basis of due
diligence or the basis of due diligence
requires a state to protect within its
territory the rights of other states so
we concluded in the tall emanuel group
that the principle of due diligence
meant that if you are in control of
territory then you must ensure that
territory is not used to the detriment
of other states now that's a very broad
statement and what I'd like to do is
spend the rest of our time here together
teasing that loose the first question is
where does the principle of due
diligence attach clearly from island of
Palmas it attaches within the territory
so with respect to all activities all
activities in this in the territory and
with respect to all cyberinfrastructure
in the territory because a state enjoys
sovereignty over things in its territory
the due diligence principle attaches we
did struggle a wee bit with the question
of does the
diligence obligation of a state attache
outside the territory of that state we
said it did so in two different cases
the first case here is when you have
cyber infrastructure that's under the
governmental control of that state
outside its country so I'm an American I
work for the Department of Defense we
have facilities outside our country that
involves cyber infrastructure and to the
extent that's under our control or under
joint control by the way then we have an
obligation to ensure that cyber
infrastructure is not used to the
detriment of other states the second
example of the of the obligation of
chatting outside of territory is when a
state controls that territory in other
words it's not their state but they're
in control and the classic case would be
a four state is in belligerent
occupation of territory has the United
States has the United Kingdom was with
respect to Iraq even though it wasn't
our territory we had an obligation to
ensure that bad things did not emanate
from that territory why because as a
matter of law we were in control of that
territory that was pretty easy it got
very hard for us when we hit the next
question okay now we know where the due
diligence obligation attaches but when
does it attach what are the conditions
precedent to the attachment of the due
diligence obligation we said there were
two the first is that the obligation
only has to do with cyber operations
from or through your territory that
affect the rights the rights of other
states in other words a right of another
state under international law for
example the right to be free from
intervention by another state
the right to be free from the use of
force from another state and if
sovereignty is a rule the right to be
free from violations of your sovereignty
by virtue of cyber operations conducted
from another state so we'll focus on
rights
we'll move to the next question the next
criterion which is those consequences
must be serious and adverse so the the
operation from your territory or going
through your territory or through cyber
infrastructure must affect the rights of
the state the the target state and in
addition the consequences there must be
serious and adverse with respect to the
rights of other states we drew that
directly from corfu channel
that's what corfu channel said here we
go I wanted to give you an example
though because this is often
misunderstood we're not talking about
the interests of other states we're not
talking about merely doing something
other states don't like we're talking
about an operation from your territory
or from cyber infrastructure in your
territory that affects a right that
state enjoys under international law so
let me give you an example the first one
is is clear there is a right involved
stay dazed launching destructive malware
against state bees pipeline there's an
explosion okay
malware reports back to state C and
state C knows about it you'll see in a
moment knowledge is important this is
crystal clear this is a violation of the
right of sovereignty for example it may
be a violation of the right to be free
from the use of force on your territory
for example in certain cases it may be a
violation of the prohibition on
intervention etc etc etc it's a legal
right that has been affected contrast
that with this one this is a case where
a state has classified documents of
another state a has the classified
documents of B they make those documents
available in state C so the question
here is does state C have a due
diligence obligation to put an end to
the publication of those documents
answer in this case no even if the
consequences are serious and adverse
nevertheless you can't identify a legal
right under international law that the
aggrieved state had you don't have a
right
to keep your secrets secret okay second
criterion serious adverse consequences
we drew this from the very famous
arbitration trail smelter which used the
term it is a term drawn from
environmental law environmental law has
a lot of due diligence obligations with
respect to trans-border harm so we drew
it from here but we drew it by analogy
because we could not identify a precise
point where the consequences are so
severe in the target state that you have
to act the state that it has the due
diligence obligation it has to act so we
borrowed this from environmental law we
did say that the consequences may not
only need not only be on government
infrastructure but it could be on
private infrastructure so if you have if
you're the target state and your
commercial companies your private
entities are suffering harm and that
implicates a right under international
law then due diligence has been
implicated we use the example here
infrastructure of a financial system
that's bad defacing part of the Ministry
of sports website that is providing
information on their football team in
the European Cup that's not so bad
although the Europeans tell me that
actually maybe worse than the financial
thing but whatever this is a very
interesting case that we could not come
to agreement on it's a botnet and we
asked the question if we're looking for
serious adverse consequences which
perspective are we looking at the
serious adverse consequences from from
the state with the territorial state
where there are the bots or are we
looking at the target state so you see a
botnet may have serious adverse
consequences affecting the right in the
target state but because the bots are
spread out in various countries then in
particular countries you may not have
those BOTS themselves causing enough
damage here the group of experts was
split we don't know the answer to this
question the mine or the majority of the
group said you may not aggregate
consequence
but this was the minority both views
were entirely reasonable must have
knowledge there must be knowledge that
what is occurring is having serious
adverse consequences visa vie the rights
of other states you got to know what's
happening and we extended that to
constructive knowledge so your
Intelligence Agency tells you actual
knowledge another intelligence agency
from the target state that says you know
what's happening here this is happening
from your country do something that's
actual knowledge and then construct them
knowledge there are situations where
states should know widespread viruses
and stuff we as the example of
heartbleed but there are many examples
where states should know if a reasonable
state in the same or similar
circumstances would have known then
there is constructive knowledge and we
believe that that knowledge requirement
was satisfied what does the territorial
state have to do has to make it stop has
to make it stop
we went so so our due diligence
obligation applies to ongoing operations
we did talk about a situation in which
the attack or the operation the harmful
operation is imminent material steps
have been taken and it's about to be
launched and in that case we said the
due diligence operation had due
diligence obligation attached because
the operation is really unfolding now so
maybe the results haven't materialized
but hey this thing is started and in
that case that the state where the
operation is being launched from has an
obligation to take measures and with
regard to preventive measures my friends
up here are going to talk I believe
about preventive measures we came to the
conclusion that in the current state of
the law the Lex lotta does not yet reach
preventive measures in so in other words
ensuring the hygiene of your cyber
infrastructure and so forth at this time
we don't know what it's going to look
like in the future but today we could
not find sufficient state practice or
opinion URIs in other than environmental
law to suggest that this was the case
and then there's the question let's
assume you got serious adverse
consequences
affecting the right of another state
with respect to cyber operations from
bad guys other states or non-state
actors being launched from your
territory and you know about it
what do you got to do we believe that
the standard is feasibility you have to
do everything that's reasonable in the
circumstances and every state
represented in this room is in slightly
different situation some have a lot of
technical wherewithal some are
financially wealthy okay some have great
institutional capacity to deal with
cyber incidents what you do is you look
at the state you take the state has you
found it and then you ask would a state
in these circumstances be able to take
action to put an end to the operation
and oh by the way the fact that you
can't act under your domestic law we
apply here a doctrine from the
University of Texas where I got my law
degree it's called the tough nigga
doctrine all right you don't have it you
have a law that says you can't the rest
that person that's your problem
that's not the problem of the state's
suffering you're in breach of your legal
obligation to me when we has all say and
I'm gonna conclude in just one minute
and forty three seconds when we went to
states there was some hesitancy on the
part of some states with regard to this
particular principle this particular
rule one of the things I told him is you
need to understand what this gives you
one of the things you're worried about
are the actions of non-state actors as
many of you know below the threshold of
an armed attack to which you can respond
in self-defense below the threshold the
actions you take are either a torsion
which are unfriendly but lawful actions
or alternatively countermeasures and
what we said you can't take
countermeasures against non-state actors
unless their actions are attributable
States that's the law okay
most states believe that's the law so
there's a problem is another state
non-state actors are whacking you can
you shoot back well you can't do
countermeasures against them on the
basis of their actions alone because
they're non-state actors
what you can do is ask the question is
that state in breach of its due
diligence obligation if the answer is
yes the obligations owed to you so now
you're the victim of an internationally
wrongful act on the part of the
territorial state and you may respond
with a countermeasure against the state
failing to do diligence obligation and
what does that take the form of takes
the form of an operation against the
non-state actors so due diligence for
those represents gives you an
opportunity for a more robust response
against the actions of non-state actors
when those actions are not severe enough
to reach the level allowing you to
engage in self defense I want to be a
little bit careful kinetics 2/32 I want
to be a little bit careful here because
in I come from the kinetic world a War
College there is the unwilling unable
test in self-defense here this is not
the unwilling unable test it is the un--
it is the unwilling test if a state is
unable then it is not feasible and it is
not in breach of its obligation and it
doesn't open up these doors so my last
slide
very quickly the you know we will have
to cut the time because 15 minutes I
have to impose let me finish the last
slide because it's important for the
audience Thank You Kubo for your input
the UN gge has addressed this issue
twice some of you know some of you are
part of the UN Gigi you should know the
UN Gigi has not said this as law this is
a hortatory norm they have used the word
should we concluded that that did not
mean there wasn't a norm
it means they could not achieve
agreement in the UN Gigi if it achieved
this status Kubo thank you so much for
the extra 45 second Thank You Mai and
thank you for your attention so it's
always nice to see when there are rules
with limited enforcement capability this
is international law what are you
talking about yes but perhaps there is
an obligation of due diligence but I
think we should all thank Mike for his
excellent speech
and before we move on to Peter I would
just highlight one of the things that
Mike mentioned and that's the criterion
of serious adverse consequences and I'm
really glad that you highlighted that
it's something that comes from
international environmental law because
Peter is going to focus I think it's an
excellent bridge between the two
presentations Peter is going to talk
about precautionary principle and to
what extent that can as another concept
from international environmental law
develop the law in this area Peter
great thanks Kubo good afternoon
everyone and thank you Mike for the
great start I disagree with everything
you said Paul Peter whatever Peter so as
the title of my paper indicates I'm
gonna be focusing on what Mike talked
about which is the preventive aspect of
due diligence and specifically what's
called the precautionary principle and
my my proposal in the paper my theory is
that states if they adopt the
precautionary principle as it's
reflected in international environmental
law it will give more teeth to the due
diligence principle under customary
international law as it applies in
cyberspace so my my talk today is going
to focus on three points I'm going to
look at due diligence and the
precautionary approach as it currently
exists under international law I'm going
to look at how the precautionary
approach was dealt with by the authors
of the talent manual and then I'm going
to talk about my proposal which is a
procedural due diligence requirement to
conduct what I'm proposing to be a cyber
impact assessment by States which would
then give more teeth to do due diligence
principle in cyberspace so just to go
over the due diligence principle once
more not to repeat too much what Mike
said it is rooted in the principle of
sovereignty that definition of
sovereignty which is every state's right
to exercise its rights as a state to the
exclusion of other states and it comes
from the island of Palmas decision in
that particular language and it's also
rooted in adjoining principles to the
principle of sovereignty obligations and
restrictions one of those being the
principle of non-intervention and the
principle of non-intervention is most
famously articulated in Article two
of the UN Charter to four and to seven
and so out an outgrowth of the principle
of non-intervention is the due diligence
principle which restricts states from
taking from allowing their territory or
the organs under their control or items
under the jurisdictional control to harm
other States to inflict internationally
wrongful acts so I want to look at how
the due diligence principle and the
precautionary principle have been
articulated in international law by
looking at for International Court of
Justice cases this is the International
Court of Justice for those who don't
know it is the principal judicial organ
of the United Nations it is charged
under the UN Charter and the statute of
the court to entertain two types of
cases contentious cases between two
states and it can also issue advisory
opinions when one of the organs of the
United Nations asked for an advisory
opinion like the Security Council or the
General Assembly
so the first ICJ case that talked about
due diligence is is what Mike talked
about the 1949 Corfu channel case
between the United Kingdom and Albania
and in that case the court held that
Albania did have an obligation to warn
the United Kingdom about Minds that were
in the Corfu Channel and so this was the
first time and it was the courts first
opportunity to issue a decision that the
court endorsed the due diligence
principle and it comes here you can see
it says a well recognized principle
every state's obligation to not
knowingly allow its territory so that's
the first time the Corps articulates the
due diligence principle the next
opportunity the court has is in its 1996
advisory opinion on the use and the
legality of nuclear weapons and so this
goes back to what I was talking about
before the ICJ has jurisdiction to issue
advisory opinions on questions posed to
it and in this case the General Assembly
asked the the Court of Justice to opine
on whether the threat or use of nuclear
weapons is permitted under international
law and the court famously said no it's
our famously said customary
international law has not developed on
that point so we cannot ruin that on
that point but it did reaffirm the due
dilligence principle and it specifically
said that the due diligence principle is
part of the body of law that applies to
international
Environmental Law and that's important
because after the 1996 opinion when we
fast forward to 2010 the court then
addresses the due diligence principle
and specifically the precautionary
principle that I'm advocating for in
cyberspace in the 2010 case concerning
the pulp mills between Argentina and
Uruguay and in the pulp mills decision
Argentina was contending that Uruguay
violated the due diligence principle
when it was constructing pulp mills on
the river Uruguay and that it did not
warn Argentina about the trans boundary
effect of that pulp mill and the court
affirmed the due diligence principle
generally said it is reflection of
customary international law which is
important when the court of justice
makes these statements because the
International Court of Justice under
Article 38 of its statute is charged
with determining the current existence
of international law as it exists at the
time when it renders the decision on the
dispute and so when the court of justice
says a certain principle is reflective
of customary international law or when
they render an opinion as to the
interpretation of a treaty it carries
significant weight in terms of the
actual status of customary national law
and so the court identified in this
decision that the principle of
prevention is reflective of customary
international law as part of the due
diligence principle and so that's
important because that isn't a
reflection by the court that it is part
of custom now this decision was related
to an international environmental law
case and so arguably it's only limited
to international environmental law but
the Court did say that it's part of the
corpus of international law and it
endorsed the procedural aspect of the
precautionary principle by saying States
should conduct environmental impact
assessments when there is a likelihood
that trans boundary harm would occur
from their activities when you fast
forward to 2015 the court again endorses
this concept and this was the 2015 case
involving the construction of a road in
Costa Rica between Nicaragua and Costa
Rica
and in this case the court again
affirmed the due diligence principle it
affirmed that environmental impact
assessments are a procedural aspect of
the due diligence principle in
international environmental law and it
also clarified what an environmental
impact assessment would look like in
this context and they specifically said
the court said that the content and the
subject matter and the scope of an
environmental impact assessment and E I
a will be left to the states it's up to
the domestic law of the States to
determine what that would look like
it's simply affirmed that it is a
procedural requirement to conduct the
assessment in the first instance and if
you fail to conduct that assessment then
you are violating your due diligence
obligations under customary
international law and so this procedural
aspect is really the main takeaway from
the Costa Rica case now the
precautionary principle is not just
reflected in these four International
Court of Justice cases between 1971 and
1991 it it was well reflected in a
number of environmental documents it
really picked up steam in 1992 to the
present with the Rio declaration with a
variety of environmental documents the
International Tribunal for the law of
the sea has endorsed the due diligence
principle and the precautionary approach
the World Trade Organization has also
adopted the precautionary principle it's
reflected in the ICJ pulp mills and the
Costa Rica decisions and most recently
you can find it in the general data
protection regulation the gdpr
which in my practice we advise corporate
clients on compliance with this law and
under the gdpr if you engage in a data
project or a some sort of conduct that
may impact the data subject rights under
the gdpr
you must conduct a data impact
assessment and you must document it and
you must provide the results of that
assessment to the individual whose
rights may be impacted so we see this
idea of a procedural impact assessment
being a procedural requirement in a
number of areas of law so how is due
diligence and the precautionary approach
addressed in cyberspace well in my paper
I look at the various aspects in talent
manual 12.0
and the gge reports and I'll go through
this quickly because Mike already
focused on what the talent manual said
Intel Emmanuel one the due diligence
principle was reaffirmed but the
international group of experts could not
achieve consensus on the scope and the
application of that obligation when we
move to Tallinn 2.0 the group of experts
took a more pointed opinion on the
prevention principle which which Mike
spoke about and that is that the
obligation of prevention does not apply
or it is not the Lexx lata and I'm an
agreement with that it's not there's not
sufficient state practice for that but
the reasons why or the cautionary points
in the commentary in Tallinn 2.0 about
why prevention can apply in cyberspace I
think would be addressed by a procedural
due diligence obligation to conduct a
cyber impact assessment perhaps not
equivalent to but similar to an
environmental impact assessment and and
as Mike indicated in the 2013 and 15
reports of the gge they endorsed the due
diligence principle but they use the
word they that's type of it they used it
was more oratory than mandatory and so
it raised the question generally is the
principle of due diligence actually
reflective of customary international
law because states did not endorse it as
a mandatory obligation but they didn't
address the principle of prevention or
the precautionary principle so it leads
me to what is my proposal my proposal is
is that if states as the Lex Rhonda
adopted a cyber impact assessment
requirement as a procedural due
diligence requirement that doesn't
necessarily require them to act in any
particular instance but it requires them
to conduct an annual cyber impact
assessment on their national cyber
infrastructure and if after conducting
that assessment they determine that the
cyber infrastructure is either being
used by third parties or the way it's
conducting its cyber activities may
impact the rights of another state then
the substantive due diligence obligation
to notify the potentially harm state and
potentially take a
remedial actions will be triggered so
it's a procedural obligation that would
only trigger a substantive obligation if
certain findings are made and so the
features of this cyber impact assessment
is I think it should be conducted
annually and one of the things I
struggled with and sort of developing
this idea was how often do you have to
conduct it in the environmental context
an environmental impact assessment is
only conducted once the state undertakes
an industrial activity or some type of
activity that may cause harm to the
other state so it doesn't really apply
in the cyber context you can't really
say a state can only conduct a cyber
impact assessment when they undertake a
cyber project that may impact another
state because the cyber infrastructure
is always developing is always evolving
so I think an annual assessment as a
baseline requirement and a continually
mockin tin yule monitoring requirement
if certain findings are made would be
part of this obligation I think an
existing existing cybersecurity
frameworks could serve as the model for
the cyber impact assessment the the
current cybersecurity frameworks that we
have that we operate within the United
States the NIST framework you have the
ISO standards you have standards issued
by HIPPA there are for example the high
trust Health Trust Alliance develops a
common security framework there are
robust cybersecurity frameworks that
could be used by States to conduct the
cyber impact assessment the Department
of Homeland Security has a very robust
critical infrastructure assessment tool
that's available to industry that they
also use for the for the national
infrastructure and so States are
actually already engaging in these types
of assessments so it wouldn't be - too
far afield to impose this on them or for
them to impose it on themselves and
again action this is the critical point
is that it's a procedural due diligence
requirement it's separating it out and
so action and notice notice to the
potentially impacted state or action to
prevent the what what is found in the
assessment would only be triggered if
the state determines that there's a
reasonable likelihood of harm to the
other state and a question would be well
how do you keep States in check
how do you know that they're actually
going to follow their substantive due
diligence obligations when they're
conducting the assessment themselves
well that's where state responsibility
comes into play that's where a case
before the International Court of
Justice could potentially flesh that out
because under the pulp mills decision
and under the Costa Rica decision the
court made clear that the state
asserting an action under the at the
International Court of Justice bears the
burden of proving that claim by fully
conclusive evidence and the state who's
the defendant or the respondent in the
case has an obligation to provide
evidence to assist in the fact-finding
of the court so in that case in that
scenario the applicant would allege that
the respondent did not follow their
procedural due diligence obligations and
would demand the production of their
cyber impact assessment perhaps under
the review of the court confidential
review of the court and from there they
could prove their case so this again
this is a procedural requirement
importantly the court said and in the
Costa Rica judgment in the 2015 judgment
that the materiality of the assessment
what the assessment is conducted of the
environmental assessment is left up to
the states the domestic law and I think
it could also be left up to bilateral
multilateral treaties again though still
reflecting that the procedural due
diligence is is reflective of custom I
think procedural due diligence would
provide clarity in cyberspace for the
application of due diligence with all
the questions raised by Mike's
presentation I think that could be an
area of a starting point for States and
I do think that it's scalable and
manageable because the cyber impact
assessment that the United States would
conduct would not be the same cyber
impact assessment that Nicaragua would
conduct yet they would be obligated
based on their national capability to
conduct these assessments and to provide
notice and take action where adequate
and I think if that were adopted by
States as the Lexx Fronda not it's not
the Lexx lata if that were adopted I
think it would provide greater teeth to
due diligence in cyberspace thank you
thank you very much Peter and again I
would just as perhaps a bridge between a
Peters talk and caffeine stock that will
immediately follow when Peter talks
about this the the scope of the
obligation to prevent one way of looking
at it is that obligation to prevent
although tempered by all the procedural
considerations implies an obligation of
result now Corinne
on the other hand is going to look at
obligations of conduct and the variable
or the variability factors that the due
diligence principle entails cutting over
to you thank you very much and I'm very
happy to be there today in order to
present you this question of flexibility
and obligation of conduct in due
diligence principle keep in operation
this is in French I will translate it in
English he who can and does not prevent
since this famous legal seeing of the
17th century reflects well what the
principle of due diligence expresses in
the 21st century
toward sovereign states in the
cyberspace to intervene when they know
and they may in order to prevent at
injurious to the right of other states
further principle of international law
due diligence is called today to play a
central role in the regulation of
digital activities especially in the
prevention and reaction to cyber attacks
however a few states and also some
scholars have questions the very
existence of obligation of due diligence
in the cyberspace these objections seem
to be due to a misunderstanding of the
very nature of due diligence which is by
definition an obligation of conduct and
not of result and which implies
variability factors it is true that the
concept of due diligence is a complex
one but the answer to this complexity
can certainly not be to delayed due
diligence from steps of
but to better explain the nature
functions and parameter of this
principle so my presentation will be
twofold
I will first briefly address the
objection concerning the very existence
of due diligence in international law
and in the cyberspace I will then
concentrate on the challenges of the
application of due diligence from both
from the point of view of the behavior
required by state and from the point of
view of the international
responsibilities many objection against
the application of due diligence in the
cyberspace turn around the very
existence of obligation of diligence in
general international law or the
existence in the specific field of
cybersecurity for some due diligence is
only a soft law standard for others
there is no general rule relating to due
diligence that would be applicable in
all fields of international law thus if
one wishes to put forward the existence
of an obligation of due diligence in the
cyberspace it is necessary to provide
proof of a primary rule like a treaty
imposing such obligations in the
cyberspace but this does not exist for
the time being and according to this
objection there is no state practice in
this field however I do not agree with
these objections because if we have a
look to the International jurisprudence
and practice of states in the 19th
century it is very hard if not
impossible to find one field in
international law where due diligence
has not been incorporated moreover it is
uncontested that the obligation of due
diligence applies in the specific field
of the protection of the security of
states because due diligence is founded
on one of the most important obligation
of
international law as was recalled by
Peter and Mike which is every States
obligation not to alone knowingly etc to
be used for are contrary to the rights
of other states there is the stood a
ample evidence that due diligence is a
general principle of international law
which flows from state sovereignty and
that applies in all cases odd field and
all activities due diligence and refers
directly to the responsibility of states
for transboundary harmful acts whether
public or private and irrespective of
the precise nature of the acts in
question whether physical or cyber has
rightly said Italian manual due
diligence is part of the legislature and
as a general principle of international
law due diligence applies also in the
cyberspace moreover as you can see some
states there is now a practice of states
some states have also recognized the
application of the due diligence in the
cyberspace for example France in its
very recent strategic review of cyber
defense published this year has
expressly recognized the application of
due diligence in the cyberspace and it
has also recognized the Associated
concept of cyber diligence used to
describe in one word due diligence
obligation in the cyberspace a concept I
used already and explained in 2014 in a
conference in Tartu under the
supervision of Mike Schmidt and in an
article published in the Baltic yearbook
other objections again do diligence in
the cyberspace are focused on its
application and on what scholars called
the normative indeterminacy of the legal
regime of due diligence according to
them due diligence could only be applied
in the cyberspace
on condition that it be specified and
clarified they also denotes the dangers
of the applique
of the principal arguing that the
responsibility of state could be engaged
every time they are not able to prevent
the occurrence of a now to another state
due to a cyber operation launched from
the territory or transiting through the
territory or infrastructure it is true
in that concept such as due diligence
seem to pertain to what Hart had
described it as the open texture of
legal language but it is also true that
all legal orders of norms that are
imprecise vague and with the texture
that women's very open these norms which
variable content are willingly
introduced by the legislature when you
want to take into account the fact that
is not capable of predicting everything
and setting everything with precision in
advance so an attempt to define
determine specify every norm before
applying it in a specific context would
destroy the inherent flexibility and
adaptability that make the strength of
these norms it divorced them to the
organ of application of the law starting
with judicial codes to detail each
content on a case per case basis and if
we look back to the past it can be
observed that international courts that
have applied the due diligence upholds
for the very first time in entire no new
field of international law such as
neutrality in 1872 or in the environment
in 1941 were not stopped by the
normative indeterminacy of the
obligation of you diligence this juris
pigeons and also the work of the UN
International Commission show that due
diligence is not appraised in abstract
manner various parameters of
vulnerability factors are used when
assessing the obligation of due
diligence it seems that we have in this
field ferment variability factors
knowledge capacity risk and harm so I
don't all the time to read detail here
each of them so just a glimpse and I
have published an article on this
question of who is afraid of cyber
diligence which detailed us these
variability factors so what is important
is to see that in the cyber space
knowledge can raise some legitimate
concerns however it must be recalled
that as the ICJ said the obligation of
due diligence does not imply that states
knows everything that happens on the
territory or under control the degree of
care expected is that of a good
government capacities that do not have
the same capacity in the cyberspace as a
consequence some state could feel that
the obligation of Duty due diligence
could expose them to easily to the
reaction of third state however this
concern must not be always estimated
because capacity is a variety factors
what we accepted by the International
Church and Cyril Hetalia
may be returned to assess this capacity
in concrete Oh
for example economic technical knowledge
etc according to the UN International
County Commission the standard due
diligence against which the conduct of a
state should be a German is proportional
to the degree of the risk and the
International Tribunal for the loss he
found that the standard of due diligence
as to be more severe for the rescuer
activities however not all risk of armed
are covered by the obligation of the
diligence the damage must reach a
certain threshold the tally manual
speaks about serious adverse
consequences why we can find also the
term significant rules by the UN and
iesson or in other judgments
well I will end my presentation with
some words on state responsibility due
diligence could play an important role
in order to circumvent the major problem
of attribution in cyberspace
indeed it is indifferent whether the
acts in question were committed by a
state a non-state actor a proxy the only
thing that matters for due diligence is
to know whether the elements
constituting its violation are present
jesus said no or should it have known
that its infrastructure was being used
to launch a cyber attack causing serious
adverse consequences to another state
had it failed to take the reasonable
measures to prevent the are the answer
to this question are positive the
responsibility for of the states could
be involved
whatever the author of the Acts of
course this does not resolve all the
problems but I'll summarize in the first
strategic review of cyber defense a
state which has not fulfilled this
obligation of conduct good verse in
certain cases until its responsibility
even if it is not the sponsor the fear
now that states responsibilities could
be engaged every time they are not able
to prevent the occurrence of an armed to
another state due to cyber operations
since however highly exaggerated and it
goes against well-established
international case law in all fields and
in all jurisdiction in the GLC versus
Uganda case for instance the ICJ clearly
said that despite the fact that GRC had
been unable to deter attacks launched by
rivers from its territory against Uganda
its responsibility could not be engaged
because GRC has taken all measures at
its disposal in order to prevent the
situation due diligence is an obligation
of count
not off result and so as a result there
are very strong requirements and
condition to engage responsibility for
the failure of true diligence obligation
so as a conclusion I would like to say
first that far from the stabilizing
international law the obligation of due
diligence in cyberspace who could turn
out to be salutary in making States more
responsible without however increasing
international the international
responsibility due diligence could also
make it possible to resolve the problem
of the legal qualification of a cyber
attack and the existential question of
knowing whether or not the cyber attacks
constitute an international wrongful act
instead of putting the emphasis on the
legal qualification of a cyber attack
this principle makes it possible to
focus on what could on what could have
been done by a state and on what the
state did not do this without having to
search whether or not the cyber attack
equation is the action of a state and
without having to search which exact
norm has been violated one could focus
on the fact that the state knew that a
cyber attack had been launched had the
means of acting to prevent a cyber
attack or to stop it and however did
nothing talk to others so returning to
the starting point of this presentation
people in a bash bash he can and does
not prevent since thank you very much
for your attention
and thank you very much cutting and I'm
sure you're already starting to think
about questions I see no hands
immediately up in the air so let me kick
off by asking each of our speakers one
quick question and then I'll ask you to
answer those and then I'm going to open
it to everybody in the audience so maybe
I'll do it in the reverse order
Kadena I found it very interesting in
your you know the star shaped diagram
that you used in the beginning of your
presentation that you except that the
principle of due diligence forms a part
of the Lexx Lata and now we know the
position of the International group of
experts on this but I wonder what your
thoughts are on the UN Gigi being much
more lukewarm much more ambiguous
because even in the 2015 report all that
the group of governmental experts said
was that states should be engaging in
due diligence but there is no must
engage in due diligence and also you
refer to the French position but just
last week we have had the UK attorney
general outline the UK position and due
diligence is noticeably absent from his
remarks so I wonder what your thoughts
on the like slaughter aspect are now
Peter I think Kathleen highlights
something very interesting that feeds
into your presentation and that is that
the biggest bite of this rule is as it
pertains to non-state actors now your
argument primarily focuses on state
operations so if a state engages in this
cyber impact assessment this will be the
impact that it has but what happens if
we have opera cyber operations by
non-state actors that are launched from
a territory of a state can this cyber
impact assessment help against those as
well because arguably this is a bigger
problem in the area of due diligence and
Mike I wonder about your your thoughts
about the following scenario so let's
accept that it's a it's like slaughter
let's accept that it's about non-state
actors now let's suppose that you find
out that a cyber operation is underway
and it is underway against another
statement under your analysis under
certain certain circumstances you have
to notify the other state right so what
if I'm sorry cyber operation from where
to where
so
there is a cyber predator there is a
cyber operation from the territory of
state a that will negatively impact will
impact on the rights of another state
exactly as under your analysis now at
what point does the state need to notify
the other state of this operation if
that would mean that in doing so it
would have to disclose its capabilities
because it has to know somehow but there
it might be a lot of confidentiality and
a lot of uneasiness related to
disclosing those capabilities so that
would be my question but shall we start
with cutting yes thank you so concerning
the last latter and due diligence I
think that first of all we have to see
that since the 19th century there is
such huge practice in this field
application of due diligence in every
field of international law
so it became very difficult to say that
due diligence is not part of the
legislature and of course the question
is why the UN gge said should and not
must this is a good question and I think
that there is some members of the UN Gd
he here that could be better to answer
to this question
but say I think that they should but as
it did not reject the the fact that you
diligence this part of the legislature
says it was not written also and to be
sure that a lot of member of the UN GGE
agreed that due diligence is part of the
legislature so maybe some staff members
obviously against this case maybe as you
UK but I think it's not enough to reject
your the positivity of due diligence the
cyberspace thank you Peter so so the
question is with the cyber impact
assessment address non-state actor
activity and I think it would because
the procedural requirement for the cyber
impact assessment is on the state to
conduct the assessment and what the
assessment will do it will trigger the
knowledge requirement for due diligence
and if the state through their cyber
impact assessment sees that non-state
actors are you
using the cyberinfrastructure then the
due diligence obligation would attach to
the state to try to prevent that
activity and so it that's the advantage
of the procedural aspect is that it
continuously places the obligation on
the state even in the presence of
non-state actor activity which you may
not be able to get state responsibility
for through an attribution model thank
you Mike
did you want us to comment on the other
so you just want us to ask the question
can you maybe now respond to the
question if we have more time we can
then also respond to the others so
actually your question is an easy one
your question is operation from state a
clearly not by the state organs
obviously because this would not
implicate due diligence or rather this
would obligate other primary norms so
it's not by the state and it's
negatively impacting another state and
your question is when is there a need to
notify it's important to understand that
there's never a need to notify the other
state that is suffering the harm unless
that is the only way you can put it into
the operation so we address this very
situation in the manual and we say that
the state must do whatever it can to put
it into the operation and need not
contact the other state because its
obligation is an obligation of conduct
to take feasible measures to put an end
to it so the better question is what
happens if necessarily the state and it
could be with respect to classifications
classified information or whatever what
happens if the impact of taking the
obligation that you have under due
diligence works harm on you on the
state's shouldering the due diligence
obligation and Karen address this
cutting address this very nicely in the
left corner of her triangle and she said
there's a waning of interest so the due
diligence all mitigation is not its
attached if you're going to for example
suffer great harm yourself thank you I
think we can then debate the the
balancing of that but I see already now
a forest of hands so I have a Gary Dan
Theodore and then sattvic Gary I thanks
colonel Gary corn US Cyber Command first
for Peter not Paul nor Mary I just
do names just pee-pee works so let Jeff
talk and there's a thread here Thank You
Michelle and so it starts and so it
starts yeah there's a there's a thread
here to the following question for Mike
and we're carrying it so you said
national cyberinfrastructure I'd be
interested in your definition of that
that can be fairly narrow or very broad
is my home router part of the national
cyber infrastructure that would be
subject to your it you know cyber impact
assessment and I'm absolutely convinced
I'm not an environmental law attorney or
expert but I do think just as you
mentioned even environmental impact
statements within US law and I think
it's probably fairly consistent there's
a balance in those as well it's not that
you know if you find that you will have
some level of harm to the environment
it's an all stop there's a balance of
interests one of the interest national
security another interest is privacy
interests that come to play here which
is I think the elephant in the
due-diligence room and so Mike over to
you you are carrying the the question
there I have is I get that domestic law
is not a relevant factor in your
assessment that's relatively considered
fully consistent with other principles
of application of international law it
does put States in a very difficult
position in this area but also there is
an international law human rights law
component to the very kind of issue at
stake here which is the the sort of
privacy question that looms large in
this area of cyber monitoring and all
these other things which I think
ultimately does distinguish this area
from environmental law or other areas of
law because those don't implicate the
same sort of clash of interests that
this area would would involve so those
are the questions thank you very great
question Mike Oh Gary it's a great
question and it's a like point on
observation we were speaking only about
domestic law to the extent that you have
a prohibition under international law
and the one you
site is the prohibition most likely to
be implicated violation of an
international human rights obligation to
individuals under your effective control
etc etc etc in that case it would not be
feasible as a matter of law for you to
engage in that particular operation
putting it into that operation so unlike
domestic law international human rights
law is a get out of jail free card very
good observation Kathleen did you also
want to respond I wanted to come back to
the question of monitoring because I
think it's a it's a very important
question concerning knowledge and
monitoring and if state of the
obligation you know 2 to 12 constituent
knowledge and it is true that the
question of human rights is an important
one
because we have to be very aware with
the application of the due diligence in
the cyberspace in order you know to
avoid that the due diligence could be a
rod civil liberties and humanitarian law
because of trying to have knowledge
about what's happened on that territory
so from this part it was very
interesting to see also the legal
aspects in the States
it's to answer your question on what
would the cyber infrastructure look like
in those cyber impact assessments it
would be whatever infrastructure objects
persons that are under the sovereign
control of the state either domestically
or overseas outside extraterritorial so
those would be objects that the state
has either enforcement or prescriptive
jurisdiction over under international
law and the states define that it's this
it's exactly what the International
Court of Justice said for the
environmental impact assessments which
is the scope and the nature of that
assessment is defined by the state and
the state's own domestic laws okay so
theater is a theater Christakis the
universe that accounts I have a double
question for Michael but everybody could
love to do that before but it will be an
easy one and I think is the only one
probably here to be able to respond to
this
you ain't silly be the follow-up of your
question we know that at least among the
like-minded group of states in the U n
gga and the international level a lot of
states not only France but several other
states were very very much in favor of
the principle of due diligence in order
to introduce rules of responsible
conduct of states in the cyberspace the
Nordic states I think a lot of states
were in favor of this there were two
states who were reluctant to endorse
this principle the one you mentioned the
UK and especially the United States so
my question is Mike can you please give
us an explanation about this reluctance
of the United States to the due
diligence principle and the second
double question which is linked to the
first one is a following and you hint it
to do this at the end of your speech is
there not an amazing contradiction in
the attitude of the United States on the
one hand they say that there is no
general rule of no general principle of
due diligence and on the other hand they
try to promote an able or unwilling
theory let's forget the unwilling as you
said and let's focus on the unable so
and you and this is something that also
concerned the talent manual regretfully
the Talley manual well not as a rule but
the majority of experts who say endorsed
the enabled unwilling principle which is
regretful because a few months before
the publication of the second edition of
fatal manual 250 professors of
international law all over the world
including authorities like Rajab Assad
Martin Goscinny and many others signed
the petition and guess the abusive
invocation of self-defense in cyberspace
in order precisely to focus on this
issue of the nebular ruling theory the
risks that it entails and the fact that
it's not part of the leg slit so my
question is can we say at one hand there
is no obligation to prevent no due
dilligence obligation and on the other
hand say that you have the right to bump
a state which is unable to prevent I
think that there's something incoherent
there Thank you very
you know you're giving him an easy way
out because he can just say he's not
representing the US here of course but
if there is somebody who could have
knowledge about the answer I think it's
Mike Mike so you know I'm just a simple
country lawyer from South Texas I don't
make you as policy amigo okay so I can't
answer the first question I do not want
answered in the context of the United
States or United Kingdom because we
discussed this question ad nauseum has
part of the Tal and manual process the
government of the Netherlands have three
meetings with state representatives
delegations some of whom were in this
room and we were operating Chatham House
Rules so I can only tell you what the
objection was not which state was
involved in the object which states were
involved in the objection but the
objection was a reasonable one here's
what one delegate said to me a person
who I have extraordinary respect for has
an international lawyer the individual
said to me this due diligence obligation
you don't understand what this means for
us this is an extraordinary obligation
to take on our shoulders because every
single day we're not talking about an
obligation of prevention we're talking
about every single day from our
territory thousands and thousands and
thousands of operations that are hostile
to other states particularly if you buy
into the rule of sovereignty which this
individual did in which I do too he's
how in the world do we shoulder that
obligation and that was a fair comment
that's it's nice for some small state
that doesn't have a lot of operations
mounted to say Kumbaya you guys got to
protect me out there but when you're a
big territory and lots of bad stuff is
happening on your territory that's a
mighty heavy burden to shoulder my
response was we need to understand what
we're saying what we the manual and this
is why we were so very conservative
it affects rights not interests rights
not interest you got a cite a legal
right it has serious adverse
consequences you have to demonstrate
knowledge on and on and on it has to be
feasible feasible takes into account
your capabilities and as my friend Gary
feasability takes into account your
other international legal obligations so
we we said to these individuals I'm a
believer in due diligence awfully we
said you need to understand we're not
asking for much we're just we are will
be conservative and this doesn't put
much on your shoulders I do know in a
number of states that this is an ongoing
discussion I'm not a party to the
discussion I happen to believe that what
we set forth and not by the way the
preventive principle is a fair
reflection of the law and as I travel
around I see a lot of states that are
very supportive of this but we have to
watch yeah you're a law professor I'm a
law professor guess what we don't make
law States make law with regard to the
unwilling and able test boy you really
poked me in the eye there so I'm a big
advocate of I've written for years years
in support of the unwilling and able
test and international law and this is
the way it works for me in the unwilling
and able test we have clashing rights in
international law you have the right of
sovereignty which protects the the state
into which the operation is being
conducted you also have the right of
self-defense
these two rights are among the most
important rights that we find in
international law and in these cases
clearly they come into conflict so there
are those scholars and they and I'm not
among them who say it's a binary choice
they win sovereignty wins or
self-defence wins I don't agree with
that I believe that when you have
conflicting rights in international law
it fosters international peace and
security to find a reasonable
accommodation of these rights the most
reasonable so you know my writings on
this subject I although I say there is
an unwilling enable test I go on and on
and on about the limitations placed
there on for example in and out as
quickly as possible avoid collateral
damage Bubba now we're here to talk
about due diligence in the due diligence
situation we adopted only the unable I'm
sorry unwilling that open that that
causes a breach because here we don't
have this clash of the giants of
international law principles
we have a state that's suffering less
used usually less harmful operations and
we're not really in a way were affecting
the sovereignty of the state would do
diligence but not in the way that you
are when you conduct a drone operation
and kill someone in their country so we
said in this particular case we did not
feel that the logic that applied in with
respect to the majority in our group
visa vie self-defense the logic applied
has cleanly here and because we were
taking a conservative approach we
because of the pushback of states we
listened the states because we were
taking a conservative approach we
decided to stick with the only when a
state is unwilling and we would not
impose we would not say you're breaching
an international law obligation when you
don't have the ability to comply with it
makes sense glad I've convinced you
thank you Mike
next on you and we can continue the
discussion afterwards definitely we have
a few minutes left and two questions
still in the queue so it's said leak and
then lay oh and I think I'm afraid that
will be the end of our time Cedric
one question for Mike and one for Peter
where's the question coming from here ah
okay hi hello
so one we've had this discussion before
and it's still not clear to me exactly
where you stand on this you've said at
the beginning that due diligence give
something to States which is the ability
to take countermeasures if the other
state privilege a non-state actors
operating right does not take feasible
measures now this is helpful when the
state is unwilling but if the state is
willing and unable what then would be
under your construction the available
tools for the victim state that's one
question and the question for Peter it's
something about your proposal it's not
clear to me as Mike initially pointed
out when we talk about preventive
due diligence and the all the scenarios
that he's given it's scenarios where
there's a non-state actor using the
servers of some country to conduct an
attack and in the two ICJ the most
recent ICJ cases didn't if in the field
of environmental law in both cases as
far as I remember it was cases where the
country on its own is building something
and it's starting something that it
knows or should know you could say will
cause transboundary harm so how does
that fit exactly with the scenarios that
Mike was giving and I admit these are
the scenarios that I have in mind when
when I think about due diligence where
it's not the states that on its own is
doing something because that would be a
cyber operation but rather that against
its will its servers are being used so
how would you apply the the impact
assessments to those cases and so the
the red clock of death is telling us
that we have one minute left so with
apologies to layer I think we will have
to park that question until the coffee
break and with an eye on the organizers
Tomas can we eat five minutes into the
coffee break yeah so I'm going to give
you each about two minutes to respond if
you could do that Mike yeah so I'm not
convinced that you don't understand my
answer I'm pretty convinced you don't
like my answer because we've had this
discussion before listen we took the
view the countermeasures are under the L
of unavailable against non-state actors
so let's look at a situation where
there's no breach of due diligence
non-state actors are in another states
territory acting what can you do Steph
one Rhetor ssin against that state that
caused that state to round them up
cooperative law enforcement sanctions
etc etc etc that's obvious now you have
a bit of a gap the next step here is the
plea of necessity the plea of necessity
under article 25 of the articles of
state responsibility say that if you're
a central interest are being affected in
a grave and imminent way then you may
take actions into the other territory
even though the other territory has
nothing to do with it it is not in
breach of any obligation owed you the
problem here my friend is that we have
to get pretty high
central interest and I think you
understand that and of course if you
have an armed attack you know my view
very well my view is that non-state
actors can commit armed attacks there
isn't out four states we weren't
preaching to States we were committed to
providing all of the options for States
that was our that was our Charter and so
when we went to The Hague at leas V Hall
and I were at The Hague talking to
States in the sessions a view was
expressed that says you may take
countermeasures against actions by
non-state actors in fact some of the
same advocates also said that non-state
actors can violate sovereignty so as you
look at the manual it's for states to
decide what's the right view we put that
view in there although none of the
experts agreed with this we acknowledge
the existence of such a view and so when
I look out at the ambassador and other
representatives of states I'm not
telling you what what to choose all I
wanted to do is lay out the options so
if your state is concerned about that
option I would recommend that you adopt
the view that you may take
countermeasures against non-state actors
and then your problem solved every
problem is solved in the little green
book okay do minutes exactly well done
Mike Peter so you're correct that impact
assessments in environmental law are
limited to the state's activities I'm
proposing a broader approach because of
the nature of cyber attacks and cyber
issues in that the state has to conduct
an annual cyber assessment that would
include a review of third party
non-state actor activity if it becomes
known to the state through that
assessment so this is a broader
assessment than what would be required
under international environmental law
and only when the state gains knowledge
through that assessment of a particular
type of potential use of the cyber
infrastructure and what the threshold
for harm would be what the threshold for
response would be is a separate question
this is just at the outset the baseline
procedural obligation is to conduct the
assessment and from there they can
derive the knowledge and I would just
say a general comment on is due
diligence reflective of customary
international law I think due diligence
is reflective of customary international
law period and that international law
principles apply in cyberspace and
tell States agree otherwise and develop
a lek specialis that basically withdraws
themselves from that general principle
so if you're not a persistent objector
to the due diligence principle and you
don't develop with other states elect
specialist that carved yourself out of
the due diligence principle I think it
applies to you in cyberspace I don't
speak on you have any government but
that's my that's my position
thank you Peter and so as you can see we
haven't exhausted our speakers we
haven't exhausted the questions we
haven't exhausted the topic but we have
exhausted our time and so it would be a
violation of due diligence on my part
and I would suffer serious adverse
consequences from the organizers if I
didn't draw a line here so please
welcome me and join me in congratulating
our speakers thank you