yet another Seiken we are talking about
norms so we have been talking about the
norms I think the past five years we
have had specific workshops focusing on
norms specific panels specific books so
this topic kind of keeps on giving
we don't we are not exhausted from this
topic and and hopefully you won't be
exhausted either after this session and
I was very very glad to see the set up
for for this session because we have a
very interesting mix of people I would
say you have this ideal set up we have
an international organization
representative we have a speaker from
the government and we have a speaker
from academia so we have very
interesting different views and it will
be very nice to see how it plays out and
first a couple of words or norms before
we get to the first speaker so I'm sure
you're very you're very well-informed
about the latest developments and our
speakers will give you a heads up I
would just want to point out that if we
say norms depending from our background
we may talk about different things so
from for lawyers we talk about
international law norms which are
legally binding for example you would
have the initiative of code of conduct
that was proposed by by several states
proposing a multilateral treaty or norms
however in the UN gge context we will
talk about politically binding voluntary
norms and we will have several comments
on the UN Gigi process coming up from
the speakers and in addition to legally
binding norms politically binding norms
we today will also talk about domestic
level norms and how to best harmonize
these approaches between different
states so I'm looking forward to these
discussions we start off with with mr.
ban Hitler from OSCE offering us
hopefully positive understanding on the
way ahead regarding norms thank you
thank you very much for inviting us to
contribute to this session and to this
topic
my name is Ben Hillier I'm the OC cyber
security officer and the OCE
is not always well known what it is but
it is essentially the largest regional
security organization spending almost
entire northern hemisphere with 57
participating states and we came into
existence in the 70s as a platform for
dialogue between east and west and our
founding documents the Helsinki final
act which nowadays has some sort of
revival given the security situation in
Europe now the session as we heard
addresses tribal norms and where the
debate is heading and I'm very grateful
for you to point out that when we talk
about cyber norms we often understand
different things I'm coming at it from
an international policy perspective or
when I hear norms I understand
norm self responsible state behavior in
cyberspace a very much interpretation
the UN group of governmental experts put
on it and and also you know the work of
the UN Gigi and where it is heading and
I think we all agree that looking at
recent developments at the UN gge we
need some fresh thinking of where we are
going and where you know this non
consensus has left us and what to do
next I think it's also fair to say that
we are observing how international cyber
policy dialogue has very much stalled
and I'm talking here about between non
like-minded States adversaries have or
seem to have little confidence in
international negotiations or
international platforms and little faith
in finding constructive solutions at the
moment and what we witnessed I think at
the gge is that rather than promoting
dialogue we saw States to gain the heels
and the national positions hardening
often coming back to positions that are
long held and focusing very much on
scoring maybe points rather than
engaging in in good faith
but I think that's not surprising I mean
given the current state of cyber fairs
it's very much reflective of the wider
international political environment
recent events are creating an
environment of unease defensiveness and
inwardness and the question is how to
move on from this paralysis and I chose
this title for a reason it is a nod to
Sir Ian Carey Codd art who is a Danish
writer social critic and religious
author and he introduced the concept of
the qualitative leap of faith taking a
leap of faith when a thought process
constraints you so much that you are
ultimately not able to carry out the
planned activity when you too much
dealing with processes rather than
without come and I believe this is
exactly what is needed in the global
norms debate and mechanisms that are
associated risk reduction mechanisms to
reduce the potential conflict stemming
from the use of cyber capabilities so
the larger context matters when it comes
to cyber policy negotiations and me
before we go into the knee credly just a
reminder what is happening currently and
I would say we are living in an
extraordinary time when it comes to
international security clearly the DNC
hacks without any doubt had a major
impact on pretty much any cyber related
activities since then it's set the
discourse the Ukraine conflict something
my organization is very much engaged
with and trying to monitor it remains
one of the most contentious issues in
Europe Russia's military exercise set
was a reminder that trust building does
not work in an environment of constant
provocation and expression of power the
refugee crisis and the Syrian war are a
continuous challenge for citizens
diplomats and military experts and of
course
China's Island building activities in
the South China Sea represents a
significant geopolitical shift in the
Pacific and there's of course the Iran
deal Kim Jong Un's
efforts due to nuclear weapons
negotiations that are on and off and on
and off both are contributing to
environment of little trust and
confusion and there of course many many
more incidents and two things that are
happening so clearly we're living in a
tense world and relations between states
are at best shaky at the moment we are
observing a global strategic shift at no
state has complete control over this
process and even states that are willing
to engage diplomatically in good faith
are having clear limitations be it
because of domestic politics or foreign
policy limitations or overlapping
strategic priorities or quite simply
because the counterpart is not willing
to listen anymore over all the problems
it can be messy and it's sometimes quite
astounding to see that we accomplished
anything at all especially also in the
cyber policy domain I think this is
something we cannot underestimate given
current developments and this is
something I want to hold high especially
a panel when we talk about norms and
cyber security cyber diplomacy is very
much tied to broader geopolitical trends
and we cannot understand the challenges
at the UN or the OSCE
ERF or as without looking at what
happened lately now having spent so much
time talking about non cyber events let
us look at what happened on the UN level
regarding cyber security and this is not
news to many of you the UN jiejie
reports now we all know that there was
no consensus in 2017 so I will not delve
into why this potentially was because
there's plenty of literature about it in
the open instead I want to talk about
the components that were confirmed and
are and were agreed on through the 2015
UN GG report because these components
are still valid and should guide our
behavior now if you overly critical a
narrow look at the report might lead you
to think that this talk
does not really add much to the
international policy debate but when you
look at the agreement from a wider angle
this is actually quite impressive that
states were able to chart a way forward
in terms of global cyber stability by
focusing on a four pillar approach and
these four pillars of course is
clarifying international law response
norms of responsible state behavior in
cyberspace confidence-building measures
capacity building and international
cooperation but I think what is
important here is not to look at these
four pillars in isolation and this is
something unfortunately which is often
the case when it comes to international
conferences norms alone and in itself
will not create the sort of stable
cyberspace
we are all aiming for and I sometimes
feel that the other elements of the GG
reports are somewhat not considered in
as much as norms but clearly it's
important to implement all four
components in tandem because there's a
reason there are four components for
instance what happens if norms and rules
are broken this happens every day you
can have the best to the clarification
on international law and how it applies
we know that states break it every day
what happens then
well then you need practical measures to
address those digressions you need the
communication channels between states
between the right people to either
prevent escalation or to address the
issue and to I guess punish the state
that digresses now this is what the CBMs
come in this is exactly the focus of
practical confidence-building measures
but equally if the state doesn't have
the capacity to engage in responsible
state behavior or to establish or
implement practical measures to reduce
potential tensions then they cannot
contribute to this process so this is
where capacity building is coming in and
that's the third pillar and again all
elements have to be implemented in
tender
but is this the case at the moment I'm
not too sure for me personally currently
there's a real appetite for norms be
proposals for new norms on the state
level norms for industry norms
regulating state and installations norms
for civil society and it seems that
there's a lot of push for norms and
everyone is in the game the positive
side of this proliferation of the norms
debate is that international style
policy issues certainly have become
mainstream it's not anymore an issue
just for the technical folks it is a
policy issue and all other sectors that
are affected thinking about it so the
multi-stakeholder approach and model is
very much alive
but the key question is do these
discussions and processes make an impact
on cyber stability between states and
what is the uptake by governments and
I'm looking at the NAS debate from a
cyber stability perspective and the
connected question is what happened to
the measures that were actually agreed
at the UN and the OSCE and elsewhere are
we making progress here and are they
being implemented we threw out to the
first question my personal view is that
it is getting quite challenging and I'm
in enough negotiations between 57 States
for policy makers to figure out key
priorities within cyber diplomacy given
a lot of noise around the issue I
observe how they can become distracted
by ever more catchy proposals even
though most of these proposals have
little to no chance of ever getting
sufficient governmental recognition on a
global scale with regard to the second
question I might hold also a very
unpopular view but I believe that the
key emphasis at the moment given the
extraordinary times we're in should be
place and implementing what has been
agreed or clarifying
what has been a great this means state
should focus on implementing in
operationalizing agreed-upon norms and
CBMs and capacity-building they should
use existing diplomatic for to highlight
when agreements are broken and develop a
set of consequences in case of
non-compliance of norms discussions I
believe need to become more nuanced
streamlined and channeled into the right
structures and I believe what the CC
ture is doing on the Tallinn manual but
also recent you know da kind of guidance
material in terms of clarifying
international law or how to implement
norms of responsible state behavior it's
a very good demonstration of how this
can be done it helped States enormous ly
to hear the view of academia and
non-governmental experts on the thinking
all of those experts how these measures
can be implemented I think we should
reflect on which norms agreements
regulations are actually crucial for the
maintenance of peace and stability among
states at this very point in time if a
norm at hand does not fit to this
description maybe it is better at the
time to put it on the back burner and
what I'm saying here is mean to be
honest about what actually matters at
this moment quality should be placed
over quantity now that leads me to the
often cited challenge that we are trying
to deal with the 21st century challenge
through a 20th century framework and
institutions absolutely we are I
couldn't agree more
however while for some issues such as
international industry certification a
multi-stakeholder approach makes a lot
of sense negotiations on international
security efforts have taken place in
inter governmental fora for many decades
and for good reason I understand that
this is not appreciated by many it is
backward in some way
but it remains effect on the ground that
will not change anytime soon we're not
going to abolish these institutions that
will continue being the prime fora for
international security and peace but as
link instead is the key objective should
be to parse out what the vast amount of
topics within the Snipe security
umbrella and identify existing fora for
each issue who's doing what best and who
should be dealing with the what global
institutions like the UN or the OSI on
the region level like mud entities and
for that facilitate dialogue among non
like men estates all have their value
and need to look at their added value
and what we need to do is to maximize
the effect an impact of existing
platforms by using the right platform
for the respective topic at hand and I
believe we are not making it too bad job
of it
and this understant goes very much
against the general notion that
everything is bad at the moment I
disagree this also means that we need to
keep in mind that there are windows of
opportunities that come and go in cycles
this has always in the case and it will
continue to be the case if at times
negotiations are stalled in one
particular forum it can make sense to
wait and pursue another pathway or
another topic for a while instead of
pushing for a deal within a context that
is not conducive to meaningful outcome
now by matching topics with the right
for one also needs to consider
stakeholders well for some issues as I
said before private sector or civil
society engagement is key cyber
stability negotiations between states
might not benefit as much from this
input now let me be very clear I do not
mean to say that their input is not
needed but a significant amount of
states will simply disagree that
non-governmental stakeholders sit on the
negotiation table states sovereignty is
not gone in the age of the internet and
states will make sure that this message
is understood whether we like it or not
and of course this is not something the
Western world is very keen on understand
that but I do not see that a state
Russia or China will change the tune
anytime soon in the end of the day a
related question is also whether we
really have the time to spare to
negotiate new all inclusive institutions
and platforms given that we already
struggling to agree on norms voluntary
norms before we even get to finish what
we have started we simply do not have
the luxury to ponder on processes and
platforms in the light of increasing
number of cyber incidents that threaten
to impact on international peace and
security
I believe now's the time to get on with
implementing agreed measures and serious
cyber stability negotiations in
established formats and this is a task
of course that is already difficult
enough given shifting priorities by
States and blurred policy priorities in
between them I love this picture
[Laughter]
now I rushed through a vast set of
issues ranging from geopolitical tension
strategic shift stalled international
negotiations etc etc the question is how
can States maneuver through all this
without creating even more damage the
diminishing faith in international
institutions negotiation and conflict
prevention is real concern for all of us
but the fact is diplomacy has always
been the marathon rather than a sprint
but in the end the agreements that have
brokered in Vienna Geneva New York and
Brussels and elsewhere are designed to
stay they will shape how future
generations of negotiators will frame an
issue maybe even how a potential treaty
on cyber security will look like in the
very long term but in order to get there
all states need to consider whether
their international engagements can
really be labeled as constructive and I
mean all states once you combine
constructive engagement with a decent
amount of good faith the rate of
diplomatic success even if it's just on
small scale will pick up and why do
small achievements even met at this
point if we had the brink of sigh
or as some claim we are well we need to
take the few islands of cooperation that
do exist seriously and keep building
from them progress and agreements might
be small and look benign at the
beginning granted but they do contain
the potential for more sophisticated and
complex agreements in the years to come
now from the OSI perspective this is why
we keen and states are keen to
operationalize both CBMs that have been
agreed on by all 57 including Russia the
US EU and many Asian states because we
believe that is the right way to address
less contentious issues between states
and ultimately contribute to the
establishment of mechanisms that create
a certain routine and behavior between
states and what that means in practical
we're currently designed to set up a
communications network for decision
makers that can be used during cyber
crisis and once in place all 57 states
will have the opportunity to pick up
that red phone to call others to
de-escalate potential tensions now
admittedly after two days here what i'm
saying doesn't sound very exciting I'm
sorry
kind of continue what we have started no
new big regimes no new platforms etc etc
but the fact is we need to build on
those islands where the big cyber powers
have agreed on a need to build from
there and this will not be done by
proposing a model that we ultimately
know the other side will not accept
simply because the fact is focusing on
agreed measures will keep channels open
and focus on practical cooperation and
has the best chance to depoliticize
the debate from which we can build on
for more grander and bigger things later
on so this effort is not about reaching
the same speed or level of technology
developments this is something that
often is said you know technology is
outpacing what we can
in diplomacy and how we wrecked it's
true we will never catch up and that's
my person but what we need to make sure
is that the core pillars of state
responsibilities are prepared for what's
to come
beat artificial intelligence or even
know connected world we cannot win the
race against technology but we need to
focus on the essential and build on
islands that make sense and that ladies
and gentlemen requires a leap of faith
given the current political and
international environment and this is my
call to do that leap of faith and to
finish what has been started thank you
very much thank you very much Ben and I
can really hear the first-hand
experience in cyber diplomacy echoing
that from your your your words we will
take all the presentations in a row so
keep your questions write them down
don't forget them and we'll then open
the floor to questions after all three
talks so please without further ado mr.
Cedric Saba from Israeli Minister of
Justice who will offer a different
perspective on how to develop cyber nars
I'm also sorry who mentioned that we all
look like cyborgs thanks very much it's
an honor to be here I'm not sure how
different that's gonna be I've found
myself listening to Ben and agreeing
with much of what he says so I hope it's
not gonna be too redundant or repetitive
for you guys so being a lawyer I of
course need to start with a disclaimer
which is that the views i express here
are completely my own and they don't
reflect the views of my employer the
Israeli Ministry of Justice or the
Israeli government in general actually I
have several more disclaimers to make
but I'll raise these as I go along
so the subject of cyber norms has
generated quite a bit of discussion in
recent years particularly after the
publication of the UN Gd report of 2015
prominent academics cybersecurity
experts in the field the cyber security
experts have to have discussed these
issues at
analyzing the ways in which norms
existing norms could be implemented new
norms could be developed which forums
are appropriate to discuss which norms
and the sense of excitement and promise
that existed after the 2015 report
subsided somewhat in 2017 when it was
reported that the subsequent ung GE did
not reach consensus but despite this
apparent setback the topic of cyber
norms is still very much in the on the
international agenda the question that I
started with is where are we headed with
cyber norms and it seemed to me from
multiple discussions that I was having
was that there exists a gap has been
pointed out between let's say the
initial excitement and promise between
of cyber norms and their actual
implementation by States in practice I
believe that the potential pitfall in
the current norms discussion is there
over emphasis on global stability norms
that aspire to foster a peaceful secure
ICT environment what I'd like to submit
and this is the focus of my presentation
is as follows one that in the current
state of play crafting norms with a goal
of global stability as their primary
focus might be somewhat ambitious to a
more modest objective might be within
reach by paying greater attention to a
different kind of discussion going on
right now namely international
cooperation in the field of civilian
cyber security things like information
sharing between the public and private
sector software patching regulation of
cyber physical systems and our argue
that these types of discussions which
are already happening to varying degrees
can actually contribute to security in a
pragmatic way and three the process
matters just as much as the content and
the promising the most promising way I
think to forge norms that stick is not
by positing the existence of a norm and
then trying to implement them but rather
by empowering civilian cyber security
officials and policy makers across the
world those who device policy and also
those who
mitigate cyber incidents in real-time to
engage with one another in a practical
way and only then can we begin to make
out the contours of possible norms so
this is essentially a bottom-up approach
in this presentation I'll elaborate on
each of these three points for the sake
of good order I'll adopt a very general
definition of norms taken from a recent
article by Duncan Hollis shared
expectations about appropriate or
inappropriate behavior within a given
community so in the current state of
play what do we have when reading the UN
GDP report of 2015 and particularly the
part about cyber norms their intended
focus on global stability really stands
out you have your just a few excerpts
where the word stability peaceful comes
up very often now some of these norms I
would argue are rather generic or
abstract for example the norm that
states cooperate with one another the
norm providing that states adopt good
cybersecurity practices however other
norms revolve around cyber operations
for example the norm that prescribes
States attacking and other states
critical critical infrastructure or
another state cert we've had we've heard
about other norms being suggested after
the 2015 gge such as the prohibition to
manipulate financial data which
reputable think-tank advanced not too
long ago the prohibition to protect the
core not to attack the core elements of
Internet infrastructure such as the
domain name system and if we expand the
definition of norms a little bit further
we could also talk about norms aimed at
interpreting how International applies
to cyberspace for example the data tempt
to define sovereignty in cyberspace
jurisdiction the definition of use of
force armed attack under the law of
armed conflict effort said clarifying
the rules of attribution so to be sure
these are all fundamental questions and
they are very concrete implications for
States all these kinds of norms will
present efforts whether by States or
organizations or academics to make the
world a safer place by clarifying the
rules of the road so to speak
setting red lines and what these norms
have in common I think is one they're
expressly designed to foster global
and to they approach the core of
national security how a state operates
in its defensive mission these two
points are related of course you can't
talk about global stability without
talking about how a state uses its power
however this is also what makes cyber
norms and a deal with global stability
challenging to implement in practice
norms on global stability has been
pointed out invariably involve complex
issues of international relations
geopolitics national defence and
international trade
there are also fundamentally different
conceptions about information
communication technologies what the role
of government with respect to ICT should
be this has been one of the enduring
questions since John Perry Barlow the
Declaration of Independence of
cyberspace and what this means for how
international law applies to ICTs for
example we heard last week from the UK
Attorney General who in a landmark
speech seemed to be suggesting I think
he was saying it quite clearly that
sovereignty is not a legal rule echoing
the writings of Gary corn from US Cyber
Command I don't want to open up this
particular debate but it's illustrative
of the real conceptual challenges that
countries are still grappling with which
make it difficult for states to achieve
a real meaningful common understanding
on these big questions at least at this
point in time states are going about
this incrementally very carefully and
rather slowly another challenge is the
technological one now it's redundant to
say that technology is evolving rapidly
and I don't think that this should be an
excuse to not try to understand how law
of lies to existing technology but we
must still be aware that the challenge
posed by evolving technology is real
aside from the current the difficulty in
categorizing existing technologies and
grappling with existing issues like
security for the Internet of Things and
on the cloud we have emerging texts such
as AI quantum computing which could be
real game changers and states are
understandably reluctant to move too
quickly on norms or a law for that
matter in those circumstances so how do
we go about forging cyber norms in these
limitations
well in the 2000 2015 GGE
we saw norms that were abstract and that
are drafted in a constructively
ambiguous manner sorry
for example the norm about the norm
about protecting the integrity of the
supply chain and we also saw norms that
are more specific but also more
aspirational for example the norm not to
attack critical infrastructure and that
results in norms existing on paper but
not really achieving their purpose of
influencing state practice so allow me
to make my second disclaimer here and
which is that all this is not meant at
all out of Chris as a criticism of the
2015 gge
or norris baking efforts in general and
I don't see the lack of consensus in the
2017 gge as a failure either nor do I
mean to suggest that we shouldn't be
trying to achieve global stability the
2015 GG achieved something very
meaningful if contributed to the
international conversation we saw it in
Dorst by the GA the g7 g20 and the idea
of conceptualizing something as a cyber
norm sorry as a norm rather than
international law provides a certain
flexibility to States and also a way for
states to agree about something without
having to commit in a firm way so
without being naive about it the drive
towards peace and stability should
always inform our course of action but
three years later I think the
international community can and should
assess where we are at this stage and
whether continuing on the exact same
trajectory is bearing the expected fruit
in my view if we stay overly focused on
crafting global stability type norms we
might lose it out on another opportunity
that is right for further developments
and that's in the field of civilian
cybersecurity so I'll define here cyber
security in a rather narrow sense the
policies and actions taken by a state to
protect eight computers and its networks
it's critical infrastructure and also
the computers and networks of
organizations within its jurisdiction
and mitigate attacks on a technical
level I'm influenced here by the setup
we have in Israel where we have the
cyber Directorate which is a sole
purpose agency that is separate from the
Defense Forces
other security agencies and it has a
basic mission which is acting through
regulation law policies it operates in a
highly transparent manner in cooperation
with the public and private sector
organizations and all this is in order
to promote basic robustness of
organizations because ultimately the
cyber batterer battlefield is in their
networks these organizations are the
first line of defense other countries
have taken their own approach and we
have certs in the US and the EU and I
think we can confidently assert that at
this stage cybersecurity has evolved and
matured into its own discipline the
issues that cybersecurity officials
across the world are facing are diverse
and often they're more technical and
specific than these big picture global
stability world peace issues that most
cyber norms efforts thus far have dealt
with for example the challenges of
information sharing between the public
and private sectors fostering trust
between stakeholders what should be the
role of the states and the appropriate
level involvement in this ecosystem how
does a shirt assert collecting
information on a cyber incident address
privacy concerns how can a government
ensure that it's data that is stored on
the cloud in servers located abroad
remain secure breach incident reporting
requirements bug bounty programs for the
public and private sector active defense
for private sector organizations best
practices for governments and
organizations and this is before we get
into more industry specific
cybersecurity questions such as in the
field of energy banking securities etc
so these are all represent actual
concrete policy questions and challenges
that cyber policymaker makers across the
world are facing or will be facing in
the near future while each of these
topics is important
domestically not each of them weren't
necessarily a big international
discussion and in some cases they're
already discussions going on but some of
them might be right for some
internationalization so to speak for
example and I'm not suggesting this as a
specific norm but the question of
anonymize anonymization of data when
data is collected for
[Music]
analysis by the cybersecurity agency how
do we ensure that it remains anonymous
and that no privacy breach is occurs and
so here we have a space for a robust
discussion between cyber security
officials and privacy experts now all of
these four topics are indeed part of
national security they're not global
stability issues when civilian cyber
security officials discussed these
topics for the most part they're not
trying to solve world peace they're
discuss their discussions tend to be
focused on more discreet policy
questions taken together they can
contribute to making the world more safe
and secure which is consistent with the
ultimate goal of cyber norm activists
but it's not expressly placing global
stability as the ultimate goal now I
acknowledge there's no clear demarcation
line between global stability and
civilian cyber security I think you can
imagine these along a spectrum but some
of these are clearly close more closely
related to global stability and others
are closer to the civilian cyber
security side so the next step in the
analysis is to look into the ways in
which the focus on cyber security topics
could fit within the subarray norms
discussion so as I mentioned cyber
security officials are already having
discussions on certain issues first the
network of certs is discussing a lot of
these things we've seen the OECD tackle
some aspects of cyber security such as
best practices for governments and
organizations for cyber security risk
management they're increasingly
bilateral agreements at different levels
of government and to trial the UN
Commission on international trade law
has begun to address cloud computing
contracts including for government
procurement several bodies are
discussing standards for IOT so these
discussions happen are happening in
different ways at the same time I think
what's missing here is two things one is
that the technical bottom bottom-up
discussion that I'm referring to seems
to be disconnected from the global cyber
norm efforts and the two is that there
are many other issues some of which
have been addressed by some really
fascinating policy papers that have not
yet graduated to the level of
international discussions for example
privacy and cybersecurity active defense
in the private sector or software
labeling so to think about moving the
discussion forward I think it's useful
to look at some case studies one is the
norm for bidding cyber theft industrial
cyber theft it didn't make its way into
the DGE but it did end up in the
us-china agreement of 2015 it was
replicated by Canada so this to me
suggests that this bilateral approach
stemming from specific concrete problems
that a country is facing has promise for
future nor making efforts they weren't
attempting to solve world peace just
dealing with a domestic issue most
reports suggest that this norm was
largely successful in curbing industrial
cyber theft and if these reports are
accurate this would suggest that this
type of an approach can work in practice
in other cases as well another example
is the cybercrime Budapest Convention
it's not a norm but a full-fledged
treaty and here it wasn't just a
bottom-up approach based on the needs of
the police and prosecution officials but
also it requires some top-down help from
the capital level we've heard yesterday
I think discuss discussions about
another possible US EU agreement on
sharing data for law enforcement
purposes the extension of the Microsoft
case another example is that the most
recent IGF there were two interesting at
least two interesting panels that dealt
with this type of issue one was about
diplomacy and looking into how certs can
take a greater role in the international
conversation another one that I was
involved with from afar so full
disclosure dealt with how we could
leverage the multi-stakeholder model for
domestic cybersecurity policy making and
one interesting points that emerge from
that last panel was how the NIST
framework which was developed by the
NTIA is being used and implemented by
other countries so here it's not a norm
but it's a best practice document that
is
actually having an impact outside of its
borders so what conclusion do we reach
from these case studies I think it's
that there isn't a one-size-fits-all
solution every topic requires its own
approach
one thing is clear to me at least is
that the focus shouldn't be on
necessarily on more forums more norms
norms shouldn't be forced to forced or
declared into existence in the abstract
rather they should be allowed to emerge
organically bottom-up based on actual
needs and challenges faced by civilian
cyber security officials in some cases
the end result might not be cyber norms
per se but shared understandings or
short taxonomy best practices guidelines
the agreements might be bilateral
multilateral they might be between
like-minded countries only or something
more global the point is that instead of
trying to define the agenda in advance
it would be more useful at this stage to
empower and expand upon the discussions
happening between cyber security
officials one last point I started with
a disclaimer and I'll end with one this
is not at all intended to deny the role
of cyber diplomacy on the contrary cyber
cyber diplomacy is crucial here because
sometimes pure technical discussions
between cyber security officials will
not be enough in order for the process
to move forward you need the the support
from the push from the the top-down that
complements this bottom-up approach the
Budapest Convention and the us-china
agreement on cyber theft
I think are examples of that in short I
think there are different bilateral and
multilateral models that could be
explored depending on the circumstances
and the needs of cybersecurity officials
and if we can shift the focus of the
discussion on cyber norms to give to pay
greater attention to those needs we
could be contributing to cyber security
in a very concrete way thanks again and
I look forward to your questions
[Applause]
thank you very much Cedric for the for
the interesting perspective on the
bottom-up approach and why we need to
take into account all these different
new ideas as well on the diplomatic and
state level next up will be Professor
Jeff cosas from u.s. Naval Academy and
who will be introducing the idea of
putting more focus on developing
domestic laws great well thank you so
much for having me and to follow up with
Cedric I have some disclaimers of my own
I should have this memorized by now the
views that I expressed today are only my
own and don't represent the US Naval
Academy the Department of Navy or the US
Department of Defense or anyone else as
you hear what I'm gonna say you'll see
what that's particularly important
because I usually say something that
people strongly disagree with but the
and what's really important here and
this really is following up a lot on
what Cedric said I just met him
yesterday but we seems like we have been
thinking about this problem quite on the
same wavelength and that is the
discussions that we've been having for a
long time now about applying
international law to cyber everything
from due diligence to self defense
proportionality those are key one thing
that I think has been missing from a lot
of the international discussions has
been domestic civilian cybersecurity law
and how that actually how different
nations can work together to harmonize
improve and collaborate on those issues
and I think it's more important than
ever because when you look at and this
gets to Bruce Turner's keynote earlier
today we've got to be doing a better job
defending our systems defending our
networks and I think law does play a
crucial role here what I first want to
do is before I talk about where we can
improve cyber security law I want to
define cyber security law for the
purposes of this presentation which is a
tough task I published a textbook
creatively titled cyber
charity law last year and I sent in my
draft and the publisher had some
comments and one of them was what is
cybersecurity law you might want to
define that in the introduction and so
that actually took me a while because
there's a lot of different conceptions
of cybersecurity law for the purposes of
this presentation I'm defining
cybersecurity law as the as laws
domestically that seek to promote the
confidentiality integrity and
availability of public and private
computer systems networks and
information so again there are many
different definitions of this but that's
basically what I'm going with in terms
of what we might want to improve upon
and I've been at the Naval Academy for
three years now and when I got to the
Naval Academy I got a lot of messages
email messages that said BL UF at the
beginning some Naval Academy colleagues
are here today I had no idea what that
meant because I've been a civilian all
my life ask someone that's a bottom line
up front so my bottom line up front
which I appreciate that phrase now is
that our legal system both domestically
internationally does not do a very good
job addressing the confidentiality
integrity and availability of systems
information and networks and as Bruce
Schneier alluded to earlier just sort of
in terms of practice we do focus on
confidentiality quite a bit the C
everyone knows the CIA triad
confidentiality integrity and
availability our laws do focus on
protecting the confidentiality and part
of that has to do with the fact that
some of our earliest threats for data
breaches it's an outgrowth of data
security laws an outgrowth of privacy
law which has been in existence for a
while but what we need to start doing is
addressing integrity making sure that
connected devices operate as planned
availability preventing ransomware
attacks that shut down hospitals for
weeks upon weeks preventing people from
getting critical care
and that's what we need what we need to
be having an international dialogue
about that but that's not necessarily
bad news the fact that we don't have
sufficient laws on the books because
that means that we have a huge
opportunity here to work together and
come up with laws that are effective and
efficient and actually accomplish the
goals of shoring up the defenses of both
the public and private sector now you
might wonder why would country a care
about the domestic cyber security laws
of country B and I won't go into too
much detail but I would say that wanna
cry those are examples where there have
been attacks on one country that have
spread and impacted other countries so
there's really a pragmatic reason for
countries working together to overall
improve the cybersecurity and reduce the
harm of attacks that happen now there
are benefits as I said you can
bolstering cyber security in one country
can help with another country now to be
clear
there's no such thing as perfect
cybersecurity but it's at least getting
toward a point where the defenses are
stronger and it benefits multiple
countries it helps with deterrence by
denial for example making it harder for
the adversaries to accomplish their
goals but it's also more than that a lot
of the infrastructure that is subject to
the text when you think about the major
attacks that we've been suffering often
are the private sector so having a
consistent set of values that govern
that set the framework for all of the
laws that govern these companies helps
increase the likelihood that they're
actually going to be able to comply and
and it gives them clear guidance here
now I've got to pause for a second and
talk about the elephant in the room
which is gdpr which is along these lines
now I'm gonna put on my obnoxious
American hat just for a minute I promise
I won't be and just say that from a u.s.
perspective on the data protection side
for some companies it is not gone so
smoothly and I'm not laying blame on
either side I think that there have been
two years of two years in which US
companies could have complied but I what
I think is part of the problem here is
that there's a core set of values that
are somewhat different between Europe
and the United States when it comes to
privacy and free expression especially
when it comes to things like the right
to be forgotten and we have this set
this regulation that has a fairly broad
territorial jurisdiction and that's
caused some problems i from here went
onto from Estonia tried to get on to the
fifth largest newspapers website in the
United States the LA Times and was I I
encourage anyone who's not on a VPN
which we really should be on anyway but
I encourage any of you to go on to the
website of the LA Times from here and
you'll see a message basically saying
it's not available because of the gdpr
that's not an ideal outcome and I think
again there perhaps was not sufficient
dialogue about these shared values
between the various jurisdictions for
data protection and that's part of the
problem that we're facing now I think we
don't want to face that with
cybersecurity as we have jurisdictions
rolling out more comprehensive
cybersecurity laws and directives so I
again I think this is a great
opportunity to have these discussions
and I think that there are some models
that provide us with a significant
significant hope that we can do this as
Cedric had mentioned the Budapest
Convention just setting these basic
frameworks these bare minimums for
cybercrime statutes such as unauthorized
access to a computer that's very helpful
and that's helped at least establish a
common ground among the participating
nations I would be remiss to not mention
the Tallinn manual which has done a
remarkable job incorporating various
points of views when I assign the
Tallinn manual in my classes I
tell the students please don't just read
the bolt print read the commentary read
what the minority views are that's the
type of discussion that we should be
having also about other cyber security
cyber security laws domestic data
security laws and then finally going
back a little bit when you look at the
OECD guidelines for privacy which are
decades old when you look at some of at
some of the principles that they lay it
out like purpose limitation those are
those are in pretty much every privacy
law that you can see in the world I
think that is probably the closest to a
model of what we want to be doing for
cybersecurity laws so again I think that
there is tremendous hope I want to spend
the rest of my time just briefly talking
about the goals for these internet for
these principles that underlie
cybersecurity law and it would be
modernization uniformity coordinating
the regulations and the incentives and
then securing the supply chain so
modernizing I talked about the CIA triad
again focusing on how do we promote
integrity how do we promote availability
how do we prevent ransomware from from
shutting down operations so basically
figuring out what works well having this
discussion uniformity of regulations I
don't know if anyone in here it works in
a corporate cybersecurity department but
if you do if you suspect that there's
been some sort of cyber security
incident a data breach I hope the first
person that you call is your lawyer that
I've worked on dozens of data breaches
and other incidents for large companies
from private practice and I can tell you
there's a lot of responsibilities that
the clock starts ticking on immediately
in terms of notification for the u.s.
just within the US companies face data
breach notification laws in 50 different
states and the District of Columbia and
each one of those is a little different
they get triggered by different
by different types of information they
have different form requirements in
Massachusetts it's illegal to describe
the data breach what happened in other
states you're required to and I can tell
you I've seen it large companies and
small companies and everything in
between that for the first few days
after a data breach what you have is
everyone from the CEO to the CISO all
the way down from the line staff
figuring out how do we draft these
breach notifications in these 50 states
and then you add on the other countries
and you've got to wonder is that
accomplishing our goals of remediating
the damage preventing further harm
preventing another breach and I can say
from personal experience it's not it
doesn't what I would love to see are
some guiding principles that help to
start standardizing these requirements
so there's not so much confusion and so
that and so that it's a more seamless
process where people regulators
individuals are notified in a timely
manner but it's something that does not
require a team of lawyers and experts to
figure out if you're using the right
font and all of the other particulars
another issue that I think could be
dealt with it in on the international
stage is coordinating what would be
coercive and cooperative cybersecurity
laws now I personally for a lot of areas
of regulation believe that strong
regulations are necessary because the
goals of companies simply are not
aligned with the interests of the
general public I would say the
environment is one of them because
companies by definition are trying to
look out for their shareholders and
oftentimes for things like the
environment that's not going to be
aligned I think there's more of an
opportunity for an alignment of the
goals of the public and companies for
cybersecurity because if you're a
rational CEO you know you're not going
to say I I'd love to have a data breach
this seems like a great way to start the
day because that's going to harm your
bottom line now of course CEOs typically
think in three-month increments because
that's when they have to report
their quarterly earnings so they might
not necessarily make long-term
investments but there's at least an
opportunity to have more cooperative
cybersecurity laws rather than just
saying we're going to find you if you
have a data breach what we want to do is
prevent the data breach from happening
in the first place and I think if we had
a global framework or at least some sort
of set of values of how to have these
sort of cooperative programs like in for
information sharing education and
workforce development and darris a tax
incentives tax credits for investments
in cybersecurity I think that would go a
long way toward toward making sure there
are some synergies and ultimately having
the goal of preventing significant
damage from data breaches and other
cyber security incidents and then
finally securing throughout the supply
chain I know there was during the
workshop there was a session on this I
think particularly for setting these
international values the supply chain is
very important because it's going to be
pretty rare that you have products and
services that rely on components that
are entirely from one country so having
these values these principles that
secure the supply chain globally will
help ultimately meet this goal now in
conclusion I want to just stress again
I'm not looking to pass some sort of
model law or in or one single law across
nations that would be impossible both
for substantive and procedural reasons I
think what we could do is have this set
of values or principles that would come
after significant discussion among
nations as to how what is the most
effective sharing experiences figuring
out what information sharing programs
work what don't work what education
programs work or don't work and the
reason why we have so much opportunity
is because frankly our legal systems are
not addressing these things right now so
I would rather see us have these
significant substantial discussions at
the outset rather than everyone going
their own
and then figuring out how to reconcile
the different the different laws
afterward and with that thank you very
much for professor Jordan Jeff Joseph
can we have the time left for the
discussion here at our dare clock please
so let's start off with the discussion
before we give the floor to you I'll
I'll I'll begin with a couple of
questions on my own
perhaps I will brick begin with your
presentation since it it was the last
thank you for for an interesting
accountant on which domestic levels
focal points we should have you
mentioned that we should focus on a set
of core values and then hopefully as a
wider as a wider goal we should
harmonize them as much as possible how
how do you think we could in with the
with the goal of harmonizing this values
how do you think we could avoid the
pitfalls that we saw happening in the UN
jiejie process especially in 2017 which
was claimed at least in media as an end
of an era or a dead end or the UN gg so
how to avoid that yeah again I I I would
defer to to been particularly for any
sort of lessons learned from that
process but I would say that I think
this the issues that I'm discussing
might perhaps be a little less
politically loaded that I I think
there's definitely going to be some
significant business interests involved
so I think it's going to it would be
very different set of set of issues but
I think having starting very general and
having very high level values such as
would you have if law enforcement asks
for you to delay breach notification for
their own investigation do you do that
so there's one set of standards and
you're not
getting in trouble in various
jurisdictions I'm not saying it's gonna
be easy or even successful and
particularly after the gg but I think
there's at least some opportunity to
make that attempt yes because for
example the example it brought from
Criminal Procedure these issues that are
attempted to be dealt with in the
Budapest Convention but as we know for
example Russia has not signed the
document so again you have an option or
a platform for further discussion but
again we have sites who do not agree oh
yeah I mean with when you don't have
Russia China North Korea and Iran signed
up to a cyber crime statute there's
limited efficacy I would definitely take
that point do you have any comments on
on this issue so how to get others are
not like-minded States onward well I
kind of I said how to get non like
münster I mean there has been agreement
at the you know 2015 and was noted at
the General Assembly the reports so
there are documents that have been
agreed by all of them
and we need to identify and move on
those topics where we can see that we
can move on and that essentially was one
of the challenges of the last gge that
in a specially with an international law
section that we saw that two sides came
from quite different positions and that
wasn't a matter of principle rather than
of engaging good faith I commend you
because I think it's going to be quite
challenging that's to be honest in the
in the current environment there also
with coercion that we need to be mindful
not to mix up topics and I think a lot
of what you talked about really falls in
the purview of cybercrime issues and
kind of jus Google criminality law
enforcement cooperation cetera et cetera
and I think what the GG is dealing with
is a
very particular topic cyber stability or
you know how to promote peace and
stability in the face of states using
cyber capabilities nothing these are
different sets that might not might not
be helpful to mix them up as such any
any comment on this because it was
mentioned global stability which is one
of your go on the other direction so as
I said before I'm not against global
stability we're trying to foster global
stability but I think the common thread
between the three of us is that it's
being aware of the inherent limitations
of these big processes and the reality
so if we're aware of these inherent
limitations the way forward is maybe a
little bit more clear than than
otherwise because it seems to me that
the way forward is not that clear at all
currently we have you who propose that
we should use the existing platforms if
they already existing agreements
mentioning the UN gg 2015 report see
CBMs you mentioning the bottom-up
approach the civil cybersecurity
approach and then we have the domestic
kind of direction so we have very
different ideas if you would have to
point out what do you think would be the
next step next concrete step that is
hopefully more successful or but I need
to add that one of you made a point that
it was not a failure that you and GG
it's rather let's say an honest
reflection of the current state of
affairs but still nevertheless what do
you think is the next step in these
discussions discussions I I think that
there's an urgency here that so I think
attempting on all three fronts would be
and I I know that's easier said than
done and I'm an academic so I can say
that but that that would be my
preference I don't think it's an
either/or situation again I think I
think all of our three things are
connected for example a lot of the CBMs
deal with
I think if I'm correct me if I'm wrong
but it thinks that in practice would be
implemented by national certs and so for
example if there's a breach in one
country who's picking up the phone at
the first sign of the fence the
immediate case could vary I think
conceivably be the cert on the other end
simply to mitigate the attack now for
this you need domestic cyber security
laws in policies that regulate the
process automates the process systemize
the process so all of these things are
connected I don't think it's necessarily
either/or then any comments I would
agree I mean a as I said before we'd be
looking at different issues here so it's
hard to say okay this is the way forward
because each area has you know their own
sets of challenges and we need to be
very mindful of them I'm looking at it
from a global perspective from a policy
perspective if you look at the league of
respect from a national point of view
and you look at it from you know what
can be done what are the priorities in
the national level and how can they be
standing up to the global level as a
kind of common challenge how where do we
move from here I think as I said we need
to focus on what where consensus has
been achieved and these are then islands
of cooperation that we can can build on
all processes have their value with
different degrees of challenges and
difficulties along the road but I think
what we need most of us now most of what
we need most is at the moment is a
certain degree of realism what is
achievable and not and that to a large
degree depends on the international
environment that is not very conducive
to make progress in the field that
already is so contentious so so I think
we need to also have some patience take
a deep breath sir
take a deep breath yeah a question to
you about CBMs you mentioned that there
is a lack of an of overview of how
states are implementing them
or is there a detailed report on which
states are really following them at on
all accounts which states are not I mean
first of all I mean John's the question
I mean all the CPM is a voluntary like
the norms are voluntary its built on the
assumption that it's in every States
interest to be a good cyber neighbor if
you want that you don't want to be
singled out to be the odd one out or to
be the one that is somehow compromising
the cyber environment so the idea is
that you create some peer pressure and
that you you display all these behaviors
for the own good if you want so with the
CBN's being voluntary measuring how the
implement is somewhat difficult also
because you need to understand that you
know some of them focus on very
different issues some of them are an
exclamation of goodwill some of them are
actually quite detailed and kind of
producing procedures or non reducing
risks of conflicts any from news of
cyber and some already tell homework
tasks what's a it should do in order to
be good cyber neighbors to kind of
promote internet you know national
resilience of systems to to kind of hire
no software and hardware and you know
the weakest link in that community so
implementation is key and what we are
doing is to look at what can be done to
promote implementation of these measures
and we're doing that because we feel
that in essence they're quite practical
in essence we're talking about quite
benign things on paper I mean talking
about establishing secure communication
I have between decision-makers who
ultimately are taking decisions if
there's a big enough cyber incidents
that could threaten bilateral relations
now that's in the interest of every
state there's nothing political about it
and even though this is harder than we
thought because of course in the end of
the day you need to make a decision
whether you want to pick up the phone
whether you want to be reached or not
you know maybe it's quite interesting to
continue
using these capabilities so we crackling
with that question more than anything
that
yes everyone agrees in principle that's
a good idea but how are we implementing
them exactly and how far reaching you
know are the consequences of
implementation of these measures we we
do know from mutual legal assistance
process that if you do not want to
respond and cooperate with the other
side you always find a reason and not to
do that do we have questions from the
floor yes please first hand I saw here
oh great so many questions gentlemen yes
you please Oh actually meant the other
value but then you're next
all right and thank you very much my
name is Dennis Poulos I'm from Lady
University it's just been an interesting
range of thoughts and I like the idea of
sort of starting from the limitations
and and realities I have a question for
all three of you actually starting with
mr. Hiller use you sort of referenced
CBMs and then you said it was probably a
slip of the tongue but you said
punishments as well which was
interesting he did I was interesting
because Chris painter who is now no
longer a diplomat so he speaks a little
more freely has been speaking on a
number of occasions about effect
are we not actually creating a bottom up
norm of inaction because all these
things happen there in violation of some
of the norms we have agreed upon but
we're not really doing anything so that
is more sort of like a state practice do
we also need a state practice to deal
with the state practice of violating of
norms so that's one that's one for you
mr. Saba I like the idea of a civil
civil approach a civil cybersecurity
approach but to a certain extent we're
now in the landscape where industry is
actually being sucked into the national
security debate because everything
happens on their infrastructure they are
the ones who have to deal with with the
fallout of everything so they're
actually engaging
with the national security debate to
certain extent because they feel they
have to so how viable is it to sort of
retreat to a civil layer and for some
actors you referenced search diplomacy I
think a lot of certs would rather stay
out of diplomacy and stay in the tackle
area so that's that's another one and
the last one is for mr. Kosovo
you talked about cyber security is an
issue where there's actually much more
alignment between government interest
and and and private interest I'm not so
sure because what we see a lot is is
people talk about public-private
cooperation or even public-private
partnerships and so very rosy so very
nice everybody likes each other but
security as a collective thing
collective security is very different
for what a company would consider
security at a level that is fine for
them but not not does not necessarily
add up to what a government would like
to see even when you add up the pieces
so maybe a reaction on that yeah what I
would say about that is I think the the
alignment is for the ends for the
particular organization I take your
point and I agree with it that
collective cyber security perhaps is not
going to necessarily be in the best
interest particularly of a company that
is very focused on the next earnings
statement they might not realize that
collective cyber security in the long
run will actually help the company
overall so I agree the means are there's
not necessarily an alignment on the
means but in terms of the the goal of
reducing the likelihood of a devastating
attack on that company there's somewhat
more of an alignment I think it's the
challenge for policy makers is
explaining how they're suggested means
of getting toward that end benefits the
company as well and I think that's
what's easier than in other regulated
areas regarding your question
your first question about
the involvement of companies it's true
whether they like it or not
they're part of the national security
discussion but in a way in the model
that I'm proposing this is no different
than almost any other issue that I can
think of for example environmental
environmental law or health law the
field of health policymaking where you
have a state that first tries to look at
what's happening inside so it will
consult with its internal internal
organizations dealing with us so if it's
in the field of Health the state will
consult with its health providers and
the Medical Association the
pharmaceutical industry etc and then
from this will formulate a position that
it takes a broad based on its own needs
so I think that's ok there's nothing
inherently wrong with that and regarding
assert diplomacy I concede your point
first we should bear in mind that some
certs are complete you know there's
sorts of different compositions some
certs are composed of private actors and
some certs are purely national certs
so I'm not trying to define in advance
which would be you know who should do
what but let's say this if the starting
point is a national assert then here -
and I think the discussions in the last
IDF we're really interesting and useful
to look at what could be the role but it
could start with what a national cert
what its needs are concretely how could
it implement its mission better and then
from there what voice does it wants to
have and maybe other search think the
same things the same way and that could
be the basis for discussion this is kind
of the what I have in mind when I say
cert diplomacy it's kind of regretting
my word using the word punishment still
a bit strong even yeah anyway but but I
agree I mean you know what we do need is
some sort of consensus or at least among
group of states what are the red lines
and if those red lines are crossed
what is a response and that certainly as
the task for NATO here quite frankly
what happens then a difficult job
because it's always in the end of the
day of course a sovereign decision how
you react to an adversary and I don't
see that states will be too happy to not
have that authority and with regard to
the CBMs I think we need to see it as a
step before that
now both the norms and CBMs have been
conceived I believe with the idea that
states are interested in being a
positive contributor to cyberspace
rather than an evildoer so if you start
from that premise then you would think
that it's in everyone's interest to
resolve issues now anyway that that's
that's how these norms and CBMs are
conceived including our CPM number three
which is in a set in essence a
consultation mechanism between states if
there's the big cyber incident and you
have an interest of calling in
counterpart and in other countries they
look this is coming from your territory
this is how it looks to us what I mean
visit you is it someone else if it's not
you can you deal with this because
that's part of your responsibility is
that yourself so so it's an engagement
in good faith if that doesn't fail then
what is there and this is of course
something yes absolutely that we need to
that we need to address and at the
moment you do not have answers to that
all right thank you very much we're out
of time can we take one more question
yes the gentleman who almost had my cell
phone
so this will be the last question then
okay just one reflection I don't think
it's there is a my name is Hamish Kelly
and I'm from the Swedish MFA I don't
think there is a contradiction between
all the efforts on sort of the national
level civil cyber security and what's
going on in the foreign and security
global stability I this to sort of areas
are mutually reinforcing so there is no
contradiction and at least not from from
the Swedish point of view so so but but
I just have one question for Ben because
I know we're short of time so I I was
going to make a long intervention but I
realized that this is not the time but
one question with regard to
confidence-building measures if you
would pick one confidence-building
measure you know they OSI once and and
maybe also looking at the GG report what
would that be which is also realistic
thank you for the question and let me
clarify I didn't mean to say that all
these processes don't have value I
looked at it from a very narrow angle
which is cyber stability between states
on the global scale including all the
sniper powers and how they feel about
all of these initiatives so my point was
that we need to look at all of these
states and see where our commonalities
and what are the islands of cooperation
that we can move on that's not to say
that all these initiatives that are
happening I'm not contributing to
informing positions of one group of
states and that's good so it was a very
narrow focus with regard to the CBMs I
think the key CBM is for me the crisis
communication mechanism and that is also
realistic as I said being able to
communicate in an event of a crisis is
in the interest of every state because I
don't think any state really is
interested in letting
this escalate to a degree where they
can't step away from this anymore and
and this is something that we repeatedly
hear that from states that this is you
know the interest and there should be
nothing political about this to be able
to communicate on the high policy level
if there's something happening and again
I would also say that this kind of
communication between decision-makers
happens in parallel to existing channels
so it wouldn't replace certain third
communication and I would agree with the
gentleman there that certain certain not
engage in diplomacy they have they have
already established good relations with
most other of the counterparts and maybe
that would endanger that sort of
relation that they already establishing
that we are absolutely in need of and
and you know need as a fallback option
apologies one more last quick comment
let me just make one quick comment
regarding the way the way forward and I
think what the UN Gigi did and I am
really against this negative narrative
of failure or the end of an area because
I really think that the UNCG process
culminated into three very important
reports that published or that agreed on
on a set of rules and I think this is
the basis the starting point to to move
forward but what it did it left us with
a void because we don't have a platform
we lack a platform for states to
continue the international cyber
civility dialogue on ICT and in the
context of stability and peace so
Switzerland Germany and Mexico they
proposed an initiative which I believe
could be a leap of faith and I'm happy
to discuss this proposal a little bit
further during the coffee break and I'm
we have also developed an on paper I'm
happy to distribute it I would have
liked to outline this but I think in
them because we're running out of time I
think I can do that at bilateral so
approached me if you're interested of
this in this project thank you thank you
so much Laura and I do hope that we meet
again next year again with Knorr and
then we'll see if we the leap of faith
really paid off so thank you thank you
[Applause]