all right good morning everybody and
thanks for coming to my talk nights and
talent can be pretty short at this time
of the year so I appreciate people got
up early the talk itself is titled
security Moore's law and the anomaly of
cheap complexity and I currently work
for a team at Google called project zero
which specializes in doing offensive
research in order to better inform
defensive decisions and a very recurring
theme in all of our work is the
importance of complexity and the
difficulty of containing it so if we
look at the the computing landscape we
are all observing an escalation in
complexity and we've been observing this
for a very long time
it's been almost 20 years since I wrote
my first computer attack my first
exploit and I got hooked back then on
the entire idea that I could make
another machine do something that it
really shouldn't be doing and ever since
I've been working very very hard to keep
up with all the changes in the computing
stack keep up with changes in the
operating systems keep up with
everything happening on at all points
and interestingly in spite of working
quite hard every year I have the feeling
I'm further falling further behind
meaning my understanding of the
computing stack as a percentage of the
entire stack keeps on shrinking in spite
of me working pretty hard and for the
longest time I thought this is because I
was getting old or perhaps because a
computer network attack is a young man's
game
it wasn't until earlier this year that I
realized no no wait a modern CPU is
factor thousand 24 well has fact 1024
more transistors than the CPU that I
used to work on 20 years ago so things
are getting more complicated all the
time and this factor 1024 does not even
account for things like graphics units
Nick's baseband chips for Wi-Fi for
Bluetooth 4 for cell phones or linear
algebra or machine learning CPUs like
the GPUs that Google is not putting into
the data centers so if you think about
it the feeling that it's hard to keep up
with all the complexity is objectively
true because things are getting
objectively more complicated at a super
linear rate and our understanding of
things tends to only grow at a linear
rate
so along with this escalating complexity
we have been observing an escalating
security problem problem over the last
years as well and the sense that this
escalating complexity drives escalating
security problems and it's interesting
that for the first 10 years of my career
in security I was quite convinced that
the security thing is going to be solved
very soon there's an infamous mailing
list post from me from November 2000
where publicly wonder do memory
corruptions and attacks based on memory
corruptions have any future and it's 18
years later and I was very wrong very
publicly then because I think we're
still looking at 20 more years of having
fun with memory corruptions so the the
lesson that I took away from the last 18
years was the only few places where
we've ever managed to build something
that was actually reasonably securable
where situations where we managed to
contain complexity we have some examples
for for software packages that do not
develop remote attacks although remote
vulnerabilities all the time but there
are few and far between
something like SSH or kumea and they
usually achieve the security by being
very very harsh in not allowing
complexity to get out of hand and this
talk will examine if we're seeing all
this complexity where is it coming from
what is driving the complexity that is
in turn then driving the security
problems and the the two driving forces
on leave are interesting because they
they sit at the intersection between
computer science mathematics and
economics so we can't speak about
complexity without speaking about
Moore's law first
most law is on the slide depicted in a
red line as predicted in 1975 it looks
like a straight line in this diagram but
this is a logarithmic scale so there's
really exponential growth in the number
of transistors per area and we can see
that we as a species we're
underperforming was law a little bit but
not by much people talk a lot about
Moore's law being dead or we asked being
at the end of Moore's law but that only
applies to being able to switch on on
the all these transistors at once the
pure density of transistors is still
trending up
and we'll be trending up for the next
ten years or so so we're still on an
exponential curve when it comes to more
transistors per area and this increased
densification is coupled with us
shipping ever more CPUs every year the
start here is stolen from an armed
marketing deck where arm is telling us
that in in 2016 they shipped seventeen
point seven billion ARM cores and the
growth rate back then we have to assume
that they're shipping 21 billion arm
CPUs per year now let this thing in for
a second this means we're adding three
computers Pro human being on earth per
year to the existing corpus of computers
and this only covers arm so if we think
about other CPU architectures or
something like risk v we can probably
assume that this trend will only
continue to grow meaning by now we're
sprinkling CPUs into things like we put
salt into food there's all sorts of
devices that you would not expect
contain a significant CPU these days and
this is only going to get worse in the
sense that I guess in a few years time
having an electronic device that does
not contain a computer is going to be
the exception it's going to be extremely
rare to have a device that is not
contain CPUs some examples for things
you wouldn't expect to contain a CPU
these days any USBC cable will have an
ARM Cortex CPU inside people wonder why
are the Lightning adapters for like
lightning to DVI so expensive $40 while
they contain an arm core with 256
megabytes of RAM that boots and xnu
kernel this is an adapter which now has
a full computer in there that is I don't
know on the order of a Playstation so
we're really adding chips everywhere
while we're doing this device design is
undergoing something that is called the
shift left when the traditional product
design cycle you had several phases that
were overlapping so we would start
designing the hardware and when the
first Hardware prototypes came online or
we're working we'd start writing
software for it and then when the
software started working you would start
integrating and testing and so forth but
time to market is essential these days
so device designers are undergoing this
shift left process where they try to
overlap things more which means they
often start designing the software
before the hardware's even fully
designed yet and certainly before the
hardware's even available in in workable
form so the software gets designed and
the hardware gets Co designed at the
same time and that means in practice
that everything is much more shaky try
writing software for a computer that
doesn't exist yet and then when the
computer does come into existence and
has some late stage changes to the
hardware you need to adapt your software
to these changes that came in relatively
late this translates to well shorter
time to market but everything is more
wobbly now I often people people tell me
I'm often quite pessimistic about our
progress and security but I have to
admit we have gotten better at security
in the last 18 years and we've gotten
significantly better at security our
problem is though that we're being
outpaced by an explosive growth in in
secure computing while we're getting
better at security so we're getting
better at a certain rate but the growth
of computing as such is so drastic that
we just can't keep up and this diagram
here shows the projected or the actual
and projected growth of Internet
connected devices or generally connected
devices and the the prediction there is
that we hit something between 1025
billion to 30 billion connected devices
by 2020 and then we have to realize when
we speak about a connected device we're
really speaking about a group of CPUs
all having different firmware or running
different software's speaking to each
other within every device a friend of
mine works a lot in automotive
reverse engineering stuff and in mobile
phone research and he jokes that every
device you take into your hand these
days is no longer a computer it's a
network of computers they all interact
with each other and as a teenager you
were hacking through a network and these
days you can literally hack through a
device and there's natural movement
within a device which is a bit of an
interesting concept from an attackers
point of view so all of this all these
four slides can be summarized with holy
cow complexities escalating but why what
is driving this this crazy escalation
complexity and the underlying driver of
this is what I would call the anomaly of
cheap complexity because throughout
human history normally it was like if
you had a had the choice of producing a
simple device or a very complicated
device was normally much more expensive
to produce the complicated device and
the simpler device was cheaper and
computing at the economies of scale that
came with it have well flip this on its
head nowadays it's often much cheaper to
build something really good to use
something really complicated to simulate
something very simple and what do I mean
with this well most people think of
software as adding something to a
computer but to a certain extent you
have to flip that thinking around for a
second and understand that a computer
without software can do pretty much
anything but you wanted to do something
and software specializes your computer
to do something for you so in reality
when you do engineering you usually want
a machine to do something for you but
and in theory you could build a small
machine that does the something you want
but building and manufacturing that
machine is expensive so on the other
hand a general CPU is extremely cheap
these days so you buy a general CPU and
then you simulate what you actually want
on the general purpose CPU so in a way
you are simulating a much simpler part
using an extremely complicated part so
remember that software is something that
specializes the CPU that can do anything
to become a device that does something
for you okay so there's two big forces
that drive this anomaly of chip
complexity and these two big forces are
on the right hand side Moore's Law we've
seen that we're cramming more
transistors into the same area and on
the other hand universal computation
which is a computer science concept and
universal computation really means that
pretty much all all-important computers
are identical in some sense what this
means is that I can simulate one
computer using another so in reality I
usually want a particular finite state
machine to do something for me and then
I can take general CPU and simulate the
finite state machine I want
so I don't have to build the machine I
want from scratch I don't have to build
the actual hardware for it I'll just
simulate that it exists on a general
purpose CPU and this coupled with
Moore's law generates massive economies
of scale because at this point I don't
need to build many specialized devices I
can build one general purpose CPU and
then just build billions of it and get
the economies of scale that I get from
Moore's Law and get everything to be
very cheap an arm cortex-m zero CPU
which is the the low end range of the
arm family about twelve thousand
transistors is now on the order of
pennies and probably sub pennies if you
buy it in bulk a small development board
that can run Linux costs two dollars
wholesale so computers are extremely
cheap now a question comes of course how
does all of this affect security
negatively and we'll discuss four
different security challenges these are
not all the security challenges that
there are but these are four important
ones and the four challenges are
software security issues software supply
chain issues hardware security
reliability and supply chain issues
they're all intertwined and then our
problems with our lack of device inspect
ability to illustrate a bit more of what
I mean with this is software security
we're all very used to people using an
exploit to hacking machine and then make
it do something that it's not supposed
to do but it's really quite
counterintuitive if you think about it
because in the real world if I hijack a
car I can't make the car fly all right
so it's an interesting question how can
it be that an attacker can hijack my
device and make it do something that it
really wasn't designed to do and we'll
examine a little bit how how this comes
about the second question we want to
answer is how can it be that somebody's
research code that he wrote in his dorm
room 20 years ago without any intention
of it actually being widely used just by
accident ends up in a billion devices
the third question is given that it has
gotten so hard to make a CPU to actually
manufacture chips and given that there
are so few people that have mastered the
high end of the chip manufacturing
process
very few countries have the independence
of making their own ships and then the
question becomes can I even run
computation on ships that I don't want
to trust or am I am i forced to trust my
CPU manufacturer and we will discuss
this a little bit and on the last
question is device inspect ability I
think it's important to like in order to
understand why device inspect ability is
important it's important to think about
the decoupling of possession and control
and the digital sphere in the real world
possession me having a thing in front of
me usually implies I can control it
means if I have my car here I can decide
where it goes I've got the tank I can
decide where it goes now in the
digisphere
possession and control are not linked I
have my phone in my hand but the
software vendor and all the other people
that are running stuff on there they can
control what the phone does and I have
very very little hope
in the current technological stack to
establish control over a device I have
in my hand it's really difficult so
we'll talk about how how that comes
about
let's not with software security an
important thing to recall is that
securing well I mentioned earlier CPU
can pretty much do anything so secure
software to some extent limits what a
computer can do you are imposing limits
on the number of states the machine can
be in and you expose imposing limits to
the transitions that are allowed you
don't want your computer just randomly
start spitting out your secrets so
clearly you make sure that the software
doesn't allow it to randomly spit out
secrets so you're imposing limits on the
possible states the machine can be in
and the possible ways and can transit
from one state to the other and the
pitfall here is though that computers
aren't dynamical systems computers take
very simple calculation rules and apply
them repeatedly to incoming states to
produce new states say you have a state
you apply a computational step you have
a new state you apply a computational
step and so forth and so forth and the
trouble though is that relatively simple
computational rules applied repeatedly
to a state can lead to really really
unpredictable and chaotic behavior or
not
pens but the way to to illustrate this
or in order to illustrate this I I've
made these diagrams here and we see six
squares and on the left-hand side oh
sorry we see six squares and the left
column are the initial states that we're
going to be looking at and they're just
zero at one stage you've got white
squares and you've got blue squares and
there's very little difference between
these threes three states you can see
that there's only a 1 pixel difference
between the top square and the bottom
square meaning on the left hand side
there's one extra pixel and you can see
that in the middle there's three extra
pixels in comparison to the top one and
now if you apply the same calculation
rules the same update rules repeatedly
to the three different ones you'll get
vastly different results
so I'll click and then we'll watch the
right hand column where we can see the
evolution of these three systems by just
applying the same computational rules to
all three of them iteratively
so we see that the tiny change in the
middle led to a different outcome but a
stable outcome and the even smaller
change at the bottom leads to absolute
chaos like this thing will go on for a
long while and just keep on running and
creating new states that you really
couldn't foresee and to a certain extent
this is what's killing us in software
security that small changes tend to spin
out of control so it's important to
realize that when you're dealing with
computational devices and software
running on them you have complex
behavior that is barely controlled that
always runs just below the surface and
you've imposed a lot of limits on the
system in software but when something
goes wrong when you ever reach an
invalid state then odds are that all
your your carefully imposed limits on
what the system can do may fly out of
the window once you're operating on a
broken input state it's really hard to
predict how that will interact with with
other parts and if you think about what
attackers do attackers verily very
carefully set up initial States and then
set up a corruption of sorts to reach an
invalid state so that the the error has
a ripple effect and propagates into a
state that is undesirable for the
defender and desirable for the attacker
and our experience and security confirm
this like really tiny issues really
differences in an initial state can spin
out of control entirely and get the
attacker to to take over the the machine
or violate security properties a prime
example why why did I go with a single
bit flip model a few years ago I was
involved in a in a situation that was
known on the name of row hammer what
happens there is that Ram vendors were
shipping Ram and as they were scaling
down the transistors they packed them so
tightly that when you read one piece of
memory you would have a small amount of
leakage current that would leak to the
neighboring parts of memory so if you
read that part of memory really rapidly
in succession you would be able to flip
bits in adjacent parts of memory so an
attacker just by reading memory could
flip bits and other parts of memory and
the hardware vendors at the time they
all thought that this is just a
reliability issue like who cares about a
bit flippin eventually the computer may
crash but that's not a big big deal will
reboot or whatever and also the odds of
the computer crashing are relatively low
because most bits in memory don't matter
but it turns out to be to be quite
exploitable and have huge security
impact so I guess the the summary of it
all is it's really important to realize
that a tiny error in a computing system
has a tendency to spin out of control
and attackers can usually make it spin
off out of control in a semi controlled
manner okay so the answer to the
question how can it be that my device
gets attacked by an attacker and can
then do something that wasn't designed
to do in the first place is that was
much more cost-effective to put a
general-purpose computer into that
device that can do anything and then
kind of try to like control the
complexity and keep it under wraps then
to build a device that doesn't have that
computational power in the first place
now if you put a general purpose CPU
into a device you also get the advantage
or disadvantage that any added
complexity in the form of software
becomes essentially free now that I've
got a CPU in my device I can take any
piece of software in the world and
compile it or port it to that platform
and now adding that complexity is almost
free for me and as a teenager a book
that was very very influential on me
it's called the moon is a harsh mistress
it's about a colony of prisoners on on
the moon that then undergoes some sort
of revolution in order to declare
independence and there's a long
monologue in this book about the proper
organization of a revolution in fact but
it's actually a good monologue about
design because one of the people like
one of the characters in the book that
talked about the revolution there is a
guy called Bernardo de la Paz and he
tries to argue that the revolution
shouldn't only contain a few people and
not a mass number of people and should
have a cell system in order to properly
contain spies so it's it's a good quote
on engineering in general though and the
quote is how do you design or how does
one design an electric motor would you
attach a bathtub to it simply because
you have one available what a bouquet of
flowers help or a pile of rocks no you
would use just those elements necessary
to its purpose and make it no larger
than needed and you would incorporate
safety factors function controls design
the trouble is that software makes
adding bathtubs bouquets of flowers and
rocks free there's really no cost to it
and because it's free we get it so the
answer to the question how on earth did
this research code that some guy wrote
20 years ago in his dorm room end up in
a billion devices is well it provided
some marginal value was easy to reuse
didn't take much effort would have been
more effort to write it ourselves but
most importantly was free okay talking
about chip manufacturing and talking
about Hardware reliability hardware
supply chain issues and hardware
security issues it's important to
realize how insane the scaling of
transistors has gotten we're now at a
point where a high-end CPU will contain
hundreds of millions or even billions of
transistors and Intel is quite proud
about the latest manufacturing process
where they get about hundred million
transistors per square millimeter and I
mentioned that you need about twelve
thousand transistors to do an ARM Cortex
CPU so we have a lot of compute on very
little little space and the trouble is
we've seen that a tiny malfunction on
the order of one single bit
can spin out of control and make things
go go really crazy so we now have a
hundred million transistors per square
millimeter and there's just no
cost-effective way of inspecting them
all and testing whether they work
properly in reality we build these chips
or we people don't manufacture these
chips and you get this wafer and then
this wafer has a whole bunch of chips
put on there and they try to test them
and those that pass basic functionality
tests are sold and those that don't pass
the tests are thrown away and it's
exactly these economics of the chip
making process that drive manufacturers
to sell the hardware they can get away
with selling what this means is if I'm
producing a wafer and a certain
percentage of that wafer is going to be
garbage anyhow my margin depends
crucially on maximizing the yield on
that wafer the more I have to discard
that the less money I make if I have to
scar too much I'm losing money so the
chip maker is strongly incentivized to
chip the CPU that is the least reliable
CPU that the customer can't detect is
unreliable that's literally how how you
have to operate in the chip making
business in order to get stuff done
which was also the problem in the row
hammer scenario because the different
manufacturers just had no incentive to
make sure that their RAM never flips a
bit so and this is not malice this is
just economics and technological
progress because in order to continue
marching down Moore's law chip
manufacturers have to go really to the
limit of what is possible reliability
wise you're so small these days you have
a few hundred atoms in in a transistor
so clearly three atoms more or less when
you have twenty thousand of them doesn't
matter but three atoms more or less when
you have only a few of them starts being
a significant error so chip makers are
almost forced to work really close to
the cliff and until recently essentially
on two row hammer or perhaps even until
until well I would say unto row hammer
the link between reliability and
security was not very clear to the
electric engineering and to some parts
of the computer science compute
community so people didn't understand
that a reliability issue is in many
cases unless it's carefully controlled
also a security issue okay so the
summary of all of this is you need to
trust your chip manufacturer there's
just no way that under current
technology on a current understanding of
software we can run software on hardware
that we do not trust we do not know how
to write real-world programs that can
operate on chips that we do not trust
and any tiny intermittent and
probabilistic misbehavior can under the
current architectures have disastrous
security implications if leverage
properly so there's no way to not trust
the chip manufacturer yeah so this slide
just summarized what I just said there's
no way you can run a computing
infrastructure if you have to assume the
person manufacturing your chip is
malicious and even then you have to
remember that he may not be malicious he
may just have an economic economic
incentive to sell you CPUs that work
most of the time it's important to
remember that we all well historically
most people that study computer science
study computer science from a very
mathematical perspective but the history
of computers actually is said somewhere
in the middle between mathematics and
electrical engineering and we like to
think about computers as deterministic
devices but underneath all the
determinism of the computer there's
actual physics happening there's
actually electrons hopping from A to B
there's some electrons getting dislodged
and smashing into the science and to an
insulator
there's things heating up and cooling
down and there's actual physics
happening which means computers are
deterministic in the abstract sense
meaning it's useful to think of
computers as deterministic but they're
only deterministic most of the time and
electrical engineers work really really
hard to keep this illusion of
determiners determinism around because
otherwise it's very difficult to debug
computers but in the end determinism is
something that has to be fought for in
computers and is not a given all right
talking about scaling firmware engines
and general inspect ability so scaling
has yielded most of the performance
gains that we've seen over the last
decades we've made things much smaller
but scaling also makes it impossible to
physically inspect the individual
transistors because everything is just
way too small
and then while we've done this we've
scaled things down
we've also replaced many simple parts
with quite complicated parts so we've
replaced simple engines with full CPUs
with firmware and we usually have no
good mechanism of inspecting what
firmware is running inside the device
and the average laptop these days has on
the order of 30 to 35 perhaps 40
different CPUs all with different
firmware in there and we have a really
hard time establishing what is where
when and the current approach for
firmware security is usually based on a
sort of mode system we just design
things in a way that we think the
attacker can't get in we do code signing
cryptographic verification of the stuff
that's coming in but we have to realize
two important truths in the remote case
code signing keys get stolen with quite
some regularity there's a thriving black
market where you can purchase code
signing certificates so it's very very
difficult for many hardware
manufacturers to even keep the signing
keys secure step 1 and for local
attackers local attackers can often
induce localized faults transient faults
in computer circuits by electromagnetic
radiation or other tricks and once they
can get a fault induced they can often
bypass the cryptographic verification
mechanism which then means that you can
get past the you're not allowed to get
into this device and once you can
implement new firmware and nobody can
get you out so the the reality is that
at this point in our technological
progress nobody has a good way of
establishing control over device in the
sense that resetting a device into a
known good state if the hardware was in
Antakya possession in between we can't
check the transistors we can't check the
firmware properly so that means
establishing who is in control of a
given device at a given point in time if
control of that device has been disputed
before gets to be very very difficult
and that's a strange strange situation
for us because when it comes to physical
events like cars
we're very used to being able to
establish control establishing control
in computer systems not so easy at
current technology okay so the the
summary of this is that establishing
that you own this thing not only own in
the legal sense of ownership and not own
in the sense of possession but own this
thing in the sense of being able to
dictate what it does is not easily
doable
today okay
so tying all this to get together what
does this mean in the larger scheme of
things an important thing to realize is
that to some extent the pervasive
insecurity that we have in our IT
infrastructure comes from the fact that
the same forces that drive IT success
also drive RTS insecurity it is really
the ability to do Universal computation
and Moore's law combined that drive the
exponential cost reduction that we've
seen in IT and then it's responsible for
the success of IT and then it's this
generosity of computing that generates
the economies of scale so that you can
just produce billions of generic CPUs
that make complexity cheaper than
simplicity and once you have these
generic CPUs this generosity also
provides near zero cost to add more
complexity in the form of more software
so all of these are great economic
advantages for IT and they're the things
that lead to this explosive growth but
they're also the reasons why we're
struggling so heavily in when it comes
to securing things and understanding
that these things like the economic
advantages will dominate the security
concerns unless we can somehow align
them is important because in the long
run economic advantages will always
always trump somebody saying oh no I
have a concern here alright so what is
next what can we do about all of this
short little anecdote as I said I'm not
always known for my optimism so when I
showed the first slide deck of this to
some co-workers they're like you really
need to end on a more optimistic note
to be fair there are quite a few things
to be optimistic about first of all
let's not kid ourselves there's a lot of
research and engineering ahead and the
problems that we need to solve is first
of all how do we contain untrusted
software but still make use of it I mean
there's a lot of useful software of ever
written by grad student 20 years ago
that we would like to use but we need to
find a way to have the benefits of that
software without well incurring the cost
of things spinning out of control and
then us getting hacked through that
software so first thing how do we use
untrusted software in our systems
without it having a security implication
the second bigger problem is how do we
build systems that we can inspect and
that we can effectively take control of
if we need to and that's more more
difficult then how do we build systems
that do not spin out of control when the
single bit flips or when when a small
small memory corruption occurs how do we
build systems that can detect when they
are about to spin out of control and
this is not easy easy either and then
the biggest question is I mentioned that
getting the alignment between security
and economics is important how do we do
this without sacrificing the benefits
that Moore's Law and universal
computation has given everybody and I
mentioned that there's there's quite
some hope so some of these problems are
really research problems and some of
these problems are just engineering
problems in the sense that we know how
to do this we just have to do it and the
first thing I would like to mention is
that when it comes to containing
untrusted software the Luc's kernel
nowadays contains something called secum
strict which is an extremely restrictive
sandbox that limits the complexity of
the code the attacker can reach
drastically in essence what it does is
it limits the syscall a process can make
to read from a file or socket well sorry
read from a file or file descriptor
write to it exit the process and a cisco
called sig return but that doesn't
really matter so it really narrows down
what that process can do very very
strictly and my team produce error we're
not known to have a lot of doubts about
being able to break things because we're
usually quite good at breaking things
but nobody in the team would be
confident that they can get out of a
second strict sandbox
so isolation mechanisms that are very
very hard do exist
but we don't have any libraries to make
them usable so we're here in a situation
where we have something that we know
works and our challenge is to make that
actually useful usable and deploy it
everywhere and it requires thinking a
little bit about what programming
libraries do you want what programming
paradigms do you want and so forth but
this is really the the part of the of
the questions that we have on screen
that are least researchy
and most just engineering building
inspectable systems is more and more
complicated I think or more research II
also I'm not an electric engineer so
understand less about it but it's an
interesting and an important question
can we build systems that have one
component that is big enough and simple
enough that it can be inspected that can
then go and bootstrap validation
mechanism for the rest of the system and
inspect everything else and this is is
really it's not clear if it can be done
how it can be done and I would probably
have to speak to an electrical engineer
about this and even then we would have
to puzzle puzzle for a while but the
point is it's an important research
problem and it doesn't seem impossible
there's no fundamental reason why it
shouldn't be doable on the question of
containing latent computational power
there's really interesting work being
done with regards to memory tagging
Oracle when they were still doing the
SPARC CPUs had something called ATI
which was very cleverly designed and all
these things were mechanisms that help
you detect when a program is spinning
out of control
provided that you've combined the
engineering of your hardware with the
engineering of your software in the
proper way so the hardware essentially
provides facilities for the software to
tell it when an invalid state is reached
and then the heart would provide some
support to possibly detect this now all
of these approaches are imperfect but
the general gist of or the general
thrust of we can co design hardware so
that software can signal to the hardware
these are the states we we intend to
have and these are not states we want is
quite promising and I think we'll see
interesting things there now when I talk
about this it becomes clear that this
requires above re-engineering
of existing systems so who on earth
would want to pay for this right because
normally nobody's going to re-engineer
the entire IT infrastructure just
because we want securable systems and we
are collecting all the legacy stuff is
really just not economical in any way
shape or form so is there a larger
economic or technological trend that we
can ride in order to get there and I
would say yes there may be we are
reaching the end of Moore's law not in
the sense of no longer being able to
scale transistors but in the sense of we
are no longer capable of obtaining
single core speed ups the speed of a
single core the growth rate of it has
dropped from more than 50 percent to
less than 2% which means we're used to a
single core doubling in speed every two
years now it will double in speed every
20 years at max so we're literally at
the end of the rope for a single core
speed up and for the last 40 years we've
programmed computers in the very same
way we had a programming model and we've
essentially pretended that our computers
are just faster versions of a pdp-11
every year since the 1980s but if you
speak to an electrical engineer engineer
these days they're all very very excited
because for the first time in 40 years
they're allowed to go wild and redesign
architectures to be massively parallel
because there's no more performance
gains in the singer non parallel version
but all this parallelism cannot be
harnessed with existing software either
so as we're speaking here the way we do
computing is getting a real connected
and computing will look very different
15 years from now than looks today more
different then today looks from 15 years
ago so we're already in the process of
rebuilding everything from scratch right
now and that process has started so the
big opportunity we have there is try to
make sure we get the security concerns
brought into the design process because
we're if we're rebuilding everything
from scratch then the economics of
making things more secure may actually
work out now I mentioned that I'm not
always very optimistic I would put the
odds of the US actually managing to do
that at less than 10 percent but maybe
worth a bet and yeah we have a historic
opportunity here to influence the way
computing is done any questions
Thank You Thomas
we probably do have some questions
please raise your hand if you do have
one we will go through them in front
here is your C but speaking in my
personal capacity here so we have a lot
of changes and a lot of a thank you very
much for the for dr. crystal so we have
a lot of changes and a lot of new
standards and a lot a lot of
technologies are as you said and flux
but as also matter it requires time is
difficult to foresee which security
proposals which standards will be the
successful ones so how can you foresee
whether they're right and the part the
people people and the ecosystems take
are right and what they're we won't end
up in 10 or 20 years I mean at the same
place I mean if as you are well aware
that 10 years ago security on the
architectural and software kernel and
web security we would level when there
were some proposals that could bring
through fruit that could bring
improvements but it seems that they did
not actually improve as bypasses for
well formed so in your opinion how do we
proceed
and it's pretty much pretty much magic
or reasoning how do we first see how
where will we end up in 10 years so I
mentioned that I only see a less than 10
percent chance that will really end up
with more secure computing systems and
part of the reason is security and
especially insecurity is not really well
understood there's an ridiculous
scarcity of people that actually
understand exploits at a sufficient
depth and understand enough of the
different parts of the stack to to make
contributions so one of the things
clearly like why am i working in a team
that does offensive research
that then gets published well partially
because I think it's useful it's
extremely useful for us to understand
what we're trying to solve first alright
so I guess if we want to get good
solutions we have to make sure that we
understand what we're trying to solve
first and at least historically in
security a lot of countermeasures are a
bit of knee-jerk reactions so you have a
security problem and then you come up
with a mitigation before you've really
gotten to the root of the problem did
that answer your question in any way
shape or form okay cool there's one more
question yes hi I'm Carlos with cert
Latvia and my question is regarding
quality of engineering like where
humankind is pretty good at mechanical
engineering and construction you know in
western world buildings don't collapse
that often or so so why are we so bad at
engineering software and hardware so the
question I think is one of the order of
magnitude of the complexity we're
dealing with the permits of gizzay are
are set to have about 2.5 to 3.5 million
bricks we are putting a hundred million
transistors on a square millimeter and
that does not even include the the
software on top of it the permits of cos
a had more had well sorry Windows XP had
more man-hours invested than the permits
of cos a so we just have to realize that
our IT stack is the most complex thing
we've ever built like humanity has never
built anything more crazy than a
cellphone essentially and all the
complexity is in your pocket so the
reason why we're we're better at
building buildings and bridges and so
forth is because there we're naturally
constrained in how crazy we can go
there's laws of physics that pull us
back more and with computing and power
the reason why computing has been so
successful is we're not quite as
constrained by by the limits of physics
there as we are we're still constrained
by the limits of physics but we can
afford to put much more complexity in
these devices than elsewhere does that
answer the question
do have another again well actually let
me sorry very briefly to the last
question one one second I guess another
part is it's still early days for
computers it's been about what 60 years
70 years I'm not quite sure how good
humanity was at building bridges 70
years after first starting so it's
important to realize also the evolution
we're going through if you look at
something like the illusion of flight if
you look at the very first airplanes and
then how airplanes evolved in the next
hundred years
there was rapid progress but anyhow
sorry so I have some very nice
observation that a software hardware and
I mean all the layers are being
controlled by seemingly different
players yes but it appears that a one
player big corporation is emerging that
will occur it at least the press reports
that already were already controls the
their software but increasingly intense
to control also hardware the event is a
threat or opportunity as maybe if
someone would be in control of full
stacks of staff software hard world that
will be the ultimate opportunity so it's
a bit unclear whether it's Eva below
that quite a few vendors dream of owning
the entire stack but even those vendors
do not necessarily own the manufacturing
process so let's say I'm a mobile phone
manufacturer I may own the IP for the
entire stack I may have designed my own
CPU as Apple has done I still have like
I still outsource a lot of the actual
implementation of it to a third party
and I have to trust the third party I
don't think there's any any player that
is even remotely close to vertically
integrating the chip manufacturing
process as well but I don't know I'm the
supply chains and hardware are complex
and convoluted
so I don't actually know how
how it looks in the real world did that
help okay
sorry we don't have any more time for
the questions please approach mr. Dewey
and afterwards he will probably be here
during the coffee break
but Thomas we do have a present for you
excellent thank you ma'am and thank you
very much for your interesting talk and
we hope to see you back soon thank you