okay first of all I'm really happy to be
here and honored to talk to such an
audience as you just heard that I am an
Air Force officer and I'm also an
engineer and that puts me in the very
very uncomfortable position to try to
provide the operational perspective to
an engineering company and this is a not
an easy job as you can imagine and I can
assure you because first of all
engineers are a pain in the ass myself
included second thing is that scenarios
are getting more and more complex
including a wider than ever variety of
assets of capabilities of domains and of
doctrines so let me show you briefly a
small video that maybe many of you have
already have already seen don't think
this is visionary right now in Syria
we're in the most aggressive
edw environment on the planet from our
adversaries they're testing us every day
knocking our communications down just
disabling our ac-130s etc so what was
that was that traditionally w-was that a
dummy but powerful communication jammer
was that a more elaborate cyber
structured attack doesn't really matter
what really matters is that the asset
was disabled that the capability was
degraded so this is what we're facing
now a new concept of not knowing exactly
what has caused the effect that we are
seeing we are seeing at the gradation of
a capability we are seeing a degradation
of an asset a neutralization of a
platform are we not sure what caused
that if it's a standard approach if it's
a hybrid approach if it's a more
structure than strategical cyber maybe
approach
these new concepts are definitely now in
front of in front of us and the key
points of this new hybrid warfare
approach are are here are in front of us
first of all faster communication
everything is requiring a wider band we
want to cooperate with platforms we want
data to flow among assets that means a
strong need of bandwidth as a matter of
fact cutting-edge technology that can be
designed by yourself can be proprietary
can be commercial off-the-shelf but
still it's the technology that we are
exploiting and when we say technology is
not only hardware is of course also the
payloads that we are putting into our
assets the battlefields that can be
physical virtual or even overlapped so
the keywords that are now in front of us
it's first of all net-centric or network
based cyber we are here for this and
unmeant as a matter of fact there is one
key target which is the information so
this is the holy grail of the new
scenarios and when we say scenarios we
are meaning every kind of daily life
aspect as well as a battlefield
operational scenario information is the
target that you want to dominate
therefore there is a common ground where
all these aspects meet meet there is a
spectrum electromagnetic spectrum is
definitely the common ground where all
these points are merging together into
one single one single complex scenario
and this is where actually electronic
warfare meets cyber the two categories
has been
kept separate for a while there was the
electronic warfare electronic warfare
operator that was doing his his job
maybe at 30,000 feet behind a console
and then there was the cyber warrior
somewhere in the world dispersed into
the the network and in the cloud but now
these two domains are definitely merged
and this is not a case because as I said
the electromagnetic spectrum is the
common ground for all the activities
that we want to that we want to carry
out in all the aspects of operational
life so there is this opens up to new
any to a new kind of opportunities and
vulnerabilities they are always both
sides of the story so the challenge now
here is to synchronize the cyber
operation with the electronic warfare
yesterday I heard an interesting note
from mr. Moore from the King's College
he was I don't know if his presence in
in the room it was interesting to see
the difference between the two domains
one was the the event-based domain so
weapon and reaction and that the other
one is the presence the presence base
domain so where there is the network
there is the presence of the of the
asset of the maybe of the payload that
you want but you don't know physically
where it is so this is exactly where the
two domains are merging together so you
want to as a matter of fact to use one
as an asset for the other so a even
based approach delivering a presence
based payload and this is the shift of
the paradigm that you can see there was
this traditional warfare based on
spectrum as a matter of fact so mostly
physical layer
the hybrid warfare spectrum and network
based so we are not only facing one
single one single opponent a physical
opponent but there is a distributed
opponent that we have to face still on
this kind of off domain and then the
CMAs cyber lat magnetic activities that
is involving all the three aspect
including the cyber the cyber warfare
therefore they from a solution provider
point of view cyber electromagnetic
warfare means that you have to master
all the aspects in order to be able to
synchronize and coordinate offensive
defensive intelligence across the
electromagnetic environment and
cyberspace this means that as a matter
of fact you need to escalate the layers
of the information environment as we
said information dominance is what you
want to achieve in all the aspects of
your operational life and this can be it
can be done through steps into the
layers the physical layer is the
traditional aw let's say let's simplify
like this so you have signals you have
countermeasures you have analysis of the
content of the signal infrastructure so
you want to enter the network cognitive
you want to enter the content you want
to enter the functions of the network so
this kind of steps is the real real Holy
Grail that you are following when we're
talking about Sima and to do this you
need to master all the layers that are
in between physically technologically
and structurally point from a structural
point of view so the cycle of cyber
electromagnetic activity is
as a matter of fact is similar to the
more standard operation still you need
to have your Intel you need to have your
data gathering with even some of course
tradition what we say traditional is not
to diminish the value of that
traditional means more let's say
familiar approach when you collect data
from maybe an elint or a SIGINT
operation but still you have to face new
new tasks big data analysis reverse
engineering crypt analysis this means
that you not only need to know the
signal not only need to identify the the
emitter that you are facing but you need
to understand how it works you need to
understand what it is you need to
understand how you can exploit its
vulnerability if any the preparation
therefore takes into account all this
aspect that you have studied from in in
the in the previous phase so you're
still following a planning you're still
preparing platforms and let's say
jamming activities but the cyber payload
that you are delivering is something
that has been tailored for that target
so this is what I said before the trying
to match a I like the I like the
definition of a event based domain with
a presence based domain so you need to
match a payload that is based on the
presence into the network with a
tactical operation delivering a signal
okay so this is the real challenge how
you do simulate that to simulate that
you need to master all these kind of
aspects so all the physical layer all
the infrastructural layer and the
cognitive layer as well the execution of
course takes into account this kind of
approach in order to build up these this
layer from
the jamming point of view we're always
talking about jamming where we in the
traditional aw when you say jamming you
mean to degrade the enemy the opponent
signal but in this case jamming means
deliver a payload maybe you are still
degrading the opponent signals but you
are delivering a payload instead so
starting from the beginning is that does
it really matter if you delivered a
jamming signal or you delivered a
jamming signal as plus a payload this is
the question so in order to provide
cyber electromagnetic activities there
are three key points three key steps
that need to to be to be mastered first
of all is knowledge knowledge means
first of all a change of the mindset so
the mindset needs to be completely
unconventional compared to the
traditional to the traditional approach
because you have a let's say
conventional physical layer based
Network warfare and then you have an
unconventional cyber domain that you
have to exploit so this means that you
have to educate first of all the people
and you have to train you have to train
a lot trained first of all to the
approach that is no silver bullet that
needs a lot of study a lot of
preparation lot of reverse engineering
as I said I said before and the
technology the technology that is the
base for all these kind of kind of
aspects from when I say technology of
course I am talking about hardware
fermer software and malware so we are
facing all the aspects of the technology
and is still a technology
as a matter of fact a cyber payload is a
technology so what you have to do is to
master all these aspects try to
synchronize also this aspect not from in
a synchronization not in the time domain
but in the functional domain and in
order to be able to deliver something
that is effective at that time for that
operation so you see how the the aspects
are complex and are merging together so
the cyber resilience is the the as well
effect and natural consequence of all
these concepts if you are mastering
let's say the deliver of a payload of a
cyber Pearl exploiting the opponent
vulnerabilities you know how to protect
yourself or you have studied you are
designing your systems in order to be
protected so this is a key point it's
it's quite an easy bullet to say but
it's a radical change in all the aspect
of the product lifecycle starting from
the very beginning from the design point
of view so there is a big strong shift
not only in the doctrines not only in
the tactics not only in the technology
but also in the design approach and from
an industrial point of view changing the
mindset and changing the approach to
designing such kind of things is is a
strong is a strong effort because it
requires a completely shift of of the
path that you followed previously so
definitely cyber resilience is including
all the aspects that were mentioned
before and it's as a matter of fact the
summarization of all the cyber
electromagnetic activities including
protection of your own of your own
assets
I think this concludes pretty much my
presentation and I'm open to questions
Thank You appreciation for you and do we
have any questions from the audience
hmm okay I can see one hand back there
and you raise your hand once again
this is lighter Ricardo piglia Swiss
Armed Forces trying to joining the
electronic warfare and cyber domain may
have some challenges from an industrial
point of view as well
electronic warfare is it's a domain
where industry is quite strong where
army is more or less by products from
from the industry which are more or less
turnkey and cyber is a domain where
where there is a lot of brain we're
going in from the unforce themselves so
I think industry shell shall have an
approach where the electronic warfare
platforms may be more open to the
inclusion of knowledge and innovation
from from enforces themselves what do
you think about it yeah absolutely well
I have to say that the this work joint
worked together with between armored
force as industry is nowadays is
essential in all the aspects even in the
traditional aw because now the
traditionally W let's call it
traditional once again not to diminish
it but the traditionally W is facing and
all you kind of traditional threats
therefore and when I say traditional
threat means network-based threat as
matter of fact so still you don't have
anymore one threat and one asset and one
countermeasure to counter this threat
you have a variety of threats to be
faced or a variety of assets to be
confronted with so you have to face this
kind of issues
therefore the support of the armored
force is essential more than ever
that being said from a cyber point of
view this is even more more important
because as I said what you have to do is
to synchronize something that is not
time-based so it's a network based
approach into a tactical platform into
something that is actually on action so
to do that you definitely need your your
help and this is not only from a
technical point of view it's also from a
operational point of view otherwise you
won't be effective so this is a yeah I
agree with you is a strong effort that
needs to be done jointly definitely
thank you any more questions
in this case thank you for a fascinating
note thank you and we will proceed
[Applause]