dear guests welcome to Tallinn
trans-time forsaken and I am very happy
to speak here and of course I also feel
a little bit nervous because all this
legacy comes down from president Tom
eccentric Elvis the former president of
Estonia who has made it possible for the
whole world to understand that this
Woodstock place for cyber Easterlin so
please applaud president Thomas and Ric
Elvis here in the front line yes
Estonians have been strong in digital
yes Estonians understand better the
risks related to digital this is in big
part also he's doing but the promotion
work for Estonia what he has been doing
for 15 years at least this is incredible
and I am forever grateful to him for
this work which he has undertaken and
still doesn't it take also Thank You
Meryl for this introduction and for
organizing this conference it's the 10th
time and of course it's very fitting
that the theme of this conference now is
about maximising the effects I would
like to point out that the most
important takeaways and lessons learned
from these developments that could
really be used to do exactly that to
maximize effects in order to keep our
societies and citizens safe
what has changed globally since last
year when we gathered is the awareness I
think the awareness level of cyber
related risks is much greater today than
it was a year ago yes it was openly
spoken about cyber risk cyberattacks
attacks on systems Ukraine also US has
attributed their attacks to to Russia
other countries have done so but this
year brought cyber risks close to normal
people they started to understand that a
new set of natural laws if you wish have
been created by evolvement of the
technology sphere people normally know
without well we don't know when we learn
it but we all know that if you jump out
of the window then
you fall down but for some reason people
did not realize that if you're out in
the Internet then you're visible now
they understand it much better
and of course numerous efforts have been
made to make companies and governments
responsible to protect people in the
cyber alas this is not possible it will
come down to individual action
individual level of cyber hygiene how
safe you are in the internet how you are
able to choose what is visible about you
how you're able to also understand that
because some parts of you your character
your interest is visible in cyber sphere
then the bubble will be created around
you which will make sure again a new
natural law you will not see the
opposing opinions people just need to
learn these new natural laws in text
fear and you know this is also a great
opportunity for all of us who are
dealing everyday with the cyber risks
because now suddenly everybody is eager
to learn and I think I also talked last
year about the spillover effects to
civil society from the work which has
been done in cyber defence community to
guarantee but the cyber hygiene now is
your time to jump now is your time to
also make sure that the general benefits
for the overall society will be
maximized and that people will be able
to benefit from what has been learned in
cyber defence also in guaranteeing
personal cyber hygiene at the highest
possible level last year for Estonia it
was an interesting year and we expected
that we will have a very difficult cyber
year as well because we were d-u council
presidency and what better than to
demonstrate that the digital state
estonia is not functional when it
matters the most when de consoles gather
in Estonia when all your visitors and
come here in fact we didn't face many
incidents at all who had some capacity
Shaz instead with our own Wi-Fi but that
was a self-inflicted wound these things
also happen
we also had the NATO's enhanced forward
presence arriving in Estonia again we
predicted that we will have cyber
conventional attacks and also hybrid
attacks Stratcom attacks against against
this NATO's well very visible
international presence in the Baltic
states that was only one case in
Lithuania which was very quickly solved
by listening and authorities I really
would like to applaud them for that that
in less than an hour they were able to
well call the bluff and explain to the
whole world that nothing had actually
happened that this was false news which
again also shows that the whole world
has become a little bit more resilient
it is possible to send the truth after
the false statements and it is starting
to have an effect I think if we look
three years back four years back it
would have been much more hard to do so
some positive developments as well of
course we don't know that what was the
reason why we didn't come under heavy
attacks last year
maybe that was a capacitation maybe our
well how adversaries were busy somewhere
else we don't know but maybe maybe it
was because we are quite resilient
because after all we have worked a lot
in these matters on the other hand we
had an we had a really interesting
crisis last year here in Estonia
relating to a digital state but it had
not had nothing to do with attack it had
something to do with the fact that
nobody who is using technology controls
the whole production chain of this
technology as a small state of course we
don't control practically any part of
the production chain of this technology
and when 1 billion chips where we stone
from the market by a chip maker
it appeared that more than 700 thousand
of them actually were Estonian ID kah
chips the rest of the chips worked in
some other digital environments in some
other digital States on people's ID
cards but the majority were simply doll
cause it's at
it was interesting that some other
countries shut down their ID card
systems and I was sad that nothing
happened I mean if you shut down an ID
card system and you don't have a public
riot then you have not yet
digitally disrupted your society this
was obviously the case as well here in
Estonia of course it was quite clear
that we cannot we cannot do that our
people were not ready to go back to
paper it was interesting the initial
reaction of the society to this crisis
was that maybe it's not that bad
it was exactly like you see the second
world war coming and you think maybe
it's not that bad
the Society read the news decided it
cannot be quite so bad because it was
too big to believe and so the society
including media that's everybody
stabilized stabilized closer to the
cliffhanger but decided to hang on and
this was a clear sign that whichever way
we go solving this crisis we absolutely
have to make sure that that is as little
as possible physical displacement of
people to go and do something we managed
for quite a number of people to patch up
the ID cards over Internet but some
people could not and of course then it
was very clear to us once more nowadays
we cannot be happy that we'll have
digital and if something goes wrong we
have also the paper alternative
somewhere Estonia has to have digital
with digital alternative no other way
will work we have also the mobile ID and
and other options but it's quite clear
that we need to spend in the coming
years quite some money to revamp our
systems to provide safe alternatives to
the access to the systems and also think
quite quickly whether the whole
technical New Clothes the whole
technical platform of our digital
that needs to be taken to a new level
for example using blockchain this would
be no necessary not only to develop the
services because our state wants to be
proactive towards its citizens anyway
and that demands blockchain anyway but
even to continue providing the current
services it seems to be that we need to
invest quite a lot we have for years
said that we say 2% of GDP only by
signing digitally luckily we also can
say that 6% of GDP is ICT otherwise it
would be very hard to say that we also
need to spend in upcoming years above
definitely 1% but in some years maybe
even close to 2% our GDP to provide new
solutions this is my prediction and I
would not at all be astonished if if
this held - we definitely need to make
sure that we stay ahead of the curve all
the time and the main reason why which I
see I know nothing of technology but
what I can see is that if something is
out there long enough and it becomes
really really widely used and mainstream
then things start to go at one point a
little bit wrong and then it's time to
move on to a stronger newer technology
platform simply because if people just I
don't know out of fun spend time in
trying to figure out how to break
certain systems for years and years
then they more and more often start to
well have success this is just a feeling
and and I think we need to make sure
that this will not endanger the
e-governance model of Estonia the
listeners if we turn to the event that
have shaped the cyber conflict
environment internationally then last
year we already talked here about the
one at riot act that had just wiped
across the globe and brought
considerable impact with it but then we
had not yet seen the end of June not
beta which was made to look like the
work of ordinary cyber criminals but was
in fact designed to destroy information
and brought global economic loss
measurable in billions in billions not
in millions
and here is something that we the
politicians of the Western world clearly
have to think about we can today say
that the investigations of both of these
destructive campaigns have finished and
public attribution has been made by our
good friends and allies joined also by
our government in the case of not better
but strong words will not stop those
attacks from happening again in order to
avoid them in the future we have to
change the calculation of the
government's who either organize these
attacks or just allow them to happen on
their digital infrastructure cyber
should not anymore look like an easy
weapon and using it should include some
considerable risks for the perpetrators
as well in order to achieve that we have
to be ready to use stronger tools than
we have been so far using the
government's have to be ready to respond
to the attacks the government's first of
all have to be ready to call these
attacks a violation of international law
we all know that sanctions are most
effective against those who don't have
any sanctions affecting them yet they
also easy to apply because this level of
retaliation is not legally very
demanding basically you don't have to
prove anything that much there is no
need to prove physical damages at the
level which could be seriously crippling
and thus allowing for stronger
countermeasures therefore we should not
overlook the possibility to use
political and economic responses but
then they really have to be such that
they have a deterring effect there
should also be measures to support those
who are digitally failed who are not be
able to control the attacks from the
base of their digital infrastructure out
of lack of resources or out of
complacency for example if a country is
not able to stop somebody attacking from
their infrastructure then it should have
a method and the means to call for some
international collective help and this
help should also have clear limits of
what can be done and cannot be
on that infrastructure from where others
are trying to help to stop the campaign
if Western world would make it clear by
example to other states that allowing
cyber campaigns to happen why are they
ready to tell infrastructure could bring
sanctions at least distrust we could
bring much more order into cyberspace
attributed attribution of cyberattacks
and campaigns this may be technically
challenging but it's now proven that
it's actually quite possible it's not
impossible and therefore we must make it
quite sure that our Internet's
international consensus has a way and
means on how to react we know that every
time we had to build something people
will demand proof but in cyber world
like in any other international law
cases you don't need to disclose fully
the proof attribution can be done safely
explain to partners and allies bringing
us all together to make stronger
retaliation without that it remains
cyber remains the tool which is free for
all to use the way they want talking
about maximizing effects then during
away.you council presidents in 28 member
states agreed to guidelines on how
should those political and economic
responses to a malicious cyber
activities be carried out and as the
bureaucratic work is done then of course
we as politicians will now have to do
the political work and be ready for the
political and diplomatic response of EU
if any government decides to use cyber
attacks against us and Here I am again
quite happy that in April foreign
ministers of EU were able to take the
first step to such direction by adopting
the council conclusions on malicious
cyber activities all this talk about
these measures is backed up by NATO's
decision that article 5 applies to cyber
attacks as well
that cyber has turned
into fourth domain of operations and the
policy of strategic ambiguity in regards
to the means and ways of response
because by the end of the day this is
why EU and NATO were set up in the first
place to maximize the effects of their
Member States now also in the cyber
domain finally I would like to touch
upon some of the relevant changes over
the last year in regards to the age-old
attribution issue it is true that
attribute in cyber incidents to States
will not be also in the future an easy
task
there are misperceptions and they have
held States seriously back why the
paralyzing effects have been overcome
I'm quite sure that states will now be
braver in direction but of course then
the problem is that if one or two or
three of us decide to be brave and there
is no strong reaction even if we have
administratively agreed the tools in
European Union even if we have
international law base for that then the
situation will become actually worse
than it is currently because previously
okay without coming to terms we didn't
know what to know how to do we didn't
have a framework now we do have the
framework and if we now don't use this
framework then we won't get to the state
to the stage where techie guys will tell
us that we don't want to bother with the
attribution is it's expensive and there
are no gains to be had and it's very
hard to say no the gains will be there
if quite quickly now we don't see
concrete real political gain for doing a
brave attribution exercise and going
frozen this is extremely important
naming and shaming may seem like a soft
measure especially against countries
like Russia North Korea who fiercely
deny their involvement and make it seem
like they have been deeply and unfairly
insulted and then demand concrete proof
it's not easy to stand there alone
you have to have very quick reaction
medical support to the speed which was
also when Europe and the world and NATO
was reacting to the cells per incident
in UK cyber incidents can be as
terrifying cyber incidents can be as
dangerous to our infrastructures and if
they yet now aren't so then they would
become so if they if we let them to
continue without much stronger and
clearer retaliation measures if we talk
about technicalities this was good for
the first 10 years of this conference
series as well we have to bring law in
stronger because then we will be able to
work really and reverse the current
understanding attitudes that cyber war
is free so far I feel that cyber war has
been to certain extent 3 on the other
hand I'm not also too optimistic that we
will see quick changes because in some
cases also the real war has not cost
that much to those who well keep
promoting them also in the Europe I'm
not that optimistic as you may hear but
still I think we need to strive and I
call upon all of us to continue this
work have an interesting conference have
interesting debates and discussions and
I will now leave you here to listen to
the most interesting speakers of this
conference thank you for listening
[Applause]