okay so I'm going to take up a little
bit of your time and talk about tracing
a DNS reflection attack via anycast
routing changes so first some history
first there was the Big Bang than the
earth cool this is a logarithmic time by
the way so there was the Big Bang the
earth cooled tcp/ip was invented dns was
invented and then people realized that
it makes a great system for for
launching DDoS attacks and that's that's
why we're here today so just to be clear
this is the kind of attack that I'm
talking about where there's a bad guy
who can spoof packets and he sends them
to some authoritative name server and
that name server sends a response to the
victim some particular is about about
the attacks that I'm talking about now
these are occasional attacks that were
reflecting off of the root nameservers
beginning sometime in early 2010 and
continuing for quite a while for most of
that year typical load of this attack
when it started was about 6,000 queries
per second and towards the end of the
year it was his hires about 15,000
queries per second so as a comparison
each each letter of the root server
system typically sees between ten to
thirty thousand queries per second
during normal operations these attacks
would tend to last for one or two days
sometimes less not not often longer and
one sort of distinguishing
characteristic was that the query names
in the attacks was always the same or
very consistent
so normally it's really hard to get good
data out of the the root servers but as
luck would have it at this time we were
going through the ders deployment you
know adding DNS SEC to the root zone and
there were sort of about every three
weeks there would be a new incremental
deployment and all the roots of
reporters would do another data
collection and they were uploading all
of that data to DNS work so that data is
is they are dark and that's the data
that I analyzed for this it's it's
actually quite a lot of data each one of
these little charts here represents one
data collection period from from the
root server letters that are shown on
the y-axis here so they were about let's
see I think there were nine separate
eight or nine separate data collection
periods you know some of the letters
were better at participating that than
others but it was really quite a lot of
data to go through so you know to get a
handle this what I did was went through
all that data that we had and extracted
the queries that ended with these two
names that we saw in the attack traffic
so they've been somewhat anonymous here
but all of the queries ended with one of
two second-level domain names so to that
I used this program called DNS cap which
can filter on names and this process
took quite a long time one just what one
reason is just because I just sort of
let it start it and let it run for as
long as it would run and luckily you
know the server stayed up for many
months and eventually it finished in and
then I got around to actually looking at
the data there's a little at the bottom
of the slide there's a little extract of
how the queries would look in TCP dump
so the next step was to was to put all
those queries into an SQL database
here's an exciting SQL table just just
to show you that I'm serious about SQL
I'm not joking about that and so from
from this SQL database then I could run
a number of you know SQL queries to sort
of look at the data in different ways so
I I defined an attack event as when at
the start of an event is when at least
one name server sees at least 50,000
course per second for either of these
two names and it ends when none of them
see that level of traffic and if there's
a gap of five minutes or more I say
that's the start of a new attack event
so there were different numbers of
attack events in the different data
collection periods you can see for
example on march 23rd there were four
different attack events and actually a
number another definition of an attack
event was the second-level domain had to
be the same so there's two names in
there and I think I separated name one a
name to into two separate events if they
happen to occur simultaneously here's a
graph that shows the traffic levels
during one of the attacks so this was an
early one in January and you can see
that it's it's pretty flat pretty
consistent at about 6500 queries per
second and all of the you know almost
all the roots of her letters that we
have data for are at the very top there
you can see this this blue one here this
is actually je root and this does not
represent a loss of service but it
represents a loss of collection a loss
of data collection so what likely
happened here was the the site where the
data was being collected this attack
caused the disks to fill up and then no
more data could be collected after that
time so for the most part it's flat
there's there's a few dips here and
there of course
here's an his another look at that same
event so for each of these I went
through and you know just detailed the
start time to stop time the the maximum
and the mean query rates the names that
were seen in all cases these were all
queries of type 1 these were all a
queries and I listed the source
addresses that we saw and the source
addresses were always kind of like this
you know between one and five unique
sources we assume that they're spoofed
some sources were a little bit more
popular than others for whatever reason
and between attack events the sources
tended to change so there was not a lot
of consistency in the sources between
attacks however there was a lot of
consistency in the servers that were
being hit during the attacks so this
this table here shows the these are
actually the the server and the node
names that that we used at a toe arc
when collecting the data and the the
node names or the site names tend to you
know encode their location there's a lot
of airport codes in here like JFK and
LGA LaGuardia and so on there's Miami so
these happen to be very consistent over
time for each event you know we would
always see you know I routes traffic at
the Washington node and Jay routes
traffic at the bombay node and so on I
think I think I already said everything
on this slide
so this this particular attack was a
little bit different it's it's perhaps
not immediately obvious from this slide
why it's different but it has to do with
what's what's going on here in this
region there was a number of sort of
stalactites if you will of drops and
this is the list of the servers that saw
traffic during this attack event and one
of the really interesting things was
that for the first time in this event we
saw traffic at sites that we had never
seen before so for f there was some
traffic at the Amsterdam node for Jay
there was i forget what jsu is now san
juan maybe 4k route there was you know
traffic at their links node and 4l route
there was traffic at their Los Angeles
node so that you know this is something
that's pretty interesting and this graph
shows sort of zoomed in in time where
where the traffic for each server was
was hitting and you can see for example
like on this this line for k route you
know it was going along at the normal
location which was I believe Napa the
Americas and then you know popped up two
links and then down back to the nap
Americas and did this and for all of the
sites for all the servers excuse me for
all the servers that saw a traffic shift
they all shifted it the exact same time
these sort of three events so this seems
to be some kind of glitch in in where
traffic was traffic to any cast enabled
servers shifted at exactly the same time
on these three or four sites so you know
this this seems to be some kind of
routing problem and since it affected
everybody at the same time we assume
that it happened close to the the real
source of the traffic so you know the
hypothesis as well perhaps the normal
traffic was affected in exactly the same
way here's a cartoon sort of you know
showing the idea here
there was perhaps a disrupted bgp
session that caused that traffic to to
not go there and then it shipped it to
these other as other three sites for
those any casts root servers so i made a
sort of a fingerprint of of the times
when the traffic shift did and which
servers that shifted to here's the table
for again this is for f route so at
these times the other from in two
columns these times the traffic went to
this node and then to this node and flip
back and forth and so by looking for
real traffic that shifted in the exact
same way it came up with this list of IP
addresses so all of these addresses for
these three root servers shifted at
exactly the same time in the in the same
way so it turns out all of these almost
all of those addresses fall within these
six or so net blocks which are announced
by as2 1788 here's the who is record for
for this further for those networks this
is I don't know anyone familiar with
this company of this is P but they are
also known as verse net and they're a
company that sort of specializes in
hosting and and virtual services and
that kind of thing so and other things
that sort of makes sense here is that
you know this this company is located in
the US East Coast which makes sense sort
of any caste why's that those that
traffic would be hitting root servers on
the US east coast and in Europe so to
take this a step further one is sort of
more confirmation and went back through
the other attack events to see if the
traffic from as2 1788 always at the same
nodes as the attract traffic was hitting
so it was you know it's nearly a hundred
percent match I have a bunch of boring
you know tables that show in almost all
cases it was it was 100%
so you know it seems that this that this
routing glitch which feels to me like
you know maybe the the attacker kind of
inflicted upon themselves by sending so
much traffic through there is peace
router caused a BGP session to reset
sort of outed them if you will as to
their location but the reason that this
was kind of possible was because the
root servers you know it's it's a very
diverse set of servers all around the
world and and lots of different
organizations involved in running those
servers and lots of any cast obviously
and of course the other thing that
really enabled this to happen was the
massive amount of data that we just
happened to be collecting at the same
time it has been asked of me you know is
this something that we could do in real
time maybe if you had you know enough
enough machines and to throw out it but
you would really need some way to I
guess to force these bgp sessions to to
be reset and you would need something
like the root server is a very diverse
set of of any kites i think to to be
able to see it any questions that i can
answer about about this for anybody
I have my pound set from affiliates your
last couple of statements there you're
saying it you kind of need more red and
glitches in order to try and do this in
real time but it said that that tipped
you off to what was going on but
wouldn't if you had enough data wouldn't
you be able to just do that with normal
traffic without the writing glitch just
find find all the sources that are
talking to the st. always talking to the
same servers as as your attack traffic
and I mean it wouldn't it wouldn't be
quite as good because you yeah you'd
have you put you'd have some false
positives in there it might it might
help narrow it down a lot where the
potential sources are yeah and that was
I think that was kind of my plan when I
started out with this and stumbling upon
the switch was was kind of lucky you
know but I think you're right i think
you could attempt something like that
where you try to match yeah I much
broader set anyway it might at least you
know give you you know 10 or 15 knocks
you have to call to say have you got a
ridiculous amount of traffic coming out
towards this cert you know sort of thing
rather than you know right I think I
think so yeah jean-christophe kim carr
me just to follow up on Matt's comment I
guess you you could try to triangulate
doing some trickery with your own
announcements or not just you maybe a
collaboration between the roots of
whoever's involved in this by either you
know removing your routes or adjusting
your peering and so forth and maybe
announcing certain suspect asn so they
see a loop and then they you know do
something else perhaps so something yeah
i think so i think i think i think i'm
not enough of a routing expert to say so
i would rely on others to tell me what
to put in the router config to do that
Kyle Kreutz network um I was curious if
you were only examining a records or if
because aren't txt records usually used
in reflection attacks rather than hey
records that's that's true we were
collecting all the records and and this
attack traffic was only using a queries
for whatever reason I don't know yeah
though this doesn't seem to be a case
where they were relying on the size of
the response but maybe just more on the
the volume of the response traffic
ok