good morning everyone my name is Dave
Ward I'm usually up here and talking
about how to build routers and what
what's coming next in router design or
in protocol design but instead I decided
to take an opportunity today to talk
about a general trend that's going on in
in networking and it's really about
programmable networking and there's a
lot of shiny objects that can really
distract you or potentially even confuse
you when trying to understand what's
going on with all the different
mechanisms that are available for
programmable networking and the
information that's available in the
network now following before I get into
this talk following Kevin's talk being
the slow vendor up here I also do want
to mention that these large interfaces
are available from vendors and in fact
perhaps operators could could also
increase their uptake of the new
technology but that was basically
required I said that after Kevin told me
I was too slow alright so let's jump
into this talk so I the talk is named
programmable networking is safe for work
and that's really because there is a
very large trend as I just mentioned in
a number of different interfaces that
are available for application developers
to actually fundamentally get
information from your network as well as
program devices on the network to keep
it very simple and to start off this
this conversation building up to where I
want to get to with respect to
technology application developers are
wholly interested in the experience they
can provide for their particular
customers this is obvious whether it's
high definition video or its location
based services for social networking or
whatever the case might be their goal is
to get the best experience possible out
of the internet and clearly as as
network operators your goal is to
connect everyone to everything and
everyone to everyone else of course and
but the issue that we fundamentally have
is that application developers and
here's the fundamental assumption which
we can which we can discuss a little bit
later is the fundamental assumption is
that application developers today don't
have a good understanding of the weather
report of the net
they don't know where things are located
necessarily they don't know what the
utilization of the network is they don't
know what access link speed might be
available to the particular other user
or subscriber whatever the case might be
that they want to talk to and so this
fundamental wall between what the
network can give to application
developers and what the application
developers need from the internet is
what needs to what needs to change the
next assumption that i'm going to make
and this is a perhaps one of these
visionary kinoti type things is that the
application developer who actually is
the first to program either devices on
the internet to create specific paths
for the service they want to offer or to
be able to get information out of the
internet like a weather report of
utilization is going to be the one that
holds the next lottery ticket and what I
mean by this or the next winning lottery
ticket in particular and what I mean by
this is that clearly when taking a look
at applications that are available on
the iPhone or whatever the case is folks
are attempting to pick up that winning
lottery ticket by just pushing more and
more and more applications out there and
differentiation of these applications is
generally based upon the experience and
information that can be delivered and so
leading up to this the goal is really to
describe what is what's coming down the
pike and what's really different so
applications today when taking a look at
the network are really just guessing
they're attempting to divine what's
going on on the network there blindly
probing and trying to ferret out this
information by using gaming ping stats
or there's proprietary codecs or there's
control channels for variable bitrate
video or they're using who is type
technology to find which which
autonomous system or which provider has
a particular bit of data that's not
suing them at one particular period of
time really there's no fundamental
interaction to get this data out of the
internet to find either the best
location for content or the best way to
deliver this service I can't tell you
how much it drives me crazy that for
example proprietary control channels
attempting to scavenge bandwidth out of
the network are being proliferated left
right and center when in
the network has the information directly
and if they just asked and if we just
had the ability to give them some
information the switch in and
understanding when HD is available vs SD
when to scavenge for a certain amount of
bandwidth would be possible this would
be a much more efficient way to do it
then a very aggressive algorithm of
everyone attempted to compete with each
other for this particular bit of
bandwidth that could be available now on
the converse side as networking
professionals we're really spending a
whole lot of money and a whole lot of
time and a whole lot of effort trying to
figure out what's going on on the
internet itself there's deep packet
inspection xand stateful flow foo bars
and all sorts of other different things
that are being implemented in the
network really just to try and find
application signatures such that
interesting things like application
based billing or just understanding if
there's some good behavior or bad
behavior going on on the network in
addition to this whether their IP data
records or whatever the case is for an
attempt to find out when a user has gone
above a particular bandwidth threshold
for any particular purpose is about the
current state of the art we actually
could no more information the eff
applications would simply tell the
network so on both sides of this
conversation whether their applications
trying to divine something about the
network or the internet trying to figure
out what's flowing across the network
they're very expensive as well as
cumbersome behaviors and trying to
figure this out so really what I'm
leading up to is that these four
different actors need to come together
in a coordinated fashion whether it's
the application where it needs to know
it would like to know i should say the
end the end device capabilities
proximity to a particular bit of content
etc whether content which is located
somewhere in the network can either be
placed somewhere else or we can find out
where to select it based upon analytics
of the server and we'll get into
examples of this in a second we have the
end user who knows what they're looking
for and we have the network which has
fundamental information of understanding
where is an end user where is the
content
what is the what is the application if
we could interact amongst these four
actors we could probably do something
better and there's gonna be a number of
talks about some of the fundamental
technologies over the next couple of
days on pulling these together in use
cases that can arise out of this so
let's move this a little bit forward and
talk about why networks and applications
need to work together so really what I'm
trying to say is that it's not just
programming the network it's not just an
application programming a device with a
specific service profile or programming
some VLAN tag there's actual
bi-directional information that's
possible for the network to give to
applications and so when I described
programmable networking it is this
two-way communication so as I mentioned
already if the application has the
ability to inform the network and the
network can give fundamental intrinsic
information back to the application we
then can begin to talk about how we can
affect in bias traffic steering on the
network to either preserve fundamental
bandwidth that's available in the core
or in particular to increase the
experience that's available and so
towards this end what I'm what I'd like
to describe is that there's a number of
touch points available in the network
that we traditionally hadn't considered
to be as programmatic points and these
can come from either on be NGS or be
razzes for subscriber termination or use
their termination today the state of the
art is effectively using radius diameter
cops packet cable whatever the case
might be to program a subscribers
profile and no doubt i'd say Triple Play
services voice video and high-speed
Internet these are well established and
have been deployed to a great deal
across the internet but what we've
gotten to the point is now is that the
high speed internet class where the
over-the-top traffic is coming in
whether it's peer-to-peer downloads or
whatever the case might be this
a bandwidth is the class that being
scavenged and aggressively trying to be
scavenged amongst a variety of different
applications and we know that the the
time and ability to turn radius diameter
or cops profiles to program these
subscribes sorry to program these
subscriber profiles these delays are far
too long the the current mindshare or or
a group think of what's a cool
application today or what's a cool bit
of download or whatever the whatever the
case might be these things are fast and
fleeting that they they're they're
completely ephemeral now towards that
end if we had the ability to program
this high speed internet class from
different applications that are part of
a subscribers profile we'd have the
ability to deliver better experience now
as you've been reading hopefully the
other touch points or other points where
we can program on the internet these are
all different what i would call
perimeters of the internet these are all
different locations where you actually
can derive where a subscriber or user
lands on the internet itself they can be
VPN gateways they can be trying to try
to go after a particular bit of content
once you have awareness of what an
application or subscribers trying to do
on the network you can build specific
profiles at each of these points these
are all of the programmatic points on
the internet or many classes of them
that we need to be interested in when
building out to the entire portfolio of
different service profiles that are
possible and we'll come back and we'll
touch on some of these with some some
actual use cases so what's possible so
applications or services can be made
better by getting a weather report of
what's going on on the internet
proximity to content proximity to a
server are some very very easy ones to
understand in addition by just
understanding the access link that your
friends or family are attached to you
understand the type of quality of
service you can get out of this and the
same at the same time there's been a
quite a bit of conversation recently
about networks being made better by
information from applications and really
here
trying to be described as you do have
the ability to optimize bandwidth or
resource reservation you can spin up new
specific service topologies very very
rapidly through some of these interfaces
so let's get into the point of where we
talk about how they actually work
together and what's key to this
conversation just pausing for a second
is that there are a number of very high
level conversations that are going on
about different programming points of
the internet and all of them appear
potentially to be solving a large number
of problems and they all appear to be
solving all problems on the planet
whether it's virtualizing data centers
whether it's sorry whether it's
virtualizing data centers whether it's
building the service profiles for
subscribers whether it's populating
content caches what's interesting about
all of them is that they all are
independent ways to program the internet
all attempting to duplicate connectivity
between two different points they keep
the key to remember when looking at
these different technologies is that we
aren't necessarily going to reinvent the
internet and all of the protocols with
any new particular way of program the
internet or any new technology the key
is how these technologies are going to
integrate directly with the internet and
the networks that we have deployed
anyone who's been around for a while
understands that if we go back to a
world where we're again signaling
permanent virtual circuits Allah x.25
ATM frame relay across all the network
we're going to have a huge control state
problem and in fact really what we're
trying to do is find a way to take
advantages of programming specific
devices and take advantages of giving
applications and services information
from the network in conjunction with
what's deployed so we so really we're
talking about what's authentic what
already exists and this will be some of
the use cases that I'm going to bring up
in just a second so the technology
that's really emerging is is multifold
and I'll and I'll bring it into a
layered perspective in just a second so
again today what we're trying to convert
from is where we're intuitive
information from the network on
application side or from the networking
point of view again we have geo
coordinates proprietary control
protocols the network is using DPI's net
flows IP data records and then we're
trying to get to a point where we're
communicating this information now the
challenge of trying to do this is that
there's a zillion different stacks out
there which are again getting a lot of
conversational highlights in the trade
rags cloud stacks openstax whatever the
case might be open flows which Rob
sherwood will talk about over the next
couple of days but also there's been a
trend and it may not have been visible
to understand that there was actual some
architectural thought behind this but
there's been a trend over the last 10
years for communicating this information
within the protocols that we currently
have designed such that we can extend
api's and extend information that's
being transmitted via these protocols in
a variety of different categories so
first is path computation element brief
bit of history path computation element
was originally built or constructed for
inter autonomous system traffic
engineering and and path set up that
sounds fine we didn't we didn't really
have a very easy ways of doing that but
what's interesting is that once you have
a server that you can program to that
can communicate with routers to set up
paths between endpoints we have
reinvented soft pvcs and I bring this up
because I have a long career of
reinventing things many many times and
in fact what I want to highlight it in
all of these cases is that by reusing
technology that we know and understand
very very well we can use these two
obviously benefit not only application
developers and the services on the
internet but the quality of experience
on the Internet itself so we'll start
with path computation element and I'll
build these up in a couple slides the
next is Jeanette and you might say well
what the hell is Jennifer I haven't even
heard of this thing
so what generic application extensions
to the igp SR is the ability to pass
application information or application
server information within and within
interior gateway protocol like is is or
ospf now you say oh for the love of God
the last thing we need to do is overload
these routing protocols with more crap
and thanks Dave for reinventing that one
well there's good news I didn't
necessarily invent it to overt or it
wasn't invented to necessarily be
transmitted directly with the routing
information we learned some lessons and
we realize that in some cases we need to
disseminate information via via flooding
protocol ospf and I esaias are very good
at disseminating information but we
don't want this to be passed with the
routing information we know that we want
routing to converge faster than we
necessarily want application data to be
sent so there's been over the number of
years there's been inventions of
multi-instance of these interior gateway
protocols and now there's the ability to
pass generic application information so
now if you wanted to for example say
that you have an at a firewall or some
kind or a dpi service at a particular
location you can pass this without
fundamentally decreasing router sorry
for a fundamental increasing router
convergence or decreasing performance on
the Internet moving through some of
these others that will talk about and
I'll talk about a little bit more detail
which is Alto the application layer
traffic optimization protocol will hold
s for a second but really the point is
that over the last couple of years folks
have been trying to build protocols that
we can begin to signal and and
communicate the best location via
proximity of a user or application to
that particular service and then the
last one which is just recently emerging
is BGP with traffic engineering
extensions and once again I recommend
you to remain calm when I talk about
putting more information into BGP
because that generally gets people upset
again we have realized that it's
possible to pass information in BGP
without using the same peering session
that's passing routing information bgp
can also be multi-instance now also the
next thing that generally gets people
upset
we're talking about traffic engineering
and bgp and they say for the love of God
we don't need to be able to signal
traffic engineered pass with BGP well
that's not what this is about this is
merely about passing interior gateway to
apology information and traffic in
traffic engineering information in a BGP
container across a normal operational
control plane like route reflection
servers such that you have full view of
a piece of a pop or the entire topology
available via one control mechanism and
I say this because again if you step
back and take a look at survey the
protocols of how you would get topology
information say into this Alto protocol
or how you get to apology information in
general we've spent a lot of time
arguing at various standards bodies of
it must be is is it must be ospf it must
be bgp it must be any of these things
these arguments are a complete waste of
all of our time and I say they're
complete waste of all of our time
because we don't have the capacity as an
industry to be able to have this you
know 42 different ways of doing the same
thing and again stepping back most
networks are built out of a control or
management functionality in which route
reflection servers actually exist and
therefore maintaining the common
protocol that's being used with respect
to manageability and putting this
information into BGP made perfect sense
next and the last piece and I'm still
introducing the subject is that we're
putting yet more information in BGP and
again hold your coffee really the the
situation when we put in CDN information
to bgp and this can be both the users
that are possible to be reached in a
particular geographic area and I said
geographic very specifically in this
case the users that are reachable in a
geographic area or the content that's
reachable via a particular peering point
these are new extensions that you're
going to see rise so tying this all back
to what we want to be able to do with
programmable networks we have
fundamental protocol building blocks to
pass information up to applications via
comment
pathways using our protocols yet not
affecting routing and we have well known
perimeter points at which we can
actually now program service profiles
program paths across the network and
fundamentally bias the service and
experience we're going to get across
across the network the key is how to do
this without breaking the system and I
know I asked you to hold your coffee
several times already this morning but
really my story that I'm trying to tell
you today is that we in fact can do this
without breaking the entire internet and
causing our routing peering sessions to
go down and causing fundamental crashing
left right and center if we're worried
about the fragility of our particular
protocols so what I've built up from the
bottom in this particular slide are the
network api's this is what you know me
your vendor is going to be building out
of the into the system and really they
come from fundamental constructs of
what's available in routing protocols as
well as fundamental constructs of
programmatic interfaces that currently
exist in to these perimeter points so I
already alluded to the fact that one of
the perimeter points of subscriber
termination is using radius and diameter
radius and diameter just summarizing
quickly has inside the device been
abstracted to a single common
communication channel between the
control plane and the forwarding plane
of the router this has basically been
done ubiquitously across all vendors
that being said it's actually very
straightforward for a particular routing
vendor to take a common API or sorry a
common abstraction of what that internal
protocol looks like at that and turn it
into an API versus getting locked into
radius and diameter same thing the same
thing goes for these other bits of
technology now what's interesting about
this is frequently you can get confused
to think that an application developer
is going to be writing directly to these
api's that are on the router themselves
and that isn't the story that I want to
tell because most application developers
and think about the folks are out there
coding up farmville or mob wars or some
other stuff that I don't understand why
anybody would want to do but but
nonetheless these folks are thinking
about programming and thinking about
delivering experience fundamentally
differently
then delivering it on the network we
don't necessarily want the guy who wrote
farmville to write directly and use a
BGP interface we know that already right
we don't want you know I don't need to
continue what they're going to see
instead our orchestration platforms that
are on top of these networking api's our
goal as networking operators and
professionals is to get this information
out and available on to these
orchestration platforms that the
application developer who's building the
next video service that wants to run
over HD using variable bitrate video or
the next mlb.com and this isn't a pitch
for them or the next what farmville on
steroids they are going to be right into
that orchestration platform they're
going to be coming to you and saying I
would like to run this over your network
and you would like to have business with
them to deliver it with the best
experience possible so they're going to
see these orchestration platforms
they're going to see the weather report
and proximity information on the network
via real-time topology information and
real-time utilization information
towards this end again we've talked
about proximity information we've talked
about taking te information just a quick
digression with respect to traffic
engineering information this this may be
a shock but we've reached the point
where we're where there are new
attributes are going to be passed that
include things like delay now I've been
around for a little bit and I understand
the issues of doing delay based routing
with respect to what happened in ARPANET
many many years ago but the mere fact
that we are not passing delay constant
associated with our paths not
necessarily using it for active or even
protection path back up at the fact that
we aren't using it at all in our
calculations the time has come where we
need to be able to talk about this again
and these variables need to come back so
delay variants loss on a path
utilization on a path these are things
that have been a long time coming I
realize that it's been over 20 years or
even over 25 years since the last time
that their attempts to use to lay based
routing were on the internet but we do
not need to take the same approach and
technique that was taken 25 years ago
we do need these variables available to
us as network operators as well as to
application developers to increase or
improve the experience on the internet
so this real-time topological firm ation
and real-time weather report information
is now fundamentally available coming
out of the out of the network but again
let's make sure the farmville guys are
recording this stuff up those frat boys
are only coding to the orchestration
platform and not touching the the
routers themselves we've already talked
about steering traffic and building soft
PVCs up through through path computation
element and Rob will be talking about
open flow in a little bit but in some
just quickly open flow is the technology
in which and it's the only technology in
which you have the ability to program
with high-performance real-time
ephemeral classifiers that are not held
in the router's configuration file
they're coming from application space in
being jammed directly into the
forwarding plane so you can think of
this as a traffic selection mechanism a
program programmatic traffic selection
mechanism it's a current shiny object
that's being discussed quite a bit but
at the same point it has high utility
for a particular bit of functionality
that isn't otherwise available and I've
already reached on these on these new
touch points so let me build up just a
little bit further on these protocols
and really what we're trying to
accomplish with them so when we talk
about what we want Alto for and it's
again application layer traffic
optimization from an application space
what you're asking the network is where
is it located on the internet and how
far is it from me and you're going to
see I'll walk you through an example is
just a second that's what we're
fundamentally trying to accomplish from
application space the next piece with
respect to path computation and path
computation element building soft bbc's
is basically how do I get from where I
am to where it is and how can i
dynamically program and using the
current signaling control and signaling
mechanisms on the internet to get me
there we've got policy enforcement and
as I mentioned open flow is excellent
program in these classifiers and there's
other mechanisms as well
and then the last one is just service
location which is basically object based
routing and this is part of bgp CDN work
these are the fundamental building
blocks where is where is it on the
internet where's my object how do I get
there and make sure only my traffic gets
there such that I don't have to compete
against everybody else with this
particular service offering as for
fundamental building blocks these this
is really what's underneath it all in
understanding how these different pieces
come together now what the application
developer is going to see are these
orchestration and development platforms
and I've segmented into these four
different pieces traditional IT which is
OSS BSS stuff and you know again there's
a number of different ways to perform
device subscriber management and there's
entire industries and have been for
decades and trying to build up these
billing and subscriber profiles and
again sorry turning this into billing
information there's network function
specific pieces and this is where
there's lots and lots of shiny objects
to to for us to get distracted and
confused over witten comes from either
service level monitoring over-the-top
virtualization path management unified
communication there's umpteen different
elements or programmatic interfaces that
are being currently espoused out there
that can solve all the problems just
understand what they're trying to
accomplish and they're trying to
accomplish network function specific
tasks the next of course would be
services service specific and I segment
this out because here really it's
related to more related to social
networking and location ID information
and what you can do with location
information when building up a
particular service whether it's social
media whatever the cases and we'll get
to that in a second and then the last
one is a provider based development
platform so looking at these four OSS
BSS network functions service functions
and provider based platforms are the
main categories that are used in my use
cases so these provider based platforms
what becomes very very interesting about
these and being from California on the
peninsula south of San Francisco these
are
several of the operators that currently
have application innovation centers
being built or currently working on the
peninsula themselves now what's
interesting about this and the reason
why these large telcos and msos are
doing this is kind of obvious they want
to capture some of this itunes in an
application frenzy that's out there it
appears to be just giant you know bag
full of cash that are available there
are and that's good and that's a
perfectly fine reason to go after the
business but what I've tried to build up
into this conversation is that these
telcos and MSOs and every Network
actually has information that will
fundamentally make these applications
better than a simple over-the-top based
service and if farmville switch it sorry
if the folks code into farmville switch
from coding say a facebook platform and
this is nothing against facebook so some
remain calm again and switch over to
these development platforms the point
I'm trying to make is that they
automatically reach half of the world's
population and two-thirds of the world's
gdp there is a whole lot of potential
here for programmatic networks and
there's a whole lot of potential for
these applications to really hit it big
if they can provide a better service
than was done just straight over the top
competing in an aggressive scavenging
mechanism as is otherwise done so let me
give you a couple of examples and we'll
walk through some of these use cases
there they're pretty straightforward
meaning that I think we've heard heard
about them quite a bit whether it's
content and service routing whether it's
locating the best content or populating
caches MapReduce stuff which is done to
a great scale by the search companies
network operations whether it's vm
mobility storage i/o etc cloud bursting
so let's walk through a few of these but
before we hit these direct examples I'm
going to tie together this technology
such that you can understand how it's
being used in these use cases and tying
together this technology is a
combination of a few of these
programmatic techniques so what I'm
trying to describe is that if I know
that Dave and I want to communicate in
Amman California and he's in Oregon and
we want to build a specific
communication
channel I need to know where Dave is an
Oregon and I want to build a particular
path to get there and let's say I me to
use traffic engineering but what's
interesting of course is that once I
built that traffic engineering path any
of my data or any of the data around me
could potentially use that path to get
to Dave but if I am program classifiers
in front of that such that my specific
service or my specific my specific
service that I want to work out with
Dave is all that will Traverse this
particular tunnel and we've reserved a
certain amount of bandwidth we now have
instead of having a traffic engineer
path coined as a service engineered path
and really what this comes down to is my
application that's building the service
can set up the soft PVC or set up the
path between Dave and I can program the
specific admit deny criteria and my
service has a certain amount of reserve
band with a certain experience that I'm
going to have between Dave and myself so
by building up a couple of these common
building blocks or using a couple these
common building blocks we can actually
easily create something new and better
than what we had in the past so towards
this end one example is what can you do
with this technology you can basically
attempt to build pools of service
applications or service appliances now
today taking a look at edge routers I
say the average somewhere between 13 and
20 different service appliances are
currently surround subscriber
terminating edge routers these are
physically bound via orange or yellow
cables directly to that single edge
router what's interesting is that they
cannot be used easily or cannot be used
at all by other edge routers so what
this technology can do again when you
classify specific traffic and have the
ability to do service backhaul if you
want to think of it that way is you can
now take these service appliances and
pull them together in a data center or
in a pop and have them just be seen as
increments of bandwidth scale or
performance so that now they now these
service implyin TSA's can be shared
amongst multiple edge routers and these
can be distributed or they clearly can
be pooled all the way back into
centralized data center there's no
topological and it fits directly into
that analogy of doing service backhaul
because again you've classified only
this
at traffic again it doesn't have to be
all of Dave's traffic it could just be
his port 80 traffic that's back called
to a scrubber to understand why he's out
of bounds on his band with threshold or
whatever your example might be this also
is an extremely powerful way to build
service-specific topologies across a
network setting up setting up te paths
just a set of service topologies nothing
new bread and butter what what is
relatively new is that in combination
with the ability to program ephemeral
classifiers into the forwarding plane I
can dynamically build the profiles and
modify the traffic or flows that are
going across the specific profiles it's
not bound to some multi-week multi-month
multi-year deployment of some particular
new service instead this can be
extremely rapid I mentioned also for a
Content request routing and I'll build
this up through a really clear example
hopefully so really what we're trying to
do is have a user query the network
where is the best place to get my
content and that's what this altar
servers is actually building or is
actually based upon it can give Network
proximity it can do a reverse SPF to a
particular user to understand where
they're located on the network we can
build a network server load congestion
etc and for that content routing request
you can get the best answer to deliver
the best experience so let me show you
how this basically works assume that
there's three users whatever the case
might be New York London and Paris and
there's three data centers Chicago
London and Amsterdam users simply saying
more applications saying where do I go
get this data and they're going to go
use DNS or a web plug-in that that web
plug-in or behind the DNS actually would
be this application layer traffic
optimization server that says where are
you where's the content let's use the
shortest path to get there we'll add in
a little bit on network utilization as
well in combination because the service
or application is going to particular
media center or media media server those
media servers can reply back saying
here's my load here's the number of
connections I
here's the might of bandwidth that I
have available to pump out and the union
of this two pieces of data then network
information proximity information and
weather report as well as the the media
server load can be constructed and built
into the best answer and so you're going
to get per site whether your network
sorry new york london or paris / site
based upon your view of the network and
where you're located the best media
server to go to and in this particular
case New York is supposed to go to
Chicago now being from Minneapolis
Chicago is rarely the right answer but
in this example it is now somebody's
listening good okay so so towards this
end I'm just going to skip over and
basically show that media servers can
use thresholds like load and a number of
connections to divert traffic in real
time and really what that means is that
Alto will direct the traffic the best
based upon network proximity up down
status and congestion and the media
server will override with respect to how
the how the load is on the media server
the next example which is again
relatively straightforward in particular
in particular if you have a video
service and you need to either deliver
that content to cash's or distribute
data or the other easy case to
understand as a data center back up when
you have to move 10 terabytes of data
long distance over the land and you have
a necessarily constrained when bandwidth
where you can't ness place 10 terabytes
at any time of the day or anything at
any particular location you want to
calendar that bandwidth onto the network
based upon priority so again service
placement data center back up and cloud
orchestration so the first thing we want
to do is schedule and reserve that path
and we're going to use this
orchestration layer and we can
demonstrate that yeah you can submit
your job that I want to move 10
terabytes between new york and Reykjavik
and I need to do this at medium priority
and I want to do this between midnight
and 6am European time or whatever the
case might be and the key is we don't
want to push all of the network state up
into the application we don't want the
application to
have to derive what the topology is or
understanding how to set up a path or
work with other multiple nms EMS systems
to be able to do this and instead use
the pieces that are available which is
that what's the real-time topology
understanding which is go query Alto
server to say what's where are these
particular locations on the network and
what is the topology look like between
these two points we want to be able to
set up this path again only between
twelve and six so we'll use a soft PVC
mechanism and the application will
program the two endpoints and say build
me a path off we go we're going to then
make sure that only specific data is
traversing that path and we'll use open
flow to be able to program that the
application developer actually would not
see any of that they would just say I
want to send this traffic between these
two points and a priority and you as an
operator would be the one who would be
managing those those particular
priorities knowing that these api is
underneath are underneath now also
towards this end the key is that as an
operator you want to be able to affect
the algorithm that's used to place this
bandwidth it could be a water filling
algorithm where it's just you know put
it on there where it fits the other one
of course could be bin packing which is
I want the ability to push traffic away
from these particular paths to be able
to load it in a loop free path that
meets my SLA or might delay guarantees
for this particular backup that's the
intersection of the two you've got the
network api's that are being exposed to
this development platform the
application developers doing what they
do which is just look I need to back up
my data I don't want to worry about this
topology stuff you meet at the two and
you can control how that bandwidth is
going to be placed on the network cloud
bursting is is the next really really
popular topic or sorry really popular
use case in this particular part of the
industry and really what the whole goal
of cloud bursting is that I'm a private
enterprise I need some more compute or
storage I don't have it available in my
data center I think I'm gonna go grab
some out of ec2 or a zoo or whatever the
case is real quickly and I'm going to
finish up my computation off I go this
is the most common
a use case used by the OpenFlow folks
and it works really really well and
really what it is is how to extend an l2
domain from my data center to a remote
data center at a particular point in
time and all that I'll save some more
for Rob the last example I want to give
a social networking and you know cheaply
i call it today's wheel of misfortune
because in social networking and
location ID which is a massive topic
going on in trade rags right now is all
the location sorry all the services you
can do on location ID information and
what's interesting is that there's a
number of categories that end up trying
to use this information from gaming
through social stuff advertising of
course and commerce people trying to
inject coupons on to your mobile phone
and all the rest of it but what's really
interesting to me is that there's an
untapped mine of information that's in
the network that folks aren't using to
be able to build better location based
services really really straightforward
stuff am i on a laptop at nanog or am i
on my mobile phone walking around about
town if you knew the difference between
the access technology of who you want to
communicate with you could deliver a
better service and better experience
this giving information about the access
link out of the network is bread and
butter of what we know and what we can
do and then the rest of these other bits
of information that perhaps you're
reading what are the capabilities of
that device and network what's the
proximity to some cash or server that
this service may be using as a third
party these types of things again our
bread and butter of what we can
understand out of the network as well as
bandwidth in billing profiles am i close
to my limit do I want to build that
information into the service as a
network operator by giving this
information available to these
application platforms you can
fundamentally by us how they're going to
be built on to your network if we can
continue down the path that we are today
which is that there's no information
coming out of the network then there's
absolutely no way that you will give
them the ability to affect their
experience or you will have the ability
to control what that applications doing
on the network itself what I find really
interesting is that
is that the three fundamental
architectures that are being used for
location-based services which is either
you're above the topology like a looped
or four square type service or you're
visualizing the topology like navteq or
you're below the topology and trying to
build location-based services into an
operating system like Android or iOS
these these are relatively simplistic
and very very basic understandings of
the topology all you have the ability to
do is say I'm here and you can do this
through active broadcast and an active
broadcast of where you are is by
checking in and yeah it's kind of fun to
know who's in a restaurant but again
these coordinates these GSM coordinates
give you information of how to drive to
your buddy who's in the nearby
restaurant it doesn't give you any
information about the quality of service
or experience that you could have with
them I don't I don't fundamentally
understand why navigational coordinates
are a fundamental interest to
location-based ID accept the fact it's
the only information about the topology
that and that an operating system on a
mobile phone actually has access to and
so if we increase the information that
that operating system had then I would I
believe that we could build a much much
more interesting and rich service
delivery experience so towards that end
the information that's bread and butter
that exists in the network today that's
possible to be given out is you're here
you have this access technology you have
this capability the network has this
utilization associated with it and
here's that service profile and these
are the things around you its content
resources places people and their
capabilities as well and so I think we
can we can get beyond the basic
fundamentals of how geo location based
services are being done and we can
improve upon it so what did I just say
basically there is an architecture of
what's being built and what's being
designed of information that's coming
out of the topology in the APA the
network api's that are emerging out of
our routers switches and routing
protocols etc these are being plugged
into development platforms large PTT SMS
OS are all over this as
we already discussed and there's a lot
to be gained a lot of people that can be
reached in a lot of potential revenue
that can be garnered also what's
important is that this is a critical
period in which it's it's selected how
this information is going to get out and
how fast it's going to get up it's very
very challenging to overcome the
over-the-top issues that may exist with
respect to bandwidth scavenging on the
network this is one of those techniques
which is to realize that the network can
give out information that an application
can use to make it better and an
application can an application that you
can control can program the network to
deliver a higher quality service so
towards that end I'll finish at this
point with just a few minutes left if
there's any questions but thank you very
much
any questions any questions about 100
Gig interfaces there you go I'll repeat
if that helps hello go ahead you're a
Valencians Georgia Tech I thank you very
talk very interesting I had a question
so you you covered a lot of technology
but could you comment more on money
flows you know who would pay home and
you know let's say Zynga or or farmville
would they pay for this and when they
have a choice of just scavenging the
band so money flows realise I'm I'm a
vendor so I already have a perspective
on which way the money flows but kidding
aside so I would imagine that Zynga
would be wanting to get into
collaboration and this is my fundamental
assumption that Zynga would want to get
into collaboration with networking sorry
network operators or autonomous system
service providers that are willing to
play this game if they can deliver a
better service over a particular network
then they would be interested in having
money flow in that direction and if
users are willing to have a better
experience over one particular network
or another money generally would follow
that as well that's the fundamental
assumption again I am NOT economist I
just play one at this podium I Patrick
Gilmore from akamai technologies so 100
gig interfaces when are they going to be
less than 10 by 10 gig interfaces less
money less money because from a network
operator standpoint the difference
between a hundred gig interface and 10
10 gig interfaces is a wiring problem
unless it costs too much money right and
so you want us to use hundred gig why
don't make it worth our while if you
were selling 10 gigs at 12 times agee
how many people would be using them or
how many people would have been using
them in the past so I think we're going
to have very nice weather in
Philadelphia this week it should be an
80s or so so I so the pricing question
is very different from an engineering
perspective so okay I can I can help
going back to the most excellent talk
actually thank you very much it was
useful and packed with information which
is
not always common so thank you for that
but when I read when I'm watching this
while I'm thinking this could be really
good a few things obviously pop out the
first is this very clearly range
gigantic alarm bells about things like
network neutrality and you the answer to
your last question actually even
highlighted that so you're going to have
services that can pay for better serve
it better performance or you're going to
have network operators who also happen
to be I don't know for instance MSOs or
say telcos that run their own cable TV
service and they're streaming for
instance could be prioritized over
somebody else's streaming you know what
happens when Netflix is competing with
18 t u-verse and one of them is picked
in this path you have a decision matrix
there that is opaque to anybody outside
of the network and then the network
itself is deciding whether they're know
their information is prioritized I
realize that we already have that
problem today but this as they say pumps
it up a notch so wondering just how far
are you going to be able to ads the
vendor here running the server in the
middle how far you going to be able to
make information public that the network
is going to feel maybe not public but
transparent to the users of it that the
network's not going to feel is giving
too much information about their own
infrastructure oh that's a very good
question so it's actually loaded with a
whole bunch of carefully laid landmines
there so so uh so with respect to what
can be done this technology I think
first and foremost if we want to help
address let's say seven some of Kevin's
issues that he talked about earlier with
respect to not a band with growing on
his network if let's say he's going to
deploy caches it generally seems to be
something that folks do and now there's
content available in a particular cache
in a particular area that isn't the one
that you're reaching at if he had the
ability to apply policy of where
requests for content is going to go in
particular cache and it other goes to
the closest one or then it goes to the
one that's that meets the SLA meaning
that it's actually not overly loaded etc
these are some fundamental ways that
that can be moved forward I'm completely
sidestepping the net neutrality
conversation as you might notice but
really my point is is that we can start
earlier without jumping directly
into an FCC legal situation by actually
improving the network without stepping
in that line landmine or is there a loot
possibility that specific services can
be built with higher quality than others
and it can be biased absolutely that can
be done today this is these are just
more flexible tools to be able to do
that as well for services that are being
provided by a particular provider at
this point i mean i'm not going to skirt
the issue of net neutrality but there's
not much i can say about it at this
particular point given FCC's position
mmm pretty good answer Thanks hi Jeff
Sachs from Blue Ridge internet works you
said that in this slide nearly at the
end you showed that network operators
could sorry network operators could
provide all this wonderful information
to the application platforms and to the
local maybe iPhones or whatever and
including great deal of information
about what bandwidth was available and
what caches were available and that
seems like very valuable information why
do you think that the network operators
would actually be willing to provide
that to the to the farmville developer
and also there there were some things on
the side as to which other people and
and you know objects we're also nearby
and why do you think those people would
be willing to provide their their
locality to to the application so if you
think about it this way so let me go
from your second point backwards so if
I'm already checking in at a particular
restaurant I've already given out the
information of where I'm located in
topology what we're adding on top of
that or could add on top of that is
utilization of that path am i able to
send you real-time video from you know
what I'm doing at this end of the
comcast festival versus your end of the
comcast festival last night if I if I
know that I can't do that in HD don't
send it in HD dont and dont give you a
blocky type of transmission so the goal
in this particular case is if the
information is already given out then
you can do something better with it
because we have the information so the
first piece that you asked about
was why would an operator want to give
this out to farmville an operator would
want to give this out so that when with
and I'm going to take a different
example of silverlight or adobe move
with their control channel / variable
bitrate video right now the api's look
like you can open up and sorry they work
over multiple tcp sessions to begin with
and that API looks like oh you have a
dial from zero to say a thousand a
thousand TCP sessions that could be used
for this video what's the first thing
that every programmer does a thousand is
more than zero so therefore I'm going to
turn this up to a thousand it's the
number one thing that's done they
attempt to amp up all of that all of the
aggressiveness that they possibly can of
that control channel to deliver the best
video it's exactly what you'd expect
them to do if instead underneath silver
letter move was information about
utilization of the network in real time
and instead of having an aggressive
control channel the control channel
would in addition go and say is it even
worth my time is the bandwidth even
available should i tune this down for
better experience of the multitude of
folks looking at this video you have the
potential to do that so why would it
operator want to do that they would want
to do that to again deliver the best
experience over their network as well as
dampen the the aggressive nature of the
current algorithms that are out there
trying to scavenge bandwidth or scavenge
information or derive information if
that made sense how many more questions
going to take Randy take the rest of
them and then we'll close lines up to
this okay go ahead Randy right up Porsha
Oh John don't you get the role in
Jennings Bryan toward for the silver
tongue in making the most complex
proposal I've ever heard um to vastly
complicate my network to solve a problem
that i can throw bandwidth that instead
of throwing money to you so um um to
answer the first gentleman's question
about economics um but the real worry i
have somebody touched on at the privacy
issue the security issue this is a
complex evolution of something that God
died about three times used to be called
active networking and and those things
and wondering and they all died on the
security vine and wondering that seemed
to be kind of missing here the security
privacy the the network neutrality
issues are in a sense part of that etc
and when I don't hear it I worry that
you're going to paint it on afterwards
and we know how well that works with
security instead of seeing it at the
base of the architecture so William
would you spin the silver tongue on
security again we're gonna have
wonderful weather here this week in
Philadelphia so the security issue I
don't think I've fundamentally so at
first of all obviously I didn't
fundamentally address it there is no
doubt about that branding others are
correct I also didn't I believe mention
anything that isn't already done or
isn't already known in particular when I
take a look at how networks are trying
to become aware of application space and
the deep packet fubar is an stateful
flow nonsense and all this other stuff
that's out there and deployed this the
the aspect of security and privacy in
particular and I'll focus on that one is
a problem that i'm completely
sidestepping and I'm completely
sidestepped
because what I'm trying to do is
potentially remove all of the deep
packet foo bars etc and instead if if an
application does want to put something
on a particular network they can at
least interact with a network at this
point so I I don't want to completely
silver tongue this Randy and basically
say I'm either punting or I'm doing
something otherwise but if I can remove
the full peeking and poking into all
flows and all information that currently
is the only way to derive this
information from a network point of view
and open this up for active
communication to go back and forth I'd
actually say it's at least a opt-in
proposal versus a what is what is
somebody scavenging about all my flows
sooo yeah August so sue hairs long time
v GP or huawei oh so Dave in when we did
network to we were looking at some of
this and you didn't necessarily like
this you who pooted quite a bit while we
were doing application-specific
networking when you were a routing ad
you didn't exactly like pce I know
because I work with some of the guys you
proposed some other things I'm looking
on the positive what's changed your mind
what new revelation have you gotten did
it come from stos did it come from
customers what caused you to take a
switch from your previous position
giclee I'll say that the bolts in my
neck that I had at cisco are now out but
no it's-- I tease my friends so anyways
we all learn now if you remember what
peace EE and I touched on this a bit was
originally set up to do and it was a
quick and dirty hack of BGP to pass some
information around i'm using the
constructs of that technology or
advocating the constructs of that
technology to reinvent soft pvcs between
endpoints with an autonomous system so
I'd say that over time we all learn and
we all learn how to use what's available
towards hopefully building a better
internet I can't say anything else ooh I
didn't destroy it i didn't attempt to
take down a number of things but
I certainly wasn't an advocate of what
they were being used for originally over
here brett watson new star i was
surprised that you didn't i had the same
question Randy had about security and
you didn't mention I f map which juniper
participates in the developing a role in
this architecture yeah absolutely so if
I was to look at what was going on on a
VPN gateway Enterprise VPN gateway these
VPN gateways have AF map information and
I f map is just a generic way to spew
lots and lots of information about a
particular session in the applications
traversing that tunnel to a that
security gateway what's interesting in
the way I consider this data coming out
of that gateway is really telemetry data
it tells me who the subscriber is it
tells me what device they're on what OS
they're running the capabilities of that
device and the application or service
profile that that user has traversing
that particular secure tunnel what's
interesting about this is this data is
being directly used in enterprises and
we can talk at another talk or even next
week at to the open networking summit
about enterprise and programmable
networks but in this case let me
describe how it's being used this
telemetry data is the difference between
me being let's say I'm a financial
trader working for some some bank and
somebody is occupying that but let's say
I'm working for this particular Bank the
fact that i'm here at nanog on my mobile
phone or ipad means that i do not have
access to the trading floor I don't have
access to the trading floor based upon
again the device I'm on where I'm
located and potentially to the access
point so inside these enterprises if I'm
not on the trading floor itself I don't
have access to that aspect of my virtual
desktop that's those storage pieces or
whatever the case might be I f map
directly is again this information
coming out of a gateway system whether
it's a secure tunnel or even subscriber
bng beer a system that will give you
this data to be able to build a service
profile out of it this again is an
attempt or sorry this I think is another
way we can overcome the current loc of
radius diameter or other ways of
constructing a service profile such that
an operator can build their own database
in conjunction with these protocols or
completely
separate from those protocols to build a
silver service profile based upon this
telemetry information once active
vibration please richard barnes BBN
first time nanog attendee but chair of
the IETF geo prev working group so I
since constraint on time I won't ask a
question i'll just say two things on the
first it's a provide a forward pointer
for those in the room we actually have a
presentation that i'm giving later in
the week on wednesday morning on
geolocation specifically and some of the
work that's been done in the IETF to
look at how we can enable geolocation
services through the DNS and through
some web services and possibly through
the who is databases so we have some
technical specifics on that wednesday i
think at eleven-thirty the other thing i
wanted to mention is um you know to echo
Randy's point in the other commenters
point about security and privacy and
maybe the sound a little bit more
hopeful note because there has been some
real thinking about privacy especially
in the context of geolocation is some
some long going discussions in the IETF
and we actually have a couple of rfcs on
this the most recent being RFC 60 to 80
so if people want to check that out
there's been a little bit of thinking
about this and maybe it can help address
some of these questions thank you very
much thanks