by the fact that we are a membership
organization now but we're also an open
organization so everybody if you
remember or not you're welcome to come
in join in the conversation and
hopefully the end of you'll want to join
the become a member as well so why are
we here I've got a whole bunch of stuff
planned for you I'm going to give a gory
court and Patrick will come up in
entertain us with some stuff about the
election the board candidates are going
to get up here and talked about
themselves then we'll hear from the
development committee and we'll get to
hear this will be really exciting joins
going to come up and talk about our
finances but he's going to talk about
future events and then actually the most
fun part is the open discussion at the
end where we want to hear from you we
want to know what your concerns are what
we can do as the board and the various
committees to make things better for you
the members so I'm going to start off
with my board report I am Steve Feldon I
am the chair for another three and a
half days so thanks for coming
what we did last summer we had a great
deal of fun this summer the board all
got together and went on a retreat yes
it's just what you think it's just like
10 Dilbert we went to a fancy tropical
resort land around by the swimming pool
and drank mai tais and not quite
actually we were in beautiful fremont
california in a corporate office park ms
thanks for hosting us by the way we were
in their conference room we actually did
have coffee and sandwiches unless that
part was good we weren't there either
just to have a good time we were there
to actually work we spent a whole day
locked in this conference room except
for the walk in the middle and talked
about what nanog is going to become and
we'll get into that moment but the
probably the biggest thing that we
talked about is this why why does they
not exist what's our purpose in life so
here's the quick answer now that is
educational and operational and whatever
by the time I'm done explaining this to
my grandma that she's gonna be sound
asleep so this isn't a good answer to
why this is actually a good answer to
what perhaps but why is a more important
question there so the facilitator of
this retreat spent a good deal of time
talking to us and it really resonated
about how successful organizations start
off by figuring out why they exist and
work from there to what it is they do
most times there for example if you go
out and buy a computer computer
companies going to say hey we make you
computers by some he used apple as his
example can take that with the
appropriate grain of salt but maybe this
week is appropriate Apple has a vision
for what they build why they build
things the way they do and that's what
this meant to you and not just cool
hardware so he challenged us to think
about why we're doing stuff why does
then I exist yeah we all come to
conferences and we have mainly lists and
we have endless arguments about stuff
but there's a reason for that mrs. what
came up with we are here collaborating
to make an internet better that's
something I can explain to my
grandmother I can explain to people who
need an elevator they won't be asleep by
the end of the sentence and it actually
makes sense to them we come here
together to exchange information and
knowledge drinks whatever but we're here
because doing so we believe makes engine
it better that's a good reason that's
something that's easy to articulate easy
to explain and it motivates kind of the
rest of what we're doing here this whole
week if you ask me anyway so it gets a
bit more about through treating a bit
but when you move forward a bit I'm only
spending one slide on what we've done
over the last 18 months since we started
this whole adventure with nothing we got
some initial donations and support lots
of advice and we worked with
our partners of Merit to figure out how
to separate ourselves and become an
independent organization we did that we
expanded the sponsorship model so we
have real money coming in we have a
positive cash flow addendum toiled about
that little while but that's a huge
thing for us we weren't trick the
beginning you can do that but we did and
this here in Philadelphia is the first
meeting that we've done completely on
our own that has pluses and minuses
sorry there might be a few rough edges
here hopefully they're minor ones and
you won't even notice them but on the
whole we're here there's a room there's
lights there's sound miss tables that
means that things are actually working
also wanted to thank those of you who
came in registered at the last possible
moment that's my additional revenue
doesn't mean total type in the back
there for which we apologize but you
know too many people is not a bad
problem to have if you ask me I was
going to come up with a slider list of
people to thank but started getting way
too long so gonna start by just thinking
everybody became all of you you're the
members who the community you're the
reason why we're here collaborating to
make the internet better a few specific
not people but types of people I want to
call out there were the initial people
who SAT again with us and helped us
figure out how to go forward how to take
this idea and turn it into a reality
there were those people who told us we
were a bunch of idiots and then
explained by we were idiots and told us
what we could do better that was really
useful constructive advice and maybe we
didn't enjoy listening to it at the time
but a developer's got where we are
thanks to you guys thanks to the people
who became members who come to
conferences all are you thanks even even
to the Patrick so what's next we have
somewhere to do everything really
finished on the operations side we need
to smooth out a whole bunch of rough
edges I guess I hope you're not seeing
too many of them from where you're
sitting but there are things this is our
first meeting your things you can
obviously do better the next time and
that's all part of increasing efficiency
that we can avoid little problems
everything went smoother cheaper faster
whatever but we really need to focus on
is what we spent the rest of the time
doing in our board retreat which is a
strategic vision we need to figure out
not where we are today because we were
here already we've been doing a lot of
the same stuff for years and years and
years but what do we want to be tomorrow
there have been a lot of ideas over the
years of what Nana I could do we're in a
position now where if you want to we can
make them happen we can collaborate to
make the internet better so let's do
that we spent like I said bunch of time
in the retreat coming up with future
goals for the next year 25 years
financial goals other goals types of
things that we could do like expanding
educational opportunities that sort of
thing but we can't do a whole lot of
that without understanding
the membership what the community wants
wants it to be so that leads to the next
slide how and the answer is with your
collaboration you can collaborate by
voting in the selection you can
collaborate by joining now if you're not
already a member and you want to have a
voice in how we do things you can
collaborate my volunteering there's a
whole bunch of opportunities is too late
for this year but next to you there's
going to be yet another board election
with a couple least one person terming
out so it definitely at least one MPC
there's program committee selections
cycle going on now if you want to be on
the program committee or if you think
you're interested put your head in the
ring or talk to an existing pc member
and find out what it's all about you
have until tuesday evening i think to
decide and put your head in the ring the
development committee is going to need a
new members always need to go members
need new ideas new people to go out and
get many for us we need people to speak
these conferences Dave in the group put
together a really good program for us
this time as they always do but probably
the biggest task is going out in
recruiting talks so why not make things
a little easier for them by volunteering
talk about something you're interested
in that you think the rest of us to
learn when dhoni about and this bunch of
other ways so I'm going to get into
because it'd be here all night but
work with us collaborate give us advice
tell us what you want join both
participating so finely again we're here
collaborating to making it better next
up Patrick is going to talk about the
election process and you're going to be
letting on to remember a day or two hi
everybody my name is Patrick Gilmore and
I am wrong meeting we are here to
discuss the election process for nanog
new dog whatever you want to call it
this week it turns out that 250 people
have actually paid their hundred dollars
and become eligible to vote for the
nanog elections in case it isn't clear
to anybody nou nog actually was
transferred the name nanog from merit to
the new not new dog incorporated so we
can't call ourselves down on now but the
incorporation is still new nog at the
moment so if i use the names that are
changeable you please forgive me 250
people hundred fifty two people are
eligible to vote you don't need to be
present to vote but you do need to vote
because just like the elections in
anything else in democracy works by the
participation of the democratized so you
use this thing called aro which all of
you have used because you are here at
nanog and to get this little badge
around your neck you had to use error
all right it really be okay that's right
so you are having
an arrow or arrow as they like to call
it and you will all be able to vote if
you need any help with that they're all
just emailed support aetna org and
they'll be happy to help you out voting
in tuesday at five p.m. eastern daylight
time that's the time zone you're in
right now so well all people here if
you're watching this on the stream then
you may not be but otherwise it's the
time zone where nanog is the results
will be announced Wednesday morning
remember now it doesn't actually end
Tuesday night contrary to popular belief
it does go through wednesday at noon so
hang out see the results and see what
happens I really need all of you to vote
anybody who doesn't vote you know what
will happen so there's a couple of
things on the ballot it's not just
voting for board members is actually
more things than that there are valid
amendments in the original in the
original bylaws it was the board was
given the right to change the bylaws by
unanimous consent but those by tasha's
had to be put for election of the very
next election the board actually did
change the bylaws because the original
bylaws had a very complicated structure
for the membership that was by the
community that means you people decided
that that was a little silly so what we
did is we simplify them greatly those
simplified membership requirements are
actually the way that we do membership
here at down on is up for election if
you guys do not ratify that it goes back
to the original bylaws so you need to
vote you need to vote yes or no your
opinion does matter there's only two
hundred fifty two of you every single
vote does really count not talking about
like a national election
millions of people and things like that
every single vote does matter here so
please get onto the web page and vote
there are also four board members that
are up for election it turns out that we
only have four people up for election
for four empty seats so I think you can
probably guess the results of that
election however it's not as simple as
that it turns out that we have three
board members that are up as normal it
turn their six not there are six
non-executive six elected board members
of those every year three are re-elected
one of whom is termed out he cannot
stand for re-election I would be our
amazing Chairman Steve Feldman who has
actually been in a ridiculous amount of
help getting the new organization going
it turns out somebody else also resigned
in the middle of his term so we are we
have appointed somebody Mike Smith Mike
raise your hand but because he was
appointed by the rest of the board he
needs to be elected or somebody needs to
be elected into that place because of
the way the elections work out because
of where the resignation happened we
have three two year terms that are
coming up and one one-year term because
the term of the person who resigned who
is rob's Eastern when we thank him for
his help but because of the when he
resigned he only gets one year left on
his term it this means that you're like
that your votes do count again because
the person who gets the fewest number of
votes will get that one year term and
the other three will get it to your term
so even though it looks like you have
four people four four places and it
doesn't really matter it does actually
matter so please get on the web page and
please vote so membership starter
turns out anybody can join doesn't
really matter you can be you know on the
South Pole ever attended and a dog
meeting never read the mailing list and
you can join if you want what this
generally means is we want a hundred
bucks so give us a hundred bucks you can
be a member we're happy to so there's
only one membership class the nice thing
about the membership class is that if
you actually join you get twenty five
dollars off your off your fees to come
to now to come to 39 hours a year it
means it literally cost you twenty-five
dollars to come to now per year in that
awesome but you guys want to I mean
sorry be a member per year isn't that
awesome you guys all want to be members
now anybody who is in this room and not
a member raise your hand Jeff is Jeff is
marvel guess he's getting a hit after
this ok I will find the two of them and
beat them silly until they give me a
hundred dollars members kept the real
difference between people who can vote
sorry the real difference between a
member and non-member is that numbers
keep up so you can elect people like me
think I'm silly then you don't have to
vote for me it's kind of strange I'm
standing up here given that statement
isn't it but if you are a member you can
vote and that's what you should do
remember you should vote so please vote
for the membership class because if you
do not it will revert to the old way
which I don't think was perfect it
wasn't bad but I think the new way is
good Duane
the other so Louie committee
simplification this is another thing
that we went through when we started we
have some grandiose ideas and they
actually made sense at the time but as
organizations evolve we need to change
slightly so one of the things we decided
to change for instance is we combined a
couple of the committee's the finance
and event committees are being combined
into a single committee this makes sense
given where we're going to go forward so
the board is also allowed at its leisure
to create ad hoc committees to ensure
that we're not just creating a million
committees and for no apparent reason it
turns out that anybody who is a chairman
of any committee isn't non-voting but
still a member of the board of nanog so
we have some board members up here who
are not actually elected to the board
such as Dave and Masako they are the
chairman of individual committees and
they get to come to all the board
meetings they get to voice their
opinions they get to see all the mail
that goes back and forth all the minutes
that we produce and everything else that
happens and there are a few other
cleanups really minor you know
vocabulary stuff and language that
needed to be changed slightly and we'd
appreciate it you know the board clearly
thinks that these are good ideas we put
it onto the ballot but just because the
board thinks it's a good idea doesn't
mean it is the back stuff of all this
the thing that really matters is the
community and you're the community so
you guys need to actually read these
things see if they make sense and vote
on them voting meeting the most
important part so if you don't want to
read them come to me and i'll tell you
how to vote how's that
so the board candidates this is a really
long URL i made Steve put this URL
instead of just go to network so people
on the stream can go ahead and click on
the URL there are actual candidates they
have some statements as they've made and
they have you know their bio and why
they think they should be elected and
things like this and this will help you
decide which ones should get the
two-year tournament which once you get
the one-year term so there are four
candidates unfortunately one is not able
to be here right now he did make a
statement that i will be reading for him
but before that going just in
alphabetical order by first name what
we're gonna do is start with dwayne and
we're going to read each of the
statements and then we're going to have
a Q&A where you guys can stand up and
actually ask them questions where where
this idea comes from it's actually
called hustings which means that you
guys get to grill is a polite way of
putting it beat the crap out of them is
another way of putting it actually ask
them really hard tough questions make
sure that your idea is that your view
that you what is important to you is
asked of these people see what they
think and then hold them accountable to
that okay so with further ado I'm going
to start with Duane and I'm going to go
get my iPad so i can read Steve
statement afterwards
hey
so hello hello and Elena was totally
unprepared to go first I have very
little to say other than i would not be
totally disappointed if I got the fewest
votes and therefore one more year to
serve still no comfort no it's it's been
my pleasure to to be on the word for the
last two years I'm the treasurer and you
get to hear me talk about about that
later otherwise I would just encourage
you to to vote I think some of the other
issues are a little bit more important
than the board candidate since we've got
44 44 so I think that's kind of but
otherwise please go out and vote thanks
Michael next okay
I'm like I'm Mike Smith formerly
communications committee chairperson I
really do think it's unfortunate that
there only four of us because it does
kind of limit your options as to what
you can actually do in the democratic
process that Patrick was referring to so
that would definitely be one of my
target goals for either one or two years
is to make sure that there's a bigger
slate of candidates the next time around
and also now that we're flush with cash
which Dwayne will talk about using some
of that for community outreach to make
sure that we have the next generation of
people that are a little less gray than
all of us coming to this meeting so that
this continues on beyond all of us
thanks
ah perhaps because Steve isn't here he
actually prepared a statement sorry the
candidates were told they were going to
make a statement before the husbands so
I apologize if this seems a little bit
longer than the last two but I promised
deep that I would read this let's hope I
can do it first I'd like to apologize
for being one of those people who runs
for the board and then doesn't show up
to stay what they should be like why
they should be elected I have some non
Nanak friends who didn't make me try
this again who didn't take now dog into
account when scheduling their weddings
all by your arriving in Philadelphia on
Monday night I've been reading the note
on mailing list since 1997 or 1998 I
will comments out and attending na nóg
meeting regularly since 2000 Nanak has
taught me a lot and been an incredible
value valuable resource I enjoy
contributing the organization as a
conference speaker as one of the authors
of the 2005 merit na nóg charter and of
the bio current bylaws of the
organization operates of it and as Na
Nog's membership chair since January the
current na nóg board has taken the
organization through a period of great
change over the last two years they've
done an impressive job converting Na Nog
from an activity to of a University
Consortium into an independent
organization or sorry independent
industry organization with minimal
disruption I'm running for the board
hoping to continue that work but also
because I'm excited about other
possibilities for an immigrant during
two years of work to bring two years of
work to bring an organization through a
dramatic change in garnets structure
would be would be rather disappointing
if it stopped there now not just put on
a good conference in and will continue
to do so but what's exciting about our
new structure is that it will allow us
to do more I'm interested in exploring
the possibilities for what else now I
can do to make the
internet better many of our counterpart
organizations elsewhere in the world
have workshop programs to train the next
generation of workshop sorry next
generation of network engineers would be
nice to do something like that here I'd
like to see Na Nog support the best
practice documentation work from a few
meetings ago I'd like people setting up
topic-specific network operations
mailing lists the various router dash in
a speed lists the security lists the
outages list for example to be able to
use nouns mailing lists infrastructure
rather than having to set up their own
in general i'd like to see now I've
become a full-fledged professional
organization for the network operators
community rather than an organization
that runs a few big meetings that leaves
the community to set up duplicate
infrastructure for everyone else since
I'm running unopposed I guess you'll be
electing me whether or not whether you
want to or not but I'd appreciate your
votes anyway again I'll be arriving
tomorrow night and would be happy to
answer any questions at that time just
to be clear steve is unelected and
unpaid but he's put in a tremendous
amount of time and effort to the
organization he did right by laws he
came to our retreat he's done a lot of
things for the organization with
essentially no thanks so I want to be
even though he didn't put this in his
personal statement and I probably
shouldn't buy us anybody towards him
just want you to know that he really has
done a lot of work and he is good for
the organization
no we're gonna have to still be labelled
yet I so I'd like to volunteer I I do
believe that making the internet better
is a valuable cause and I do think it's
worthwhile that I devote time to it so I
have the time the energy and also the
desire to continue what was started here
at NOC so I'm seeking a second mandate
essentially to continue to
transformation and also I like to finish
what I started I'd like also to explore
ways of doing other things with nana is
it education is it best operating
practices I want to listen to you and
implement what your desires are this
organization is ours and we need to
shape it to what we believe is important
so that's it I'm not going to take more
of your time thank you very much for
coming to Nana gets important
alright so now we have the QA which I'm
hoping it will be more than just I what
you staring at me two things the first
is anybody who's watching on the stream
I am on the IRC channel if you don't
know how to reach me you don't deserve
to be part of now so feel free to feel
free to message me and I will read your
question out loud otherwise please go to
the microphone so people on the stream
can hear you and I would love to hear
your questions just you know we want
this to actually happen and we do want
some questions but we don't want this
the last 10 hours so do me a favor and
don't repeat other people's questions
unless there's an actual you know
important point behind it I have a
question for you first Todd who are you
and you were tired I'm sorry Patrick is
I got confused are we supposed to vote
or not I would appreciate if all of the
members voted except Todd to the candy
that's actually doing and it's for all
of them going into that what I think is
the most significant question which is
how much money should we say and what
should we do with that money get a
microphone right there okay how much
money should we save we talked about
this a little bit in our retreat so you
may get kind of the same answer from
everybody our goal for the end of 2012
was to have a hundred thousand cash and
for 2013 250,000 buffer so that that's
our target and not and you know I think
I think that's realistic I think that's
pretty good so I'll talk about this
later again but you know that money goes
to sort of cover our liabilities in the
case that we have a meeting that totally
falls apart and so on you know beyond
those numbers i don't i don't think
nanog needs a lot more than that
so what Todd saying that nobody can hear
is what should we do with the extra if
there is extra money what should we do
with it I could use a race well I think
I think some of these ideas are going to
come out later in the meeting I think if
we were in the situation where we sort
of did everything that we wanted to do
with our extra money I would like to see
you know some of that money going back
to the sponsors and maybe lowering the
sponsorship fees because I think they've
been very generous to us I'd actually
like the other candidates if they desire
to explain answer the last questions
what else what could we do with the
extra money because I don't think that's
just a treasure everything if you don't
want to answer that's fine too no it's
fun I'd like to see more outreach
towards not only more participation for
the program but also again what I was
saying before making sure that we
continue this on beyond the present
group of people so I think using some of
that for community outreach and dare I
say it marketing which I know is a
verboten werden operations but still
spending some of that money to get the
nanog name out there in the community
and make it it continue to be important
I think is a good way to spend extra
dollars yes i would like to devote some
money to prepare to the next generation
making sure that the appropriate level
of knowledge and education is imparted
onto them and making sure to that we
develop best practices and that we train
the next generation of network engineers
for our industry
as I've noticing my new gray hairs since
Steven here not answering for him but I
think he actually said some of that in a
statement so you should consider that
and I'd be happy to forward a statement
to anybody who's interested next all the
objectives of Cisco does this have to be
a question yeah alternative question
anyway I do you guys plan to change your
mission statement so that sounds more
like a board-level thing but I think
I'll let this I'll explain the
question RFC 3935 the goal of the IETF
is to bank the internet work better
which sounds like exactly your mission
statement you might wanna sort of reward
yours theft is good theft is good Sylvie
when we launched a transition we said
that we wanted to keep the same mission
that we had and that we wanted to expand
it with education and we when we asked
ourselves why are we here it came clear
to us that we're here to collaborate to
make the internet better so maybe that's
that collaboration thing that's not part
of the IDF where it is but we want it
part of our
doing you don't have to answer i'm just
giving you your time in case you want it
ok i honestly have no idea what Steve
would say to that just because it sounds
like a board-level thing let's just all
be frank with each other there's nothing
wrong with now and I et overlapping in
our goals and let's be even more Frank
I'm not sure the ietf succeeded so let's
come on yeah you know what let me
address that what I can I'm not standing
for election I can just say whatever I
want now I don't see any conflict
honestly we came up with our Y
completely independently of theirs we
have the same mission perhaps to make
the internet better we go up at it
differently the ITF doesn't exist for
the same reason that nano does or they
don't do the same things but if at the
end of the day the goal is to anything
today what's wrong with that and the ITF
in nano deuce do actually do different
things so there's nothing wrong with
both of them making the internet better
do we have any other questions Patrick
oh sorry I was trying to find somebody
who did this side of the room but nippy
no it's okay who are you Juncker stopped
and coming so then I North American
network
should we expand either geographically
or to other constituents because I think
we primarily find people who are ISPs
are hosting providers candidates we have
discussed that one historically our name
is nanog its North American and we do
welcome people from other regions like
Asia Europe Africa Latin America we're
not a closed member group all other
regions have also operator groups they
already exist so we thought that we
should keep with our name unless the
members see it that the we should change
so then that sounds like a good ballot
for next year any other candidates plus
one AOL as long as we're talking about
other regions is Wilson in her the
Pascal the pastel scholarship winner his
name is Wilson he's actually from Uganda
which is in case you didn't know outside
of north america so we do outreach a
little bit past north america but other
than that i'm going to leave the
question alone for the candidates do we
have any other questions all right so
i'm going to put one more one more I
don't know what to call it emphasis
motivation encouragement please vote I
know I make a lot of jokes when I'm
standing up here but I am deadly serious
if you guys don't vote then don't bitch
about it and we all know none of you
could possibly live another day if you
couldn't bitch about it so you have to
find yes sir david uberman
quick question hey he's to talk david
yurman from Marin signed up for
membership the first week of is
available that was a year ago am i
eligible to vote now in my elegant row
to the next election and when does my
Congress ship expire I can't find any of
that on the arrow website so the
membership actually I really don't want
to do this because i don't have the
website in for me the website should say
and I believe it does say to be honest
that membership is one hundred dollars
per year right I but it did not start
the day of because we backed it up a
little bit everyone who has ever paid
membership up until some time before
this moment I forget when the cutoff was
but everybody who has ever paid
membership is eligible to vote in this
election right now half you will not be
ineligible the next election Alicia paid
for more than one year I believe you're
correct but you have to have been a
member up as of a month ago to vote in
this election yeah there was some girl
yeah I'd also point out that we were
collecting donations I want to correct
it's not a month ago yeah you knew not
was collecting donations long before we
started we had a membership structure
and those early donations were not
memberships in that sense because we
didn't have members of structure so some
of them were converted to membership
upon request of the people who donated
right so anybody who has ever paid for
membership not just a flat-out donation
is eligible to vote in this up to some
cut off that is before right now but I
don't remember where the cutoff was but
it was relatively recent it was it was
friday was friday okay everybody who
paid for membership before friday
meaning two days ago is eligible to vote
in this election if you paid for one
year you are not eligible for the next
election because it's only one year long
can you
find a way to be can contact us on our
memberships inspiring or make it evident
blah blah yes we will be sending out
email to people whose membership are are
expiring and then we'll go from there
useful and reasonable question does
anybody else have one of those all right
thank you very much all right before we
start on don't update is Chris casada
there if you are you stand up and wave
at us if you're not then you're probably
twice so I wanted to mention Chris
because he had to has had to step down
as chair of the development committee
but I don't want that pass unnoticed I
wanted to make sure everybody
understands what a great thing that
Chris has done for us over the last
couple of years he was in at the
beginning of what was then called the
marketing working group which is when we
started going out to the various vendors
and saying do and give us some money in
exchange for showing your stuff with me
in gear and all that a mare mare used to
handle a lot of that but under the
marketing working group and we slander
the development committee that's become
a lot more formalized and a lot bigger
than it was and I don't think it's an
exaggeration to say that without the
efforts that Chris put into the
committee we wouldn't be here we
wouldn't had the money to put this on so
if you see Chris please thank him please
tell him that we appreciate everything
he's done for him
and we hope will be back working with us
insane capacities in so with that said
like to invite the acting chair of the
development committee Masako up to give
us an update on what's been happening in
there they're wrong
hi everybody my name is Masako I've been
volunteering for now now for the last
couple years and started out in the
marketing marketing working group
interest and through the transition we
have work to put together a lot of
different programs and thank you to the
sponsors for all our contributions their
feedback everything that they have
provided I wanted to recognize some key
sponsors today our diamond sponsors we
have Google NDT embarrassing they have
contributed huge amounts of money to see
us through this transition and we
definitely couldn't have done it without
them also alcatel-lucent is our silver
sponsor and they have also contributed a
huge amount of time and money as well to
get us to this point and then we can't
forget our annual sponsors and our
technology sponsors and of course you
guys know the connectivity sponsors and
then of course the hosting providers
that provide servers for manag and help
us run these meetings so thank you to
everybody
i also want to poke i also wanted to
recognize some of the committee members
as well through the last couple years
they have put in a lot of time to help
support a lot of the programs they've
you know set aside time during their
work times to contact all our sponsors
and then also of course look for
potential sponsors for the future and i
like to have them all stand up down are
you here how about Kat Hoffman thank you
guys ok so I think this is something
that you guys are very very curious
about as far as financials Duane will go
over a lot more of the details but I
wanted to focus just basically on the
development committee committee and the
numbers that have been coming in and
this is just pure sponsorship
contributions so for Nana on 52 we've
had 200 220 7333 dollars come in for
that meeting so this was dumper and then
for this meeting for Nana 53 we've had
260 $1,500 come in
this is pretty much fifteen percent
meeting over meeting increase and I'm
hoping to continue to refine some of our
programs so that we can continue to
increase that fifteen percent possibly
up to fifty percent sixty percent reason
for that is because we need this for the
continuity of nanog and as every few of
the board members have mentioned we
really do want to see these meetings
continue and be comfortable and have
that reserve so that if anything does
happen that we are able to sustain
ourselves and I think that's very very
important and as we incrementally
increase the revenue the sponsorship
revenue I'd like to work with our
committees and see how we can pay off
these loans hey and then of course
future fund future Na Nog meetings and
then another portion of these revenues
or the contributions should go toward
nanog programs again as mentioned the
educational programs that really make
this organization what it is and then
allow other new members and new
attendees
tuna so that's always a good yeah from
near an unusual drew hi Randy G defined
sponsorship in other words is this
donation somebody just gave us is it
period here is it lunch instead of just
trying to understand since I sure so
sponsorship these dollars are actually
attached to a program and these are
programs you can see are articulated on
the website so if you go to the link you
will see all kinds of programs bien gear
once being one of our most popular we
also have not lab we also have of course
the overall sponsorships for hosting
meetings and then on the individual
items that go along with that which
would be the lanyards we make in the
batch or the agenda sponsorships so
there are little price points or
sponsorship revenue price points that we
put to these programs and they all add
up to these numbers so sakai might be
clarify one thing that we also certainly
would not turn down do not turn down
donations if a company wants to give us
cash or services or whatever not as part
of a program we happily accept it the
program is a little bit different we
call them in donations not sponsorships
but we're happy to take it yeah right
and it is just really sponsorship
dollars it does not include the
contributions and/or the membership fee
different revenue line one question
about the sponsorship so I have you were
in the older days in different housing
sponsorship programs which may be why i
remember members organized questions
about what exactly is the program so one
of the question is how satisfied are you
and how satisfied are the people who are
buying sponsorships that we've done this
right like are we going to we've got
this silver platinum gold titanium
sponsorship levels and whatever break do
keeping to those work to those work for
us is that the right amount of money is
at the right mix of benefits and are we
going to continue them it's never enough
money well of course we want more to
answer the first part of your question
these programs definitely have worked
they have worked because they have been
set up and created specifically so that
we can run these now knock meetings and
it is aligned with not only what the
sponsors are looking for but what we as
attendees wand and we got a lot of this
feedback from the surveys that we sent
out throughout all of our meetings and
so they have been appropriately set up
as far as sponsor feedback they are very
happy
of course they want to more get more to
our group in our community what the
board has done and Development Committee
has done however is we are kind of
squashing the idea that we're marketing
as if we were attending a trade show so
that is one thing that we've kind of
stayed away from and as as many of you
have said you really don't want those
sales people all over you and we have
tried to respect your space and your
privacy here when you're attending the
meeting so I think the programs are
designed definitely to allow you that
and then also at the same time have that
revenue stream coming in Boston with
water stone communications I was
wondering if these are purely cash
sponsorships or in-kind as well it is
purely cash as I said we do happily
accept in-kind donations but those are a
different program and I think it's
important just because you asked the
question we do have a number of folks
who are recognized on our website as
contributors so those in the
contributors are really the in-kind set
of services that are offered to Nana I
think it's important to mention that
what the program the development
committee what the development committee
has done and achieved this year is to
decouple the sponsorship money from a
meeting to meeting asked so we have
yearly sponsorships so a sponsor can buy
a full year so sponsorship over three
meetings and they can also buy
activities on a permitting basis so what
the development committee has done is to
listen to our sponsors that said I
really want to give you money but you're
coming to me at the wrong time in the
year so they've answer that
any other questions all right I'm gonna
turn it over to join all right turn it
on nothin pungent mind you can take it
so I again for those of you that are on
members of a only so well not these
these slides have been posted for a week
or so so I may go through some of them
kind of quickly since I think we're oh
where is it five more tears no 630 we're
close to the ending time aren't we
anyway the first slide shows the the
numbers from the previous meeting this
is 952 we had 42 5543 attendees you can
read all the the numbers there that the
black lines are in come the red lines
are expenses and overall 120 thousand
dollars profit on that meeting and I've
also listed the costs per attendee and
the registration revenue per attendee
for that meaning
the slide shows the state of our
expenses and revenues for 2011 up to the
end of August so again you can sort of
read the numbers there
oh it's cut off I'm sorry so the in fact
on this slide there 0 and the reason
that they are on there the reserve line
and the loan repayment line are there
because we plan on using sort of this
the same set of categories for all the
on the other years all the other slides
so yeah and in this in this state of
their 0 so could you hit backspace green
or whenever go back yeah so one meeting
adjourned 27th out of sponsorship
forward now sponsorship 207 and I'm so
I'm really confused by this episodes
well this is the sister the end of
August here versus meeting vs right now
my sponsor here dear i'm on buying years
worth of here so a couple of times you
see I'm coming out of waking up from Rip
Van Winkle state you know where things
were a little different right right so a
couple things the the spring meeting of
2011 does not go does not accumulate in
in these in these revenues because we
did run that meeting so so
or meet you mean Wyoming yeah yeah yeah
and this is two they know August so this
this sponsorship amount here mostly
represents the previous meeting nanog 52
a lot of the sponsors hadn't paid for
down at 53 at the end of August ok so in
fact if if we had a more current
financial report that that number would
be a lot higher because we have gotten a
lot of money in through September and
the first part of this month so are our
income revenue for sponsorships is a lot
higher at this point
here
right so Randy's point is that a
sponsorship is sold sort of on a yearly
basis you sign up to be a sponsor for a
year and then why are we sort of talking
about per meeting sponsorships is it is
that like yeah this is just by cash
versus accrual if somebody gives you a
hundred thousand dollars and it's for
three meetings randy wants to know how
that shows up do you recognize that in
the reports at 33 3333 across the three
meetings do you set something Assad like
just what are we supposed to see what
are you doing cash basis accounting your
group its architects accrual basis
accounting it's accrual basis okay yeah
so we're not recognizing the full cash
contribution at the time Randy can you
go to a microphone if you keep talking
please send people there are people on
the web and hell I can't even hear you
therefore we took in significantly more
than 270 cash up till the end of august
and you haven't realized that because a
significant amount of it was due for
future meetings because they brought in
years woman and you're on accrual basis
question I voice is yes
thank you other thing to note here on
this slide is the loan from Aaron sixty
thousand dollars total this slide
represents actual budget numbers or
actual numbers from the first two
meetings of this year I don't I guess it
is cut off there a little bit but as you
can see on both of those meetings you
know we're still coming out ahead the
second one we came out quite a bit ahead
and if I may since this is my fault on
the slide that's on the screen right now
for the Miami meeting the three hundred
seventy thousand dollar number is
combined registrations plus sponsorships
since we didn't have access to the book
work cadet numbers in Dwayne's version
of the slides that shows up in the
middle of a two columns but I did it
wrong so by me yeah yeah that's right so
they forgot to mention that the that
number under the registrations for 951
is really combined registrations in
sponsorship
this slide shows the account balances as
of again as of the end of August the
operating account again is a lot higher
now because we've had a lot of
sponsorship money come in for this
meeting and also I wanted to take this
opportunity to note that on the mailing
list we've talked about posting you know
more standardized reports and we're
working on that if you if you log into
arrow right now and if you go to the
documents tab you'll actually see a
balance sheet for for the end of August
and when we get the accounts reconciled
for the end of September then we'll post
that as well and send out some some
notices that probably won't happen until
a couple of weeks from now here are the
estimates two for the end of the year
finances for this meeting for Nanak 53
if we budgeted in our budget we
predicted about 500 attendees and I know
that we're at about 560 already so we're
doing very well there should should be a
little higher on registrations
the slide shows our budget for tails
2012 and here you can see that on the on
the expense side the reserve and the
loan repayments are no longer zero so by
the end of 2012 we plan on having one
hundred twenty thousand dollars in
reserve to pay for to cover liabilities
for loan contracts and whatnot for
future meetings and we plan on paying
back to loan that we have from Erin in
question yes 60,000 95,000 interest rate
or what we received 30 thousand in 2011
from Erin okay thank you yeah tied on
the road again so just a gross order of
not like picking up the details but it
looks like we grossed 120,000 in the
Denver Heating and then we're planning
on grossing for if you go back to 2011
for all of 2011 we're hoping to end up
with 25k so that means so what that
tells me is that you guys are expecting
to lose a moderate amount of money on
this meeting that ground no I think it's
a combination of being conservative and
operations yeah 2001 todd is only two
meetings right 2011 is only two meetings
that are new nog it's 52 and 53 okay
plus we so what's interesting is the
next year 2012 but but all I'm saying is
that it looks like in 52 we had a gross
margin of 120,000 and it looks like
you're projecting a gross margin for the
entire year including one of
meaning of 25,000 that's all the
inspector lose a hundred thousand on
this team no it's at a meeting
accounting and it doesn't account for
the regular operations like a ms Marilyn
I see you ok so either we as the
membership we're going to have to get
used to that or you guys are going to
have to allocate operating expense per
meeting because I'm still used to you
can see why I end up at this position it
looks like if there was a 120,000 for
meeting but at the end of the year we've
got 25,000 to show for it and that's in
into anal talk to about how we're going
to share the quarterly financials with
all of you but the important thing I
think correct me if I'm wrong doing but
in the number that you see for 2012 one
of the buckets is there is it already in
there it's not on the line but there is
a set aside 120 thousand dollar reserve
that's already taken out for liability
so I believe if you add it up it's
really 121 that's really net available
to use ok and this other way this is
fantastic news I think all of us thought
that was self-sustaining could do even
better and can do more so I'm not
criticizing it all this is wonderful and
really just trying to understand so
thank you for reading Moshe I take are
fairly under swelling just stood
standard ways of doing this and accruing
expenses accruing income properly
reported in recently and I'm sure you'll
find them to them and quarterly your
meeting I don't care what the particular
reporting frequency is I think a third
or a quarter of the years really nice
and the third may be easier for you
because of the meetings and it's easier
to advertise out that way but things
like reserves are not part of being come
statement it's just details ok thanks
so also on our in our 2012 budget you
know we had specific estimates for the
meetings and those numbers are here I
think the attendance numbers are a
little bit conservative but but that's
the way we like them oh that's a state
of my slides are there any other
questions about finances
sorry very okay what do I do here I'm
sorry I'll be quick it's a very quiet
group tonight lots of good questions
though and I just want to take a moment
really on my slides but to think all of
you that are here to join as members and
really just participate in something
that you own we talked about voting and
why it's important but the underlying
statement of everything that all of
these folks are doing at this table is
on behalf of something you own and
that's a tremendous tremendous
advancement for Nia knocks oh thank you
congratulations to everybody my job is
to share with you information that's
already on the website but to be
available to answer any questions about
orgo where we are going into the future
one of the commitments that the board
made as part of the transition was to go
out there and secure venues in advance
so that you could all scheduled travel
and and everybody could have a better
handle on what was coming up for the
next 12 to 18 months we've done that on
your behalf Nyan are 50 for our next
meeting is going to be hosted by telex
it's februari 5th through the 8th in san
diego work is already underway there's a
web page up for san diego and the call
for presentations will be released done
about thursday or so with registration
information and all of that so we're
we're improving the turnaround time to
get the next meeting launched after San
Diego we're going to Canada we're going
back oh sorry sorry sorry yeah there it
is multiple screen sorry we are going to
Vancouver we haven't been back to
inventor in Canada a lot in a while and
this be a great meeting Tata
Communications is our host for that
event nan r56 next fall we are again
joint with Aaron and we are going to
dallas texas all really great venues
exciting times for us and at aramark is
again a host for us we are in the
process I can't to be announced so I
don't want to release too much
information to take away our bargaining
if you will with the hotel in such for
nanog 57 but we do have the date secured
februari third through the sixth and we
will go to someplace warm so and we have
some folks who have came forward and
expressed an interest in hosting nana 57
but we do not have anyone confirmed yet
so as a company or an individual if
you're interested in hosting a meeting
contact myself or Masako we would love
to talk with you about the new hosting
model that we put in place in the net
the last year hopefully it's easier for
all of you and a rewarding experience so
that's where we're going and we'll
probably take a little bit of a breath
and deal with some logistics issues
before we schedule more events questions
oh god
Dave open mic too
are there more questions that you wish
to ask of anyone on the stage or the
organization this is your time weird
three minutes half ago oh hey buzz fresh
I like it I am Dave Duncan my work for
Netflix I date again sunako I've been
bought by IBM yet to drive the margin
zero and then let them pick up the
carcass anyway your recorded oh you know
he'll see want quick stir Tobias all the
picture that in my note anyway so I
started a thread was it last month now
regarding an idea for generating both or
interest in some of the committee's as
well as providing an incentive if you
will to people who give upwards of 60
hours of their time for committees like
the program committee on a yearly basis
generally of their employers time going
to raise this because I'm crouching over
generally their employees tie our
employers time in order to contribute to
bina program and there was a good amount
of back and forth a very respectful what
I was curious about was what the board's
take on that was at this point now that
the finances have been looked at you
know we all saw the model that Duane put
together as far as what the finances
were for the last few meetings we saw
what the surplus was think we understood
it to be you know less than something
like twenty two thousand dollars total
in less revenue over the course of a
three meeting year to do it and so
suddenly like to hear the board's
feedback from that
obviously I know there's other people
that the opposite side i'm not going to
provide commentary on that yet until you
know kind of get a response okay so we
looked at that and did your question can
we afford it the answer is yes it's
estimated to be 15 to 20 thousand
dollars permitting permitting so under
our current model yes we can afford it
but what we discussed is is that
something that you guys want is that
something desirable and that's where we
would like to hear what you think about
this so as a board where we can tell you
that yes we can afford it but we haven't
decided if we if I were for it or
against it Dave can you give a quick
description exactly what you're
referring to because not necessarily
everybody with yeah that's right that's
her so and I believe that technically
that email only goes out at this point I
think only members are subscribed to
futures correct no no future is correct
future development as a member at but it
only has like 400 is closed obviously
for some reason I thought futures at
some point had also been linked to
members in some way so as I alluded to
earlier my proposal was that for program
committee members or potentially you
know we can also talk about any of the
committee's who attend a minimum amount
of those committee meetings between
meetings as I mentioned you know if you
calculate it out it's usually about 60
hours a year of time you know that our
is generally during the work day so it's
our employers who are graciously giving
us this time to use to give back to the
nana community in exchange for that
allowing the people who have contributed
this time in this effort to these
meetings to attend these meetings for
free you know everyone so certainly
would have the option to pay if they
felt like they it was their obligation
to pay but you know I would like to
think that if we're going to select
someone for these committees that they
could be trusted to choose whether or
not it was appropriate for them to pay
pay given their means of pay whether
that be their employer or out of their
own pocket obviously there needs to be
some sort of guideline like you attend X
number of meetings you give X number of
hours whatever that may be you know that
can be able to the committee chairs that
can be codified in some way whatever
that is so I just want to speaking
slightly for the board here I just want
to be clear that when the so when this
very first came up the board took
officially no position on it at the time
we did not have the financials back yet
so just so that everybody knows one of
the reasons that we decided to do this
because we honestly did not know and
this was mentioned at the time that we
did not know what the financial impact
would be now that we've seen the
financials and we understand it as
Sylvia said it's clear that we can
afford this because we have somewhat of
a surplus on the meetings just so that
you guys do understand we make a lot of
money for the meeting but as you saw on
Duane slide that doesn't mean we make a
lot of money for the year because we
haven't put all of the non meeting
expenses into that number that you saw
which was reasonably large for each
meeting that we make some money on so
don't think that we're going to end the
me every year with you know half a
million dollars or something like that
because that is not the case as you saw
at the end of 2011 we're $25,000 ahead
and if every committee member on every
single committee does not pay a
registration fee in comes to nanog
that's the loss of twenty thousand
dollars per meeting not per year so be
clear on this we think we can afford it
but it's not a slam dunk and it's
certainly not a non-trivial expense in
loss of revenue Patrick can I just ask
how when we get to that
twenty-thousand-dollar meeting number
because if we go on 17pc members this is
an 517 I'll see members six development
members three committee 3 communications
community members 6 board members times
four hundred fifty dollars each its
twenty thousand two hundred and thirty
dollars two hundred and twenty thousand
two hundred fifty dollars I did the
calculation myself we also by the way
added in it was a little more than that
because I ended up adding some members
because if you look at the bylaws it
says things like the communication
committee must have at least three
members right so we added in some extra
committee because right before Mike was
selected to replace RS on the
word the communication committee had
four members right so there are extra
people involved so we we took a little
extra and we figured out what it was and
we were conservative about this right as
in for a penny in for a pound we didn't
want to end up like saying oh well we
think we can make it if it's only the pc
or something like that anyway end of day
just want to let everybody know we think
we can afford it it's something to
discuss and we'd like to hear what the
community has to say about it we've
heard some stuff on the mailing list I'm
positive somebody I don't know who is
going to reiterate what they said on the
mailing list but i would like to also
hear somebody else by the way i'm not at
all trying to tell randy to sit down he
should say what he has to say but i
would like also other people who haven't
participated in the mailing list to go
ahead and step up one last comment just
so that everybody knows nanog futures
talks about the future of nanog duh it
is open to everybody and believe it or
not everybody who is a member is not
subscribed and our futures don't ask me
why it just happens to be the case so
now I'm features is orthogonal to
members at nanog guitar okay thanks
Randy Randy bush i J um the finances are
of course important but I don't think
they were the real issue the real issue
is classes membership and we've been
around this at least two maybe three
issues
one was whether there should be I don't
know exalted members or fellows or
something like that etc each time I
think we're pushing something that's way
at the bottom is that as operators were
peers and what this creates unevenness
but
I believe there was universal support
for you know folk who can't afford it
should be supported somehow that that
wasn't that wasn't the issue money
wasn't the real issue though of course
have to be checked had been built but it
was classes this is a one glass of water
Todd yeah just briefly so PC members I'm
much more experienced with PC members
having served on the pc in the past for
a long time PC members are required to
attend two out of three nano a year and
I think that's makes good sense because
people shouldn't be programming the
content of a conference they don't
attend it doesn't make any sense so
that's great but by virtue of being
requiring PC members to attend those
conferences we may tend to move the pc
towards a class of wealthy individuals
or individuals employed by large
corporations because self-employed
individuals on a margin you know will be
looking for other opportunities to spend
that money now there are PC members in
the past who have griped about this some
of them may be sitting on the far right
of the stage and one of the good aspects
of this has been that it's produced more
content right because we give speakers
free attendance so I think if we're
going to look at this we need to look at
two things one is I agree with Randy
there should be a separate class of
people but I do think that pc members in
particular because of the requirement to
attend should have the option to have
their attendance waived if they think
their company can't afford it or if they
can't afford it but I also do you think
we need to look at free attendance for
speakers as well and see is that like
that's actually the bigger subsidy that
we have it's a good tool towards getting
a certain amount of content and maybe
maybe we just leave that there maybe we
just say you know committee members who
want to get in for free should produce
some freakin content for the conference
it's worked for professor converging on
the corner there so maybe it'll more
probably but that's just I I think we
should consider the way it shifts who
gets to attend and what the incentives
are so just just so that I'm clear Todd
what you're saying is you've volunteered
I think Dave said 60 hours towards nanog
and we're requiring you to attend the
conference and if you'd like to get this
four hundred and fifty dollar 425 is cat
rightfully points out because you must
be a member already so we're crying you
to be a member we're requiring you to
donate 60 hours of your time we're
requiring you to attend the meeting
and we're requiring you to pay that $425
and if you want that $425 waived please
go and do some more work that's right ok
just this so that I'm clear yeah that's
right that's actually a fair way of
saying that doesn't all add up to and
that's wrong right I didn't say did I
just wanted to be clear on what you're
saying exactly the current state of
affairs and so it is the current state
or that are those the incentives we want
and are those the costs we want that's
right yeah that's right Chris I'll yield
the joke for a second no no go ahead
that's all right good job so your farmer
I was cooking on this issue than I on
please go I'm not outspoken back in
reality land Joe provo nanog member I
realized I had something see what I did
there I realized they had something just
in a draft folder that I shot a shot off
this so this afternoon on this topic and
it's dead hey I don't think we should be
going down the road of codifying
anything because that gets in the
micromanagement that we've been
attempting to avoid in the in the
structure of any of the bylaws and
documents beyond we already had some
leeway that was during during the merit
days for the then SC chair to waive a
few hardship cases we should if
codifying anything recognize the
hardship and just go ahead and tack on a
while I agree with both Randy and Todd's
points go ahead and say and if
somebody's been doing exemplary work we
certainly expected the chair of the
board for instance to go ahead and say
yeah you're good to patricks point yes
we asked them to do some more work but
all the requirements for being on the pc
they know before they signed up if
problems with that they shouldn't be
running that's it Chris lighter now I
remember let me say to start out with I
don't believe that waving membership
fees is a creating of a two class system
because for most of those committees
you're going to turn out anyway and
you're going to be returned to the plebe
class so i'm not i'm not sure that that
I agree with that I don't necessarily
have a problem with waving registration
fees for committee members it's probably
an intriguing way to get more people to
actually want to volunteer to run for
office or to be appointed to the
committee's but I'd like to say that
when we're talking about the hardship
aspect of things if we're really serious
about you know the hardship issue I
think we should probably be more focused
on putting more into our scholarship
fund and sponsoring people truly can't
attend our meetings before we subsidize
people who are going to be here anyway
so I'd support doing it but I provide
support doing it after we got more
people here on scholarship so I was
going to say you know as Todd points out
i was on the pc for four years and i
complained bitterly the entire time that
didn't get me in for free and i had to
actually turn out content to which was
not a bad thing but the reality is
you've got a lot of people who are doing
a lot of work and not everyone works for
big companies not everyone can afford to
just have these things paid for and show
up at every meeting there are people who
want to contribute and they shouldn't be
called out as a hardship case they
shouldn't be it's not right to look at
it like that there are people who want
to contribute there are people who do
way more than the minimum amount of work
required and I think they deserve a
little something for the amount of work
that they put into this
my head lad I'm on the nano pc so i have
two points to make real quick one was
regarding the the point raised earlier
that pc members know what they are
signing up for before they do and the
counter that i would like to put there
is that a lot of times managers change
your own job titles change and your own
jobs change so that's not always the
case of the two-year period the second
point that I wanted to ask is we've
discussed the whole black and white
situation either you pay everything or
you don't pay anything has there been
like a fifty percent discount kind of
situation discussed before because
that's a balance between you know the
financials and getting some recognition
for putting time on the pc thank you I
David huberman from Aaron again it's
October 2011 this is the first meeting
only on our own I would urge the board
to be second meeting birds the birds to
be fully conservative maybe for the
februari 2013 meeting when you've had a
full year's worth of meetings to really
understand what your finances really
look like and not what they look like
right now I just think this discussion
is premature until you have a real and a
lot on what your finances are going to
be in red if you really can't afford to
do this thank you my name is Patrick I'm
a Down Dog member I've been silent on
this issue up to this point because I
I've been told in the past that I have a
really loud voice so I'm going to
whisper I also didn't want people to
think that I was speaking for the board
but this is the community meeting and
I'm speaking for myself not for the
board so the way I look at this is that
first of all I think it's completely
wrong to assume that we're creating two
classes of membership or you can go
ahead and assume it is two classes and
membership and yeah somebody who
volunteers and puts their time in there
a different class and I'm okay with that
either way you think about it I don't
care what I think about is if nanog
could write a check if nu nog
incorporated could write a check for
$425 you get somebody to put the 60
hours or whatever it is that people like
Dave and Raz and Dave sorry it to dave's
and you know everybody on the pcr the
people on the pc who actually contribute
if we could write a check for $425 and
get them to contribute that i wouldn't
blink i would do it in a heartbeat in
fact i would jump for joy to do it we
had before this meeting started before
people that were sitting up here and a
couple people out in the audience went
and physically buttonholed literally
physically attacked people and asked
them to volunteer for the pc we had
seven open slots with seven volunteers
we have four open board slots the people
standing for it are either sitting on
this table or have already donated
almost as much time as a normal board
member not one other person stood up not
one you guys talk about this stuff and
nobody's doing it and part of the reason
not the only reason part of the reason
is because I've talked to people who say
I would like to but and they need
something and letting them come to the
meeting that they helped create that
they put the effort into doing on their
own without asking their employer
without asking for a hardship case which
honestly is really demeaning without
doing something like that and just
saying please you worked really hard on
this I mean name another organization
that puts on anything a concert a
meeting a fair and anything and all the
volunteers that show up who work the
meeting who worked the concert who
worked the fair and say wait a minute
before you come in give me some dough
not one I can't think of one literally
that isn't a flat-out charity and as
much as we like to talk to ourselves as
a charity we're actually not a flat-out
charity it's nice to give people you
know we can talk about scholarships and
it's important I personally carry you
know I personally helped Wilson show him
who people were around here today he's
the postelles scholarship winner this
year and I think it would be great if we
had two of those I think it'd be even
greater if we had a contested election
that's my view just a minute oh
absolutely so we are over time I think
this is an important conversation I just
want to call it out so should we give
ourselves on our seven minutes and close
at two fifteen I'm sure we can find we
can find more time to discuss this but
we do we do have comcast as a hose who
is having a welcome social for us thanks
Freddie Randy Bush iij I've occasionally
don't need a little time to
organizations including this one and
when the call went to help especially
when the second call went out I said you
know I could do it again and I went
looked and my criterion wasn't whether I
could come up with 450 bucks my criteria
is which do nothing blow arts I would
have to listen to 15 years hey let's be
clear everyone sitting up here donated
all their time not one of us has ever
been paid a cent for any of this and if
you don't think that we put in a lot of
time you're confused there's a lot of
blowhards if you really think somebody's
going to join the pc and do the work
remember we're talking about doing the
work not just joining the pc so if you
really think somebody's going to join
the pc for 450 425 dollars and we're not
going to let them skate but you're
really talking 1275 dollars mmm he's
talking about why he randy said he's
talking about why he didn't volunteer
nah
you've given his point of view right and
it's 850 cuz ya'll have to go to two but
you if you went to three yes it'd be
1212 hmm so not you know a fairly small
amount of money for the amount of work
that people put in I I don't think of
them I can't imagine that when you look
at the budget that we're talking about
them that the money is the big deal
because it's not a lot of money to the
organization and if our development
chairs as good as her track record so
far it should become less and less of an
issue as we go on so I don't think that
the money is the issue if money's not
the issue then it's obviously people's
own personal opinions on whether those
seats should be should be free or people
would have to pay just like everybody
else and quite honestly for my opinion
it doesn't it doesn't really matter
which way it goes if you think that
people should be compensated for their
time I'm fine with that and use the
board you have my permission as a member
to make that decision for us but if you
think that that's been this way and it
should continue to be this way you
should pay just like everybody else I'm
fine with that too you guys make up your
minds I have to go end along hurricane
electric and manage member I have to
agree with Patrick I have not seen any
of can somebody write this date down and
I'm agreeing with with rads to which is
really Patrick and has just changed
their point of view just now it wouldn't
surprise me anyway that there is no
other organization that I'm aware of
that makes you pay for the privilege of
serving the organization other than
right which is a little different thing
right right board members not only get
their membership if you speak at a ripe
conference for example use all the
papers i often but right board members
not only get their attendance free they
get their travel paid
so so I think that you know meeting
attendance for the the committee members
is is a bare minimum I think that the
fact that we have such a dismal slate of
Canada and I'm not talking about the
quality of the candidates I'm talking
about the fact that we have a number of
candidates that barely equals the number
of open positions is a dismal state and
I think that this organization deserves
better and I think that the way to get a
better set of choices is to make it
easier for people to volunteer and if
giving them free meeting attendance is
what it takes to do that then I think
that's the least we can do as an
organization to support that and make
the organization healthier and more
viable thank you so we'll go we have
four more minutes one minute each three
people at the mic and there's room from
one more okay I think Fergus was first
reference I focus my complex optics I'm
a right working group chair I would
share within the right community I don't
get my expenses paid the ripe NCC which
is the executive arm of the right
community as an elected board that gets
expenses but none of the worker group
chairs none of the pc people get their
expenses paid or free meetings thank you
so Dave tempt him you know so basically
I wanted to echo a point that Patrick
made which is you know a lot of people
brought up well we should create a
hardship case you know I don't know how
many people have gone to school with
people who you know may have been under
privileged but no one really liked the
feeling of having to know that their
parents had to go ask for a subsidized
lunch and I'm pretty sure that no one
wants to have to go to the Nana court
and ask for a subsidized registration
you know it's demeaning to some extent I
guess people could get over it but I
doubt many people would use that and we
would end up losing people who otherwise
may not be able to attend the other side
of that as well is that our employers
who have generously given this time for
us
to use here should not be forced to pay
for this and or we shouldn't be forced
to pay for it out of pocket if our
employers have contributed our time to
this process thanks thanks I'm used to
Patrick misunderstanding me so I didn't
react then but since I obviously said
what I'm saying incorrectly if Dave
misunderstood me I was saying we have a
precedent for hardship case we have a
precedent for former SC chair now
cherbourg discretion in that I say if we
wish to codify something then we should
have the discretion that not separate
from hardship case just say that you
know committee members that actually do
the bloody work by some criteria that as
you alluded to before would be would be
comped not just a blanket comp whereby
somebody who could skate and we have
Patrick had people who skated and we may
still do I don't know not inside so we
wouldn't just give freebies of people
who escaped just so everybody knows as
far as I know and somebody can help me
her new knock in the this meeting in the
last meeting which are the only two new
Nagas run we have not comped anybody
wasn't a speaker or or a sponsor when
they get so many / being a sponsor is
that right yeah okay just a data point
not trying to say anything else one last
interview yep that's all I got and I'll
be fast um I mean could we try it you
know try it for a couple you know a year
or something like that and if we have a
positive uptake in in people who want to
apply for positions / stand for election
could be then say oh this is a good
program let's keep going if we don't
have a positive uptake in the same we're
in the same place next year where we
have the same number of people who want
the same number of positions maybe we
could say that this isn't this clearly
isn't working I mean I would think that
that would be the next logical step is
it if we're truly not getting qualified
candidates for our for the positions and
the reason one of the reasons why we're
not is because it's a hardship on
they're not getting competir their
employers don't want to send them or
what have you then then if we see a huge
uptake and people who want these
positions then we'll know that this this
program has worked if we still have the
same we're still at the same place then
obviously we probably have better places
to spend twenty two thousand some odd
dollars or what have you if you're
saying we should we test it just realize
this entire thing is a test I guess I
got you I and I got you can but I'm just
saying that people are saying there's a
lot of people that are saying and have
puts their their opinion on futures that
you're going to get better slate of
candidates if you do this and I'm saying
okay I don't necessarily have an
objection to that why don't we try it
and see if it works if we get a better
slate of candidates we know that it
works and we can go forward with it if
we get the same before in the same place
next year then we know that this didn't
work and we should probably say it's a
waste of twenty two thousand dollars
that's a good suggestion so we will
close for now on this on this topic so i
encourage you all to come to the social
that's put out by comcast our host it is
at Comcast Center 1701 JFK Boulevard in
philly and use that social time to
continue to discussion thank you also
you