very much Richard so as we're bringing
our nanog conference to a close here we
have some concluding comments with from
Dave and usability as well it's Betty
Betty available but he around yeah we
got tired well okay so Nana out 53
someone was asking me this morning won't
the first nanog i went to us and I
didn't really realize that they had
numbers that low but it turned out it
should not be nanog for back in 95 it
was it merit are at in an hour and ann
arbor and you know it I umich it was
really something it's worth looking at
it's worth going back and looking at the
surly agendas for those meetings that's
kind of humorous to see what people were
talking about for the most part the same
people are talking about the same thing
that kind of stuff so all right so I
want to do my thing so i can let Betty
go I first off i want to thank comcast
for hosting let's give them a big hand
great job by comcast now and I and we
have a a you know work okay yeah okay
I'm getting pushed out i'm getting the
hook already we had great a great number
of great other sponsors breaks um Brett
excuse me breakfast all of that so let's
give our all other sponsors a hand
so I'm also thinking about you know we
just did that's all you know we just did
nanog elections and I wanted to call out
a few things here first off the board of
directors of nu nog nanog did a
fantastic job in supporting us so let's
give them all a hand it was really easy
to work with them they bought for all of
those board members who are in here keep
doing what you're doing which is leaving
us alone to do the agenda I also want to
call it Steve Steve stand up Steve was a
steep squirming out as a chair of the
board he and as you know he guided all
us through all of the you know initial
process of this but Steve's been around
here I think longer than I have and so I
have a lot of I mean a lot of the
history and knowledge and culture of
nanog is grown up with Steve here now we
also have a program committee who puts
us all together for you and I wanted to
call out the names of the people who are
either terming out not standing for
re-election or who are up for
re-election right now and that would be
Kathy CJ can you stand up um Jim Jim
Kelly he's Jim in here no barry
greenstein here mohit i think maybe Oh
Jim sir okay Chris morrow dan Donny and
Sonya okay well these people are the
people who brought this out there
something back there so there are the
people who brought all this to you and
again we just did the elections and
we're going to appoint the new pc later
on but consider running for one of these
slots oh yeah
yeah I'll just I'll just I'll just say
it's tremendously satisfying when you
get to stand up here and look at you
know 500 of your closest friends and you
know they're going to have a good time
you know it's worth it's worth doing I
also wanted to thank AMS which is the
conference management company that's
helping us put on now now now that
merits not doing anymore Christian
Christian Annabelle and Bettina have
been working really hard to bring this
to you so thank you to those guys and
then Steve in the barrel and Steven the
barrel and crew doing the networking and
stuff back there thank you Steve let's
see what else do we have um speakers hey
the speakers were great i thought the
program came out pretty well and I
really want to thank all of the speakers
who took the time to build the content
come out here and give the talk so thank
you and then the final thank you is
going to have to get all of you folks
for coming out and making it happen so
thank you very much for coming to the
nanog we really we really I think all of
us who are working on it are very you
know get a lot of satisfaction out of
bringing this to you so thanks okay so
now now the hard work um so we're going
to have the call for presentations up
for sent for the san diego meeting
hopefully by the end of the next early
next week or the end of this week so
everybody start thinking about talks
tutorials tracks whatever you want to do
because San Diego is not all that far
away so with that I think I'll just hand
it over to Betty just thanks again
everyone
oh I'll be brief again I echo what Dave
just communicated which is there a lot
of folks involved in putting together
the meaning and the program for you and
I want to thank all of them from the
board members themselves to the entire
program committee to all the contractors
here in the hotel staff great job and
truly to comcast for coming forward and
hosting a hosting us again for the
second time and all the sponsors it's
it's really been a team effort and a lot
of fronts my job is to share with you
the results of the election process
before I do that I wanted to just give
you some highlights of the meeting we've
prepared some stats in terms of the
number of folks that were here and from
what regions we will as we always do
publish a much more detailed list of
statistics so this is just a real brief
summary to give you a feel for how the
meeting turned out number of countries
again just the tap but there I believe
were 30 some or something I'm not really
sure in the top organizations and by
description just to give you a sense of
the population that was here and again
welcome Nia nog 54 as we close nanog 53
we are now already preparing to support
you in san diego and i also want to just
take a moment before I announce the
election results and honor the memory of
one of our missing colleagues you will
have seen earlier on the projectors
perhaps and on the panel out front some
pictures of ABBA hula she was really
important to a number of us and to the
Internet at large she passed away ten
years ago so we like to take a moment
and just honor her memory I also
encourage anyone who feels strongly
enough and so committed there
our two scholarships available in her
memory one out of nanog and another out
of i believe f nog so we'll put links up
and if you want to learn more about Ava
in her contribution or two in Abel
others to follow in her footsteps of
engineering it would you know be great
my real job here is in closing the
meeting is to announce the election
results we will they should probably be
posted now if you go to the nanog 2011
elections page you'll get the detailed
results but i'm happy to report that all
four board candidates have been elected
to the board the bylaw Corrections the
work that others Steve primarily did in
helping us to correct some of the
language from the early adoption has
also been approved and the section of
the bylaws where we dealt with the
committee restructuring of the support
committees has also been approved so
that's the election results the program
committee as Dave indicated will be the
next set of tasks for the new board to a
point and get started on nan are 54 with
that unless we have questions for Dave
or myself for the board we're going to
close this meeting thanks again enjoy
your day
that's right because I didn't want to
forget to thank anybody but of course I
forgot to thank Betty and bet he's been
running around doing everything so thank
you Betty now we're done