bein so hi everyone my name is richard
barnes from BBN i'm actually the first
time Nana like it's andy i'm actually
not an operator i'm not a vendor and
kind of an odd duck here in some way so
Matthew I hang out a lot in the IETF off
so I'm talking about today about some
technology that's sort of emerging also
my ETF stuff that's been emerging
related to geolocation and it's actually
kind of notches in really well being the
last talk not just in kind of well with
the first talk of the meeting that Dave
Ward gave talking about the possibility
that exposing some information from
networks exposing that information out
to applications could really enable some
new stuff create some transformative
applications enable some really good
stuff and and improve the network
overall so with that so one of the
briefly review you know what the world
looks like today from from a geolocation
perspective so we have this situation
where there's all sorts of applications
that wants information about where the
users of those applications are
physically located so this includes
things like traditional location
location based services like you know
Foursquare I mean Yelp you know what's
the weather where I am what are movie
times where I am you know what's show me
some Chinese restaurants around where I
am typical location-based services so
those things fall into this bin there's
the thing that's been around for like a
lot longer is is things like content
localization and advertising
localization especially if you think
about you know people like Google and
Yahoo need to decide when I get a
request for an IP address do I serve
them google com or google.fr or
google.de since it's a very coarse and
it's not a visible form of geolocation a
lot of cases it's not something we're in
a user is explicitly saying show me
what's nearby me but it's one where you
know it's a critical one for a lot of
content providers to make sure that the
right content gets to the right users
there's also you know an increasing
demand as valuable content gets revealed
to things like Hulu through itunes to
control look access to things based on
on where people are so you know I want
to open up my service to users in the US
or in France and Germany but not in
Singapore or
japan there's also some emerging work
and using location information for
things like fraud mitigation you know
how do I detect when an online purchase
made with a credit card is fraudulent or
not or maybe if there are speed of light
constraints on you know being used in
one place and then being used in another
we can use it's at least as a heuristic
and detecting when there's some fraud
and going on so there's lots of
applications here ranging from
advertising this fairly static stuff
about you know how we picked the right
version of Google or Yahoo or if I do
for that matter to present to people
ranging all the way out to the much more
dynamic stuff like location-based social
networking restaurant recommendations
whether things like that and right now
these things are based on as they've put
it on Monday scavenged information is
over the top services that I'll talk to
talk about in just a minute that that
are kind of halfway work but have a lot
of problems and especially you know they
caused some problems for an operator
perspective at all i'll talk about in
just a second and the hope that you know
what i'm going to talk about today is
that maybe you know if we create some
interfaces from the network to allow
operators to supply these applications
with some information we might be able
to improve this situation so if we look
at how these services work today they
get location information from basically
two sources there are these third-party
services that you know reside off of
devices they don't have any touch with
the network at all when you know these
have been around for many many years so
they go under the heading of IP
geodatabases these are based on things
like scraping information out of the who
is databases you know if I register my
contact information as being in topeka
even if my network is in you know
dearborn you know the who is people will
grab that who has and say AHA you should
get ads for Chinese restaurants in
Topeka instead of in Michigan so that
that has that failing you know their
people are some of the more advanced
services that do this stuff actually do
network mapping they do Trace routes and
things like that to try and infer to
apology and improve your estimates of
location based on that but obviously
there's given the divergences between
topology and geography there's some
pitfalls there as well and sometimes in
very
limited cases some of these services
actually buy information from my SPS and
it's very limited and obviously can't
cover much of the internet that way so
that that's sort of the third-party view
and those tend to be you know coarser
grain you know you can get sort of
country or state or maybe metro area
location out of those things with you
know 90 95 inch percent accuracy i'll
talk a little bit more about that in
just a second the other class of
applicative location services we see our
own i call first party here so if i've
got an app that's actually running on a
device that's connected to the network
it can get a little bit more information
so you know we've got GPS things
obviously where that works so that works
well in some cases if I'm driving in a
car in an open area sometimes that works
pretty well but if I'm inside of a
building or in lots of urban areas it
really doesn't and so there's these
Wi-Fi and cell databases that have shown
up if you look at Android devices or
iPhone devices or Windows Phone devices
blackberries all of those have services
where the device you know the phone will
listen to Wi-Fi access points and cell
towers that are around it say I can see
these five access points in these three
cell towers and it'll send that off to
some service on the other side of the
network that has a database of access
points and cell towers and says okay so
I think these things are in downtown
Philadelphia so you are somewhere in
downtown Philadelphia and so you know
like if you use the iOS Maps application
you'll see when you make you click the
button that says where am I it will see
this rough circle up here and that's the
network based thing that's this you know
Wi-Fi cellular base thing that will then
tighten down hopefully to a GPS thing if
it works and then of course the very
last thing you can do if you're in a
pontiff devices just have the user say
where they are you can ask ask the user
where are you and use that as a location
option and that surprisingly enough is
how most 911 services operate for voice
over IP so if you look at you know if
you know there was this mandate from the
FCC a few years ago that voice over IP
did services had to provide 911
emergency calling in the US and if you
look at how that's actually implemented
nowadays it's mostly by just asking the
user where they are which you know
despite all the pitfalls is the state of
the art there right now
so you know the state of the art across
this is that the performance properties
of this whole system they're sort of
good enough to get a lot of stuff done
but they kind of suck still so if you
look at these IP geodatabases there's a
whole lot of variability kata actually
did a very good study last year
comparing these databases which showed
you know they had this variability from
about a kilometer to sometimes many
hundreds of kilometers sometimes many
thousands of kilometers in completely
different countries and there's a lot of
dependence on what sort of network type
you're in so if you're in a DSL or fiber
cable network they're pretty good but
they're much worse in mobile networks to
tend to backhaul over longer distances
to ggs NS and a really important thing
to try and tie this in with the rest of
the morning is that these databases
right now have little to no coverage of
ipv6 there's a couple of databases that
have some experimental support but by
and large they're there is no generic I
pgo for ipv6 so this is a real failing
in the mobile space in these first party
aap is um you know if you've got GPS and
GPS works then then then you're kind of
in good shape but the performance of
these wireless databases the cellular
and Wi-Fi access point databases is
really an open question because you
think they're based on the people who
operate the databases going around and
collecting the information there there's
no central registry of Wi-Fi access
points anywhere so if you want to have a
service based on Wi-Fi you have to drive
around or you have to have you know you
mobile phones Android phones report
information about access points they
observe and things like that and so this
is the scavenge database that has you
know obviously variable data quality
variable amounts of coverage you know
what I'm actually working on a study of
this and what we expect to find is that
in urban areas there's probably pretty
good coverage but if you get out into
rural areas or developing nations you
know there's probably much much less
fidelity there and if you look finally
at fixed networks so you know looking at
this this first party perspective what
we're in the device it fixed networks
they're pretty well covered by these IP
geodatabases but if you wanting any sort
of greater fidelity than that greater
than this one kilometer precision like
you would need for a 911 service you
really do need to ask the user and of
course that gets stale
very quickly if someone takes a device
from one house to another and and you're
sort of out of luck so the question is
you know you know when things go wrong
how do we fix them and right now this is
you know emails to the nanog mailing
list seem to be the primary mechanism
for this give it in the in the IP
geodatabase context you know there's if
there's problems in the David databases
obviously you need to detect them as an
application provider and then go fix
them on a database by database basis so
you know there's actually this wiki here
that says here's how you go submit these
web forms or something right emails on a
database by database basis assuming you
can detect what's going on what's going
wrong and figure out which database is
that you've gone wrong in and if the
database you've gone wrong and happens
to not be on that wiki page and no one's
figured it out yet we get these emails
to the nanog mailing this that I
scanning back through the archive show
you know a couple times a month on the
order of one to five times a month so
it's kind of a an awkward situation for
operators that you know you've got your
users that are depending on these
services you know they want to get the
right version of Google especially
outside the US where it's determining
what language the content is delivered
in much more frequently they want to get
google or they want to get yahoo in the
right language and when they don't you
know it you get help desk calls at the I
you know you're at the ISP because you
know Google doesn't work right for me
here why is it in German instead of
Dutch and then when you try and go and
fix this you have to fish around and
find the right place to stick it in so
the question is can we find a better way
to do this so there's a couple of
technologies that are emerging to do
this and so that what we're hoping to
provide here in there's a couple of
different avenues for this is to provide
some channel where the ISP who owns the
physical infrastructure and knows where
things are can provide some
authoritative information up to these
applications that want to know where
things are so you know as as on the
previous slide there's not really a
channel for that information now there's
these individual / database web forms
email contacts things like that but
there's not any sort of automated
universal system that that everyone can
feed off of it can be simple for people
to operate
in terms of the last presentation and
the upshot of this is that you we see
fairly frequent failures for the
applications fairly frequent failures
that users see and and on the operator
side there's not really any way to fix
this when you have an unhappy subscriber
so I want to briefly chat to talk
through a couple of different avenues
for for fixing this problem I'll sort of
go in in order from from worst to best
so the one that's been getting a little
bit of press lately is is this injection
system so there was a startup called
Feva there's another one called bearing
media and what these guys are doing is
they're building transparent HTTP
proxies that you can put into routers
and so what happens with these is when a
user sends an HTTP request out the
router or the proxy that's sitting in
the router sees this HTTP request go
through and it talks to some
infrastructure in the back end talks to
some isp infrastructure radius
infrastructure and says hey where is
this IP address and it gets back an
encrypted result that can only be read
by this demographics provider and it
sticks that encrypted result into an
HTTP header that then gets you know
conveyed to this web server of an
advertiser something like that so this
is kind of terrible in a couple of
different dimensions first of all it
only works for HTTP so if i have a VoIP
application or a 911 application that's
trying to do that do its job using some
protocol other than HTTP this system
doesn't do anything for it at all and
second it's it's really really awful i
from a privacy perspective so I share
the geo print working groups like I care
a lot about geolocation and privacy and
if you look at this it has a couple of
really really bad privacy properties one
you know users have no idea to how to
connect when this is being done um you
know there's if you look at what
providers tend to do when they enable
this sort of stuff they will contact
their users and say hey we are providing
your location information to some people
sometimes you know say if you want to
turn this off usually without
specification where it's going when it's
going there and usually with only a
binary option for users to turn things
off to protect their privacy
and and so there's this limited very
limited privacy control channel there
and if I'm a user I can't even detect
when this is going on right so it only
goes out in HTTP requests I can't see it
in the response that comes back to me
and even if I set up a test server it's
only been being injected when it goes to
specific advertisers that the provider
is partnered with and so it won't go to
my test server I can't see it so yeah
this is it's it's sort of interesting as
a proof of concepts that you know there
is a way that that operators can provide
information out to applications but it's
maybe not the long range path in terms
of having something that works for many
applications and something that has a
reasonable privacy story so the second
one that's a little bit better is this
an effort that's going on in the GSMA
community in the mobile community called
one API and what this is is this is the
suite of rest based http-based what they
call network api's that open up access
to various network services for
applications to take advantage of so
there's a geolocation API there's an SMS
api allows you to send SMS messages over
HTTP there's a charging api that allows
you to you know ask for money from a
user and one of the things that's nice
about this is that in addition to being
easy to program for cuz it's rest in
json over HTTP it actually has sort of
an authorization story so the IETF and
some of the web community even working
on this Oh auth thing as a way of
providing delegated authorization and so
the whole idea of the OAuth system is
that you've got a user that has some
resource that he has control over so in
this case I might be the user and
Verizon is my wireless provider might be
the one that holds that resource and so
off provides a technology for for me to
automate automatically delegate access
to that resource so access to my
location to some app and so I might say
hey verizon you should let Foursquare
use my location through this API so
there is something of a privacy story
developing here in terms of controlling
that access via the user the challenge
here if we were to sort of consider this
you know maybe this is a path toward
something for the Internet
that there's there's still a little bit
of technology missing so the critical
thing in terms of making it work is that
there's not a way to find the right
person to talk to you for a given
subscriber so one of the overall themes
here is that there's not really a
database a single database that's good
for every subscriber in the world right
there's no single database and you know
there's no one that knows about
verizon's users as well as SingTel's
users as well as dr. telecoms users as
well as you Armenian telecoms users
right so we need to figure out if we
want to make an application that's
globally deployable we need to discover
for a given subscriber where which
database which geolocation service I
should talk to and so this API is built
more for a statically configured thing
where I can look at say a telephone
number and say okay that's a verizon
number i'll go to verizon service i'll
go to ATT service for this number so
there's that challenge there's also a
few sort of gsm telephone specific
things in the API itself that that would
need to be squared away if we were going
to try and consider this for the
Internet so in a third thread there's
been an effort in the IETF to do to have
to create a system that can improve
provide a geolocation service for the
Internet historically speaking this came
about because the IETF started looking
at the problem of 911 for the Internet
how do we take this VoIP system we've
developed this the SIP protocol and make
it possible to do emergency calls with
this 911 calls 112 calls and it turns
out that it's actually pretty easy to do
that once you have geolocation
information and so the question arose
then how do we do geolocation
information in a way that's highly
reliable it's much more reliable and
much more authoritative than the current
IP geo regime that we live in today so
the idea is you know we should have the
system that's simple to wrap around
Alice existing location resources so
providers have databases of where things
are we should have something that you
know they can wrap around that and
provide a uniform standard interface to
those things we should have something
that has you know internet scale
properties that we can dynamically
discover which database to query for an
IPA
and we should have an explicit
consideration that takes into account
privacy considerations and how users
manage privacy so this has been going
for a few years we're starting to have
some mature technologies coming out of
this and the basic framework is you
allow both end devices and and third
parties applications to discover the
right location resources and then have a
standard protocol to talk to ask for
that stuff so you know the first step is
to do this discovery thing so the
standard near the ideal way in the ideal
case if you're talking DHCP out to your
subscribers you can provide a name to
them that says you should go look for
your location server over here and so
you provide this name example.com and
then the device can go out and look and
say AHA that is the URL for my location
server and if you're thinking about a
911 app or something the 911 app can
then go query that location so forget
the location and find out who it should
be sending its 911 calls to you know
likewise um you know Foursquare can
query the location server and figure out
where it should be checking in right now
so there's actually so this is the lead
so this is sort of the gold standard
discovery mechanism I'll mention a
little later other mechanisms for
handing out these URIs because the
overall protocol being an HTTP based
protocol obviously all you need is a URL
to get to it the most obvious thing you
can do is not stick this under some
arbitrary domain abuts they could under
reverse domain and in that case you know
if we start from an IP address you know
whether it's the IP address of an end
device or the IP address that I see as a
source IP address as a as a web service
say then we can look in the reverse DNS
tree for these records and find out
location server you r is for for remote
services so that that's how we find the
services and once we have those URLs we
can we can talk to them and so this is I
won't get into this in detail but the
idea is that if we're on a device we can
send up these measurements cellular or
Wi-Fi or dhcp information or dsl
information if we built this into it
some cpe we can get back information
about this the location of this device
either in geodetic form with coordinates
or in the form of an address and you
know in this case we've got the address
down to my my guests office in Cambridge
in building five room 123 if we're a
third party if you've got some web web
app asking for location through this
channel right you can send up
identifiers for the device you know
we're not on the device so we can't send
up measurements but we know what device
we're talking to so i can send an IP
address in v4 or v6 um I can say what
sport I saw this coming from or if you
know if I'm some telephony enabled
service I can even send up me on msisdn
or and MZ or something and you know
likewise the response actually looks
just the same but what I'm trying to
illustrate here a little bit is that one
nice thing about this being a web
service is that you can distinguish
who's asking and so as a location server
I can see is this the device itself
asking me or is this somebody else and I
can make privacy decisions based on that
distinction so when the device itself is
asking I can provide very detailed
information down to the room number
whereas here I might provide only the
building I might provide a little bit
more uncertainty in that geodetic
location so that's that's the protocol
it's pretty simple so there's also a
privacy framework that goes along with
this I won't go into this in tremendous
detail because we're getting short on
time but you can read RFC 60 to 80 which
provides a very detailed architecture
for how you manage privacy rules around
location stuff but there's the really
simple shortcut story through all this
is that you know if you're running a
location service you can provide the
user himself whatever he wants and you
can distinguish that by based on you
know what IP address you see your
request from and then you can provide
something that's more general fuzzier to
any third parties that ask and you can
use that distinction as a very basic
thing to help make some privacy
preserving thing decisions and so we've
built all these things and one thing
that I think important to emphasize in
this case is is that while we've built
the hooks in here ultimately it's going
to be up to the location providers
operators and thing and folks that are
operating these location services to
choose how they preserve privacy and
it's an interaction between operators
their subscribers and possibly their
regulators so you know the goal of the
technology is to provide the right hooks
but ultimately what gets instantiated is
going to depend on on those three
parties so so that's the technology
we've got running around nowadays and
what we at the IETF have tried to put
together for folks to use to improve
things so so where do we stand in terms
of deploying this stuff if you look at
where geo prep stands right now we have
sort of a chicken and egg problem you
know the typical new protocol thing
where you know this would be really
valuable if we had it but you know I'm
not going to write code to this
interface because nobody's providing the
information through that interface and
I'm not going to provide information
through that interface because nobody's
asking for stuff through that interface
so sort of where we stand now is that
there's very clear interest in this you
know from an application side we've had
some interest in sort of who is based
discovery systems from from google and
max mind and cove on mozilla sort of the
application location provider side of
the world and we they're starting to be
some interest interest in the u.s. from
the regulatory side in terms of enabling
these ng 911 ip-based 911 solution with
some better fidelity than asking the
user to register their location we do
have some open source implementations
out there I think on the next slide so
you asked me for information about open
source I forgot to put the oral in the
slides but there are open source
implementations of this held protocol
and and the discovery part of this you
may notice is just about configuring
DHCP and DNS stuff so it's really
configuration thing no no real code is
provided on the provisioning side and
there's some initial work I mentioned
alternative discovery system so you know
we I just described some DHCP and DNS
based systems you could also in
principle put this stuff in the whois
database right you could put add a line
to who is records and say for location
information that my geolocation contact
is this URL so go talk to that URL if
you want location information about my
subscribers and so there's some work
being done in ripe that might show up in
a piña caswell and there's I think 10
minutes allocated in the open policy are
in the air in meeting tomorrow to
discuss the possibility of doing this in
the whois database in the Aaron region
so this is just a picture of the the
right version of the
the prototype that was released last
week actually doesn't have a URL which
has may may cause some privacy concerns
it actually has you can see this geo
larkfield that has the coordinates where
I've said that my network is located so
just to wrap up you know how what can we
do now I always like to finish with
action points so if you wanted to play
with this you want to start seeing how
you this might be feasible in your
network you know you you're the ones
that know your network um you know we
work at the internet layer at the IETF
Flair we only sort of know about types
of networks and mostly about packets we
don't know about all the specifics of
how networks get put together at the
physical layer that you're going to need
to know how to build a location service
so you can look around you know go home
to your network and say hey what do we
have here that could be fit together to
make a location service you know we
played around with this at an ietf
meeting a little while back and you know
said oK we've got SNMP tables that tell
us what mac addresses are assigned to
which I PS we've gotten dhcp lease
tables and tell us what IP addresses
have belonged which mac addresses so
yeah we could kind of trace through from
at least an IP address to the location
of an AP and get some idea of location
that way so that's sort of you know it's
sort of like the information is hanging
around but it might get need to get
piece together and so like I said
there's open source code that you can
use to provide a standard interface to
this and of course the DNS records or
who is records possibly to allow people
to discover these services is only a
record provisioning away and again we're
going to be discussing this in the air
and open policy our the possibility of
adding the stuff to the whois database
so I would encourage you all to come to
that and engage in that discussion if
you're sticking around for the air and
meeting so with that some references if
you want further information and that's
all I have questions
ok
is any sandy Murphy Sparta I had kind of
a rumination sort of question Jeff
Houston spoke about the possibility of
not having an open one internet
everywhere but balkanization would this
architecture which is focused on
applications that need geolocation
information work as well in cases where
the networking services need the
geolocation information hmm that's a
good question what I haven't really
thought about there's already been a
little bit of accommodation that's
that's sort of starting to be built into
the protocol for things like
carrier-grade NAT you noticed in that
third party example had there was a
source port yeah so you can say what
port thing you got something from in
addition to you know what I what address
you saw it from and so there's starting
to be some accounting for disambiguation
at that layer in terms of providing us
to network services i don't know we
thought about that it may be an
interesting question look at Thanks ok
Chris Chris wealthy from switch this is
just a comment from a user perspective
to the service providers that use
geolocation please don't forget that as
a user I like to be able to change the
location so I I don't always want to
have the web pages or whatever localized
to my current location that I am or that
this reported by geolocation this also
makes it easier to not having to call
support or something when I don't get to
see what I'm supposed to see yeah the
one of the other things that I didn't
mention here that's been worked on the
GRE of working group is the question of
how you express you create a policy
language for expressing privacy
preferences and so it's it's pretty easy
to say don't tell my location to better
than a kilometer I'd like one kilometer
accuracy around my location and then
there's been some initial proposals for
that sort of full replacement you know
don't just fuzz up my real location
actually provide something completely
different it's sort of sort of one thing
something that's been proposed it's I
don't know how far along the process is
right now yes Mike Joseph google
actually to my question sort of relates
to the last one is the the problem with
obtaining the data either from the user
or from an authoritative source rather
than from inference is that you can't
rely on it as much and in particular one
common use case for location data as you
mentioned earlier is being able to
filter content which is often either a
regulatory or contractual obligations so
if you have to be able to determine with
some degree of accuracy where a user is
the problem with the system like this
and particularly a system where the user
could provide input into their location
would be you can no longer rely on it
for that sure so anything that you're
dealing with in the protocol or design
well so the idea of at least these
systems is to provide a channel for the
operator to provide input that doesn't
say that you know whoever is receiving
that location information that input is
going to treat that as the only input so
it's it's completely plausible that
systems using traceroute studio to
apolog-- using Wi-Fi information to to
corroborate a location value I expect
those will persist and and the location
services like cova and maximum will
persist as people to vet and corroborate
the information that providers supply
with regard to geo location because
you're right you know there are some
incentives for for operators for users
to lie about this to get acting you know
if I'm in Malaysian I want to access you
know right yeah that place or what have
you even providers may sell it as a
premium service to give you absolutely
and so there there will be some need to
do anti-fraud on that channel as well
yes sir any new clean air and staff do
have a question the right implementation
puts coordinates into the who is correct
in in the demo version of the demo
displays last week so that's supposed to
be the coordinates of the network or of
the endpoint or so it is assigned on a
network level okay um so it's an
approximation presumably of where where
the end users are with the intent of
putting a URL and who is point to a
geolocation server be that you can hand
it the IP address vs so you can get
location of what something more
meaningful than a network vs ok yeah so
you can in it I a P address or maybe a
prefix and and because there's a richer
geolocation syntax in that XML you could
you know the provider could hand back
something has a postcode or a country
designation or even you know some
polygons that describes a region all
right thank you all right thanks a lot