so my name is Birla sure I'm with
Internet systems consortium and I'm here
to talk about a little incident that
happened about 10 days ago so first I'm
going to start with a little bit of an
overview so that we operate is he
operates one of the 13 DNS root servers
out on the internet but we globally any
cash to the service from as3 557 we are
at over 55 sites worldwide and for those
nodes are what we consider global nodes
where asp 557 actually doesn't pier with
anyone directly anymore but we have what
we call management a esas so in the case
of the global node it's fully within a s
1280 which is our wide area network
which if you're in North America
hopefully your are appearing with the
remainder of these nodes are considered
local nodes and so the concept of a
local node is that we're serving a local
community whether it's a Nyack's network
access point or if you're in a small
country in st. Africa the major telco we
restrict the traffic be via the no
export bgp community string and for each
one of these local nodes we have a per
node specific management AS which then
peers with the either the route server
or appears directly with participants so
you see if you're looking at the route
path you're seeing a s3 557 our
management a s and then and then you be
peer on that particular IX or nap or a
route sir group as the case may be we
tried to drat drive traffic wherever
possible to a local node we do this for
various reasons we want to disperse the
DNS traffic as wide as possible and get
it closer to the end users wherever
possible so say someone in Bangladesh
doesn't have to to query their traffic
and have it go all the way to California
we want to hit Hong Kong or or if we had
were in our case we actually have a
local node into kha and the traffic
should just stay inside the country this
also has other benefits in the cases of
D doses and so forth as have been seen
over the years where we've been able to
mitigate the traffic by spreading it
over several local nodes rather than
have all the traffic trunk over the OC
over the Atlantic or the Pacific to our
global modes so we tried we do that by
obviously we prepend r.a.s several times
from our global nodes so you'll see like
a s12 a s12 AAS 1280 and to make sure
that the local nodes always have a
shorter path so if you want more
information about this we do have a blog
post that my colleague Leo becnel wrote
that explains this in a little bit more
detail we also on the global nodes
advertise covering / 23 instead of a 24
and that / 47 to cover those edge cases
so no one is left behind so a little bit
about effort in Beijing we actually
operate two instances of F in in China
we've been there since about 2004 one is
sponsored by AP neck that's the one
that's been there the longest we
recently turned up another one back in
the summer which is sponsored by CN deck
we operate the service but we the local
sponsors usually cover colocation and
handle network connectivity and and so
forth but I FC directly operates still
operates the service both of these nodes
have connectivity to the national telcos
and research and educational networks so
we have access to say china telecom
china unicom you name it they have their
own dedicated management asses so at PK
one we're at a s 23-7 those 07 and NP a
to we're at a s55 439 so those are being
up streams of say a s 3557 at those
locations the PK one is still just ipv4
direct ipv4 only the other is dual stack
ipv4 and ipv6 and in PE k1 were
connected to the Beijing nap and PK two
were actually hosted by CN neck and then
they export our routes over to to the
telcos and research networks so in
traffic in traffic numbers actually
Beijing is one of our largest local
nodes so what happened on October the
first at the time indicated there was a
leak of our ipv6 network block from PE k
2 to the ipv6 internet at large the
leaker right originated from a s3 3794
for which is the China science and
technology Network basically an are any
network actually was easy to find out
because they are currently our only v6
beer so the leak propagated from that a
s 2 a 2 hurricane over the Hong Kong
internet exchange and then from
hurricane to the world so is he was made
aware of the issue about 24 hours later
and once we verified the attack or a
very verified the leak we pulled the
ipv6 announcement straightaway and nanog
goes wild so there was a nice long long
thread about this so I wanted to to
clarify some issues some issues my
colleague Leah ilio bicknell addressed
some of these already but just to point
out there was no rewriting of answers we
actually checked this before we actually
pulled the route there's no there was
any traffic that came from that
particular location wasn't getting
rewritten by the Great Firewall of China
and and and so forth and the other fact
is that this actually affected less than
0 point 0 point four of our global
traffic flows now granted this is
partially because it's ipv6 but the the
other point is maybe you can say we've
actually made some progress because at
ipv6 day everyone was chomping at the
bit that we got point point2 of global
traffic so hey we've made an increase
but in the particular case this is
basically mostly of global traffic if
you are actually appearing with us
directly at any one of our other local
nodes where we already had b6 where we
already had a v6 session enabled in that
particular case you would be most likely
using that node anyway because it's a s
path web and shorter than this then then
the leaked a s path to Beijing and we
have seen no sign that there was a
malicious intent to divert traffic
someone's sticking a hijacked route or
or anything like that this looks to have
simply been someone stripping
accidentally stripping out our no export
and propagating the route to their up
streams and in fact we actually deal
with about handful of these every single
year most of the time you never hear
about it someone from an re need network
linking out to another are any network
and you find the routes gone halfway or
circled the world at least twice but
that's something we take very seriously
and we investigate and we and it's
usually take taken care of so some
takeaways from this there needs to be
more and better bgp monitoring
especially with ipv6 i mean we'd all
like it if we could get bgp monitors on
every a s and have a complete view of
the world but obviously that's that's
likely not possible we are looking at
various options ourselves whether or not
we use something we've been talking with
ripe about doing some stuff with atlas
as a possible mechanism there may be
other other BGP type services that we
may may may investigate in future
obviously we'd like more ipv6 peers
wherever possible
so those are the usual URLs third the
internet needs more diverse ipv6
connections the ipv6 table is still
relatively flat and basically for ipv6
it's usually yes but I have provider
that's all I need well could you get at
least a little bit more diversity so so
please check I know most of our
providers in the Bay Area we're mostly
dual-stack so please check to make sure
that your provider is offering v6 and
try to appear with them so it's just not
one provider and last but not least for
those that decry the fact that there
might be some shenanigans and DNS
rewriting going on please please please
please PLEASE deployed NS a-- sign your
zones turn on validation at the end of
the day if you're worried about the fact
that that that oh my god there we're
getting to or getting a dns responses
from x country and they might be
rewritten well the root sign a lot of
ccTLDs are signed a lot of teal these
are signed both make the effort to sign
if you're truly worried about your
online presence take take take control
and sign your bloody zones and turn on
DNS SEC validation and that's it rock on
thanks
oh so we have a question I taught
Underwood google so I have left my
tinfoil hat back in the office so this
is not a question about you know
nefarious hijacking obviously everything
you say seems completely reasonable the
the question is really straightforwardly
and it's genuinely a question because I
don't understand why do root name server
operators choose to provide service from
a network that has promised to rewrite
answers and then hope that it won't leak
too far and this is not a question
saying that China doesn't have every
right to implement whatever censorship
it wants to implement they do this is
not to say that other countries or
hotels don't have the right to implement
whatever kind of censorship they want to
they do I just don't want to be subject
to the censorship that I have either
opted into or been foisted upon me by
virtue of my passport so can you can you
answer the question why you do this well
I can only speak for F I can't speak for
the other root server operators we feel
that we provide an apolitical service
that basically the world community has
every right to good clean DNS services
and we make every effort to make sure
the answers that we give out are the
correct and the correct answers wherever
possible once they get out to a
provider's upstream we have no control
over at that at that point now as we've
had this conversation before we make
every effort if we find any sort of
shenanigans going on we immediately pull
the route and investigate right so that
this is actually my question I can
promise you their shenanigans going on
with the data you're providing in China
in fact the Chinese government has
promised you and they've explained what
those shenanigans are and you've chosen
to pick those as you're up streams right
so if this weren't a country if you had
three up streams and one of them said
hey by the way i'm going to rewrite the
answers you give and two of them didn't
and you picked the first one this would
be the situation we're in it's not a
political question i'm not saying
that you know the Chinese people don't
have a right to fast reliable name
service I'm just saying the rest of us
have a right to not have your answers
rewritten we make every effort wherever
possible thank you we make every effort
wherever possible I mean other thing is
is that we tried to keep the local
traffic local wherever possible and so
we do the no export once we find a leak
we investigate and pull it at the end of
the day the end solution and I'm going
to sound like a broken parrot is that
DNS SEC needs to be applied at that
point you don't care where the bloody
answers come from as long as you can
verify that the answer was correct as it
was signed and and on top of that
there's also the issue of all of a
sudden my 80 milliseconds got routed to
300 milliseconds the DNS infrastructure
will sort of self clean because it will
find a closer name server that will
there are 12 other root servers out
there they'll deep pref us and go do
someone else so if tundra it just takes
one more spansion on that this is the
last question then I left a Godwin this
thread all I was going to say I'm Jim
Martin with ISC as well the bottom line
is that we are providing a network
service we're not making any judgments
about what is right or wrong in any
country we don't believe that it's our
place to be making a decision about
what's right or wrong because just
because we believe one thing doesn't
mean that that's the appropriate thing
in every environment what we do believe
in is providing the clean route
everywhere in the world that we can
because we believe that that's something
that is fundamental for the growth of
the internet and so it I think the basis
of your question has to do with an
assumption that what they're doing is
wrong and we're not prepared to make
that assumption so I will we get the
guillen asses track if you want to
continue this further yeah yeah taken
you were waiting patiently we have time
for the for the one more you were
waiting like I actually have a fairly
quick technical question and actually
richard barnes BBN so you mentioned two
things you mentioned that it took about
24 hours before you guys became aware of
the change in the routing here and that
you deal with several similar events
every year so I was wondering if you
could comment on whether the delay here
between the change in the routing and
your awareness and reaction to it was
typical how that compared to the other
events you typically handle um well part
of it was is that it was weekend and so
I mean this is discussions we're having
internally 24 hours was a bit long so as
far as we're concerned so we're looking
at measures to try to it and at in this
particular case it was also a very slow
drip it was v6 we were only seeing a
very small section of our traffic
getting rerouted but obviously seems
something like a route route detection
change where all of a sudden all of our
global v6 traffic is diverted to China I
should have probably are diverted to a
particular location should have thrown
up a red flag so thanks