okay so my name is David second from
from Ericsson and I'm here to talk about
unified MPLS so basically where this is
coming from is this is a transport
architecture using MPLS obviously you
know as ericsson we we look a lot at
mobile networks and we think a lot about
kind of how you know in in various
stages these networks are starting to
start leveraged the the assets and
infrastructure for both fixed and mobile
so if you know in certain parts of the
network we see you know this
infrastructure coming together for
instance if you look at the edge of the
network where services are delivered
then we can start to see solutions and
and kind of elements of consolidation
and convergence where certain platforms
are leveraged across different functions
different services we have kind of
solutions which are an to end proposals
in terms of how to you know have
handsets which are you know mobile
handsets which typically get
authenticated in the mobile network
using sim based sim based authentication
technologies there are Wi-Fi solutions
which allow users to get access to
bandwidth in their home or in certain
Wi-Fi sort of hotspots which is using
this authentication from from from the
mobile network it uses the packet core
assets that that that the mobile network
uses but it's what it's leveraging the
fixed backhaul which which obviously has
much more higher capacity you can help
to alleviate this this this traffic
offload problem so you know from the
edge there's there's kind of elements of
kind of fixed to mobile networks coming
together you know looking at the IP core
you know this is kind of caring you know
all types of traffic today and in this
sort of consolidation convergence has
already been there for a number of years
if you look at the Metro and backhaul
there's a lot of things happening in
terms of kind of thinking about how to
use packet technologies in parts of
mobile networks which used to be
circuits circuits which TDM you know
leveraging kind of the same sort of
infrastructure that's used today with
with microwave and fiber and in the same
in the same in the same infrastructure
kind of combine these two things
together and you know have one one set
of equipment one set of technologies
that can support all these different
types of services instead of having
different sort of networks to support
all of them so essentially what's
happening is the collapsing of layers
and this is kind of a slow slow process
but kind of what what we see is you know
there's an IP services layer which which
has to you know be there to deliver all
the services that were used to getting
but you know MPLS which started off
essentially in the IP core is moving
further further in you know into the
metro network into the aggregation and
even towards the access so and MPLS in
some cases can serve kind of a packet
multiplexing transport kind of a packet
transport sort of function that spans
kind of you know from a you know from
the core all the way potentially to the
access and you know that's what we can
think of kind of as a packet
multiplexing or packet transport layer
we can think of this is now a proper
transport network if we look at kind of
the physical the physical media we have
fiber technologies WDM microwave even if
you extend this to the handset we have
radio technology so this is kind of a
generalized simplified view of the world
where we see kind of three functional
layers in in the network and in the end
the idea obviously used to really
consolidate and and and simplify for you
know food to optimize costs this is one
of the kind of solutions or one of the
techniques in which operators can start
to solve kind of the issue of you know
traffic and mobile networks increasing
and improving the cost sort of
consideration I think a key part of this
is really looking at you know if we have
this packet transport MPLS layer which
spans over a wide distance in the
network then how can we use you know how
can we make these different parts of the
network talk to each other we have MPLS
we have MPLS DP we have elements of
using OTN and DWDM and different
technologies essentially because if
we're building a
and antennae Network we still need the
segment when he still need to scale the
network that way it's important to kind
of look at these inter inter connection
points of the - of certain parts of the
network that need to be working together
so you know what what we're calling
unified MPLS is kind of an approach of
using MPLS TP which is kind of you know
this technology that has been developed
in the IETF over the last it's in
cooperation with with the ITU you know
to you know to develop a packet
transport technology which is kind of on
a data plane level is interoperable and
is just label swapping in the same way
that MPLS as we know it is today but it
also gives the the deterministic sort of
characteristics the the bi-directional
sort of circuit switch characteristics
that were used to in transport networks
so unified MPLS is a way that that that
we see of using MPLS TP to extend this
MPLS further into the aggregation and
into the access part of the network you
know this is kind of just a a different
approach if you compare with you know
another approach that's that's kind of
been proposed in the IETF which is
seamless MPLS and this is a way to use
the kind of IP MPLS if you like to call
it that which is MPLS as we know it kind
of where we use an IP control plane to
you know to automate topology discovery
and routing to build up and signaling to
build up our paths the the seamless MPLS
case is using this toolkit to extend IP
is it excuse me to extend MPLS to the
access we see a use case in in in many
instances to use MPLS TP for this
function and and and and that's and
that's kind of the idea with unified
MPLS is how to build a net it end-to-end
network using a common packet transport
technology and have it operate in a in a
simple way so basically the reason why
we're looking at MPLS TP is because in a
lot of mobile networks the requirements
are basically to upgrade well used to be
a circuit switch network
but have a packet technology allows us
to have efficiency of course of
bandwidth and statistical multiplexing
so we can have that but we can also
create these bi-directional paths with
with Co routed traffic between the two
different directions to have fate
sharing we can use the OEM mechanisms
that allow us to have fast failure or
fast fast fault management and
performance monitoring for detection of
failures and and in degradation in the
network so I think the important thing
here is that you know this has to kind
of plug into the existing IP MPLS
network at some point and that's that's
that's usually at the edge or the
service edge of the network and this
this this infrastructure there today is
already capable of offering IP services
fixed and mobile you know pseudo wire
handling IP VPNs VPLS all these sort of
things the in addition if we look at end
to end sort of connectivity then we have
techniques like multi segment rewire and
ways to handle LSP stitching and
tunneling that allow us to create LSPs
that span end-to-end and then we can
start to look at connections that allow
us to give certain services you know
across different sites so just to just
to elaborate on this if we look at the
different models here this is actually
this is better with animation but
basically if we look at the first the
first model with the termination mode
this is kind of a generalization of at a
very high level of kind of all fixed and
mobile broadband services we have a
backhaul from an access point which goes
through the aggregation part of the
network into some sort of service edge
and we have sort of a hub PE element
that's there to terminate a suit of wire
and handoff to a service node whatever
is kind of being aggregated from the
axis and this service node in a fixed
network is a bier as in a mobile network
it's s gateway or sgsn rnc once this is
handed off then this is you know then
it's up to that service node
handle the traffic either delivered
remotely or interconnected with the
internet with the i-x point of the
internet but but the connectivity is
defined that from a backhaul perspective
as access node to this to the service
node if we look at business VPN
connections which are the next three in
this and in this diagram
we're basically connecting an access
node to an access node and that axis and
these two access nodes can be located in
the same Metro or the same region or
they can be they can be remote and in
the case of the remote they need to be
interconnected over a core and if that
core is of a different flavor of the
MPLS technology then we have to think
about how to interwork in these sort of
scenarios so from so the in the second
model here is the first model for the
an-2 and sort of connectivity is is a
partitioning model this is when these
these two networks talk to each other as
as peers so at the LSP level they are
terminating LSPs and have in doing some
sort of stitching between two this could
even be extended to terminating pseudo
wires and having stitching between two
different pseudo wires so like a multi
segment pseudo wire approach which
there's proposals and IETF as to how to
do this an alternative approach is to
just layer it's just tunnel
whatever packets we have on one side
into the core into it a different LSP
and popped out the other side this can
be done in two ways one is your your
your interconnecting IP MPLS Islands
over an MPLS TP core or vice-versa
MPLS TP aggregation over an IP MPLS core
in the first case you know we've we
we've worked with a number of operas
that are looking at MPLS tp'ing a core
you know basically as a way to upgrade
their their their TDM backhaul a sorry
TDM long-haul network in in some
variations they're looking at doing this
automating that like the routing and in
traffic engineering signaling using
gmpls and in some cases they're looking
at
NMS to basically statically provision of
a mesh of LSPs in the core that's one
approach the other approach is to is if
you already have an IP MPLS a core and
you wanna if you want to if you want to
use that infrastructure and build out
sort of new backhaul networks for
example you know in mobile networks
which which are going through a process
of being upgraded right now
MPLS TP Kim can make sense in this case
and then in that case we can tunnel MPLS
TP over the IP MPLS core so basically
there's a number of different options
here there's different variants
dependent of course on a number of
factors based on the technologies that
are already installed in the network
conditions so you know basically you
know just to to look into one case you
know we we we're looking a lot of LTE
backhaul and basically we see the
opportunity to use MPLS TP in the
aggregation network even though even
though LTE is defined IP is the
transport end-to-end which means that we
have you know we have IP connections
defined by 3gpp starting from the e note
B going all the way into the evolved
packet core are sort into the EPC the
evolved packet core portion of the
network even though that's the case it's
still we still see that there's you know
you can still achieve what you need to
do having a hub hub spoke topology in
the aggregation so basically all your
traffic is without doing any processing
at the IP level you can actually just
backhaul a traffic to a hub PE and then
if you need to localize it 4x2 traffic
which is which is therefore handover
between different Ino B's we can still
meet delay and jitter requirements even
if we go back to a centralized site
another point of this sort of traffic is
so far what we've seen is that the the
actual bandwidth that's required for
these sort of connections that are
defined in 3gpp for LTE the amount of
bandwidth that's required is not very
high so we're comfortable with you with
this approach and and and and the good
thing about this is that we can use MPLS
DP we can we can build a static
LSP from from a South Side gateway which
is aggregating one or many in obese all
the way back to a hub P and we can pre
provision back up paths so that the data
plane can do whatever sort of protection
events that are required because there's
no control plane involved we can easily
meet sort of 50 millisecond transport
failover requirements in that case so
this is the this is kind of the vanilla
case of LT backhaul where we're just
building a transport network in the
aggregation but the we think that this
network here because it needs to process
IP we can also have this this PE sitting
at the at the hub site which has to hand
over to to a serving gateway for the in
the in the vault packet core part of the
network we can integrate the IP
processing function so now if we do this
we can have this this provider edge
device which not only is kind of a
termination point for our transport
network we can terminate in LSP and a
sewer wire the transport layer but we
can also we can also process that that
IP packet and act as is kind of the next
hop for the e node B and that's kind of
one of the things that we see it is
useful in this approach that you know
you need one box instead of two and you
know you don't need any kind of an
external and an I so this is what so you
know the there's obvious benefits to
this approach we think that it's it's
it's a way to kind of simplify the
network even even further and and
importantly because this is a full
functioning IP edge device we can start
to you know we can also reuse it if if
it's if if if it makes sense or if it
fits into a current current network
environment to for other services like
fixed or you know fixed fixed services
like beer as or even video delivery or
you know even for solutions like you
know Wi-Fi integration so
we see advantages to this sort of
approach so basically you know this is
this is kind of a bright bright picture
apologize for the for the for the
marketing slide but it's basically you
know we see kind of this as a way to
bring bring together two worlds one is
the is is is the transport and the other
is kind of the IP side and you know we
think that you know there's a lot of
different ways of doing this but
essentially you know we can start to
think about kind of you know ways to
collapse the network and build one set
of infrastructure for different services
and having different segments of the
network talk to each other in a fairly
operationally simple sort of way so
that's kind of you know what we see with
this with this approach so you know
basically we you know just to summarize
you know we see you know convergence is
kind of kind of out of necessity driving
opera operators to look at you know
different ways of of cost optimizing the
networks and PL STP is an approach that
we can you know used to extend MPLS if
if if if if you choose to you know all
the way into the aggregation and access
portion of the network and you know by
having this comments in our architecture
we can start to think about ways to
integrate transport and kind of IP in
the in the carrier network so that that
concludes you thanks any questions from
the audience okay thank you
okay I have a litany of announcements so
and then we'll let you everyone go to
the break a couple minutes early tonight
the social sponsored by Aaron who is
coasting here at the hotel their program
begins tomorrow afternoon is on the 33rd
floor at the hotel here basically pizza
party as well are the elections for
nanog polls close at 5:00 p.m. that's
for the steering committee bylaws as
well as accepting program committee
nominations through 5:00 p.m. today the
is coming back from the break at 4:30
we're gonna have the DNS track appearing
track and then as well we're at we're
gonna have ipv6 technology overview part
2 which is a continuation of a tutorial
it's going to cover
routing tunneling and transition
mechanisms so for those of you kind of
in the thick of of transition it's
probably a great talk to attend for
those of you that were at the newcomers
breakfast we're going to have a
newcomers debrief tomorrow morning that
starts at 8:30 in Washington a B which
was the same room that we were in for
the breakfast that's where you can come
tell us you know what you got out of
this and what you came here for and what
we can do better next time I also like
to remind everyone that the nog lab is
open so like to break now for until 4:30
thank you very much to our break sponsor
which is NTT America thanks
I've got about five presenters lined up
to give talks of varying lengths and
including myself and if everything goes
according to schedule we should have
some free time after after all these
talks so we welcome you know continue to
discussion on open topics and Peter from
ISC has volunteered to put his asbestos
suit back on and stand up here and field
some more questions about the politics
of China and whatnot so again thank you
for coming and I'm going to start off
with my friend Matt here is going to
give an update on D in a second comment
net and I'm gonna try to find your slot
you probably not to do this
afternoon everybody so as everybody
probably knows there's been a lot going
on DNS likewise and this is just a recap
of things that have happened if you've
heard me talk in the past six or nine
months there might not be a whole lot
new here but this will at least bring
everybody up to date so I'm going to
talk primarily about the zones that
Verisign had a hand in signing here's
the timetable we've had some really
significant deployments in the past year
so starting with the route being signed
last summer closely followed by dead you
we signed net at the very end of last
year and then the big one was calm on
the last day of March this year so now
that comma signed if you take a look at
the entire domain name market worldwide
and Verisign has a quarterly publication
about the domain name industry called
the domain name industry brief
interesting ly enough and it sizes the
entire domain name market worldwide at
200 million names plus and minus and
about a hundred million of those plus or
minus or in ComNet so when you look at
ComNet and all the other TL T's that are
signed you know well over half of all
domains worldwide can be reached with a
chain of trust starting at the root so
that's a much different place that we're
in now than we were just a couple years
ago so at a at a high level I thought it
would be interesting to talk just what
our philosophy was and and how we
actually went about deploying DNS SEC we
did a slow rollout of the DNS SEC
capable name server code at all our
resolution sites so we're running custom
code for resolution are our atlas name
server and we deployed the new code that
was DNS that capable but without DNS SEC
turned on and let that bake a good long
time and then we published this
deliberately unvalidated ozone this is
something we came up with in conjunction
with ICANN when we were deploying DNS
second the root and the idea is get the
effect of sending larger responses with
DNS SEC sending responses with DNS SEC
data types in them but without having
people actually depend on the sign zone
and you don't want people actually using
it for signing so what you do is publish
a zone that's deliberately broken
it has a key that's not usable so with
that technique in place then you can do
a gradual rollout that's the big thing
as it lets you do an incremental rollout
without this you've run the risk that
you'd publish a legitimately sign zone
at one site and no sign zones at any
other site someone would try to validate
it would work some of the time and not
some of the time so this way it's
guaranteed to work none of the time and
so this gradual rollout lets you observe
what's happening again this is an exact
duplicate of what we did for the route
and it worked very well then you're
relatively quickly unblind we call it
the unvalidated alone in other words now
that you've got this sign zone
everywhere serving up its signed content
which is larger but not working then in
relatively short order you start serving
the properly sign zone with the exposed
legitimate keys and then the last step
is very shortly after that you add des
records to the root zone in terms of the
provisioning side this would be what the
ICANN accredited registrar see we all
the time we have what's called an
operational test and evaluation or an OT
any environment and this is always a
sandbox registry system that the
registrar's can connect to this works
for new registrar's when they want to
connect and test their code that they're
developing it also works for existing
registrar's if they're doing upgrades or
changes on their site they know there's
always a place where they can connect
that as well you know whatever we're
currently having production on the
registration side so we DNS SEC enabled
that long before any of the other work
and that meant that as the registrar's
were implementing their DNS SEC
extensions on the registration side this
is the EPP the extensible extensible
provisioning protocol that's what the
registrar's communicate with us to
register domain names that protocol so
that that's been DNS SEC enabled and it
was in a second tabled in the sandbox
environment for a long time and the the
biggest thing I guess if I were to
summarize here the final bullet is that
we always allowed a lot of time at each
step to just let stuff bake and
wait for problems to surface to just put
some dates on this unvalidated oil
technique as we used it for calm at the
end of February so about a month before
the final deployment that's when we
actually started publishing calm but
with the keys obscured so we ended up
having an entire month where we were
serving a signed coms own that wasn't
usable by anybody and then in late March
through the 23rd to 24th we actually
unblinded the zone and then we did have
this this window where theoretically
somebody could have noticed the
unblinded sewed with a legitimate key
configured that key as a trust anchor
and used it but you know that's there's
nothing we can do about that that the
alternative would be to unblind it and
very quickly go into production and we
weren't willing to do that the whole
deployment well the root zone deployment
which I don't have on this slide was
remarkably uneventful no problems and
likewise with that edu net and comm
there was really almost nothing but one
thing we have that's almost not worth
mentioning is a bug in a few versions of
vine that affected the Indiana SEC
validation in certain circumstances so
this happened after dotnet was signed
and it required that nameservers be
restarted but we reported that is C and
it's since been fixed to the best of my
knowledge so I want a you know a
fairness to ISC we had one literally one
person report this so it's it's barely
worth putting on a slide but I think
that speaks well to the whole deployment
and the fact of you know how ready
everybody was and how mature d in a sec
is that it was such a non-event when
these big zones were signed if we look
at what happened to the actual traffic
after dot-com was signed for a long time
about 60 percent of the queries that
come to us and this is across all DNS
queries that we get about 60 percent of
them request DNS SEC information and
this means they have the DNS SEC okay or
the do bit said and that figures been
relatively static for years because for
a long time
popular recursive name servers have set
this bit even if they don't intend to do
DNS SEC validation they still request
the DNS SEC
metadata in the responses and when you
factor in how much larger the responses
get when they are d in a second abled
from a sign zone and the fact that 62%
of them them then are then going to be
larger that adds up to almost exactly a
2x increase in traffic so basically we
sign calm and instantly our response
size went up to X if we look at TCP
queries we expected an increase in TCP
queries because we did expect there
would be people who would be unable to
hear our UDP responses now that they
were larger and that they would then
retry over TCP and this I would qualify
as you know almost none in terms of
single digits per second per server
beforehand going into hundreds of
queries per second and when we look at
the overall volume of queries this is
this is nothing as I say it's from
almost nothing to very few not not
anything we were worried about we also
looked at what we call possible TCP
failover that is we looked at sources
that we heard UDP from followed by TCP
for the same query and this would
indicate potentially somebody having
trouble processing our responses and
this was again a very very small
increase this is lost in the noise as
well so this data leads us to believe
that we did not strand any large user
populations by sending them these larger
responses with new record types we don't
think anybody went went deaf to our
responses they certainly haven't told us
about it if we look at some numbers
about the registration side as of right
now there are 36 ComNet accredited
registrar's that have registered at
least one sign delegation in other words
they've sent a dias record for one of
their customers so that's you know there
are a lot of registrar's over around 900
registrar's but when you look at the
ones that are in
associated with one another they're
about 300 families of registrar's so
this is roughly 10% of registrar's have
registered at least one DS record so you
know i it's not that's not too shabby
but it's you know it's not as much as
we'd like to see there are some
exceptions one registrar has a lot of
signed delegations and a single
Enterprise has gone ahead and signed
lots and lots of its own so over over
500 of its owns and then you can see the
counts we have these are real-time as of
today just over 4,000 comm names are
signed and about half that mignonette
and just a few in dot ed U and thanks to
Duane we have scoreboard Verisign labs
comm so you can always hit that site and
see how many signed names there are in
comm Ned Ned you and finally lessons
learned I think the biggest ones that
after all the concern there was over
signing the route last year and and how
methodically and carefully we approached
that followed by how careful Verisign
was with calm and net and edgy because
of the importance of those zones because
of all that you know I think that was a
concern in certain quarters and I think
the happiest important news is that the
internet didn't break we saw just know
you know just nothing there was it was a
real non-event I think we showed that
this incremental deployment is possible
before we did that with the route I
think everybody had assumed that when
you deployed in a sec for his own it had
to be a big bang you had to go from no
DNS SEC to all D in a sec on all of your
servers within a very short period of
time and I think the fact that we
figured out how to do this incremental
deployment with the unvalidated zone I
think that's a happy discovery we found
this is particularly for the edu
deployment where we had some you know
very interested and engaged educational
institutions that worked with EDUCAUSE
and us we found that the test
environment for registrar's was very
helpful particularly because we provided
a signed version of that edu so but the
testers could submit DS records and see
them come out at the other end in a test
signed version of that you you know
monitoring as in anything operation was
critical and there are still minor
issues with some of
hardware and software install base so
with that I'd be happy to take any
questions
hey Matt John John Christophe from is
this hot here john christow from team
Camry from the the registrar's that you
listed in a couple slides back they said
there was thirty five or some number of
them can you you tell or do you know if
there was any particular effort by them
to actually go out and do the marketing
for DNS sacker or and for the one that
had the thousand was it just that the
there was a one particular registrar who
had a thousand domain names or you know
what what was kind of this success of
them doing that I guess yeah I'm not the
best person in verse nine to answer
those questions because I don't have you
know the direct contact with a lot of
the registrar's I know that I can tell
you verse nine has done everything we
possibly can to encourage registrar's to
deploy to you in a sec just because it's
been such a huge effort for us we don't
want it to be in vain so for example
we've got a bump in the wire signing
surface that registrar's can use if they
want to do in a second able their own
signing services we've written white
papers deployment guides so we kind of
feel like we've done just about
everything we can I saw I don't know
specifically what weirdest drivers are
doing I you know I do know that some
very very large registrar's are DNS at
capable so that that's the good news
all right thanks