now for a very exciting show coming up
here
we have mr mike ruth
talking about attacking and defending
infrastructure with terraform
how we got admin across cloud
environments
so you have a background i guess you're
working at brex right infosec all right
well uh take it away let's get them
around the hand up there
[Applause]
thanks everyone
i want to say like it's great to see
everyone but i can't i can't see anyone
actually right now so
but thanks for coming
my name is mike
i'm a staff security engineer at brex
my co-researcher oka was unfortunately
unable to make it but just know that
sort of all the slides and all the
presentation and research that we talked
about today
that was uh done through both of us so
big thanks to him
so yeah i want to talk a little bit
about
our supply chain security
hacking terraform um in particular we're
going to talk about how we got sensitive
credentials as well as ultimately access
into admin into cloud environments
okay
so
i'm sure that a lot of you probably
already know what terraform is but for
those of you who don't or perhaps a bit
of a refresher
um i wanted to talk about some of the
basics
starting with what is terraform so
terraform an infrastructure as code tool
right um and it's used to manage and
deploy uh
cloud resources as well as a handful of
other resources now whether it's on-prem
with vms
kubernetes clusters now has support
right vault handful of other things they
come in a different
flavors
it started as an open source tool
and
for individuals who probably use the
open source tool still
they're probably
using it directly from endpoints
strictly from laptops right so that
means that all of your source code is
local to the endpoint
all of your credentials to be able to
get access to cloud environments and
things like that that's also local to
your endpoint
um over time though you know the idea to
productionize that so that you can
remove those types of credentials from
those environments um you know it became
more and more of an idea
and so hashicorp came
came around and pre created this sort of
productionized versions right these are
things like terraform enterprise and
terraform cloud
the scope of this presentation is going
to focus on those latter two things
terraform enterprise and terraform cloud
and not so much on the open source
version predominantly because all the
credentials and things are already local
right um for individuals or or companies
who may have productionized terraform
their open source version of terraform
themselves some of our findings might
still be applicable but just know that
the majority of things that we're
talking about today are through term
enterprise and internal from cloud
all right so let's talk a little bit
about the internals of these services or
these tools
i think it's best to start with
organizations and workspaces so these
act as logical boundaries
starting with an org you tend to have
many workspaces inside of a network
inside the workspace
that's where you sort of manage all of
your resources and these workspaces they
tend to be associated sort of one-to-one
with your different environments right
so you might have a workspace for your
dev environment a workspace for your
staging environment for your prod
environment right
you might also have workspaces
specifically for a dedicated application
an application in devs staging prod etc
but typically you have them per per
environment
inside a workspace you tend to have
what's known as a state file and as the
name implies it handles and persists all
of the changes that have occurred what
it believes to be the state of your
given environment so this is useful so
that when you go and make
changes in the future there's a
cross-reference between what it thinks
is currently out there in states as well
as the incoming changes so that they can
perform a diff between the two
the sort of
meat of what happens inside of the
workspace are all done by providers so
the providers are responsible for making
all of the changes in your environment
so we might have providers for a bunch
of different clouds aws provider gcp
provider
kubernetes provider etc right
these are binaries that run
that are responsible for knowing about
all of the resources that need to be
managed right so
it knows about all the configuration
details and it knows how to hit the
responsible or the related apis for that
given provider to go and actually
configure
and apply those resources
okay a little bit about access so
for an organization who may just start
out using terraform enterprise or
terraform cloud it may be such that
you've removed for example
all of the cloud credentials from your
endpoints and instead have replaced them
with terraform credentials so that they
can go and actually make requests to
terraform enterprise
terraform cloud etc and this works
very much like a crud model and it's on
a per workspace basis they don't
necessarily call it crud instead they
use different terms plan apply read you
can see their definitions here
up until
a couple years ago
these were basically the only
permissions that you could modify on a
given workspace but now you can actually
use custom workspace permissions and
this is actually pretty relevant in
particular for the read based permission
because read for a while meant being
able to read the output of a given plan
or apply but it also meant being able to
read the state and the state file the
contents of the state as well so these
custom workspaces permissions were
actually now granular enough to only say
allow
read access to the output and not
necessarily read access to say the state
file which you'll see might be relevant
coming up here
okay so
there are there's some challenges or
perhaps some problems with having
everyone at your company or anyone who
needs to
manage infrastructure at your company to
be able to go and communicate directly
to terraform itself
so a more sort of mature approach might
be removing access all of those sort of
individual credentials for being able to
get access to your terraform cloud or
enterprise
systems and instead use version control
this is actually pretty beneficial for a
developer experience perspective too
right because
you don't necessarily want everyone to
go and learn a new tool but most people
are probably at least most engineers or
developers are probably pretty familiar
with version control right github
probably in particular
and so the way that this works
is you have a repository map to a
specific workspace inside of say
terraform enterprise or terra from cloud
so there's sort of a one to one
relationship between work state
workspaces and repositories you might
have a monorepo instead where you have
sub directories that map to workspaces
but this is
essentially how this works and so
when you have a repository and you go
and submit either a pr or commit to it
it goes and kicks off what is known as a
speculative plan against the workspace
and that speculative plan is then
responsible for doing uh like that dry
round that we kind of talked about or
that you saw on on the access side of
things
one thing that's worth noting is that
speculative plans do not show up in a
work spaces job queue so a job queue is
basically all the list of plans or runs
that exists for that given workspace
that'll be relevant for a little bit
later so just keep that in mind
when these jobs are created though we
have sort of a
set of nodes this terraform
infrastructure just a bunch of compute
that's responsible for like doing all of
the work that's associated with
whether it's a plan or apply right all
the job and and those are terraform
workers right those are the responsible
for doing the actual work itself
and so the idea for this reference
architecture is
you know you you have these terraform
plans that exist they provide provide
dry run results and then you go and look
at the results perform some sort of code
review if everything looks sane you
merge the pr right and then you actually
perform and apply and that's how your
infrastructure gets gets modified
updated and managed
so this is sort of a reference
architecture diagram at a high level
we're going to be talking and showing
this type of diagram a lot in it so it
you know it probably makes sense to just
sort of take a second here and
look through it
so
it's a pull request the question was
what's a pr
um
so it's it's a request to go and make
change to a to your version control to
your repository
so a user goes and creates a pull
request
to the given terraform repository that
goes and kicks off the speculative plan
that we talked about which just happens
to be a web hook that gets configured on
your repository for the specific
uh workspace you can figure that
beforehand and so that pr gets triggered
the terraform workspace has a job that
gets scheduled on the terraform workers
then your resources are eventually
managed after the terraform plan gets
reviewed the code gets reviewed merged
and eventually applied
okay so problem statement
we contend that
in most organizations most engineers
have access to create prs against your
terraform repository so maybe a quick
show of hands for individuals
who use or have used
terraform enterprise or terraform cloud
at maybe their current organization or
previous organizations
show of hands how many
of these organizations sort of allow
blanket pr requests to terraform
repositories
i
i see a handful i mean hold on
yeah all right i see a handful and it
makes sense right it's
it's good developer experience to be
able to sort of allow many individuals
to create prs and the assumption is that
that's a safe action
so why is this a problem
all right let's talk a little bit about
our
findings so finding number one is all
about secret sex filtration
so we were able
to access the secrets of a workspace
through a terraform plan and in
particular a speculative plan from a pr
this allowed us to exfiltrate all of the
terraform variables all the workspace
environment variables and all the
secrets that existed within that state
file for that workspace so some of the
secrets that might exist in state
depending on your organization might be
secrets that exist in hashicorp vault so
if you have some sort of connection
there if you've got a vault provider
it would make sense to manage your
secrets in such a location but in doing
so referencing them in your terraform
workspace means that they end up also
getting stored in state
another type of secret might be say
certificates or certificate keys
so if you're responsible for handling
ingress or load balancers or any sort of
you know front-end communication and you
want to do that in a programmatic manner
you might use terraform for that well
certificates and keys they might end up
in there another use case is kms
encrypted secrets if you're doing any
sort of encryption in transit
and you want to define say the cipher
text inside of your terraform source so
they can be decrypted in sort of this
programmatic fashion well uh
all of the uh both the ciphertext and
the plaintext might end up in state file
as well so
we were able to get access to all of
this and
this is sort of a workflow for how how
it worked
so step one very similar to what we
looked at for our vcs reference
architecture instead of um any
individual creating a pr well now a
malicious pr gets crafted and that gets
sent up to the terraform repository
which in the same way kicks off a web
hook that triggers a plan
that goes to the terraform console
which eventually ends up being run on
the terraform worker and then our
malicious code kicks off and goes and
extracts all of the environment
variables that exist for that job and
either sends it back to the output of
the plan if you have access to that but
it's just as easy to go and send that
information say out to a remote listener
that you've already configured ahead of
time
okay finding number two this is about
state exfiltration
so
we talked a little bit about workspaces
being logical boundaries and we talked
about how each workspace has a state
file we were able to access the state
files through a terraform plan of all
the other workspaces inside of an org
and we're able to do that from one
individual workspace or any individual
workspace and so the way that this works
is that
um
whenever you create a job for a given
workspace that runs on those workers
a token a terraform run token is what
hashicorp calls it
is created it's also known as an atlas
token if you kind of look at the
variable name
and that gets available with every plan
and every apply
and it turns out that that token is sort
of over authorized it has the ability to
go and fetch the state from any other
workspace that's within that
organization
similar workflow
malicious pr gets crafted
web hook triggers a plan
plan goes to the console
that body of work gets um
kicked off on the terraform worker
uh then a malicious code runs we go and
fetch that token probably using finding
one right and then we can go and fetch
the state from a given workspace by
communicating to the terraform console
and similarly we either push that the
results that are in the state file back
to the terraform console or you kick it
off to you know send it to a remote
listener
okay finding three this is probably the
most important finding
apply on plan bypass so
it turns out that when you perform a
terraform apply you can actually perform
a terraform plan within inside of it
so our expectation if we consider our
reference architecture previously there
was a an assumption that existed where
when a plan was created
some sort of review had to happen prior
to the apply step right that you needed
to do the code review you need to merge
the code so that you can eventually
perform the apply turns out that's not
actually true we were able to perform
terraform applies through unmerged
non-code reviewed prs
and they're super difficult to audit too
because they're those speculative plans
that we talked about earlier
because the speculative plans don't show
up in the job queue it's not easy to see
you have to go through audit logs that
provide you with sort of a run id and so
now you need to know exactly what you're
looking for or you need to come in sort
of from the other end and know exactly
how to look at a specific pr to find it
perhaps more importantly depending on
the use case it also grants access to
the underlying file system of that
terraform worker
so depending on your environment this
may or may not be
critical
if you're using terraform cloud then all
the workers are managed by hashicorp
themselves and they're pretty well
locked down they have your own dedicated
aws account for you they don't have any
instance profiles or any extra im
permissions so while you do get access
to the underlying file system
and you might be able to get remote code
execution you're not necessarily getting
lateral movement here
however
if you are using terraform enterprise
you're responsible for managing those
terraform workers yourself and that
probably means that they exist inside
your network
and that could mean that the terraform
worker has access through vpc peering or
through transit gateways or some sort of
access to all of your other environments
that exist as well
and of course privilege escalation is
kind of the big thing here
if you have access to the underlying
file system of your workers chances are
those are configured with some sort of
best practice in mind right so that
means if you're in aws
uh the workers are using probably assume
role with terraform profiles if you're
in gcp or azure you're probably using a
service account of some kind and in all
those use cases you can hit the metadata
api to go and fetch those credentials
and because terraform is responsible for
managing all of your infrastructure and
all of your accounts it's probably admin
level credentials that you then can get
through that so privilege escalation is
very real
and the last point that i want to make
on this slide is with
we don't talk too much about policy
enforcement but hashicorp does provide
sentinel which is sort of a policy
enforcement framework and more recently
they've provided run tasks with
terraform
and so the idea with these is that they
you can have sort of an advanced
language to be able to enforce any sort
of you know your unique or niche use
cases that you want to sort of prevent
these types of things from happening
uh but unfortunately these things run
within the context of a pre-apply and
post plan so any sort of policy
enforcement that you might be able to
get out of these tools
only applies after a plan and since all
these attacks are occurring during the
plan step we were able to bypass them as
well
similar to our last two findings finding
three is the apply on plan bypass again
malicious pr gets crafted
pr kicks off a plan
the plan goes and runs we perform an
escape
from that the context of the plan onto
the underlying file system and instead
of sending the exfiltration results to
say the console or to a listener we
actually just go and we actually write
malicious resources into the environment
itself
okay
so let's revisit the problem statement
if anyone in your organization can draft
prs against your terraform repository
that means that they can exfil
exfiltrate secrets from any workspace
they can access the state file from any
workspace
they can bypass all this access control
that we have in place right through
unmerged non-code reviewed prs
and perhaps
more important to some you get access to
the underlying file system of your
compute for your tf workers
okay
so we have some demos
i want to show you that kind of
illustrate the workflow that we just
went through
so this is sort of the demo architecture
pretty similar to the reference
architecture that we have looked at
already so we have this sort of fake
hypothetical company crypto exchange co
uh and they have a repository that goes
and creates speculative plans uh through
this vcs integration
and they've got two workspaces website
dev and website prod so basically
they've got one website that works and
they've got a dev version of it they've
got a prod version of it because they
use terraform cloud their terraform
workers are all kind of within the same
environment and then the terraform
workers are then responsible for
managing the resources in a dev cloud as
well as in a prod cloud
okay so let's look at
finding one which i think needs a second
to load this video here
there we go
okay
so we're going to run this get
environment on the dev uh the dev
workspace so we go and create a
pr the pr gets kicked off with a sort of
innocuous or simplified name creating a
template instance so it's very
unassuming
we can see when the pr is created that
the web hook is generated against the
website dev we go and take a look at the
details inside of the terraform console
and in there our malicious code is
running where we generate a null
resource to null resources in fact one
to go and exfiltrate all of the
environment variables which you can see
all the environment variables of the
worker are just sort of listed here
and also the environment variable tf
vars which as we can see has say
presumably provider credentials for aws
here's finding number two
similarly we want to get the state file
from
our prod environment by running in the
context of our dev environment
so again we go and create a pr
the pr is run against website dev as we
talked about
you can see that there
the plan kicks off and we can see again
that our malicious no resource was
created
and inside this we'll be able to see the
link to the state file right there
and then we sort of unfurl what's in
there and we see that we have database
credentials from vaults configured
and those database credentials are
associated with with what appears to be
the prod environment
so we've been able to get
say an act username and password for a
prod environment through a pr from dev
okay finding three
so we want to perform an apply on plan
for our example we're going to go and
create an s3 bucket
so this s3 bucket is going to be named
remove this bucket
so when we go and take a look at our
current environment we can see that
crypto exchange code does not have that
s3 bucket
so we go through our same process again
we go and create a pr pr goes and kicks
off the terraform plan the speculative
plan
we're in website dev
malicious code triggers a null resource
and then here we can see that the
terraform apply is actually running and
we can see the output of the apply right
here
apply was complete and resources were
created so we go back and take a look at
the environment
remove this test bucket exists
so we were able to go
and push resources
through a plan
even though you know it was actually
performing and apply
okay um so next let's talk a little bit
about remediations
mitigations and some limitations
to those so the first thing that we
thought was like okay i think we've got
something here what should we do
uh so the first thing was we should
probably talk to hashicorp about this
and so that's what we did we ended up
getting in touch with a couple of
individuals from hashgraph security team
uh we brought this to their attention we
had some of these conversations uh and
they sort of agreed uh you know that
these were sort of legitimate findings
so the outcomes of these discussions
were sort of twofold number one was that
a security model which consists of sort
of a threat model uh was created and
available to everyone and then the
second thing was well there were some
actual
mitigations for some of these findings
i wonder if
does that help hold on
slideshow
that's better okay so this is the
security model i you don't need to
squint and it's actually blurry
apparently so don't worry about it the
link is there and we're gonna dive into
uh each relevant section for each
finding a little bit more so don't worry
too much about this
okay remediations for finding one
so the first thing is
you know while we showed that this was
applicable with speculative plans it's
still just as true for regular plans as
well right if you have the credentials
to go and interact with terraform uh you
can make the same types of you can you
know use those findings as well so if
you're not using version control um
and i guess regardless actually you
should probably implement the proper
access control on terraform enterprise
terraform cloud and all the workspaces
right so this means that we should limit
who has plan apply and view access on
all the workspaces if you are using
version control with that web hook
configured chances are the majority of
people do not need plan apply or view
state they might not even need to view
the the output the only individuals that
are probably need to do that are the
owners or the individuals that are
reviewing code
secondly is probably implementing access
control
on on github on your version control
right so chances are you want an
approval flow you probably do not want
by default everyone at the company being
able to
uh submit these prs this is sort of you
know lease privilege if you will
the third one which is probably the most
technical control here is you you can
disable speculative plans and that's
currently disabled by default you have
to turn it back on but if speculative
plans are disabled uh well then plans
aren't being being pushed and you know
the the avenue for these findings uh is
basically gone
so here's a bit of a all right yeah that
looks pretty good so if we this is the
same workflow that we've shown on the
previous slide but now we're seeing it
in the context of hashicorp's security
model
starting in the top right vcs
contribution is the individual right the
user they may have access to go and
submit a speculative plan which ends up
being able to read sensitive workspace
variables which is kind of in the bottom
left here
okay so what are some of the limitations
to these these remediations these
mitigations that we've just talked about
well
the first one is if you even though you
have all of these access controls on the
given workspace well if you have a
speculative plan that's running it's
going to bypass all of them right
because it has plan access that's what
it's responsible for doing
if you have access control on version on
your version control systems it's very
possible that you've just implemented
some sort of regression to your
developer experience right it's really i
mean when i asked with a show of hands
how many individuals work at companies
that anyone can push pr's the reason for
that is that it's very convenient to do
that so if you remove that convenience
you know you're sort of shifting the way
that many individuals work at the
company and that might lead to some you
know experience problems
uh the most important one though is you
know disabling expected plans because it
removes that web hook it makes it super
difficult to review code you know i'm
not sure about anyone here but for me
when i go and review to terraform pr the
first thing i do is look at the plan
results from that speculative plan to
see like what is changing and what's
happening and when i take a look at that
then i can cross-reference it with the
source code to make sure that those two
things align and then i can go and you
know sort of give the plus one on the
code review so without the terraform the
plan without the speculative plan that
gets super difficult and often times
that might be a non-starter
this is part of the
the security model documentation from
ashley corp one of the things was
basically what is out of scope for their
security model
and we can see the first thing here is
malicious contributions to terraform
configurations and version control right
and that's kind of that's the demo those
are all of our findings so
we can see why
sort of the planning one still exists
even though we have some sort of
mitigations in place there isn't a
surefire remediation
okay finding number two much better
story with finding number two so we
talked a little bit about this atlas
token or the tf run token
and how it was over provisioned well
the most sane thing to do was actually
reduce those permissions by default and
that's exactly what hashicorp did so
they created you know you can see the
announcement link here on the slide but
basically the idea is by default
that token does not have access to all
of the other workspaces within the org
however if you would like to provide
access to specific workspaces back you
can do that inside of the console itself
you can see the workflow here that we've
talked about but with the context of the
security model again starting in the top
right
someone
pushes a pr kicks off the speculative
plan typically that means that the
terraform run token can go and read and
get access to the state file for other
workspaces but with this change that's
no longer possible
and here's a little gif that kind of
shows that functionality in action
so we can see that you can share state
globally which is sort of the known bad
default prior however the default today
is with that off and you can then on a
sort of workspace by workspace
environment add them back in
limitations on finding two um
you know the finding still exists we've
sort of reduced the blast radius here
unless all of your workspaces have this
off by default um you know you're going
to slowly add you know
a threat landing in the threat landscape
a little bit more right one workspace
might be of access to just one instead
of all the other workspaces i think it's
a pretty good mitigation in those types
of scenarios though
we didn't talk too much about cloud
agents um
the cloud agent is basically the agent
that you can put on terraform workers or
on compute to turn them into terraform
workers so this is something that you
might want to do if you wanted to manage
your own terraform workers with
terraform cloud for example
basically the cloud agents have their
own token that can go and fetch
jobs from the queue and when you fetch a
job well you get all the environment
variables that exist in that job and so
that means that you can potentially go
and get access either to the state file
or to any individual workspaces in the
state files of those workspaces
that it has access to
and we can see from hashicorp's threat
model that that's the case right
crossworks based data access via cloud
agents is still possible
okay finding three
i wish that there was a better story for
this um
there aren't very good remediations at
the moment
um that's finding three is pretty
similar to finding one at least in terms
of
um the
access pattern right the the exploit
pattern as well as some other
remediations so we can limit perhaps who
can commit and create prs on the
repository we might be able to prevent
speculative plans but they come with the
same sort of regression and developer
experience that we talked about with
finding one
there is a possibility of system level
enforcement it's not something that
we've looked too much at but if for
example your terraform workers are
running linux you might be able to use
things like app armor se linux things
like this and create profiles to ensure
that all of those
providers the binaries that are running
all of this code they might not be able
to do things or you might have them
configured so that they can't do things
like run arbitrary bash or run python
scripts or things like this
that's worth noting that this is only
going to be possible if you control the
terraform workers if you're using
terraform cloud and they manage the
terraform markers this type of
mitigation is not going to be available
okay
so when we take a look at the security
model
in the pathway there actually isn't
an established route for this when you
take a look at the contribution and it
goes and kicks off a terraform plan
there is no
line if you will to the terraform apply
operation so it's not actually well
established which is probably why there
aren't very good remediations that exist
so like we said there's some limitations
and they apply mostly from finding one
and again you're limiting the blast
radius which is great by limiting access
control and who can submit prs but it
does not actually remove
the finding itself
and we can see malicious contributions
again
but if we think a little bit about it if
we could sort of
be in
the hashicorp engine engineer's shoes or
if we could you know snap our fingers
and provide any functionality what what
could we think of for proper remediation
for this finding
and so this was sort of something that
we came up
with and i think that we see this
pattern
in the open source productionized
versions where people have sort of full
control if they're not responsible for
or if they're not using terraform
enterprise or terraform cloud but
organizations are instead using open
source version of terraform and they've
got the flexibility
i think we start seeing some of these
things so when we go and take a look at
how the web hook triggers a plan and
step number two the terraform plan
should have its own dedicated
permissions right only read-only
permissions for terraform plans
furthermore it has dedicated
infrastructure only plans run on this
set of terraform workers today you have
sort of a set of nodes a bunch of
terraform workers that exist both plans
and applies will run on those sets of
terraform workers so in our sort of
proposed model we have dedicated
permissions as well as dedicated
infrastructure right back to the basics
separation of duties and least privilege
that way if we try to attempt to perform
any of our findings
well yes you can still perhaps you do
read based actions
but any sort of right-based actions that
might happen to be
attempted to be performed to the plans
well they're no longer possible because
the permissions just don't exist there
and that way um finally when you get to
the terraform apply step well then you
have a completely different role or
different set of permissions that has
read write and it's capable of
performing you know read and write based
actions
the one thing that i will say here that
isn't kind of listed is if you have the
ability
um
again maybe through this sort of open
source version that we see i
you might be able to
put access control or policy enforcement
kind of before the plan step and that
would be my sort of my suggestion as
well uh you know
to say hashicorp or anyone who has the
capability of doing so is let's consider
these
secrets
how great would it be if we could just
move
those
they actually run pre-run or plea pla
pre-plan and not after plan right and
now we might actually have uh an
opportunity to catch sort of these types
of malicious code and things that we're
running during these speculative plans
and in our prs
okay some conclusions
um
if there's anything that you take away
from this hopefully it's these three
things one all of these findings are
still exploitable today
so be sure to go through the
remediations that we've talked about if
you're practitioners or users of
terraform enterprise or terraform cloud
bullet number two
we should really have separation of
duties
and applies with these enterprise
products and i hope that they come soon
um
you know we should make sure that we
have those separation of duties and
least privilege
and number three
secure architecture and the threat model
documentation that hashicorp put out
right i think it's super important for
practitioners to understand what the
strengths and weaknesses are inside you
know of the products that you're using
and i think that'll be super helpful to
take a look at
okay last but not least we didn't talk
too much about the how here we saw some
demos and we saw some workflows
we just didn't really have time so
if you're interested we've automated all
three of our findings
it supports
two entry models whether you've got a
repository that's associated with
your terraform workspaces or if you have
access to make requests and plans
directly against terraform with a
terraform client
you can go and take a look at the link
here
examples and usages are all on the
readme but you can go and download that
and use the automation for yourself
and that's it
thank you very much for attending
any questions
excellent
good stuff here man i really appreciate
your work
hi um should we take this as a
cautionary tale uh against having
um
you know companies like terraform with
their commercial products
do this for us i mean i i thought that
was a very interesting point you're
seeing people who were working in open
source they may have some limited
features compared to that commercial
offering or more work to do
but as a does this should this cast into
doubt just the whole idea of
infrastructure as code being uh
outsourced to a for-profit enterprise
like this oh i don't know
well i mean when do you think they might
fix this well um i don't know the answer
to the last question but i will say that
there's a constant
build verse buy
challenge that all of our organizations
face if you have an infinite number of
resources in an infinite amount of time
maybe you can go and build this open
source version and maybe you can go and
solve all these problems
but lots of organizations don't
necessarily have that opportunity and i
think this provides a lot um you know if
if the alternative is that all of your
endpoints for all of your developers or
engineers have aws creds in the prod i
think that this is probably the better
approach
that would be my thought there
any other questions
went over here all right
hey mike uh quick question i know it's
your first two examples used null
resources in terraform i couldn't tell
if the third third example did it did it
did okay great so i was assuming we
could also mitigate this by limiting the
use of null resources in terraform did
you like exporting ways of doing that
well on terraform enterprise or cloud i
i don't think that it will solve the
problem because the no resource was just
the one that we ended up using because
it was the most convenient but there are
a lot of different providers that can do
the exact same thing you've got remote
provisioners you which actually
work on apply but you also have
http providers there are remote
providers from remote marketplaces
so while i do think that trying to take
a look at
specific providers and not allowing them
to to run that might be helpful um
again though a lot of the policy
enforcement that well anyway yes i think
that that's a uh avenue of invest you
know research and investment but a lot
of times that might not be feasible if
you can get rid of everything that might
be able to work i will say one last
comment is we were able to exfiltrate
all the environment variables um just
using the aws provider right we could
actually set the name of a resource to
the value of a secret and it would just
show up in the terraform plan results so
um i think it would be a slippery slope
i don't think it'll solve the problem i
guess is what i'm trying to say i think
they'll find other avenues to do the
same thing
okay we got another question
um hi uh thank you great talk um i was
wondering if there is a way to use other
tools like static code analysis tools
kind of like checkup or some grab to
develop uh
detections prior to running the webhook
as early as the steps to the pipeline
use some other tooling yeah possibly
right so chekov is pretty cool because
it does provide sort of this sanitary
you know in like even even on a
developer endpoint right it could
provide some sort of uh feedback um it's
not something that i've investigated too
much
and i don't know what the extensibility
of those types of tools are um if i mean
i'm sure clint might be here if you know
if he's a some grep expert so that might
be something uh worth talking to to
anyone who knows a little bit more about
that
excellent question all right we got
another one
uh thank you for your talk it's
extremely illuminating i'm sort of
already in a thought process about how
to control some of this stuff and we're
considering taking on uh resource
whitelisting or allow listing to attempt
to mitigate some of this and i'm
wondering i heard your about the
information leaking but at the very
least do you think that would be an
effective control against the arbitrary
script uh execution stuff
maybe i guess it depends on how you're
doing white listing i've read um article
like uh
vendor
sort of uh
customer
like articles that are in unison with
hashicorp that try to use sentinel
policies to try to do these types of
things um
the problem i guess that i was i
mentioned right is it happens a little
too late so potentially you could do
white listing it just depends on where
in your sort of supply chain you've put
that
if it's prior to your speculative plans
then that might work you know if it's a
if it's a web hook
that kicks off that prior to you know
your terraform plan web hook or you know
it's required to run before your tow
from plan web hook maybe that's
something that that could work yeah
okay other questions here
all right um oh good
fantastic
you might great presentation um just
quick question like what would you say
is some or i guess kind of like low
effort quick wins that you'd put into
place just based off of everything right
there was a kind of like a lot of
mitigations that could be used but would
be some quick things that you could do
easily to prevent some of these i would
i would say that um they're probably all
of the suggested remediation points that
i was suggesting right so it depends
on each organization's environment um
you know if you're using open source and
you've got all your credentials locally
move to maybe an enterprise version or
productionize it
if all of your engineers are have access
to the credentials in terraform let's
remove those and perhaps use version
control if you have the capability of
putting like pre-configuration checks
prior to your plans that's probably a
little bit more effort but all the
access control for vcs and for um
for these providers i think is super
important starting point
okay cool other questions
all right um
i guess one last point for anyone sure
who wants the slides um i think i can
upload them to the b-side site or um
i'll i'll put them on my twitter as well
and uh is this
part of the show here
up on the board
what is that
oh i mean i've been doing this whole
conference just to summarize it
oh
it's pretty cool
i'm super pumped by it i love that we
have one here
excellent work
i'd like to think that i probably don't
should get a screenshot
okay well i can tell you i've learned a
lot from this i mean i've
packed it before but a different way
and but now you just like really took a
deep dive on me are there any other
websites uh of hacking
uh terraform
that you know of oh yeah i've seen
plenty so we started in this research in
2020 so it's been a couple years with
covid and all that stuff we haven't had
a chance to present it but in that time
you know similar i've seen similar uh
blogs and things like this have come out
so yeah i um i don't know the links off
the top my head but they they're out
there so it's uh great for red team
exercise pipeline poisoning right sure
okay
um
last chance for questions
okay well please give it up for mike
ruth
in conclusion of this sorry francisco
akka couldn't make it but
thank you and y'all have been a
wonderful audience as well so