hi folks oh there we
go perfect um thank you for your
patience uh thanks to besides for
putting this on for having me to all the
volunteers and to you for coming this is
buying security a client's guide and
today we're going to be talking about
how to buy and get value from security
services vendors specifically around
security assessments
um
hi i'm rami uh i do not work at twilio
i'm at a series d health tech unicorn
out in new york city i'm based in boston
um
i am what i call a reformed security
consultant so i have experience both
buying and selling these assessments uh
and i just want to give a quick thanks
to tldrsek and my friend clint who
worked with me a lot on this content
more on that in one second
so quick heads up you do not have to
worry about taking notes and photos i
made this super dense there are a lot of
references there are a lot of call outs
these slides will be published after the
talk a link will be available at the end
and clint and i have put up a long form
version of this guide on tl dr sec that
you can read at your leisure in the
future as well and of course the talk is
being recorded um so feel free to take
pictures but don't stress about it
so why are we here why do i feel this is
important you can't buy security right
it's not something you can purchase but
security services are a really important
part of security programs especially as
your company grows you'll need
capabilities that you don't have
in-house you'll need to scale your
program in a flexible way
you'll need a third-party validation of
the quality of your program and shopping
for and deriving value is therefore a
core competency for a lot of security
engineers
but organizations struggle it's a really
hard thing to do when you're doing it
maybe once a year maybe you've never
done it before
there's information asymmetry there's
difficulty assessing performance of a
vendor or quality of your assessment
there's infrequent or limited awareness
of just the breadth of this industry and
the services on offer
there's frankly misleading sales tactics
and a lack of standardization or quality
on delivery across the board so it's
really easy to buy a dud
and there are
a lot more alternatives nowadays that
make it harder and harder to navigate
this marketplace
so we're gonna dive into it um hard to
say better than the survey respondent
and a little programming note more on
the survey in a second but when you see
this logo on the top left
that is all sourced from the security
community who participated in this
survey
it's also just a big industry like
security services are almost 100 billion
dollars i know in these rooms at these
conferences we can feel like a small
community and i love that but there's a
lot of money in security services and
that means there are a lot of competing
interests at play
so today we're going to talk about
buying security assessments as a narrow
lens to look at the security services
industry as a whole
security assessments just in case you
you know don't have the definition off
hand there's the nist version
it's all about assessing
architecture implemented controls and
really just making sure your security
program is accomplishing its goals and
meeting your security requirements
so what do we get over the next you know
40 or so minutes um
i've synthesized 200 resources on the
topic from all across the internet
i surveyed over 100 security
professionals in collaboration with
tldrsec and we've put together a
comprehensive guide on dying and buying
and getting value from these services my
goal is to use this to work together and
like really continue the conversation
about how we as an industry procure
assessments and then use them to
measurably reduce risk because that's
what it's all about
so numerous sources just wanted to throw
up some logos quickly we stand on the
shoulders of giants there's been lots of
writing and thinking on this topic from
pen test vendors as content marketing
from standards groups government
organizations conferences academics
a full bibliography and citations will
be up with the guide as well in case you
want to dive more into this
and about the survey
this was circulated throughout the
security community slack groups networks
tldr sec again we had over 100
respondents 71 of whom were buyers and
68 were sellers with a lot of overlap
and it was basically a 20 question
survey about buying and a 20 question
survey about selling just trying to get
some frankly quantitative sampling bias
present data from the community at large
beyond you know what we were reading and
what our personal experiences were
and like here's some of what we were
surveying right
if you look we had representation across
industries obviously professional
services are really well represented
when you're interviewing folks who work
at security consultancies
but also a big representation from
like the information industry financial
industries as well
and companies of all size right about
half folks worked at companies with more
than 500 employees but uh you know a
broad array of folks represented and uh
procuring when you're under 10 folks is
definitely different than when you're
over 500 so sort of a broad swath of the
industry here
and i just wanted to talk about like how
much coverage do we get we only talk to
100 folks obviously it's limited but
together and this is a logarithmic scale
we have coverage of over 1 300 purchase
security assessments and over 25 000
sold and that's like especially on the
right hand here you have some folks
selling 5 000 security assessments which
is a bonkers number to me um so i went
and checked into it and i will say these
are folks who have like 10 to 20 years
running a consultancy or sales for one
um and they just have this wealth of
experience that we were able to tap
so like why are we here why am i
entering with this presumption that this
is hard
well i really latched on to this idea
from haroon's 2012 2011 talk
some of you have seen it others should
he comes up with this concept of
security pen testing companies as a
market for lemons
it's a
economics paper that talks about
marketplaces and it says basically if
you're selling used cars you have good
cars which are cherries and bad cars
which are lemons and if in the market
both exist buyers have to average their
expectations they don't want to like be
paying cherry money for a lemon and so
slowly folks will take cherries off the
market and only be selling lemons and
this is like how information asymmetry
where buyers can't trust that they're
getting a quality product can really
just degrade the quality of the industry
as a whole and i think and haroon does
as well or at least did in 2012 that
this is emblematic of security services
buyers don't trust they're getting a
good quality product and so they average
their expectations and so we're slowly
moving to sort of the least common
denominator product
even in 2007
we were talking about this
gary mcgraw likes to refer to pen
testing security assessments as a
badnesso meter right on one hand you
have like you and your security program
suck and on the other you have well i
guess we don't know
there's no winning in security
assessments you can't prove a negative
there's no way to say there are no holes
there are no vulnerabilities there is no
risk all you can say is that in the
target scope with the time allotted we
didn't find any um so this is hard this
makes it a really hard like product to
buy because
is a blank report a good thing or not
what about one with a lot of findings
right like what are you actually looking
for how are you assessing quality
and
how do people feel about the quality of
the marketplace right here's a here's a
statement we made and got some you know
how much do you agree with this
statement metrics um the average answer
you know a normal distribution right
around to 2.9
this was the same for folks who had done
both buying and selling agreed
but when you slice the data by buyers
and sellers you see a shift
buyers actually have a higher confidence
in average quality
and frankly i actually think this is a
problem i trust the sellers here who are
likely more informed on the industry and
the offerings
obviously with some biases and i think
that this is evidence of like some
issues where buyers are overconfident in
the quality of the services they're
receiving or unable to dig into the
quality
and similarly concerningly um like
the output of a security assessment is
probably some risks uh and some advice
on what your priorities should be and
what the risk level is and there isn't
like this overwhelming consensus that
risks are appropriately graded we'll
talk later about how to account for this
discrepancy um but you really uh would
hope that we could trust that vendors
are working in your business context
giving you like well-groomed risks that
you can immediately apply and that's
just not the case currently
so
we'll dig into more challenges as we go
um but i want to talk about how we can
do better at buying security assessments
it's certainly generalizable but much
easier to carve a slice out and talk
about it in specifics here
and i stole this diagram from patrick
who i believe is somewhere around b-side
so if you see him thank him for me
but there are a lot of types of security
assessments out there he slices it along
scope and
the level of visibility given to testers
there are a lot of other ways you can
slice it
but i just like this to show that like
when you're buying an assessment there
are a lot of things that could mean and
you should probably know which one you
want before you talk to a vendor
here's a different breakdown right we
have vulnerability assessments threat
modeling red teaming social engineering
white box testing is dominant this is
actually interesting outside the talk
this wasn't always the case and there's
been a big push by security services
vendors to get more access a lot of
clients historically don't want to give
you access to source code or their
systems through fears of the risk
involved but it does let you get much
more efficient thorough comprehensive
testing done for cheaper
so it was actually good to see that
reflected
and then you can see there's a long tail
of all sorts of assessments represented
here
and big red slide i don't know if this
is a hot take or a warning we'll we'll
figure out how you all feel about it but
when researching services vendors you're
going to stumble across emergent
offerings bug bounties and automated pen
tests or red teaming are super trendy
right now there's a lot of marketing
i don't want to digress too much but
there are false comparisons out there
between these services and a traditional
you know consultant-led engagement um
and i just don't think they're a
one-to-one drop-in replacement and i
think that uh folks who are buying their
first pen test now can get you know
taken down a rabbit hole of other
services
to put it another way or as one
respondent put it it's gang tough to
find something that's not just a dressed
up nessa scan this has always been a
problem it's a problem with legacy
vendors but it's especially a problem
when you're looking at
the level of automation used in some of
these places
so let's talk about the process right
how do we go from deciding we need an
assessment to actually buying something
delivering value for our business and
then what do we do after we've done this
once
i have kind of arbitrarily created this
11 step breakdown i want to note it is a
circle even though it doesn't look like
it
you probably don't want a one-off
security assessment you want some sort
of program of security that security
assessments are part of
and so we can start by figuring out our
motivation and this is like fairly
obvious to some folks but a misstep in a
lot of these processes
to book a successful engagement you have
to have a clear goal it's true of any
product management but
there are a wide range of reasons to you
know book an assessment for a report
yours are going to have downstream
considerations for how you operate the
assessment what vendor you procure
you might want to just do pure risk
reduction i want to know what risks are
out there i want to fix them
maybe you're trying to sell your
security program internally and are
hoping for a report that shows that
you're doing a great job or maybe you're
hoping for a report that highlights the
need for more resources
it's involved in the sales cycle
although i will say that for sales wait
until you have a client deal contingent
on an assessment before procuring one
for that reason
it will save you some time and pain
early on
and also post breach and this isn't
instant response this is you know after
a breach i want to identify how they got
in where they otherwise could get in
raise my risk baseline
and so you know
great to see risk reduction as the top
cause of folks buying a penetration test
uh security assessment in my mind um
that's the most altruistic reason to
just holistically improve your program
but you'll also see a lot of folks are
buying them for compliance or internal
evidence and this is interesting because
you probably want a different test for
each of these reasons and we'll talk
about that in a bit
but you know you've decided you want a
test for risk reduction or for your you
know pci
compliance
um any go about finding vendors this is
like the first question right like
what is the list of vendors what are the
good ones how do i find them
it's surprisingly difficult you can't
just like type it into google and trust
you'll get a good deal uh you can't tell
the wheat from the chaff
um and there's a lot of marketing out
there trying to uh muddy the waters
and so i was gonna give you a taxonomy
of like the types of vendors but i don't
have five thousand dollars to spend on
this talk
so we're just gonna give you the types
of vendors minus the taxonomy so um
there's a broad marketplace there's
misleading sales tactics there's
evolving terminology and an overwhelming
array of vendors and services but
navigating this as a buyer it helps to
try and like bucket the vendors you're
seeing um into common patterns and you
can take this and your goals and then
really start to narrow down the possible
vendors for your contracts so there's a
big range here from multinationals to
solo shops you have single service
specialists as well as you know low-cost
vendors that are competing on price they
have their place and then mssps and vars
and on the last two i just want to say
it's a high trust relationship to have a
managed security service provider or a
var
however if you're buying a security
assessment in order to validate the risk
reduction they are providing think about
what it means to book the pen tester
security assessment through that partner
you may want external validation in that
case
and so
here's the first set of challenges we
got from survey respondents
finding good vendors who provide
significant value who are available when
you need them who have expertise in your
specific subsystem and who can provide
consistent quality staff it's
true throughout the industry that um you
can definitely find a vendor but finding
one that meets your needs is still hard
and so there are a lot of strategies you
can do to find them
this image is associated with
certifications in case anyone was
wondering
so you can start with network
recommendations this is the first thing
you'll hear generally right like talk to
your network find a friend who's gotten
an assessment ask them who their vendor
was
when doing so keep in mind that like it
depends on the quality of your network
and their ability to vet whether they
got a quality assessment a lot of folks
will get referrals from people who
may not
have broad experience with different
vendors and have no way of you know
saying how good it was or not
or folks who haven't been a client at
all and are recommending a friend who
they trust which
has a little less diligence to it
i also just kind of
like this follow the leader play in
finding vendors which is a lot of
marketplaces and integrations for big
tech companies require an assessment to
get into the marketplace to integrate
google's oauth stuff has this facebook
workplace has it
and they generally name a few vendors
they trust to do these assessments and
that can be a good way to kind of get a
picture of what big tech is using that
being said your needs are probably not
the same of those of like facebook or
google and keep that in mind as well
depending on your budget um
but there are a lot of ways to do this
research quick call out
great to go up to conference speakers if
they work at security consultancies and
hire them as someone who used to do that
and work at a security consultancy but
watch out for pay-to-play schemes watch
out for sponsored sessions
um this is the stack rank of like what
other people are using to find their
vendors
um i would call out that i'm a bit
surprised by research being so high
research is very cool it contributes a
lot to the industry it's not very
tightly correlated to like real world
assessment competencies and so like
going to a conference talk and having a
researcher say like
a war story about a cool exploit they
found and then hiring their company as
your pen tester is not one to one to me
so i'd argue a little caution there
and i'm surprised by the low view of
analyst rankings although not offended
by it uh they get a lot of attention
especially on twitter a lot of effort
paid and apparently we're all
in this cohort at least in some
consensus that's not how we prefer to
make our decisions
so we've defined motivation let's get
more granular on what you need
and what sort of like constraints you
have on the vendor you can choose
and so scoping is during a security
assessment it's like here's what work
we're intending to get done um and like
let's put some boundaries on it so that
our vendor is not just wandering in the
woods
and it falls under parkinson's law um
this is the law that states that like
work expands to fill the time allotted
um you scope a project because you're
trying to give them just enough time to
give like pareto principle 20 of the
time 80 percent of the outcomes high
return on value
if you ask a vendor how long something
will take without giving them a tight
scope you can expect them to try and
take as much time as you can for it
and it's all about balance right when
you're scoping an assessment whether
this be a web app or a network you're
trying to do a comprehensive set of
tests
but a focus on the greatest risk because
you're not going to pay for an
assessment that covers everything
everywhere all the time
so you have to be thoughtful about where
you pick your battles
and does the client you get ahead by
coming into procurement um you know
something like half of clients are
coming in with a clear scope in mind and
this will really help you groom your
engagement to provide the most value to
your organization
there are a lot of things that you
should think about when you're scoping
like budget is the first and biggest
constraint here you can see the folks
are saying that you know assessments are
a big part of their security program but
budget may not be totally there
and it's important because if you can't
afford everything you want you're going
to have to make difficult decisions and
cuts
so also think about the motivation and
how that might impact scoping if you're
getting a pci assessment for example
there's some pretty clear guidelines on
what you need to include um if you're
doing it for sales you may
care a lot about what sort of
public-facing materials you're allowed
to use and say
you may have documentation needs like
you need a letter of attestation to give
to a client or maybe even a public
report which is something like pretty
complicated and expensive to procure
if you have measurement goals like
you're trying to test your blue team
you're probably talking about a red or
purple team engagement which has all
sorts of different constraints scoping
is a huge topic of its own i'm linking
here to four different guides i found
helpful
marks from 2007's still holds up so like
that's the one i'd read if you read one
thing about uh scoping application
security
so
these are some dots they are hopefully
animated we'll see how this goes
awesome so
there are requirements you may have that
limit your available pool of vendors and
your optionality here
if you are requiring a remediation
assistant not all vendors will offer
that um you should know that in advance
so that you can kind of use your time
wisely similarly any requirements you
place on the assessor whether that be
requiring them to be on-site or have
certain citizenship or clearance or
methodologies or certifications these
all serve to limit your pool of
potential vendors
fundamentally that's not always a
problem it you know reduces your
decision space um but it can also make
things more expensive because you're
limited in your options
so you you know you you roughly know i
want to test this web app
i have a few you know tens of thousands
of dollars
i have a rough idea of a list of vendors
like let's gather some proposals and
start figuring out who we're going to
use
and so there's a few steps right if
you're a large company you probably have
a formal rfp process
smaller organizations it's normally like
call up a few vendors and ask
rarely something so formalized
generally industry analysts my
experience your shortlist should
probably be around three organizations
it's really time consuming to have all
these vendor conversations and there's
like
limited incremental benefit to adding
additional vendors to that pool of
selection
so cut early
get some high confidence in some vendors
through your rfp or request for
information or some basic scoping and
then really drill down into some initial
calls
and here's where we flash back to
motivations right like what are some of
the ways that your motivation may
influence your vendor selection
if you're looking for compliance you may
require vendors with certain
certifications you also want to have
what i call a balance of substance when
you're trying to target compliance with
an assessment you want them to provide
value you want them to do a good job you
also want them to help you pass
compliance so there's a balance there on
the type of vendor you choose
um
similarly like there may be auditor
relationships um in internal
attestations
this also may be like depending on your
audience you may know that a certain
executive has a lot of faith in a
certain
external party and you can use them
mmas are interesting because it ends up
boiling down to speed of engagement in a
lot of cases but they also have specific
characteristics you'll want to search
for
and then of course like
for sales like i said wait until a
client deal is contingent on an
assessment because clients will have
really strong opinions on who the
assessor is if they're at the scale
they're trying to throw their weight
around here and the worst thing is when
you've like just paid for a shiny new
assessment and then a client says they
don't care and you have to go to the big
four
it hurts
from a budget perspective
so like what do you do on this first
call i've been on a lot of these calls
with clients and with vendors and
there's no consistency to like how we
talk about an assessment and try and
figure out if the vendor's correct
here are some things you should think
about
from a logistics perspective like how
soon can you staff this engagement is a
really early way to call vendors
especially as you get into q4 calendars
get packed generally you're looking at
like a week or two lead time for the
average vendor in the average period and
then in q4 that balloons you're also
going to want to focus on experience
with organizations like yours and when i
say like yours i mean things like tech
stack industry vertical risk landscape
you want to hear them speak to your
industry business logic threat model and
needs and not just give you like a
you know here's a web app pen test in a
box here's a you know network security
assessment here's our standard threat
model
and you want to talk about engagement
model and this really depends on your
organization as well and how you like to
work
but how do they collaborate are they
willing to open a slack channel with you
will they communicate over email will
they get on calls with your pms
how do they staff engagements and make
sure that you're getting a qualified
assessor for your problem space what's
their project management methodology and
as you get bigger and bigger and are
doing more of these this plays an
outsized role because you want the
vendor to kind of self-direct as much of
this as possible because this is why you
are outsourcing
and you should take these opportunities
to judge vendors on their communication
on their responsiveness on their
collaboration if they can't field these
initial calls effectively in a way that
inspires confidence why would you expect
the assessment to be any better
so you've gathered proposals right you
have a presumptive vendor the next step
is actually like welcome back to scoping
again this time with the vendor involved
vendors do their own scoping process um
it's in sport it's important you've
explicitly communicated your
expectations because otherwise you can
do a lot of back and forth as vendors
revise
proposals that are just out of line with
what you're intending to accomplish
you can request multiple scoping options
most vendors will give you like a big
medium or small if you request it and
that gives you some flexibility and you
should expect that this will be broken
down by level of effort coverage or
inclusion or exclusion of certain like
types of assessment elements
deliverables
you're going to want this like scope to
give clear
objectives for the assessment
an expected level of effort which ties
directly to cost and what they think
that gets you in terms of depth of
coverage
and another little warning here um watch
out for vendors that are willing to like
write you a quote on the spot based on a
metric like number of ip addresses or
like number of apps
um it's insufficient to accurately scope
and it lends itself to false precision
and i consider it like a smell when this
is how a vendor's gonna scope for me uh
for example when i was on the vendor
side we were getting clients come to us
and say like i have 200 ip addresses how
much will an assessment cost and you say
well like let me run a quick nmap scan
let me see what's out there you find out
that there are 100 ip addresses inside
those ip addresses there are three web
apps and they're actually asking you to
scope three web app pen tests right very
different approaches very different
levels of scope or scale the difference
between like test a single service if
it's a crud app or a static website are
different
it's important to right size your
assessment over scoping and underscoping
both have problems over scoping you're
paying too much under scoping you're not
getting what you need accomplished and
you're not identifying risks
and there's no consistency in how
vendors are going to want to scope your
assessment but this is the basic process
they'll send you a questionnaire or have
a call
or ask to like scan your perimeter or
maybe like give them the outputs of a
specific tool or look at your code a
little bit and then they'll have a
conversation about you know what you're
trying to accomplish and how big your
app is and what kind of screens there
are or what services are running on your
network or
how many employees you have for uh
threat modeling
and then like maybe they'll ask for a
demonstration or some documentation and
they throw that on a blender and come
out with very different numbers if
you've ever run procurement for pen
tests like
pick five vendors you will get five very
different quotes back
so that is why it's helpful to come in
with your own preconception of what the
scope looks like
and they're giving you back a quote and
it can either be fixed price or time and
materials
but basically your goal as a buyer is to
get detailed pricing and this is so you
actually can compare like for like
apples to apples across your various
quotes you're receiving because if you
just get like a bundled price it can be
really hard to tell where your
flexibility is what your axes for
negotiation are
what each is offering
often they'll call out earmarked
discounts like here's our list price
we're giving you 25 because we think
you're great
um take it with a grain of salt focus on
the bottom line number uh
payment terms are super interesting with
smaller vendors uh this is something
that i as a security person didn't think
a lot about um but you know whether you
get paid 30 60
365 whether you get a percentage up
front or in full um whether you're
paying on milestones like for small
consultancies
getting the cash earlier has real
leverage on you know where they're
willing to compromise otherwise
and something that comes up when you're
like working as a security vendor is
people ask why the heck it's so
expensive uh this is a pretty old
reference as well but just gives you a
high level of like everything that goes
into selling security services that
results in the day rate uh you know
hitting the level it does
especially in this market hiring
qualified security people is expensive
um
utilization like they're not working 24
7 every day they're scheduling
constraints there's inconsistent demand
there's ongoing professional development
there's burnout prevention which we've
heard about already today
and there's like the fully loaded cost
of employee and overhead of
non-assessors so um i'm not defending
the pricing model of any specific vendor
because i'm not aware of them but i will
say that there's a lot more to it than
like taking the salary you pay your
employee and dividing it by the number
of hours and comparing the two
so
you get a vendor proposal you get a
contract great like what goes into it
well you might want to negotiate um
i personally hate negotiating with
vendors is not something i enjoy i know
people who like take to it a lot
there are a few axes you can do this
along negotiating on pure rate is
effectively asking for a discount right
you're saying well instead of two
thousand dollars what if i pay you 1900.
there's not a ton of leverage there
scope is often easier to work with
vendors on
generally this is either taking down the
level of effort saying like can i pay
you for a few fewer days and we'll
accept there'll be some gaps or it's
trading depth for breath like we would
like to cover fewer services at the same
depth or i'm willing to say that like
let's do 80 of what you're saying
um
reporting also comes into play a lot of
vendors charge for reporting time the
more types of reports deliverables you
want the more expensive it gets you can
cut some of those depending on your
needs
and if you are a big enterprise paying
millions of dollars a year you can
probably expect the price to go down a
little bit
but you have to remember project
management triad for those that don't
know good fast cheap i think normally
it's pick two in security sometimes it's
like pick one um
if you're trying to be more flexible on
timeline you can save on cost and
quality by like cherry picking a vendor
that's willing to work with you
on the other hand if you're trying to
book in q4 like we talked about before
it's tenuous or expensive to get on
calendars and while there are certainly
varying prices uh if you're getting a
quote that is abnormally cheap be a
little skeptical please
and this is the same thing that we're
hearing about challenges from people in
the survey balancing quality price and
availability justifying spend or even
affording it all is really hard in
security services
and
like
vetting the proposals also takes a lot
of work because you're going to want to
think about
comparing multiple proposals like for
like is the quality similar is the level
of effort similar what are the
qualifications
ideally you're performing reference
checks on your vendors
if you are a large enough deal you can
request that the vendor put you in touch
with a client of theirs and they might
do it you also probably want to pump
your network for anyone who has an
existing relationship
a lot of people will tell you that the
consultant matters more than the firm
and this is true
but unless you're working with a really
boutique or solo shop
you're going to have a hard time
requesting specific consultants
so just to warn you a lot of time like
first-time assessment buyers really want
to review bios pick a specific
consultant someone they've seen at a
conference
for a variety of like valid and less
valid reasons big firms are going to
probably not play ball unless you are a
massive client in which case you can
often get a little more specific there
you can also review example reports see
if they have public-facing reports
really try and get an idea of the
quality of their work
and then do a bunch of paperwork so i
don't want to dive too much into these
but i will just say that there is a lot
of paperwork involved in security
assessments hopefully it is not your
problem but someone else at your
company's
nda's msas sows
you're going to see requirements around
insurance you're going to see liability
and
there's a lot of resources out there
cure53 is a consultancy that's made
their contracts public
secureworks has their msa there are a
lot of options here
for
cutting down on this
so
how do you prepare and deliver your
assessment right like you've picked a
vendor they're starting in two weeks
um a lot of logistics tips from the
surveys right it's gonna take more than
you expect you're gonna need technical
people on call you're going to want
clear lines of communication and you're
going to want to use business
initiatives to
potentially fund the pen test right like
these are small disconnected tips
here's how i break it down there's kind
of three horizons you're working on
internal alignment which means getting
authorization and buy-in from all the
right people that this assessment is
going to happen and they will be ready
to deal with the results
as well as in some cases blue team
collaboration if you are running a red
team assessment have a very clear plan
of how your blue team will become aware
of it if they need to
communication channels are important how
are you going to internally track
progress who's responsible for first
applying to vendor questions how are you
going to dispatch vulnerabilities
internally and what's your escalation
policy is there a level of risk where
you'll want it reported immediately and
what are you going to do if like a
critical comes in off this assessment
and then this is fairly uncommon but i
really advocate for people considering
sharing their known risks with vendors
if you're getting an assessment share
your previous reports share your threat
models share your risk assessments this
transparency is uncommon but lets them
hit the ground running and build on
prior art you've already done so you're
not starting from scratch each time and
that really speaks directly to your most
business critical risks
there's also technical preparation the
first one feels obvious but like think
about resolving anything outstanding
before commissioning an assessment if at
all possible the worst thing is when you
as a client buy an assessment and then
are paying them to tell you a bunch of
open findings you already know about
there's also a lot to do with the test
environment assuming you're testing in a
test environment setting up integrations
configuration feature flags roles
seating data some of these are more
common than others but when i was
working as a consultant the number of
times i walked into a company and they
gave me like
an empty b2b sas app with nothing set up
and i spent my first three to five days
just like typing in data entry um it's
fine as a consultant if that's where you
want to spend your day rates go for it
but really think about whether the
environment's sufficient for them to
express all your functionality same with
like network environments um is
everything actually like ready to be
tested configured in a prod similar way
you may need to change freeze if this is
a like production environment something
to think about
reporting vulnerabilities and then
having to like trace them through
various versions of applications to see
if they exist or not because of moving
environments is never fun
and consider disabling out of scope
controls this is sometimes controversial
with clients but if you have a waf if
you have ip allow listing if you have
risk-based authentication unless you are
intending to get an assessment to test
the efficacy of those controls
just turn them off
you probably don't want to pay a
consultant to test cloudflare like
cloudflare does that
so it's better for everyone to just like
let them focus on your actual scope and
your controls
and just to call out that like folks
forget about onboarding depending on the
size of your company this may involve
like putting a ticket in jira for
another team to manage it but there's
hardware there's software there's demos
and documentation you may need hr
paperwork legal paperwork you may need
to warn it if they're coming on site
there's all sorts of badging and
security
get this done early so that again you
are not paying your vendor to sit around
and wait for their stuff to get set up
and disappointing for some of you i'm
sure but i'm actually not going to talk
about the assessment at all there's a
lot of great resources out there on like
how to do a security assessment there
are a lot of kinds of assessment um i'm
focusing on the scaffolding around it so
you know voila your vendor comes in they
perform their assessment and you're on
to the readout off to the races
so
right the report is the key deliverable
for most security assessments um almost
everyone based on the survey like does a
pdf report and a presentation that's
what's involved
the report the thing to note about this
like breakdown is that reports are
designed to be decomposed like if you
receive a pdf report you can split it up
into sections and send those to
different audiences internally um
executive summary is named that because
you probably want to field it to like
higher level executives well finding
summaries
are really useful for your security
leadership to have a meta level and then
of course you can break out like
individual findings for line level
engineers and a fun fact for me which i
disagree with but there you go is that
according the survey clients prefer an
overall risk rating in their report so
if you are a vendor your clients would
like you to tell them if they're doing
like
you know
good bad or mediocre across the board in
your reports
and then like after the assessment
you're going to want to do a
retrospective
with the vendor this is where like in
the readout you can take advantage and
get additional value by asking where
they'd look next what they'd recommend
you do differently what trends they
observed systemic mitigations they might
recommend
areas that were well hardened get some
positive feedback
but especially like how do i compare to
other assessments you've done this year
or industry benchmarks or your
expectations
a massive benefit is that like
security services vendors are one of the
best ways for you to get aggregate data
across the industry on security program
health and performance
and please make sure your vendor cleans
up after themselves i'm just going to
point you to this excellent talk from
wesley mcgrew
which goes into all the various ways
that a security assessment can make your
environment more vulnerable not less
as a consultant more than once on a
security assessment i like stumbled upon
findings wrote them up reported it and
it turns out that my shell i picked up
or escalated access was just left behind
by a previous vendor in prod
never a good look
and this was fun task vendors is like
what happens if you have no findings
like i said earlier no findings does not
necessarily
read as all clients to a successful
engagement like they're paying you to
write up risks
so vendors do three kind of buckets of
things
they manage client expectations note
limitations communicate early and often
they might write up a really detailed
test plan um and try and like do quality
control sandy check the results
or they can also talk about like other
value add defense in depth additional
measures you're at a really high level
of maturity but let's talk about what's
bleeding edge
and then you have to ingest these
results um a couple tips use your
standard process retriage findings you
know your environment best
uh you want to do root cause analysis
and variant analysis and this is what
takes an assessment from like a one-time
point in time whack-a-mole on risks to
actually scaling your program um
determining root cause finding variance
block out some security team time to do
this after the assessment so that next
year you're not like getting a
cross-site scripting this year two more
next year three more the year after that
like build in some secure defaults
security assessments are generally like
an expensive way to find a single
vulnerability so you want to do
everything you can to scale that impact
and just to note on personal reporting
um
if you are a big enough client or many
vendors do this by default you can
request like a csv of findings and then
you can automate piping that into your
vulnerability tracking which can save
someone some data entry time
and when you're remediation planning
just a reminder you can always choose to
fix mitigator accept these risks in many
cases
these assessments will report things
that you're going to just accept not
everything needs to be fixed all the
time it's all about your business's risk
appetite
so speeding up a little here because i'm
down the last couple minutes uh
please remediate your vulnerabilities
job one fix vulnerabilities job two
minimize transactional nature
point-in-time assessment maximize your
overall value
if you have validation or re-testing as
part of the contract especially if
you're getting client-facing documents
make sure to follow through on that
and do a retrospective internally this
is where we're talking about like how do
you tell if you got a good assessment
same reason procurement is hard this is
hard to do you're going to want to look
at like report quality how they handled
false negatives and false positives
it's especially insidious but you can
use canary bugs if you have open risks
and they don't find them you really want
to have a conversation about like
were there
good reasons bad reasons what
methodologies were they using why did
these latent bugs not show up again in
the report
and think about vendor communication how
did you feel about price for value did
you feel prepared were you able to reach
them
uh did the readout answer any questions
and then you have to talk about testing
cadence right you're not just doing this
once
annual is a good starting point but
other teams do it quarterly or aligned
to development cycles
uh continuous testing is certainly
gaining momentum as this one quippy
person said
uh i'll give you a second because i
enjoyed that
and you're going to think about scope
and vendor for future assessments right
talk about breadth and depth did we
cover a wide enough scope did we get
deep enough what limitations were there
do we want to retarget the same surface
again to get more depth or a different
surface next time and vendor rotation is
divisive some people say you should
switch vendors some say you shouldn't
what i will say is that there is a
compromise use the same vendor use
different consultants at that vendor
pros of rotation is like cross vendor
comparison it works if you think firms
are fungible quality
cons
or pros of repetition vendors will
recommend this they probably have their
own motives but i will say it does give
you like improved continuous context
and then you want to scale your program
um the bigger you get the more you
optimize for product management uh the
more you want to standardize procurement
the more you want to decide when to
staff in-house for high value
and basically select a handful of
companies
to make contracting easy reduce like
one-off pen tests with different firms
it has high overhead and think about
return on investment
and with that i will leave up the fact
that most people don't uh i am at time
so i just want to say
think about how hard this is
structure things based on motivation and
use assessment to not kill bugs but to
kill bug classes
if you'd like to dive deeper into this
it's available on tl dr sec slides are
available as well and thank you all for
your time
[Applause]