good morning everyone
welcome to b-side san francisco in this
next presentation we have uh tom alcock
acting as moderator for the ciso panel
discussion
uh so without further ado uh take it
away tom thank you for many of the
hiring managers in my network
hiring and retaining security talent is
by far one of the most challenging parts
of their day job
on top of this niche skill set we find
ourselves one of the most competitive
markets we've seen in many years
and twins with the great resignation and
mass layoffs more recently it's becoming
more and increasingly challenging to
hire and retain top talent
i'm tom alcock and i'm one of the
partners at code red and we exist to
bridge the cyber security talent gap i
spent the last
12 years of my career helping companies
to build technical teams and the last
four years
working on security hires with a lot of
these companies at the table today
we've got an incredible panel um today
of season security executives and
leaders that i'll introduce in a second
um and we're going to explore hiring and
culture and how to kind of hire and
retain talent
uh before we get going is there any
hiring managers in the room
anyone's hide in the last six or twelve
months
yeah keep your hands up if you find it
relatively easy to hide during this
period
there's no hands up in the room
oh okay find it easy over there nice
we'll come back to you
we'll make sure we'll come back to you
yeah because they think i'm an expert
and i'm not so
good
well um these these folks around me who
are introducing in a second may have not
completed it but they've done a pretty
incredible job of hiring retaining and
scaling security teams
today we'll be exploring how
these folks have approached it and
approach talent attraction in general
and they'll be sharing some of the wins
challenges
that they'll face when building teams so
without further ado i would like to
welcome to the table jessica
caleb and furman if you'd like to kind
of start with you on the end fermin
introduce yourself where you're at right
now give it a little little intro to
yourself and then we'll kick off some
exciting questions of course
for me cerna i currently serve as cso
for a company called databricks i've
been in the job for the last six months
not
10 months
i feel like i replaced caleb at
databricks so before that i was the ceo
for citrix for a couple years and before
that uh i was at google for almost eight
years uh and in my last years i was uh
head of product security at google
very very excited to be here thank you
tom for inviting the invitation and you
know very very excited to be part of
this panel
thank you
um caleb sima i'm currently the chief
security officer at robin hood um prior
to that i was at databricks i helped
build the team there at databricks
and then prior to that capital one and
actually most of my career was more on
the entrepreneurial side so i've
actually been in this hiring operations
side of the game for not that long um
although it's been very very
entertaining
my name is jessica ferguson i'm the
chief information security officer at
docusign i've been at docusign for
about two years and three months now
started as the deputy ciso and then took
over and the cso roll in march um
i've been in
cyber security for way too long uh
mostly in a lot of tech companies so uh
a servicenow f5 networks alaska airlines
done a lot of hiring
great stuff well thank you for the
introductions um as this is a community
event i spent the last couple of weeks
playing on linkedin and twitter and
trying to get people from the community
to ask some questions i mean this is an
incredible panel that we're very
fortunate to have in front of us today
so
i've had
so many kind of questions thrown my way
which will kind of start um it's really
nice to see that the two keynote
speakers which by the way were
incredible both asla who maybe in the
room and jackie yesterday
a golden thread of their talks was
bridging the cyber security talent gap
and building culture of cyber security
and building a great culture within
these companies so i think we'll find
some interesting conversations today
coming from here so the first question
that i did have come through and and
thurman we'll start with you if you
wanna answer this one when the questions
came through what are the key factors
and considerations that you have when
you're looking to build a security team
from from scratch
that's a great question um i mean the
first thing that i
i look i mean let me tell you what i did
when i arrived at data rigs and this is
a story that some of you um i i'm
looking at travis that he knows his
story
the first thing is you do an assessment
what is what is the
what are the needs from the company what
is the the current tools you know uh
budget the engineers that you have and
and i usually do four things the first
one is what is your strategy in in the
security field it's like how are you
going to outpace the attackers right uh
the second thing that you do is like
what is your security organization that
is going to you know help uh fulfill the
strategy the third thing is like okay
what are the leaders and the that they
are going to help you to build that uh
that organization and finally you know
you building that organization from an
ic level and execution right so um
essentially is going back to
the the the company that you are in what
are the needs what are the tools and
bridge the gap between these two things
right and the first thing that you need
to do is like do i have the tools that i
that i need and if not you know i always
say this thing is like during my first
six months at databricks i was not a cso
i was a recruiter
essentially right it's like uh uh
sourcing you know convincing people
building culture for uh the existing
people assisting with people to
to to persist in the company through the
changes that we're going you know super
super important to to bridge the gap
between where you want to go where you
are always be recruiting always be
recruiting always be recruiting
you want to go come back
yeah i think that's been a goal of going
through our professional relationship is
you never you're never offline caleb
with with hiring same question to you
when you come into organizations i know
you've worked on startups and now large
enterprise customers like robin hood
how do you approach that how do you
approach it starting from security
hiring from scratch
so yeah this is a very complex question
um and i think really
there's a lot of context that has to be
taken into account i think going off of
what firm said like what stage of
company are you what type of business
are you when what's your threat model
what where is the existing team where
are the gaps in those teams what are the
leadership look like there's so much
context in terms of i think who you
choose to hire so what i'm going to do a
little bit of is i'm going to kind of
skip over some of the strategy of who
you choose because i think it can be
very very context
driven is maybe talk a little bit about
maybe how i hire because i think that
can be just generic across the board
um and so when i think about how i hire
you know i i do agree with from
especially when you walk in and you're
building a team you are
dedicated to recruiting you have to
understand i think you have to take this
context that people are number one
talent is number one
and you cannot do anything without
hiring that talent and so you have to
have that in your mindset you have to
have you have to inflict that into your
team and to the people around you that
people is number one and how do i hire
so that you start really focusing on
what is the hiring process what's the
recruiting process how do i choose
what things to deal with and let burn
versus
focusing on the people and the
interviewing
that's a really really tough part so i
think when i first came in that was one
of the big things is instill a culture
of
interviewing people and candidates being
number one what's the process how do i
make that as efficient as possible
and make sure that we do the right thing
and focus on hiring and how to hire
and i think that in doing that you have
to make this decision because i think
what the hardest part is
hey i've got 50 fires that i've got to
go deal with
or i go focus on hiring and at the end
of the day hiring is kind of treated as
this you know you know manage the corral
of herd of sheep coming in and people
and it's just a process right like it's
a process
when that's you have to look at this and
say like these fires
if i don't get the right people and look
at this not just being a process and
about herding cattle this is an
important critical piece of what we do
you get these people the faster you get
good quality talent in the faster these
fires go away so you have to say these
fires are going to burn for now and i'm
going to go focus on this stuff around
making sure that the hiring process is
just not considered a process it's
something you invest in it's something
you care about it's something that is
the core part and how do i instill that
into the teams and the culture of the
company i think is important yeah
great answer thank you
um jessica
to kind of dovetail into another
question that's come up is
building these teams yeah and moving
quickly and as caleb says kind of
choosing to kind of let fires burn
to sacrifice making these investments in
highers that can then eventually put out
the fires um
in such a competitive market right now
that we see ourselves in how can you how
do you get the edge over the com
other companies that are hiring for the
same skill set um and able to build a
team of top security talent
yeah i think that there's um there's a
couple different
things that that we have to look at and
you know on the on the tactical side i
think you know kind of echo with what uh
caleb furman said you know when you look
at your strategy
that kind of sets the
direction the north star of where you
want to go from a hiring perspective
but i think the yeah the first thing i
always look at is having very close
relationships with my hr business
partner folks because they are going to
help me with looking at things like
paybands and how is comp
benchmarked uh because in a lot of cases
comp is benchmarked against i.t
positions and we all know that security
positions cost more than i.t positions
and so so you can go and get all these
great candidates but then you're running
into roadblocks trying to get them all
on board it um so you know i definitely
think starting with looking at kind of
the fundamentals of what you have what
are the factors and metrics that you use
to determine headcount ratios for me
appsec ratio appsec engineer ratio to
developer right there's that's a metric
um trust we deal with a lot of business
customers that you know we have a whole
team called trust services that handles
all of our customer requests and we need
to benchmark how many sales people and
how many customers and to you know right
size and help understand how many people
we need to support the to support the
mission i think that um
in the overall um
you know hiring good uh
good talent um
you know
most of the people i i feel like the
really great talent that i've have have
i either been um
you know uh connections um from the past
or
having my uh my folks tap into their to
into their connections we found
a lot of some of my best hires have been
very kind of just random and then they
happen and it's like two weeks later
you're getting this person an offer and
they've been at
boeing for 25 years and they really
thought about leaving until you talked
with them right and so i would say
there's a definitely a lot of kind of
uh having to sort of mine through the uh
the large um
you know the very large looking
uh or maybe the scary dearth of of
candidates and then you know being able
to find out find those kind of those
diamond of the rough folks that you can
kind of pull up we also do a lot of uh
internal you know recruiting right so
some of my best abstract people are
former qa folks some of my best you know
uh
you know folks in my security
engineering team came from you know and
services support and you know so looking
for the looking at those folks and then
those you know places who
you know maybe kind of uh you know have
kind of a security mindset that you can
pull into uh into um security roles you
know and i think
i think the one thing that sets security
folks apart is
and the one thing you have to look for
whether you're recruiting outsider or or
internally
is you know
i always kind of say i can teach anybody
security i cannot teach you an innate
level of curiosity that says what's next
what's next what's next right and it's
kind of that constant question asking
that security professionals do all the
time right
um
you know i can i can take anybody who
has that and i can teach them security
that's not the hard part the hard part
the harder part in a lot of cases that i
find is is really finding the folks who
have that kind of innate sense of
curiosity that innate sense of kind of
okay you've given me an answer but i
want to know the answer behind the
answer and then the answer behind the
answer right which is what you know from
a security perspective we do all the
time whether it's threat modeling or
third-party risk assessment or whatever
but i think there's you know uh there
there's a definitely a couple different
a lot of different factors and areas to
look at when it comes to to pulling
talent into your team
thank you jessica i think another
question that has come in that we'll
answer in a moment is the transition
like people are that are not in security
like kind of what is the pathway to move
into that so we will address that i
guess throw it
to both of you kind of
i've seen you both scale large teams in
the last 12 18 months
what's your secret source what's kind of
how have you been in this kind of
competitive market recently of course
i'm not going to tell you
and then you will know right so now my
point is um going back to the challenges
let's assume that all these you know
combines and all these processes they
are they are good which uh
the norm is that there is work to be
done then what is hiring right it's like
there is a lot of work that uh
goes back to us right it's like you may
have an amazing talent acquisition team
but you know um
in my experience over the last probably
three four years
around sixty seventy percent of the
sourcing
is internal sourcing right and it's done
by us right these references that we
know people from the past or friends or
friends or campaigns that we do
internally right so
hiring the challenges is to to
differentiate yourself from caleb from
jessica from others right because at the
end of the day you know they are i mean
they are csos and css for amazing
companies and you need to make sure that
the candidate understands why we are
better than others or why we are uh
different than others let's say this way
right and and one thing that i do is
like i uh at the end of the process
whenever we do an offer um and this is
well i'll disclose a secret i do
something that i called a champion call
right
and i talked to the candidates and i
explained them hey now you have an offer
and you also have an offer from google
you have an offer from robinhood you
have an offer from all these places and
i told them amazing companies right but
let me tell you why databricks is better
from my opinion let me tell you why um
the culture that we're trying to build
here the challenge of the company right
uh uh where we're going and all these
things let me give you enough
information
for you to make an informed decision
right those champion calls they are
amazing right
i uh i'll give i'll give all my secrets
out so
i
need a notebook it's it's so here's the
thing is i actually find i do a little
bit the opposite um you know what i tend
to find is like
by and large most interviews are
the company vetting the candidate it's
basically like hey prove to us that
you're good enough to work here and then
we'll sell you
right so i just reversed it so i just
said okay it doesn't matter who you are
what we're going to do is i call this
the reverse interview
and many of you who work maybe at robin
hood have probably been been through
this with me is the first call and this
is what i mean by dedication and time so
you understand the level at least when
building the team that you have to
commit
in the first calls i will sit for 30
minutes and i'll basically say you can
ask me the questions
you can interview me if i can sell you
on me the company the culture the people
at the beginning
because it's to me it's like let me
prove to you why we're good enough for
you to come work for us
then they get hooked and when they're
hooked
they're more excited to go through the
process
and so then it's not at the end where
you do the battle you just do it right
at the beginning and by the way
i've had candidates
at the beginning we'll go through that
at the beginning the candidate will say
hey i don't think this is probably the
right fit
and i'd be like that's awesome and we
figured it out right right there at the
beginning
and i found like that to be one of the
most amazing things is when people go
through that process
you know the
the culture of us is basically saying
how can we tell you that robin hood is a
great company to work out how can i tell
you that i'm a good leader or person to
work with
and as soon as that is good i think that
opens up the floodgates of the candidate
going through and asking the questions
and that's helped a lot and by the way i
you know at the beginning when you're
building a team i don't care if you're a
junior i don't care if you're an intern
i don't care if you're senior i will do
those calls with you
obviously as the comp as the team scales
as the company scales it becomes a lot
harder for me to do those things but i
always offer
in across the board one you gotta tell
your managers and your leaders can you
convey that same culture to them
and two i also offer hey if you have
candidates that you consider sort of p0
like you know they're coming in this is
a the you you definitely like i'll go
and do it like i'll come in and say
right at the beginning in the first call
reverse interview what can i answer for
you and so that's a it's a big secret um
so
for those of you
uh
really working hard over there but it's
i think it's helped a lot and it helps
establish a lot of uh trust i think with
the candidates um one thing i want to
mention is like um we're talking about
the edges of the process yeah it is key
the the the interview i mean even in the
middle right uh
the candidate through the through the
the panels through talking to people
either interviewing one way or the other
ways because remember whenever you
interview for a company it's two ways to
interview right is to give them a an
amazing experience that's that's uh they
are literally going to have four or five
hours
with with the company uh they you need
to sell them and they need to not only
to sell them
sell certain the reality of how it's
going to be them to be working over
there right it's not only on the edges
it's through the interview
everyone through the panel the the
interview uh
the interviewers you know to to to be
able to explain how it's going to be why
uh working for this company is is a good
thing what are the challenges what is
the company where is the company going
right and these touches of caleb doing
at the beginning or myself doing it at
the end is what what's what help but
this through the interview process
i can tell you from firsthand
experiences that actually from the
recruitment process
having that
kind of level of involvement in
investment and communication is is such
a golden thread of of how you've been
successful in hiring it it adds so much
difference and is a big differentiating
factor against a lot of other companies
out there for sure one other thing i
just want to put like a double plus one
on is the firm is thinking about
transparency
right when you go through the interview
process
um i think it's so key
you know i've heard from others where
um people will candidates will go
through an interview process and the
in the company will just sell how great
they are what awesome things that they
do um and then when you walk in the door
you're surprised at the
the the
disaster that you've kind of walked into
uh which by the way you all know this
every company is a disaster behind the
scenes so like we all know this
um and so but i think being up front
about it is really really key and what
he was pointing is like talk about the
challenges talk about the the disaster
that it is because that's the thing i
think candidates really like because
that shows hey those are things i can
have impact on right like i've done you
know sdlc before and if you're telling
me your sdlc is super immature and
really early you need a lot of help like
wow that means i can come in and really
add the value that i've learned in my
past and so i found you know again that
transparency thing is really key yeah
you know if you don't do it
in six months that person is going to be
gone and you're back into you know the
first stage so you you lost you
essentially waste time for the candidate
and yourself
that's a great point right i mean i
think most folks you know when they're
looking at you know uh leaving a company
they're looking for a challenge right
most people want a challenge they want a
vision of
where
where is
where is this company going where's this
organization going you know
what am i getting myself into and i
think that um
you know being able to kind of sell the
here's the challenge and here's where
you have opportunity to make impact
because
sell the disaster
and have an impact right like i think
it's just a fundamental human part of
human nature is you want to be able to
make a change so make a difference
nice you talk about kind of um
trust and transparency i think we're
talking about kind of hiring and how we
get people through the door i think a
nice little segue
is around kind of retention right now i
think there's a lot of companies that
kind of the term
great resignation gets overused but has
been a thing i've seen a lot of people
move and and kind of a lot of churn from
a lot of companies so
what what do you do to build trust
collaboration transparency
in a remote workforce like this this is
such an amazing time to have so many
people in a room right now but it's rare
it's it's rare that we have this kind of
face time so
how do you get how do you build trust
and collaboration in a remote workforce
um
the first thing i do is i block code red
from the email system so you cannot talk
to my people
at the end of the day i mean same as you
are attracting candidates to increase
your security team the size of the
security team you need to make sure that
you spend equal or more time
building
you know the the qualities of an amazing
team right
that we operate as a team or
psychological safety or where we we got
each other's back and things that you
need to build a culture where people say
you know what you know i could go
shop around interview and things like
that but why should i i'm happy here i
am challenged and doing the amazing
things that i i uh that i'm doing right
now that they are up to my expectations
why should i risk this right so it's
super super important to build that uh
to spend that time to build those
qualities inside the team
and of course blocky
[Music]
we'll talk after okay
i think there's there's a couple um
thoughts um
so
i think that the pandemic did some great
things which is it allowed everybody to
work remote which means now we started
hiring remotely in a company like
docusign where we used to hire everybody
in san francisco and seattle now i've
got a third of my team is probably
remote all over the united states right
which is you know fantastic because we
changed a lot of culture around how the
company thought about things um that you
know the downside is is now you know how
do you operate in that in that world um
you know i would say that the the
biggest thing that i learned is over
communicate if you think you're
communicating enough with people you're
not communicating enough with the people
i'm going to tell you right now because
now all you have all these remote folks
and they all feel
remote and alone right
and so it's really hard for them to feel
connected to a building i'll be i'll be
really honest i started at docusign
april 2020
post everything shutting down
i didn't come into an office until i
think
april of this year and you know when you
go in you're like oh hey there's walls
in a building and i feel physically tan
i feel tangibly connected to this thing
and these people right and that's that's
really hard when you have somebody who
is remote and it's really easy for them
to feel
like they're just doing the job and
disconnect it from the broader group so
i would say you know over communicate
you know that if that means that's where
i spend i would say so much of my time
uh monthly amas one-on-ones with
everybody i have 110 people on my team i
still try to do one-on-ones with
everybody at least you know
one supporter it's it's tough but we we
get through it usually you do well to be
hit today then right
right now with 100.
you know forums like we've we've had to
like get creative around how do we get
these different groups inside of you
know the work just to communicate
together right and that's been another
thing is like
again there's all those those uh
stop by the desk conversations that
don't happen in a remote workforce and
so people feel like they struggle with
understanding what's happening you know
what's happening across the organization
who's doing what you know kind of that
natural conversation kind of things that
would normally happen don't get it
happen so you really have to be
very intentional about how you
make that happen and you know i think as
you know the leader of the organization
our respective organizations is up to us
to make that happen right because
otherwise it's it you know it will
happen organically at a maybe a group
level but at an org level it it'll
struggle sometimes
yeah i really don't have a good answer
for this that's why i'm learning from
these two i'll add these two so i can
learn
[Music]
i would just say this i think that what
i've noticed if i were to think about an
overall
challenge with remote work is it seems
to me that
remote work there's there's like
is really lends itself well for
in-depth tunnel focus sort of vision and
working hard through deep problems right
like real work
as long as you're not on slack um
and then the
but what really suffers is decision
making fast decision making i think
suffers
um and so
it's difficult to figure out well how do
you really make up the fast decision
making
[Music]
problem
working remotely and i'll be very blunt
i don't know
of a great answer to that
i think there's lots of different
thoughts from you know daily stand-ups
to
you know having a strategy meeting
everyone comes in the office once a day
or once a week you know what are these
whatever these things are but um i don't
know i would love if people have good
thoughts on that that would be great to
hear i think elon musk uh has recently
made a decision on how that works maybe
don't take advice from that one
um it's a good opportunity i mean i'm
for hiring it's a great opportunity
no i mean think about this i'm pretty
sure some some people are going to be
happy because they want to go to the
office some people they don't want
they feel like okay maybe one or two
days some people is like no i don't want
to go to the office right so you know
he's made the call well one thing to
respect is he made the call yeah exactly
if you don't like it go if you do you're
in and i mean it's
you got to respect the stance he made
the call and he's owning it like he is
he is present and he is there in the
factories every day so yeah
cool
the last couple of well yesterday i had
a lot of people come to to our booth and
we talked about this panel today and not
to inflate all of your egos
but you are very seasoned leaders um a
common question that's come through is
we fake it well
yeah but you're
you're at prestigious companies then
you've done great work with hiring
talent but a common question that's come
through that knowing that i had this
panel today was
i'm a new security hiring manager or i'm
a startup owner or i'm just being pushed
into a kind of a leadership opportunity
i want to scale a team i know that this
is thinking back many moons from when
you're kind of just building a team out
what advice would you give to somebody
that is starting kind of their
management career and needs to hire
okay why am i always the first one
um so i would say for for
someone who is uh uh
moving into management or building a
group hiring a team whatever that is um
uh congratulations and welcome to the
hardest job you will ever do i'm just
gonna say this like i i think that you
know we talk about resignations and
people leaving and you know
it hurts right like i hear people give
resonations and i'm just like oh my gosh
like another one right and so you know
you you you feel that you kind of feel
very connected to your people hopefully
and hopefully you know you you build
that investment so when people do leave
it's it's tough um i would say that um
you know
the
from uh
the first thing that
you'll want to understand kind of moving
into a new
into a new manager role is
it really is about
building that investment and that
mindshare with
um with your team and with the members
of the team that you're bringing on
board
um i think that you know there's there's
a saying that you know and i don't know
how true it is today but there's a
saying that you know
people you know uh
what's the saying something about people
don't leave great managers they leave
they leave bad companies um and i think
that you know there's uh
there there is a big piece and and it
gets understated where you know
a great manager can hold a team together
right even through a lot of uh adversity
as a company and i think that um
you know building that mind share and
building that relationship with your
folks and
is going to be
you know job number one and i've i'll be
honest um i've learned from so many
people who have been
uh peers of mine on you know how to
uh build team cohesion how to uh
lift your team up um you know
and really kind of make uh you know the
folks on your team sort of the front and
you know i support them from behind i
think the other thing is
you know make sure that you are being
intentional about building diverse teams
and i know you know we we talk about it
all the time but you know it we still
haven't done enough and i'm going to be
raise a hand docusign hasn't done enough
to build diverse teams
um you know who are your who who are in
your
who's in your interview panels is it all
white guys because if a black woman
walks in the room there's
gonna be really tough if any kind of
underrepresented minority rocks in the
room it's gonna be tough it's gonna be
very intimidating right going or it's
going to give a real insight into the
culture of the company right it's all
very
monochrome
you know i think that you know
hiring
diverse candidates you know building
diverse teams bringing in different um
points of view
you know
be flexible with who you hire like like
i said before like there are
people that you will identify in other
groups in your company and you will say
and i've done this before and it's
actually one of the biggest things
that's brought me joy is i will take you
know somebody who is in desktop support
and they're they're like hey i'm
interested in the cyber security thing
like what should i do and i'm like yeah
come on come over here right
and building them up and now they're
architects at ebay and stuff like that
right and you kind of get to see them
you know kind of grow up and move and i
think that um
you know finding that that diamond and
the rough talent and and and being like
yes you i want you on my team right and
in making that sense of inclusion
you know they don't need to be you know
the whiz-bang hacker right um some of
the best folks on my team were
you know
in the video editing business right like
they had nothing to do with with cyber
security or even with technology in
general but you know now they're like
kind of some of the leads of some of our
biggest projects so i think that um it
really is
key to look outside of kind of just the
normal box of where you would look to
hire from
so i'm sorry long answer
that was
a great great answer
in fact there's not much i think i can
follow on to that because i think these
are all phenomenal points around
just learning how to be a manager and a
leader and what are some great so i'm
going to be a little bit more tactical
on mine and i'll be very security
focused since i think you really covered
a lot
um i'll say when i think when you're
thinking about building your team
um
you know first if you're a first time
leader and manager building a team this
probably means you're working at a small
company would be my guess and you're
starting from scratch so i would
recommend two things in when you're
looking for your first team to hire
which is going to be really important
whoever those first people are that you
hire are going to help set your culture
of your team
first i would probably focus on good
general athletes
the and second they need to have the
attitude to sort of a point made earlier
around curiosity um hard work good
general athletes when you're small and
you're starting a team it's not like oh
i need someone really good at dnr oh i
need someone really good at pen tests oh
i need someone really good at appsec
you need people who have some good
diverse experience and just want to dive
into they just they're curious they just
want to learn and they want to dive so
when you think about hiring
those the first sort of three or four
people around you
really look at some good general
athletes and how they're going to help
you um and also you always need one
person that's going to that's going to
help tie all the
people policy programs compliance you
need one of those
in your teams to help tie everything
together too um i would say those would
be the the tactical things i might say
when you're a first-time manager
okay um yeah i don't know what i can say
after this
at least next time
i will try it right so you're you're a
new manager right so on top of all the
new things that you need to do you need
to build
feature x or you need to mitigate
whatever it is right so there's a lot of
pressure right and then
you you need to build a team and you
need maybe you have two or three people
four people you need to retain those
people right on top of that you need to
you know increase the team size to
deliver you know the final thing that
you work hard for right so there's a lot
of pressure right so the the best advice
that uh
i can give you to a new uh manager is
like don't be a hero you are not alone
right so start talking to others start
leveraging uh you know the knowledge and
expertise from other people get a mentor
uh talk to
andreas there's actually uh maybe not
even in your company there's a people in
the industry that uh they do the hey i'm
the cso for well i'm going to quote uh
someone that i know nico weisman cecil
for left he does
uh sessions uh with uh you know uh folks
from the industry that they want to be a
new sis or they want to do these things
right so kudos to nico by the way um
what i'm trying to say is that you have
your job to to do you have a job to
retain the people the good people that
you have so you need to invest in you
know the good qualities that i was
talking about and then you need to hire
right and don't be a hero there is
multiple things and you will make
mistakes
it's totally expected i mean i made a
ton of mistakes i i probably should not
mention them because this is being
recorded
but uh you know it's okay to make
mistakes because by making mistakes you
learn
for the next one you're going to do
better you're going to retain your your
team better you're going to hire people
better right and other things that uh
that jessica and keleb mentioned is like
you know the the
i mean hiring only security
professionals with security experience
that's one way
hiring people new grads i'm
building them as a security professional
that's another one
you know
going to other fields you know a
developer that is an amazing developer
and
helping them grow into a security
professional that's another one right
it's it's there is no silver bullet it's
like put your uh put your bets in
different things right and and and that
way you will be able to you know
accomplish with mistakes you know hiring
retaining and doing your job right but
don't be a hero i i mean i
i don't know that you're you're worried
about going last but that don't be a
hero and use other guys iconic yeah that
was amazing
that'll be the only quote of this uh
whole cso panel
because i just want to just re-emphasize
this like
when you're small you're you're so right
for me like working with engineering and
the rest of the company getting their
help
is part of the job as a cso too right
and getting that culture and getting
them to help and
uh doing that that's like that's super
critical you know
nice thank you folks
um i had a question come through from uh
twitter the last couple of days and it's
kind of related to recruiting but it's
um and maybe we'll start with you
further okay
you guys battle between yourselves uh
with all the economic uncertainty we're
seeing right now especially in the tech
space um companies making layoffs um and
cuts generally how do you
plan to make security a priority your
company
i mean it depends on the context of the
company right so
um in in the context of data breaks
right because of the product that we
sell right to some degree we we deals
with other secret sauce right so
security is a priority for the company
right at the end of the day under any
financial situation right you you are
going to take a look to what are my
priorities uh
you know marketing or uh
sales or engineering but
for us security is a key pillar because
without security um there is no gtm uh
focus here right so
obviously i mean there
i mean we will see this and we i don't
have a crystal ball to see if we're
going to go into a recession or not and
things like that companies are adjusting
right for me
it's not a challenge it's an opportunity
right because uh if companies are
adjusting it's like hey uh
let me take a look why uh i mean let me
go into linkedin and search for all
those tesla security engineers that may
not want to go back to the office right
because there could be good people over
there right so again
take advantage of your strengths as
exploit the weaknesses of others
i'm going to be a little spicy on this
one
my thoughts are are don't try to make
security the top priority in the company
i don't think
oh well i got one fan on that spicy
condom
[Music]
isn't that your boss over there
yeah
um
yeah i would say you know when you think
about like that it doesn't matter what
business you're in security is never
going to be the top priority even if
you're a security vendor uh it's not the
top priority um what i would focus on
instead is there are spots or areas in
your company that you can make security
in the top three right or at least in
the top five
um and so the way like i think about it
i'll be very sort of generic is like you
ever heard of sort of like the intel
architecture ring zero ring one like
there's like in ring zero this is your
top critical super paranoia ring one a
little bit less ring two ring three you
know you can look there are across an
organization they're gonna be different
levels of where security really needs to
be priority versus where it doesn't
or where you can be a little more
relaxed and i think you need to find the
areas that are the most critical for you
to have either ring zero or ring one
focus on those areas and help the team
do it and ultimately if you really do
the job really well security does become
a little bit more built in and becomes
more invisible to the business and what
it does
but i think those are the key areas i
would focus on hey this team in this
specific area what they're doing is
super sensitive and super uh super like
we got to focus on that help go to them
and figure out how to embed security
into their processes and make that a
priority with that team and you can make
a lot of progress that way
okay so
yeah i think that um you know from a
from a
from a docusign perspective you know we
uh we consider ourselves a trust brand
we use that terminology all the time
it's all over the place right um we hold
everybody's data right we hold
everybody's mortgage documents and loan
signings and i'm sure everybody's
documented something once
it'd be an interesting study on who
hasn't but anyway um you know but all
that data yeah lives in our cloud right
and so
um
you know from our perspective uh you
know
we're going to continue to build and
grow our team that's that's not really a
concern from my perspective you know i
think that um
you know and we'll take advantage of
everybody who's laying off and we'll
pull all those people over because it's
good talent
i think there's a huge opportunity yeah
i agree entirely i think that you can
spin out his head and say we're able to
reach out to talent and attract talent
that we weren't able to do so 12 18
months ago yeah but tom i mean that's if
if you have the
if you have the opportunity to keep
growing right because there is companies
that they will not because you know
security you know as i agree with caleb
right it's like may not be their
priority one of their top priorities
right so then what do you do you focus
on retaining your people right you you
going instead of going out out there is
that you try to protect your your your
crown you also essentially or or if you
think about it if security is not your
top priority right which listen at the
end of the day every business like will
always say hey security is important but
it's never the top well why well because
the top business the top party is being
a business
right we all know this like we have to
be a business otherwise we security
doesn't matter because we won't exist we
need to make and that is really
ultimately the most secure to be blind
um but here's the thing is like we know
this then our job is not to go and fight
for the top spot and also i feel like as
our job as an expectation as being in
this industry is we're not going to be
the top priority so how do we make
changes and impact in order knowing that
and knowing it in a way that enables the
teams
sets the right context around what
they're doing allows them to say hey
it's not just hey do this to be secure
but hey if you do this it's an easier
route of what you're doing today and it
also happens to be secure right this is
a much better model and allows you to
align with the business allows you to
make more more progress with the with
engineer and the rest of the
cross-functional partners and you're not
like i should we should set that
expectation like hey
as although it's great when the ceo
stands up and says hey security is
important privacy is important right
like for example at robin hood we have a
safety first right that's right in our
principles it's great when you hear that
happen but like let's set the
expectations hey at the end of the day
it's awesome to hear it but when it
comes to execution let's not expect it
and let's not rely on it right we can't
rely on someone at the top saying it's
important for us to adopt what we're
doing we've got to assume that they're
not and that we're not the top priority
so then how does that change our
thinking
yeah it's um i'm sorry to hijack this a
little bit but it's a it's a question of
being more efficient right at the end of
the day
i'm pretty sure that all of you have a
long laundry list of things that they
are wrong in in your own companies right
um and if you go one by one it probably
will take ten years to do all of that
right so
what are the top three top four top five
that
if you have resources not infinite ones
or maybe less than what you have right
now because there may be a recession or
whatever right
what are those ones that they are going
to be giving you the most bank for the
back right so completely agree with you
caleb
great stuff well i think we've got time
for one last question something that you
actually kind of indirectly addressed
earlier but it's a dying question i've
had about from three four different
people
what skill sets do you think can be
learnt on the job for security folks
i guess what skill sets can't
um you know i i
think i'm gonna repeat myself a little
bit but you know there is
if i look at what makes you know some of
the best security folks on my team it's
not the background that they have it's
not
the
you know
experience that they have although that
helps right but i think fundamentally it
is right in and whether it's incident
response threat models
engineering i'm sitting down with the
development team talking about a new
feature
it's always asking the
okay that's great and what else and what
else and what else right it's that
curiosity of getting to and sort of
extracting and pulling apart everything
and figuring you know and being able to
understand
the inputs and outputs and and the
of a thing right and and how it works
and what are all the things that a
development team is not telling you
about that or the really really
interesting parts when you start asking
questions and it's like
yeah uh and and so
again i think that is
that kind of that curiosity then and
that innate um
you know
uh
sort of follow-up is is the thing that
you can't teach you know i i can bring
folks in from
community colleges and put them into a
sock and teach them to be a sock analyst
and then move them into ir i can put
developers who do qa right work into
apps teams i can pull you know folks who
have done you know
desktop support and put them in
engineering teams right so there's a lot
of transferable skills right pretty much
anything that any group in a development
slash i.t
even legal and you know um
finance organization was done has some
translation
capability you know uh into uh into a
security function whether it's you know
audit risk you know appsec secops right
in any of those functions so yeah i
think that uh it's it's really more
about
so i would say
if you're thinking about going into
security and you're hung up on the
oh i don't know enough to go into
security i'm going to tell you right now
you
probably
there's an opportunity for you there
somewhere i'm just saying like there is
a security manager that's looking to
hire you i promise um
so you know i would i would definitely
not be hung up on the well i don't know
so i can't do this right and
and and really look at the
what do you know and what is the skill
set that you do bring and then you know
a good manager
can probably map most skill sets into
into what they need
and
form that person
multi person
i can do next so
i'm going to differ a little bit into
this one although i agree but i think
there are other type of skills that uh
you can learn on the job right um i mean
apart from the technical skills i mean
if you're on ir you know you will learn
how to do forensics how to manage an
investigation but at the end of the day
security teams usually
um
we we interact with others so others do
the the changes to mitigate risk and
things like that right so
the things that i uh think they are
super super important are the soft
skills how uh how you talk to others how
you write an email
i mean literally the way that you could
write an email you could you could win
someone
or you could lose them forever right and
and then if uh the way that you build
the bridge they will the way that you
it's totally different for example
whenever you send an email to someone
asking for hey sorry i'm going to run
your friday but can you do this
if you have had a coffee or a beer with
that person before it's way way easier
right so those soft skills how to build
those bridges how do you you talk to a
new person how do you understand their
their world how do you uh try to you
know to be a partner on their world
while they win them over to be a partner
in your world right so soft skills those
are the things that and and they can be
used not only in security in other other
fields super super important right
technical
skills yeah you will keep growing
but people
usually forget about the other ones and
they are probably as important as the
technical ones
yeah um i will say i agree with all of
these um i actually
will just add a nice to have
um
i don't think this is even an
essence necessary i think it's just a
little bit of passion for the field
um
you know like we're here on a sunday um
you know
some people people who are in security
sometimes stick in security just because
they love it it's just a great thing to
be in you love the
the
the like this is a weird thing i must
say but like when i read about the new
like if i see a new exploit that's been
released that's like
pretty innovative
it kind of is exciting i'm impressed i'm
like wow kudos like this is like a good
one um like you know it's just it always
impresses me the way attackers work and
the way this field works and it's just
something that i'll always be in and
you know this isn't nice to have i don't
believe this isn't necessary but if you
can find people that really just love it
for what it is it's it's a great thing
yeah flirtation you know you know i'm
sorry to hijack the meeting again
one thing that i
um
as a tldr of what i was mentioning to
some degree to what you were mentioning
uh caleb don't be a jerk that's
something
that's something very valuable to learn
right it's like you know if you're
object to someone that will come back
later right it doesn't cost you anything
to be nice right if you say please with
a smile and and then whenever they do it
say thank you you know you're going to
win a lot of people over
hold on now thank you
sincerely you're welcome caleb talked
about giving time upon a sunday like
it's i feel honored to have shared this
stage with firm and caleb and jessica
some both um foam and jessica actually
flew in today just for this talk keller
walked a couple of blocks so thank you
but sincerely can we raise a round of
applause for these incredible seasons
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you all so much for the discussion
and presentation here at b-side san
francisco on behalf of the conference
and uh our speaker gift sponsor maltego
we have gifts of appreciation and so
just want to thank you again
[Applause]
you