hello everybody oh that is well loud
hello everybody Welcome to security
besides San Francisco 2022.
[Applause]
so very excited to have everybody in
person yet again it's been a crazy last
two years
um but so excited to be back in person
hope you've grabbed some breakfast and
we have uh really great coffee stations
this year so definitely take advantage
of those and be ready for a full day of
events
our theme for this year is from the
ground up we chose this theme on the
tail end of our 2020 event
um just because we were you know we saw
the stuff was happening and was like
okay we're probably going to have to you
know going through a big change and
think about like okay we're going to
have to to reset we're going to have to
start from scratch on a lot of things
um and so uh you know we picked a theme
that focuses on return to the basics
um specifically the security besides
core tenants of community collaboration
and education after foregoing our
standard in-person event last year with
a you know limited virtual one we
decided that we thought this theme of
from the ground up would be more
appropriate than ever
so the the event is and will always be
centered on the community and we're so
very excited to bring this community
back together after being apart for the
last two years
so this year is a one of rebuilding for
us and we ask for your patience uh as
things may not go as smoothly this year
as you would expect we actually had a
fire alarm go off this morning as well
so we actually had to to leave the
building
um so again we're all 100 volunteer team
that are managing this um they've been
working tirelessly for really the last
two years to put this event on uh we've
had multiple changes in dates policies
mandates to deal with
um so just please be patient with us
especially this uh this event
um there's about 25 staffers that work
year-round on this to make it happen and
then we have special some special teams
including our call for papers our Review
Committee our couch the flag team that
puts in so many hours and over 175
volunteers who are Manning the event
this weekend
so there are
three floors on different spaces so make
sure to walk around and explore there's
a lot of stuff on our schedule this year
I want to call out special attention to
the chair massages in the lobby so if
you have an opportunity to Avail
yourself please do I hope I do it'd be
nice
um but yeah make sure that there's a ton
of cool stuff going on so make sure you
check out both uh here in City View and
also in AMC as well
so as I said lots of opportunities for
conversation today you can check the
full schedule on sched.com or on hacker
tracker for the first time ever we're
holding our event during the San
Francisco summer so to take advantage of
this we've expanded our use of the
outdoor patio I hope you've been able to
go out there and check it out we have an
outdoor lounge space which is really
cool and there's a couple of games and
such there too so again you know
hopefully to fill it with participants
that are having a conversation on the
next big thing stick around tonight
where we transfer in this transform the
space into a quintessential summertime
party I'm complete with a variety of
yard games all lit by string lights
again I want to call out a few things
here the CTF is going on over here so
please you don't have to be an expert at
doing Capture the Flag you can go and
participate they have puzzles at all
levels speed mentoring is something new
this year so down in the AMC Lounge is
the speed mentoring you do need to sign
up via slack on the BSI SF slack in this
speed mentoring Channel there's a little
bot there that you can talk to
um we have lunch from 12 to 1 30 in the
participant Hall and on the patio and
they're in the tent participant home
make sure you go check it out it's where
all the villages and the sponsors uh and
everything else is there
um happy hour today from 5 30 to 6 30
and the party tonight is 6 30 to 9 30 in
Embarcadero on the patio also just a
reminder that the outdoor patio is
non-smoking only and take the please
take the elevators down if you need to
smoke and that includes vaping as well
so for for Q a during all of our talks
we're using slido again
um you can use the hash code
besides SF 2022 I just picked the track
for your talk and then ask your
questions
but we want to know if this is uh if
we've created that atmosphere for
conversation we want to know your
feedback so please provide feedback
either uh generally at bssf.org feedback
or if you have session specific feedback
you can go on sked
um and there's a little thing at the
very bottom where you can provide
feedback on the session itself
so we need help
um it's been really tough on everybody
uh including the organization organizer
team and we've had several of our staff
who have actually just flat out left the
sfb area as I know many of your friends
probably have as well and colleagues as
a result of the new normal and several
others have decided that you know after
many years of doing this that it's time
for them to move on as well so we need
some fresh perspectives to keep besides
SF going
if that you think that it could be you
please let us know uh express your
interest at bssf slash be sensitive.org
jobs and we'll be in touch post the
event
so we have a code of conduct we have a
couple of signs in the front this was
sent to you also in in your email and on
the registration page but it's pretty
simple it's show respect and tolerance
for each other's uniqueness be kind and
practice the Golden Rule simply put do
not be an ass or we'll throw your ass
out so uh no tolerance for physical
verbal sexual harassment intimidation or
marginalization of any human
if you have any issues please feel free
to find anybody on a radio or any of our
safety Ops members and we'll be happy to
help you out the for the full code of
conduct it's on science it's also in
your program as well
so I know a lot of people right now are
thinking about covid as well I mean it's
been on our minds for the past two years
uh so
um in fact many cases we were probably
the last in-person conference that maybe
some of you went to
um and before all the lockdowns in
sheltered in place and so uh we are as
you know we're requiring vaccinations
and masks please wear your mask if you
are not actively eating or drinking or
you're a presenter giving a talk you
only need to do it inside you feel free
to take your mask off when you're
outside but while inside again unless
you're actively eating or drinking or
you are a presenter giving your talk
please have your mask on just makes
things better for everybody case counts
have been going up and we're trying to
make this as safe as possible for
everybody
um if you feel sick please go home
simple as that you know if you if you're
not feeling good just go home we record
all the talks so except for the off the
Record ones um so they will be on you
our YouTube channel within the next few
weeks
um so hopefully you won't miss too much
if you need to go home but again we just
asked that hey if you're not feeling
well go home
uh tons of hand sanitizer around the
venue but as always go to the bathrooms
and wash your hands use real soap thanks
um so video and photo policies
um General our policy is that you just
need permission of everybody in the shot
if you're taking a picture please make
sure that you have permission of
everybody in the frame
um so uh and if you take a photo or
video without permission
um just delete it if you're asked by
somebody to delete it or blur your their
photo or something like that please
respect them the only exception to this
is that we do have an official
photographer and I've totally lost her
where she is but she is
um there there she is she is the only
one that will be taking photos on her
behalf and so um but if for some reason
you prefer not to be in a photo just let
her know she's great
um and she'll be happy to do that
I just want to talk about kind of our
merchandise sales this year so
um you know one of our big things is
that we do uh Pro net proceeds from our
merchandise sales we give to three
Charities and you get to pick the
charity so our three Charities this year
are codepath.org eff and women in
security and privacy so when you uh are
either picking up your pre-order
merchandise or buying new merchandise at
code check you'll be given a token you
can put in the box of your choice and
we'll announce at the end of tomorrow
night in the closing ceremony how much
we're donating to each one but that's on
you you could say it's one great way
that we can give back to some really
great Charities so please take advantage
of that
but last night we at last but not least
this event would not be possible without
the support of our generous sponsors
each one of these organizations and it's
a lot because this is San Francisco and
it takes a lot to put into VIN on here
has contributed to something that has
enabled an aspect of this year's event
we want to thank all of them for being
willing to support in-person events uh
once again so I just want to give a
round of applause to all our sponsors
right now so
thank you thank you to all our sponsors
please
please make sure to check out all their
tables in the participant Hall inside
your registration but actually uh the uh
there should have been given a sponsor
passport card in your bag if you did not
get one some people did not they were
available uh at registration as well and
at the B size SF table in the Pacific
Hall so make sure you do that get your
passport stamped by all the
participating sponsors and you can enter
uh to win some really awesome raffle
prizes we have some really amazing
things in fact I had some staffers
asking me if they could participate and
I was like no sorry
um but it's uh we'll head the raffle uh
today and tomorrow starting at 12 30 in
participant Hall so make sure you get
your uh your passport filled out and put
in the Box in front of the bssf table
and participant home
and I just want to do a final you know
special thanks to our five leading
sponsors this year that's Adobe app Omni
code red Partners Google and Optics uh
so let's give them a final round of
applause here
it would not be possible without our
sponsors so thank you to all