all right everyone now ready to get
started with our next talk
so our next speakers are nicole fishbain
and ryan robinson
nicole fishbain is a security researcher
and malware analyst nicole has been part
of a research that led to discovery of
phishing campaigns undetected malware
and attacks on linux-based cloud
environments
and ryan robinson is a security
researcher for intesar he specializes in
malware reverse engineering and threat
intelligence
today's talk is go with the workflow
thank you very much
i'll just start our wee timer here so
there we go
thank you very much for coming to our
talk and pretty simply what our talk is
is it's about workflow applications and
the security implications that
come sort of with them which turns out
it's quite a lot but first let us
properly introduce ourselves actually
know that introduction is very good but
so i'm ryan i'm a researcher at intelzer
i mainly specialize in i guess cloud
frauds
a malware
in previous roles i was
a security engineer for consulting
company and then a research and
anomalies threat research team
on yourself
hi my name is nicole fishbein i'm a
security researcher at intesar and
previous to that i was in the embedded r
d department in the idf
all right so today we're going to talk
about workflows and how dangerous it
could be when you misconfigure them and
expose them
and we're going to present two case
studies one is argo and the other one is
airflow we will explain a bit about the
different features of each platform and
how it was misconfigured and what
information we were able to retweet from
there
and we're not going to leave you without
some practical advices on how to you how
you can detect this type of
misconfigurations and
detect it in your organizations
all right so let's start with what is a
workflow let's say you have some data in
a source database and you want to move
it to another centralized database so
for that you will need to get
information maybe analyze it and then
store it each of these functions can be
broken into smaller things like smaller
functions smaller tasks where each task
will pipeline pipe the relevant
information to the next task
and that's how you have a workflow
and you're probably going to
want to schedule it to execute execute
on certain hours certain dates and so on
so that's exactly what works of
platforms are meant to do and provide
you with disability
and some workflow platforms cost money
some are free and some are open sourced
so our research focused specifically on
the most popular workflow platforms
based on github
repo and stars
and we wanted to see can we find someone
that misconfigured the workflow instance
and now we can access the dashboard and
if so what kind of information we can
find there and lastly if we have access
to the dashboard can we execute malware
so the first case study is argo
okay so yeah our first case study is
argo workflows in my opinion the
workflow software with the best logo i
love that guy it's like a squid or
something uh
octopus but so
just a short about uh argo workflows
there's also an oversolver called the
argo cd um but this one's really really
popular so container native uh
workflow engine and for those who don't
know what container native means it's
kind of it's the best level of uh
infrastructure so hypothetically if you
can run kubernetes or containers and
stuff you can run the software so you
can't it's uh
open source which obviously we love open
source fantastic it makes it also
slightly easier to do some research on
so it does you know compared to pen per
product and doing sort of research on
that
it's designed for kubernetes
um great stuff and it's incubated by the
cloud neural computing foundation and
these are also the cm people that
maintain kubernetes so it's probably as
unofficial a workflow engine for
kubernetes as
you'll get
and then i set up that as my last point
there it's great for compute in terms of
jobs and away when key fees for sort of
foreshadowing
but the first talk about what a workflow
is
nicole's pretty much covered it all
already but in argo it's defined in yaml
and you'll probably notice quite well
like similar to jason
so it is
a workflow would consist of one or more
steps
typically a step will be a container it
can be a few other things it can be like
scripts or kubernetes resources but
for the most point people running
computers inside that and very simply
start a step with an
input
capture the output of the processing
from that step for a container and then
use that output as another input and
next step and busy so on until
you finish what it looks like
that's just some yaml for a
world um for hargo and then
um that's what it looks like whenever
you can submit it through
the server uh ui there's also a cli tool
if you know
you kind of like the terminal more than
using sort of an annoying kind of
browser you know
um
so there's one other important concept
is called off mode or
authorization mode um there's three of
them
oh please click
okay there's server client and sso
and for the purposes of this talk we're
going to focus on server so we are but
one thing i'll just point out before i
go further is that server was the
default
until version 3.0 and maybe this you'll
kind of find out why
so and what the
the sort of definition of that is is
that server see here
in hosting mode use the cube config of
the service account in local mode use
your local queue config
and in short terms it's pretty much
if you can access
the web gui for this and it's in server
mode you inherit those permissions
so
um
what this is here is the ammo for the um
you know you can use a cube cuddle and
apply like the quick start but
um in the default quick start that i got
you got all these permissions here
pretty much the full monthly permissions
so um pretty much out of the box like
the default configuration or at least
for the quick start it came kind of uh
about the permission heavy so that
and
so
busy hugging that be exploded and i kind
of brought it down into a simple
equation
on the equation i sort of say it's
server off plus excessive permissions
plus external access
equals profit
so it does and
you know you can
sort of think what you can do with that
and uh but for this case study we find
something pretty interesting but
obviously to find something interesting
what you first have to do is kind of
look for stuff
so what we've done is we tried to find
as many
um instances as possible that were open
in the world and you'll see this with
our second case study that we find even
more as well but sort of what we've done
for this is use internet census tools
stuff like showdown census uh i know
that uh
robert 7 have like open set of data as
well where to scan the internet and you
get those results
um if it's setting out on the internet
there's probably a good chance that it's
being indexed by google or ally you know
so you can just kind of google it and it
shows up
or what's a
slightly more experimental one you don't
get as many hits but it still does work
is what i call the brake force so
whenever many companies
will deploy something especially for
production they'll create a certificate
for it and like
a sort of domain and you know it used to
be something like argo.company.com
you can actually just permutate a lot of
company names and then just stick
argo in the front of it and you'll
actually be surprised at how many you
can find and yeah we did find some crazy
ones so that's that's pretty much how i
went through finding it just
google it
so when going through one we find this
like what
so um
to most people this might not be that
shocking it's just some yaml but what we
found on a few of the clusters was so
this one in particular running for nine
months by the time we found it was a
axam rig
monero cryptocurrency miner
and
so yeah on on a few of the clusters we
had found that
i guess uh fret actors whatever you want
to call them had gone on and started
using argo to deploy um you know
exam rig miners across like all these
clusters like many many different nodes
in each cluster so that's that's the
great part about the compute in town
support that particular image was on
docker help it got taken down now it had
been used millions of times and it was
even an azure blog for being used
against mass attacks against
kubernetes clusters
and so yeah we found it quite
interesting i wouldn't say it was fully
wide scale across all of them it's
almost maybe like someone was
experimenting and had a few of them or
else other people find it out and kind
of
wiped it out but yeah so we found it
really interesting so you can on your
workflow software you can get some
malware as well so her next key is today
all right so the next case study is
airflow and airflow is the most popular
open source workflow platforms based on
stars in github with over 25k stars
workflow is based on python so you can
write your tasks using python and it
supports multiple plugin and play
plugins
and the core unit sorry the core concept
of airflow are the directed acicli graph
so as we describe the workflows when we
create a few tasks and we one pipe the
information to the next one you can
create branches and so on
and the core unit is a task
uh writing in python
now your workflow is going to use
different variables global variables and
you can store them in a
structure called variables
and your workflow is probably going to
connect to other services and databases
and so on so to connect securely and
store the passwords and api keys that
you need for the connections you can use
the connection
and airflow supports logging mechanism
to emit metrics and to better understand
what is going on in your workflow
now
we were able to find credentials to
these applications like aws api keys
azure api keys paypal wallet ids and so
on
all in plain sight
and just to be clear we're not saying
that these logos are compromised who are
saying that we find lots of credentials
to these applications
and these credentials were still stored
all over the features of airflow that we
just covered
all in plain sight all are visible
through the dashboards
so to understand how we were able to see
all this information
we just
access the dashboards
and we access different tabs
so the top play is where we were able to
find credentials
was in the code
bad code practices lead to leakage of
information
one level of obstruction is when you put
your api keys and credentials in the
variables
well
the information is not getting encrypted
and it's in plain sight
and the connection structure is actually
the one and correct place to store your
credentials you will need to enter the
information to the password field well
when it will get encrypted and will not
be in plain sight
lots of users did the opposite thing
when they put the information in the
extra field where it's not getting
encrypted
the logging mechanism and airflow has an
actual cv
because when you would
enter your credentials through the cli
it will be get it will be
presented in plain sight
and if you connect to the uh using the
password field in the connection
structure it will be once again logged
in the plain sight
and this vulnerability was fixed in
airflow version 1.10 and later
the configuration file is created as
soon as you create your first airflow
instance
and lots of users put their credentials
in this configuration file
now
maybe that will be fine
but the thing is that the configuration
file can be stored in plain text on the
dashboard when a certain flag is set to
true
so once again we will we find lots of
credentials in the configuration file
and the ad-hoc query uh allows you to
run queries on whatever platform is
connected to your workflow
and if you're connected to a database
anyone with access to the dashboard can
query the database now if your dashboard
is
is accessible to anyone
anyone can query your database
so it's a very dangerous feature
and now we're left with one question
can we run malware and the answer is yes
during our research we were able to find
lots of
container images that are publicly
available so threat doctors could
replace the legitimate image with a
malicious image and when the workflow
will be executed anyone can
sorry everybody can uh run a malicious
smaller amorous container
and
we set up a test lab in our test lab and
airflow instance
where we used a plugin called code
editor that allows you to run to write
and run python code
and we were able to create a malicious
container
so
we found lots of information that we
were not supposed to be to see
and it was caused by
insecure coding practices by using the
features in a wrong way or
vulnerabilities
but airflow did an excellent job on
improving the platform and now it's up
to the users to actually um they update
their versions
hobby days and library to action
actually we're doing quite good in time
i started laughing especially for the
airflow um
slides like it's just it's just a blur
of like pixels it's like all sensitive
information it was insane like to
quantify how many credentials we find i
just want to say it's on an absurd
amount
so
but anyway
um so for the protection part
uh
i would sum it down to one phrase really
and it's the basics
really
and so the way i said that is um and i
really want to put this point to the top
is that
each of these issues on their own
might not actually be that bad but when
you chain them all together it can be
really really catastrophic so and like
we like we've seen this stuff like mod
you know you'll have someone they'll
deploy or flow to their cloud instance
and then maybe the one of the first
things they do wrong is the security
groups or the firewall rules
as configured anyone can access so
someone can access from the outside they
get to your flow instance it's a
outdated version unpatched version or
something therefore there's no
authentication there's no
login whatever so they can get past that
stage then they can get the cr code and
the code has hardcoded the credentials
inside that the credentials you know we
sell a lot of uh aws
keys
they have like way too many permissions
and then from that you know
steal customer data do whatever there's
so much sensitive information we saw so
you know there are kind of multiple
points along that line that you could
have stopped that you could have done
the permissions correct you could have
even just done like the firewall rules
collect but
people just it's every step of the way
that they will mess that up and it leads
to something utterly catastrophic so it
does so and not to say it's kind of like
a lecture bsx matter secure coding
practices
even if you feel that you know you're
sort of making code for something and
you feel that no one else will ever see
it
you know are you sure about that because
you know depending on how you do
processes within your company like
someone else could maybe mess up and
someone else gets access to that code he
shouldn't see that code
and then that becomes an issue patching
updating you know what's really really
nice with um both of these that we've
shown on other uh softwares as well you
know they have
like uh airflow itself has something
like
three thousand contributors you know it
is being updated all the time and you
see that but like version two it's so
much more secure they even have like a
security tab now when you go in with
like permissions control so update that
get rid of like the cvs and all
um secure configuration
just sort of goes about saying
especially if you're going to use
someone within
production
you know they're sure that the
configuration that you've said that is
actually good
um permissions yeah use the principle of
least privilege you know you don't need
to give the intern kind of god mode for
your hey oas clyde you know again i've
seen it happen before it's very common
and the word for party plugins so you
know i really like the nice example of
that there's a code editor um for
airflow usually you submit you know you
can submit the code via
like the cli tool but they're like no
let's put it into the server and so
whilst that third party plug-in it might
be
useful for you it could also be useful
for
an attacker as well and you can also
actually introduce more sort of
vulnerabilities than that you know if
you think about it um the plug-in is
being
uh
it's being made you know in a separate
repository from the main run so like the
the maintenance of them are not in par
with each other so
yeah beware third party plugins and i
always wanted a full slide for this next
build point the default configuration
does not equal the secure configuration
so if you're going to put something in
the production and do the you know the
quick start sort of thing that's that's
probably not a good way to go again if
right time you see like kubernetes gets
more secure our flows get more secure
argo as well
over time it does get more secure but
you know
whatever that you're deploying millions
of things the default configuration is
not always secure just think about that
and
last but not least the documentation is
your friend again for each one of these
on more products there is a security
page that is dedicated specifically for
our product and genuinely read it
because it's got some really good advice
so it does you know you might actually
understand
what's going on
and uh i'm going to leave with some open
source tills um
i'm i'm not really going to go for any
uh all of these you know you can sort
out or take a photo but a couple ones
that i really want to point out um the
get secrets one is fantastic it'll stop
you from committing
uh any credentials to your code so it'll
sort of scream at you if you try to do
that um clay custodian is a really
really good one
um
you develop
sort of policies within yaml files as
well and then you can run that with sort
of aws lambda or cloud functions
whatever cloud you're using and then you
can find the
violations of that and i like
the magpie project as well it's really
good especially if you want to
find what's exposed and all you know
i've had my season come to me and go you
know what's our exposure in our cloud
environments
i don't know like we've got a lot of
stuff up there so that'll really help
you defined stuff
and pretty much we're about the 20
minute work and we can go for questions
there's two of the blogs that we wrote
on i assume the left one is
um yeah oh yeah so that's the argo one
and that's the airflow one and there's a
lot sort of more
screenshots in all so yeah with
uh that's also up to 20 minutes any
questions from anyone oh thank you very
much thank you
that's about to say if anyone puts up
their hands i really can't say
you can also post your questions on
slido
hashtag besides
okay
how many
most of the containers
most of the instances were version one
and as we continued our research we saw
more version two but most of them are
version ones yeah especially when i came
that you can sort of tell there's a lot
of version two out there but they're not
necessarily exposed it's like you hit
the login page for it so whenever km2
misconfigured airflows i would honestly
say about 95 of them were version one
and then there was about five percent
version two where even though it comes
more secure out of the box they still
somehow manage to misconfigure it it's
almost like you have to actively kind of
sabotage version two to make it
yeah but people did the major thing in
version 2 is that they added uh enforced
login
so you can just access anything without
logging your authentication
um so yeah
yeah so i guess the fact that most most
of the exposed zones we find were
version one it's a really good way to
say yeah like
update your stuff
you know
anyone else
no it sounds worse thank you very much
[Applause]