okay it's 1 30 and we have
two amazing speakers here
avi
and ryan
um they have been uh they worked in
tesser i believe and also our
security researchers of malware
so that should be fun um
and
uh
it's a cobalt strike
beacon type right
implementation re-implementation
okay here you go we're here to explain
about it so
okay cool so hi everybody we're very
excited to be here um welcome to the
rise of the vermillion crossbar from
kabul strike beacon targeting linux and
windows
this talk is based on a research we
conducted during august
august 21.
i'm avigil i'm a product manager at
inteser before that i was part of the
research team and i focused on malware
analysis and threat hunting
thank you very much i'm ryan i'm a
researcher with
in telser on the previous rules i was a
security engineer on the researcher and
anomalies
threat research team
first we
agenda
of what we're going to be talking about
today so
um cobalt strike itself because um
this is really the popularity of this
tale is why a vermilion strike has come
about so a bit of background around that
is good to
uh understand then avi is going to talk
about the
uh the linux malware frat landscape so
you know why is linux being targeted and
who is targeting that
and then we're going to talk about
vermilion strike
in sort of more detail itself so the
background and then uh sort of brief
technical uh analysis of some of the
code
that's inside at hand
and then there's some stuff that we can
actually learn from that and we'll chat
about that and then we'll wrap up the
talk as well at about 25 minutes
so what is cobalt strike and
um if you look at kind of the website or
the marketing material it says it's
software for adversary simulations and
team uh operations
if that doesn't really clear it up for
you um the way i'd freeze it is that
it's a malware framework um and it
doesn't include just like the actual
malware payload itself but
the like command and control
infrastructure around it comes with it
and clients the sort of generate
payloads and also it's basically the
fill capabilities you would need in the
simulating adversary stuff
so the components inside it there's the
bacon
and
the bacon comes in two parts there's a
stager and then there's the full back
door what the stager is it's usually a
small piece of shell code that will
reach out to a c2 server and then it'll
download the main back door execute that
in memory so well
not every attack uses a stager you can
have something just go straight in with
the back door but it's slightly easier
to detect
there are things called loaders
and what loaders are is
there's just a huge amount of like code
snippets or scripts that you can take as
a loader and that will either execute a
stager or a back door
not sort of to help you
um
then there's the team server which i'll
say somebody else just the whole command
and control
infrastructure a cobalt strike
and you log into the team server using
the client and then the clients what you
see in the screenshot there and that's
where you generate your payloads from
so that's in short and sort of a couple
trick looks like at like a high level
um it's very very popular so it is
um you know it has great features hard
to detect often in memory payloads
pretty easy to configure swap out c2s
things like that
for payloads and say no
basically whatever target you're trying
to go for you can
get the quite a lot of payloads to
handle each specific uh case
um command control is handled you know
everything's encrypted and all you don't
really need to implement that yourself
um
and i say hard to uh attribute and more
so the reason for that is that there are
now so many people using cobalt strike
that it creates a bit of a spartacus
effect you know where you can't really
tell out of the noise who exactly this
is so here are the intended users of
cobalt strike
the real intended users are red teams
and you know
red teams will get a licensed version
from the maintainers and they'll use
that to simulate the attacks on their
company and then what they learned from
those attacks they can patch
those vulnerabilities
but unfortunately we also have what is
uh adversaries
that use a cobalt strike as well
and um
you what they will get is not a licensed
version usually but a cracked version
that they'll get online and then use
them
in cyber uh operations
where do they get it from
well quite simply every time there's
like a new version of kobold strike
released
honestly within like a matter of weeks
or sometimes even days there'll be a
cracked version online
and you can get this like on github
pretty easily or and it wouldn't
surprise me if it's on sort of dark web
markets or stuff that you could over
tour as well
um
so it's been in the news a lot and
honestly you don't really need to go far
you can just do a sort of google search
and you'll see many things like this
it's been used by scrub kitties up to
uh nation state sponsored trad actors
you know and you get news stories like
that like european diplomats being
targeted with it and all it's
really i could have replaced these with
like a 100 different news stories it's
all over the place really
um
what's the history between uh behind
cobalt strike on using it for linux
officially
there is none so
the maintainers of couple strike help
systems release the blog a couple years
back busy saying like this is a windows
only payload but it really doesn't stop
a few um
smart sort of programmers you know
creating a linux based payload for that
so
notable examples there's one called
geekin and it uses golang to implement
beacon and you can have elf
payload to that
um there's another one called cross c2
framework
and then like really funny was there was
someone on twitter had managed to run
the windows version of beacon and linux
using a wine
emulator
so i did so
i think it kind of half works
there
um
so until you help me for market
thanks
okay cool so now that we have some
background about cobble strike
um let's talk about the linux
um malware threat landscape and this
will help us to connect all the duct
dots together
so
the linux market share the desktop world
is really really low it's approximately
two percent
however the situation is quite the
opposite um when speaking about cloud
servers where linux is the predominant
operation system
which makes sense because of the of the
nature of it
however this really affects the linux um
maori fit landscape is because we see
many many coin miners and botnets
okay
um which again makes sense because they
are designed to take advantage of
computing powers and
the attackers behind of these malware
they just want to spread to as many
victims as possible okay so these
malware usually are not targeted now we
also see ransomware which are usually
targeted and delivered to file hosting
servers such as qnup and ransom
and vmware esxi servers
which can refer to ransom ex which was a
quite popular
like a few months ago
and
lastly
less populated let's say frequently
documented are backdoors
which are targeted and usually the
adversaries behind these backdoors are
nation state
now the nation state that historically
been documenting
targeting linux
are russia north korea and china now an
interesting fact here is that
most of the tools most of the linux
malware that was
developed by nation state has at least
one other version that targets other
operation systems so for example we have
apt-29 in russia which have the wellness
malware that targets both linux and
windows uh
for north korea we have the lazaros
group um they have decals the targets
linux windows
and mac
and also they have a manuscript that we
found targeting linux and windows
and for china we have the winter group
they have backdoors for linux and
windows and also the blacktech group
they have ts cookie and pleid both of
which were first discovered targeting
windows
and after a while they were found
targeting linux as well
cool so we have some background about
coba strike we have some background
about linux malware let's connect all
the dots together and talk about our
research
so one day we got this set um for a file
an elf file
from our thread hunting tool and we
uploaded it to our system which is
integer analyzer
um and from the analysis we saw three
interesting things
okay this screenshot is taken from our
platform which is integer
so the first thing that we saw which is
super interesting
again this is an elf sample
and it shares strings with cobble strike
now as ryan mentioned before
there is no official version of colbert
strike for linux okay so this was by its
own very very interesting
uh second of all
um the file shared
like
about
um of previously unseen code okay so the
code that we see here that is marked as
vermilion
um
it the screenshot was taken after we
marked the code okay i'll i'll just
explain a bit about integer
so um integer has a really really big
database containing trusted and
malicious code
now every file that is uploaded to our
system is divided into chunks of code
and compared against our database
so the fact that the file had a very
very large percentage of previously
unseen code
is a huge indicator that this file might
be written from scratch
and lastly
we saw network related capabilities um
such as
resolve dns um
socket stuff and so on which was
again really interesting all those
things together
so in virustotal it had zero detections
um which is not really a decision
differentiator when speaking of linux
malware and we'll talk about that um
later
however the name of the binary was
was a bit odd
um x11 jtk now x11 is a graphical
environment for unix and jtk widget
libraries now it makes sense each x11
jtk they come together however when
searching for the exact binary name in
google and in virustotal
we got no results
another interesting thing that
this file got triggered by our rules
written by florian ross detecting
corporal strike which kind of aligns
with the string we use that we've seen
an integer platform
so all of this together made us really
really happy as researchers because we
know that we have something really
interesting in our hands
and uh we started to dive deeper
technically
okay so um just sort of dive deeper into
the file let's just jump straight in
they give a macro sort of high level
view when vermilion is executed
it will demonize itself in the
background
it'll then
decode its configuration import rsa key
that later uses for encryption it'll
fingerprint the machine and it'll start
the c2 loop which is largely what
coupled strike does since just a
re-implementation of that
so for the configuration
um simple zor cipher
hack 69 which is quite a common uh value
used might be
the default for one of the versions of
cobblestrike
and what's quite interesting is since
it's
the exact same configuration as you saw
like the arrow rules headphones you can
use some cobblestrike configuration
parsers and it'll handle it completely
fine even though it's sitting inside of
an elf file
and you can still see is that the
windows artifacts still exist in the
linux version so as we're talking about
before once you start seeing stuff
that's for windows but inside and health
file you know if you're really looking
for a red flag for what is a suspicious
well that's probably quite a good one
a highlight just in the top there that
is
the c2
or so there are multiple c2s configured
for the file
um
so when it fingerprints the machine
very simply collect stuff like the
process id kernel version
network on the user
piece that all together in a big string
and then encrypt that and then have that
staged strategy for being sent off to
the c2
for command control
it is dns in his tdp but primarily dns
that's that's what it
goes for at the start
um and the commands are received over
address and the tax records so attacks
as if the c2 wants to send sort of
information down that that will decode
that and then run the
command for it
what was also really interesting was
that there was code inside the file for
icmp communication but there was no way
they actually got that so
it's either a feature that's still in
development or else they went to develop
it and then just kind of like kind of
dropped it so
pretty interesting
when it came to commands
it can change the directory it can list
the present working directory
list files in your directory it can
write the file send the file to the c2
execute a command or it can even get a
summary of the minded disks
for the machine
so
you know looking in this sort of
grabbing some ioc stuff from the
configuration you know you start to try
to pivot you know we fully understand
what the file does
so
whenever
we
pivoted on the c2 address or the two of
them there what we found was
a windows stager file that reached out
to the same one and when we actually ran
that stager file it used powershell to
download and execute
a payload in memory and then we found
out what that payload was was the
windows version of vermilion strike
and
what was
pretty funny was that it had been
detected back in 2019 so it was you know
a few years later and there was a tweet
from silas cutter it was a sort of
interesting code strike sample and
turned out to be that vermilion strike
one
the functionality it's largely the same
so if you look at one of the functions
on the left it's done on itself and then
on the right the windows
version of vermilion so this is the code
in the configuration
so from like a graphical higher level
it's pretty much the same as what's
going on you're able to use the cmc too
for all the the systems
in the wild
so we partnered up with mccoffee
enterprise atr
we provided them iocs and they queried
it against their telemetry
and the results were quite interesting
we saw that vermilion strike
actively targeted high-profile companies
around the world this includes advisory
companies financial institutions i.t
government agency um and telecom now
with that being said um it was still
specific okay we didn't see many many
samples and we didn't see many many
victims
so as for attribution
we know that this is a backdoor
we know that it's written from scratch
we know that it targets both windows and
linux
and
it was found in live attacks around the
world but yet targeted
now
based on historical knowledge we can
assess with high probability that
vermilion strike was developed by a high
profile adversary
specifically probably a nation state
however we couldn't
attribute it to a specific one
so
the windows version of vermilion strike
got
a nice amount of detections by security
vendors in virustotal
but the linux version got none
although it had string reviews with
global strike and it triggered er rules
which i think are probably
publicly
available
and this raises the question of why
linux malware
fly under the radar
let me show you this screenshot taken
from ubuntu's official website
it has
the title do i need antivirus software
and i marked two sentences
first sentence
anti-virus software does exist for linux
but you probably don't need to use it
second
whatever the reason linux viruses are so
rare that you don't really need to worry
about them at the moment
so
this misconception
leads to low demand for linux and
malware detection
which
shifts away security vendors from
spending time and resources
on linux detection
which leads to these scenarios
this is a
mirai sample
mirai is one of the most
popular botnets around targeting linux
it has many variant
variants its source code was released
publicly a while back
and the developer of this sample added a
spice of sophistication and obfuscated
some functions and strings and this is
the result none of the security vendors
in virustotal detected it
and i find this really really disturbing
and
this is one of the takeaways from our
talk is that
we really should um
spend time
with detecting linux malware we should
it is it is around okay and integer is
rapidly uh
posting blogs about it and we're going
to post another research very very soon
i think
two or three or
so yeah
okay
so um
sort of as sort of wrap up you know how
would you protect yourself um
against the vermilion strike
um for the windows version
it's a memory only payload so you see
you have to make sure that you have
antivirus or
uh
edr even like a endpoint scanner it's
able to get that in memory
um
or you can
you can get it by the stager as well so
the stager we found it was also a unique
code so we're pretty happy to say that
if that stager is there then you're
probably infected with vermilion strike
as well
um the linux version a way more simple
there's no stager for that that can be
found on desk
um
some of the cobbled strike
methods for detection you can use that
for vermilion strike as well
and um
you know and we saw that with like the
arrow rules and all and you can also get
it uh by the network since
it's communicating in the background
with a couple strike c2 you know those
sort of uh other methods will work as
well
um
for protections for the future really
it's uh well so for cobblestrike itself
it will probably remain quite a big um
frat
uh for the windows space i could still
be in minty and there's still new
versions coming out and then cracks like
following that pretty soon after you can
get that online and it still seems to
work pretty well
so it does
um vermilion strike is a bit hard to say
as we find you know
the code for the windows version hadn't
changed since
2019 it hadn't affected too many people
but it was still active when we found it
so it's been going for a few years
and they haven't been detected so why
not a couple more
um but one thing we are pretty certain
is that the cross-platform malware will
uh continue and we see quite a lot
especially you know with the rise of
cloud and all
um the incentive for
targeting both windows and linux
is still there
and what that always says thank you very
much and if anyone has any questions
that's the qr code for the blog there
[Applause]
okay thank you abby and ryan um
we got a few minutes for questions
questions anybody
anyone
okay well i have a question i guess real
quick
um so clam av
could that detect it
it's on linux
and
okay we need to test it i don't know
yeah put a signature for uh clam av on
that i mean from from moving forward
yeah of course um
okay cool cool yeah i love linux
backwards and forwards so they would see
that on servers right yeah
uh aws probably okay so anybody
questions beyond me
all right well um thank you very much
for your time and i really do appreciate
you sharing your knowledge so
let's give it a round of applause for
these folks
awesome awesome
thank you
[Applause]