will edit that part out you're right
look out of course
RI goodyear facing the street
offer process i sec hack forbidden ever
was freed science PCTV
their zakka America okay
yeah
thought cop spoken to congress few
you that's a whole other awesome univer
causes of
Friday makes subjects
his life story who wonder gees 3
is have incriminated speaker this
particular pizza
basic Brazil because I expect it to be
this week
he doesn't know very good if they are
these he was chosen as one of TIME's
Person
here 2006 you
very long I
goes it's time for some years ago safe
where's my that I of I'm yeah
I via a all that
a just like to argue I are victims of
explains 5
think that that's okay I however girl
slow very opening people of my brother
is here
a upon you want to go placing Houston
ago so his all I
very well the of securing a very wrong
so right this is not forever of this is
actually how long recovery
guys I'm of and so
yes you have following day file you know
I
why I feel I was actually I
sticks I guy who felt like it was a very
very late
I'm going to talk about that when I talk
about things like that things I've done
wrong
have however is its freezing taxis are
going wrong
is not saying I'm checking to you I'm
doing things
I've got everything okay are here I'm
guilty of so does not solve your finger
you
there's like a you know showing you go
go for it but I have
I I'm very
granting your asking if I i'm
those from you yes I
that you know of so I won't refuse all
KK more last 0 me
thank you the idea so most of his life
remains
you know I think this song is over
country
and not everybody's of Indian culture
others
so I was like I flew into the lab every
using the youth group fear of a very
good so now
where you go 0 okay it was worth of yeah
so that yeah they have
this is all there I
2005 of about it's like hey this is a
visually
of guy University call Arizona elvir and
invasive
also little the security office are
measured by
I always him packing up
I'm told the conference that out by this
of try so day so I've heard
offices of and I Gregory you go
very aggressive yeah yeah thanks a lot
so I have enough bodies like this your
finger out of business
successful visit of however I just love
it you know
it of both it's like a of
hours users think still I'll it all
I all for you every baseball
graduate and the I
freezes with us are worse
boss yes of golf
like other he says twenty dollars for
the Tea Party over
no your health
they the this at home so
400 if they think them all there you
have
Express cards giggles of you will see
how that small phrase
this is worth I totals for growth
you see of its I stay there also
thinking okay
I 404 oh yes oh
Google Talk did
here you have a very forward also
going up against hearsay oh I wave year
ago
of this because of me go this device
and yet although go on think
we'll see if they have my this year go
to a shop
we have to approve the day
so it is a good movie you know for our
sister
secret archives up so how do you think
that's how we tried it
set of processes me a
rest assured things they don't for as
gonna
his whereabouts at all provoking this
talk
all I me okay
her I me as I right now
questions here there's wifi so many
different ways
say of the same time day as they have
over good at what they see if it works
on clearance tango
I patches 0 job
not secure the more of however I have a
question that
yep this goes we have her ways to do
that
as good as anything so
the first or of school talk about things
we have a problem with this industry
okay yes for your of
you over that's how information security
wise to think of marriage that's how we
like to think of
yes that because mean like approach
we might think it was a other interest
to you
fact the only one go how to deal with
them are that
of is not
RAF drop do you think you are how
in the for calling the terms okay
secured
there under is that's okay
if they will be probably the first
exactly they no longer have this
way to go still something that's okay
so is updated information future
to were house of communication upper
management
any cannot were house music's got a
problem if you don't learn how to
address
arrangement if we don't stop looking at
you
for its been coming from that standpoint
it never want to do that 30 isn't that
something you're always going to have
that this day
wrong with content how are you
to actually figure out hey I old but I'm
hoping to talk about
he didn't know this for and that's why
it's my job to educate
part of the show was always acted as if
you do this because I've learned II
Friday though
try cancer you know which marks a very
act of God
way what he's also Meyer sorry law
well crazy situation awareness I
we need to do to help operator
a process I don't know if they just a
nice the European if you're a situation
awareness
over go try your request raising lots of
time busy
what we gone wrong arms as they say you
all have back
I hope that creating a I red going acted
a high threat I you know if they have a
problem with golf
that K but also very slow it back
because
is being done by someone who's problem
copyright here
for person I Gervacio visiting right
thing
so you have contracts and that place
to exactly how series of five rather low
impact as well
I'll ways I agree with this would
actually have
eyes were after groupware the situation
over
that over and over yes have I heard for
this job
he was i've I'm these two jobs won't let
me
what's our fans were hailed from
subsidies
Jason I want you have this problem
Joseph
few okay you think my English eyeball
hopefully I don't worry about that stuff
you know so
they want you also a poet
word 3s by I you can also noteworthy
for the CEO company rather than helping
I got this
he didn't know him very well I very
thorough
so I posted a letter on my was like I've
I so I I i'm here
I hosted on the site the actually
sprayed are so I'll
fair Frank actually formed a
if you understood of his life I
president email from James a okay data
audio
is that you know higher Skaife
story time I I have a few
than 40 passing out that okay place
group as well there rosy
I a and their
or back to their on Friday
able whole hey of the morning
a very good morning I overall with
witty president of being and if you go
for some reason will both be reading on
the job very well
yeah so it was very rare any
yea I was going to say well you know
this is you know that this guy's
view for fuses ok I'm I
the CEC yes but not very pleased right
no and go to i Jason L below
the reserves frightened set sorry
and I'm as overlapping over like a truck
driver
draft I that what your when we go
20 go right so I
while angle they're going to say all
here yes for this is that you know
K I those other jobs
through the nose for rancher and I would
like to know
right rise country girl yes for
exactly where view actually acted nation
in sacks
you know it's gonna persons up so video
I any go also who have passed you
yeah my her
and a very easy I okay that go you know
who you know if you want to get a job
I
yeah right hey
will also see safe day see you
like this over
fools I okay
a it up walkout
I with prior I to hold a school or
rather so I
I very well thanks for the call goes
like a
over I Hyundai I've asked to work
yes like 50 of the might of
and I i also not going to the same
I want to know something about I for
fire
to are you first one of
RI gets worse one of the house Fri Mar 5
you the jurors were I felt good out
there too
followers know there is a few
there although ordered never ever go
yeah I something back
and go to work for all where are you
change
on those alerts
I races where I it was it worth
II that is me for it
of I i'm
I three months later your receive
I the request okay
lo que it's like
we not only my yeah so that's that's
rather
not one customer of mine really
supposing they
for you all up a that if up for good
act as though you know those are fires
really concept of class
so that this was like antiquated yeah
iraq
good-looking one thing I think that's
why I'm
stuff I find you 0 so mean greater yeah
yeah really well here also
okay long are they so that it like in
every situation where
game a few K they don't see me
the hearing they don't see how you
factor in possibly happen
they call AAC I do not suggest
doing the exact you whether it is up to
you now as I can create your house is
wasteful
another day that I'm really really just
drive
be nice call okay
54 ok to improve
over I okay
find everything here it could be a fight
or
I for all baseball
him do you know what
graduates are no
those
lol you Harry King of Kings your gateway
how do you stay hey are stacked
aggregate
yeah okay irony desktop
I are all yes our tax how to install
are I up overall numbers overall numbers
a healthy
more texting you gather the or where you
were
the more you understand what's going on
under network he said
love metres you low like that day
year you're going to go to your calls a
I'm not giving you hell little I'm to
use our
then cover strong very good well
outbreak both pressure going on
how many okay we're going to mitigate
these risks that
of any that helps word fire
okay I'll sell it to you thanks to you
your things up
we have Thursday that though congress me
song pie charts are not going to dismiss
executive hire cars her assets cooney
help educate your management you start
using that way
I
I'm fossil I Mason
thank you so much there's like arce
great job you know thing %uh sewing well
good its light out there what does it do
well as a wife and a man's
I Tuesday a wiser emerge from someone
else's
five-dollar dangerous loves arms away on
Saturday
I feeling that there is one of the best
walking over I
Gophers yes everything was ok from her
and
impacted record back because you don't
know your CEO
network of for yeah go
overall yeah extensive
shows you go up to you we have event
unique
I job we have any without the
he's involved in the nineteen and
secured
on the front page yeah there are two
scores
and stroking good sex workers wife
some of True Range was only one wrong on
reviews
I just ten stories ok I i
facts going on right now
use well they've read it go
but it shows you this is not something
that's going away
this jobs bill let's not be
guys for me specs so at all times
something like that goes on
this is a way use music to your behavior
of
lather this is what we do I
a few yeah I love that you know if
placed on my
of your thinking this information you
use for free that before
okay because you have to have that come
from UK
yeah and access there you go
the hero some hungry or have I S
you have to do that I
tackles the of as long and that's what
you're doing more
you're trying to communique trying to
make sure they're helping out
you're amazing I do these things that
song
have you create something right all
you're after
UK what the overall we have yes it will
I like of yours
jordan Crawford
pretty to a draft okay you
believe president of okay
I'm here 100 hear you for
yeah you doing here
yeah remove their I'm here
guy I'm here measures like I
2030 I I heard some things you go
here and I have no heart attack
says yeah conniving got what do I think
you're always a shopping mall
yeah I i thought was what the heck
I'm there too distraught to go there
lines of I through your thursday okay
however I now
my jaw I've come to realize
is not to live there yeah
over here I got this group is still here
my job this year midday
Chris my stop is your day
must rest at of my job is you
n after a Vijay that we're 14
what group that's not oversell okay as
in what they view it
that's why I'm blessed with a very small
said
they didn't of their
by insurance my be recorded as the way
they also at risk yeah
back week that
we have to learn to accept risk
they're alright will still feel that you
know
yes this is our is so the more I think
it out
we have burned trees that for risk
make a let's UK all
their what's left over you're just going
to have to learn is that
yeah ice is a rather
every of coping mechanisms somewhere
half over
right things like that risk so geyer
I our community a how long after that
are amazing
it's like are dropping group of girls
are
this is wrong pay I
running for their lives my yeah
I humor okay yeah
drop my god is great clear
over there stop I
going good I
you're going to hear your 500 of
got everything I have your five-dollar
very of the hacking cough okay for
fake one yeah the of
yeah over here as you are you there
so time he going to go
I Outback
that happens I've got this he said that
he is a
there it's not my job to stop is my drug
three for you
engines are yeah I think they got back
okay
of think that perhaps
that's what happens if I can go from you
where does Chris Carr worth or
why are you surprised thinking of
so I have to learn how to better
communicate with her over here
we have miss you yesterday why
music has always been so or this act
like they don't ever have to a bar
well iraq we have to learn how to
communicate
if you haven't Galway Bay
things right you know a reason why you
ask your pharmacist
the Spartans 300 okay the
the network you know actually you know
goes for all the rest
I'm passes over every are you waiting
for
back you know yeah my is over
it's like having to go over your house
life
you don't know they just got here
anything like that you know next to a
wall
are you just wait for the next day you
have to learn how do you hack
they've got some if all your I Park
Service
they don't understand all yeah in for
that interview
positions the Masons they freeze is this
your visits go
this through their security
exists you know if this is your
okay we have %uh there you go that low
gray days you if
I am so tired hearings are you sure this
thank you for coming thank you very much
for
up still I security department records
that hot ass yeah
I car I 2005
ever drew or forget your
yes require rest
why is that these employers I'll
they know what you're doing this
okay if you don't think you have what it
is always good
your boy is more thanks author of
desktop
yeah come back
envoy not create a more Facebook
see you I was actually it as easy as you
want for me
yeah for your 3y there early this
morning because my
company what fires of hell
for whom this scale of how are you
okay
yeah good morning hope you
I do it yeah okay
I resolve
you yeah exactly
is this your gVoice what are you of
of you go call fair K
well I person before
well overview I have their or
ongoing ever I wasn't saying for
rich countries are you HR
thanks for all their 0 everyone else
here
okay more ok hey ho also
over so yeah
world back where all the way
hackers your Mac they're a bit more
I vs is this ok your YouTube it's rough
outing
it out because a more this business
yeah so you are still reporting
we're just not OK problem
you know well I don't raise your voice
we tried it seems to believe however
they're copying data
we tried a few always why it's so
important to you
protect okay these always
are your credit card number strong-arm
home
big boy don't know I'm sorry for what I
said
funding of the always don't know how to
upgrades those games on Fupa Amazon the
rumors were going online
why do they care about your day
stop trying to teach your always however
yesterday
teacher following how to protect myself
start having less are and your belief
however lost
are tries your voice how for example
sells
online NRK show her voice
how people approach I one Facebook
fighting off
on hot you for protecting your
alway I don't know how to protect myself
any
actually you know this if
nasty sector yeah it's
they from of base of your day
but now we're actually more heavily my
every day to have this I problem
don't try to get some respect up
see actors K they are smart they came
from
where you are on the wrong way around
frame
I gotta yeah I think our
go to the actual mad
your life that every single employee
your information security
today for this video to the mailroom
view always no governor Nations Security
yeah it was a vast I yeah the world
going up your everyday
suspicious the overhaul
you know contact you this is enough
I at my job right now hey
every single freaking banning of yes
he had he known for his home thrash 43
just like you there yeah
I way you I a reasonable time
thank you that's great all of its over
they've got me out there
you you
yeah you I know if you know if you think
your heart with
over one ways in which is very hard I
game great at work where you parked free
are identical huge Rathdrum
wireless router if you have this phone
worse than mine yeah go to war with one
another or
of expired fire doing
make sure there's your asset
that's how you approach your voice I
have used for
communique call office
but yeah they a letter or something
you're almost here
of your daughter dare trachtenberg
like okay are I specifying or I'll
I up other of back I
you go or not so sure or you
engineer I go back I
world a yeah
yes throw me
good work I of course
golf course we have a good thing right
Carlisle good here
you going away G sheegay singers
Qatar's yuri and Charlie
mediate over I'll four paragraph
write-up
are others were spraying
watching Dayo very how to hack
you yeah that a circle greater
go you then also collapse
of frequency you
changes like chairman United Way case
worth the hassle of althaus rate of I
have dropped I think stuff like I think
yours up are looking back I
up are of being
for you create that habit of work that
whole competition
yes for yes you wall
crew every four believe that we have
you think they were here we walk it
works
love you what you think more
overlooking two years rather
look if you move around offer
everything's okay whatsoever
aversive yet also you know hack
I as well so I'm sabu reviewing
result all this time that
various no information security if both
worlds there you go
a hacker