'em
developers extreme
here's screens
countries testing
differences multiple operating systems
but the streets or cystic
insists trees
multiple operating system
manner
it
through testing francisco sir
artists
status
who's just
says dot
so there was a news report
of
character
bar it for a
pcs while
about st restating that's what's up and
show up
the police in the afternoon
clearly wants the beauty of the tasks
one st
some files for both parties
is ideal
what world record
yes good hospitals
lessons
subhakar
dvds traffic
their used
the truck yeah
undergone cities that's fine
so really
recess you certainly
uh... insisted
bananas and i'm sure i'm not sure that
outing
mug
what
what u
epidermal growth parties spoken tulip
poplars
alaska reads gate
to agree with speeches
everything cities
crazies either
ariel assessments etc
included people so that we have to
happen
my column
so briefs eleven people
our statement
like he said
uh...
so also it work
is that people there's this
who really good
reinstalling air up
tomorrow so disasters on its p_c_r_
and
laws passed by
here's a reach is
levels is by story i just look at case
for about an hour
introverted so scared he got reason
didn't stop
most region
rules for purposes
uh...
did here
utility responsible order
and it is a hat
that uses a report to the state
website
you kiddo
you drive thousands next month away
notebook
so of resisting or housing
pat i'm going to be system
what's up
now we are proceeding
peeled off
programmable listings
uh... two months ago businesses now
really excited
profits
washer
uh... actually
insolvent status
we've got a lot of the server scrap
itself
uncritically part
you know sort
saluted was the first time out
cities that are happening
sponsor
went out
this is over the years
appreciably in south africa so these
guys
actually broke into the system
is that uh... ever
tried it once it's on the accounts
polonius these cats are always
a_t_m_ cards
kehta although he
right now
enabled three-day three-day hopeful
cities
inside society
of pity als dat
they discovered
installed a unit was in school
well
services dealers finals though my
beloved
really knows
uh... results once
impersonal style
anglesey sheet
uh... being one of the fire
hacker programmer this interest
in its usual skills did
the criminalist
going after that
activation
base he she had to face website
yes people uh... blog post
alerted
refusing to be good
morass
on our safety had a beautiful our
theater
accidents have
inorder reported to have a lot
several fold up
also is
uh... cdrom next
uh... heart attack
spirit
came into each of our
lady clothes on
and it may have
so wanted
how committees are computer
acts
city in office and if you do
when all over the organization that east
again
immediate ours is not
action news featured car parks two weeks
ago
endorse candidates feature bridge
seventeen
uh... happy
force of about sixty families that were
offerings
and definitive
god's look at
how those things
r_c_a_ and i had cousins problem about
medicaid
art states
staying away
uh... about privileged
psychopath is are
banners pencils pens
hostility
you're not
decade places
itself
nasa bball dreams
so these guys came in
export
sonya
sits there
so that's what
is iteration
about thirty seven
players
they finally hundreds of eight million
dollars
elitist way
i think it's three times
solidity
reacting address season
you know
what isn't
and without it
me and that's the best of
right there
atmosphere visiontek tech
based out
front row
was this is the essence of the
initiative
it was a good with israel
you're
beads that will be a tax
lost a survey and while
is gets a lot like these
let's face it
it's not for me
it's not real address
it's not mine
ideas forward regarding collins cancels
uh... history
it's all things
basically all day long
most of your are
are
a truly caller
so sounds like
so of course the accident by half
here
myself but
hopes audiences as the sun music u_k_
so regarding their missile the our
always instead
export
well what's interesting instead
extraordinary anyway
hampton-el
who's got worth
anonymously ap everything
response
said there is excellent
uh... nasa
right here indecent
so the inspector general
uh... looked at it
did this for
instead what what what do you know it
all other
or me
is here
every u
which
here
uh... hospices awful you gave her
this affects a lot more action
it was a so they have a whole surplus of
our driveway
it's not hard for us
and were
with the way
upheaval
and you start getting started so only
today
all problems anymore
so would they have
alternative
the honda on
it is the past about powers
the way i don't like pride
they act
school district
uh... reacting of
uh... programs
if
it
that problem
uh... stratford otherwise tracker
people
uh... awesome
information red
hackman's refer
use alternative hasn't
salaries for
uh... on this
well uh... they stole
it's it's sixty f
credit cards cannot after
almost all set cat
understands that are
it's freezing
apoplectic about these guys
the clinton modeling
k was enough thought
today to watch the tds credit cards
the insurance
if you're a price
lurches
all of these guys
and often results emails today call
sheets
do you think that
withdraws
so basically i think that the orchestra
exited
well
uh... so alcohol or other rayburn
were forty-five
of us are basically
but if you notice
adopted rooted infected eight hundred
thousand
uh...
so hackers are said to be doing
satellites it's easy
it will you secured with the
secure internet access team www
okay a safe and take ten million dollars
to do this
stream
culpability
the partnership is that now
conjures face xvi right now
we're just going to be done
c using every five six
you see
record
yahoo
they hurt myself
designed to extent companies wonderful
are not good enough
idris
actually got better
this uh... a laptop stole a couple years
ago
uh...
forty million the records were on their
own records in all those uh... when it
was on a regular injured
personnel
what the software veterans but i don't
know how did she get
on
whether it's like the world
undersell lautenberg says because the
bottom
the or
for a record
in the day in average day coverage
people that are used on the banks
after all a little coffee tea sets in
holocaust are a lot for all
if coca-cola bought of drug makers it
does cost nothing
the case
it's gonna cost of your attorney sits at
a cost
uh... consultants cut intrepid
references people
uh... then i might
says the possible
you are
now a lot of infidelity acts
dating back to you look at their actual
financial
that they follow up define financially
that went down three percent
first three months after the retreat
odds at least two people
uh... pretty said this is uh...
prakhar us
uh...
that they say it usually doesn't always
equate la familia
but there are
that recently art
in this e-mail reported accompanying
kuwait city
stopped
likes that
when the bridges announced
idolized her
ipl
i get your weather permitting
expense on the bridge depends on how
many to sub some places he i have five
hundred records
took forty
t debris and reports of money
you know i was a kansas couple weeks ago
portraits the spot
dept at five hundred lost five hundred
lost it has to be
interactions with that
uh... date was on the project
or obfuscate that you know it's not
redacted information
luxuries in places where you go
look to see if your company
kathleen dot texas
absences joins us live about six times
now last week
uh... texas a and we had here
welfare
has for
so nl
food for three hundred things ever
invasive
utilises
insulting killed notice until the
children
in three persons uh...
uh... they'll also broke into their
system
the ussr
went on to say
uh... upward tick
that they've lost summer cap
uh... they've also left a and
which is pretty good
twenty-four powerful delimited upgrades
in waffler regards author points out a
system
without interest
over it
that doesn't mean it's anymore
securities they probably couldn't have
been invited to come and it's been
tested
uh... so i think
is a great place to go on the sale
blvd example
here's the phone
unless they what kind of reach it was
what was the
there was a bit are
writer or
like these
this is erica haha
swalker
uh... indebted to you dot means or or or
information paper
but he said
working for laura stillman mister
in companies you can actually fall
stanley reached has to do this
any updated piya every single
you can to look at every single day
i think about once a week
and i to go
checkpoint customers you have any of
those are all there
uh... they often be counselor they need
to get people were dead
uh... and
this is just brought up a bit of a
connection
cities italy's comma
there
you can see all the work that law
what wanted
uh... quest
ourselves
because they just don't know
at sos com customers that has lost
out here
so
they might use these two sides
cubes two sites
it's its
you don't use the sites
uh... here
cdc actually
invited
yes
standard were
that my background
and setting up
suggesting that hundred thousand
bathroom
units of got to stop by accident
uh... according to an end to end user
guide
all right on andrew
and this is eric another conference
three weeks ago
worry of
and state and revised with the usb
exploded folders
dislike that concealer
uh... anyway if you could see
of malware forever
and
now powerhouses
simple different sides of the pittsburgh
andrea i want to return to miami
repro
uh... interviewed at a different
passports
you know how do you have to ask me for
my phone
couple anyone who would have been
and u
that night after work tomorrow
sorry i didn't get you more about it
wasn't like that
it's yours
so what he said
difficulties at first might not even
know about
is that right now we're has not related
to the uh...
uh... housework server
working for a outside yourself where
but there's stuff that these
put out there to start
stealing your commission as an actress
kooks dealer i wasn't that big
through apple system
will make a difference is that a pretty
cool automated system in houston that
their software out there
it see if it is a box that all this
stuff
the article recall
lady and
you got this in this message is sent out
it wouldn't send out as soon as this
rip regular
it was added to a premium service
cc alright not overtime salts that
specifies buses
and so on
the couple of hours needs were uh... on
elected details below
first people to school
work like that and the battery
so we're talking about reno right
was in the actors below if there's a lot
more
okay
in area where it was a reasonable
but we're still
separation remain
in charge of ten bucks
bogus book is bogus
he did nothing
you click on it at all and it was
shutdown of the browser taking to the
website of the waters
it invaded what happened
this is a triple net
so they can
uh... repair who's worked very hard to
do
couple people
caper and uh... i don't care
everybody and hear at the time of year
character who is probably
said no way
do you find anything
researchers are into
difference of two thousand devote their
software
running on stilts
interest instances pretty crazy stuff
went as soon as the subject of your book
it would be intercepted analyzing it
change whatever he wants it often
observers of the displayed on the phone
you know says dot
institute for keywords for words in
preparation
it's reported she strokes
you could say they're watching
demonstrating this and he recorded all
those business development
it would be good work easter partner
paul hotmail
well there
phone companies
if he had a report
two days ago a_t_t_ rising is selling
everyone's about
web browsing on your folder select
marketing people
but i think it's crazy opened our gate
but this is a
the act says it's economy
an update and i was five
elaborate fall apart c
clean sheets on but it's definitely
their kids with the lines of pharmacy go
go
look a wrecking
if you're if you're a dreadful no it's
not the vatican
another farmer on somebody site
here
and another sisters monitor software
could rocket action we could see
we're all accounts receivable straight
no because
these guys
went to the recruitment site
did package hindu religious but the
bottom
here comes all usually
vista
they had to ask you what these guys have
long and it is terrible
time i've ever seen
what was it sold individually all
shawnee estimates that suggest he lost
everything
always alleviating molding
and that's about sixty
uh... this company
resist asking a lot of fun
mobile banking and social media
uh... acts looking for daily gauge
you know it
your full account number came across to
this story is it not criticism critical
stuff
and fourteen
hawaiian slaps
uh... after
so that you know
path past
this just basic daily for
the social here
so-called called social
engineer
uh... sites
the passenger
uh... is anyway to read it
for sure interactivity costs
uh... resisted
not for u
so what do you have to think that there
has been a part time marrow they are all
the seventy-seven paperback
literacy bonnet
there over the spot where all other
computers from now
did you take shape interval welfare
so the car
redhead with pictures of people in
compromising position
so they said
we need this to track are people so they
don't pay the bill
and at stake in wilkes-barre itself
schools
because they're was u_s_ the said this
is all about what's right
information and what's what's the
the problem they were doing
was they were picking certain people
going example showing everything from
production indestructible off
they worked hard to know all the women
lost a laptop that works for you know
watching
uh... programs habits taxes your credit
card a review of your right now
without of
uh... it
it already
it was a
right
one-two-three u_s_
per broker
dot it
i'll get out of here
well i computer think
itself like
cut and that's all right
uh... was not
the reason is because i don't know if
he's got to do
somalis forums
and listening to these kroeber parsons
really wasn't once a month ago
populous as a regards
itself
if you buy their status
arctic too personal
making these making instructs all these
cards
you can you ask test part
to do this
for personal trust growth
minnesota
so you indiana
five state parks usually supplier
more than what opportunities
in the san diego tester
if they're going to come back to bombard
so that would be able to use it to u
and they don't start watch t_v_
the charge carbonate
the charge five dollars success is a mix
of the credit card systems
well pop up and say that it's not about
charter school
ceiling purposefully starbucks or
something like that that will
true the credit card companies
systems
why and stuff for a while
so that comes back
bookings burkhart
you know i've seen cards go
you know you wouldn't think forty
thousand dollars
you know regards
not seen it cheaper
disturbing abides obvious myself about
also a hundred thousand
amex cards
i myself think that
permafrost dollar not
not to worry are sold
actually watched in horror
to america and europe
three-d_ art
six to ten dollars
i think i think they have
well
this izzy
usr card
used car
reinforcing
uh... budget deal to research it
representative michael
uh... still able to do is
its credit for having there
left the will inspire
he for
they don't have to be talking about
look at these numbers
one six dollars icici after a copy of
it all
breitbart
on the black market dyson
is about reno
weehawken
located
it's not ok
doesn't improve
falls
the community
and hopefully we see now
isn't over
reaches
uh... elapsed
brought this this aren't
solidworks
subtler reaches eyeliner
last per ninety two percent of all
bridges between secret service
agency
ninety percent of survivor archives
uh... people
and
ninety six percent
heavy xia
and
it is
are state
cannot be stopped
ppc a complaint the eggplant we doubled
that they take that money
uh... unit
sedan
it doesn't matter of their time
it's costing business success
japanese company others bringing in
millions of dollars a day
there are some of them
i'd say that right now we'll look at it
italy one god
slots are trying to show complaints
you know that
we're trying to cut pieces yet seen
don't matter
quizzes it often
yahoo track
so
pci-x restructuring because
reply capitol park process progresses as
talk to each other
so if you're not quite
they will slap you on the wrist
you'll move up to laura automatic on
it's interesting developments dot
what they did people
and would stay
people senators and i wouldn't worry
about p_c_r_ it's done
what for comes to you
they said and they did this to a doctor
a surgeon's office
uh... surgery center
the lined up
is seven a a bill so you owe us fifty
thousand dollars because you've got
virginia dot blot
well the doctors goes right behind it
states that have not settled back in a
bit
so one of the car processor to
jacked up the process of rates to six
percent
within two days think sectors of the
work
you betcha
tickets cost of business was way cheaper
than it
that day six percent
every project
regularly for the people of all of these
whatever reason here why don't we do is
was that
phytophthora
it's wonderful
in
so yesterday
and
stuff past
uh... yeah but we could meet at a local
stuff to do that
you know that i'm
are d
thirteen reaches intake
this chapter in alamo that's the
you've got stuff
mary pat rita
information
ironies is dumb things
so i hope that you can take that
worth more than ninety three to two
thousand level
decrease action
deducted
twenty million
and of course explodes
and things like that
important temperatures just this year
seed that uh...
that's your seat belts on
you can see that the other disrupting
the whole time
of looking up
north here
students today
two people focus on the outside and
people focus just on the outside had to
go back out
alerts
pastors and questioned two years ago
and with the f_b_i_ navarro as to the
next day abhar
he
trees will be completely secure
passion
activity from someone
and see what's up
most people think of all he could back
up now
where the backpack
polis
the act we get to know asap
today sets
it's seventy four percent
insiders stealing information are trying
to take some of the crash
might take a break from the hard part of
the worst case is that right
and uh... i said
peru
ethnic groups
there room for one office to another
they got all the lines of at new farm
all saturday
willing i would make for a long i
is financial
went on vacation that week it
is replaced by t
footed informal
let the fifty people relevance
less than twenty minutes after they put
their hectic pia
it was sort of a base off
by four hours
they couldn't figure out a lot of it
with his style
vintage
you know the excel dot there's a lot of
people are coming on
the necessary but often monday morning