a couple years ago i
had a laptop that vga and it was always
fun trying to get that to work
all right um so i'm going to talk about
auditing
web-based or browser-based
password generators just a little bit of
a warning
i have some explicit slides i'm using
memes from ethan birds
so if you decide that vulgarity or
profanity
is not for you i will not be offended if
you decide to leave that's perfectly
okay
otherwise be prepared for my god damned
slides
uh first a little bit of background
i work for x mission it's a local isp
out of salt lake city
and about five or six seven years ago we
hired a junior web developer fresh out
of high school
and he was highly inexperienced i mean
coming out of high school i guess it's
not too surprising
but he was also kind of cocky and his
first task was to develop a password
generator for our customers
we have a control panel where they can
manage their account
including changing their password we
wanted to provide a
password generator
in the web-based control panel and so
that was his first task so he was asked
to work with me
i have a background
in mathematics and cryptography
as well as security
so we were working on banging this out
and getting this
working
and unfortunately he wasn't listening to
the math i don't know what his
mathematics background was but i have a
degree in mathematics it's kind of my
passion and he wasn't
trusting it he wasn't trusting it the
math was holding up
and he trusted his intuition more so we
ended up banging heads and locking horns
during this project
regardless though we still ended up with
a decent result and this is a screenshot
if you go to xmission.com generator you
can play around with it
but you're presented with 15 random
words you have to select at least three
and then you just click generate and
every time you click generate a new
password pops up beneath the one above
it
and it also will
separate those three words or more if
you choose more
with numbers and special characters
from the technical side of things
the words are coming from a word list of
11 121 words
and they're shuffled
and then we give you say the top 15 out
of that shuffle that means there won't
be any duplicates right in the the
presentation of the 15 words
you have to collect select at least
three you can select four more if you
want
and like i mentioned the words are
separated by digits and
special characters punctuation symbols
for everyone column i'm only choosing 24
of them rather than the full set
two digits have to be at least present
in the result we require at least two
numbers
so from the lowest security margin
if the user only selects three passwords
and the separated characters are all
digits we have four digits then i can
find out what the security margin is
using the log base 2 function so i can
take the log base 2 of 11 121 times it
by 3 for the three words log base 2 of
10 times it by 4 and i get about 53 bits
of security
so the question is is 53 bits of
security enough
is this giving me the necessary security
for my customers
if you go to that url and i only created
it for the slides i'm not interested in
tracking your clicks
so if someone wants to share the result
with the rest of the class that's
perfectly fine but if you go to
tinyurl.com
gtx 1080
this is a github gist basically a large
paste
of a hash cache benchmark from
professional password cracker
jeremy ghazni
and he's got eight nvidia gtx 1080 gpus
that he's benchmarking with hashcat
the fastest hash in his result is ntlm
no surprise
and those eight gpus in concert can work
through 513 gigahashes
or
513.1 billion
ntlm hashes per second
okay
so if my passwords were hashed with ntlm
at xmission
uh what would those 53 bits of security
provide my customers
well 513 billion hashes per second is
effectively exhausting the key space of
38.9 bits of security every second and i
broke it down you can see it by second
minute hour day up to about 63.8 bits
per year now i'm assuming in this case
that he's not blindly attacking the ntlm
password hash that he has a copy of the
11 000 words
he knows about the number and the
character space separation so he's got
an accurate hash cash
hash cat mask
for attacking these hashes okay he's not
going at it blindly
so it would only take him about five
hours to completely guess every possible
combination of passwords that can be
generated with this scheme
five hours is not great
however
yes i forgot the slide so this is to my
co-worker you should stay in school and
remind me why i shouldn't just ignore
your
however xmission doesn't use ntlm we
don't use ntlm to hash our passwords we
use sha 512 crypt and maybe pete doesn't
appreciate me sharing that with you
but we use shaw five shelf crypt with
the default five thousand rounds cost
using that same github gist that jeremy
gasney
provided with his eight gpus
that same benchmark can only work
through
about eighteen hundred eighteen fifty
kilohashes or one point eight
five million hashes
of sha-512 crypts per second which is a
far cry from the 513 billion ntlm we saw
earlier okay
so with the same setup then
he can only exhaust a full key space
again using the correct
hash cap mask he can only exhaust
48.5 bits per year to get up to that
53-bit
benchmark it would actually take him a
full 32 years to exhaust the key space
so
fair enough
i will give credit where credit is due
it turns out that what we have for our
customers
is
a decent result it holds up okay
that got me thinking
here we are working on this project for
x mission
what would i do for a personal project
if i were to design
my own password generator
and i would take my own advice that i
was giving the junior developer when we
were designing x missions
what would mine look like okay what
would my result look like
so initially i knew what i wanted i
wanted a reasonable default security
margin clearly defined okay that was
that was very important to me as a
mathematician
the second i wanted something clean i
wanted something clutter free i didn't
want a lot of switches didn't want a lot
of options i didn't want to confuse
people with the ui which also meant that
i wanted a pleasant user experience i
don't want
to frustrate them and trying to generate
a password
and i came up with some other ideas
obviously i'm going to choose
passphrases so i probably want to
support multiple languages besides just
english can i do that
um is there a way to do
visual versus audible unambiguity in
other words when i present a password
visually is it visually distinct so
there's no confusion as to what each
character is but further what if i was
in a noisy data center and i had to
communicate that password to another
system
administrator can it be verbally
distinct as well so he's not confused
that it could be another word or another
character so these are ideas that are
working through my head
and also different memorability
approaches can i
present the password in such
a way that it's easy to recall later
right
so it's time for me to do some market
research
so the first thing is i did a duckduckgo
search for secure password generator
and the first result is passwords plural
passwordsgenerator.net
and this is a screenshot of that webpage
this is exactly what i don't
want there's a lot of check boxes
there's a lot of text
there's quite a few buttons it just is a
little overwhelming to me the text kind
of blurs together and i just see this
big wall of text i'm not really
interested or motivated to read
everything but one thing did catch my
eye
halfway down those check boxes that very
bottom blue check mark
says generate on your own device
otherwise do not send it across the
internet
so this generator can either generate
the password on the server
and send it to your browser
or you could generate it locally in the
browser make the server ignorant of what
you're doing
why would i want the server to generate
the password for me and send it why
why would i want that so this is
something i didn't consider
when i began doing
you know some research into this
let's look at a few others some heavy
hitters like lastpass lastpass has a
web-based password generator maybe some
of you use lastpass
this is their ui it's a lot more clean
less cluttered
the the password is prominent
fewer check marks
um if i go back to the previous i don't
know if you can see right at the top the
default password length is 16. however
here the default password length for
lastpass is 12.
so
which is better is the 16 characters
better or is the 12 characters better
they're all using uppercase lowercase
numbers and symbols so why did lastpass
go with 12 when this other
developer is going with 16.
there is one password even more clean
and what i like about this is they are
color coding certain characters
digits the numbers 0 through 9 are blue
and if i had added symbols those would
be red
so visually
it becomes very clear to me that oh this
is a zero and not an o
this is an l and not a one because the
one would be blue
right so visually i can look at that and
know immediately what each character is
i kind of like that their default
password length however is 20
without symbols
so is that something worth considering
here's bit warden another heavy hitter
in the password manager space they have
a web-based password generator
i'm not a fan of their ui as much as one
passwords or lastpasses it's a little
maybe a little cluttered a little
spacious
but they copied the same idea color
coding their digits as well as their
special characters their default length
is 14 characters
and then one more that came across my
radar which i
kind of thought was kind of funny is
dino pass
a password generator for kids
now
why do kids get a different password
generator than adults
like
maybe the adult password generator could
be profane and we don't want to put that
in front of our kids i don't know
the dyno pass just generates two random
words in this case fuzzy and error and
then appends two digits at the end and
that's the entirety of the password they
have another button for generating a
strong password
and that will randomize
one of the words first character getting
capitalized
and then another character getting
replaced with a visually
similar
symbol like for example
an s could be a five or a t could be a
plus sign something like that
so in terms of all these password
generators on the web security is
defined in a number of different ways
we've got length anywhere from 12 to 20
characters
complexity
numbers uppercase lowercase digits
punctuation
bit warden and
1password also provide passphrase
generators
so is the security the same for the
passphrase generator as it is for the
password
then we also have audience which is
something i hadn't considered until i
stumbled on dyno pass
if a dino pass password is not secure
for an adult why would it be secure for
a child that's an interesting question
so
as the bird says i am in no mood for
this today
so let's see if we can't make an attempt
at a formal definition okay i am doing
market research again the whole
motivation is for me to design my own i
don't like
biting heads with my coworkers and
coming up with something
that i don't agree with 100 percent
right
so let's see if i can't make a formal
definition before i start designing my
own password generator
so that means i'm going to start jumping
into a slew of other generators and
start auditing source code and learning
from other people i want to see what
they're doing so i'm going to be looking
at their code and things stuck out
immediately and we're going to look at
some examples here
we see uses of an insecure versus a
secure random number generator when
generating the password we also see
whether or not that generator is being
used uniformly
or in a biased approach
so let's look at
four code examples and these all come
from
password generators that i audited web
based password generators these are all
javascript copy pasted right into the
slides
so here's an example of a generator
that's using an insecure random number
generator and they're doing so not
uniformly
so
if you don't read source code that's
okay i'm going to walk you through it
it's not too painful
so we have this variable e that we're
adding all of our uppercase characters
to and then we're also appending the
lowercase characters the digits
and then some special characters the
length of that string e ends up becoming
85 characters in length okay so we have
an 85 character long
variable e
then i've got two for loops
the outer for loop is actually
generating a number of passwords that i
request
if i say give me 10 passwords that's
what this outer for loop is doing it'll
say all right here's your first one
here's your second all the way through
your 10th
the inner for loop is actually
constructing each individual password
it's building the password itself
um before moving out to the next the
next one
and then
which is interesting is this generator
was putting everything in a text area
and so they're appending the carriage
return and the new line at the end of
the password
so in the text area each password that
you request
is one right after the other rather than
all in one long string line okay
so why is it insecure and why is it
biased well first off it's insecure
because it's using math.random
math.random is not a cryptographically
secure random number generator and when
we're generating secrets in this case
passwords
for authentication websites
we want them to be indistinguishable
from true random
white noise data and that's what
cryptographically secure random number
generators provide for me
math.random is not that so if i observe
enough of math.random's output i can
predict
all future output
so for a password generator this is not
a good idea
second math.random is actually a 32-bit
random number generator and it turns out
that 85 does not divide
2 to the 32 evenly there's a remainder
in this case a remainder of 1.
so that means that not everything is
going to get treated equally
if i were to generate 0 through 84
i would get zero
one more time than i would 1 through 84
as i'm working all the way up to 2 to
the 32nd power okay
when i'm doing mod
85 arithmetic so in this generator
specific case that uppercase a is going
to get favored more
than the rest of the characters in the
password now it's it's it's favored by
one i'll admit that and when you're
generating billions of passwords
i mean the law of averages shows that is
this really that big of a concern
when it comes to cryptography and
security yes actually it is everything
needs to be as uniform as possible we
should not be able to give any adversary
an advantage in being able to predict
or make guesses at what the output is
going to be
so we don't like this and they're doing
that i'm going to go back a slide if you
look at the code right in the center m
plus equals e dot car at they're doing
math.floor of math.random times the
length math.random gives you a random
number between zero and one not
excluding one okay
and because it's a 32-bit random number
generator that means there's 2 to the 32
possible decimal values between
including 0 and 1 exclusively
so when i times it by 85 i could get
27.639
something
so we take the floor of that even though
it's 27.6 we don't round up
we take the floor and i get 27 and then
i say give me the character at
27th position in e okay so this
what's called the multiply and floor
method
is a biased way
of picking random data
okay let's look at an insecure but
uniform
approach
this comes from one where the guy was
using your mouse as a source of entropy
you would wiggle your mouse across the
screen a little bar would grow and grow
and grow until it's green and then you
can click generate and generate your
password
so as this function get random number
that max variable is how many characters
are in our string so previously it would
have been 85
and then we have this variable bits
needed
and
he's determining how many bits
need
to store that number so in the case of
85 let's use that as an example
um
six bits can get me up to
63 right zero to 63. i can represent 64
possible values with six bits
seven bits though i can represent 128
values
so for if max was 85
then bits needed would be seven i need
seven bits to represent all 85 possible
values right
so now we're going to go ahead and get
one bit at a time with this little
function called get random bit and we're
going to expand that bit by multiplying
it by two
and then adding the new bit on the end
okay it's very simple
math in this regard
where it becomes uniform
is if that random number is greater than
or equal to the max value in this case
85 if the result comes out as 86 or 87
then we discard it
and we try again
so we're only going to allow
values that come between 0 and 84 as
valid
so that's where we're getting our
uniform
but what's unfortunate about this is
even though he's using it uniformly
and you would think using mouse movement
as entropy would be secure
we can get into the details of this
after the talk if you want but physical
sources of randomness need to be
whitened or decorrelated before they're
put in use they need to be
de-biased it's unfortunate but physical
sources of randomness have a tendency to
skew one way or the other it's just the
way nature kind of behaves
so we need to remove that skewing and
we could do that with a simple hash we
could hash it with sha-256 that would
certainly be appropriate
john von neumann the computer scientist
of the 50s invented an algorithm
where you can remove bias out of unfair
coin tosses called the von neumann
debiasin algorithm we could apply that
he's doing it one bit at a time that
would certainly be appropriate
but there are different approaches
just so long as we de-bias that true
input so if we had had decorrelated the
mouse movement and then applied it it
would have been secure
there's another piece of code this is a
secure random number generator but doing
so biasedly oh that's a word not
uniformly
so he's using the web crypto api and
right there in the top we have this
function o
and we're setting us a variable c to
either be window.crypto or
window.mscrypto before microsoft
brought chromium into the edge browser
and they were using their own engine i
think it was chakra
maybe don't quote me on that
an internet x411 and earlier they had
their own version of the web crypto api
via the window.mscrypto object
so
we're ensuring we catch everybody either
firefox chrome browsers or
early microsoft uh with that variable
and then we're creating a 32-bit
unsigned integer array and we're
assigning just one space for it
and then we're using the get random
values function which is
cryptographically secure because it's
coming from that web crypto api to
populate it
and then we're returning it divided by 2
to the 32 so i want a number between 0
and 1. so it's kind of behaving like
math.random in that regard instead of
giving me a number like 15 612
i'm getting
0.416 or whatever
and then there's my variable t with my
characters
and then finally in that for loop
towards the bottom of the slide we can
see that he's using again the multiply
and floor method
he's doing math.floor of
my cryptographically secure function
which returns a random number
times the length of t
in this specific case he is using crypto
dot get random values that's
cryptographically secure that's good
but he's using the multiply and floor
method which is a biased approach
just like earlier 90 does not divide 2
to the 32 evenly
in fact there are 76 remainders
so we end up with
well in this case because of the 90 the
length of our string
we end up with those outputs being
favored
over everybody else again
observing the output i can see
we have some favored characters in my
password versus some unfavored
characters we don't want this
final example here is a secure and
uniform example this is the golden
standard this is what we're chasing
after this is what we want
so again we are we have this function
called uniform n
is the number of characters in my string
or a max number if you will like give me
a number between 0 and n
uh then we're instantiating a new 32-bit
unsigned integer array in the variable a
and then
and we're forcing it to be a 32-bit
number so that's kind of some javascript
uh bit manipulation fun
but if n was larger than 2 to the 32
this would force it into that space okay
and then we have this do while loop and
i'm saying
give me a random number and populate it
in my array
so long as it's less than m so what is m
m is a minimum value and if you were to
run that code in your browser
it would be the same as taking uh 2 to
the 32 mod n
we're looking for a remainder and then
we're setting that as my lowest value
okay
so what i'm ensuring then if i come to
my next slide
is that m
to 2 to the 32
will always get evenly divided by n
there will be no remainders and will
always divide that range perfectly
evenly so i'm not going to have any
biased output i'm not going to have any
favored
numbers any favored characters
and it doesn't matter what n is and can
be completely variable we will always
get uniform output
so in the case of this example this was
building a diceware passphrase
dicework contains 7776
unique words
so n is 7776.
when i apply that math there on the
third line or the fourth line m equals
negative n
it shifts to the right
zero mod n i end up with 2560. so this
becomes my minimum value so when i'm
generating random numbers
they have to be between 2560 and 2 to
the 32
minus 1.
otherwise i have to regenerate
but if it falls within that range i know
it'll divide
7776 evenly i can go ahead and take that
result mod 7776
and i will get a uniform output and
what's great about this is you would
think with that minimum
with those 2560 numbers that we're
rejecting
that's kind of going to hang up the
generator right like
how many times am i going to be
rejecting numbers because they didn't
fall within that range
well 2560 is
0.00006 percent
to the 32 so
effectively it's not going to happen
you're not going to notice it
all right
so that was just looking at
cryptographically secure versus insecure
generators and whether or not it's
uniform
but i began noticing in the audit
seeing and from my early market research
that there are generators that want to
generate it on the server
and then send it to me over https over a
tls connection instead of doing it in
the client
it usually forces a browser refresh or a
new post to the server
but the server is doing the generation
not the browser
and
i can't audit that i can't look at the
source code that's running on the server
unless it's open source and on a github
repo or somewhere else
i can't look at that source code i can't
see what random number generator it's
using
and i can't see if it's using it
uniformly right so it's completely
unknown to me it's a black box i don't
know how the randomness is being handled
i was also came across
password generators that would do
deterministic generation
deterministically generate your password
this is usually built from a master
password you would come up with
something in your head
you know maybe like your mother's maiden
name or something
and then you would also supply like a
username or an email address or a domain
something
and you would put these together in a
form field and click generate my
password
and it gets hashed with a hashing
function and then spits out the result
and as long as you provide the same
parameters you'll always get the same
output
um
i have some issues with
deterministic generators though first
off they can't accommodate different
password policies without keeping state
i don't know how many of you guys are
fans of bruce snyder the security expert
i follow his blog recently he blogged
frustration
where his password manager generated a
password for him for a site
and he went to supply it and the site
rejected it because it did not contain
two numbers
it only had one
and so he was frustrated with password
policies that are seem ambiguous and
arbitrary
you can't do
pastor apology pastor paul
you cannot accommodate different
password policies with deterministic
generators without keeping state if it
doesn't provide the policy you'll need a
counter or you'll need to be able to
fiddle with your username or change the
domain in some way so it gives you a
different output that does match that
policy but then you have to remember the
state the next time you need to
regenerate it in the future
you can't handle uh
breached passwords
have i been pwned as a thing
passwords getting stored in plain text
is a thing getting password cracked is a
thing
if you get an alert from google that
your password has been breached
and you're using a deterministic
generator
you need some sort of counter some sort
of state to change that password right
you need some
variable in order to give you a new
password
you can't do that without keeping state
and further and i think the worst fatal
flaw
is if the master password is exposed
and the adversary is aware of your
system for generating passwords then all
of your prior passwords are now breached
he doesn't even need knowledge of what
they are because he has the core secret
which is your master password
so these are these are some concerns of
mine at least with deterministic
password generators
but further
most people will deterministically use
fast
hashing functions like md5 or sha-1 or
sha-2
when in reality they probably should be
using slow hashing functions like
password-based key derivation functions
the reason is let's assume
that the adversary does know
my system but doesn't know my master
password he knows the approach i use
he's just trying to figure out my master
pass we're trying to figure out my
secret
if
the generator is using md5 then he can
work through those guesses quickly
but if the generator is using something
like pb kdf2
or s-crypt or argon 2 these are things
that are designed deliberately to be
slow with cost factors then we can slow
down that brute force attack we can
prevent
the adversary from being effective
without
spending more money
distributing his workload
that sort of thing
um and i should this is a little nitpick
that i put in the the final
bullet point on the slide
key derivation functions are more
appropriate in this specific use case
than password hashing functions there's
a subtle difference
password hashing functions give you a
static output like bcrypt
or shaw 512 crypt like we use at x
mission
um sha-512 crypt gives you 512 bits of
output and that's just static and that's
how it is but with key derivation
functions i can say i want 160 bits or
256 bits or 512 i can be completely
variable how much data i want returned
from the function
so
in the case of a deterministic password
generator we don't need a lot of bits
we're only generating what 12 16
character password strings we don't need
these massively large things so i can
restrict this down to
70 bits 80 bits 90 bits of output
rather than taking 512 and then
truncating them
all right
what about security margins talked a
little bit about that earlier if i go
back to that cluster of eight nvidia
gpus that jeremy ghazni has
can i make reasonable assumptions about
bit strength
i think i can
so
remember i'm trying to make a password
generator
that is not
messy it's clean in the ui and it's easy
to understand for the lay person i don't
want to confuse them
so when it comes to bits that is maybe a
necessary evil but i don't want to go 55
56 57 58 i think every five bits is
perfectly fine for the lay person
so
in terms of that ntlm
hashing password hashing
55 bits is exhausted
in 20 hours
so i think anything less than a day will
probably be considered broken
60 bits gets us 26 days it's a month
i consider that a week because it only
takes a couple people to decide to join
in and help
that can significantly lower that time
but as we move every five bits we can
see that full exhaustion of that key
space gets exponentially longer 65 bits
is that three years
70 bits is at 73 years and so forth
so
i decided and i am completely open to
debate on this
that
because 60 bits might take a little bit
of work takes a month on an individual
person or to get a team together to
lower that threshold we could consider
that weak 65 bits moderate because it
would take more of a distributed
clustered attack to really bring that
within a workable manner
but i think 70 bits and above in terms
of password security we could consider
strong that's certainly a good market
or a good point to reach for
so here's just a quick table i'm going
to go through this quickly
but in the columns i have the unique
characters in each set so 10 characters
would be my digits 26 would be the
alphabet 52 be lowercase uppercase
94 would be every graphical ascii
character on my keyboard and then the
rows are my bit strings
so how many characters would i need in
my password
based on the characters in the set and
the bit strength so for 94 characters if
i wanted to hit 70 bits of security i
would need at least an 11 character
password okay randomly generated
what's interesting about this table
however is how many sites do you see
when you're creating a new account that
they say your password must be at least
eight characters
right and that means
as we are well aware everyone will
create
an eight character password
they won't go longer if they don't have
to
but do you see eight anywhere on that
table
right we already considered 55 bits
broken
and if it's using all 94 graphical ascii
characters
on my keyboard
i need at least nine to get to 55 bits
eight's not even on the radar
so it would be great if any of you are
web developers this is just a cry
if any of you are out there it'd be
great to see us maybe bump that up to 10
or 11 or 12 as a minimum because you
know the users are going to pick that
you say 12 they're doing 12. they're not
going to do 13 if they don't have to
but if they are using their password
generator in their manager or somewhere
else
then we know what that security looks
like right and we know what it looks
like for eight characters
same thing with passphrase security
here's a number of unique words in a set
versus my bits
notice at 55 bits for 16 384 unique
words i can get four words how many are
familiar with the xkcd comic of correct
horse battery stable right generate four
random words good enough
that's fine
but four is 55 bits of security if your
word list has 16 384 unique words and it
was generated uniformly and securely but
we already decided that 55 is broken
so xkcd random monroe kind of hit the
right tone in terms of memorability
but the execution was sloppy four random
words just
isn't enough right we need to move
across that
so to recap really quickly
we started late i'm going to run a
little bit late i apologize to the next
presenter
but i'm moving fast
a secure password generator then can be
defined as being generated in the client
not on the server
if it is deterministic it's using a
proper key derivation function with a
cost factor
if it's random it's using a
cryptographically secure number
generator uniformly and we're defaulting
to at least 70 bits of security all
right
yes i'm completely judging you
so
let's go further are there any other
security concerns we can take about
that's all the math right that's all the
big
rocks what about some of the littler
rocks well i think it should be obvious
the page needs to be delivered over tls
plain http
opens up the user to injection attacks
what's to prevent
a man in the middle from compromising
the entire security of the password
generator system
ads and javascript trackers in the web
page also compromise the secrecy of the
password generation process
right these things are trying to track
you across the web they're trying to
build profiles of who you are
so
if these exist in the password generator
it may already know details about who
you are the
social accounts you have
you know and here we are now generating
a password on this password generator
um it just shouldn't be something that
they need to know
sub resource integrity is a standard by
the w3c
where it guarantees that if you're
calling a resource from a third-party
server
externally on the internet
that when it gets delivered it gets
delivered as you expect
and so there's this integrity
attribute in either an image tag a link
tag or a script tag
with
a integrity hash either shot 256 sha-384
or sha-512
and when that resource comes off of that
third-party server like the image the
browser then can quickly hash the image
and see if it matches what's in the html
if it does we're good to go if not the
browser will complain and not give you
the requested resource
usability concerns do we have a mobile
interface
right mobile is a thing now
it should be no surprise that we should
have mobile interfaces on our web pages
is the source code open source right
people like me who are auditing these
password generators and see legitimate
flaws
can patch it up and send patches to the
developer but if it's not open source if
i'm restricted my ability to use the
software i can't make those improvements
is there anything else worth noting
comments like is it stable does it
perform well okay
so this is a lot to audit so i decided
to do a simple scoring system out of 10
and i gave you one point for each of
those items you get a point if it's open
source get a point if it's generated in
the client a point if it's random not
deterministic
if it's using a cryptographically
secured number generator uniformly https
mobile interface no trackers
and we're using or not requiring sri
that's 9 out of the 10 for the 10th
point i look at the security margin
if it's less than 55 bits no points
but if it's between 55 and 69 i give you
half a point and if you reach that
70-bit security margin or better i give
you a full point and this is by default
i should mention i'm not deliberately
trying to make your generator weak just
saying what is delivered to the user so
when you click generate without mucking
with anything
what do we get
so that left me now with what to audit
so i started just searching and we've
got passwords passphrases
chrome extensions firefox extensions and
bookmarklets and i'm going to pick on a
couple people
i hope he's not watching
taylor hornby some of you may know him
as defusek on twitter security
researcher well known
has a windows password generator you can
go to that website defuse.capacion.htm
and download the windows generator
but on that page he also has up in the
header a big web-based password
generator and here's a screenshot of it
just want a password copy and paste
these or refresh the page to generate a
new set
so let's hold taylor's taylor up to
those security standards that we just
defined okay
if we're auditing his web-based
generator he scores seven out of ten
this is what he does well it's random
not deterministic he's using a
cryptographically secure random number
january i'll talk about more than a
second
he's doing it uniformly over https the
default security margin is 256 bits
which in my opinion is overkill but
that's fine point
there's no ads or javascript trackers
and he doesn't use or need sub resource
integrity but where he could improve is
even though the web
source code is on github he doesn't have
an explicit license to find now i don't
know about canada copyright law but in
united states if you don't explicitly
define a license
then it is copyright you all rights
reserved it's not open source it is
proprietary
so
until a license is there unfortunately
it's proprietary software
also it's php it's not javascript so
this is being done on the server and
he's sending it to you through https
and then finally he's missing a mobile
mobile interface
let's look at bit warden i mentioned
that let's pick one of the heavier
hitters bit warden in this case i'm
showing off the passphrase generator
interestingly enough
their passphrase generator is weaker
than their password generator by default
well look at that
they also get a 7 out of 10.
they do well it's generated in the
client not the server it's random not
deterministic they're using a
cryptographically secure random number
generator
uniformly https they have a mobile
interface and they don't need sub
resource integrity
where they can improve their web
source code is nowhere to be found which
is weird because the android the ios
clients and the desktop clients and
everything else is on github except for
their password generator that the source
code just doesn't exist
other than getting delivered to your
browser
also the default security for the pass
phrases is 51 bits but for the past
words it's 83. so for the password
generator he scores 8 out of 10
but for the past phrase we get 7 out of
10.
and then finally it does have javascript
trackers i would have expected better
out of bit warden but they do have that
on the website
so now we come back to my generator and
this is a screenshot kind of a bad one
if you go to my url a7.stashg
a7st is my
amateur radio call sign
so i just bought the dot st
domain slash g for generator but this is
what i ended up coming with
the default there's my security margins
on the top
and then i have a bunch of different
generators all of them meeting that
security margin that you select it
defaults to 70. and all you have to do
is click generate copy and paste it and
you're good to go
so how do i do
probably not very fair
i am the guy who's doing the auditing
right i am the guy who's defining the
standard
but i guess that's just how the cookie
crumbles
but i did score a perfect uh 10 out of
10 but i did design
my generator after the standard rather
than dividing the fighting standard
after the generator so i can be honest
about that
um all right the current audit status
i'll show a quick screenshot i've
currently audited 209 password
generators 89 passphrase 114 chrome
extensions 36 firefox extensions and 20
bookmarklets
you can go to that tiny url it's a
google spreadsheet and see the status of
every single one of them their urls will
be there you can click on we'll play
around with them
tinyurl.com
generator audit
um
one quick note extension score seven out
of seven uh
and when you look at the audit you'll
see why
but here is a screenshot of the
passwords tab of the first part of the
audit anyway and you can see the score
on the left it's kind of small
perfect 10 out of 10's get our color
blue 9
green
8 through i think it's six or five are
yellow and then below that is red
and then on the right the green and the
red and the yellow you can see
uh how they scored right greens are a
point red or zero point
uh the yellows
might be a half point it depends and
then there's notes on the side
all right final topic i apologize for
running late to the next presenter
webex web applications are actually
super dangerous very very dangerous
why
so
even though my password generator that i
built
has a perfect 10 out of 10 and many
others do as well
you're all we're all trusting on the
web server to deliver that code
correctly
what is preventing a disgruntled web
administrator for sending javascript on
a page refresh that compromises the
entire stack
nothing right it could be a perfect 10
out of 10. everything's done great and
all it takes is one descriptive web
admin to say screw it
i want a log of all the passwords so i
am sending this javascript on the next
page refresh you don't know that unless
every time you refresh the page you're
inspecting the source code this is why
desktop apps
minimize that vulnerability because
they're strongly versioned they're
compiled until you update to the newest
version
you know
if you've audited it at least or trust
someone who has you know that what
you're using is what you expect okay
until you update again
um that's not the case with web apps
anytime you hit that f5
you get a new version you could get a
new version of the software so
despite doing everything perfectly
these web-based generators are still
vulnerable to this sort of attack all
right
and that is all i've got
so i went through it quickly and we
started late are there any comments
questions or rude remarks
nope all right thanks guys
[Applause]
you