all right i'm gonna go ahead and get
started
so
this is actually maybe a good talk to
follow collins um in the last talk colin
was talking about privacy and you
mentioned vpns fit really well under the
uh the privacy enthusiast model so we'll
talk a little bit about vpns
awesome
um
so
i'm kevin
i work at servicenow on the red team
and was that adobe on the red team for
five years and
i was in the intelligence community
before that
now i live in utah and work remotely and
i like to be outside with the kids so
hooray for that
um who knows what a vpn is
like
knows the
denotation knows what vpn means
yeah
i'll get to that in a minute
but uh yeah vpns are virtual private
networks who uses who uses a vpn
um for like tunneling their traffic
through their isp
or who uses it so they can watch netflix
in another geo
or who
who uses it who uses it for work so that
they can actually connect to a private
network
so that's how vpns you know got started
that was the original intention was you
have this private network and you're
you're physically separate from it and
so a vpn allows you to connect to a
private network over a public network
so the typical use case is to connect
one of your devices to a private network
or
connect and that's the case you know if
you have your laptop and you're working
at home and you need to be on the lan at
work that's how you're going to use the
vpn
another use case is to connect two
private networks together so you sort of
have two gateways that
tunnel traffic between two two
geographically separated networks to
make it look like they're on the same
private land
so that's kind of a typical use case for
a vpn
um as we talked about uh they're
becoming super popular for just
tunneling traffic um and so for whatever
reason privacy security anonymity you
can fire up a vpn on your laptop tunnel
all your traffic through it and then
um and then things are great
um also give you a source ip somewhere
else you can watch a british comedy
this talk is sponsored by all of these
vpns so that's what i was getting to if
you guys spend any time on youtube or
like
pay any attention to your favorite
influencer
vpn providers
get a lot of their
get a lot of their user base from
affiliate driven marketing so you see a
lot of that um
and there are countless options these
days you know there's vpn companies
everywhere
so um so this talk is kind of about vpns
but more specifically about wire guard
so wireguard is a specific
implementation of vpn technology
and uh talk a little bit more about the
technical details by the way like half
of this is going to be demos so i'm
going to kind of roll the dice here so
uh yeah be patient with me but i'm going
to get through slides and we'll do some
demos
so um so wireguard is an implementation
of vpn technology
at this point as of
i think last year it's integrated into
linux kernel it actually creates like a
network interface
and does all the things magically behind
the scenes there for you so that's great
and there's a speed advantage over
userland vpns because you're not
constantly copying data between the
kernel and user space
and although there are there are user
land implementations of wireguard and so
you know obviously windows isn't running
the linux kernel so there are
implementations you can use on windows
and darwin and
your mobile phones and everything so
so that's great
um and the other thing that's cool about
wireguard is it has a really small code
base i think i'll i'll talk a little bit
more about that later so oh and one
other thing uh all those vpns i put up
there earlier use wire guard
that's the technology behind all those
brands
um so some technology
specifics um those little bubbles on the
right
show kind of like the magnitude of the
code base of other vpn options so ipsec
specifically strong swan
is about 420 000 lines of code which is
insane like if any of if any of you have
ever done like code audits or
um application pen testing like you
don't you would not want to land on that
gig right
um so it's really hard to audit that
like there's all kinds of
all kinds of um
risk there right and then openvpn uh 120
000 lines of code and that's just
openvpn but like the
the crypto libraries openvpn uses uh are
just
which is another 400-ish thousand lines
of code and as a lot of you know it's
also uh like
getting pretty aged and there's a lot of
tech debt in there so these some
buzzwords cross that one off so um
so yeah those are massive projects right
and then that little dot in the bottom
is wire guarded it's like measly four
thousand lines of code really easy to
audit and just clean and and fresh
lemony fresh
so um another nice thing about wireguard
is it's cryptographically opinionated so
like a lot of these other technologies
let you use whatever algorithms and they
negotiate you know like a public key
algorithm and then they negotiate a
symmetric key and hashing algorithm and
they have all these things built in it's
just like this massive surface area
and so
what wireguard has done is they've said
we're going to use these industry
standards these industry favorites to
use cha-cha poly for like authenticated
cipher we use curve two five five one
nine for for any like asymmetric stuff
we need and blake two for
uh hashing and keyed hashing and then
hkdf for key derivation so we're using
these things and if you don't like these
then you're not going to like us that's
and that's a really really good way to
keep the complexity low
on the technology so that's really cool
they have this notion of cryptokey
routing so what you do when you set up
your configuration and you'll see this
in the demo is you take an ip address
and you have a public key associated
with that and anything that goes to that
ip address gets encrypted with that
public key
and then anything that
comes from that ip anything that comes
decryptable
decryptable anything that
anything that comes signed with that
public key should have come from an ip
address associated with it so anyway
so
it uses this notion of like pairing
uh cryptographic primitives and um and
tunnel ip addresses to sort of like
authenticate users as well as like
authenticate the data which is cool
and then i didn't mention this earlier
but it's implemented as a network
interface so it's kind of cool
and we're ready for our first demo just
like that
all right
so this is going to go really smooth i
can already tell
all right
so
um can you guys see this okay
this terminal
is that big enough
yeah
okay thank you vocal person in the
middle of the room
one more bigger why not
is that good
all right
uh i could never tell when someone's
being a heckler when they're just like
trying to be helpful you know
all right um and then
does that look good i'm just kidding
um
okay so what i'm gonna do is uh
here i'm connected to this
um server in aws
i'm gonna set up wireguard there as a
wireguard server you can just see
that process
i'm going to copy and paste because i i
seem brave but i'm not
so first i'm going to be root for
everything american people are angry
about that
and that's great
um
let me use tmux
and then
i'm going to install wireguard
have to install wireguard hooray ubuntu
now i have wirecard that's cool
okay
now some interesting things let's start
configuring it
so what i've done is i've created this
file
so there are two sections this file
there's an interface section and a peer
section you see that
so the interface this is my private key
you guys can have it i'm just going to
destroy all this very fast as soon as
i'm done so
this is the private key associated with
my wireguard server so
that has a public key and we'll see that
in a minute
the public key goes on the pier so the
peer can encrypt traffic to the server
i also tell it to listen on this port
that's the standard wireguard port so
if you're a network person you like
looking at pcapp
use your photographic memory
and then i'm going to set up a pier so
this is going to be my laptop
uh once i configure my laptop i'll be 10
10 10 2
um and
the public key associated with my laptop
is going to be this so this is just
32 bytes
on
a 32 byte integer on that
25519 curve so that's all that is super
simple like small key to move around
which is cool
okay
so we have a configuration file
now we're going to do some system
configuration
so
i'm just going to tell the kernel
hey anything that comes to you that's
not for you just go ahead and route that
through and then
this nat rule is just going to
not traffic in other words
it's going to act as a route on netting
router
okay
and now i'm going to add that wireguard
interface that we talked about using ip
route 2
and add the 10 10 10 1
ip address to it so
remember the client will be 10 10 10 2
and the server will be 10 10
1. um and now i'm going to associate
that config file with the interface
and
set the interface up
so if we do like iplink
iplink
here's that interface
cool and you can also use the the
wireguard utility wg show
and it'll say yep
this interface is associated with this
public key
i'm not going to show you that even
though i already did
and that's the port it's listening on
it's udp
and then sure enough the pier 10 10 10 2
with this public key is going to be my
laptop we'll configure that next i don't
know if you guys picked up on this
little easter egg but
you can actually make these vanity
public keys
so all you have to do
is uh solve the discrete logarithm
problem and then you can make any key
you want
i'm just kidding
you just generate private keys
and then
generate the public key from that and
you just forward generate those a
million times until you get the keys you
want so
so yeah if you solve the discrete
logarithm problem come find me we'll do
a talk
okay
then we're going to go to our client
i downloaded the client the wireguard
client on my laptop already
so it's just called wire guard and
unfortunately i can't make this bigger
so if it's hard to see i apologize
but you do add empty tunnel and you say
b sides
and paste
configuration in so this is the private
key on my laptop and that corresponds
with the public key in the peer section
on my server if that makes sense
and then i set my address to 10 10 10 2
and you can set a dns server
and then
my peer is going to be
the server in this case so if i go back
to that terminal
wg show
kl
tdup
matches the public key that's in my in
the peer section
and then i'm going to say allowed ips so
what the allowed ips section tells you
is
um if
if traffic comes to this interface with
this ip address send it to that peer if
that makes sense
um and so so what this zero zero zero
slash zero
tells you is that any traffic at all
will go through the vpn tunnel
great and then uh endpoint is that
server in aws i'm gonna go ahead and
save that
and i'm going to allow it to access my
vpn configurations
and activate
and first good sign is that that turned
green so i'm already happy happy man
and then if i go ahead and on my laptop
ping 10 10 1 that should be the server
sure enough
60 60 milliseconds is pretty good
and
check my public ip address and that's
not so good
so i'm not sure why that's not working
hey demo's over all right
um
yeah that's not
good um
did i turn off yeah i turned off proton
trust me it's easy
i'm not sure but i'm going to move on
so um
hopefully we fix it before the next one
because it builds on that
oh wait can't reach google because
wirecard
okay
cool so this is interesting technology
kevin thank you i agree
but how how interesting exactly is it
well there's this thing in linux called
network name spaces and it's it's um
separation in the kernel of different
network objects
um that's that's the idea and so when
you create a socket in one name space
it remains in that namespace even if you
move whatever has handles to it around
so that's a really interesting property
because
when you initialize your wireguard
interface
it creates
it creates your wire guard interface in
a specific name space which means it
builds that udp socket that it uses for
the tunnel and so if you move that
interface into a new namespace that
tunnel socket stays behind so that's
really interesting
some of you who like deal with this
technology are probably already know
where i'm going with this but in docker
one of the ways docker does isolation is
with these kernel name spaces
does process mount ipc and username
spacing but also network name spacing
and so
what you can do is you can create a
docker container and then you can
create a wireguard interface in the host
like the init namespace
and configure it there and everything
and then move it into the docker
container's namespace
and now that docker container has a
wireguard interface that can talk to the
internet um
magically without having any wireguard
software or anything specifically
installed on on the docker container so
that's my next demo it's way more
complex than that other one so hopefully
it goes okay
what we're going to do i still have this
laptop terminal on the left and i have
this
server terminal on the right
and i'm going to
[Music]
create a new tmux session there
okay so um
first thing i'm going to do is
going to
run a new docker container i'll explain
this docker command
so what this does is
docker run starts a new container rm
says delete this container when i'm done
i don't i don't can be ephemeral it says
uh give me this interactive prompt
um
this interactive tty
and then network none says don't attach
me to any networks so all i want is a
loopback interface
and then i just called it secret because
you know
and then i'm running it in just vanilla
alpine so there's nothing special about
this container so if we do iplink
iplink
link
you see all we have is the loopback
interface
so that's cool so what we're going to do
is we're going to go ahead and build a
new wireguard interface
move it into this container
um
so to do that
i'm going to create a new config file
just like we did previously
[Music]
and
it looks very similar so you have a
private key
this time we don't have a listening port
but that's okay
and then uh public key this is the
server's public key and i'm gonna send
all traffic to it and that's the
server's ip address so pretty
straightforward configuration
now i'm going to do some setup that's
going to make working with namespaces a
little easier
so
pay no attention to
that
just creating some sim links in bar run
net name space directory
okay
so
here we go we're going to create
this new
interface
wg1 and we're going to put it in the
container's namespace
so
container is a secret i could call it
called it earlier
okay
and then we're going to
just paste all these we're running short
on time
in that namespace i'm going to add 10 10
10 3 to this containers
interface
and then i'm going to set the
configuration file
that we just created we associate that
and then i'm gonna put the
put the interface up and then i'm gonna
make wg1
the default route for that container's
namespace
so
um
so try not to freak out but i'm gonna
show you something cool
so now if we go back in our container
and we do ipadder
there's a magical interface in here
which is that wireguard interface that
we created in the the init namespace and
moved into the container's namespace um
so that's pretty cool and if we do
iprout um
all traffic except for uh 101010 traffic
is going to go through wg-1 just so
happens that's the subnet associated
with that interface and so that's going
to go through the tunnel also so
any traffic to or from this container
can only traverse that tunnel that's the
implication it's pretty cool
all right um now back on the server um
we have a new pier which is this
container so
we go ahead and add that to
its configuration file
so now the server looks like this you
have two peers my laptop and the
container and then its own interface
configuration section
and we're just going to sync that
configuration
now
do wg show on the server
two piers um this one is from the
container and it hasn't had a handshake
yet hasn't been hasn't been contacted by
the container
um and then i showed you this but if we
look in the namespace of the container
um that's that's the configuration
and now i'm just gonna run tcp dump
well my demo hopefully doesn't fail
so
if we're we're in the container now
which is again this container is running
in docker on us on an ubuntu server in
the amazon cloud my laptop's here at
b-sides so if i ping 10-10-10-2 which is
my laptop i can't reach it which is
fantastic oh wait
i disconnected
from wire yards okay
still can't dang it
all right so on my laptop i can ping the
server can i ping the container
i can't i
cannot let's see if we can diagnose that
so here's tcp dump and we see from two
two is pinging to three
and three is responding to two
so
i have no idea why it's not working i'm
gonna be totally honest with you but
um i am on the wi-fi here
i think he might have saved me well but
it's weird though because i can i can
ping
the server right
oh that's interesting
i'm gonna go with that yeah it's the
network guys demo solid it's the network
i don't know
all right thank you thank you for that
brave audience member
okay
oh yeah
see it's blocking my slides
ah man network guys
it's the worst
okay
so um
there are also some bonus tricks i
showed you the vanity public keys um
so my initials were at the beginning of
all the public keys that you saw up
there
um so that's cool hooray for that and
then but
another side note is you know that's
just a 64 byte string
no
64 bytes no i don't think that's right
uh it's just a string of bytes right so
you can make that it doesn't have to be
like some ascii it could be
it could be
binary data so what you could do is you
could use that for good you could use
you could make the first four bytes like
the same as your ipv4 address which
actually be pretty cool where our guard
wouldn't enforce that like that ip and
uh and and public key are the same match
in that way but it would be cool to put
software on top of it that does that um
the crypto key routing is also similar
to that but anyway this is a cool idea
um that's it you guys have questions
is the network the network's just
i do yeah i could probably try that uh
we're out of time though
[Laughter]
cool well thank you guys
[Applause]