so i made a commitment for this
presentation there's not a single slide
so as you can see by the very
professional um presentation wireshark
is fun
and i think it is uh i live and die by
the peak app it's my favorite thing ever
um i'm actually going to move this mic
to the other side if that's cool
now that you all adjusted the cameras
you're like dang it sean
there we go
okay cool so one thing that i always i
always thought with wireshark and i've
lived by it is the the devils and the
details the devils in the packets i'd
have application guys i come from a
background of
network troubleshooting i was on a lan
lan analyst team for 10 years um
and i'd always have the application hey
tell me hey it's the network it's always
the network
our logs say we're having network
problems and i'd be like okay well cool
let's get a packet capture and i give me
a packet capture and i just show that
it's not the network and they go well
i still think it's the network okay
that's fine right and i'd always like
break out the osi model and i've said
osi model and i've seen a few of you
grown already but yes i live and die by
the osi model and it's great
um so we're going to dive right into
wireshark like i'm not going to do any
other
presentation starts but i want to see if
has anyone ever done this you open up a
p cap or if anyone's seen someone do
this and they just start doing this
this action
you ever see this
and then they scroll down and they're
looking and they're looking like oh
found the problem it's red there's red
in that pcapp
and then they go to their network guys
and they say hey just so you know you've
got tcp dupe acts on your network
and the guys go
okay
that's great
and pretty much all of your credentials
and all of your uh
goodwill that you've fostered over the
years is now gone so at a brazen who's
actually opened and installed wireshark
before
who would consider themselves somewhat
comfortable in wireshark
a few cool that's good enough um i want
this presentation to be kind of like the
cafeteria style take what you like leave
what you don't some of the stuff is my
own personal preferences and how i do
things if you like it great if you don't
that's cool too the very first thing i'm
going to say is ditch the default layout
because it's terrible and if you use it
you should feel bad
because it was designed back when we had
43 monitors so i'm just going to switch
the profile to my own fun fact you can
actually have multiple configuration
profiles in wireshark so based on what
you're doing if you're trying to
troubleshoot a certain thing you can
actually build an entire layout
different columns different coloring
rules based on different functions
you're doing so if you're like doing
slowness or
resets or you're trying to do something
completely different you can have
different configuration profiles so
you're not always going through and
changing it which i found is great so
i'm going to switch it over to mine and
if someone wants this i'll be happy to
give it to them again this is just my
personal layout what i like to do as you
can see i've changed the your packet
list packet details back at bytes right
there
you'll see my coloring rules are a
little bit different and i've got
different columns than most folks have i
like it this way because i can use my
widescreen monitors and kind of break
this up a little bit you'll notice that
i've got different columns first one is
length and that's very important i'll
show you why in a bit i've got delta
time displayed and as you may or may not
know that is the time difference between
this packet and this packet is
calculated that delta i've got an
absolute time and i use that just for
the old like when someone says you know
the issue happened at three o'clock so i
can go and go go look at three o'clock
most people don't know this but by
default this time
the default in wireshark the time if you
don't go and change that to a utc time
or something generic it'll actually
change the time zone from where they
captured it to your own think it's being
helpful i've spent hours upon hours
analyzing a trace when they said the
problem happened at 4 00 p.m
and it was on the east coast and i was
in utah and i was looking at two and i'm
like i'm not seeing anything well turns
out wireshark was doing that for me
um
so yeah the first thing you do change
layouts um all that stuff
um i kind of want to talk about
filtering filtering is the real power
that comes with wireshark and and i
worry that people get um intimidated by
it like they're like i don't know the
syntax and i don't know how to do it
they've actually built a pretty robust
click point-and-click like gui driven
filtering that that you can take
advantage of so literally i'm just going
to start scrolling this random trace
and i'm going to go to that git right
who's familiar with the tcp three-way
handshake you know that sin snack act
we've seen that before what if you want
to see all the sins in the packet
capture
well the cheaters are just going to go
like this
tcp.1 right we have them memorize some
of us some of us don't well those same
they're that same information is in
every packet if you just drop down to
your tcp header here
go down to your synbit you can right
click on that prepare filter and do
selected tsp flags at syn equals zero
chain it to a one you just built there's
all your sins in your whole trace right
cool gui driven way to do it um super
handy
let's say for example um we want to see
all of the
times that a box reached out to cert or
any box reached out to a certain host
i'm going to switch captures here
i'm actually using the ctf pcap from
sync con this year thanks to them for
them to use this
it was super helpful if you didn't get a
chance to do that at st khan try next
time really great a lot of fun
um let's just say i want to find out
every time
someone reached out to a bad host so i'm
just going to do http for my filter
there just show me the http for now
and again we're going to drill down just
like we did before
for those that aren't comfortable with
the osi model i can make it even simple
layer two layer three layer four
application layer that's the simplest
way to remember it but we're gonna drop
down to this http
and there's the host that's the host
we're gonna right click on that prepare
a filter selected http.host
right there that's how you can build
that build those filters if you don't
want to remember the syntax you don't
want to learn this syntax you're still
getting used to it and you'll eventually
get there and you'll start remembering
and that's great but there's it's nice
to have some gui driven things to kind
of help you there in the beginning
one thing you can also do that a lot of
folks don't hang out with let's say
you've got a ton of data and you don't
want to filter it that way and you just
want to have a header or excuse me a
column and you want to see that you can
actually right click on any of these
things down here
and then do a applies column
and then you're going to get grumpy
because wireshark doesn't like adding
columns while you do it you're going to
have to click and drag and move around
then suddenly it'll show up on that
right side
and there it is so if you're looking
this trace kind of like holistically and
you do want to scroll through and say
who's everyone that talked out to this
particular host
super cool now let's say you don't want
to scroll let's say i've got this let's
say you took the trace from a mirrored
port um on the egress of your network
which is fine you take out an airport
and you've got tons of hosts you're like
i don't know every single host that
reached out to this particular bad actor
this accounting.acmephysics.com
that is throwing credentials out in the
clear but we're not going to worry about
that for now
so what you can actually do is go out
here to your um
statistics hit your conversations
limit that to your display filter
because we are filtering on that bad
host
and from there there's only one host to
talk to it but that would actually dump
an entire list of every host that
reached out and docked to it so if you
wanted a quick who got popped run that
be super easy
um
another thing that comes through a lot
as i mentioned tracing and doing a
mirrored port trace a lot of times when
as a um
as a as a packet analyzer you'll say hey
i want you to give me a packet capture
and i want you to take it from a
mirrored port i don't want it on the
machine i want it for my mirrored port
and they're like okay sure and they
think they're going to pull a sneaky on
you and they'll just capture it on the
machine
and the first thing i do every trace i
get i kind of try to figure out where
did this trace come from now one super
cool thing about ethernet is for a
packet to live on the wire it's got to
be at least a length of 60. now it's 60
plus 4 bytes for error or track summing
but wireshark wireshark strips those off
for us so there's 60. so if i ever get a
trace that is the minimum like 60 and
you can actually sort by that
i'll know that this trace was likely
captured external to a machine
but if i get a trace that looks a little
bit different i'll show you that
let's do our ttl little example
and go up here i've got packets that are
less than 60.
and i can click on one of those
or i can click on them there's actually
a lot of them on this one
let's just grab one of these i now know
that the source where this was captured
was this microsoft device right here
with this mac address because my packet
length is 54
and then that's my source mac address
right there so when everyone says hey
yep i absolutely mirrored a port and i
see packs that are less than 60 i go
no you didn't why don't you go get me
another trace and they'll double down
they'll say no i'm mirrored a port i'm
like okay you really didn't want to give
me that trace and then magically we got
someone else involved and then the trace
i want actually shows up which is super
super handy to have so
just these small little tips and tricks
that i'm showing you are kind of things
that you just need to build in your
brain as you become an analyzer going
okay check the packet length is it less
than 60 great this trace was taken from
this particular perspective right
um
on that note i'm actually using hard
copy for my outline you like that old
school time
um
one cool trick i want to show you um i
call it bookmarking and bookmarking is
something and we're actually going to
we're going to do a demo lose a sale
here why
not this is crazy we're gonna do it
anyway one thing we like to do we're
gonna get on a network here
lh miller was that it
no
one thing we like to do is we're gonna
go to captures and get on our wi-fi and
we're gonna start capturing stuff
oh cool we're capturing stuff so let's
say the problem statement is
i try to go out to google and it doesn't
load that's just the problem statement
one thing i will always like to do is
i'll get everything kind of pre-staged
and i'll get my browser open and i'm
already tracing so i'm like wasting time
but we're going to do it anyway
and then our mouse is going to die and
it's going to look really awkward on
camera
that's awesome touch screens cool so
we're going to ping 8.8.8.8
and then we're going to go over here
wait until that's done four pings great
and then we're going to go to google and
i'm just going to go to google again
that's a lot of fun and then i'm going
to ping
8.8.8. again
and four more pings
cool
and i'm going to stop my trace
now in my trace if i go for icmp
there's my pings that i sent to google
right
i now know that in between these pings
my problem occurred or the issue i was
trying to reproduce occurred
so one cool trick that i like to do is
if i go into this wow now i have no
mouse
this is super nice
you can right click on these and set a
time reference
now the cool thing about a time
reference
is time references will show up no
matter what filter you are doing
so let's say i want to see just uh
tcp.port
equals equals 443.
as i look here in this trace
i can find my bookmarks
sorry i'm gonna cheat
they are
right
i saw them another gone
actually we're going to do a different
way we're going to cheat a different way
because it's a better example
so same setup
and we're going to ping
8.8.8
and then i'm going to do a test net
connection
um
google.com
dashboard 81.
and then i'm making my attempt
and then i'm going to do
ping
8.8.8
stop my trace
um i'm going to tag those
pings really quick just so i have them
and then remember i'm going to use that
set time reference
and i'm going to set another time
reference now i'm not doing it in
between the actual ones but i'm just
giving you the example and then if i do
tcp dot port equals equals 81
those pins still show up
even though that's not in my current
filter they show up so
you tag your first one before you
duplicate you duplicate problem you tag
your next one and then as you filter
those will always show up and you'll
find the problem you're looking for so
pretty handy i use that quite a bit
one danger of that is you'll notice like
this is the display filter and when
you're filtering or when you're tracing
you can actually do a
a filter on your trace when you take it
and just a word of warning on that
don't don't filter your trace before you
don't filter your trace while you
capture it filter the trace
um afterwards while you're doing the
analyst but capture every packet you get
it i always i'm gonna go back to buffet
analogy let me pick out my own food
don't hand me a plate on what you want
to give me right
let me go through as an analyst and find
those packets
unless you're in a scenario where it's
going to be so ginormous you can't
really try to avoid capture filtering
from the get-go
and the reason is you run into dangers
we're
let's just say we're
for example let's say we had a ping pong
and we wanted to find it
and we're gonna start another trace here
and for my test case i'm to ping this
isn't a real oops we're going to put
those in there in a real domain and this
won't work
and they say okay i duplicate it for
that and you look in here there's no
icmp
well of course there's no icmp we failed
well before that even happened we failed
on name resolution so this just
illustrates the point capture everything
analyze second i've been burnt way too
many times personally of doing just that
thing i'll say yeah it's probably okay
this time filter the traces you capture
and then within a few hours i'm like no
go give me an unfiltered one
now
one other i think how many people work
in environments where it's like you
can't just install whatever you want on
our machines you have any of those
and you say i want to get a trace and
it's like we'll put wireshark on there
they're going to be like no
well you could always do net sh trace
start capture equals
yes
that's built in you can run that you'll
get an etl file which can be exported to
a pcap but you can actually go ahead and
run this on pretty much any modern
windows box
um and snag your trace that way i have
to do that quite often
the funny thing is i know about this and
i use this pretty often i'll still tell
people install wireshark not thinking
like yeah just install washer and get a
trace oh wait you could use an ssh and
there might just go through it
um this isn't a linux box obviously but
for linux friends
there's your linux version that's what
your command you'd use for that
um tcp dump is our friend we snag those
okay
now one other thing i like to bring up
is i've been in places where i say hey
you know what i want to get a trace and
they're like this is a secure facility
we can't give you a trace i'm like okay
can i have headers and they'll be like
yeah we even have headers and then
they'll try to take a capture and um
they'll end up grabbing everything i'm
like well actually it gave me everything
but i really wanted your headers if you
wanted to do that you can actually go to
your capture options here
go to your output well not output on
your input sorry
go ahead here to snap length change that
to 54 and you'll snag headers and
headers only
um
really useful if some folks are saying
hey we don't want to see we don't want
you to see our application traffic
just give me the headers some still
information can be get got can be
analyzed from the headers it's not as
great as having everything but it's a
way that you can kind of appease the
masses if they don't want to give you a
trace
the other very common thing when taking
a trace that i always hear is well the
issue is intermittent it happens
sometimes and i hear that so many times
um that's when you use what's called a
ring trace and so what you'll do is
you'll have this new file creation
automatically you can you can trigger a
new file based on how long the trace was
how many like multiples of hours i
normally just basically say give me
rings of like a gig each and then use me
a ring buffer of like five or so
so depending on how busy the network is
that'll that'll obviously influence how
big those files are um but yeah get this
trace going and say hey the moment you
see the problem you let me know and then
you can remote in and stop the trace or
you can have an admin remote stop trace
having that ring buffer of five files
building a gig file each time usually
enough time to get in there and stop it
so very useful for intermittent issues
times you don't see you know sometimes
when things aren't happening all the
time you can't trigger it it's kind of a
there's an outside condition causing it
all that good stuff like that
um
cool
on that note i'm going to dive in some
traces i'm just trying to show you some
cool stuff that we find on here okay i'm
not really doing this i promise
cool
so what we're going to do is we talked
about the three-way handshake a little
bit before
um let's open up our
let's do an unanswered sin
so
let's just snag
oh actually did i keep that trace this
one just did
i think it was
okay so this is a
so i'm looking for the sinbits over the
tcp three-way handshake a sins and a
one thing you can do if you're wanting
to look for your unanswered ones you can
actually go here to your statistics
and then go to your conversations
and then limit that to our display
filter
and anytime when you've got host a and
host b if one of these is has like three
four or five packets and the end one is
zero those are unanswered sins so if
you're trying to troubleshoot something
where let's say you've got an
application where you don't know the
port it's going to be listening on or
with that dynamic and you're like i just
need to see all the times that a sin
failed do that display filter to see all
those sins to speed up flags flags.equal
equals one equals equals one and then
head out to where there's zero responses
here um quick way you can just find
those that
those sins that go unanswered
um
there there's always there's always tips
and tricks and things that speed that up
but honestly using these built-in
statistics conversations your endpoints
your io graphs these are the things that
help you focus in on what you're going
to be looking for specifically
because it's really easy in a pcap and i
do it all the time is i'll pigeonhole
myself down a path and i'll start
looking just like oh there's some errors
i'm just going to sprint off in that
direction
i do that myself often but using these
built-in the conversations the endpoints
all that is is kind of a good way to
keep that holistic view of what you're
looking at
one thing i want to check show you is
we're going to open up this ttl example
right here
and throw that trace away
and then i'm going to filter to
this because i've already made this
trace beforehand it's like those cooking
shelves where they have all the
ingredients lined up in little bowls
these are my little bowls of ingredients
here
so what this is is this is a machine
reaching out via tls https and there's
that three-way handshake we know and
love since the netgack we love it so
much
um as we go down it has some
communication this is encrypted so i
can't see what it is
um scrolling around scrolling down all
sudden
i get a reset
now
everyone's going to play the game of
well who sent the reset why did i get
reset now at face value you're going to
say well obviously this 172.217.7.110
sent me a reset it's in the packet list
i can see that
not entirely case i'm going to show you
the beauty that is the ip header down
here
this is the ip header
and you've got this time to live of 128.
now this is my own machine this
192.168.1.89
the server that i've been talking to has
a time to live a 59. now these time
delivers in routing world they start at
some number depending on the
manufacturer it'll either be 128 or 64
or some older stuff 255. and as it goes
through each router it decrements that
time to live by one reason being if you
didn't do that there'd be packets still
circling the globe today you basically
have to say if you can't find your way
someone needs to throw them away so you
set this time to live and say if after
64 hops you don't find it i am so sorry
for your loss you're getting discarded
now how is that useful for us well i
know that this guy that i've been
talking to that's been working fine is
the time to lose 59 i just got a reset
from that guy
that has a time to live a 64.
why do i have a time to why did my time
to live suddenly change
answer that question that far side did
not send that reset
that far side was sent by my router on
my local broadcast domain because it's
64 hasn't been decremented so a firewall
in the middle reset that connection
the reason i know it did that is because
i actually did that on my firewall to
make this example however
if you look at that and and you'll run
into this a bunch when you're doing and
doing um doing analysis you'll see
resets the first thing you'll always
want to check is check that conversation
you've been having this whole time and
see if that time to list has changed if
that time to live has suddenly changed
good chance there's something in them
might not be a firewall it might be
something else something in the middle
has introducted itself
and then count the hops away of how far
it is to start looking to start
furthering your investigation that way
in the world of pcaps not every time
will there be like a smoking gun in your
trace what it will do is it'll say hey
here's our next place we're going to
look at
i know i got to reset on my local
network i now know i need to investigate
my gateway because he's in my broadcast
domain
that reset had a timeline of 64. so it
hadn't been decremented that's my area i
need to focus my investigation so kind
of cool that's probably that honestly if
i just say like the best trick that not
best trick but the best thing to learn
out of this is if you're trying to find
connection breakdowns look at your time
to live
moving on um i'm going to show you i
took a bunch of traces like samba samba
like and i was doing kind of older
school song i wasn't doing anything
fancy samba 3 stuff um i'm going to look
at this samba client 200 millisecond
latency
um and what i did on this trace
is i have a samba server that was just
running on an ubuntu box and then i use
traffic control on linux uh traffic
control is a cool utility you can
simulate all sorts of network problems
you can throw 200 milliseconds of
latency on every socket you can
corrupt or garble five percent of your
packets you can tell it to retransmit
tempers in your packets really useful
for building traces for examples but
also useful if you want to say hey what
would the real world example be if i had
a big long wand link across the country
with an 80 millisecond delay you can
introduce those um delays in in in your
trace
so this is a samba this is a transfer
samba and i'm going to practice repeat
preach and look at the conversations on
this trace
and you can see a bunch of conversations
a bunch of stuff was going on that
network if we actually just flip around
those bytes one of those conversations
is a lot bigger than the other ones
that's 88 megs and
um we'll go to tcp
so
tcp
port 445 that's a windows file copy
right one thing you can do right here
right click on that prepare filter
selected a to b
close that
and that's filtering to just that
connection
without having to type a single query
command so super handy super cool to do
now one thing i want to show you in
statistics if we go to our service
response time and go to smb2
it's going to load that up this is every
call that was made and you can do
display filters here so you can actually
copy pasta this one right here down to
the display filter if you wanted but
since the
trace really only had one big summit
connection and this is it you can see
the minimum service response time the
max response time and your average
response time for each one of these
verbs so i did 77 verbs
and my minimum was 0.2 because remember
i said that 200 millisecond delay and my
max was point was 8.4 with an average of
5. the sum of all those verbs were 427
seconds
so what does this tell us is this a
smoking gun in this trace no it's not
but what you can now do with this
information is say come start comparing
these numbers now since mine's an
artificial trace and i added that
artificial let's say we're doing a sama
transfer in that file and that
back in storage is on a is on a lawn on
our sand somewhere and that one's having
issues but only on reeds you could
actually notice that these reeds are
much higher or much lower than the
writes
so you can use this from by the nature
of investigating the protocol you can
actually use this information to say hey
we're reading great read performance
fantastic right performance not so much
and so it will kind of guide you into
the next thing that you want to that you
want to take a look at
um one other cool thing i want to show
about performance
and we're going to use the same trace
we're going to packet 693 for example
right here
i started this trace kind of in the
middle so you don't see the actual tcp
three hammer three-way handshake the the
socket had already been established but
i want to point out this packet right
here this is me
192.168.1.95 talking to 192.168.1.99
and i'm doing a smb verb of tree connect
request and that's the path that i try
to do
notice this next packet right here
doesn't have
any application data in it you see how
it's just layer 4 there's just tcp
and then right next is the tree connect
response which is the actual response to
that
tree connect i did
why is there a tcp right there in the
middle
the answer to that is the application
layer hadn't responded yet i had done a
request to do that tree connect and say
hey i want to talk to this ip and i'm
looking for the ipc dollar sign share
tcp after waiting and remember we're
going back to that delta that i would
leave up t is people waited now tcp
waited 200 milliseconds before it sent
that response now since i have that
artificial in there that number's gonna
be a little skewed but if an application
doesn't respond in a timely manner the
tcp stack's gonna act that packet and
say hey you know what i got your request
don't send it again i'm working on just
hang out for a bit and you'll see that
all the time now how is that useful when
you're analyzing traces if you see a
bunch of that if you see
the package the request the application
layer requests go out that tree connect
or whatever an http get and you see tcp
ack it really quick and then wait and
then wait and then the application exit
and that pattern goes through all that
or it keeps following that pattern you
can say well my network's really not
having problem delaying delivering those
packets i'm getting a tcpac
lickety-split but the application layer
is not responding to me in a timely
manner so from there you can now focus
your investigation to whatever damon's
listening on that back end whether it be
apache nginx whatever because and
they'll say well it's a network problem
it's slow slow equals network problem
always because that's what we've trained
ourselves to do
however by using this trace you can
actually say nope i made it
lickety-split and for whatever reason
your application responds in a timely
manner now we need to go look at that
application so super cool check for that
when you're looking at traces and you'll
see this one has a ton of those examples
examples there's a create request
there's the tcpac there's another one
there's a tcp act so yeah just keep your
eye out for that and as you kind of get
more comfortable and as you keep doing
these you start learning these patterns
you're gonna start learning hey i'm
getting tcpx but not application layer x
let's go look at the application layer
um
another cool thing we're going to jump
to a different trace again
again this is the cafeteria i'm
literally just like throwing food out on
the thing and just take what you like
and what you don't like saying no thanks
we're going to go to this five percent
corrupt and as you can see i cannot
spell the word corrupt that's corrupt
whatever that was
and
if that wants oh let's get rid of our
filters
that's better
so i've got another trace and what i did
is i told um
i told tc on um on linux go ahead and
corrupt five percent of the trap packets
just for funsies just corrupt them and
then i said and by the way do a random
smattering of retrans just as much as
you want and 10 which is a lot
let's say
you've just got some slowness you don't
like how it's running one great thing
you can do is go here to your statistics
or sorry analyze
and then go to your
expert information
and again like before i can still limit
to my display filter so just look at
what we want to see
and there's an error and i've got oh
malform packet there's only one of them
that's interesting
so let's take off that display filter
and look at all of our others
wow
we've got 11 538 retrains
why did i not see it the first time
because
i filtered only to smb2 and so as
relying on wireshark's dissector the
looks of those packets and make sure
there's an application layer header on
there that says this is smb2 and that's
how it was classifying it since i got
rid of that and i undid that display
filter now i'm seeing anything
that is a suspected retrans and i've got
11 538 of those retransmits cool thing
you can do click that drop down right
there and as you click through it'll
actually take you in the trace where
they are now you'll notice in the
background it's saying it's not
displayed that's because i've still got
this filter on there
take that off
go back to here
try to find your retrans there they are
and as you click through it'll actually
take you in the trace in the background
you can see it's moving around there to
all those retrans now granted you're
gonna get retrans you're gonna get
dupac's that's tcp doing its job it's
going to do that that's just how it
works don't go crazy going oh my
goodness i'm having 100 retransmits in
30 000 packets guess what who cares
that's tcp let us do a thing but if
you're seeing in a trace that's only a
few seconds long you've got 12 000
retrans
you've probably got something you need
to look at there right
now
moving right along to our um
the world of samba i'm staying sam just
because it's kind of easy to illustrate
i'm going to go to samba wireless
and all this was this was me just
copying a file across my network over
wireless
really not super exciting it is kind of
a big file because obviously i captured
everything because filter second not
first
that's my golden rule and so now we just
get to awkwardly look while my laptop
reads these packets so
how we all doing good great
cool here we go
now one thing i want to show you is i'm
just going to filter this trace in the
display filter i'm just going to filter
to port 445 just to save us a little bit
of time as i go into my next area that
i'm going to show you so we don't have
to do this more than once
wireshark has a built-in i o graph that
will actually calculate your your input
output speed based on the packets coming
through it
um this is super handy especially when
you have users telling you hey you know
file copies are slow they're they're not
going to expect i'm getting
one megabit or they give you some
arbitrary number you can actually
capture that packet or capture that
trace as they do it and see what the
actual um
what the actual speed looks like
that's here on your statistics under
your io graphs
and again you can filter this down to
i'm going to go to all packets and i'll
pick them into the port 445
and we're going to recalculate that
and while we do that i'm going to bring
up the screenshot of
windows what it showed so we have that
up there
that work yeah you can see that cool
as we load
um you can see kind of the hills and
valleys here
this obviously windows is smoothing that
out and it's not giving the exact number
at each step but it kind of gives you
the average
and if we look at that graph you
actually see
it looks pretty similar as far as
there's obviously a lot more detail here
in the
in the wireshark version of it but you
can see that pattern follows a pretty
similar drop is that so you can actually
extract this performance out
from the from the raw trace itself um
on that note um a lot of times when
you're taking when you're talking about
performance tracing getting one side of
a conversation isn't super helpful
because
you'll you're tracing from the work from
the um
the viewpoint of this workstation you're
sending out across the wire and you're
just waiting whatever comes back to you
right so what we'll do a lot of times
we'll call do what's called simultaneous
traces where i'll trace here and i'll
trace on the server at the same time
and and we'll compare them and see
what's going on well one thing you need
to do when you do that is line your
packets up in your list because you'll
have a bunch of packets here from this
workstation which is obviously being
exposed to different networks that it's
seeing you've got your server network
that's being exposed to different
networks and different packets and all
that good stuff so you need a good way
to line those up so i'm going to show
you the niftiest trick ever to line
those up
we are going to go back to our
200 millisecond latency there's the
client side
we're going to open wireshark again
and we're going to open the server side
uh there's the server side
and thanks to the magic of wide screens
we're going to go like that and it's a
little smashed and i'm sorry it doesn't
look great but that's kind of the best
we can do
so we're going to go like this tcp.port
equals 445. okay so we just filtered it
basically to sombon both sides
if you go to one of these packets and
just pick a packet that you like doesn't
matter which one let's just do this tree
connect
you go to your ip header and each one
has this identification on it you can
right click on that
prepare a filter
selected
hit enter on that
there's that particular ipid copy that
go to our other trace
go like that
there it is right click on there
and do mark packet do mark packet you
could do a time reference if you wanted
to show up all the time
and then when we go back to our default
filter
and those two traces you see that one
and that one that's where those two
packets line up in the trace so as you
go through you're now lined up and you
can keep doing that you keep doing that
this procedure over and over again
it's depending on your protocols how
chatty they are how many times they
perform the same functions sometimes
i'll mark each one each time i do like a
tree connect or an open file or whatever
do that ip line them up mark all those
so as i'm analyzing on both sides of the
trace i can kind of keep those lined up
in my head
um so yeah so that's how you the best
part that's the best way to kind of line
up your simultaneous trace and again
it's going to be a matter of looking at
who's having the delays why are we
seeing deltas why are those increasing
on one side or the other um sometimes
you'll get a packet delivered really
speedy that box will sit and chew on it
for a while and then send it slow back
after a little bit or it'll send a
response really speedy and the and the
client doesn't see it for a while it's
all about narrowing down your next step
troubleshooting like i said you're not
gonna see a smoking gun every time but
you will get it narrowed down a bit
i wanted to jump into file extraction
because that's a cool thing that folks
like to do
i'm going to use that ctf from
from st connegan
so inside this
trace
there's things that happen i know what's
in this trace because i've got obviously
gone through the ctf but i know files
were transferred i know that actually
occurred
so i'm going to go here to file and
export objects and then based on
protocol you can actually export
anything that was transferred over those
protocols during the trace so just for
funsies let's click on samba
and then i just go change the size
and during that time someone transferred
this mp mp4 file on our on our network
now can i save that you bet i can
and save that and just throw that to
documents
save that
and
there's the file i just ripped out of
the pcap
that works for smb you can over http
super cool super handy one alternate way
i want to show you to do that same thing
which i think is
a little bit easier he's using a cool
tool called network miner
fire up network miner
we're going to open that same peak app
no we're not going to update in the
middle of a presentation that would be
bad
open up this
it's going to go through and parse it
network miners are some other cool
parsing stuff for you um it'll have all
your hosts and you can filter down on
those
um
it's going to fire that up
cool and then i can click on the images
tab and here's every picture that was
transferred during that session and nice
easy thumbnails
now let's say someone has a silly uh web
service and they're just dumping
credentials on clear text well we get
those too
super cool tool um here's everyone's dns
queries
where they're all going who's making
them all that fun stuff
network minor is super cool tool you can
use especially if you are um just have a
network tap somewhere and you just kind
of keep an eye on what's going on let's
say you're worried someone's
exfiltrating data throw a network tap on
have network miner on there have a quick
look of see what's going through super
handy for from a blue team perspective
um
those are kind of the main tips and
tricks i wanted to show you i and a lot
of this is like question answer and
stuff so what question does anyone have
in the whole world of pcaps for me if
any and i will do my best to make
something up for you
everyone's like
yeah please go ahead
i i heard something with us aside sorry
okay so you're going to run into some
issues especially anytime you're doing
security stuff on sso because it's going
to be encrypted you're going to run into
that so you're going to have to do
expert exportation of your keys to be
able to have a look into that but one
cool thing that i'm glad you brought up
is
in the world especially if you're on a
linux box in the world of linux a lot of
time when application one application is
talking to another on the same host
that's talking via sockets just
internally to itself
in that tcp dump command that i
mentioned if you on your interface do lo
your loopback interface you can actually
see applications talking to itself on
the same box just different
just different demons talking to each
other so on a state where you're trying
to like troubleshoot an sso problem and
it's this box is talking to itself super
easy ways to do it you don't have to
worry about certificates because you're
already on the box so kind of a cool way
to do that
cool if there's no other questions
that'll do it for me thanks so much
you