veronica is the last presentation before
the break so be nice with her as you see
from the title the presentation might
raise a number of questions so think
about it and when you do ask questions
later make them short and quick so the
only guy can have time to to answer all
of them the only guy you have the floor
ok thank you I hope you guys hear me
yeah responsible ok so my name is
Veronica I work for the cognitive tried
analytics team in cisco czech republic
and i'm going to talk about an analysis
of network traffic that of a mal work
that we run in our lab and that in that
in it end up in a brute forcing attack
so if you have questions you can ask
them later or feel free to ping me later
so okay so as many of you I work
studying and analyzing network traffic
from alwar mostly from different sources
usually these sources are very small
like blogs Twitter trackers every source
of intelligence that many of you had to
create but so these are usually small
sources and then I can apply to the
Tecton identify tried seen like large
amount of data like real traffic in
insider or company and customers and so
on but most of these sources of data
from my world has been run for mostly
from one to five minutes that's the
usual sandbox in time for example
most of the blogs and reports some
sometimes cover this time maybe more
than me its top maybe one hour but
usually there is no more intelligence
more than one hour maybe some hours but
not so much so the question is like what
happened next what the malware does
after one hour of infection what the
malware does after one week of infection
what the mango does when has been
running for a month is something changed
it is like worse to run mad one more
time or not maybe maybe it's not maybe
it's just five minutes we have
everything we need right so I was
curious about the about this so I want
to try it so I run it this malware in
your love is the sandbox environment is
very basic is not nothing from nothing
complex it runs filter box I don't have
any until Tony station tricks is just
normal BM they actually the malware is a
camera and Romelu malwa it was come
categorization his car we base or
judgment on some virus total results
also from the traffic and also Jose is
going to talk about Toro about Gamma Rho
and remain as well so he also
double-check these so we took this
malware run it in your laugh and we let
it run for a month and this is called
them malware infection is an area looks
like so the infection started in May 12
and we let it run until june twelfth and
you can see well infections started and
the first 10 days
the bonnet was alive the command control
was was active there was some
communication but there was no
instruction from the one master the
bonded the boat actually was kind of
either we call it so there was nothing
happening but from from the one master
point of view this is our waste of money
because you have some machine in fact in
even if it's in a sandbox environment it
is kind of not giving any profit so
after some time it seems that something
happened and that the behavior change
the body was instructed to start
downloading new pilots it attempted we
are going to see later how many it tried
to the Lord and then some of them worked
and we can see that at some point it
trigger another infection and from that
moment on the word the body was infected
like twice and we have like two common
controls communicating at the same time
and that new behavior was the brute
forcing the time going to cover later
but if you can see the graph the route
14 behavior lasted only four days and
after that the primary component control
was he was instructing about to start
download new fails to change the
behavior again but it seems that I don't
know something happened there wasn't
nothing interesting in the last end of
the capture so this is called the
traffic looks like from the camera
common control it's a simple HTTP
request post request you can see that
there is and keep the traffic being sent
and received I didn't reverse the vinery
so I'm just focusing network traffic so
because I from the network perspective I
cannot do anything about this so i
calculated some statistics
characteristics about the traffic so I i
took some values about the amount of ID
sense without headers
like the beer data transmitted over time
in a daily basis and you can see that
the bot contacted actually three
different servers but only one was
active and that's the red one was alive
during the 30 days but there was no
difference with it with the other two
the amount of data sent by the bot it
was a very stable along the the
infection it wasn't the same with the
receive advice we can see here that in
red there is the active command control
and the amount of fights was very small
on the contrary w1 the server was
responding but it actually it was an
error code and it seems like a not
crafted ever call it was just normal one
and I think that probably server was on
the and after some days he'd stop trying
to contact that server and in the end of
the capture we tried the boat righted
attempted to contact another common
control server but while it was replying
it was replying with zero white so I
think it also wasn't very alive so this
is the activity of how the Gamma Rho
command control was downloading new
instruction the WOD to download new
pilot and this is very interesting
because this is a primary command
control that was leaned infection and
was said telling the machine how to
behave and you can see that it was very
busy and most one of the most
interesting the second one more
interesting part is the one that you can
see in the middle that I don't know if
you can read the names of it since I is
the same file name but version so maybe
somebody was trying new versions of
work and see if they worked or not but
we are going to focus on the fifth one
because that's the one that triggered
the brute force and activity so then
this file was not loading downloaded
from this server it was a HTTP request
like this like very plain downloading
some excellent if you're in a network
this is very suspicious you can have the
cash here later the the malware was a
very simple functionality it was capable
of performing logins to WordPress sites
and then communicating with the command
and control in in different ways
informing whether it was successful or
not so from the traffic point of view
and the command and control
communication of this malware was HTTP
and there was no encryption nothing
she's plain text and the communication
can be splitted in three different
behaviors the first behavior is were the
first request you consider where the
boat was communicating the status of the
of the brute forcing so there are some
parameters like which gate he was used
how many good but unlucky results and so
on and the second behavior was where the
world was retrieving the files txt files
containing a list of work besides to
root for lady and it was also the answer
in plain text plain text as we are going
to see and
the third one was were a special request
that happened in very low volume that
the body used to actually report the
successful attempts especially the
successful attempts so this is an
example of report status request and we
can see that how these requests is
linked it to the second behavior because
in the answer there is a next file that
the board should retrieve and this is
the file that is retrieve a devout and
you consider the list of sites that is
just ally of txt file with maximum 1000
sides or their alphabetically and
sometimes the files containing just
1,000 sites starting with a sometimes
starting with g and so on here is an
example of one of these sites you can
see that it's possible that they are
WordPress race and this one is kind of
shedding I'm not sure if it's legit but
anyway and this is where the bot sends
the success data you can see the request
is is interesting because is it split so
you are not going to see it quite well
even a proxy log but extending the
domain that was successful as part of
the post request so this is this is the
brute force in activity overview in the
in the the white is the amount of
requests per day HTTP requests and you
can see that only the fourth day the
first four days where the brute forcing
was active and the the red one is where
it was how many files were retrieved and
you can see that this about once a 100
per day mostly and there were also some
success data requests which is quite
interesting because it seems that did
work
right so there isn't a brute forcing I
say it's horizontal but forcing because
it's not that the boat was attempted
attempting to access us website trying a
thousand different password user
password combinations for each side it
was updating just one or two
combinations / / site and trying many
sites at the same time so i couldn't i
had only pick up so I could see what
user password combinations it had a
tried and most done more than fifty
percent of the cases it tried admin and
mean I guess it was hard-coded in the
binary because the word didn't retrieve
any password leads from anywhere the
other combination was mean and some
custom password and this is interesting
because the bot had the functionality to
some somehow craft the domain the
possible potential password for that
site based on the name of the domain
that was attempting to logging so if you
have for example we wanted come it will
try admin Google and yeah it worked so
in total there were more than 8,600
Samsung custom passwords attempted you
can see here some examples there are
some Slavic wars that are interesting
some polish cities and some typically
this this custom passwords are
associated with domain name so it makes
sense
okay some how aggressive it was so every
day if there were more than 40,000 sites
that devote attempted to logging and
that's a lot and in total you can see
that it was very aggressive border for a
very short period of time and that's it
so it was it was my interesting to see
and so in total devote alone one bottle
own tried to login into more than
150,000 work besides with only 23
success cases so the ratio of successful
pneus is it is also interesting to have
in mind for this type of automated work
that the boat was doing this is an
example of a website that was actually
the boat was able to log in and you can
see that is a Brazilian blog there is
nothing seemingly wrong with it and if
you I don't know if you can read but by
stata have a report on that I piece with
some malicious heat on August that's a
couple of months later since my boat was
able to log into the site so you can you
can get the economic cycle here like we
have about that is just attempting to
massively login into size and you can
sell them and then other people install
malware and then you can send a phishing
email to get more users infected I'm not
sure about how much access to this type
of sites cost but you can make the
control how profitable this can be in
just one board was in my point of view
was kind of very successful getting six
new sites for free every day
if you have like 100 baht 1,000 baht
that's a lot and there is a lot of
bondage like for example crypto wall
that when you analyze their command
control traffic they are all using
WordPress Hackett sites to communicate
with to Costa Rica man controls
momentarily and then they just move on
to another server so the question of
world oh how do they get this type of
site may this might be an answer right
in the end i did a analysis of how these
targeted sites were distributed because
i was just worried if this was a
targeted attack on so i was part of the
source of the dark so I was kind of
concerned but as you can see there was
no special distribution of targets the
only word besides were kind of well
distributed among the world and there is
of course a high amount of sites in US
but that's I guess that's okay so there
wasn't any special this is not a
targeted attack so it's cool so my
conclusions were that yeah we would we
would have never seen this type of
malware behavior ever even the this type
of payload vein job if we run the
malware choose one hour so it's kind of
worth not for all the Marvel of course
but maybe some samples it is called also
it's important to execute the malware in
like with real internet access many some
boxing solutions don't do that and it's
not really possible to see what the
Manoir really does if you are emulating
it also sometimes there are reports
saying this man washes behaving this way
tomorrow is Justin
motion stealer yeah we cannot define a
bond that anymore by a single behavior
they can update themselves like very
fast so and all the route 14 actually
work because we are still having
credentials with a mean and mean and
mean google and mean my side so all the
work we are doing in education I think
still is not enough so we should work
more than that and if you have questions
we have some minutes
so we have some time for a few questions
in the middle introduce yourself table
ok my name is tebow I work for the
sorter G and with Thomas you may know
him I was asking did you make any
statistics about the websites that were
attacked by these botnets you talk about
WordPress you saw a lot of it it was
specifically corporate ok and it seems
that the malware has like some kind of
hard coded the way how to create the
post request ok so the WP login excited
PHP exit route before single ok ok and
any kind of website young WordPress to
all purple all my always WordPress
without any kind of website it can be
you just a blog or something or
corporate websites yeah it wasn't any
yeah only on the targets were of people
creating work besides that hosted on
their own domains there wasn't any
domain something that wordpress.com it
was just it seems that people buy that
kind of site and they create their own
blog or site thank you very much yeah on
the right here when did you analyze the
sample when did you receive it roughly I
found them all or around april and i
started the infection on me and for for
a month so okay yeah i just found like
early samples all the way from back to
May 5th listed on malware calm so it was
interesting that it was very close yeah
well I didn't submit it there so maybe
somebody else was trying to shake it up
yeah but thinks yeah Andromeda is a
plug-in based yeah I started did you see
the plugin download and did you see
anything else or just that well I in
this case I chose analysis brute forcing
one but you can see how it was
downloading different type of files and
Jose is going to talk about plugins
tomorrow but I I believe that many of
them might be some updates to London but
I didn't took a look at the vinery said
other questions one in the middle Dennis
hi hi working out work my name is Dennis
from IBM the question is mother was
running on your system for about a month
yeah and during this month your cisco
were contacted by any law enforcement
agency someone to say you know your
brute forcing our servers please stop it
no thank you answer is no but actually
and from my detection point of view it's
not that it wasn't a vertical
brute-forcing that someone could notice
right because if you are if you are
monitoring the purpose server will at
least one or ten more besides were were
hosted you will see only done request of
looking at least you know at least a
localized speed at cisco connected this
year the czech republic can ask you a
question but since no
last question I'm retail job from
Microsoft I got two questions one so
you're kinda related to what yes sorry
running the mother in for one month is
it a supervised or unsupervised running
really you know how do you supervise and
taking off I decided oh maybe doing some
other pillows essay with the email
account that you have in your vm they
might send other mothers in tubs
something malicious activity that you
cannot control how do you you know
control that how do you monitor that I
actually these long-term manual capture
experiments were kind of unsupervised
Aisha's infected on trying not to even
open the machine or use it so it was it
was kind of let's see I was of course
checking the network traffic to every
every day to check that this kind of was
under control kindness but i only have
blocked some spam because i'm not
interested in that type of traffic but
the race it was kind of completely
unsupervised that one more so you're
tracking the smaller and are you guys
taking note of the server where this
successful brute force has supported i'm
painting out like if you have a list of
server word rip where the mall report
this successful attacks well we have the
command and control servers and from for
the words that were successfully
attacked we are trying to contact them
before polishing any more information
same thing it might be interesting to
correlate it to the maullers that
distributed by a wordpress yeah i wonder
if you could share that the port service
yeah i think so we might talk like that
thank you
thank you you're breaking the braid okay
last question here hi and what is
cognitive security research we are very
short we are grouping site cisco that we
work doing animal addiction in network
traffic doing machine learning thank you
yeah