okay good morning right into right on
time and right into the topic crypto
well this morning with a unit and
clients ma yeah you have the floor all
right before I start on Krypto a quick
update on pom woke up we actually pissed
them off apparently because they're now
d dancing to single the singles now down
so if you're receiving reports it will
be down for some time so I'm going to be
talking about crypto all but mostly what
this top will be is looking into the
history of these guys so what they've
been doing over all these years because
I know a lot of people are looking at
the latest version are looking at three
point 0 a lot of people jumped in on two
point oh but I don't think a lot of
people actually knew what they were
doing before all those versions so I'll
quickly introduce myself first and then
I'll jump into the history immediately
so i'll start off with the first version
i basically explain how this version
work and then from every version i'll
just show the changes so i'm not going
to explain everything for every version
because then we'll need more than 30
minutes but it's just going to be the
single changes and at the end i also
have a sort of a word of caution about
these guys continuing on I'll show the
infrastructure I'll social interesting
discoveries I made while I was
investigating these guys I'll show some
tools I've made which are going to be in
get up and I'm going to thank some
friends who've been sharing samples or
information so i don't think i need
introduction that much i'm a guy with an
opinion so i have twitter that's sort of
the thing if you're on the internet i
have a blog so let's just start so the
first version of crypto wall when they
started they didn't name themselves
scripta wall they were doing something
everybody was doing at the time which is
cloning cryptolocker so there was back
in november two thousand thirteen and
this basically what you were seeing you
know so kind of similar to what
cryptolocker looked at looked like at
the time they only swapped out the logo
slight modification indie GUI because
they couldn't mimic everything you know
but pretty much the same but they
weren't the only ones you know everybody
was doing this kind of stuff you had
tons of these clones
floating around yeah so encryption at
the time they locally generated in RSA
keep keep air with the link rip to the
windows cryptic crypto API files they
would encrypt we were slightly larger
because they added a small tags that he
could find back to files added to check
some hash from the file and what's
decrypted so you could confirm it was
correctly decrypted and it was basically
it so everything is local even the
private key so it's kind of interesting
what they need it to identify system was
like a unique system ID and this is AF
implemented this in the first version so
the clone and it's still used in the
latest versions of the crypto ball four
point oh if you can call it that and
basically it takes it makes like a
string which is a concatenation of a
bunch of information so the computer
name volume serial number processing
information and your operating system
version take a string take the md5 from
this hex notation and that's your unique
identifier for your system basically so
they could identify multiple system
behind single IP communication protocol
really simple just plain HTTP basically
we need when an infection would start it
would report in with like a campaign ID
which nothing more than an identifier so
on their back end they could just filter
on specific campaigns so let's say
something was being spread via email
they would tag it with email one
something was spread by exploit kids
they would tag at explicate one so they
could just know where it was coming from
and possibly what was the most
successful way to spread around so he
checked in with unique system ID what
happened on the back end is it made an
entering the database with this unique
system ID or to see the scenes he
responded you know I've made his entry
it's okay startup declined did another
request and again with his unique system
ID to identify itself and what did what
the scenes he responded was a download
location with a like a kind of our guys
a foul blob and it contains some I do I
stuff and some other resources for the
payment processing their kind of stuff
after it received it and it you know it
did its thing it would just report back
and say everything you know everything's
fine I'm done so if you look at what it
actually looked like on
the wire was just this so you have a
post other words interesting about this
post the location little sis post URL
it's actually a key it's an RC four key
for the rest of the data only they sort
of scrambled it basically what you have
to do is to solve this you just have to
sort it on s key value of the characters
in its path and then you have to correct
RC four key they just scramble it up a
little bit you know inviting it looks
like this pretty simple the data that's
actually in the post request is just
hacks encoded so you decode from the
hacks takes our c4 and I mean you got
your decrypted request in this case so
sort of the same thing I showed on the
other slide you know you're the first
thing if the brackets the first thing
they have is like a unique I can command
number and you get your campaign ID and
then the system ID which which it checks
in in this case the response one more
this gets the response was actually the
Donald location so the file blob also we
know the encryption on this was using
the same key so the client could also
decrypt it pretty simple protocol small
detail of it is that it does a forum
post so form your own coding and the
actual parameter of the data was just
the last or highest value in the key
after it's been sorted so the protocol
itself is actually pretty simple it's
just the curly brackets in between that
the first thing is always the command ID
and the command ID after that you have
data you can see this parameters to
function so the command ID is basically
a function and whatever it comes after
it with the pipe symbols are just
arguments for these functions pretty
simple so I feel look at an example this
is for example the first check-in
machine ever does so command ID 1 it's
just register decline basically so after
that you get your campaign ID in this
case Wolfgang is the campaign ID they
got your unique system ID and which it
checks in after that there's a there's a
number which is basically an index on
the table said it would know which kind
of system you were running you know if
you're a Windows 7 Windows XP when I say
just for identification after that they
did some stuff for their architecture so
we'd know if you're running 32-bit or
64-bit
they also want to know if it was running
elevated so if it had full privileges on
the machine was running on and in the
beginning it also needed the remote IP
address and the reason why that was is
because they're seen see infrastructure
is on tour so you know they don't get
client at peace it's no remote IP
address they can use and the way they
set it up is that they have a proxy
server which is owned by themselves
which is set up by themselves they run
engines on this with privacy and this is
what it does every request this upstream
to the back end which is inside tour
pretty simple setup but if you kick down
that server it would be done for a while
now in the beginning there were actually
in the payment wise if you wanted to
unlock your files there were a lot of
options which was kind of interesting
you know you could pay with money pack
right going you cash they save Bitcoin
as well but you know there was just a
lot so it started with file types this
whole bunch i'm not going to talk about
all of them basically they're just the
file types you would expect to see on a
normal machine of people using documents
their pictures their you know their
music their videos just to catch
whatever would be interesting or vital
to somebody using his machine so a
little bit later february2014 actually
updated they removed the name they went
on to a different name call themself
script of defense this time so that you
know they picked up their own name
ransom notes kind of changed it wasn't a
GUI you know inside the application they
really made their own design of this
it's no more cloning of cryptolocker
that a small text on their singing or
files are is it basically encrypted
using RSA 2048 the ransom notes will be
dropped in every directory where you had
files that were encrypted with how to
decrypt HTML txt URL at the bottom they
explain how you get on the payment
server to get your files back and you
had something that was a personal code
which they call it which is just a way
to get youtube page specifically for
your key to get your files back now one
thing that change from this version is
that the campaign is were not random
worse or that kind of stuff anymore they
were actually
these kind of things so it was death
with some kind of number behind it these
numbers were incremental and between all
these different numbers you could see
small changes in the binary so this is
just development this is just version
tracking in development of Terran mallar
base t or ransomware this case so slight
change so the red stuff went away which
was the GUI blocking retrieved the first
part is still same it needs to check in
with a unique system ID but what changed
is it now sent away deprived key so the
scenes to serve for now would have the
private key instead of it being still on
the system the server would acknowledge
that the client send the key and it
would purport in how many files had
actually encrypted on the system so net
were wise small change it was an extra
post request you saw some data in there
and quite at least you see some
artifacts dars a file blob basically so
what's kind of interesting the way to
implement this they use the legacy
crypto API from windows and basically
the decrypt apic speech stores keys you
generate in your profile they have like
a certificate management key management
but did you know it's sort of private
key on the system again so a copy would
stay and people might the tool for this
people were decrypting is so nice you
know you could help victims and at some
point semantic published about this and
less than 24 hours and they had a fixed
so they you know they pay attention to
what's being published about them and
with this flaw basically they fixed it
they move the name they trusted name
because you know it was bad people knew
you could decrypt it so they went on
they call themselves scriptable one
point 0 and it was in March 2014 so
pretty quickly campaign IDs changed
again instead of death from crypt of
defense and now is CW again version
numbers would be incremental you would
see slight changes and you could also
see they were experimenting with some
stuff so there were some tour versions
and campaigns and these versions would
actually talk on tour directly so no
more proxy servers it would directly
connect on to tour and they also made a
CW 404 there were no changes they
probably just there was a funny
complaint ID to use again some slight
ransom note updates
major thing blew some small cosmetic
changes now says all of your files are
protected with strong encryption what
encryption also changed so instead of
generating anything locally it would
actually request a public key from ours
a public/private key pair from the C&C
server so no more private key on your
system so again small change in their
protocol first things still the same it
has to check in the surface technology
client existed instead of sending back
deprived kid would actually retrieve a
public key from the back end server and
the server would reply with an md5
checksum from this public key so the
surfer would know that correct one
basically so the server says okay you
got to get the right key clients come
comes back later to reporting how many
files that had and that was it so it
also did something interesting it added
exempted countries so it would not
encrypt if it's any of these countries
being the source of the infection so you
know Russia Belarus Ukraine and
Kazakhstan they were all okay if you
would get an infection you know your IP
would be reported it did a geoip check
would respond with a country code inside
a crypto wall daresay like a crc32
ashing of these country codes and would
check it against the list and this was
the list they implemented in their first
script of all version so they were
excluding all Soviet Union countries so
moving on October 2014 they popped up
again new version crypto a two point oh
so first spotted in emails from IRS just
you know file attachment usual stuff
fake document it's not a document slight
update on the actual ransom notes they
added a two point now behind it just to
identify hey it's a new version they
also did some stuff with the
infrastructure so this was what we had
on the cloned version this is what we
had on the crypto defense but they had
more versions that were running directly
on tour so it wasn't all of them they
were still experimenting with him
because were some issues with it at
times but you had a lot of thorns
directly so now serves to take down they
also went into the affiliate biz
it was kind of interesting it sort of
you know they got in guys who would
spread for them and would get it cut of
the pave somebody actually paid to get
their files back he would see these
crypt 12 it's like currently son like
3,000 or something there are a whole of
a lot you can sort of see that it was
affiliates because in between numbers
would disappear so Phillies would drop
off it wasn't like consecutive version
numbering they would just go off and on
you could see different versions or
different campaign IDs appear something
disappearing over time but that was
basically the whole change so I think
the big exchange here is that they just
implemented an affiliate system so
instead of them spreading around
monitoring their system they would get
other guys who also help with this so
further on January 2015 so this year
they appeared with three-point oh but
before that day sort of took some time
off so you know caffeine also node this
on Twitter 18 of November 2014 was the
last time they updated binaries on their
deployment servers and the that's binary
she would see from exploit kids so they
took some time off like a maybe a
vacation or something you know November
past December past still no samples
still no new stuff from these guys
January came New Year's still nothing
but January thirteenth they were back
three point 0 in this case so they just
took some time off again slight cosmetic
changes on the ransom notes new version
new naming of these ransom notes because
they were quite static you could
actually use this to the texts and stuff
internally they made a change in the
protocol that when it responded with the
check some of the public key it will
also respond with a lock screen so
instead of the malware having this
embedded it would generate this on the
server side which means they didn't have
to build new binaries every time when
they had new domains for the payment
system it would just generate this on
the fly so they could use old samples
this was all dynamically generated on
the back end again network can change
they like to play around they like to
develop this kind of stuff so they
didn't do tour they didn't do their own
proxies they move to ITP which was kind
of interesting so I know it set up
to this only problem was didn't really
work so well I tepees doesn't seem to
skill for them because their servers
went down the whole time like every time
we just go down this Li the decrypt
surface so basically the surface where
you could go to pay to get your to get
the key to get your files back but it
just didn't work you would get errors
from time to time like this in Russian
so infrastructure change after the ITP
stuff they figured out you know this
doesn't work we need something that's
good so the old the old proxy servers
they would maintain themselves you could
take them down and then it would be done
for a while so what they did is they
employed something they're currently
still doing they would hack websites so
old wordpress joomla drupal and it would
food small PHP files under which were
just proxy scripts small scripts using
curl to upstream requests and this
helped because talking to all these
individual holsters to take this stuff
down takes forever and some of them
don't even reply and at the same time
you actually want a copy of this because
you want to know you know what is that
real server they're owning you want to
take this down it just improved from it
helped them to stay active much longer
they also maybe they got a new partner
i'm not sure but they added armenia to
the white listing of exempted countries
it was kind of interesting I you know
maybe they had a new partner in which as
you know i'm not going to spread it and
don't want to be having issues in my own
country could be and in some versions
they also had i ran in there but not all
versions i only found a couple of
samples that had this kind of white
listing so i'm not sure what was going
on there one thing day also added was
that they changed the crypto they made
it faster actually they did some
optimizations so instead of using the
RSA Keith actually encrypted files they
were generating aes-256 key / file I
didn't use this to actually encrypt the
file then they used the public key they
could get from the server to encrypt AES
key it was faster streaming cipher is
way faster on big files you know if some
guy was connected to a file share this
was way faster you didn't have to hear a
machine
buzzing up because it was encrypting all
the files they also slightly had to
change the file format of course so
every file was prepended with an md5
from the public key so it could confirm
if it had the key if it was right then
the encrypted a s key and then the
encrypted file data and they also
expanded their list of targets so 312
instead of 146 they have had since the
beginning you know there was a lot of
obscure files lot of stuff for
photography so raw files for Fatah
photograph files a bunch of design
documents some programming file so you
know dhcp HP HP also some back up back
at DBS sequel I'd database that kind of
stuff these role in their target is now
they were expanding so moving on the
current version which they're now using
I've updated these slides I think four
days ago before I came here so they're
as recent as I could get them this is
November so last month for the November
that isn't change so cosmetic changes on
this part the version number is gone so
there's no 2.9 no three-point oh people
are calling this 24 point no just four
consecutive numbering and I think it's
good to identify this new version we
don't know what what they're calling
this version so slight change in the
naming of the ransom notes you know help
your files but they were also quite
confident about what they were doing
they were saying you have become a part
of large community encrypted law
congratulations you know they were
mocking whoever they were infecting and
they would continue it on in a message
they would also say unfortunately these
sites so basically the sites they were
referring to were the payment websites
and firstly these sites are temporary
because the end of our companies are
interested that you cannot restore your
files but continue to buy their products
you know they were mocking the industry
and mocking the people they were
encrypting their files from doing even
more crypt all projects not malicious
and not intended to harm a person in his
or her information data now they were
just mocking they were nobody seemed to
do anything against them they were just
having fun however the four-point-oh
change wasn't
on all affiliates some are still using
three-point know some are using four
point oh sometimes it drops this you
know the ransom notes where they make
fun of people sometimes it doesn't it
depends on on what kind of affiliates
they have so I'm not sure I think
they're also kind of experimenting with
some new stuff they also change the
communication protocol probably because
there were a lot of publications and how
you could decrypt the stuff so for one
part you couldn't plainly just decrypt
it by doing a hex decode and doing the
same scrambling what they did is if you
look on the PHP files they have on their
proxies they did a nasty trick that
first trip me up as well basically they
take this key and they conferred so in
this case it changed from just a post
location judicial parameters to the last
part and this thing it's the key what
they do is they convert every character
in a string to an integer so apparently
PHP which I'm not really a fan of one of
when it gets a character you cast it to
an integer it just says hey that's not a
number I'll make it zero so instead of
giving any exceptions I was doing you
some pie tin a bite and it's a lot more
compliant that way and starts
complaining about this stuff so what
we're doing if you walk down that string
basically all the characters became zero
and then you had an eight and a five in
there a plus 5 to 13 and this was
basically an offset in the actual hacks
data now you could do decode and you get
the rc4 again just a slight change to
I'm guessing stop automation of this
stuff kind of knowing but fixed it I
have a tool for this I'm going to Lee's
letter and you can just calculate offset
really easily but just you know it broke
a lot of tools for people now through
all this history I want to give a word
of caution basically these guys learn
and profits from everything you publish
on I know it's fun publishing about this
stuff it's fun pointing out stuff that's
wrong but they learn from this so the
first cryptolocker clone they probably
stopped it because of the takedown you
know they wouldn't refer to the name I'm
not completely sure but they change from
Krypto defense 24 script a while because
somebody pointed out there was a
flounder crypto the fixed it meant a new
version because the name was sort of
tainted because people saw it in the
news as being bad
encryption you could just decrypt all
the files so from Krypto one point oh
they sort of moved to the heck website
system and did some tour stuff just
because of frequent takedowns was pretty
easy to kick them down you just took
this proxy server you got to take him
down and then for a while they can do
much and from two point oh they did the
same thing they tried some tour stuff
ITP this wasn't related to publications
but their own findings you know so the
ITP stuff didn't work out was kind of
bugging they move the three-point oh
they went back to the hacked websites
and then from three point out to the
current version they made a change
because somebody made a publication
about them there was a flaw and
basically out of their proxy servers
with filter requests so it could send
stuff like a server stage request it
would upstream to one of the backhands
you would get a server stage page from
the back end they figure this out and
overnight it changed it fix everything
so you know these guys are smart they
adapt quickly they read what people are
publishing about them and if you find
any floss I should just not publishing
these I know it's fun you know it's like
kind of cool when you find something but
these guys they really closely monitor
this stuff you really want don't want to
explain to them what they have to do to
fix stuff you don't want to give them a
free pen test or you know free advice
how to improve their operation so if you
do find something and I shared with
trusted partners or interest groups
there is law enforcement working on a
case can say who what if you want to
work with those send me a message I'll
forward you to some guys where it can
help out do something about these guys
instead of helping them with their
operation basically so infrastructure
this is the generic infrastructure
they've had for a long time to just did
some layering on the top so connect
directly on tour ITP which option to the
tour service or their direct proxy
servers so on the left you have the
proxy server which is just the upstream
requesting to tour this can be the
public payment systems they have or when
a client initially checks in so the
initial check in is actually into the
backend server it has the blue icon if
you find it the fav icon is actually
this blue
thing don't know where they got it the
payment website is in between that's
orange icon you connect to it but it
would actually upstream to the backend
so you know it's just another proxy in
their whole system of proxies and the
operators would also connect on several
separate backends these were also up
streaming on to the other back-end you
know and if you find this login page you
know you found one of the backends that
you can do all kinds of management they
have account management for their
affiliates they can build new samples
they see geographic locations where they
had infections statistics all that stuff
but you know there's more behind it
these guys love proxies like seriously
everything in their whole infrastructure
is proxies they proxy all the things
with layers and layers so it's really
hard to find out where they are and what
you can do about it so you need to
explore it is if find every next hop to
actually get to the backend some
information the outside proxies are
engines with privacy to upstream to
specific 8 and services so either the
affiliate page or the payment wall and
the back end as far as I got is actually
Debian machine running PHP Apache with
my sequel they also have some validation
in this infrastructure so the tier 1
actually decrypter requests they check
if it's valid dear to validate sexual
request post locations so you cannot do
server stage stuff anymore and the back
end completely parser in order to
confirm what you're doing and the
payment wall and affiliate stuff is
similar to your too so just filtering on
specific stuff they don't want to pop up
so interesting discoveries i made over
time so they have this really unique
logo they put on the first version ever
and they put on every payment website is
this just a lock simply part of a big
set of icons and it's just an icon pack
they stole from somebody who made this
so soumya graphic so i won't name them
name of the guy because he doesn't need
to be affiliated with this they just
stole his work and put it on my
ransomware a while ago about a year ago
they were screwing up some internal
systems in their infrastructure so if
you did the server stage request you saw
this so just a normal serve stage
request only
you looked at it I you would see there
was actually up streaming so we get
server status pages from different
backends depending on which Brock's you
would ask this stuff too it's kind of
interesting you could figure out their
proxies this way at some point they were
also putting messages so in their
initial Packer wrapper around the whole
core of crypto wall so here's our crypt
of our shut up and listen you know they
like to have fun make fun of people but
one thing they also do just like they
check up with people write about them
they keep track of new techniques so in
November 2014 power tool guy over in
China he made this proof concept to run
code or actually execute something if I
compiled HTML files and he uploaded a
park of this on mega no fe detected is
USC doesn't pop up and anything so then
februari 2015 came and these guys were
using this they used this to spread and
they went as far as to not even remove
the name of the original guy so they
just took the proof concept they pasted
it in some stuff to just download crypto
law and executed and the guys name was
still in there one more thing this if
you go if you decode the whole Corps you
get to the school of I which is just you
know if you want to insult somebody say
to him it's in there I don't know why
it's if somebody if you're looking at
this if you get into the whole Corps
there's the file names of the ransom
notes and if you go 16 bytes up there
are four bytes which if you decode it is
this I have no clue there's no reference
to it but what was interesting at some
point where i found is that they made
the slip up and i made to slip up all
the way in the beginning so i said there
was this compressed blob witcha
cryptolocker clone downloaded right
which was this thing now if you looked
at it you saw some artifacts from a PNG
header it's kind of compressed you know
there was some stuff missing now what it
actually was it was like a like a small
data container so the first four bytes
with the size they can get the whole
size you could decompress it with rtl
you compress you could get sort of a
list of small file blobs indicated with
it checksum
we did a size and then the actual data
so made a small script to decode is
because I was interested in what was
actually inside was a bunch of PNG files
some text files and if you looked at the
images you got this it's kind of
interesting they weren't on the actual
locker they weren't used in the locker
at any point if you look at the HTML
file so you fix it up a little bit you
saw this now that's even more interested
these are the police lockers
specifically the ones from a group
called elevate on which is a group that
has doing been doing this these lockers
on Android and you know web page lockers
for a long time the actual code from
processing these payments was the same
as the guys from Quebec on the first
version of crypto all you know you could
pay money back you cash this exact same
payments you could do with these guys to
locker but you know this this
disappeared day went on to Bitcoin ever
since crypto defense what's kind of
interesting there was you know the code
the these foul blobs were also used for
these lockers first day with the old
lockers which just request all the
different images from the lock page from
a server but this one would actually get
a foul blob the latest version which was
similar to the crypto wall stuff so
maybe lead to the author's so quickly
I've got some tools I made a request
decrypter a client in the server I'm not
going to release the server simply
because I said this one's on Twitter I'm
not going to release something with
which you can patch old samples and
actually run your own ransom or
operation I don't like that stuff I
don't like Elvis or transfer so I'm not
going to help them so this tool you can
just rip the responder requests and
responses so you know you give to post
location key parameter key would decrypt
response i made a client allows you to
communicate with the proxies or the
backend servers it's all inviting you
can do it interactively and I just use
it to explore these command IDs so it's
currently broken because a four-point-oh
I'll fix it later it's on get up I'll
publish it tonight or something so
quickly thank you to some friends spread
from our traffic analysis go to his
website there's tons of resources if you
want to do analysis and stuff Nick
Hoffman for sharing some old samples
check helpless there's a guy in Twitter
who shares a ton of information in his
free time awesome guy and there's
tons more unnamed people and I'm just in
time I had too many slides sorry papa I
on the diseased tree enjoys it um any
questions oh very oh this one it's 0 x3
a which is accident ation of a column 0
x3 a tom has a question hi morning nah
nothin and have you looked into Tesla
crypt we've seen it very actively being
distributed in Switzerland just very
recently I have some what I've been
looking at some of the proxy stuff
because what they're doing is to mimic
encrypt a while so the lock screen
decoupling from Krypto all the backend
server do you know the looks stolen from
Krypto all and there now also doing the
heck proxy stuff all crypto wall so
maybe my next thing next to still
tracking these guys because I've looking
at the these guys since 2013 I'm kind of
done with them so I haven't looked at it
too much now whatever okay thanks
okay thank you I nailed it