but
K
hello everyone
lol
welcome alright
ok with us closer
okay
hours okay welcome everyone
I today like to talk
we view on that about about just about
forty minutes it's all about four min
and its relevance still infrastructure
and virtualization
I also just for me to know how many are
using or no
foreman here wonderful
I can go out now thing okay Corp
so its new set of lights are hopefully
it's not boring for for everyone
including myself
to do repeat and
on I meaning maybe I'll fail with the
new flight so bear
me alright so for so are we talking
about in terms of nominal do a very
quick introduction up
what form is about so we on the same
page a
no money we're talking about life cycle
observers a
where based ever start somewhere well
when they're initially positioned set up
all the way to whatever needs to happen
to make them
production-ready up to the point where
they
eventually stop could be very short
could be very long period depends on
your
use cases I we specifically
talk about in very a focusing on
integration with configuration
management provisioning services
and monitoring the infrastructure we
actually supposed to be
is it suppose isn't running and
configure the way it's supposed to be
so when we talk about provisioning I
think paula has a
a the unique point of view in terms of
allowing you to go all the way from
bare-metal
I all the way to virtualization and
cloud
we pretty much the same process so if we
think about
large organization usually sadly there's
not not only a single system
this may be very mental and beer or
maybe cloud and or hybrid cloud multiple
data centers will triple combination of
things and when the complexity goes
a higher and higher at the end of the
day the people who actually launch those
stuff
could be API but could also be operators
and we want to simplify the process for
them so it's pretty much the same
process
whether you deploy on bare metal or
employees OpenStack and so on
I'm in terms of configuration
I am I I miss you most if you're well
aware that
about today mostly most configuration on
American thing
career configuration is done with some
sort of a framework whether it's proper
chat fanciful Sol
see if engine and brother and so on so
the idea is
a not simply to try and gap does I
bridge those gaps re: between the
provisioning process
the setup process and the reporting
process
all into unified framework and when we
talk about
a my toe ring is basically making sure
it's not a nag yes typical type
monitoring
but actually making sure that the policy
that you've set your configuration
management policy that you've said
actually I
is done correcting are not correctly and
then you could get
all kind of information about what's
going on also inventory for systems and
and and ability to use
scan in search and get information a
in a nutshell former and architecture a
has basically four major components
we are forming itself which is a Ruby on
Rails application
we have smart proxies we have their
consideration
integration management the compute
resources and obviously the UI APIC line
all those elements so when we talk about
smart proxy is basically a
a mechanism allow for men to reach out
if we've think about
large-scale organization that problem
has lots of data centers lots of
networks
lots of different network types network
segments
proxies kinda a gateway that
woman can reach out and manage remote
services running on remote data centers
are isolated networks
whether it's things like I maybe I know
your DNS or maybe just BMC and manage or
IIPM I bare metal servers
this mark Fox itself because we're
trying to
can imagine that makes a match a lot of
things a smart box itself can actually
run on Windows for example obviously run
Linux and talks to
standard DNS services but can also run
on Windows if you're an enterprise and
you have
some you know Active Directory things
like that so we went we try to integrate
and expose the REST API across all of
those services so it's kind of a
one REST API for example to add DNS and
the name
many providers a in the back and whether
it's Active Directory bind
and so on I the configuration management
so we have a very deep integration the
moment with puppet when it comes to
things and and shift now starting as
well but things like
knowing what's going on known weeks
reports what actually happened on your
system
which inventory do you have and
obviously what is the role and
what which what the system is doing it's
not enough just to
just enough to last the Jews we want to
know exactly what's
a is install on that system what its
purpose maybe
me even more important there's multiple
environment support staging production
other multiple versions of a production
and so on
and integration ball that making it
kinda seem less
as much as possible to the user
um when we talk about compute resources
this is the way for men
basically reach out to remote systems
whether it's the
over there OpenStack being where
ec2 Leeper directly and so on
mobile computers on Rackspace a and
allow
basically obstruct the process of what
is involved what
what's required to actually make a
change in obstructed into single
I'll process regardless of the provider
I'm so we use
alive recall fog I am wouldn't
in Ruby based very popular library which
we
happily contribute in use then we have
another abstraction
which we call computer profiles which
allows us to let's say define our own
sets up the fall for example we could
think about the traditional small medium
large
and then define what is small medium
large and every different provider
a and also for different a set of
customers
so we can use we don't identify for
example OpenStack is
OpenStack obviously its attendant in
OpenStack that's a given user in
OpenStack
thing goes for ec2 and so on and we can
define different sets different people
which one of them so later on we we'll
be talking about the high-level object
for example I want to deploy
a small webster and and that the
position of
I'll a web server or your Apple whatever
it is
is something we call host code which is
basically the system defined that
definition
of your system a so it's
it's a it's a way to say this is the
default operating system i want for my
web services the fall
a puppet relationship marcia
recipes and obviously associated with
the computer profiles
now why I'm telling you that because the
idea is that you can define a high level
of dicks such as a
web server and have the ability for for
men to spin up a VM create an image for
it
on every different provider
automatically so
I have all the information I need up
Braun to define the system regardless
of where it's gonna run I can define to
the web server
I have all the recipes all the
ingredients to make it happen on
different flowers and then I don't need
I can easily transform revealed the same
system
on a different cloud if I would like we
can also do
interesting more interesting things for
example detected
some sort of a drift if there was an a
package update
that we can detect from let's say a
public report and that claims that it
took
a make more than a minute maybe it makes
sense for us to spin a VM making it
snapshot that make an image outta that
and automatically
next time system puts up it will consume
the latest image so there's a lot of a
a nice things we can do abstract that
and I don't know how if you ever use the
traditional image building tools
but this approach actually I uses the
store the storage
out of the you know and provide I'm not
building a
image on my laptop and uploading it to
ec2 for example
I'm actually building it NEC to in the
first place I
when we talk about provisioning we talk
about basically everything we can to
support
so we go all the way up from traditional
PC based
to image-based we can do the traditional
use be
or I so all I txt manipulations we can
if we doing image
obviously use the data or SSH to reach
out to Damon
to the system involved and as a
complimentary when you create a new
system for me all
automatically creates the DNS records if
its peak see the TP reservations
required for the PC
and TFTP and Certificate Signing all
kind of things that are required in the
process
I'm we have also pick sea-based
discovery
this is more for the use cases up I have
a rack of servers
I turn them on I want the automatically
show up and start managed I don't want
to
inside and mac address for every you
bare metal system I got
the stability just two discover all the
system that basically
launch into a many fide a cent OS
a operating system that is like a live
CD
reports all the inventory and then you
can make decisions based on that you
wanna automatically provisioned
or select this system belongs to this
organization
or the stand and so on um
we're also the yet sorry operating
system agnostic so
will happily install for you any of
these
a operating systems a and others if you
willing to send the patches along the
way
a so Esparta I mention it earlier but
it's part of the creation of a system a
lot of things are happening so it's not
just enough to create a VM
and maybe its storage I also want to
create that the NS I want to sign a
certificates
I wanna make sure if expressed
specifically for
for bare metal and Vera I want to
control the IP address
so we have like the address management
and I that we offer automatically and on
use IP address
and and a lot of things that happens
when you create a new system
that's completely expendable for plugin
system there's a
hope plugin hoaxes that allow you to at
your own hooks and we try to
when something fails we actually make a
lot of effort to ensure that we don't
leave
stuff tackling so if I create a VM I
failed to create the storage or factory
something else I'm not gonna leave
something in the air
that you IP address will be used and no
one can use it anymore
for example now
now we've we've been around and we know
that most of these features are mostly
for enterprise users people who have a
very complicated and large environments
and that regards we obviously integrate
with either held up Active Directory
Kerber of
and whatever here SSO approach if you
know how to
configure remote user: in about you for
example
we had our Barack we have detailed audit
logs
and we also have multi tenancy
multi-location so
you can go up to the the final location
as
I don't know resso or you can define
wreck 5 in
bristles Data Center West whatever
someone so
there's a hierarchy I that you can go
down in the final patience is so
we try really to make a
traditional sysadmins lives a bit easier
obviously when we have this kind of
system we would know
which resources or the administrator
will define which resources are
available for example for
which location are organization so we
would know that this
network for example is accessible in
this building or this network
or you know something in your
infrastructure is mapped basically
to a a given context a given context
the q/a team willing main be allocated
to different resources than
engineering team and location A or B and
so on
I'll no foreigners really really
pluggable
the lot there are a lot of plugins this
is really just the
finalist of logins plugins could be as
a simple as sending a u-boat you
sorry a you put notification or
as comp complete that or feature full
features like as
Patel over content management and this
really a lot of
everyone can extend this is tradition of
your Ruby on Rails developers
this is a just rails engine with some
API around it so
it's really easy to extend and and at as
required
I'll obviously it comes with a REST API
I'm we have multiple versions of API
that we we know that you know API's one
of the
most important thing we try not never to
break so we have
we went through the exercise adding
multiple versions
and out of the API the res 3ds
I think one of the things really useful
is the powerful search in PI
that means we have a release reach a
search language which allows you to
figure out and find the exact resources
that you're actually looking for
regardless the in the specific context
so you can easily
automate over the API we've specific
search query
a and you can fully automated a very
natural example is
I want to monitor or something which
what do I need to monitor or so you can
simply define a search query
I want to monitor all of my web service
in location
bristle so you define it as a search
query you feat that back into your
configuration management
and your consideration and systems
conceivably that
managed or I'll start monitoring it
automatically
you don't need to start writing all your
customized a
scripts that whenever a new system comes
up I need to add it to my monitoring and
all
all kinda I things like that
I'll try to show if there's enough time
will try to show some demo around that
we also have a full-featured a Celi call
hammer
I'm similar we took the approach of the
get submodules
so to hammer and similar commands it
uses the
be too API and it's actually built from
day one
to support forman plugins that means
that if you write your own
a plug into forming you can actually
extend to see a live with plugins
that automatically a dynamically learn
from the API
are in various options that you can
thank you
now I wanted to put some me so call you
know try to put a bit of
all over real use case that the actually
use for men
that may be more bit more relevant room
and
I think deploying OpenStack is something
that a
pretty large topics been discussed
heavily and
as you saw earlier this triple 0 this
quite a lot of different tools
every configuration management to has
its own set up
recipes to deploy it and we try to make
this
problem a bit smaller a possible
I'll and using a customized woman plugin
and I'm so I'm just gonna show you a few
a screenshot so
this is based on our geo for those who
don't know are to:
is a distribution of OpenStack
for cent OS and rail base operating
systems
which is pretty easily too pretty easy
to install and total package then
and and all of that I'm and Rd own phone
actually comes together bundle together
see if you using are the only an
accidental format
their configured when you configure the
audio repositories
and this case is just yum install and
for men form in OpenStack I'll
the installer and basically we get back
to form in with a set of slot you know
screens
that allows great a given that open star
cluster
so obviously you can create multiple
clusters of OpenStack
you know staging testing small meaning
latest whatever
a and you can just be fined tries to the
guide you through I'll for
for the various you know what is the a
bit about the networking
a bit about various
farm it is a few I don't know if you
have a che off-roading IP's
I'm and allow you to override any
a different values it also automatically
generate passwords and we try
it's not perfect will be tried to
simplify the process of deploying
OpenStack
still someone with Alan knowledge can
actually even
deploy OpenStack in relatively
straightforward manner
two to three screens click Next and
Rowntree OpenStack
there's a lot of options for OpenStack
and I think the diversity here is what
makes it so challenging because there's
a lot of
I'll overlapping combinations in
OpenStack
and this is a real problem for
configuration management in general
and we're working hard now in coming up
with a new approach
in in the configuration management area
to try and and solve that but I guess
this is another
topic for another room I'll generally
about four months community
the the project is about four year old a
roughly 200 fifty-plus users on the
mailing
on Darcy and some pictures here you can
see
a we're trying we're growing as we go at
me as much as we can
these are roughly the numbers the
most of our users or I would assume all
our users are enterprise users or
users with infrastructure otherwise
doesn't make sense to use
this kind of a product I'll
and I hope hi
convince you bits to get started I'll
try to do a demo but in between will
pause for a second for questions I mean
the get started you can obviously see it
on the website if you go there some
tutorial videos how to get started
we have a really active IRC channel and
decent user group so
if you have any questions before I try
to do a live demo
go at now's the time
yep how to deploy Windows that with the
question
can ask you a question back why no
getting
I
alright Windows Deployment at the moment
it's possible for image-based
provisioning only
I'm so if you have a a template in over
or an image in OpenStack and so on it's
possible just like any other
I'll you know if its user data
driven or SSH weekend ok into that
and yep your
sorry your provisioning method sounds a
lot like
would razor does you guys in today with
razor are so
so we don't agree razor directly there
are some overlap
ball I'll try to give background to your
question right
not sure i won understand raisers the is
a great provisioning tool
on started by overlap
they're here I'll which has
started from day one with the discovery
principles in mind that means to you
turn on servers and they can
automatically assign themselves
roles be functionality based on
predefined roles
arm for an excessive before
and we added the discovery functionality
similar to raise or somewhere around
after raising started we did consider
using
razor is a compute providing informant
a and but that never happened from
one reason or another it's not a you
know we had a lot of that logic already
didn't make it didn't necessarily feel
right to rewrite that point drop all
those stable lines of coke
for for out are at that point in time
you know
a bit our alpha product I
I think today razors a great product if
it solves the problem that you
if you're facing it's great and you
should use it I think we're trying
aim the overall use cases
razor is a service in that regard that
it can
create bare metal systems that you can
consume very mild my bare metal systems
this case we're trying to add another a
few more they mentioned the management
of
the whole I'll problem but they
okay like more questions there any
get I'd
like to see the future for me let you
see the future forming where they see
the future for men
I'll so there is a short short their
future in the long term future
I'll short term
wanna the involved
one of the completely new two main
functionalities we're adding to forming
besides a
enhancing the confidence we have is
personal everything around content
management that mean
the ability to classify your content
management life cycle so what is
production which packages of production
what do they mean how do we do testing
and staging and and how do we
promote content from one point in time
or one
said a function out to another so when I
deploy a system
I'm not just randomly getting a set of
rpm
for example repository and configuration
data
from a seven point in time where I
installed it but actually
as a way that you can say this is
production
I can I can be pulling my production of
this production I can take the
production that was five years ago in
the point now
again to really try to look at the whole
continent problem
something which is kinda a snapshot of
content
that is consumable as you go forward
this is important with you if you have
to have
multiples I'll versions
of your production maybe you have two
sites and once I can
perform a change in the given time the
others I can perform a change in another
time
argue orchestrate all that that's one
thing
the other thing we're working on we're
working on extending their
remote execution framework in this and
more for complicated workflows
so if you need to dynamically
orchestrate change across multiple
systems
you know I'll take a and I'll take an
example from
from over for example when you want to
upgrade
a hypervisor you need what you need to
do
you basically need to go the chai
provide put it in maintenance mode so
all the PM's running on it will
live migrate to another VM then you
wanna upgraded packages may be for karen
was upgraded you want to reboot the
system
then you don't you wanna go to the next
one you know put
take it out on maintenance to go to the
next one a into the south
cycle again this is just one example of
often orchestration framework that
as a problem that we're trying to Sol we
want to build a framework that is easy
to use
that can automate this kind of work plus
and there's probably a lot of things
that
happen you know is an open source I
project
where amazingly surprised the pull
request that we get
so the site that I have no
you know where we'll well will be in two
years
we'll see alright
or questions only this guy
were okay alright
so I'll try do given we have enough time
right
david is a nap time enough time
okay cool so I'll try to jump into a
demo
if the gods Wireless will allow me a
see alright so this is foreman's
a dashboard I'm
in here we can see a better and a pie
chart
showing us what r which state are
systems are
so I could see that forty percent on my
systems are in OK state they
that means that they've Ron
configuration agent on them
but a puppet and up and executed
and there were no changes that means the
policy that the predefined is applied
everything's working great move on they
are think basically means
a nothing happened so that the agent did
not run and we don't know whether to
what is the actual state of the system
at the moment and no reports
the I no report means never send the
report
not so interesting there's also other
states this is a life system or
my laps set up so there's there are more
rare earth but obviously something
failed to execute
or things like that we could see I am
we have a Nazi
we have all obviously I it's too slow
try to see if I can I have a local copy
of the database
maybe
no okay will
go back to VPN but this takes a while
I so while you look at that the
I guess on my a so
basically I am this is to stop
I would encourage in the meanwhile olive
you to come we have a booth outside that
the
k building and also if you happen to be
in there in Gantt
on Monday and use they there's a
configuration management camps we can
ask more questions
is also couple more talks about are
continues in
integration infrastructure and
integration with Chef happening
a today and tomorrow and
on unless the now this is too slow
sorry I
the sites that I think I covered the
basics there's more question to say
save me so go ahead
the question was what is the relation
between former then heat
or is there a every nation ship between
former nanny
at the moment there is no the
integration between foreman and heat
I would love to see one I would love to
see heat
be able to consume resources from
forming that would love to see forman
the manage he templates I think these
are two things we would love to see
I'm and yeah with
that much in a bit too small I'll
but I generally this is at the moment is
no such
such them yes
question back yep
okay so the question was if there's a
plan to
fix host group by okay the
so this is only for those you actually
using it and
and know the problem a so host group I
have a nature or can it be able to
inherit
so you could define a top-level pace
for my app and I love that you can say
the my database and my web
server or my whatever functionality and
you could go nests
very much unlimited level of a
down in the tree and you can ship
armistice between those
you can share those benefits you could
be fine things that are common thread
to and share information between those
using search or
other mechanism I and one of the things
and I
correct me if I'm wrong if I translated
correctly but what you mean
basically that ability I not to redefine
public office or
what what is the exact problem okay
so so at the moment informing it's
possible to
so we started with the term host group
and later on its actually going to
something
we now look at the system definition and
if we look at this
look at it from Asus as a system
definition going to view
it doesn't make sense persistent have
multiple definitions
and but to solve that specific problem
we we are now will be working in the
probably in the near future to
handle a classes
and classes group that can be reassigned
so take what you look maybe as host open
try to
expected to another object that could be
applied multiple
then you could apply multiple but they
puppet group a puppet
classes recipes whatever it will be
called and you could try to solve it
and out approach but this still be only
one post for persistent yes but will
will try to handle that specific use
case which i think what this what you're
paying
we can take it offline and maybe you can
enlighten me why we're doing it wrong
I'll be more than happy to learn how to
do it right
right anything else
okay arm let me quickly try
open some tab so they're bits not as
slow
so when we talk about and last
okay open the fuse you slide that see
okay alright
a this concludes the live demo a
the
more than happy to show later on we'll
make sure that we have a working life
then later on down the road
so you feel feel free to play
thanks everyone
that
old
field
bugs
price
school yup
month
right
is it on
art
Sol hello everyone
up
hello this up
good
up
that
the pope I'm not some
spiegel hi final