was a mint
alright so
all the talking little bit about the
Tegra
mine
my and some other people's efforts to
try to understand the
thats intern working or other for berkes
author yes but is this
drivers so
personal to land but a bottle I am on
have about the twenty years graphics
programming experience to know those
here 7 Professional in
his work it's arm and thanks for an
at the mall a driver team making
the drivers that look care has been so
friendly to
try to pick apart a
and while doing that I was involved in
the development of the OpenGL ES 1.1 and
2.0
standards on lovers reasonably active
open source country reuther a mime
biggest portion of that miss
forgets but also the
casual pipe a
and I'm an active de Masi nurse thano
now so that its
and fortune no
because other they don't there's love
them a stronger
oh I have released a lot of DeMoss farm
is the work at our im
what my I'll sir
right so on missus title great I'll tell
me a little bit about
what greatest that's the nomogram for
terrazzo
probably didn't seem but and
it's a it's an effort to reverse
engineer the Jeep you
and eventually to create an open source
driver from it I it's probably the
furthest behind of all these
arm such a projects a
due to not very much time well
available for doing this but I
yeah will still give it a go ion
the usual everything here is based on
reverse engineering so
you know don't invest all their life
savings into something
based on something until you hear it's a
most information much
indeed be incorrect I
so I'll Tolbert abouts what has happened
so far um areas in the summer 4th 2012
Diana
I N heard about that Lima project and i
John there are
RC channel but it was so boring because
I'm and it into
did to my arm work so i cant touch their
stuff so instead I decided or
rather large commencement to start
looking at the Tehran I
and then so I'm just quietly backed away
and the
around for some last year I had well
implement and countless
months from a capturing
and parsing second pick it apart and see
a beautiful something
and I did some and the tools
the cheddar database arm reg is that a
vis
for on the some other
I say the says most will open the lists
numb center stage but its it's a bit
difficult because so love this getting
compiled into the shade or social I'm
I've had a very rough fragment shader
disassembler
a and I had the a
reverse engineer the proprietary
compiler a shared object interface I
can't
compile shares from my own programs
without using their driver a
and then I got bork bork its and
kinda fun stops working for a while
so I at that point or a
so a few months I think among players oh
I was told by
look that I had to get my ass onto
IRC because something some most so
almost doing something
and I was Terry and
and it turned out he had the not at all
been man
idling while I was procrastinating a
so he yen already I think been working
on the
on the mimics kernel drivers
he started packing together some my lip
DRM
interface for that and
the replayed come on streams and it has
known RDX driver
and a even did some work and volume
so for Massa I
and then yeah jerry has hired by ended
up
so I I'm
slowly trying to gonna follow up on my
own one is doing
a but bear in mind that my biggest
interest terrorist the reverse
engineering part not so much the driver
development part
because I've already it's that scratch
at our so them but I will
I will you know give it a go but they're
all summer terror and a more also mark
in the future has thrown in the green
t-shirt back
but they're and also I
should mention that Rob Clarke whose
that's doing the for drina project s
also had some
had a little bit of bleach at some other
some other stuff
so helped a little bit as well so
yeah the the current status as of now
the so this was
you know the year ago I am so yeah
I'm basically I've been focusing on
Tegra 2
I
I'm Tegra 3 in for I will mention a
little bit about the
its now so we have an
months trend on things we can replay
that
and do some basic rendering rendering
been
tampering with a lot of states to could
have confirmed suspicions
so for us so we can with new you know
little bit of
souter a
down there some upstream Linux the arm
driver
and now it's even as of: think a
to three weeks ago or so it support for
the
for the 3d core downstream outlived I am
support
the blue thing cerrar links and my
I in the slides but I'll put them up
online
someone wants them meant a
and I we have a very very unfinished
masai Gollum
driver and can only do Jill clarren
Repik suspects
yeah its at least some basic stuff
working
that deals with no
telling him these kinds of things so the
Tegra 3
since just work it I don't
I don't really know this but thats I
haven't seen any real differences in the
and I come on stream so it looks like
that's just the same
Precor a figure for
has some more registers a with
found I'm some other
I don't think it's strictly compatible
as and I think the first
amounts transferred it didn't replay
there but
there has been replayed a some months
trims
container for hardware so it seems to be
roughly roughly compatible
day one a you heard about those of you
who were in the last time the previous
talks
probably heard a little bit about that
its Kepler based
at its only has the Jeep you are the
three core from
Kepler a rest luv de force and
infrastructure since the been lacking
there so
I have not done any work guess down
focusing on the three coram
on the Tegra so that don't that's being
replaced
Anya this is something that will have to
deal with yes
what
let's discuss that later
I'm be I I need to to work with the guys
and some things
a yeah
so I won't talk more anything more about
the the k-1
and the stock missus just
short summer
alright so it's just them all but
apparently we can't stop my
I'm not so good at reading email so I
miss the detail i cant connect
HDMI equipment to the big screen
and mine them a platform doesn't have an
external monitor so
back and show you anything here either
Yemen
so I don't have a screen to show it on
either
so ap and turn
trims lies it's been less than us so I'm
sorry about that it wouldn't have been
too exciting it's just like a rotating
triangle with grown children so it's a
that's a
the protests were for a quick little hut
yep
so imagine that trying rotating I guess
at so I O I'll go a little bit into the
into the hardware I so
as Chaudhary author the Jeep use the
its them its codename they are 20 from
them
and missus them deeply
found some traces but deeply down and
some columns %uh via
a its animated mode runner
it consists of at least three components
I'll the graphics 2d and 3d
for and then there's also some kinda
video system a
and Calder decoder I don't really know
the spectra I
yeah but plans are programmed the so the
this could components a program through
something called host 1x
which is a DMA engine for on writing
registers the to the GP is a drives the
trust the Jeep you and
it has a proprietary OpenGL ES driver
which is useful for
version genera
I ass on the GR to the is that it's a
and
its public plan document on great so
this means that everything that's
needs to be doing in the deck striving
for instance
available 'em yeah and it's a sign up
the mic return
turn and disorder license agreement but
its it's not
very strict on a
they have source code available for on
for
doing some glitz and stuff like that a
it can do the a lot of different things
really and what's Phils
whether you know telling parents a
likened tiling
are linear nonlinearly addressed sources
are
surplus a again this
stretching rotating flipping but only
like turnin
other so most was 90 degrees rotation
a some fun blending
I and coverage sampling and a listing
resolve which is a but interesting I
think can do
up three was more so it can do basically
it's capable of doing all the all other
to day operations from jail second day
for blending and
or both would mask stance on asking him
with the
censoring all these things so yeah it's
quite capable I am
yeah the gr 3d is
I yeah
a bit different a it's a it's a non
unified shader
so the it has a separate partition
cheddar
and British and French enter ISA I am
and yeah it performs blending in the
fragment shader rather than fixed
function
sergeants which means that we need to
recompile the shaders
old-time a it all
only has a 16 that the floor for but it
seems to her for
added support for for 24 bits as well
with us
the 16 rent render targets including
that from San switches
quite a lot where support seclusion
curious
a quite a bit of the picturing features
although the they do have some kind of
Numb power of two
pictures which s not
so nice are other it it only supports
the well it supports that without
without permit perhaps
but also with the with met maps for them
if you run
achieve try to access outside of their
01 range than getting
undefined result so yeah
there some
separate extension file I
yeah the standard or derivatives
and the a a quite interesting I think
draw a path extension
which is for drawn to the graphics the
Berserker some
things like that I haven't really they'd
into that
but its to interesting feature so
it might be but bisous this feature
softer only from the
from the driver
rights there's a video product but I
haven't for tonight's
I'm not a video experts I'm not gonna
try that either
if anyone wants to have a look at it
feel free to
alright so I'm the vertex shader
instructions
instructions that is basically a subset
of Leandra 30
which is sana means that it can do for
component vectors
vectors for me normal ale you
instructions or single-component
a scaler as a view and sections and
it seems to be able to those in peril
although I don't
think I'm ever seen the compiler
generate that a
there it has no so the control flow so
loop since been rolled
I but its very straight forward to
generate conferred looks basically
exactly like to TJs I
so yeah %ah
and the there's already a back-end the
nine-man a false messiah
driver so probably to share some
code there
yeah the front and center ice I ISAs
quite a bit more interesting slash
crazy a so all the registers are
either what representing one 20 bit
floating point value
or to time but fixed point was that sir
2.86 the this point signed
on their
are at least three separate instruction
stream so there's
the the prohibition programs are not one
stream of instructions there there's
three different
at least I suspect there's five but
haven't
really figured out all details a
streams and the the their are some
additional comes
control streams that kind of the fine
how they get executed
are scheduled I'll with each other
so there's the yeah the alias trendy and
I'm
are manic much unit and there's the
multifunction units which just both
varying installation
and complete function evaluation
so dusa typically you know meant what
barings over the triangle
or and/or the
do sine cosine this handsome things I'm
and it seems that some those two are not
executed in the same clock which so
the instruction artists room for
encoding both kinds of instructions and
the same
then if word and now it seems there
securing the two different books I am
there's a texan units and then there
seems to be some kind of export units
for
writing the out the
caller to the Columba for and disbursed
some not one so I was just under and
share the spill registers
somewhere that mean even more stuff
starts the show up but I haven't
really a understood that party
and %um there's no control flow
whatsoever so olives group unrolled all
conditionals
don't become other a national selector
products
so the Baillieu 'em unit
its pretty well understood there's only
like the
the few bits that arms
there are so only a few bits that ives
I see pop-up let I don't not yet
Phil have a good understanding of what
means and instructions come in
packets a flower for I
64-bit words a which I there are
for scale operations a or
3 skiller for operations and the
up to up to 4 a.m. but it comes so
that either you know either
to twenty-fifths floats or are
now forces time but
3.5 hours
and the other estimate is basically a
glorified Madden
can do a this
at one this nation for resource our
brands missus so this is
llame an example for for that visit the
mad instruction and have some bits to
choose
a some of the different modes for it
squares thing
component before doing it are at change
the order of
adding so it can all plan for it out
some
these kinds of things I'm are before bus
and is also has to say but that since
the
seems to mean that accumulates the
result so
a the this nation register just come ads
to it a and when it does I did use a
some kind of special
accumulation registered since and its
also house
min max international Select and I think
as a minor stunning
so far as that when induced if you
change the man's to
men is still get the the sea stuff so
still tries to add Singh so it
so quite just just postero i'm for
scenes that
so slight problem yeah
and all the although I daily inspections
have a
predicaments so so there are some
condition register that
that gets sucked Amanda
that connects to execute conditionally
this summer
yeah the results can separate the
source Branston absolute on negates the
that's right seems to have some are
under him but I transit them a
the multi-function units this problem
based on this paper
call the high-performance RF Ishan
multiple fresh mint litter
which is some and media research paper
propose the idea for merging the firing
and the
and the complex function about your 21
so the complex functional inner part is
pretty much a mister thats
very simple just takes a register and
and in and writes that this nation %uh
the result
the same register as the source and it
does
police operations I'm and to people and
they just I'll there sir
two-step I train and also
the the exponential function
so I haven't the
started what the intermediate result is
but it doesn't Center
doesn't seem to require an extra extra
values
or anything like that so it might be
bring reject range reduction are
something other
and
to and but the Merengue right to still a
minute mister s
a see where by see which varying at and
blitzen image
instruction right camp Fig figure out
which register it
rights to and the I've had
had some friends look at this rope
Larkhall
also her look at them stuff haven't been
able to figure it out
some mister so yeah was for someone else
wants to have a look at them that would
be also yeah
leave texturing construction is so
somewhat no understood its
it seems thing coating is rather simple
it's not entirely clear
how it passes the picture for not a
that's not so much that's a it's a
mystery but
more that's you know I haven't really
felt like working
too much I'm not a without getting the
firings working because
looking up the same the same
a fish apartment for an entire triangle
is
extreme little line Tristan its
foreign that but it seems simple
a both lookups have to thank you maps
the
compoz onto the exact same binary code
so
it seems the the the harbour deals with
all the
all the stuff for so now
well there's no need to France's
normalize the kidnapping but just saw my
Zeiss
require
and then there's the export an ass and
section but I'm
a fun which which
runs are you its it rights to butts the
rest is just
looks like garbage to me surprise so I'm
now
I'm not really to spit on that other
yep so as you guys problems and the
this is rough stuff from and to help the
stuff on the one in
a there are some things that needs to be
done
I saw this is just implementation
working mothers
this this song versions nearing
so that we have a bunch live DRM patches
that
should be upstream a
and yeah finishing out the
kinda for the details a
we should probably have an ex RDX driver
finished their
is a stub driver but it doesn't do
anything
with the have except from mode setting a
yes
so
doesn't accelerate and an amp drawing
a yeah and so that's
this is the GR for an answer out into
this pretty much
document its it should be pretty he said
do also and we have a working with
diadem interface so
so it's made mostly kind of knowing
really how
the GDX interface works I think you're
gorgeous the biggest
I don't know the ex the but the deck
stuff but also
from it would be quite a bit of reading
code to
understand what min saddam yeah
a member's servers and learn the Bering
rights
are as I said still a mystery the said
that Prime genetics
a exporting and then there's registers
billing which happens
the happens if it didn't use registers
and they also sent to trigger the same
kind of could pass if you use
more than more than
32 uniforms because there's only
the non-uniform afloat co-processor
and there's some weird stuff there I
don't really see where the
the extra uniforms that some to the
harbor at all but its
dust work in this does give the right
result so so it's a little strange
so maybe maybe there's something wrong
with my come on stream stuff air
yeah yeah and there's the
MSI column driver and thats huge
huge bitch his work and its
probably going to go on for years so I
am
that's pretty much mine talk there some
questions
a
you a helped others the
a olds and BDS the with which never
drives
that so Tecra and Kepler heavily all
relate them
it's in a booth at the Karachi its
developing notation
terrorists apart from the vertex shader
being now
being mami 30 basically the vet said
that is based on the
open should I say so it's yeah
that millions those even them the bit
fields are exactly the same
yeah so it's the so it's
the Events section and I'm pretty sure
they're just both a llama conover
chatter
stirred and cat was the desktop
technology not related to
Accra yet what they do to go out the
who pick up the k-1 is just cover letter
but seat has nothing to do with the old
Cup
the ought to go yeah I should probably
start using AR
they are 20 rather than to grow because
it's a
tigress a product lineups energy field
line damn marketing people
yeah his
I'll admit I haven't been keeping up to
date with
a I went and read it does and does not
release i think im
on the new beau Saif a starter slowly
share or
act your start work with the community I
thought it was in the impression that I
was reading that
Tegra was I am more open source in any
of their other
work had their phones are far so for Jah
Cure biggest only thing that is not
to open source in there src so a
the Tegra Tiger has great support in the
in the kernel the can work this the
that they did they do excellent work and
and
support first purely users as missing
right now
uses base dismissing and a
and I'm I'm talking a bit to sum it up
people and
and there that trying to get some
agreement to get some
information out the I don't think
there's any chance that they will open
up their drivers are
are the documentations and other
questions
use it the most job board with the
project view with the
reverse engineering part working on the
chips kitty just ago
through you'll work blown a tool to use
that part of the project
sure yeah the I should've spoke a bit
about that I guess
a we haven't we have a bunch of the
tools a
knots and where a sophisticated us the
foster for
or anything like that but the we do have
a an repository
called great time to come under the the
under the I was a call organization
great dash driver a that contains
a some my british chick into
open jail programs Lincoln LD preload
and it will dump out the workman streams
that are sent to the
for the crime or I am missiles from that
the we have a had
disassembler for the merger some
fragment shaders
a so
that but actually takes GLS also risk
source code compiles and whether on
tired compile and dumps out
the disassembler towards like the
compilers a bit crazy because it are
mcrae someone untraditional in the way
that its out but
its binary is actually a command lists
buddy a cement
to the to the
hard for her to the campus so it's not
it's not just the instruction streams
its you actually gets
the whole thing to up a
yeah there's some other I have the
I have think into bed and some stuff
with the with them the tools
have some documentation for register
that's their
I am planning to some but up streams at
some point
cuz I've I've also added some personal
to them the tools for instance
reading planets floating-point yeah I
so that so I
now that i think thats pretty much it
for the tooling
terrier Moran thing important now
yes oh and I'm
the workflow is basically writing small
open delia's program sumber
looking at what they're what they're
doing a
what the output is how it changes when I
change the
sequence of commands I
am could you go into a slight bit more
detailed up what exactly
the upstream looks like like for
instance this exhorted the X Drive with
that you have on the to do this
that the except 86 with you printer from
Chile that
like brahmin for over a year or yeah
development happening in other places
now
now yes %uh there's nothing has happened
although the next driver ass and sister
terrorists working hours
sensei gets hired by Amadeus and so high
that
their arm there has been a little bit
talk from Invidia
about put the possible to have open
sourcing their
existing Tegra driver so that might
happen
but that I wouldn't have my hopes too
high fly either now
and what about the %um how does that
relate to like
the could have great project yes 0
there's
to this current the two different they
had lived their arms for
for Tehran one that is some in 10 by
someone that
MIDEM for and for the kernel from
contesting the cum
and then there's other one which is men
$10 by all the guides had me they are
other
Terry and I i think I'm the one doing
the most things muscle maps
now so there's what the one under the
great product project which
I think is a cleaner approach to it
the the
and the other one has said high-level
API that this
little bit too high level I think tablet
same I have some in there in the
in the repository there some tests for
doing some blitz and stuff like that
with them
with the to the unit so some functions
from
injecting the right stuff so I think get
I think the
the the deck stuff for someone who knows
but driver should be fairly
ezer I mean to the extend for you now
writing and so for Cesar
it's a a its
a its old known problems really and
are is that that crosses like waiting on
certain design decisions that are in
packed I'm waiting on the rivers and
some
is open which is to complete with mister
something where people can actually help
our
or where you are but you have like a
time frame when you can
you're done know when it might be
available and Nana this this and there's
no
kind of project management at all there
sir just some
repose and some code and the a
a so if someone wants to pick something
up from they're free to that a
I would appreciate if they'd let me know
that they're they're working on it so
I'm not
spending time on or something but apart
from that so the
yeah and there's basically me and a
other specimen just me doing something
right now
right but seems to fit thank you
%ah