I think everyone settled in you jump in
here
I'm mine is just the bonds at work in
the until open source technology center
with but then it was just presented an
several others
who were were here today on the another
team graphics are primarily in
miscellaneous other GP related stuff
inside Intel
but today I'll be talking about
I'm then tell better platform and I
actually want to come with us last year
but I only got approval to talk about
anything in any detail
this year so push forward I'm so
some this may not be a totally new to
you especially if you've been reviewing
but
what came out IVF a couple months ago on
Bay Trail but
I'm this is something I'm really excited
about because it's a
it's a a new src for us
um in a couple ways it's gotta I'm a new
Cebu
I'm resigned I'm CPU and a a
and new GP relative to our previous src
products sows it's a it's really
interesting and we've also been involved
on
on the the bring up and some other
design work from very early on the open
source anything so it's
that's exciting for us from my
perspective as well wasn't just totally
driven by
when the stuff or or Howard on solely
with windows that sort of thing
so you may like I said this is a I'm
a new src I'm specifically focus that
like the tablet market
and convertible market I'm not
it's not designed to go into phones
doesn't quite have the the power
envelope that you need for that in love
with immigration in for that but it does
make a previous a tablet chip
its working arts five-dollar are 22
nanometer process which isn't hard
bleeding edge which is the the bottle
stuff that we're pushing out now that's
on 14 and Amir
but are 22 nanometer process is pretty
good its it's premature and
I'm works well for us there really big I
mean
its a really big change both you and
your viewers for us
on the SRC sidon on the other side I'm
and like I said the elec stuff was
was a priority from early on and the Lex
team
has been involved up you know are open
source
team doing 1x drivers has been a ball
from very early on we record
power on the silicon first came back for
the factories doing the initial
debugging development
over for driver stack so band who may be
some around here was at that
can grant to use on the Mesa team was
there
helping and I'm we got you know three
games up and running and stuff within a
day
were to have getting stable silicon so
that was really exciting
I so it's on the slides you may think
that is a really pretty how did you come
up with those well I didn't know
these mostly stolen from idea so
hopefully there will be two
24 marketing stuff but BR the whole
world is the overall architecture the
the chip so it's it is an associate
gotta watch my PB
blocks on it but the big changes are the
new
Adam up two quad-core and then the new
HD graphics which is I'm not new from
the client side it's basically an Ivy
Bridge graphics part
but it's been shot down and put onto the
SRC
so if you're familiar or if you've been
following our
our previous out and stuff you know that
I'm
earlier chips used the IP block from the
machination
the PBR graphic stuff and I'm sure
everyone has a lot of love
for their for their stuff from no be sad
to see it go but now we've got Jan
graphics and stand
to have to tolerate that I
and then you know it's going kinda
similar feature set to what you'd see on
a client parking others the CPU
and graphics power sharing and you know
the
syncsort ice extensions for security and
virtualization
that sort of thing is all is all present
so it's
you know it looks like a regular client
CPU and actually has some more speed
so like I said these are Kentucky the
key changes so
the big be one on the Cebu side is going
to the cinema architecture
I'm which I'll talk about the second and
the graphics are going from the SGX
I'm running at at a lower frequency to
the
to the Jackrabbits winning a higher
frequency of course is that only but
rather a model to the summer
deferred rendering the for tile baseman
minutes its immediate
I'm resolutions increased in fact
we go up on the next time we go pilot
wifi best 16
thanks to the the motoring architecture
stuff that danny was talking about were
able to
and change the display clock the chorus
play clock at one time
if we need to bob up to an even higher
resolution member down with his
dramatically increase on somebody's cues
like on the
a convertible tablets and notebooks you
know you get like regular PC style
memory bandwidth which is really great
we went up to new USB
as well so that's that's also important
I'm
sort of the way for ever for your what a
gigabyte USB stuff
overall um this is what the
kinda basic block diagram looks like and
and this is
missus and a bit different than what you
would see on a on a
a client platform does not like a QB I
bus it's a custom
bring fabric that we use on the item
side just you know within the SRC
I'm one other big difference is that we
have relative to the client parts
at least since Sandy Bridge we've had
I'm
the GP was able to share and Kashmir way
the last level cache
on the CPU and so they're both the Jeep
you on the CPU are
are in a great on the same die and they
can share the last level cache
on here they're gonna same die but we do
not have that cash during sorry to those
a dual-core chunks by PE has their own
share cash but its independent-other but
the graphics
so that makes for I'm quite a different
sir performance characteristics of your
tuning for performance
on on this part versus a and Ivy Bridge
laptop computer gonna see
a very different things because about
lack of cash Aaron
so you have to be careful how you map &
and we back memory and
and also how your how you set up your
rendering and things like that
a and it has a so I it has the Intel HD
graphics plus the
back but Quick Sync stuff that you'd see
on the client side so I can do
live regular video decode events & Co
you'd see at the client's base
and addition to that we've got a VP a
few good engine on these parts
I'm that's available and and
used in some cases
this one looks really marketing like but
that the cat takeaway for this one is
the
the the huge improvements in empower or
performance you
you get to choose the at the huge
difference here is this
this as the first out in part this outer
border so if you look at our previous
my correct pictures on the CPU side
there been in order maybe do a less you
now we've got up to four cores out a
border and the performances just
dramatically improved if you if you use
when the old adams is like using ARM
platform you know you like
I don't want to do it builds on this I
don't want it actually log into the
speci- I want to discard his stuff onto
it and
and kind of pretend it's not there this
guy you can log into it and it's like
using Core 2 Duo laptop from a couple
years ago
I mean it's like reasonable speed you
don't wanna stab your eyes out when
using it since
a huge huge improvement from that from
that point of view and it's got the new
architecture extension so it's a I'm
it's a reasonable Cebu to deal with in
terms of
having features that you're used to
there's a love for had stuff if you're
interested in a
3d gates
um so this is a some some benchmarks
we've done comparing the
the new Atom CPU side too to some the
competition
I'm like I said the be other guys you
know these are fast arms accused but
they're still terrible
right I mean
sorry if there any arm folks nearby I
just I can't
I used Adam and like even our own
generation Adam was pretty
competitive like it back to be doubts
alarms
and in using unlike I don't understand
how the young guys even survive like
this is a terrible thing to use a
I don't want to use this platform this
this new one is like
its significantly faster so it's
you can see I'm in this respect and so
this is like what you know this is or
chrome bench basically
right and its its WAY WAY faster
and the power consumption is also the or
some these guys you know them
the I don't know if this is actually I
so power but you can see the
at least the clock rate
Greg saying that a great even takes more
power on the same benchmark and gets
less performance I
a there's legal disclaimers beyond that
I don't know what I'm talking about so
yeah I'll just agree with that
the like us for the next big chunk is
the is the graphic side so
getting with imagination I'm you know
legislation is
for their faults their tune into a work
in the mall space and and tell me fairly
power efficient and can achieve high
performance and if you look at the new
latest iPad airs we've done pretty
amazing things with an architecture its
and it's a it's proven I I don't like to
work on it because it's a it's a close
source driver stack as a different
architectural and
them what we have and I'm Maurice hours
so I'm really happy about this change
because we have a fully open source tak
I'm
but that's mostly a personal preference
from from a from an Intel perspective I
think we have a
we have an opportunity here to really
prove this architecture out on a
in the lower power emblem I think we're
doing that been
and patron also like you can see that's
only got
for use like it's a pretty simple
chopped down from the
from the the client-side Ivy Bridge I'm
so the the performances go scaled-down
on what you
to what you'd expect minus tell us the
Syrian military talk about
um and all I can say is and so is the
futures just
keep your eye on the space it's gonna
get pretty interesting
this year and next year and I i talked
about the
the power and the video decode stuff all
available to
um here you can see the the gaming sites
this is basically comparing the graphics
performance
um whereas in a leadership art
by any means for from a graphics
perspective its its
merely competitive I'm to me this is
actually pretty impressive given that
it is a a fairly straightforward chopped
down versus like a
be no dedicated redesign for mobile
I'm the fact we did this well
a with without a tremendous amount of
effort
I'm tells me that we have quite a bit of
a room to improve and such what parts
you
should be really nice plus we've got an
open-source tax that's pretty exciting
and it beats the crap on a roll stuff
a thirty media folks in here there
there so many acronyms and different
codecs
but it does have like the white house
that has the
the same encode and decode supporting
entrance good sport that you'd see in a
quiet part so
I'm that's nice promote Mike
teleconferencing or
I'm you know video calling that sort of
thing
point of view so it's all that stuff is
there and that thats
actually really nice feature of our over
parts and I probably ought to know more
about it but I don't spend much time in
the media side
on the display side
um at 10 by seven you can't really see
this this is the chamber four hours
there are
demons hanging people and torturing them
the
on the display side the the the pipe
stuff in the register block
on the display mostly matches what you'd
see on a client on the client side
but when you got to the port side they
redesigned everything into the custom a
custom implantation above the
but the display fire itself that's the
chamber for sale that's been a
a thorn in our side but I think the
hardware guys really take pleasure in
torturing us um it's just a totally have
a program model we have a very low level
access to all of the five
characteristics and
a all the filtering and things are good
got applied
on on the on the DAC for the for the
fire
so it that's been a challenge to get get
right across a variety of configurations
I'm but on the plus side we've got
may be here we've got I for
for by lanes DisplayPort and we can
actually go up past 25 by 16 which was
mentioned earlier
come I think we're at like 38 by 18 or
something like that so it's a
it's not a it's not a bad display part
either and its relatively low power we
have some
I'm our dating features that we can do
like reading when we ship when the pipes
go off we can actually powered a pole
display engine
a like we do on the graphic side but on
the underside
a.m. when the duties I to weaken public
that so we have that support on the
display side not too much as we missed
some
but the the low-level aspect of it is a
is a pain but were mostly we must live
within our control no
so this is what we're shooting for this
is
this is a a like a display on Idol case
you know we're just looking at your
screen but you're not doing anything I'm
I'm able to render a little bit you can
see the Graphics is what up
but what we're shooting for on Linux
is this when the display goes off
we want the whole src to basically go
off power everything else uses some
like tiny microcontrollers and things
still awake but this is not a force
three-state
this is a a runtime suspend state so let
the SRC
architecture we have now let us get to
really low power consumption
during winter Greg s
are we gonna do are gonna bother with s3
because going to run time: suspend
but yeah I'll s3 in some cases can still
save me a little bit more
then a full runtime: suspend case so
will support both
both s3 and intend to spend over the
place
going forward if we can get parity
between us three in on time to spend I
think
at some point we may just implement s3
in terms of runtime to spend
but I'm there is a there's a logic and
there's an overhead to all the meantime
stuff so
s3 is also simpler from a platform
implantation love you so
was trade-offs
so upstream status this we started
pushing these bits way back
almost two years ago now a
landed the initial graphic stuff in 36
I'm
and the and the fold a ser lacks
that's our I runtime: suspend supporters
and pushed upstream just yet in the
course
in the course of things and then a
graphics thats that's pretty much done
we just have to get it
get merged I'm things will stabilize
around 3:10 so if you're starting to get
these platforms for yourself
I'm don't do anything for 310 or you're
gonna be in that same reporters that I
talked about
I'm the display up and down clock I
talked about so
at I don't think any of those super high
res display
products are out on the market yet but
when they are will be
ready for them so you'll be able to to
use those right away rc6 is
is a feature on this too I'm and it
works I know
so you may have had problems with the
rc6
on Bay Trail is a different connotation
that it is on the clients I'm
and its actually simpler and it seems to
be pretty stable
I'm got
some some display power shutdown stuff
like a talked about some other display
features that are actually not met real
specific bar
dynamic refresh rate support so like if
the screen is mostly
I know you can actually drop the refresh
rate save some power on your Iran
rebound with what your
members then so free fresh for longer a
we have some bugs um again chamber of
horrors
the this one we just fixed a the day
before I
caught my flight out here and that about
and
been driving me nuts for we can have so
I'm really
set happy that we we fix that so I'm
if you're buying a a better base
platform on Amazon or something now
you you would have run into that like
right away but
we've got it under control Sebastian fix
the current girls on wall
personal attacks stable I'm and then
there's some other issues like Alan
Alan Cox got this to 100 machine with a
bit rail Tia tablet
ask you in it and it had I'm
it's actually maybe base panel
on that on his machine but it showed up
as a VGA
some for some reason and and he was
as he was trying to configure it you
know he's like I can go to work by
if I program the VGA to do this and it
just so happened to use program the BJ
in such a way that
we were driving both BJ and and maybe
with the same timings and that this
would happen work so
there's still some things we have to
work out on the piece I we haven't
tested it tremendously
I'm just an upstream the next we have a
caller and retries but
some so was his improvements there on
the Mesa side it's been
it's been in for a long time since
mister 92
and even before I think a there's
a lot of performance I'm head room here
like the
performance first for some things is
actually looking pretty good
but for other things were like a half
the speed that we could be so the Mesa
teams just kinda
continue improving performance there I'm
ian is probably not here since
we're out last night until about 6:30
a.m. I'm
but you can ask him later when he shows
up
on the media side
it's been supported it in Libya a
as a 121 release the vp8 stuff is in
progress
um the way that the vp8 better
integrated they
it share some logic in terms of power
gating and then rub support
with I 15 IP blocks 0 there are some
money for 10 changes required and then
there's a
a buncha a driver and retrieve thats
that published an open source but it's
not a great upstream and I don't know
if the the people we have working on are
actually pushing upstream
or not might blame in staging at some
point but I'm
its it's pretty ugly still so I'm
working on that there are a few
platforms out there now
a mostly windows stuff um I
I keep refreshing on Amazon until up
because I wanna see that the Android
tablets come out
but I think those are becoming the next
couple months I'm
or if you go to Shenzhen China you can
have them will be one right now
on thats that's been another kind of
issue
people building where configurations and
saying it doesn't work I'm
and if you'd so be looking for this news
items include them here
you can also jump on Wikipedia was all
there but if you're on Newegg or
something you want to look
there's a a new a knock the next unit of
computing
I'm intel's let's have a side project
for Intel
nice little tiny form factor device
but has there's one with nature on it
now there's
as a new love has well a new betrayal
and Sabah those are really nice
platforms for
for tired a nice like that better one
hopefully it's painless
a.m. so that's a fun way to get your
bitter feud with but with petrol fuel
and then there's there's new stuff
coming soon as keep your
keep looking
okay legal disclaimer anything I said
you can began speaking
I'm fool to
so any questions
Andrew
I can hear and PSO you're going to be
on the Mesa side I love the graphics use
police poor
Open GL yes 3.0 in when you bring this
over to enjoy
there obviously gonna be supporting it
there as well will you be bringing
desktop Open GL to the Android side
while being able to read it with Andy GL
context
will we be bringing full Open GL
to Android um but let's not something
that we're gonna stop people from doing
I don't think Google has any plans to to
expose the full geo API through their
framework
I'm which is really will be required but
if you wanna take
a you know builds an engine with Mesa
and an A
and enable 4gl in your build and then do
and UK stuff that's definitely doable
think I'm
that on enjoy their slight some
additional complexity to the grotto GL
wrapper library
to Turkana unify the the feature set
I'm buddy at something that something he
could if I do a few
wanted to I'm experienced so here but
you'd be good when asked about you
and the other questions
no cool I'm glad I got to brag about
this I've been excited about this
performance from the upper
thanks %ah
so next up is going to be about
Nouveau a its gonna