so my name my name is Daniel bariloche
I've been working on the lippert project
for about seven or eight years now is
the time just flies when you're having
fun i'm here to talk to you a little bit
about the project and i'm going to talk
about a number of features that we've
developed over the last year or so we're
probably less well-known but interesting
and useful application developers
building a virtualization applications
going to assume i'm assuming a little
bit of knowledge of liberty and
virtualization and but for those of you
who have never heard of that it's it is
at its core it's stable c library API
with a number of language bindings two
languages like Perl Python Java PHP
ocampo and most most of the ones you
care about and somewhat you don't care
about and it's we try to we try to be a
pretty simple to use API we obviously
what about big selling points is that we
are a stable API and that means in the
entire energy years and liver has been
going we've never broken the API in an
incompatible manner and so if you write
an application today and the goal is you
should run the same application against
lip virgin 10 years time without
problems
it's a cross platform api and it's
across hypervisor API and we support
most hypervisors you can name so kvm Kim
you then both the open source and
commercial versions of them to some
extent and hyper-v vmware ESX vmware
desktop
more the other vmware variants that use
the same API as those two and how
hypervisor lxc containers parallels
that's probably more than forgetting
their but you get that you get the
message where we're across hypervisor
portable and wherever GPL license liquid
limit architecture is basically two
modes in which lip that works is what we
call the stateless architecture and this
is where you're just using the liberal
arts library and it's talking to some
other external system that maintains the
virtualization state so this
architecture is used most notably for
the vmware ESX driver and the microsoft
hyper-v driver because in both cases
you've got some an external management
server that is maintaining all
information about the virtualization
hosts so we just talked to that and let
it maintained all the states for us and
the other the other type of architecture
is what we call the state full
architecture and this is what we use
when there is no other component in the
status maintaining state so we use this
for qmu kvm Alexei and the open sources
and integration and in this case the
local library is talking to the loop
road demon and look at Diamond maintain
state about the virtualization Hearst
you can see in this example the
application talk to the Liberty library
in the library uses are generic RPC
mechanism thought to the little demon
and the lipid demon then talks to the q
mu processes and in the case of qmu it's
talks the communal violence and qmu
monitor interface
that's a very high level view of the
architecture of Liberty in general and
now we're going to talk a bit about some
of the interesting features that you may
or may not be aware of depending on how
familiar you are with birds when when
you are running virtual machines the
vast majority of the time you have some
storage attached to those virtual
machines and unless you're running a
cluster file system inside your virtual
machine you don't want to have to pm's
using the same disc at the same time
because if you have a ext3 file system
inside your guests had to guess it's
right at the same time you haven't got
any data left at the end of that so
that's that's that's a dangerous
scenario and the other scenario
dangerous scenario involving disks is
not a single VM and you're doing say
live migration from one host to another
you want to make sure that one virtual
machine doesn't end up running on both
hosts at the same time because again
bad stuff is going to happen to your
data so liquid has a notion of access
methods associated with each disc and a
disk can either be set up so it's
read-only in which case it's safe to
share almost as many guests as you like
and the disk can be set up as shared
writable in which case and again it can
be attached to multiple virtual machines
but if you're using a disc shared
Michael mode you can be using it plus
the file system or some other file
system was aware of the fact that you
can have multiple writers at the same
time or the default method of configured
risks is read/write exclusive in this
case only one vm access any one disk
image at a time so those the access
modes now the dirty little secret that
you may or may not be aware of it that's
it but never really enforce this very
well
you can set up your disk has readwrite
exclusive and liver it wasn't never
going to stop you're running and 2
guests using the same this so we have
these access modes but it won't be doing
anything they were just a show in the
past about two years really now we
introduced their new bit of
infrastructure and birds and for disc
release or lock management and this is a
way of actually enforcing the disk
access modes the first implementation we
did of this was using a technology
technology called sand lock which was
developed by the overt project and Sam
lock uses something called the disk
access algorithm and for maintaining
active leases on virtual disks and the
actual the actual sand lock locking
mechanism uses historical site was like
actually locking your disk images
directly you got you got a quantity of
storage and set aside as your storage
for holding leases and it's up to the
management application how they
associate at least with a disk image
anyway there that the sandlot projects
although you can use it with storage on
NFS the sandlot maintains really don't
like you doing that they really want you
to use sand storage for maintaining
leases and and the way we've integrated
into live births there's there's two
ways it can work
what we call the manual approach and the
automatic approach now in the manual
approach the management applications say
overt is responsible for saying this
lease is associated with this disk image
and little does trust it when it gets
told that information and so when the
guests starts up
Lippert will acquire all of the leases
that are associated with that and vm and
only if it managed to manage to acquire
all he says will be and startup actually
succeed
excuse me in in the automatic mode
you don't have to do any special
configuration and in automatic mode
libvirt will automatically creates one
lease for each virtual disk you've got
associated with all your guests and this
pluses and minuses to using automatic
mode versus manual mode and if you're an
application like over or OpenStack then
your manual mode is probably what you're
going to be using because it's give you
much greater control over exactly how
your leases are stored and maintained if
you steal your lightweight
virtualization management application
and you don't want to have to worry
about this too much then the automatic
mode or do what you need most of the
time and one last thing about Sam lock
and the sandlot Lisa's there is an
active least mechanism so the leases are
being continually refreshed so if
there's any i/o problems that refreshing
the lease then that is detected
immediately and the virtual machine is
immediately fence I the q mu processors
killed that gives good response time to
a storage videos or four and locking
problems whatever they may be
now one of the one of the limitations of
the sandlot approach i mentioned a few
minutes ago is that the sound of
developers only like using it with sand
storage so if your storage is all NFS
based or some other shared file system
like cluster or sell for whatever you
might be using sand lock probably isn't
the solution you want and so we
developed this second locking plugin for
Burt's called verte Lochte and and this
is intended to be the default locking
mechanism for liberty when you deploy it
on a host
mhm
in the absence of any other
configuration and this just takes blocks
using the posix fcl locking mechanism so
obviously requires that this positive
feature is supported by your filesystem
the majority of file systems support
this but you you get the odd case where
is either not supported or the process
of developers don't like you using it i
think oracle ocfs2 was the last file
system i heard of where they don't
really like you're using the ofc MGR
locks I can't remember the exact reason
why but I mean the majority of case and
this is gonna this is going to be
workable for your shared file system and
at this point of time it only works with
an automatic automatic mode
this is where lipids automatically
determines what the locks are and the
way we do that is based on the file path
of the virtual disk backing store we
will we will either take a char 256 hash
of the file path that's the default
mechanism but you can also tell it and
that's if you're using lbm storages your
virtual disk you can tell it to do locks
based on the lvm uuid or if you're using
and fibre channel or some other scuzzy
storage mechanism you can tell it to
Duloc space on the scuzzy unique idea of
the lung and that is slightly better
than doing it based on the file path
because if your storage appears as a
different file path on different hosts
then the latter two mechanisms of stable
across hosts are slightly safer if it
was looking at the architecture has that
changed when you're adding the vertaki
mo the answer is not really very much
and the q mu driver inside loop let's
just talk to the multi demon using a
simple RPC mechanism so whenever you
start a guest
the first thing it does is it talks to
the vote Lochte and says
acquire locks for all of these disk
images and only if that succeeds where
the where the curing process then
actually be started and these locks are
also actually released the reacquired
whatever you pause the virtual machine
which is key to making migration work
that's not enough about this blocking
the next thing i want to talk about is
access control historically look at a
very simple access control mechanism if
you're talking to liberty over a unix
domain socket you can either talk to it
over what we call it the read-only
socket or the read/write socket that
basically does exactly what it sounds
like it does if you talk over the
read-only socket you can get information
about your virtual machines and your
host but you can't make any changes and
and if you talk to the read/write socket
you can do whatever you like with no
restrictions whatsoever
this is fine for many applications
OpenStack overt those applications
basically want to be able to do anything
at any time so that's not a problem
other application and savor top which is
a monitoring application that only ever
once read only access to the query
iostat sound like but every now and then
people crop on the mailing list saying
what we will be able to do finer grained
access control and so i'll be able to
say user Frank can access the virtual
machine blah and he can do x y&z
operations on it so we developed an
access control mechanism in Liberty
which allows you to express rules like
that and this access control mechanism
operates across all of the drivers that
live inside with that demon that's kvm
bo- nxc user-mode linux if anyone really
use a pistol
look the access control mechanism
doesn't affect the stateless drivers
like VMware and hyper-v because that
would be really pretty pointless to do
something that would involve doing
asking access control in the Liberty
client
well you can get around the access
control just by talking directly to the
vmware server so we don't even attempt
to access control for those we need to
access control for things where Liberty
is the exclusive mode of access to the
functionality and the access control
mechanism was done in a pluggable manner
because we anticipate but over over time
people all up will we want to integrate
with different access control mechanisms
and but we explicitly don't want to
allow closed-source out of tree plugins
and all of the access control plugins in
networks we want to be open source and
maintains as a normal part of the lipids
and character development process so
although we have a pluggable framework
for this it's not a free-for-all for
anyone to do whatever they like
if you have other requirements for
access control mechanisms comfortable
about making this to propose them and we
can work them into the call about
release you so the first and currently
only access control mechanism we have is
based on policy kit and every every
Lippert API has one or more permissions
associated with it when you go to the
API documentation it will tell you
exactly what permissions are required
for which API and then we map those
permissions into policy kits actions so
if you want the start commission on the
main object that gets mapped into a
policy kits action called or Liberty API
remaining
not start as a whole bunch of these
permissions which you can find in the
online api documentation for liquids so
you figure out what the mapping is for
any AP is now I'm nothing is any part of
the information you need to know he was
going to identify the object you're
managing so the virtual machine for
example and there's three unique
identifiers for a virtual machine
there's an integer ID value
there's a human friendly name or there's
a globally unique uniform and unique
identifier uuid this very variety of
different ways to identify the objects
that you're wanting to control and
finally but I identify the user but
you're trying to restrict access to and
currently due to limitations of policy
kits we can only identify local units
users so this this mechanism is only
useful if the finger traffic control is
running on the same host those lizards
talking to it over the unix domain
socket but we need to know the local
units user and was calling the api's and
once you have all that information the
permission the object and the user then
you can go about defining some rules for
managing it policy kids and has a
JavaScript backend and say your actual
access control rules are written in
JavaScript and this number of objects
provided to you
so there's an action action object which
tells you basically what AP is being
invoked as a subject object which tells
you the user who is invoking it and then
the the actual object has a number of
properties to identify the object so
this short example and we're looking at
a API fall in the commission of get
abstraction
and the user is there O'Shea myself and
we're looking at guest running on the
LXE hypervisor with the name of demo and
it's all of those things match then we
allow access if they don't match then we
deny access this is obviously a bit of a
a trivial example that is not really the
way you do it in the real world because
if you have to define rules for every
single individual permission for every
individual object you you get a
JavaScript file tens or hundreds of
thousands of lines long and so if you're
doing in the real world you probably set
up roles so define a set of users which
were all in the same role set of objects
which you want to manage in the same way
and then write your rules for mapping
rolls two groups of objects that would
dramatically compressed the amount of
rules you have to write we don't we
don't provide anything to particularly
help you do that is this time because
this is fairly new functionality we're
really looking for people to try it out
and give us feedback on what works and
what doesn't work and what extra things
that would be helpful for lipid to
provide in this area
and the other reason we chose to use
policy kids the first and the first
engine for access control is because we
had the idea that's if you're going to
write JavaScript backends well that
means you can write a bit of JavaScript
to integrate with ldf so if you want to
find all of your rules and an ldap
database and then just query them you
just a bit of JavaScript glucophage to
connect for Policy kits you're out rules
database or whatever other databases of
access control rules you might have and
so again we're looking for feedback on
whether this actually works out in
practice or whether we need to write a
dedicated ldap authentication back end
as an alternative and we need feedback
on this area doesn't have enough without
access control for now and I want to
talk a little bit about and expert
expert is the generic term for our
socialization security layer this
started out with an implementation for
selinux and the idea here was that
you're running for any loss of virtual
machines each virtual machine is a qmu
process and qmu well it's attempting to
be secure and if they've got their code
exactly perfect than it it might be
secure but history has shown us that the
kuro u code isn't actually perfect and
this major chemistry surprise to some
people it may not and the idea with
selinux is that we have an extra line of
defense in the event that there are some
Florrick um you that allows the guest
operating system to break out into the
host a sadistic still be used to confine
that breakout within they within the q
mu process so they can compromise qmu
but they can go on to compromise the
entire host and your qmu processes are
also running as the same user ID by
default so if you are able to compromise
1qm you can easily compromised all the
other
ones so selinux also actually protected
protects that you can't one guest can
compromise the other guests and so this
is this has been around for quite a
while and put in the in the past year or
two we made this a bit more flexible so
you can more choice over and the selinux
domain can be used so it's actually now
works for both kvm and cam you emulation
mode and we've also added the ability to
define custom overrides for those for
the labeling so if that's if the
standard estimates policy doesn't work
for you you can write a customer
assessee lyrics policy and tell me but
we use that one instead we've also made
it possible to override the labeling on
individual disk images so if you have
some disk images you want to have
labeled one way and other discs you want
to play with a different way you can you
can now set up those kind of rules and
further developing further developing
the the aspect framework and we have now
introduced a proper discretionary access
control mechanism and so few minutes ago
said every time you process runs at the
same user ID
well now it's possible to give them or
their own unique user ID so you can rely
on traditional units permission to
separate your cure your processes
securely and you can have lipids
apparently also currently have to assign
those those user IDs per guest
statically with nipple take care of
dynamically setting the ownership of the
disk images and to match whatever use
writing your guests runs under
slightly related but also not entirely
related and is ordered logging and if if
you wanted to keep track of who's doing
what on your virtualization host and
what you want to know what you don't
want to know what operations of happens
the audit log provides a way to find
this out so whenever libert starts or
stops a virtual machine it will generate
an order to record for that that
operation saying when it started
whatever makes domain it's running on
their the uuid of the guests and a few
other pieces of information it will also
tell you how many virtual CPUs that
guest has how much memory was assigned
all of the disk images that were
assigned to that guests so you can look
back in your audit log and say well
which guest was accessing this disk
imager what time meaning you can find
out what networks it was connected to
when it started when hot-plug operations
were done or you find out what cgroups
access control settings were done with
the block storage this is quite a lot of
the order to information recorded about
a virtual machine anytime any changes
made to it so if you have an exploit you
can go back in the audit logs to find
out what what that guest was announced
to do and that may help you diagnose the
problem is also general debugging
debugging historically we will send the
sorta syslog but now
systemd is available in many
distributions we have integrated with
the system be journal so all of our
login information we sent to the journal
by default if it's available in a
structured format so that makes it a lot
easier to extract information from the
logs programmatically and match on and
anything right down to individual source
file line models the last thing i
thought he got tired of talking about is
our secrets integration now
loop has integrated with see groups for
quite a long time but the way we did
that integration was not really it was
already too useful it turns out for
starts the way we laid out see groups in
a very deep hierarchy cause a lot of
pathological Colonel performance
problems except that it was completely
unusable if you had a large SMP guests
more lots of guests running now the
colonel guys of thankfully fixed most of
the colonel performance problems and by
the same time we simplify the way lip
that users see groups to avoid tickling
those cattle problems in the first place
and so we've now got and what that the
top example there was the original way
we did it we always had three levels
deep of of see groups in the new way if
you're not using a system be host and
we've got one naming convention if you
are using a system be host then we
really are reliable system be to create
the secrets for us so we put the system
be naming convention for the key the key
takeaway is that at the very top level
you've gotta an arbitrary group on the
next level
you've got your virtual machines so you
can now easily setup arbitrary groups of
virtual machines and apply resource
controls for the whole groups of the
ends at a time and the way you do this
in the xml configuration for your guests
lieutenant a resource partition and on a
non systemd host we just map the center
IC group directory using fairly
straightforward an alien convention on a
system being able to host as we react in
using the system be naming conventions
so the vm groups have dot slice appended
to their name possessed of system be
named for a genetic resource grouping
and we're gonna have type over there and
the virtual machines have got scope and
painted onto the end of their name
actually that was why you up so that
once i'm showing two levels deep of
grouping and and so you can get you can
have multiple levels of grouping virtual
machines and and once you place you've
set up your cgroups there's a whole
bunch of performance to Nobles have
become available to you you can set up
relative cpu waiting which is the cpu
shares tunable or you can set up
absolute time slices and those are done
we're setting a quote saranda period
both those are both in microseconds if i
remember rightly and related to tuning
the CPUs and you can set up a name cpu
models if you notice my cpu model you're
going to get you to get generic default
the kvm things as applicable and you're
not going to be making best use of your
and your Intel or AMD cpu features so
you really want to set up name cpu
models which is closely matched your
physical cpus as possible if you're your
squeeze every last ounce of cpu
performance tuning memory
this is another another very important
thing if you want to maximize the
utilization of your hardware and quickly
if you've got a new machine if you're
not doing new replacements then you're
straight away all the benefits of your
new machine
so you can control this manually by
telling liver to what the memory notes
you want to say the vm to run on or you
can teleport to do it automatically in
the automatic case nobody will talk to
something called new MIDI and this is
just a very simple a demon that runs on
a horse and says this Numa node has got
a lot of resources free put the vm over
there and you can also have control over
whether you want to use huge pages again
this is give you a bit of a performance
benefits although with carrot top stream
Colonel's you now have automatic huge
page support so there's not as much
benefit to doing huge page and manually
anymore and you can also turn off and
memory sharing so if you have lots of
pleasure machines are running the same
software stack chances are they got a
lot of memory pages which have the same
data in them and so there's there's
something called that official KSM which
will identify those memory pages which
are identical and merge them so you only
have one copy of this memory page shared
amongst vote multiple virtual machines
and so you get you get higher density of
virtual machines because you can squeeze
more virtual machines into your program
and the one where you can also define
various limits on how memory is used by
virtual machines weather how much how
much physical round they have I was
physical around that guaranteed to have
a few other things on on the virtual
disk side you can you can set a whole
bunch of policies against virtual disks
being said how many i/o operations per
second there and out how much how many
bytes per second they're allowed and you
can also set us on a vm level as a whole
see if if the virtual machines using
physical block devices you can you can
set a policy against individual physical
block devices to apply to and all that
just SAT vm users that vm use on that
block storage and okay i have this is a
lot of this is the last slide your
memory tuning where again you can set up
various policies on bandwidth
utilization which just delegate through
the next traffic shaper and that's
basically it is a whirlwind tour of some
of the features of lipids that arrived
in the last year that's a useful for
application developers to know about it
again best out of your hardware so now
we've got to five or ten minutes for
questions
five minutes for questions if anyone has
any other microphone coming around
ok again me one question that I got
actually three questions the food is
about you talking about applications i
thought one simple application which is
which which I like as a sysadmin it's
the best I can help with the shell and I
can also you use words manager if I'm
lazy and about this whole things you
told about with how are they related to
work do you implant implement any new
feature in worse as well like like you
said about the locking thing and not
like that and for for an application
like various h that's what the goal of
verification just directly exposed the
little functionality to the
administrator we don't ride we gotta
party policy in this what we want we
want to leave the full range of control
up to the admin so what I want to make
use of this clocking they have to
explicitly specify that in in the
configuration they provide the virtual
machines but there won't be something
like an xml
the option where you can say dual
locking like in the domain into the main
specifications not a remote locking
locking you can actually turn off the
house as a whole as an administrator you
can turn on locking on the Hearst and
all virtual machines will then be happy
desks lot probably yep but when I like
to do it / a little machine like you
said about the whole matter locking
thing then you have to do it yet then
you have to explicitly specify the locks
in the xml configuration but that's
possible that yeah and ok and then the
second I try to keep thought you saw
this book about policy kit and haven't
you have you thought about using Pam
blugirl detention models and yes we have
but it's it doesn't really it doesn't
you do what we needed to do as far as
I'm as far as i can tell
although it if you see if you think
otherwise feel free to raise that on the
main respects and I don't think it's
especially flexible ok what we need and
then you spoke about the unix user back
and you said X about the unix use a back
and you have to set X the explicit about
local users but when I would use the
yellow pages then I can use it or why
you said an open when i said look for
years I mean any application connecting
area with the unix domain socket
I don't know Stan application connecting
over the TCP socket
ok then using unix the main socket we
can we can query what the user ID on the
other end of it is and that the put i'm
quite sure about the cpu mobiles about
the features like let's say MX for
example yeah are all those things
multi-threaded very CPU so when I got
that one cpu with let's say eight cores
and I've got 16 we amps can i use the
feature at six
the whims or just an amazing where's I
mean if the PM's actually doing work
they've got to contend for resources on
your host cpu but they can always make
it will see the same feature set but
then they use them at the same time
yeah i mean that the virtualization
takes care of
take care of that baby I'm doesn't
matter but just from a point of this is
that men can i use let's say as e4 point
something for all 16 machines haven't
got yet
ok that's it I think I out of five
questions that come find me in the
hallways afterwards if anyone else has
got questions
yeah sorry