I'm
six more minutes will be next condition
with I will be there was no honeymoon
I will like what you badly
on we know
the judge
Libyan room
the
in
good
you mean
and on
good to me
and
I
go
love you
there
going
the 50
good
then
a
and going to me
yes
I mind
ground
from you
and
home with
the moon
you with this
going on I O
gone
good
large
good is it over with really
a 0.1 the full
on the pool
polls we still have more minutes Yemen's
weak oversight
yeah and just gonna I'm just trying to
see whether
and do that
I'm
him
home
and
be
good
wall
I'm
time
this
on for me
no basically thanks more room
for a long time
you
and room
them
dream
moon
them go home
on
on time
time
loan
on
room
the
we'll room you really do something
people to do something schorr I'm
soundcheck went to the gym
yeah okay com okay make speaker are
muscle I L object the small all
squeaker from longtime hey long long
time ago
i seemed short coat with a stainless yes
you have okay so I'm i'm talking about.
object to small talk one on the tomb
and non a classic small talk
a.m. something to talk about today and
I'm let's my own company made objects
been around for a while I just recently
started
them with X Megan and Brian the startup
and I'm also attached to the house
Oakland Institute in Potsdam
during my PhD which is related to this
stuff so
a lot on my plate and and I really like
small talk
from but also really like see from
because it
get it lets me get stuff done at a lower
level so I really love check to see
I'm so much that actually way back when
anybody remember the anti-gun
so I got my first amigo and on the first
thing I did as a
implemented a.m. check to see
preprocessor for it
arm and that was
a little over a quarter century ago
scary and I next came out and that
you know they did the job for me and I
it's it's now lost to history
Peter I'm this week's stuff he added
some we embark a lot a long time ago
when the first cup coffee I'm
which is also lost because it was a very
good I'm
and a the stuff that's going to still in
the image i think is a buscar generation
so that's sort of where I come from
and I'm
being an object to C programmer I'm its
it's a great language
but you know it does have limitations
%uh because originally was I'm really
meant as a stopgap measure for a first
I'm
those situations we couldn't use small
talk and that's really kinda
changed a lot so a noob minimizes it
simplified
back down again on the other hand the
small talk never really caught on
me I'm I i wouldnt community for quite
some time but I could never really use
it for my
day-to-day work just kinda sad I'm so
it be nice if it be more practical
nothing I could actually use it for my
work the bomb
and finally I'm I always really been on
the lookout for something to make this
whole program thing
a lot better because quite frankly
programming sucks
my I mean really deal with all these
low-level
things and when are you getting I
and I mean I don't think you know this
is not going to be huge
should be a huge relief but I maybe we
can make it better
and so
my first thing is you know I'm let's
simplify objective-c
and and this is why I I'm
jesse has really grown over over over
time used to be justice system for
wrappings see function seen programs
in little small talk like properties but
we can become stop doing that we
actually using the object system
and as that it's not really very good
time you know
if you want to have an object number
that's and his number number with
in for well thats not me
square brackets now we think there's
been some additions
so we can say at 3 yeah at four
but again if you gonna do that a lot
that's just going to be
really that whereas now to use just
plain did you say that
that looks that's right now that's
that's actually okay
because promise we have to sin taxes two
languages jammed
together and no that's just not been a
good idea
in the long run I'm and here
this is my one of my favorites after
they had lost recently
and that's that's what I lot looks like
that loss
peace to you I'm Council I'm
what happened here right so
um maybe you know if you could
look like this right like small talk and
that's pretty much the same examples
I'm except they have a okay not and
we still won to have both these systems
the object system and the primitive
system because
again I I like see and we sometime we we
need to talk to the sea world
and but we can't do much simpler because
just
do not apply foundation say that senator
and that's a seat
and the rest it's just objects and
so that that's kinda think the
motivation that
and in terms of I'm
just be a more practical small talk mean
small talk the image
it's a great concept but the again the
world has changed since 1980
I and when or even the the seventies
when when it was created
when when a Xerox park had their Altos
there was really no outside world to
talk to so
you know having a midget having your own
world with you that's fine
I'm other you
oh that's it it is a great system
and I isn't that weird him
it'll be his now day
oh absolutely and then change right
and that's i mean i i think i yes its
its it's a pragmatic thing
I it you know if you if you have
I'm a world where you're comfortable in
the image below
that's great but many people don't
I why do we have room I'm
or and Python I am small talk should be
better than that that then the sentence
but I'm I think 11 big I'm
and problems that people had his you
know they couldn't integrating the
command line tool he can
to an SSH in any one year's Mohawk some
with you
it be nice if you didn't
it would be really nice and certainly
not it seems to me you can build a
a nice image you know on top of that its
it seems to
I mean just given history it seems to be
difficult to get
a good scripting UNIX shell integration
on top of that the image
we've been trying for a long time and we
have
systems but the even the fact that we
have so many of them
seems to indicate that may be happening
don't have good answer
I'm so
you want to run the native baby I'm
and and we have a nice little object
system that's very small talk her into
it with objective-c
it's very small and so we have no yeah
he had no
no image and we don't even have a cheesy
which is Force Base
talk I'm there's my home you get to you
expecting
I'm the right now though the study
population is a future thing I'm working
on it
its not there yet same with objective-c
tribute equipment and and the other part
about being
it within these other systems is that
there is just so much more
other color on Thursday vendors you know
Apple
does courts they do all these kits I'm
having to recreate all that just doesn't
scale
and David Chisnall denies he was here
last year I think right
and he had a nice cool paperweight
anyway did some numbers
and he said hand those even if small
targets are 100 times more productive
they still couldn't match the outfit
just what is there in SeaWorld
so what we have I'm it's still a little
demo
you
and
a pic and the cursor okay so we have a
small talk scripted show
and
so you know we can do three-plus forget
so yeah it's a small talk
I'm we can do we can just write
stuff done right so low
we can send messages
to standard that
time we can do
standard string concatenation that
also to work for the works we can do
slightly more fancy stuff
so me and let's say
I we have and the ball
that works that we don't see it
as apps
and anytime I'm my syntax right
and so all that that sorta stuff works
and of course the example we had the
Objective C Block example let's do that
a little better I'm
so we had a couple strings maybe
and the and we do
do
so your basic small talk or spin in the
command line
I'm so I mean no small talk is his is a
little like that
I'm but I think it's it's this is a
really useful
a capability to hang out and especially
sense you can I am star
and doing real scripts now for example
I'm just to get so to sum the syntax of
the way
I'm went from two does is really simply
just come so
I
I think that's that's trio
and if we look at the helm look at this
time itself
I'm
NCAA's there's no them there's another
ashe and Lorna does in a situation
between
was what what what what is a script and
what is a massive
so me saying this script is a method
from to with two
crackers from
and then adjustment France them and
having this type of med information
then allows me to for example doing some
error checking I completely
automatically
who because I declared what I need
and the thing well he didn't want any I
and so I'm what you have is a circuit is
the starting to get
a a softer architectural idea other
doctors where you have this
the scripting world and the math you
know the objects message messages were
all the and you started trying
bridge the gap
the other thing you can of course doom
I'm
is let's see what I have it
but you can and I'm
starry bringing code from
from your a game. drop it low is a the
app is the year
basically we framework and think
Parco and so this but this will do
is well it will know if I'll I
nationalizing image and just like that
so he'll ever tell you what the images I
have
image info through the J pick somewhere
here in various
New York City and
well so yeah yeah I
I'm 36 and
some information about the day again
hear your bridging those gaps
bring things closer together to make
make it easy made X just become more
productive
usually what happens
is when you have these two worlds I'm
you need to
that the bridging code tends to be so
much
so much more than the actual
functionality because you're you
especially during
small things but you don't do it
right and then you need to write a C++
at either a full programme
or you need to and get these other
packages involved
it it just becomes more cumbersome
okay back to slideshow
had
so this was trying to being object to
see you see an small talk together
and now we're going to talk about little
bit I'm trying I'll be on small talk
and again D&D idea is
something about that I'm I Marcus talks
about the little bit
at trying to specialized the language
I because we 10+2 at at higher levels
when we doing application programming
its it's often the case that we doing
something very similar but just so
its it sufficiently different that we
have to reinvent it from scratch for
example
to the example that and they also gave
if we have
I'm instance something that we've is
conceptually million instance variable
but we need more with them
and they need to be dictionaries or we
need some special functionality by their
when they get call we can use the
language anymore
directly please we have to build a
scaffolding on top I'm similar with Matt
messaging and if we want to have the
built in messaging to find a combined
a synchronous messaging or messaging
applied to collections or
some other form or remote messaging that
kinda have to build it ourselves
possibly go through the Indian you have
a I
in the end if ninety percent of your
program is going to be the new handler
maybe just maybe you need to know maybe
the language needs it'll be fixing
so again idea is
about what what sort of the next thing
well actually we just need to buy small
talk itself
right we need to stop being be able to
subclass and compose the pieces
them if they make it makeup the basic
system and
then we can build whatever language we
need which for example with the
escaping we just shot and
ok components there are I'm
polymorphic identifiers in first class
references which
generalize the idea of and identify and
in essence very well
talk about that I'm messaging
so we can play around with that and
finally
and that's the part that's at least
well-developed that's a
dataflow which is I'm in also wanted to
strangers asymmetries in small talk is
be assigned operator
right this kinda the one thing you can't
override there is deep reasons for that
but if would be nice if we could for
example have custom or
customer site have constraints where
it's not a one-time assignment but
you just say this should remain for have
I'm place same well it's not
that we just want to shove this one
thing over here but reaction I just want
to connect the two things
and keep people connected and
the inspiration for solving this is is
really
a software architecture approach and
actually
I'm the original by Brad
talks on object to see to talk very much
about software architecture in packaging
I'm and another fantastic why
is this one and which the
pick that that he's among computer
programming although they they saw the
base everything on the functional model
they I managed to get the relationships
between different programming models
in there and classify what how how far
can you go with a particular model and
when
should be maybe move on to something
else moment in time
okay I am
and so I when
sending thought about things for a while
and came up with
this what's that this is a
classification
of small talk in terms of such
architecture
you have basically UK
I'm imposter is the connector
which is just you know well let me give
architecture lead put things together
somehow
and declassification
I'm here there Islam so you know
something
a.m. passengers right I are I'm
those value as a dataflow connector I
you have access
he thinks there is local variables I'm
somewhere else immunity environment
variables small talk
doesn't happen articles but get bigger
I'm
and then have messaging which I you know
that I use as a sort of general
generalization of Mata procedure call I
position all these it at the time but we
don't have to
small yes mom we couldn't earlier
messages that I
I'm sure a synchronous I'm we have no
indication that I don't have a receiver
now these are are text messages but the
end we r
following her these things that
characterizes specific language and
I'm when I have a different language
we have the same overall
picture stress be parts this is just
ISO he saw this I'm now yeah
hiatus we have movie realism
with function dollars on usually
environment variables we have files
which
and small talk and directly going to
following in the shower just let down by
I and maybe in the fall
missus no why is this right as it seems
completely random to me
having looked at it for like and of
course your your
I'm particular problems will therefore
call for different languages
but for no really good reason it's just
somebody decided well we're gonna split
it up this way
and what if you could just decide to mix
it
so
whether cornerstones of that and
actually took me awhile to figure that
one out
on it is you have to be able to name
things properly
and the philly.com
start messing with the other party to
actually make naming flexible
and thats
what on the market for sorrow button and
then there was just a
DLS paper I'm October
than any language support himself sort
of particles from
and the basic idea is really just put
you take
the concept that for you I from the web
and putting your program
I'm a you can actually
also write your eyes so it should be
something something something
and have that simply identifying program
no hillary rodham
are here
research this is cool you're always
these uses place
loses know you
you may be searching resources for
campaign work or
was a cemented with
right yes what is actually a min and
then that this is
I mean I i couldn't i couldn't you
something else and come up with my home
by I we have your eyes and they're
called universal universal
room resource identifiers universal mom
so I just the site today syntactically
that makes some some things a little bit
more difficult
I'm but a
I think the pragmatics partly in this
case
so yes this is really just important
that concert into the program
the existing awesome I'm
you cannot make them you I accessible
I'm
a every scheme has has handler and you
can define your own
I'm this solves a lot of
um issues for example the property
pattern where you have to chase
on that you know accessing dictionary
he's strong and he's
I if you look at for instance on the
Apple towing
I'm Xcode is ninety percent dictionaries
which scenes bought you would think you
know
that money my point to model actual
objects the functionality but not stick
children's
and there's reasons for that yeah
reasons in
on for good in the end some
you can also do something I'm check
alone process rest
I'm that essentially you fill these
POS system identity is I can't do that
inside
process and we had very good experience
reengineering ABC
on system using that type technique I'm
get it that allows you to do the
hierarchical management
up data um flexibly
without having to have a external file
system
for example
soul I'm quick de Mon who
out a time almost back that's
just see I have a network I do not have
an hour
miles down tools
back
be a I'll try to do some of the other
stuff
various do were yeah but the other ones
don't seem to work with my machine for
some reason
yeah I don't know why I people in six
years
yeah ABC's The View yeah and it should
work i mean another Maxime to
connected just minus doesn't like it i
don't understood my
though like okay so
goes back here a
my standard example good
goes and 70 and that it looked at the
source code
they have the meow at the end I'm I can
now
but that invariable I say
so how long is that well as you know 155
K
let's put that in a file a
and that just works right and I can
I can also of course when they could
have done that directly right
time
and I'm and variables
actually also have a scheme so
a few different one be doesn't exist
so that's a sign it but that's actually
the same
as if I say Barbie I'm
I can I can access environment variables
so it's my home
okay I'm I can nest them
so I have home
add a listing of my home directory I'm
and that began its integrated so I can
this bus thats
yeah consistency there so I have 89103
I'm for I can't just retrieve something
from their
I'm
long past research I'm okay I think I'm
said and done I'm and the first I weapon
at see but actually that was my last
night I have more than I stuff if people
are interested
I'm you objectives does St that's where
the
that the site there's a reference to get
other parts stories
I'm basic idea everyone scripting
compilation why do you think need to be
distinct I'm objects and Unix also
should much when I think together and
software architecture is the answer
I'm polymorphic identifies home are some
other
techniques used implement that and the
step compiler is in progress
apply I found they don't have time saw
thank you well guns
as but trick question I'm home I hope to
see everyone
people basically disease that much the
hula hoop oh absolutely I i has mine are
less
I'm I I made some changes so I think
probably is not
but that s it generation I
that mention human Yahoo Video
from the the end of the the one who hunt
liddy
unquestionable
updated to buy it there is no with the
growth in look okay Yahoo yeah
I'm I I had both versions and just a
he's changing around a little bit
but is not YouTube video I'm the
that one thing that's currently I'm
maybe the problem is I'm
I'm you law stop and I just haven't
looked at home at work
it seems that as far as I know and in KS
at one time yeah right and should work
is
I haven't gotten around here Tom want to
look at that and like that moment with
another holiday
have to check it well with that yeah and
the school your day
there's no girls collection there is no
the to object to see has reference
counting okay
um and various techniques for dealing
with circular dependencies
that are not if a doctor used to have it
I'm
it sucked and didn't work and so they
Rep ripped it out again
can you do lonely heart problem
yes this is come this is iPhone
compatible
I I don't think I currently have in the
ass in the store that use it
but um its they also said
the here fifties yeah sciatica and I
haven't I haven't tried
that this particular thing but it should
it's designed to be calm
and doesn't use a chip think about which
thank you good
well