thing no for couldn't fisting if these
seems like a
very interesting discussion okay great
fill my name is Martin pets today
I'll talk about the state a bit itself a
nation I'm am
have been elected as one of the
directors this year and
I'll try to introduce you to what the
foundation is about
and I'm and went well changing right now
information
several I'm just saying this because
this is but I think the
condition is a non-profit corporation
chartered to develop and execute
effective strategies that provide
worldwide
to it said and encouragement other X
Window System
and related projects which are he's idea
I well and so
just to be clear it's not only about X
its bro did not so Antipolo goes of
course it's
XE bi its TX so limits because we have
no logos fall
dr. I and he said is Janet's guess
and Wayne and as a little while you
okay so
the foundation is not about I providing
technical guidance
offense perhaps need to %uh for
I'm creating road maps all deadlines
releases
and %um no supervision at an
inspirational
what he does is providing communication
architect all tools where in relation
with a protest up
a it also provides an annual physical
meeting
XTC X developer conference we'll talk
about that
the next line and provide money to help
the demand the government uptown traffic
stack Saudi XD cortés
I think now we are through the the XTS
will only use XTC
but it used to be XTC thought that the
young
US version of the year XTS
and X yes will be in your in Europe
somewhere
dis attain a 10:18 a.m. I
yeah so when he had seen US one and
you're in Europes was being
we have a load-balancing in and
78 once again usually in september or
october
and it lasts for three days settle for
this conference
okay maybe for first-time I members
exiled members
can I require for and travel sponsorship
of course they need to present something
for that I
bed this is something that the bird can
provide so
as a friend and as we have cooperative
I'm
entity we can be brought up the some
I Google Summer of Code so im we've been
working on approved I
organization and this allows students to
be paid by Google will fall on
doing welcome the graphics that during
summer and so to flip
bit since that up burgers in they're
more productive this way
and so as some examples up this year's
projects
we've had that David Hammond I don't
know is here
not get you'll be coming soon
and men to baghdad he barely and the
roads
I mean the rapid implementation for end
nodes and I'm
some security fixes sits there are very
good in very interesting
i render nodes will be I'm providing
GP GP you without X all
okay okay it's too long to explain that
several my student I'll
was 72 as a has-been reverse engineering
performance comes as amended your cards
so as we can
I on tell developers application
developers what is wrong with the
application
and why they are hitting about to make
this kind of stuff so it's a lot of work
I am but we've got some mom
comes as waking in a in me so so make a
team of that
two morrow if you come to new
presentation
and end up in the both miss I
mentored by I N right here whom write on
the implementing GL
X thank state access I so far the code
as not
the on it pastor all
okay because you know his enough for me
now
meant to that's what he said for the
video guys okay
several yeah but
we also have our own program that is
kinda like a
kind of like that she suck it's called
the ebook unless the cation of code
so basically I am it's not but with some
it can be any time %uh yeah
thingy but you have to be issued in and
arm and you have to be indication at
this time
but so
I when the project in 2013 because when
g-shock and any 2012 we didn't get
accepted 4G sucks so we had many
students applying so we had to
Francisco Torres who worked on the
german teen a seal supports
I'm yet from the world but disco didn't
make it upstream a some current did make
it up stream for a gallium
a then we had some print work in on down
not staff on that I mentored I'll
blatt sat on how to pronounce that what
was times that on the
creating a framework for testing open CL
so basically adding
up until test two piglets if you know
what this is otherwise it's a
testing architecture we had more but
no place on the slide and
we also provide communication I said
before also
some we have a Google class YouTube
account were
we used to stay running to talks a
slight submitted articles
Canton I'm the maintenance of that so if
you want me to put something
on it just send me a mail whatever
find a way to come contact me and for
Twitter
its mostly used for security pick up
some not Texas
issues and random but they descend on
that's well done by Alan companies
well so I'm am just a guide yes now that
exam
is not really but not anymore I mean the
ex parte good now
good 382
whites who had sweated and I it has been
mostly written by hand and I met de
and well him want to know
on it love another offense but they did
all the heavy lifting
presented by bob massey from mom
up PSU Portland State University
and the get so you can accent the
weekend and the guy down
in with the phone which is nice so as we
can. updated
in case community several
now let's talk about the current a
situation with membership
and members of the board and all that
so what is a member sOooo
its people actively engaged into the
community
and community so tell guidar
the whole Lambretta not just X and XI
for
and it is someone who is so
supporting the goal of deformation
and a of course they need to sign the
membership agreement so
as a member if you become one and I
suggest you do
I you connect the members of the Board
of Directors
and you will be. consulted
when the board is trying to make big
changes to Don
the foundation so for instance changing
the BIOS
a change in the corporate state status I
dissolution
up the deformation or unusual agreement
that would make
this year will have below changes and
corporate status changes so
Pelini's applying the country seventy
nine members
and if you want to become one tests
I well you get the URL for please do
okay the book I so the best directors is
composed of
I eight members every year where you
reelect
from you people so in 2012
we had collected next to each other
Keith Packard
mad do and much esubs so exposure is
working for AMD key is working for
Intel Matt is not working on something
that is
song created Matt yeses I'm
a professor in Germany
and that's yeah I mean while last year
but so I think a business is
working for Oracle a has been elected so
Peter
I working for Red Hat and is now the
Secretary of the Board
stewardess is that treasurer and I think
he works for Oracle Team
and should be good and I'm not impressed
summer peaches units in a
in bordeaux so
the schedule for the reelection is this
one as
all day a nomination period opened at
well last month thirteen-a of January
so basically it means that if you want
to become a board member
you apply your you just apply
and and you have to pull some rules that
I explained in the the link below
the nomination period answer have to a
month
so some then we'll a make it public
so the reason why it's not public before
is because we want to allow
amend candidates to retract
without it being public it's not to hide
anything
some some if you want to have the
elect now if you want to participate in
the election
you need to applied before done 1905
February
so piece duvet bow
the section opens so on the 17th so
Gavin day for the lab and it closes I'm
well three weeks later some
please apply as a candidate in if you
are a
nine-member up tons of invasion
and I get
so so far no questions it's gonna be s
shop Talk sorry
okay could corporate status year
and okay as for the formation as the US
IRS 501 c3 status so what does it mean
it's the US a I'm not-for-profit
organization
sewing pins that if we get the nation's
me
on the donor's don't from have taxes
don't pay taxes for that
it means that we don't pay taxes to yeah
and well it's mostly irrelevant for
non-usa donors
so most of us here
so who i am. getting the status has been
quite however
so it was decided to get in 2005
I we got in 2012 and retroactively
got it bad to 200 that 2010
9 yeah I so we gained the status thanks
to the
the wake up their softer freedom though
senator well who went with them but
they did a lot of work we must this
status for a few weeks
in 2013 because we didn't I'll
published that we had income we fed them
I suppose he would have
the people would but the didn't so we
had a mishap in communication
for continued bad SF LCT managed to get
it back
so if you want to I'm numb the full
history of what happens if I don't
you can I look at Howard down
secretaries bus than that
so many situation is so
we have a lot of money and we can
worship I
at the current rate weekend last fall I
for 25 years
without requiring and fundraise
we've been living on nom on our funds
for maybe 10 years
up I mean I mean you members so I
yeah I've always known the formation as
having money and not
I'll requiring fund-raises
Saturday why the mishap
with SA a chase BC baby basically
changed the rules
and should on no account very
unfortunate
with the have the money but yeah so from
the past the fact that bad they used to
process to pay a thirty dollars p
every month for basically doing nothing
and the fact that the while the website
wasn't that good for money transfer than
all that
subtle we just moved to the bank of
America
I'm was yeah it's easier now apparently
and that treasure
it should be cheaper to good it should
be cheaper
mister from the old
some beacons will not account since then
the Wii
apparently bad me
by this status is not something that we
need anymore
at the time in 2005 it was needed
because we need to get a lot of income
I we don't need that income anymore so
yeah it's an earthquake so it's a the
technical achievement apparently
I wasn't there but they've been
struggling to get it for seven years so
I guess it's
quite an achievement I am
yeah but it's not it's not a problem
proven itself
so as as I said we are not US
accountants
I said US because well we come from
other one around the world
and and as we don't get it as much money
as
we use to me it's not worth being funny
countenance
and in the end it's just easier to I am
move to a number to corporations such as
as a full CR SPIA
I will talk about as the I am in a bit
and so I think manage demand the money
for us
and a you feel all the paperwork for us
skip so we booted
at XTC flights SPI I the reasons why
they should be public
um mostly because it cheaper
and bad will be conducting yes FLC
and I'll and spik and bend
when everything is ready for that and
the transfer then we require
a vote from down to members as I said
before all members should vote when we
changed the corporate status
which we are going to do
so SPI what is it I Satan
the nation infrastructure basically so
they manage on the money to bank account
and the taxes earned all the paperwork
that he can collect money from anyone in
DC you'll speak
didn't do that before we usually are and
the weather had two companies
was easier an intern day you get to keep
five percent of all the donations
SPIA is also handling our genetics that
be in for desktop
LibreOffice and Drupal and a few others
can't remember but couldn't be blessed
so if it's good for them must be good
for us right
in then as we need to
I as we want to move to SPIA we need to
change the BIOS
settle because the findings have been
returning and
OpenOffice in 2006
the russians out quite difficult to see
differences and all that so I put that
bad to
latex and I get so as now we can put
Tigers and feed
commit things in so it's good
a some and as we are going to change the
BIOS and changing the bylaws require
both
from the members it's a good time that
we say that
thereto conditions not only about eighth
it's good to know
talk about the right way and me sir this
kind of projects
so we would but that into Dom
the binos so if you wanna see the
the vision and the the conventional
version of the BIOS
I think there are two branches the
master one is the current state
nobody take it no medication it's a
sporting the open offer document to
8a and those in SPI a branch that is
just about as PI and no changes for the
the I'm changing the will
the the changes for changing the scope
have done
the foundation but on the wiki for all
intents and purposes
the itself a nation is about every
project
I'm yeah weight and tax and everything
and a
okay so as a conclusion you should
become a member now
when the GOP in very thin I
pizza become a better candidate I
brother
um yeah so you have about
15 days left far a plane
getting better than improve the
communication this is something we suck
at
and we should keep on working on it good
and to keep them coming on improving the
graphics back that's what we do best
any questions
I have am him right sleepy
am so you x.org foundation maybe he
spent seven years
getting this 501 c3 status and then
dropped a bit
and another sided don't need it anymore
at all
yes why is it still there
wise exhort still there wyeth is also
why it's now a graphics that woman
objects orbit room
for you may not know why is the x.org
foundation still valid
all it did was create this his new
status
and that was it days bases
we have elections 10
he well as a as i said it's easier to
get
and to be in the in the G some program
if we are on a reorganization we could
have when for SPI at the time I agree
and for the reason that have been said
to me because I wouldnt
I wasn't there before sure that for the
board in general not only yeah
as so the reasons where that we use to
get its
100kg I year
so of course Intel if they could not pay
taxes on that
Intel and other companies out yeah I
don't know who was
giving us money I'll of course they
would
be my or willing to the money also maybe
just put a little more
so at the time it made sense that's what
I've been said
min and now a we've been living off
what we had I for quite a while and I
think yeah I i mean obviously we don't
need that status
now a so
so minute one less thing as a corporate
a thing it's also easier to organize the
XTC
rights own that's just yeah reinstating
itself there
me yeah at this point it might be better
to have it be there
the open-source graphics confederacy or
something
way but wish all me what you wanna
do you want to have some kind ever other
thing
right I would he want to have some kind
of a thing to
for organizing events for participating
in things like
like gee sock it's probably not as
important as it was
arm right
but I mean use you still want to have
some some kinda love
and organization that can that people
can point to
but but having it be
eccentric and in may be happy he
well well it it is but a it is the same
as
has the vestiges I love how
how X was organized right i mean that's
it has history to end in n
and and maybe I all has a sad hey
mysteries late got cancelled but he
didn't
1 yes I'll also that he should answer
this
are but I mean is you still want to have
you still want to have some have
always with me
get get the mic otherwise in no one will
hear
I don't I'm really happy to be changed
three you your four years ago
and finally started doing I point out
everything was completely close the
meetings were just
some people on the phone and was it so
now everybody can only see you know
that's already a good change and
now apart from that one artiste
meetings about usually what's to see
what the status with the
501 c3 more when are the elections
starting
and that he saw and XTC you need both
can
I mean I put everything in the print
edition about what we doing
a bomb hidden yeah for so yeah
but I before to be more open your you
doing gonna put but
everybody should be more vocal about
covering all project with with the old
name because it's nice Europe
keep yeah I was interesting in changing
that
interested in changing the name but it's
not something apparently we can do you
and some people lower love having you
know one letter
good tonight at European its lame
but I I had similar I'm concerns to look
for a long time have been like what is
the board do all I hear is
I hear stories about how they care pay
their obligations right solar
what are the functions at the borders to
arm help pay for XTC
and get people there writes a sponsor
travel and
some people will will get travel
sponsorship dot com
and then that foundation fails to pay
them for like a year
you know which is be our yeah they don't
get the money to the venue
let that happen in Australia to which
seems like just the absolute failure on
the boards part which is really
frustrating but on the other hand I
think we do need an organization to
receive that funding and and manager
properly
ideally so I think there is a role for
the board there
but obviously yeah I agree you've been
there there were some issues and that
was before your time
yeah but and yet so maybe that's why as
I said we are not the countenance
and we usually don't like it a in with
the FBI man
moving to SPI would maybe make it easy a
and
usually we just send money every year so
we forget how we did and sending money
it is a quite difficult because who have
I all the the bank fees and all that
it's changing all the time he doesn't
know
I yet for the reimbursement I got night
fall xD she is and had a difference of
about 130 euros or something something
like that
just in bank fees want yes so
money working with HPI really just nicer
and I'm
there
it first question done
go ahead town will the will the move to
as the I change
anything within the the formation I'll
processes are the project or something
project know as I said we don't provide
technical guidance we're just here to
help
when people need us when developers need
us
that's what we try to do and so it
shouldn't change anything in the project
management
um but it will change the way we work as
the board and I i the foundation itself
in does it answer your question no then
did you rely
no from so
to feature I didn't add the research but
a SPI is
but now of course you're you're just
you're moving into an umbrella
organization
and the the only change
the is going to be the Treasurer that's
it from
the the pressure as work is going to be
different
so I'm if you want to have a look at the
differences
and the way we weren't you can have a
look at that SP a branch
Inderjit repo this one
because yeah admits the differences and
Howell
we are going to need what is going to
change I he didn't put a Seagate
I link because I couldn't find it didn't
rain and the 3G connection was horrible
so on this one wakes should
leg there was a question there
okay great
okay i was just curious um the
fundamental we whether more between say
this of freedom Conservancy specifically
in SBI
the just the ten percent to 5 percent
all was there some other philosophical
difference I'm curious
what that poll a.m. I'm surprised that
we have two organizations that do the
same thing and can you tell me what
you thinking on it was who
at the top of my head since September
because we haven't looked at it
since yet has since and it really was
just the difference in the
money I as planned to be
i think is gang was there and managing
less
I so it's just about money and
I R and taxes that's it that's all they
do
I suppose he had mall but I can't
remember what it was
yet
I'll it works
okay nah two questions actually um for
small
I on any plans to improve the members
that side
its okay horrible right now yeah
know we have no plans so least make this
a priority
confusion it's a horrible yeah here
trying to get people into the foundation
and if you look at the HTML code
don't embarrass it was good because I
could count the numbers
grabbing and counting the right now in
30 conceded hmm
yeah yeah I agree its home alone but
during rem into you really want s to
maybe
pay someone to change that yeah I will
expect the foundation with all that
money that the
at least get their website right this is
something I couldn't submit to the board
yeah oh yeah and
yeah with and what the Fed if someone
wants to
step up and fix it it's even better when
you need to
spend money bad I don't know who likes
to do when
development here for
yeah i'm just repeating what he said we
r
how costly program is not web developers
another Gaza
frequent overlap between the two
communities good just pay someone to do
it
and second one a I
thing it's a not that much the
Foundation does
just providing money to the invention
travel
expensive um I would expect the
foundation
to actually be more active than
something like the Open GL armelle
or we have all those great
for free graphics drivers now
new mobile radio on whatever and all
those
don't have fun Open GL certification
because you have to
ideas tests are stuff and
I think the foundation could spend some
money there too
get them those certs a
think this would make a difference yeah
yep
of I think new
new can do open feel free both free and
we can't really advertise it because
it's not paid for the test two we have
picked lit
rear all those a Howard
at least that and I think wouldn't be
too much of an effort to you and get the
official
11 can can make it a cost problem
92 in so yeah before entering will give
them a
that Mike 2in because he's been got in
trouble and that certification so
so you know better yeah been have been
doing that work for Intel I'm also one
of intel's representatives to
to Kronos arm for desktop Open GL their
is know who a compulsory conformance
process or versions previous two
four-dot
or I believe Lalan
there is an optional process for for
previous versions
arm and learn we r are currently trying
to to get some things fixed up so that
we can
we can pass all that are are on our
driver
on so so than anything
at mean you can advertise any person
love desk OpenGL the
that you want and not be technically
running awry
I'll I'll the the krone's process
are this story is quite different for
OpenGL
yes where there is an established
process for
all the versions that the aviões are
and actually not there's anyone from
from him the in in the room messages it
yourself
be get your stuff fixed up and submit
conformance cuz the company
already paid for it for for the other
driver
are there is supposedly
a process by which on
basically nonprofits
can submit conformance on on drivers
without having to pay a
the usual fees are people have told me
about
that this thing exists in Kronos a
couple times but
I haven't been able to figure out what
it actually is
Musso missouri's because go with it and
you know what that means is that we may
well be able to
get saw pipe in LVM pay
certified as as component yes
implementations
without having the to shell out a bunch
of my are
part part of the difficulty is there's a
buncha weird
legal agreements well not weird but
a bunch a legal agreement about getting
access to the conformance tests
are and it's not clear
exactly how that would work and he would
run the conformance tests
in order to to be able to submit them
because the people who do have access
are people like me who are really busy
and don't
one trains ground with operated lol BMI
bill some test okay great now what how
do I get
you know how do I get that to someone
who's actually working on that driver so
that they can fix it
are so there there's some other
sorting up out that
that needs to happen com before before
that can work out
arm and I don't know how that would
apply to
hardware drivers so I don't mean I don't
think that we will be able to
to get a free pass on Nouveau or
for you know on any the associate
drivers the people are working on our
or things like that can you give us an
estimate up the price
but corporate not a its
on the Kronos website are but its
on the order tens of thousands I
I wanna say it's like 30 grand
for ps3 but I don't I don't remember
I did I didn't sign that check yeah okay
I just had to to pass it along to people
who could sign that check
so you had money on a new one in mind
that I kinda responsibility
a mean yeah I think it's a
I mean it's interesting this is
something that I could bring up to the
the blood and I mean
maybe you wouldn't as a member you
wouldn't vote on that because it's a lot
of money
and if you think that is needed I don't
think knew what he needs that
because its mayeski for users
and users I'm not companies so they
don't really
can as long as it looks good I'm I don't
know
I mean way
okay okay and then
I'm yeah it would be nice if we could
just sit down together and write an
email to the board
because I'm just me forget so forget to
send the mail but just for good reasons
because yeah I don't work and that's a
little okay great
something else um so it isn't that slide
with an identity crisis is
prime yours you guys have find families
that it's more than just
he made his England sorry SBK I'm
so you're trying to establish that
you're more than just X that their Mesa
that you are also weighing on everything
do with graphics an important stuff I'm
one of the ways that you can make your
self visually
very visibly as well I'm
very important all this on his bike to
infrastructure by taking over
be to stop it or for instance and paying
for infrastructure getting is properly
at no longer user directories which they
don't disappear
or I reporter its hackers something that
would be something that
exhort has the money for the budget for
they could do that and they could give
us good hardware now we can
the panel this is something
we need to discuss indeed but
yeah we have we haven't had the time to
do that because you have free desktop is
not
that's not aboard no election and
yeah so yeah no accountability in any
way
that's the one thing X or cat
the organization is there and it's like
accountable
once a year bien but that it matters
much
for right I mean yes no I don't get
elected
all we didn't get much better ways to do
that
from on you can get you more power now
there's we're almost there is
yeah I'm here yeah it's important then
yeah this is something good
and I think we need to discuss that
there are however relation was free
desktop
right balcony over love that tho
condition you the plane but I think I'm
the only one
can yeah but that's a very personal
opinion not the opinion that the board
anyone else wanna make the fat man run
pack
you're allowed to I accept
mmm okay thanks very much fun
welcome way