to welcome everyone to the wonderbra for
them
folks who are new I think a replacement
for the they had for
work %uh that they packed arm
and what we're gonna talk about on this
next
30 minutes or so or 25 minutes as the
wine
test framework where there's a couple
areas there
and I'm going to try to briefly overview
give an overview of the wine
test framework and these guys can make
fun of me cuz I might get it wrong
on I'll be entertaining for them so if
that works
arm and then I think press was gonna go
in more detail with
the new test pot and some other
situations there so
arm so very briefly for those of you who
don't know
wine has up a ferry rich and mature
setup unit tests for Windows
so there's a very powerful said oh I
don't know how many tests there are now
but it's thousands right
its yes every every Windows API
has a test that goes with it and in fact
we had had
um VMware uses the wine test framework
to verify
that their windows runs correctly so
it's how they prove the Windows VM is
running right is because the wind test
run to completion
it's a very powerful so does tools at
most commonly done by running just make
test or that other developers do it but
there is also a
Windows execute a bowl on that is
created
that you can download and you can run
that execute all runs a quick a social
the cola make test
and then upload its results to test
got one each dollar to show test at last
you dork first
arm yeah
at this is the holding up today you why
developers
and anyone else who wants to help is
where an atrocious shape right now
art testing whatsoever yet he didn't
want to show this page City
hey so it did last year there was a lot
of green on the board and we are
celebrating how much green there was
this is showing
damages were 10 percent failures on
white wire we feel it so badly
do you have any idea 6
guard
yeah but we all know where goes about
its you all a shirt
and that's all you know is your area so
in what's unfortunate is
is this is actually really this is
horrible you guys this is horrible cuz
we're on a path all green and now we've
like back slip what
but okay yes I don't know we need to IRA
limited get up yeah
yeah we didn't have that the make test
lecture alright with this is the great
guest lecture
okay stop white green next time we meet
so and actually in all seriousness for
any view that have laptops what are the
things we are hoping to do what we
traditionally due to weinhardt is
we will look at them a test at us and
then we will have a session or that such
a schedule for for this afternoon
we're all kinda look at some other
common tests and see if we can squeeze
somebody's out
so I i say that technology has moved on
and it used to be a one after their own
a laptop and that's no longer the case
which is interesting
I'll so get running mate test on your
tablet in your phone sorry
and that will be Carter
so for any who are new to wine on
can we go to the the it you can do
something very useful and
there's a simple executed well you can
download and if you have wine installed
it
get build a wind um you can download and
run this execute a beloved a lot about
the upload to the web page in a
generates great statistics for us on
but you're showing city dog is there
some green okay so you feel better about
this page
I'll its to just
aka that's not all that obvious there
was a better pay is
there's a better page this
yeah okay so the bottom a test that one
issue there are there's a link
but because of your screen how maybe we
should put it at the top
okay alright so there's another to do
who could take that to do
you do that under oath over
yeah just move this to the top so this
is a useful thing you can do and then
what after you run it
your results will appear and you can see
results and then you can even go in and
see
what areas that your developer you can
run make testing you can submit patches
and fix it
and that's a glorious thing to do and
arm
so I think that was the paul got what I
wanted to say around
though regular wine test framework
and I think we have a lot of talking
about the new wine test but
arm just and took brain that for people
we in addition to running all these
tests on latex
we now also Ron all these tests on
Windows
so we have a Windows QEMU we we had a
VMware
system for years and years and years
that was the test but
and unfortunately %uh the maintainer
that
passed away arm as a tragic about
that we've been shifting it to a QEMU
based
tests that some well we're running all
these tests actually on Windows
and in theory they should all be green
on Windows but then what's good about it
as a patch can't get into wine
a change to the task and get the wine
Eliza runs correctly on Windows or so
goes the theory
a to the line test pot is actually a
wind said a Windows VM's
that brought all these tests on Windows
and
unfortunately we're having problems with
the new want us but to the other thing
we need to exhort people to do is help
us get those tests fixed
and working that's where i turn it over
to you then decide
its
so yes just
worth us
was just
us
missed just
its just
her his
both was of
they were who were
were whole shutdowns
girls I your ISP
made it's really more
hers really
his time
at
this us
bus she just
its sources
just does sold
weren't as used
she's
do see sure
since means
submit lost
school
just just
buses
she such us
just shins
so just is russians
stops
much is
said space
just arms want
schools is I'll
yep
this some South
Hills
like this
20 one
as just the world
huge
just is so is those
news
those Sudan
tourists toward
one storms
news
world this
news slow
use this
you know
to this she's cool
yousef this
its
those is workers much services
funds
Angeles so to do this book since
you just looked just
this
right
alt print
and the card
much
solution
looked
to richest
learn
these this wants to rebuild
to use to
walls sold
much get is which gets
two guns short CSU
sure us yes this post
sent
of this as
us use you
just shows
you can
just scam
soon changed
stew
this this
school
missions
sold
this
much
was some old
which
chilled
people
you
his
us
suspicion
right
just
ons
its weird test
Jim you wish she goes
slurs
others it
this
just
is she won't
just world
ones
this
those the actual are all
who you are his
soldiers
loses his mint
this
weird world
few old
this
news diverts
you you get lost
pic
with work
you here rush
by six so simple yet you
used
yes
work yen you get this all seems with you
and I just
he
s
chill
much shield
much heels
I while orange
this she's send one back yes
so just us
well
to go
up for
which support
just of course old
line
this
else
whose its mint russians
us splint
was revised
its once ort
rights ends
host those since
41 wish weird
whose
but just sees it
vote just
his just
just just is
words yes Ste
use looked
lines Paul is
this earth
world
forms its
this
used
us
spoiled
its
is
dispute its which
much
used
built
is
news means
chills
this news missed
sealed
his
this just
to me
posted
since this
alt since
whose this
its stalled
news sold
I
the world us this
be don't you
yes you
which who is
this sure
up
yeah
L
yeah Jerry
that yes
to JavaScript
actually
yeah
its
this was just was is
us
walls
news
sold both
is took 0
is chip
this
why both
you'll which
wall
wetlands this weird
still watch
it
releases yeah
donations 2004
world souls
its
fall
just wall
much
yes
us
to is Dutch fans
issues
life
is his
hard
harbors
in Iraq whole available well
art long one
water
notice he was yet
the best see stay like
all below
yeah
me
the I guess
every now and then hour
its us
says us
used
us
spoiled
its this
is
you
news
war
up with this you
yep you
0 you
I think that's actually bonuses stable
it's like
the big boys stable at least freeze was
the third
not as right work
us but the
lineup
well to you
who is this one think
disperses lines are great for any
he will see is the air close-up
all hey work hard
that's the one that's right my best is
your issue
steer the that
that everyday magic this is being
his vision for me
just for take ownership
soothed
is
just waffled
its much this
spins
want
doesn't
posts
either
bus
seeing on
it didn't bring goals
something
she's
this
get thats presenter death yes
you're pretty yet what earth
over as it they were broken by
video
no this
yet there are a few different things you
that
different these
keepers you can have that see problem
job is them you
everybody you doing fourth
last so I
our so there's that which
much just rooms
sometimes okay
I'm
Hughes cool
as
X-rays to cool burns
Swiss old
school
but do you think
do yeah session his group
a his and a
medium he'll
also me
we base a
you know what all yeah I love you
%ah