much and ok maybe we can have a
discussion
it's a topic is this the rise and fall
of open source gaming projects
and we take a 6.2
the project we work on battle for
Wesnoth who has not heard from
West not yet pocket
quite a few okay you here we have solid
but
no picture who bucket
better for West not is a turn-based
stretchy game
so it means you can move all your units
in one turn at San pressed send Turnpike
said the hey I and computes
or your opponents human opponents you
have a hex
field based game or because
text fields own allow at but our
the movement sheehan for example if you
have
squares so diagnose our more
lot right away Sen
support a cause was a horizontal we have
a picture
of right I
a yeaa you to everyone who knows German
right
yeah if there really someone not knowing
German in here you
dunno you okay I
ever seen him when can you start see old
version please
I can mainland
I cannot stop the old one
maybe mississippi no it's not our me
pics the pic but I'm
okay but I can switch wet one moment
please thank can you
mission I but do you want any strikes as
a list of supported language I want to
do this late on my talk
are you want to do this during your talk
you're okay with it if you didn't have
much
a separate company organized okay
training
this a okay
but but courage or too fast
met okay you talk hoster
it the O'Shea
met me
the home needs to demonstrate a little
bit of the game plan a whole
I'll try to
a.m. games following the KISS principle
kiss means
keep it simple and stupid that basically
means
you remove everything a.m. from
the user interface are from the game a
chain Mission TX
until you have reached 11 a.m.
red barely but yeah nothing
left to remove so
you can just click units ethelson or
we're tech as a human's it's nothing
more
right did I miss anything
recruit yeah okay you can you can call
if a new units
if somebody has don't
are not in no I'm lazy yeah he just
avoided
society okay
less not is a major project menchu
approaching
I'm what we have for each 10 years last
you
and
settling you during the last to once
you saw power or
form visit us %uh stagnating so we are
not growing anymore
the question is why that's difficult to
answer
them maybe
from it's because we failed to deliver
this new content content now we are
fully
content is the most important stuff
for open source games many
open source projects gaming related ones
have problems was content you have
attention
you have them
this debut idea of the game ish annex
but only a campaign with three scenarios
if it is campaign based and 2 a.m.
thats Hafen hour gameplay and cents
finished
I'm can can you leave
it's a scenario Keith I just want to
attack
yeah okay %um attack little him
pimping okay and
must come on you the No okay
said unless it is different we have a
lot of campaigns
17 her eighteen have come many
many good most awesome
are la chanson 10 scenarios so you can
play them
at least two weeks around-the-clock
if you up past include
earn sets much more certain commercial
many commercially games of all
for example I'm the last Starcraft comes
with one campaign
power 24 scenarios if I remember
correctly
I'm that took me two days
to finish on on the easiest difficult
level
and the second that was too easy for me
the next difficult love you
was too hot for me truck wasn't
exactly a the right audience has a game
okay we are not a burden
to include anymore campaigns into our
game because the last
our pros manager and sets really a
problem
we need a certain quality of
lot for work trolls a
story whatever and
it's hard to reach anymore
the without salt stuff and
stats stuff changes over time because
people lost interest
or are not at University anymore don't
have time or
Trust I we not sure the last one we have
heat but
it can Josh maybe one of our developer
style
didn't notice could beat you up could be
happens no chance to tell the
the Henry lever be really um
if they don't then we live how will we
know mmm they would just drop of
inactive
be but we actually made so anymore and
basically the same which happens if
you're really busy from the time we left
work
yeah sometimes people just quit basalt
noticing or all are answering anymore to
email it's all
however you tried to contact them yeah
reason to unknown but ok I
you know for yourself I
that you have created something and a
trust
bro up so every contact button at least
once in your life well
he didn't believe him let's just touch
yeah okay
but all about one of /url
also campaigns we have is some are
collected from
our I don't serve us so they are in fact
made by
users firm which
but hoped to the game and produced
one or a more campaigns we talk some
if they are fine polish them and include
them in the game
which isn't but possible hurt right now
anymore
so him sign up new version of les not
show some improvement but you can't
deliver
a.m. Wes some most important stuff you
content
a tooth mostly true for
a ojeda Playaz or longtime Playaz
long-term name you play yes of course
have to still plenty of content
to choose from still you need to arm
keep your user base happy if long-term
use us
tend to produce more content so
you do not want to lose them it on
yeah this of this
them please make sure to speak up
we try to record and other what's not
portable
a game developer you a he said he
doesn't have time for a call that
on it though somebody's a or scenarios
so what he did was owner Jerry Brown
to of a move is genetic algorithm maybe
0 the pic um old
thats aren't
and generate their own stuff well
its can be interesting on game
there your story me
still in the arm
normal game you want to have some cum
some campaign with some storyline
evolving
around some characters good or evil and
you want to have something going on
for this you need people who are able to
create scenarios
so the basic setup of each single
scenario
then some overarching concept to make it
a campaign
and who people also able to coded so the
finest
and maintain a doctor watts as you can
see in the ad on server
we have lots of content from users
because make it really easy to produce
new content
and uploaded their been real problem
converting
from this new con la pelota their them
first finding the
high quality content and then getting
into mainline
because all the level of maintenance you
have to do
whenever you change something in
mainline he might have to touch this
content
so ventral you just get
two large I'm
peace OpenSim and to mention a Yaris air
yeah okay love it pickpocket
says a lot of at once on Sarah M Sarah
over 500
I guess 620
something so it's quite a lot but
says a lot of unfinished on not working
what just them but quality
or not what's the use all wants to play
hmm okay
yet he was open source developers should
be confident saying those words numbers
me he picked not
no I'm how do your
find quality content or discriminate
quality content from non quality content
on such simple you card from I'm
was integrating with the
that the problem you you can a.m.
sarge by side miss you
my aunt be a side of quality
how do you get news yeah might be a sign
of quality
the process much using I mean Parkins
there but yeah him
it also might might be just a a
collection of
stuff sent base though since
if a you can also sought by totals
so if you don't know it
someone with some most downloads it gets
more downloads
saudis and empowering
system and mostly
supposed although it's not just thinks
this fancy names
for which one so once said got first
happens and 17 above the open a new one
for you
the a rating system
would be a solution cool was sentenced
yeah
do you have any experience with reading
systems are doing
are you a game developer a game soap
other BP stock louder so you'll be fine
some
way LittleBigPlanet up on
hello crop
in nineteen system some
hope
and cells
mmm it's not set easy to
establish a rating system but mostly
all concerns are said it leads to worm
yeah that competition might spoil all of
Troy friendly community yeah that some
the reason anthem I think we you will
need to or
get to a rating system sooner or later
yep
just to to make sure that some at on am
server is still use boom are usable
again
I'm but term
yeah old habits and all drawers hmm
are changing slowly in large open source
projects
especially if you don't have a dictator
yeah so I like
to advice you keep your dictator happy
so 13 lbs yeah our detailed I left
and in to become find new law in our
country a new one account agree that we
need to
dictator yeah you always have stuff
well I guess a basic problem
often face when implementing rating
system if you upload finish content
it's good but if you upload
interactively
like buttons also acutely is done yup a
little early version
someone downloaded sees but doesn't work
better rating next on the list that
doesn't work that rating
then you have some boats you have a very
low waiting
company working what do you do do you
discard all the old Commons
or do you keep them without your real
chance for improving
on nation to like he
about you in any
like late values
ready rating pain a year ago
it might be a valuable ap
yes for problems with we have not
tried out we are still in the face of
'em fighting against each
us a if you really want to read to them
couldn't help it
if one what about maybe
it in the channel a it show conned into
yet 1 a group called that you dole
pic from the core developer yes the %uh
structure that yeah I accepted
Melissa yeah know they are actually good
quite proper
I like Google
edition on the anybody can upload lately
I get that way
home yes I promised that ended ended in
a flame war of course
yeah I think it's a good idea
picking him his neck
%uh the most a you
the other gap but what effective I'll
cool number
me maybe our went with the United Way
they the
yeah you get some most every day
yeah we had one already have come back
to him
yeah written down below it was comment
on 1800
get more down low since on the list long
good we have at least one active you
the party also download house yeah
with him human him okay
that Yahoo Monday
yup
old
he said do 63
yeah I'm no stranger who do not okay
there NOP
things I have and reading
game reversible vision personal
people then the a to provide
the comp so me user as
rarely would see it into a processing
13 I'm well with open source in general
through past to be different you expect
assistant to rise
overtime my humor K months to pay
prop yeah indeed however recently
a games like Minecraft the and so on
have managed to
like the sOooo through process with
development with I
my suggestion actions since me
how beat the Browns so talk to the
people
this industry tassel iraq yes just got
caught up we haven't
you have a bait up branch course I also
the top
you try operating system time other
stuff which
was says yeah I'm backup
its stable engine want years
notes from well what's
based upon and you action
lame see yeah thing
it is thing branch and pay
development pushes through this pizza or
whatever
yeah from commitment and moment
my point is beautiful perspective to
develop
used so think so curious to see what
happens with you
with power SMC group and
is stable you house public
months
major them about home star like dumb
see back it's certainly not we have a
very strong multi-player community
and we make sure that our stable
releases a competent with each other
so one stable series every minor bugfix
release
what's a compatible with the other while
in the development really is because
we're doing some crazy stuff sometimes
they are incompatible so the players
just see
okay when I go to the multiplayer server
how many people will find their
for finding a place
now I have crossed I want to continue
as you can see here
160 another games players right now on a
Saturday afternoon
and they're even 32
ok 831 guys come hang around just in the
lobby
waiting to start games or stuff like
this whatever
talk just talking so the matter is now
if you come on the development server
and only see two guys around
and that's if you're lucky those guys
who want to play multiplayer
will not be there and if you have no one
there
the which a circle stocks you can
promote this one
I think he was first loud up
much not often result beloved
bit
game him
be great works
break him
I
old other here basically
me able
were C
and
he 3
his old
up
say yeah me
days we don't watch our thing playoff
make
that some we had a system once upon a
time
together statistics like this they do
was great
no internet so no many had it on
we had a lot of data yet but nobody we
made use of the data
because it was just too much information
to go through yeah
data mining is not too easy touch
exactly people
help
and upsets ideas we have over
Meyer
similar idea week up
her used
you
made three
we
by playing reading it so
persian rating but we sue
have so much you step forms
people photon one 5 stars Matt work
really well
everything we've done it before really
well help
crime sponsor month
here and people will us levels
people and we've got some really
fantastic
and I found the sense people get upset
optician fine competition actually heard
people's to push himself here what sorry
guys who owned it
better than that next time after
real Muzik think any yes people involved
in all
really depth there is good
cooperative competition and Jeff naked
competition to you need to encroach the
positive one
distinguish negative are you are only
PPP good him
when
pardon the pun p getting plowed 11 the
good work like group
live right here people were they did
back then
what no im a lot of people are and that
would be a way
rebel for but I'm not that I was the
test this
three years ago record every let me
check if we cancel finders
but I think it's gone but it a.m. it
wasn't easy to
to say quiet why did people quipped
that scenario 5 trust from
this is the testing or no longer there
why
the go insane also said gordon says
scenario
am it was difficult for me
but Yahoo I just used to put developing
pay maybe it can be used for
a yeah pretty add-ons better said for
development minute to try out
yeah a physician truck yeah the middle
so next mickey I i would tell you
pppp passion for you right now
really recognition issues to
carpentry week a forum titled
YUM our condo our content creators
the main exchange platform is our forum
in the forum we have some titles
of course every developer gets a title
translators get a title
artists get a title and those who are
known
to create good content good title and
those who are known to create
in normative content get a different
idea to get so
we'd use the system especially since the
forums on the Main Place
to complain about content which doesn't
work yeah it's a
serve most the balloon in
who was b what is the yup positive
comments and form
and yeah not very much
and maybe a high download rate but
yeah you can't refuse the dow not
counter
like like just the like i cum explained
before
and yeah this may not only one I'm
UMC in you submit content inside out the
head turned
going to rage yeah
mom kiss I nice neat more
we bought that's definitely the case
is p
so I want to come back to the point we
are just said on that
you need to basically four board I have
gone through in US not
versions is that many
yes yes yes the very great show stopper
for
place because as: for use
12 tryout perhaps very old
Adams have been reviewed in any way so
if you compare it with other games
for example the very obvious do
you can still play maps need in 1994
because
all the versions are supported through
Anders no
for plotting needed um grappling 16
on what we do have is we do have
different it on so what's the difference
wasn't
so we have 18 on some up for the old one
point six series
we have an at home so for the a 1.8
series we have a different one for the
11 Sep 10 series
don't but the basic not anymore okay
it's mom the six years ago so
you have a small anti fatigue Klein
front-runner right now bean
can you nope they were confident that
can run
almost all no of yeah and hence that
song
the experience we're updating stuff
going on that's
week our people forms about or content
and for and problems or homes
the matters if we kept the backwards
compatibility all the time
we will just should also select hasn't
been a problem
whole games it depends on how well we
find you engineers
and basically what we are developing
these days is the engine and since the
engines of changing all the time
and we don't have a one single fixed
for most apollo everything should be
it's not as easy
especially since we also say that our
core content
which can also change if you know stable
release
little stale API so to say core content
they are also being the units with the
unit ima just so frewer if you reference
10 those
from the core group it's perfectly
working in this
release in a statement series for
example but we do not guarantee
that we don't for example change the
mission Ave unit meaning that the frame
you will then see
if you are looking at frame 5 is not a
complete different one so
continuing the condom I loled but it
might not look
like the design intended to author
like content
usual on out mind
another live you K other
people what get
no yes there are plenty of players
election call and you any robbed
more making
way at all
morning pre-selection
possible increase the for
actually yes 5
lia's possible use to test
those version something like that Playaz
want to review stuff
yet just denying it was the toilet with
that we don't want to encourage
competition
yeah he plays Lowcountry you
themselves and will return they my team
yeah no and more
shadows competition get
his go fishin
um vision competition is strides
kids this optician up yeah anti-theft
outside
sup
from so the main point which is CS
unhealthy competition
often ojeda what's because leaderboards
of me to flame balls and stuff like this
so that's why we say we do often
that's why we say in our multiplayer
community
we do not support an official ranking
little something like this:
if you do want to do some drinking you
can do so but we will not officially
supported
within the game itself ya cerraron
let our game ass Who Am yeah
have some chest like its it's called
in law yeah in the ratings saying about
3 a.m.
we don't give some any support and point
was for your sons and because they do
this isn't it since we don't do this
we just ignore it know if there are you
think people
but OK yeah UPPP
Hughes be right players
and then palm different
that him killing
you players you something good play
you pension can't be yet he
stay yeah it's not but plate
play yeah I'm
idea is that term content creators
don't head each other anymore if there
is too much competition
but I don't shares that ICSI I'm
completely agree that
and there's health dept unhealthy
competition but im
num a large project
takes a lot of time to change
a week rules yeah and its an engine
rules that you don't like to encourage
competition
pp at and relax a dictator success
okay we do it because we need to do it
yeah have %ah behind the father
one something
a again you must be much much much more
louder
looked
I'm correct use this
it won't and yes yeah
so the game games
if people who
like you way detail
goes him provide
used like
serious games some
people worship wall
its slow everybody's
as its greatest does he is OK
before his well I don't think you
see and so long his
way up
and him you me day
release his
by is
commercial the
lot him in eighteen-year
only his
for
may disagree
here he no
who
me
the
rap
hahaha heat yes 3d graphics I'll
been is OK am yeah
everyday at home someone drops into the
foramen
us when who s not goes 3d the
yeah if you compare our pics I
images 20 80,000 nineties
we're doing quite well yeah guy I
good
me problem no measure your progress
to the the FB world
yeah in you are right them
commercially games what to say
the new game so you have to pot to our
part 3
we don't need to 'em who leads the park
to look past three
you can trust and incrementally at new
stuff
up but the problem is everything you
is always causing resistance CS always
at least
want develop of well once to help avert
at it says oh no my popular ap
so everything you as always
it a huge fight many yeah
don't dictate up um that's a problem you
all we're talking about open source
projects
everyone working on such projects has
their own motivation to do so
no matter if it's a game even some of
issued or
if it's a web browser or just some
commodification
the mattress if you have a project which
is
of some size and some H
you will have several old developers and
their
of course think have contributed so much
what I say is so the golden rule book
you know SFS he won't get around it
so it will be difficult for new
developers to really get hurt
and get there at New end of a great
ideas we implement
that's why fobby says you need a
dictator
you need to tell you need some shit this
celo unit held
can make them %um don't you
ruling him nope
um I think if I want to say is
what else most is to have someone else
handle the project
who is one strong my not
but you can also listen
and who doesn't say okay we have always
done it this way so we need to continue
this way
must be so doubled its site
yeah absolutely old
him I'm
both Graham
like use or his
ha on
the money not sure what you mean
yup ish then that we have hello
huge efficiently change
to sleep
loans
comp martin's family people like them
happening program
up
some all that stuff is possible some
content creators as assessed
a very innovative and what they are
doing um
who was it who made him was basically
movie player do you remember
no it did if him
yeah so you saw the game he basically
use the system to create a movie play
with it
main problem see you in
have lack of his okay ship first-year
site
today I
you know like that that it
that family I games like play it
the week one with me
you but you don't like a G
like like you me
like a
okay I think
play it again weekly they might
robert Half Mile by I
no but i dnt yeah I is gay
them so it by I like the left like
years ago I more than anything that yeah
3ft
II climate yeah he didn't want to
it both ways Groupe you have a and also
G
they wait you you development a you
might be
like yeah we tried to let you measure
like days ago developers it won't want
to keep my
the old one yeah the day you doing
Elizabeth for the day
for developers or people want to do that
they yeah I with me
whether to or no question what is the
difference
between West local one and what's not to
it was look at what what would be in a
theoretical idea
what would be the difference I think
deep down 88 wealthy
is a big butt it yet he is a UK
so people I would say yeah okay to get
that high the yes you're gay
you get to see ya from now on you're
going to
he's got the whole the waged we love it
as a very sharp
you a thought I
the IAAF later and we're going to have
that the
we do it then I all the good days or
try to do this you will wake up I
the Korean I but somewhere
date yeah no no all not that's basically
what we're doing with every new stable
release
yeah we just may it not naming in West
LAF to West Mall 3 US mobile 415
and we're still and we're still keeping
the old condom there and updating it
the merits what commercial games do
their is
they have all campaigns they just drop
them they no longer there
and you get the new release which
doesn't have the old campaigns put some
new ones and staff what we are doing
instead is
if we have some new content for example
we edit in addition to the existing
stuff yeah I
gory you don't want to support all good
it didn't look at the summit but the old
version
and that's fine I they like it to be
it was vision get online a you say
yeah now I'm is that neither should you
you wait you name it
and it can you call them the UK say the
best it out but they believe they have
the movies
8 what these and this is about done and
that
the next in you gave the gay but what's
the benefit of the only content
make because because the yet
you a good game the that you know it
gore is it you Yahoo inc.'s
looking yeah II and a
these little all of my day yeah
thank you I don't know why I am
they would look like want to know maybe
you'd like to
well said hit the nail on the head me
that it's not give up
you gave anything the also
it they maybe a little less mature
would not defend seemed but them
steam go yeah the problem it's just
there's
if you changed this red E coli it would
mean that you would have to redo all
artwork
that's not viable I
what that yeah he did that my
Soriano I guess we also the same
promised
most open source games probably half the
ratio between told us and doctors
is heavily focused on coal dust that
so couple you have well have loved
hello artists and from the house but
then come learn stuff you but
those artists solarz good data
you don't have well might happy less
experienced mom
texture we don't know whether I LLC
ones I don't think we've really because
I i water the movie
or me and old young donde
Anne mmm you direction
where they saw the art world
you mount work London in this past
years all over I'm
hoodie hard
market
like you
here and me
the membership
fish much him but history like a
I be word of noting that means
the sea best wealth
change
and you this that way
like the doesn't up
please hookup like
like schools with the the
Russian up
yeah
let's have to online won't play in game
day
lead Walker may open yeah throw in the
government
a just think that was important invasion
and
just changing every main like campaign
are already done
with that Scotland invasion in my place
it's difficult yeah it's very difficult
his
removed
yup men tried new world future society
candy some mister we'd Middle East and
Japan
more yes I think so yeah
we try to interview snows new stuff but
I'm
stock dropped tries to balance
three different action and say do
reasonably well
Koreans are think they too well
we we have balanced six or seven
some below this yeah and that took us
yes
yeah 55 yes all maybe we haven't been
fitted
yet thought introducing a new faction
Luther Bourque
mmm iterating over the balancing issue
again
we are doing that now for one new
factual
just replacing more someone
are I'll yeah a a lot a lot a lot of
in this
I thought about
Kickstarter project to collect lot
money Young Money can move
okay come
I think we just do those two questions
now we basically out of time
so I'll I i think people who have a
choice
going love with were be yes
this game has been going on for ten
years thank you
this staggering G and were happy
in commercial games the winter nights
way Sr
that's it no PPG and face
at some point impasse to Cup core
starkly
not you think what defines Lesnar
and what can be huge roommate it
different
game bill upon simple dish because I'm
sure
fancy source Co but I'm sure that prove
it ten years
development it wasn't yesen structure
which lawyer his
direction propaganda press conference at
work someone you have to
good structure take away everything that
is not needed
go again to the campus cool with me
normal
%um on that and thing is that up to ten
years
I think was a chance to have 5 yeah
only we downward I miss you me
project these with the police month
that might be true yeah here
this of more he was just more content
more probs nicer traffic
the people I yeah more and better
basically replace all those people in
the community we don't like
with people we like good health and he
gave
commercial or on world
nope yeah someone needs to be first to
be okay
this the gots
good