alright here
40 line Herald
all his way that
well heroes words
yes work they looked
day all speak you have
slide hallway is have cue
have you this air
Chinese
low s okay so
user experience last year
flurry
and I every
this year
split
Ste
cell actually scraped
the floor last year
see but they were 816
threats
Ste
well any this experiment
scientific stance
part so information review
experience very messy
for me cell
first thing keeping first-hand look at
hard
through with
overlap here who won
last night you know last year
so I'll or you doing great yes but
three-quarters
posters specific
usually
most house cell
also is questions artists or
and then there's small other
reese's
of suggestions
which T users are
admittedly of suggest
race might
the developers
course users
don't have a clue how it
so you know I will give you 50 bucks to
write this patch their money
I'll
race now
tests tell
you okay those so
I'll are for users yes learners
lives users
only
yes it and there'd
0 yes was a
users portion under
recent there
yes or
sticky saying we don't support
the state's telling them
so I suspect there
California up there certainly personally
but they're not going to come there
lol
up to the extent
I many
it but forcefully yes
old this list
separately enough okay in way
other and a breakdown were
other other is yeah
does cured p
Stenhouse up so this
he
by this yes
through strippers
speculate
like I think
his
release
in Jan and other still
people this all
us well cs4
you know last year is
just finished stalin and they're not
even quite sure how to use their
said i think thats
resupply you see so many can I don't
think they're necessarily
that terms
we're hearing to look it
what first one me
yes I actually 54 percent
August
previous
I'll their
always general reasons
hard
or
his made it
this
here looks like
like no
use to the current state
s missed
but meets
one his
spell
know cared
be points the next
shoes
I all night 1.6 usage was it
time this
his also session drought as expected
7 that group
one unexpected is
nosedive height six
takes tender
and i dnt here it actually below his
three
this bus
to use or yes
because
steeled yes
last shit
team peace
don't necessarily know he is something
let there yes
whose
for
deal part
well told
test I'm long time
up and late
so me
interns
British shows held
users experience
there
smack
old
test his
after is this cell by
sol y
so is this up package
was call
see
today
way
and change him he's here
be way
get one
16 which which
ok cement to
shit here burns
okay him
maybe then I'll normal
yeah I just
yeah and this is
at No 10 have
the state release yeah
belgrade as expected going up
hire you
going up is the other big thing that
happened last year's
December all
higher 16 it up
superiors you
spent a lot of time
what
so
again that's also OK for people who
perhaps
may have prepared to stay me
just its
we have share
use round open doors
yeah just breast
make hers old
some users
or list
yes race after
to Newsday grant here
I start to see
care loves his
home
stacked yes
experience here improved
no I'm is but
for the things you don't know users are
happy
yes oh yes
no I
say
scheme skiers
were very unhappy card
any is
yes this and
yeah pro richard is
true in
injured find a stable branch
precious Lord France in particular very
point 1 and the reason for that
cheaply
frustrated Voice 1.4
East
one point yet ready
this
up so
were still senior foresee
I'm land he must
cell
i cant me sorry mystery to help
meatless problem they didn't you
spread silly
yes whose tables slow
a ish
you
first
six months
screening tests already
not know volunteers
Houston
fifth scared
there many
space used
tired house
yes this
its semi support
says fish
play online playing
he said X
us help mostly
who sells speaking myself some highest
problems live tracks
fly I S
I know the answer or
said
yes
others lines
rappers
this
yes definitely underrepresented
out using
its we have telling
I'm ask
accused he usually
a St her up it
let's
her
cell
yet there
first score
early next old
for it
miss you
problems building said ass
hands
most are you sorry but you
very me
neighbors
is Easter
day some
is some
cell
terrorists for damian
such problems laws here
is
instructions
our wiki predate totally useless
for current people using real
first K PS
people playing me for help just
I'll fight give them advice
here they're used
up
yeah week your fellow
users very great and I love you very
great
yes like 8
close his
more on which calls
W
somebody his Hill post
up today instructions for building why
and its little step 2
people's said they have searched the
entire I
today instructions you know actually 8
love that
look like militants up in
very users to this blog entry
nobody said it didn't work course the
other always
that the other but just
playing aged
ok yes
I severe
I you something out billion actually
their
me this actually is the he do it
the thank you
a yeah
you know his status
he really is you know suggestion
here yes and maybe that's because work
in their head its
me this is the time difference yes me
they
hurt
you
in yeah
everything in it
actually cells
I the
yeah Inc this problem
here Getty up-to-date information as
well
yes just yeah
from Sergio
but
her building you know
I okay because I see any bill
its top-line you know to
cather's
circuit helms instilling
yes list
also is
well
hard experienced paltry
for westerdam's in September is caller
actually was every
stop Shiancoe the ethnic
in December travel carried out me
our the
PA pay like you know
week idiot through nice pictures and
eastern
ornate happy mp3 shrine now have any
place for a
but we did
because there was an extra space in the
HTML
because i text a
hell huh history
I'll he's staying
I lol is trashed fire they don't work I
think used
brushy up someone
thankfully figured out lol yet this
at
well
this was our fault
%uh
again because yes
we have I
his this paint
so I use
but killed
last list
first 3l yes
it yes questions her
it is naturally people St
but you know that there's
unexplored
has nature
his are its yes
so at some point
but this was definitely
okay space stirs
okay lol Chris
red all
but the keyword
most customers crash already has
something necessary SEC
graphics
units
weird and stuff input
is that I
West location number
say face one
area actually stage
stairs place
last percent
yes so hardcore gamers
support
this represents this this
range my experiences
this stage use a at
this K I have to
just face
the user's
a
rose
use cool place I a
those guys a slow
that
yes
yards take their
okay
looks here hearing
happily are some cases showing up
response on
like in cues
session actually
language really you know
tree Japanese fast if you try it later
a Japanese program for your sisters at
the ish it just doesn't work
slush yeah you have to make sure that
the locale
she matches look out the program any you
can stack
you know wine through a little bit
nascent
people marines last election let but s
terrible and variables
it's actually not accurate we have here
questions the user
yes thank you
still light last
was or
North
users to the east and
help read correct L
but and it's clear
that people really in many cases
loved here
you
now my night
which means yeah expect them to do their
homework
expelled
I
teachers Ste
just
no last
teacher cell
in but yes
why that
week doing there make
the sample problem page
is example girls are well try
now
it's obviously don't
hmmm a healthy
cell
yes up but
terms
well like their
is filing
boast face
yes
16 held
cell
it's not like information every
scared a
there you go I
jurors
me
all or lot
this
first thing less
which
search looking
keep or
they can I help pretty less
name roles
say
their their you
n yeah this the information me
shared
and see so
underestimate
now let's say sided search warrant a new
one
they will sometimes
by okay yes
saying done
but cell I'll
yelled
for structures I'll
same thing here
pretty teacher somewhere used
isn't
scratches haven't 3 any
this H
just just all and do
yes he's
office but
this is old
here's experienced
last problems certainly
intent next nation
here think about it or
its hit here
russians which
process this is a
job group
well
choir still lightly fixing this
could be done by there may be little
required ACK harder
we stop here
his stock
here hey
with old
up day turns
use I
this is the one
well he me
paged now
shorter
like
sold
talent
here me
we'll skilled
reads
you try experience
I hope
yes nice
last
you Pray Love he
loved
step
up
skills her
this start looking so I'm I just
installed Ubuntu
10 minutes ago you
I'll
you know that now hi there
and sell you know I love yet
okay there is lols
I'm by so
100 well see
other I 30 7700
don't let takes a while play cell
user me see
his
est
s selling heard that now
step 3: his
police first yes similar goals
recent okay
I just a
yeah align their yeah
I'm here were
you sure for here
does
what you do is yes we are you lost
so is okay
division alright
just looking at grammar science
true yes lol
have it fixed committed if I
yet me paged
I
me latest stable heard
understands old
cell his
eerie
hard already for a couple days
no late us this has nothing
I'll just get
Sunday tired I'll
but this late is what leads
hate has the accurate information an
escape
doesn't look like it anything
do with factory Corey read the FAQ
like you there me know and I'll close
you actually help
two conflicting this one will actually
finally scratches
homeless not or in a way to train people
more so if he
to say experienced
direction intelligent people
or teaching flights
this
yeah it's
should have anything else are
its