round trip time or zero rtt which is a
performance optimization feature and
what that does it enables the client to
Recon that's reconnecting to a server to
be able to send encrypted data uh back
to the server without need without
needing prior interactive handshake so
it kind of eliminates that and while
this is a great enhancement for
performance and um avoiding latency that
can come that can be used as a
vulnerability if used
um a certain way so how can that be
vulnerable well the TLs 1.3 will
generate a new set of keys for each
handshake and the pre-shared key cannot
be refreshed without a trip but remember
this is a zero round trip time so when
that's when that client sends that
packet the server will already
authenticate it and if it gets sent
through again zero zero handshakes so if
it gets sent again or replayed by an
attacker it will be authenticated and
will go through just like an original
request if you haven't already thought
about what can go wrong with that
um basically one of the main
vulnerabilities on here is that the the
the replay packet will be recognized as
the legitimate one and
that can be used in a replay attack
let's walk through the steps of how that
works so hacker intercept initial
connection client and server we can
capture that in Wireshark and after that
we um
the hacker will replay the initial
connection let's say we're making a
purchase buying something at a
restaurant the food the server will
recognize the initial connection as
legitimate so at that point we already
know the client we know who it's coming
from it's authenticated if it's coming
again we didn't have any around uh any
um handshakes on any Ryan trip round
trips so what that means is that once
it's sent again the server will be like
well I know you so here is the um here's
the payment we'll go through again at
this point we have a duplicate payment
in the system now while that can be used
to replace packets and get to what we
want because once we get a duplicate
payment we get free food or a duplicate
order there are a lot of fraud detection
mechanisms in place especially from
financial institutions uh some of them
include duplicate transaction detection
so automatically when something with the
same exact amount at the same exact time
goes through that can just uh disregard
it but sometimes it can be a card
verification value tokenization or IP
address and geolocation this is actually
an important one because say you're
making or a customer is making a
purchase at a restaurant in Phoenix the
attacker can be remotely replaying that
attack in Texas that's obviously going
to erase some suspicion and the bank
might just block that because of that
discrepancy between the geolocation of
the initial transaction and the replay
the two-factor authentication also
includes when the bank will send you a
text message saying hey is this you
trying to authorize this duplicate
payment
but um
how do we take all this information and
execute it into getting the free food
which is also our goal first we select a
Target restaurant of course we'd want to
select a restaurant that we like
um the food there and also one of those
where you go and pay uh it's a
self-service restaurant where you go and
pay yourself for the food once we do
that we start hiking hacking the Wi-Fi
such as with the process that Ryan
explained and then we start capturing
Network traffic this is not only
important to see what's going on but
also to kind of make sure that we're on
the right network Wi-Fi network because
sometimes they'll have multiple networks
and we want to make sure we're on the
one where the pus is connected to see
that as shown on the screenshot we um we
saw a clover packet Clover is a part of
the POS terminal system which reads the
card information so once we see that we
know we're on the right Wi-Fi network
then we proceed and check out uh what
happens next right
okay so eavesdrop's customer name and
number this is the part where we um
listen to a customer ordering food we
like that food we listen to their name
write it down because we'll need it
later then uh once the order uh once we
have captured all those packets in
Wireshark we will have to save them in a
new um in a new file or a new PCAT file
the reason why is because we don't want
to replay the whole traffic that's been
going through between in that Network so
we will save that range usually to make
a transaction go through there is not
one single packet there's a range of
packets so we can transfer over all
those packets into a new into a new file
to replay later using TCP root light
what that will do is they will allow the
payment to be duplicated and
um the order to go through again which
is what we want once that goes through
then they will call the name of the
customer that we impersonated and we can
just go collect the food
so how did we do like we said our
overall goal was to try this in a home
lab setting get it working and then go
into an actual restaurant and try it out
so at our home lab Wi-Fi worked well
right uh that was all the videos that we
showed you were able to very easily try
it multiple times with success
the POS bypassing was a little bit
harder to test but we were able to find
instances of that TLS 1.3 replay attack
vulnerability and actually exploit it in
the wild we were not able to actually
test it on an official POS system as
short of creating a fake business and
convincing a sales team there's no other
way to ideally get a license and then
test it on a local instance but in
theory that means we can get free food
now in real life it's never as easy as
it seems and believe it or not not many
restaurants are open to the idea of us
going around and poking in their Network
to try to find vulnerabilities so at the
end of the day we were only able to get
one restaurant to give us permission and
even then it was a pretty limited scope
and timeline that we had so when we did
it wi-fi hacking works well we were able
to use Wi-Fi capture a handshake and
then we were able to run our customized
word list to get the right password
which was just the restaurant name
followed by a number
then from there we did some more
enumeration found some other things that
would be interesting were to be in scope
such as the actual access to the admin
side of the router having a nice little
hint on their password about having two
kids so if you did some more osin may
have been able to crack that as well but
it was not in scope so
what about the POS bypassing well
unfortunately while we were able to
confirm we were on the right Network and
we found specifically a clover instance
packet of being run so we know we're on
the right one we were not able to test
the TLs 1.3 replay vulnerability as
during the short time frame that we had
for testing this restaurant we were not
aware of it and any other instances of
trying to bypass the POS did fail on RN
so while we did not get free food we
still have a potential exploit that we
want to be trying and we're going to be
actively trying to utilize in the future
with other restaurants that we're still
working on trying to get permission to
do so legally
awesome and that's the wrap regarding
our research I'm not sure if we have
more time for questions but thanks
everyone for being here we have two
minutes okay we can take a couple
questions here uh if we have more
questions we'll be hanging out in the
hallway or you can ask us on the Discord
Channel as well
thanks everyone
[Applause]
what's up guys next speaker I think so
yes sir
it's a pretty common name you may want
to drop a last name
I was in a group one time where I was
the only one there who was the Special
Forces
like that was the dude's real name
foreign
and I go crazy anytime I actually have
to sit in front of a mic instead of
being wired up
it's not I said I go crazy anytime I
have to like sit in front of a mic
instead of being wired up I've got two
handhelds
no no no it's like karaoke
thank you
foreign
got it
all right good morning everyone
into Maya talk best practices and
Lessons Learned From setting up multiple
oscent units that is a big title my name
is Matt Edmondson I just recently
retired after over 21 years with federal
law enforcement I have founded multiple
osync units for the United States
government both in the Tactical level
and at the headquarters level I am the
Sands instructor and also the author of
the new Sans SEC 497 oscent course
are you back
consulted with a bunch of multiple
Fortune 500 companies spoke a black cat
spoke a wired yada yada yada
I'm going to talk about a few things
today we're going to talk about some
recent changes that have been going on
in oh since the past couple years some
of you may have already experienced if
not and you do oh sent you most
certainly will we'll talk a little bit
about operational security opsec because
that's something that's so important to
people and we'll talk about a little bit
about persistent monitoring there at the
very end the Genesis of where this talk
a lot of the material came out of was a
few months ago out of the blue got an
email asking me if I would be willing to
fly to the east coast to Quantico and
present on starting an osync unit to the
heads of security for a bunch of Fortune
500 companies most of them Fortune 100
and ciso csos Etc
sounds amazing yeah let's do it and you
go there and it was like going to be a
pretty big room and you're expecting
people to be polite and you're expecting
people to pay attention but they were
just super engaged and I saw a bunch of
people taking notes like asking
questions after the fact like oh Santa's
definitely growing like it really really
is everyone realizes it right it's skill
sets of the thing a lot of people
realized that they needed before but
maybe they weren't calling it o sent
right but there's definitely a a strong
demand for that what do I mean when I
say what's been changing at Ocean the
past couple years right
historically if you think about oh sent
oscent rules have been relatively well
defined and consistent right law
enforcement
short-term quick hit I'm looking at an
individual a group of individuals right
I want to degrade disrupt dismantle
right can I actually arrest someone can
I break up this organization that's what
it is usually quick hit intelligence
like Department of Defense you normally
think of more
kind of holistically maybe instead of
looking at an individual or group I'm
looking at a country you know a region
of the world an industry something like
that
CTI units for the private sector
companies right things indicators of
compromise a lot of technical people in
here deal with no doubt right what are
the ttps who are the main threats to my
industry certain things like that
and people usually describe the
different rules like that and you
describe it like if it's buckets of
paints like this is the law enforcement
bucket this is the private sector bucket
this isn't that bucket
but in the real world it doesn't look
like that on the left it looks like that
on the right and it has been for the
past few years now this has been going
on for a while right and I've seen it
from both sides of the coin right like I
have a decent amount of private sector
experience for Consulting my wife ran
sniper threat intelligence for a fortune
hundred company right so you have a
pretty good purview of a lot of
different ways
and so I've seen law enforcement
analysts that weren't technical at all
and it's no knock on them there's hadn't
been trained that wasn't really their
specialty but now they're doing things
like researching IP addresses
trying to figure out if it's a VPN where
in the world it's coming from just
looking at technical things that they
don't fully understand
and from the flip side right what I saw
firsthand was private sector companies
especially a couple years ago we had a
lot of civil unrest here in the country
that are all of a sudden doing like a
force protection mission
right like I can remember my wife
getting phone calls like hey I've been
in the office building now for 16 hours
but I don't think it's safe to leave or
hey I just got off the subway I can see
the office from here but it doesn't look
like it's safe to actually go in there
right and all of a sudden like there was
some code that I wrote for persistent
monitoring that I used in the government
and I know of at least two Fortune 500
companies during that time period
they're running that code trying to keep
an eye on situational awareness was it
safe for their people right or threats
against Executives you know Anonymous
threats and trying to track down who it
is all those types of things and so we
see law enforcement people
doing more technical work
we see non-you know private sector
people now doing roles traditionally
filled by law enforcement and really
like I said it's all kind of blending
together
and this is the last slide on that topic
but why is it important right why does
it matter
when I was driving on Quantico a couple
months ago I got very close to where I
was going on base and I drove by here
and I stopped pulled over my rental car
got out and I snapped a picture of it
that is the long range rifle range there
on Quantico and I kind of thought like
wow you know I remember when I was a
little kid reading a book by a guy named
Carlos Hathcock and he was one of the uh
one of the most decorated snipers in
American military history he was in
Vietnam and there's a story from that
book that always stuck with me I don't
remember a ton from that book but I
always remembered this one story and the
story was
there was a mission that he thought was
very very dangerous and he was close to
being able to get out of there but he
didn't feel like it was safe to send
anyone else in he thought he was the one
who had the best chance to do it so he
felt right that he would go
and so he's going there and he's
stalking his Target and he's out here by
himself right Vietnam no one else around
just hiding in the grass for a couple of
days
and he's just slow at his tired he
hasn't slept in a couple of days and
he's hungry and he's thirsty but he's
still got a couple hundred more yards to
where he's planned on taking the shot
from
but he got close and at that point he's
like
damn it I can make it from here
I've made the shot from here before like
I can do this consistently I'm just
gonna take it from here and he was
having this internal struggle with
himself as far as
what are you doing
right yes you probably could make it
from here but you're hungry you're
thirsty you're exhausted mentally and
physically you made that plan when you
were well rested
well fed
you know didn't have these problems
going on stick to the plan that you made
when you were thinking clearly
not the plan now when you haven't slept
in two days and you're exhausted
and it's kind of a similar thing right
it's a similar thing when I was doing
I've done a lot of digital forensics in
my career as well too I hate doing
something for the first time when it
matters
right and that's true in oscent that's
true in digital forensics like can I
practice first can I have something like
what I'm going to do and have a chance
to kind of go through that and so always
think of like things that you maybe
haven't dealt with yet but you think you
might have to deal with right that's why
it's so good to do things like tabletop
that's why it's good to come to
conferences like this and kind of talk
to other people and hear what other
people are having to deal with
because like I said if you haven't dealt
with it yet at some point you probably
will and if you've kind of prepared for
it done some research practiced it a
little bit it'll just make you so much
more confident it'll make your work
better it'll make you less stressed
there's just a lot of things going and I
realize that's not always easy but I
realize that we're all busy we're all
swamped and so it's tough to like man I
don't really have time to work on these
other things and try to practice and try
to improve my skills because I'm just
swamped at things that I absolutely have
to do before I can go home at night and
I've been there before and I get it but
just at least in the back of your mind
right we're always trying to work on
these things that we think we may have
to face at some point and get prepared
for it and we'll talk about some actual
things to possibly prepare get ready for
and the rest of this presentation
so best practices for starting up an O
sent
it's kind of worth me I think taking a
second at this point yeah thank you
I have Mayhem Lauren
I didn't set out to be an ocean person
right I was law enforcement I was doing
digital forensics kind of specialized in
that I started um I kind of wanted to I
had an interesting incident response and
just kind of the way my mind worked I
thought well shoot before I learned for
evidence of people hacking I myself
should learn how to hack so I started
doing that taking classes went got my
oscp you know doing some offensive style
work
and as I started doing that and I got
better he realized that like the most
important phase is reconnaissance and
it's not even close that information
that you gather drives everything else
that you're doing
and so this is going to sound like the
stupidest
it's like man there
and applied to what in the day job and
what some of my co-workers in the day
job do and so I wrote this tiny little
stupid like one and a half page white
paper
basically calling out listen we have
enough people here now
and my analysts and no disrespect to
them they hadn't been trained for it
what they were basically calling Osan
right they were very very good at using
government systems of record but then
they would do like
three four minutes of Google searching
and call that ocean right I did the yo
Sin and so I basically wrote like a one
and a half page white paper and shotted
up my chain of command and said hey we
have enough people now we should
probably carve off a few people to
become true ocent experts and really
understand because of some of the stuff
that I've seen from my technical work I
realized there was a lot of potential
there
didn't think anything would happen from
it about a week later I got notified
that they were pulling me out of digital
forensics to go start up an Osa unit so
I didn't even want to run it I didn't
even want to get involved with it with
myself it just kind of happened right it
just kind of happened and so knowing
that and starting it up
you know what are some of the things
that I uh that I did right and what are
some of the things frankly that I did
wrong one of the things I did right was
I started working with legal from the
very beginning both starting up a unit
at the local tactical level and then
later on a few years later at the
national level of Washington DC my first
meetings were with legal or with privacy
I'm gonna be honest like I pulled some
shady stuff more shady or honestly off
work than at work
but not so shady that I ever demanded a
full-time lawyer like I never pulled so
many hijinks that a lawyer's full-time
job was to keep me out of hot water
thankfully
it was close it was close a few times
but what I did do is I'm like listen I
don't want a lawyer full-time but give
me two lawyers who can spend a little
bit of time to become familiar with me
and my team and what we're doing and the
reason is that is huge because then when
I need a quick opinion I actually stand
a chance
right actually extend a chance this
picture right here is from an
international airport when I was doing
digital forensics a lot I got a phone
call one day from another agency hey can
you get to this international airport by
this time and you can if you leave
basically right now we have a high value
Target it's going to be getting off a
plane we can give you about five minutes
alone with their devices what devices do
they have don't know
okay
and basically to the point of where I
only needed to leave in like the next
two hours if I was going to make this
happen
if I didn't have two lawyers that were
familiar with me and what I did
and I just called like the duty pager oh
gear God there's no chance right who are
you again
what's your name
what's the name of your unit what do you
do
who are you under again
okay one more time what's your name like
I don't stand a prayer right but by
having that
Rapport already built up in the
confidence hey this is what I was just
to ask this is you asked me what do you
think yeah I think it's fine to do this
this and this just don't do this Roger
that take off and I'll do it right and
post it up shop in a back room under
construction took that picture I haven't
showed it to anyone until like a couple
months ago it's the first time I ever
like I'm like wait a second I think I
still have that on my phone right but
this is why quick opinions matter trying
to trying to build that relationship
before you need it right there are some
things that I absolutely hate and I
don't use that word lightly and one of
the worst ones how much do you hate the
first time you meet someone having to
ask them for something
right you just go up to someone man like
what's your name
Chris hey Chris oh nice to meet you oh
man yeah I talked to him for a second
and he's like wow this mat seems like a
great guy hey Chris real quick can you
uh can you go do this thing for me real
quick and instantly right what happens
he goes from thinking yeah that man
seems like a great guy to that son of a
was only talking to me because he
wanted me to go do something right yeah
he set me up
all right but nah seriously building
that Rapport having that relationship
before you need it if possible once
again is important is important right
it's important to work with legal
but it's also important to be very very
careful and to try not to let them if at
all possible and sometimes it's outside
of your control and I get that
don't put more constraints
on yourself than the law does
if at all possible if at all possible
Right
and you got to be safe safe policy wise
and legal wise right but there are some
key decisions that you can make and this
is one of the things that I was
hammering home when I was speaking to
those Executives a couple months ago
about things like violating terms and
services right how many Facebook
accounts are you allowed to have
according to their terms and services
one what name does it have to be your
real name right from an opsec
perspective anyone want to go
investigate a target with their real
personal account
I've done it I don't recommend it I've
done it when I had to it's a whole
different story over drinks all right
there's some stories you got to get me
liquored up for but not too much but uh
but not seriously right from an opposite
perspective that's a bad thing and so
I've seen places like their terms and
services says we can't do that so we
can't do that
oh great guess what you just hamstrung
yourself next time you have some
information posted there that you need
to go check out what are you going to do
and the worst part about that is people
still go do it they just use their
personal accounts
right I remember one time a buddy of
mine went with some Mucky muck for the
Department of Homeland Security down to
a facility in Florida
and he saw people working there that
were researching Targets on their
personal phones and he's like I can't
believe what I'm seeing like don't these
people know that's a poor idea
yeah yeah SOB they do but you haven't
given them an alternative
right you haven't given an alternative
and God bless them they're trying to do
their job
right so be very very careful about not
violate saying that you're not going to
violate terms and services because that
can have some ramifications that
sometimes people don't anticipate
acquiring and utilizing breach data
right people have some very very strong
opinions on this
I was listening to a podcast with an
ocean expert a couple months ago
and they said why at the very end of the
podcast interview the host asked them
well what do you think about using
breach data I would never use breach
data right I don't see any difference
between using breach data and buying
stolen property
the host is like yeah I agree and I was
sitting there like really Queen
like seriously like and I didn't think
less of them
I thought man what a hike maybe a narrow
field of experience
right anyone here I remember about a
year ago when koalas got popped
yeah word spread that there was client
vulnerability scans sitting there on the
dark web
yeah I got contacted by a number of
companies private and public sector
wanted me to go hey can you go grab that
data and let us know what's in there
right what is our exposure in there
right MGM gets popped I remember a large
company reaching out hey we some of our
Executives think they might have
sensitive information in there can you
grab a copy of that and see what of our
information is on there right there is
all of these very very in my opinion and
once again this is my opinion there's
sometimes and I'll say it's my opinion
and just kind of leave it off there
sometimes I'll say it's my opinion but
I'm right right it's my opinion but I'm
right there are some very valid reasons
to look at this stuff sometimes and so
knowing that and kind of anticipating
and being able to explain cool if you
shut this off this is what we were
potentially losing
right just just know that right try to
fight for it if at all possible and the
same vein visiting the dark web I know
places that aren't allowed to do that
well once again it's all fun and games
until supposedly data of yours of data
people you've been dealing with right
and you want to remember like the uh Law
Firm that got popped data posted on the
dark web saying hey they don't pay the
ransom within about two weeks we're
going to start unlocking these files
let's see what you've been talking about
with your clients
right like stuff gets real scary real
quick sometimes
and the last topic on this right if the
scope of your team's research is going
to include looking at employees make
sure HR is involved right it seems
should be fairly obvious but I think
it's worth taking a few seconds to
mention right you may be the one doing
all the technical work but HR is
actually the one driving and I've been
caught up with this a few times I've
never been in my entire career I was
never Internal Affairs or anything like
that but sometimes they would need me to
do the technical work that I could do
and it's like great I'll do the
technical work but I'm following your
directions right you're the one driving
right now
all right
up sec
it is the most challenging topics to
discuss right I put one of the most
because I don't like to speak in
absolutes but it really really truly is
and I think too
this is one area where a lot of quote
unquote ocean experts have done the
industry a great disservice
and I've seen it firsthand at
conferences like oset conferences you go
there and you see someone who's kind of
Twitter famous and then you'll see
someone who's eager and they want to get
into it and they come up and talk to
them and they're like oh hey I'm trying
to break in you know I wanted to do
these things but I want to make sure I'm
doing it safe
and all of a sudden the person who's
quite a Twitter famous the quote unquote
experts just starts rattling off like oh
you got to use at least three vpns you
got to use this you got to use this you
got to use disposable VMS you got to go
pay cash for a laptop at Best Buy make
sure you're wearing a fake mustache you
gotta do this and I seriously and they
start rattling off like 17 things
not the way humans are wired
or wired if I give Chris a list of 17
things to do you know how many is going
to do
maybe one maybe giving yourself a lot of
credit there well look yeah a lot of
credit yeah he already has the mustache
he checks that one right off the list
right it doesn't even need the fake you
might have to shave it then just to
throw them off
but seriously right that's not the way
human brings are wired like two things
do those come back like two more right I
have seen ridiculous opsec when it was
needed I remember one time I had a buddy
of mine was working a um one of the old
anonymous hackers one of those cases and
it was to the point of they had rented a
fake up they had rented a created an LLC
a fake LLC rented an apartment under
that
had a computer internet connection
everything in this llc's name and they
were using two vpns out of that and in
the first VPN they were connecting to
the one closest to them they had a
confidential informant that worked in
that company so if they ever got any
indication that someone was researching
them they were going to look them up
you want to talk about tradecraft and I
could go on about that that was some
trade craft that is also overkill for
99.9999 of the people in the world right
it really really is and so that's what
makes opsec
so tricky to deal with because there's
always these people out there oh more
and more and more and more it's not the
more is a bad thing but just level set
right and if you think about what opsec
is right you can look up different
definitions things like that
but at the end of the day it's a risk
management framework right it's all the
steps that you're taking to try to
reduce risk
but a lot of people in here know can you
ever eliminate risk
can't
right you can take the steps reasonable
steps to reduce it as much as you can
yeah one open mouth
at the end of the day though
you got to accept that risk or don't and
don't do the job right but those are
your two options at that point so you
try to minimize it
when I first started my oscent unit when
I was pulled out of there I was told
you're starting up a unit and you have
no budget no budget for training no
budget for tools no budget for anything
this is gonna sound like a joke and it
kind of is and it kind of isn't
one nice thing about having no budget it
makes your decisions really really easy
yeah what tool am I going to buy I
wasted zero seconds on that problem
right I figured out what I could do
I figured out what I couldn't do that I
needed to do and I figured out how to
build a tool to do it
right the same way I kind of got sucked
into like
ocean I kind of got sucked into coding I
never set out to be a computer program
I'm not like I am not a computer
programmer like I write computer code
that is functional and works and helps
me and my friends and everyone at work
looks at it and they're like oh my God
you're
my wife who's an actual engineer looks
at it and like your code is crap I'm
like
I know
just hanging my head in shame yeah I
know just don't tell anyone right but it
got the job done right and so you learn
it's one of the things that I had to
deal with several times in my career
unfortunately was um
people making purchasing decisions
that weren't Technical and the problem
with that is
people making decisions on what to buy
when they don't understand what we can
do without anything
right and you end up with this oh my God
this brochure is so glossy the sales
people were so nice this lunch was so
good and this tool can do 17 things and
I'm sitting there like I can do those 17
now
right versus some small company that can
only do two things but damn it I really
need one of those like one of those
would be a huge huge game changer right
so kind of fighting for that is a tough
but like I said understanding when you
have nothing in no budget you really
understand what matters and you really
understand how to get some bang for your
buck and so there's a lot of cheap dirty
tricks that I would figure out out of
necessity frankly
and if you thought this guy seems a
little immature you're right
thing about opsec and we kind of talked
about this a second ago it's a spectrum
that it really really is on the left
hand side we have no opsec whatsoever
like none right people using personal
devices personal laptops right got
Chrome open got your Gmail in one Tab
and you're researching the target next
tab over right just things that are
generally considered pretty poor idea
all right we want to kind of avoid this
and then on the far right right this is
where we have the pay cash for the
laptop multiple vpns all of these types
of things it's crazy crazy stuff I used
to tell people when I was a teacher I've
traveled all over the world for the
government teaching us it and I tell
them like when I would kind of explain
it as a spectrum I'd tell them listen
we're never going to get here
in my career I'm like listen I only got
a few years left I am never going to get
here and I know it
right but we can get close
without a ton of effort honestly and
without a ton of money right we can get
close fairly easily and fairly cheaply
let's talk about how but before we talk
about how one more about the why
this is a crazy story
if you're visiting Twitter
Facebook sites like that you're giving
away your IP address to them all right
maybe you'd care maybe you don't
but if you leave those sites right if
you click on a link somewhere else
you're giving up your IP address to
whoever posted that link potentially
right and we know this we all use Link
shorteners every day like Bentley and
other types of Link shorteners there is
some that will let you track the IP
addresses and some basic browser
information of whoever clicks on those
links and you can start to track that
right
I've seen this weaponized a few times
but by a mile my favorite and my
favorite because I wasn't involved in it
I wasn't the one who got burned in him
there was an individual who thought that
law enforcement might be researching
them
they were right
so what they did is they've been posting
content to Facebook now what they did
they threw like a little party something
like that and they're like oh yeah I was
down here at this party last weekend
here's some pictures but instead of
posting the pictures on Facebook they
posted the picture somewhere else
and they use one of these link
shorteners on Facebook oh yeah you can
click here to view the pictures
they were then monitoring the IP address
of everyone who was clicking through
those to look at the pictures
and you're like wow how did you know
that did you end up arresting him and I
told you no no no no they were calling
people out on their Facebook
oh yeah law enforcement agency would
click on the link to go look at the
picture and like 15 minutes later they
were getting called out on their
Facebook page oh it looks like the
Department of Justice is looking at my
picture
oh looks like this agency isn't like
this was like oh my God I'm just sitting
there like with a bucket of popcorn
because I wasn't clicking on the bike
right like
as a casual Observer this is amazing
and I'm here for it right like oh looks
like the Department of Defense is in
here okay yeah like seriously they're
calling out the a more agencies are
going and you're like oh my God what are
you doing stop clicking on the link
right they were clicking on the link
just to see what all the fuss was about
right but they weren't managing their
attribution
right they weren't fired up a tour
browser they weren't using some type of
other service they weren't using
anything to try to manage their
attribution they were just going from
their normal work browser that comes
back to Department of Homeland Security
or Department of Justice or whatever it
is right so we want to be careful with
this that's why managing your
attribution can be very very important I
have seen some sites run by absolute
wackos I mean people that just tinfoil
had like crazy crazy
and there are certain sections of the
site where if you go there it claims
that hey we just logged your IP address
and we monitor that and it wasn't like
something that was built into WordPress
or a plug-in or something like that was
modified who knows if they actually do
or Not Right But like I said I've seen
some people that don't look like they
could tie their shoes that at least
claim that they do this so we want to be
careful it's not hard to do right it's
not hard to do
what are some of the kind of best values
in opsec if you have no budget
whatsoever it's Tor right it really
really is just fire up a tour browser is
tour perfect no it's slow as heck you
get to capture every three seconds and
captures are getting worse right spiral
galaxy the horse with the white hooves
like captures are getting ridiculous
nowadays they are what Tor does a good
job some of you may have heard a story
it was uh God it was just a couple years
ago there was an individual
like just an absolute scumbag of a human
being that I hesitate to even call a
human that was harassing young ladies
online on Facebook
and this went on for way way too long
law enforcement was working it Facebook
was working it but they didn't know
where the person was because the person
was using Tor to protect themselves they
were using Tails if you're familiar with
Tails where you can like boot up a
little USB with Tor on it so this went
on for over a year and this guy was
doing horrible things he was basically
convincing these girls that he had nude
pictures of them and unless they sent
him more nude pictures that he was going
to kill their family and things like
that and it would escalate from there
eventually Facebook got so fed up with
this what did they do they went to a
security team a security researcher and
they paid I want to say I forgot it was
like like low to mid five figures like
20 to 50 000 like that range for a
vulnerability in the video player
entails
that gave that vulnerability to law
enforcement that exploit law enforcement
crafted up a video had one of the
victims shoot it to him he played it
gave away his true IP address they went
and arrested him
Kudos right everyone is happy
that guy is off the streets everyone
but from an Optics perspective that was
a weird case
right because all of a sudden Facebook
which is already battling massive
privacy concerns which is hilarious
people getting like pissed off at
Facebook like did you pay for your
account like how do you think they make
money right but already a company that
you're just battling some of these
massive privacy concerns
and how they do that and how they get an
exploit and give it to federal law
enforcement to use it against one of
their users like like I said everyone's
happy is off the street but it was just
kind of a weird case from an Optics
perspective and so
people take that and they argue about
the morality of it and I'm like listen
I'm not the morality police I would be
the horrible morality please I would
tell you do you Chris as long as it's
not hurting anyone else you do whatever
the heck you want man I don't even care
you know what I got from that story
though
everyone was trying to catch this dude
for over a year but they couldn't
because of Thor
right when people think like Tor is
horribly fundamentally broken Tor has
issues right denial of service right now
on tour is out of control haven't seen
dread formed what two months now but
like nah it does a pretty good job it
really really does and I see so many
people oh it's broken like is it
I think so right I don't really think so
nothing's perfect but it's pretty darn
good and it's free if you have money
and want to use a VPN do it which one do
you want to use pay for it right that's
really the biggest advice I got you
start tracking down the financials of
free VPN providers it is insane a bunch
come out of China which is hilarious
because China doesn't even let their
people use vpns so think about that they
don't let their citizens use vpns but
they can start at VPN companies to sell
to other people right kind of makes you
wonder what they're doing with some of
that information uh decent percentage
come back to Pakistan which always kind
of floored me
but um they're just garbage too they
just really really are get your accounts
suspended
like very very quickly I remember one
time when I was in DC hearing a rash of
out of one part of the country all of a
sudden getting a ton of reports that
people's social media accounts were
getting suspended at an alarm and rate
right and their stock puppet accounts
just can suspended suspend to suspend
I'm like wow I have a buddy of mine down
there that kind of knows what he's doing
let me call up Jeremy so I call him up
and I'm like Jeremy like what's going on
he's like
there's this VPN that's both paid in
free but a free VPN called TunnelBear
anyone use TunnelBear I will give
TunnelBear credit right here right now
TunnelBear has the best graphics I have
ever seen in a VPN it really really does
right there's like this cartoon bear
that looks all fun and you're like
tunnel bear I want to come out of the
Ukraine it's like and it jumps in this
green tube like Super Mario Brothers and
the map moves to wherever it's coming
out of and then the bear emerges and
you're coming out of there and you're
like this is amazing I love tunnel bear
it's great but once again it's a free
VPN service you know what type of people
use a free VPN service
yeah it's like the Cantina from Star
Wars it is a wretched Hive of scum and
villain right and so all of a sudden
your Facebook profile has a shelf like a
shelf life of cottage cheese at room
temperature right don't be surprised so
pay for a VPN use one that has
commercials
some people use protons some people use
Nord grade I wouldn't try to talk anyone
out of that me personally I use one
called private internet access some of
y'all may use it too I like Pia there
are a lot of VPN providers that claim
they keep no logs right there was one
called hide my ass that claimed they
kept no logs they got drug into federal
court and ordered to produce logs
magically they had logs like seriously
they rolled over in like three seconds
right they folded up like a cheap lawn
chair you stole from the front of a
Kmart and it just instantly produced
logs
private internet access has been drug in
in order to produce logs several times
and they have always failed to do so
they haven't been jerk weasels about it
like they haven't flipped anyone off
they just show up we have no logs all
right we have no logs and there was
actually something about two months ago
where Nord kind of got beat up a little
bit for uh some privacy concerns and
then uh
and then like that same week like it had
already happened it wasn't like they
timed it but that same week Pia private
internet access they announced that they
had Deloitte come in and do an audit and
actually verify that no we audited them
and it looks like they keep no logs
that's important right
and it's not that I do like I try to
minimize the number of felonies I commit
on any given day
and I say minimize because I'm a realist
right let's be honest sometimes stuff
needs to get done
and so it's not even that I'm necessary
you're like dude this guy is Shady
he was not lying right it's not even
that I'm trying to avoid being arrested
or anything like that I just don't want
logs of what I do
right there was a I have terabytes of
breach data like for a lot of different
reasons there was a there was a VPN
provider that got popped last year
and all that information came out in a
breach right because they had had logs
and so now here was people who were
trusting this VPN provider to keep them
safe
and now like all their information is
right there their true IP address like
if they were using it on a mobile device
things like the IMEI and some of the
selectors off the phone all right there
right and so that's what I want like
data eventually has a way of finding its
way out there and so that's what I'm
trying to avoid that's why I want
someone that doesn't keep logs sir
it says they tried to not
yeah it's a great question so the
question is that he was the gentleman
was saying his VPN provider saying that
they try not to keep logs but sometimes
they have to because of the countries
that they're in and everyone for the
most part if they actually care abide by
those logs but there are some countries
where they actually do not have to right
what uh we saw a few years ago we saw
thank you we saw a few years ago we saw
Russia pass a law that all of a sudden
like monitoring kind of need to be in
place and instantly within like a week
several VPN providers private internet
access and I have no stock in them right
I'm just saying they were one of them
they pulled their pulled all their nodes
out of there because they weren't
willing to do that and so yeah that is
something to pay attention to right it
absolutely is
so like I said tour is free vpns aren't
that much I think I paid like 50 bucks
for mine for two or three years or
something like that virtual machines
right totally free VM workstation player
it's free get a new bun through ISO set
it up now you have a nice little sandbox
separate from what you do it just gives
you an extra kind of layer of security
right and so once again a VPN
a virtual machine are these things 100
foolproof no but think of how much
better off you are with not much money
and not much effort just by using things
like this right it's not Magic
when you go to set up an account
on sites like Facebook and Twitter you
need to give it a phone number right
this gets a lot of people years ago like
a decade ago
if you told me hey can you set up 20
Facebook accounts today no problem yeah
because there was all these like
completely free apps that I could use
like text plus Talkatone text now to get
these just just free BS VoIP numbers
confirm the text message they sent I now
have a Facebook number that doesn't work
anymore not even Google Voice works
anymore that was kind of one of the last
holdouts right you actually need a real
honest to God phone number now and once
again this is where so many people mess
up
because they're under the gun
they need to answer this question right
now
they don't have an account on this site
and they need to set one up I'll just
use my personal number
like whatever I'm not going to use my
real name I'm not going to use anything
else I'll use the email setup I'll just
use my personal number it's all fun and
games until the breach data comes out 18
months later
was that Bernard Berner Works some I
didn't have burner work the last time I
tried it on a Facebook but I have used
burner on a few other things Facebook to
their credit is really really good at
this stuff like they really are as far
as detecting BS phone numbers and things
like this if you want I've heard
burner's good yeah all of a sudden you
turn into Johnny tight lips yeah I heard
yeah yeah hey how's your mother who says
I have a mother yeah
yeah
if you need a prepaid number there are
some really really good options here in
the U.S we're very he was talking about
laws varying from country to country
with vpns you want to see laws very
wildly about prepaid phones this is
America
this is the land of freedom and I can go
down to the Circle K right after this
talk slap down forty dollars of cash and
leave with a prepaid phone like God and
mother nature intended all right
I can do the same thing in the UK I can
do the same thing in like Amsterdam
right you go over to Germany not so much
right they want to see some ID they want
to start seeing some things like that so
here in the US we're fortunate it's
actually very very easy to do these
things a couple of my favorite options
number one is the one on the right mint
mobile right the cell phone service more
people know about it now because Ryan
Reynolds right has all the commercials
or whatever fifteen dollars a month for
mint Mobile SIM card that sounds
extremely reasonable but their whole
shtick is like listen we don't want to
send you a phone you probably have a
phone so just we'll send you a SIM card
you can use our service well how do I
know if you have good reception at my
house don't even worry about that listen
I don't want you to waste fifteen
dollars of your hard-earned money and
then be disappointed so here's what
we're going to do we have these SIM
cards that are only 99 Cents and they're
good for a week
foreign
that doesn't sound like the shadiest
thing you've ever heard of in your life
right
they're usually five dollars but they're
like always on sale for 99 cents and
what's funny is it's limit one
at a time
so if you look there on my Amazon I
purchased those eight times
that's not counting all the ones I paid
for at cash at Target and Best Buy like
any other self-respecting drug dealer
right
and so this will give you a disposable
phone number that's good for a week set
up your accounts and everything's good
for a buck it's amazing right if you
need a phone or if you actually want to
keep this number for a while because you
actually want these profiles to live off
and not lose them potentially look at
that on eBay TracFone straight from
TracFone himself not even like Bob's
totally trustworthy phones or anything
69 for an Android phone and a Year's
worth of service
and all you need is the text messages
right all you need is a text message
just to come on in all right so we have
options here in the US where it's very
very easy to do this style of work
if you try to give Facebook
or more and more social media sites now
a picture from you know this person does
not exist they're getting really good at
detecting that was AI generated right
the process that they do is called a gan
right generative adversarial Network
generative because they uh because they
actually make something adversarial
because it's basically two computer
programs pitted against each other
right and then you know comes out with
this fake face but there's certain
Telltale right the most famous one being
the eyes the eyes are always in the same
spot on all these pictures and so like I
said these now are going to get flagged
out as that's not your real face I'm
going to suspend your account well there
are face swap apps out there there are
face swap sites where you can take a
real picture like that handsome
Gentleman on the left hand of the right
side mix it in with any other picture in
this case I even mixed in with a gan
still looks largely like me
but it's different enough now but since
the base
wasn't generated by like I have you know
this person does not exist something
like that you see the eyes are offset
and still has the characteristics of a
real person like all of these things out
there like we can detect fake faces no
you can't
they detected the image was generated
using that Gan methodology
and so if you start off with a real base
and then just kind of morph something
into it you can end up with a very real
looking picture that still isn't going
to get flagged right totally free
totally free
all right last things we'll talk about
right here and then we'll end up
persistent monitoring right something
very very important brand reputation
executive protection potential Insider
threats either uh intentional or
otherwise plenty of stories in that one
right there initial access for sale
right more and more now you're seeing
data Steeler logs become a thing right
and these places are getting hacked
because someone just bought a cookie or
someone bought some creds from some of
the data Steeler logs right and you're
just basically buying initial access
right there those marketplaces are out
there and they're kind of crazy and so
monitoring
right seeing Haze or anything out here
that could be me or my organization is
very very useful it's extremely
important and it doesn't have to be
expensive right Google Alerts are free
and you can have like a thousand of them
now it's amazing right I remember one
time I had a student who uh
they were with a Big Ten research
University and they came up like hey I
want to pick your brain on something
like yeah they're like I'm really
concerned with intellectual property
theft and I'm like like your students
pirating stuff he's like no I don't care
about that he's like I care about we
have these research Labs with some very
very viable research and I'm concerned
about people leaking them out and that's
a big thing right research linking out
to foreign countries Etc that was
something that I had to deal with in the
government
and he's like I just have a very very
small team and I don't really feel like
I can do anything I don't know what to
do and I'm like shoot start off with
some Google Alerts where I go talk to
some people there at the labs that have
some key terms think of some good
criteria you can get very very specific
with Google searches right with Google
Dorking and actually set up some Google
Alerts it's totally free right so that's
one way Twitter API Keys they're free
and they're amazing all right you can do
some amazing things I gave a talk at the
essence Summit two years ago about
basically a Twitter bot kind of
monitoring 24 7. it wasn't just looking
for keywords it actually had some logic
I kind of joked when I did that that if
I was trying to like sell the product I
would claim it was artificial
intelligence and machine learning it's
actually just a bunch of lists right but
just going through with like kind of a
good logical process and alerting on
things that actually matter you can do
this for free with a little bit of
effort and that talk and code is all
still out there there are commercial
options like Flashpoint if you have a
budget that are amazing but some people
don't
but one of the best kept secrets and my
wife actually turned me onto how amazing
these were about a month ago something I
was aware of but she was like whoa yeah
I know you're aware of it but check this
out
these Google programmable search engines
right and what these are is they're
basically designed for imagine if you
come up with some really really good
Google query and it's like yeah this
query you're going to search doc Spin
and you're going to search you know
paste bin and these four different other
sites with these keywords and so now all
I have to do I can leave that query
exactly the same and all I have to do is
put in whatever name I'm looking for
right what these personal search engines
do is basically let you take that query
and kind of freeze it say hey I would
like to save this query off and so now
the next time I need to do it I don't
have to retype that entire query I can
just click on this link and all that
other criteria is built in and now I
just put in the name and it's also
designed and then you can share it with
your friends share it with your
co-workers hey I've got this really
great query that searches for this here
you go and I can share it and that's
great and I was aware of that
functionality and it's like yeah it's
moderately interesting but if you look
at this I don't know the font's a little
small there
you can search for specific sites or
Pages great that's kind of how it's
designed or you can search the entire
web
down at the bottom what is the point of
searching the entire web like like not
just use Google thing right instead of
these programmable search engines
the reason why is this
you can actually API this up
you can set up a search for the entire
web
add on whatever criteria you want or
leave it as empty and wide open as you
want and look at that 10 000 queries per
day
nice Json results you can script this so
you can have keywords criteria whatever
it is you want and automatic alert
emails when you see it and you can start
adding in more logic potentially than
you could on like a Google alerts or
start cataloging things there is a ton
of potential here right like you see
search engine optimization like the SEO
tools like charging a ton of money just
trying to like catalog Google search
results and certain things like that you
can do it for free right here using
these programmable search engines
here's a little bit of python code
to kind of go through
a list of Search terms and give you
results from these and you're like
that's great but I can't code
you know what
I was interviewing someone last week
they said they had done a little bit of
pen testing and I said okay you've done
a little bit of pen testing I'm like
assuming you know your Python's okay you
know what they said no but I have chat
GPT I swear to God not even making that
up not even making that up no but I have
chat GPD I'm like respect right it's all
fun and games though until chat GPT goes
down because you don't have that paid
membership right that code yeah I did
not write that code
give me some python code to use Google
programmable search in this API to
search for term and report results here
we go tested it works like a chap
works like an absolute champ and now you
can just start adding things yeah if you
haven't played with chat GPT to write
your code yeah like it's kind of amazing
it really really kind of is right so
yeah programmable search engines like I
said if you're interested at all in
scripting that type of stuff check them
out they're kind of like a little cheat
code and I am now officially out of time
thank you very much for coming if you
have any questions I'm six foot four I'm
tough to miss find me thank you all
appreciate it
[Applause]
what's up
[Music]
foreign
thank you
[Music]
foreign
thank you
[Music]
foreign
all right
[Music]
foreign
they're doing
I appreciate somebody's words
the problem is I want to walk I walk
yeah because I tend to want
off stage right are you attractive
yeah we're on track two tomorrow I think
track one and part three has mics that
you can walk around with this one not as
much
I do like that they blocked my view of
my my slides because I tend to point at
them and help anyone
um
my clicker will like allow me to like
come in on stuff but it'd be good
just waiting for a cue here because
we're a few minutes over it
well
yeah a sand destruction
you know
foreign
to talk fast
I've got a ton of slides too so I'm
already worried about times we'll see
you just laugh and roll yeah
let me go
it's a nice thing about like not having
a script is like you can speed up and
cut out the portions and you build
everything and literally you just have
to like talk faster
no
I I did check in back there
can you just give me a thumbs up and get
started I made a fancy introduction
I'll just stand up here until I see a
thumbs up
no we got
we have Cozy Bear turbine panda
imagine
yeah
I've got a little Cozy Bear that I can
go to my desk
I've seen the big ones
insane I don't know how much those costs
a little bit no it wouldn't fit right
yeah
I barely got this new oh you got a strap
into the power plant like a like a
shuttle right that's how you have to get
it home
good morning Cactus cons
um today you have Ryan Thompson talk
about a peek inside an adversary toolkit
please welcome him to the stage
[Applause]
all right so I speak a lot of people in
the back of the room we've got some
seats up front I know that's always an
awkward call to action but uh we're
gonna be sharing some screenshots here
that
um I would love to make larger uh but
there's only so much room on the slide
and so if you are interested in being
able to read that the back of the room
is probably not the best place for that
so just want to get that out of the way
thank you all for coming to my talk
um I want to talk a little bit about who
I am who I am right why am I up here why
am I talking to you guys uh well I'm a
security researcher crowdstrike and uh
in the past I've done some threat
hunting I've done some instruction uh
I've also dabbled a little bit with some
Cloud uh Cloud infrastructure security
and so what you'll notice up here is
there's not a ton of red teaming so if
we go back one slide we're taking a peek
inside the adversary toolkit we're not
going to rummage around we're not going
to get super super deep and so if you
are a red team and you think man I'm
going to learn a new tactic probably not
the right talk so let's get that out of
the way real quick but what I do want to
showcase is from a blue side we don't
get to look at how the adversaries are
leveraging their tools so that's the
focus of this talk
so with that said we're going to take a
look at the context for the the data and
the tools we're going to be using today
we're going to dive through four tools
those tools are going to be any desk
engrock sliver C2 and fscan and we'll
wrap it up with a quick summary
so work for crowdstrike right I support
the OverWatch team which is our threat
hunting service and so there's Telemetry
that's generated from endpoints the
process is much more complicated than
this but our Hunters are looking at that
data and most importantly they're
notifying the client this happens pretty
quickly as quickly as we can
and there's the the data that comes out
the other side are very much ioc focused
and hey we found these things here's the
the call to action for the client
so you can imagine that those
notifications you couldn't very much
query and pull stats and metrics out of
and so that's where my team comes in we
get handed the intrusions after the
hunters find them and we do a
post-mortem analysis on those we
normalize that data and we're able to
pull stats and Trends and so get a
little image up there of the threat
Hunter report my team is responsible for
for generating that and kind of pulling
those stats together
so when I when I tell people that I look
at all the intrusions that are happening
from e-crime and targeted a nation state
they say great I want to know the top
tools what what are the adversars using
and I hate to break it to you it's not
very exciting when we look at the top
Tools in 2020 it's Mimi cats it's Cobalt
strike PS exec right proctom and so from
year to year surprise surprise it
doesn't change all that much
and so everyone immediately wants to
know I need to know that you're the top
five the top ten that's going to make a
great BuzzFeed list right and inherently
it's just not very interesting and so
this year we decided to do something a
little bit different
and we broke up our tools into three
classifications Mainstay which is
historically what would be a top five or
top ten list those have been around for
a while and are used very heavily
we have trending they're not new to the
environment but we're seeing usage uh
increase right and the last one is
emerging this isn't to say that the tool
is brand new but it's the first time
we're seeing it in our data sets
So speaking of that
let's provide some some caveats I'm
going to go back one slide real quick so
this gentleman can get a picture I got
you
uh I'm also going to post these slides
on LinkedIn so
all right a little bit of context about
what we're talking talking about today
the first thing the the first Keyhole or
aperture that we're looking through
these are based on OverWatch intrusion
so obviously it's only customers of
OverWatch uh only ones that are being
caught by our threat hunters and it may
be not caught necessarily by the product
or the automated detections and then
even more specific we're looking at
Hands-On intrusions so if there's
automated malware that's being dropped
that's not really an interest for our
team we're looking for interactive
sessions
so
the next caveat we cannot get
screenshots from our clients and if we
could I wouldn't be sharing them with
you
all the things up here are from a lab
and so I just want to get that out of
the way we're not sharing anything we're
not leaking anything I wish we had the
capability to get this level of access
from a screenshot perspective we don't
final piece we are focused on adversary
intent and so we see a lot of these
tools ran we see them attempted to be
used for certain things sometimes
they're blocked by Windows Defender
sometimes they're blocked by Falcon
we're not interested in that that's very
very complicated when we start talking
about the different protection policies
that are in place for some of these
sensors and some of these products I'm
focused on what is the adversary
intending to do with this tool so with
that said
here are the four tools again any desk
and grok sliver and afscan and so let's
go ahead and hop into it
any desk for anyone who's used it any
desk is just a remote access tool right
the idea is that you have a host maybe
at home maybe a desktop and you want to
access that on the go you've installed
an agent there you install an agent on
your laptop essentially it's it's a
really really easy RDP it can Traverse
over over the network you can password
protect it and that's kind of the
functionality of this tool there are
plenty of Alternatives out there but any
desk is the one that we see most
prevalently in our data set
so it's a Mainstay tool what can they do
with it well we see attackers using it
for persistence as well as exfiltration
and the benefits of it is it's not some
script that somebody ran or created and
it's on GitHub and you just download it
and it's not signed right it's an
official tool it's officially supported
and so it's likely going to bypass a lot
of AV
so that's why we see people using it
installation is super easy you don't
need to take these down it's in their
documentation but it's super easy
um they're able to run it from a command
line go ahead and use a dash install
start with windows so install it as a
service
update disabled so they're not getting
pestered about updates and then do it
silently right so pretty straightforward
nothing crazy there and then once you
get it installed in order to access it
remotely from another machine for for
that other machine to initiate you have
to set a password and so these are the
two major commands we see ran from there
unfortunately we don't have a lot of
visibility into what they're using the
tool for so I installed it and we're
like we're going to take a look at
what's possible within a desk
so real quick we have two different
hosts here and I've tried a designate
those best I can in the blue outline you
have the victim host in the red outline
you have the attacker host once again
slides have very limited space so I'm
trying to do the best I can with the
space I have
first of all once you get it set up and
you launch any desk and connect to a
host there will be a notification for
the victim there's gonna be something
that will flash on this screen briefly
and there will be a notification icon
now I'm hoping everyone in this in this
room would notice that jump on it and go
investigate it
some end users may not and so once you
get that access then you have a full GUI
and you have full interactive access to
that system depending on how it's
configured so no surprises so far
next up once you have established that
you've set the password and you can
access it you can actually go into a
file browser so no more interacting with
the GUI you have direct access to the
file system of your machine and their
machine side by side you have the upload
capability to say I'm going to select
this file on my my host and send it to
the victim host or you have the ability
to say hey that that file right there
that I found I want to go and grab that
so you can see that happening here on
the right hand side the attacker is
navigating to a Secrets folder
navigating to the desktop on their
folder or on their machine and clicking
download
and we can see that file has been
brought over inconveniently put in the
bottom right but it's been brought over
and now we have access to that and so
that's a way yes there is a blinking
notification there's no interactions
Windows Explorer isn't opening at all
and they have full access just kind of
browse through that
the other thing that I noticed is that
there's a sync clipboard capability so
on my host or my attacker machine you'll
notice that my clipboard is filled with
nonsense text
but once I connected this victim host I
can actually go through there and say by
the way I would like to go synchronize
our clipboards so at this point I'm
still really not touching that other
machine sure the notification is there
but now we just kind of play the waiting
game we can watch that that user we can
see what they're doing let's say I don't
know maybe they want to log into a bank
they can open up that and let's say
they're practicing really good hygiene
maybe they're using one pass so they
grab it
put it into the browser and go and
authenticate well because we're
synchronizing clipboards that is now on
the clipboard of the attacker machine
and so I would love to say that I have
absolute proof that this is being used
um we don't all the any desk commands
and and all the communications are
encrypted so all we know is it's being
installed and I know this is a
capability
now this is a highly intensive probably
super targeted approach right you have
to wait until a user puts something on
their clipboard unlikely but not
impossible
so the problem with using uh legitimate
tools something like any desk is that it
Crea it creates an uninstall option so
we see that here it's listed in the apps
and we have the ability to uninstall it
that's pretty typical we've all seen
this and interacted with it what you may
not know is all that's tucked away
inside of the registry so I went in and
I changed uh display version to hackers
and instead of showing uh I don't know
what the version was before I think it's
ad717 I can change that to hackers or
whatever value I really want another
interesting piece that I learned in
digging through the registry is that
there's an uninstalled string so when
you click that uninstall button this is
what this is the command that's ran it's
that can be changed to anything
but most importantly from evasion
perspective what do we want uh to do as
an attacker we want to hide that
entirely so we can either clear all the
values out of this registry key or
we can simply go in and remove a display
name so that's the command that's being
ran along the top I'm only going to
Target one value and I'm going to clear
it out
and so when we run this
and update everything it's going to take
a few seconds here for me to refresh the
screens what you'll find is the display
name on the right hand side is going to
disappear when I update my registry View
we noticed it's gone now it goes display
icon to display version and then when I
refresh it over here
any desk no longer populates this is a
Technique we see happening happening
often and so once again the idea here is
that we're just trying to hide the fact
that it exists for later use
so what do we do about this
um I put application white listing up
here knowing that's very much like a
draw the rest of the owl type
recommendation it's it's very difficult
to to implement but that that is
absolutely an option
we can block certain ports
um now keep in mind that the only
downside to this is that if this is used
for localhost Discovery so if you were
to install any desk on one machine on
your local network and install it on
another they're going to try to
communicate over these you know 50 000
level ports and so you can block that
local Discovery I think the best way to
do is to Black Hole a.net dot any desk
because even if it's installed
that service cannot connect to the nades
network and therefore attackers get
so up next is ungrock this one was kind
of interesting to me this is a I don't
know I I think more of a fun thing to
look at from
um how easy it is and how much of an
impact it has so what is it
in Greg is reverse proxy
um kind of offers itself as a tunneling
service there are tons of Alternatives
out there and what's Wild is how easy it
is to use
so when we look at I think one of my
favorite things I just went and browse
their website
this is what uh
oops there we go this is what their
their website looks like
it's in it this is the marketing it's
like oh we're going to enable SSH access
with one command we're gonna put
localhost on the internet we're gonna
connect to networks without pain which
hopefully for everyone in this room
sounds like a nightmare
from a different perspective though this
is exactly what developers want to do in
a lot of cases just to to get something
up and running and to test it to make
sure that it's a viable product and so
that's how they're they're positioning
this I took a lot of these I said you
know I could probably make a vendor ad
pretty easily by just changing the
background and moving those same lines
over
and that's exactly right it's a
different perspective
um the one thing I will say about ngrok
adversaries don't put the proper
Protections in place but ngark allows
you to so if you wanted to use enggar
legitimately you can do SSO you can do
saml you can do MFA and so those
capabilities exist
I have a series obvious that aren't
doing that so let's let's take a look at
how it works
we we've seen this for a while but it's
starting to see more use really these
adversaries whether they're nation state
whether they're e-crime they've got run
books and over time they learn about new
tools and they add them to the
repertoire and so this is absolutely one
of those that we're seeing starting to
Trend upwards we're seeing it used for
command and control and then x-fill so
I'll show both examples of those and
once again the benefits for the
adversary are absolutely the same as any
desk it's a legitimate application
so I want to break down how it works I
didn't want to put in a whole lot of
theory slides but I think it's important
to know what's happening here so an
adversary usually can't reach out to a
specific host because well there may be
a firewall in place blocking that
connection that host may actually not
have a public IP maybe it's netted and
so there's no way for them to directly
access that host for the most part
and so how engrock works is once you
install that or once you move that
binary over and you run it
that host reaches out to DNS uh
communicates with the engrock service
and opens up a tunnel over Port 443 now
from a blue side what we're looking at
is just an outbound outbound
Communication number 443 nothing nothing
crazy there very difficult to block and
that communication is held open
now the adversary has a ngrok domain
that they can access they access the
Android service and it pushes it through
that tunnel and so you never see an
incoming connection so to speak so
that's what makes this really dangerous
so this is literally the command you run
you run ngrok TCP 22
it's going to reach out to engrock give
you a domain and the domain in this case
is right here this four tcpng.io and
then overport uh what is that 11 200.
and that's all you need to access at
that point from anywhere so on my phone
I could go and say great I want to I
don't have an SSH client but if I did I
could access that from anywhere in the
world
here's what it looks like you see me
trying to SSH to my local host and it's
been shut down by the host firewall
but if I want to go and access that same
host through ngrok I can put in the
ngrok domain specify the port and enter
the password and all of a sudden I've
connected and so it bypasses a lot of
the traditional controls especially from
a perimeter perspective
another thing it can do so actually let
me back up for a second this here allows
you to host any port not just SSH and so
how it can be used is you could stand up
you know a python file server and tunnel
to that Port right and that that exposes
your files it's a little bit you know a
little bit extra work an extra step
and grock actually allows you to do that
with a single command as well you run
ngrok HTTP and point to the directory
that you want to point to
it says great I've given you a new
domain and I'll give you access to the
files in that that particular directory
so here it is in action they can
literally just drop it into a browser
and navigate right to your directory
and so pretty powerful for xfill um
once again not impossible to stop but
just another Avenue that we actively see
Avatar is using
so if I want to recommend anything once
again we're going to Black Hole domain
that's my favorite way to stop a lot of
these legitimate Services because they
have domains that don't change very
often and so if you block that all of a
sudden you see this this application
struggling to reach out it can't reach
its uh certification revocation list it
can't access the tunnel domain because I
block those and so it just shuts that
down so you can download engrock all you
want but once you launch it you're not
getting out now
once again maybe you can specify a
different uh a different DNS server
depending on how a network is configured
maybe you reach out to 8.8.8 and you get
around that
all right sliver
I want to fully get ahead of this bishop
Fox is here as a sponsor and they are
definitely more of an expert in this
tool than I am I think one of the people
who actually wrote slivers here and so
hit them up if you have any further
questions beyond what I'm I'm going to
show you here
so what is sliver it's a C2 framework
it's built once again by Bishop Fox and
the intention is not necessarily for it
to be an adversary tool it's meant to do
red team engagements and as we know if
we build really good teams for our blue
slash red team adversaries are going to
pick those up and start leveraging them
the Alternatives here are your
traditional Cobalt strike or Metasploit
or Covenant
um now the big Advantage here for sliver
is that it's free it's open source
with that we do see it as a trending
tool it's not entirely new but we do see
adversaries starting to pick that up
more and more they're using it for
command and control and exfiltration
just like the last tool but also there's
some pretty nifty defensive Asian tricks
in there so not only is it free but
every time you generate an implant it
dynamically creates that to where it
doesn't have the same hash every time
and you'll have to manually go keep
evading things one interesting thing to
note here is that I downloaded it with
Microsoft Edge and Microsoft Edge says
hey I can't tell you this binary is bad
but it's pretty rare we've never seen
this executable downloaded before which
I think is a cool functionality that
browsers are starting to implement so
even if they don't have a true match on
the md5 and it being a known bad bad
file it'll let you know hey this is rare
and quite frankly Microsoft Edge sees
enough traffic to where they can make
that determination
gaining popularity
I I was just trying to get to sliver's
webpage and I just kept getting
bombarded with all these articles it's
like hey adversaries are using this over
Cobalt strike so very clearly
crowdstrike isn't the only one seeing
that shift
so I had to stand up a little bit of
infrastructure to get this to work I
thought about just skipping over this
but once again if you're a blue teamer
that doesn't have a whole lot of red
team experience I mean like me quite
frankly it's important to know what the
adversary has to do to get these things
to work
so first up um I could have done this
locally the way they're leveraging it is
going to be through the open internet
through uh usually a fresh domain uh and
so that's where I started started with
Google domains
I I bought a domain and then I spun up
an AWS ec2 instance trying to keep my
costs pretty low and once you have those
two you can set the domain or the DNS
records for that new domain to redirect
to that AWS environment and so once
again this is not my strength this is
not my background took me half a morning
to get all this stood up and so as you
operationalize this this could
absolutely be automated you start
putting in randomly generated domains
it's very low lift for adversaries to
stand up this basic infrastructure
so what does that mean for everything
important things to note here
if you go to this tiny fragment of
wood.com it will redirect you to my IP
address of my ec2 instance now what's
what's crucial about this is because I
registered it through Google
and I haven't really changed any of the
defaults with the authoritative answer
for that DNS query is this nscloud Dash
D1 Google domain so basically what that
means is the source of Truth for where
that domain should be redirected it
lives with Google
and so if I send a DNS request it's just
going to go to the Google uh
infrastructure so as an attacker that's
not very helpful for me now sure I could
adjust this to send it somewhere else
and that's exactly what I did in the
second one I created a subdomain called
really tiny fragment of wood
created some some DNS records and so now
the source of truth lies directly at
that ec2 instance and so now when anyone
on the internet makes a query for you
know this new domain or the subdomain
that DNS request is going to be sent and
directed to that ec2 instance so not
only am I sending traffic we're just
talking DNS record or DNS queries are
now heading that way too
so we got our infrastructure in place
let's go and install it once again I
keep coming back to this these tools are
incredibly easy to use and that's why we
see adversaries leveraging them so in
this case it's the one-liner for for a
Linux installation we're literally just
curling it passing over to bash and it's
doing all the work for you I think maybe
I had to type in a y for yes at some
point that was a super super easy
the next thing is great the DNS Network
the the the hive mind knows to send it
to this IP address but it doesn't do any
good if that host isn't listening for
DNS traffic or if it's not expecting to
process DNS queries so the first thing I
did was open up a security group within
AWS to allow Port 53 to through and then
the other thing is I boot up sliver and
I said great I need to start a DNS
listener once again a one-liner I said
DNS Dash domains and I put the domain in
so now all of a sudden that service is
actively listening the security group is
allowing that traffic through and we're
ready to ready ready to go
generating an implant that's the next
step of a C2 infrastructure that's great
you have everything listening you're
waiting who's going to reach out well
that's where your implants come in so
once again it's a one-liner we're going
to generate a beacon we'll go into the
options here in a second but in this
case I'm focused on DNS uh DNS implants
I put the uh the domain that I've
redirected and I've determined where
it's going to be saved and you can even
specify uh operating system here so here
are some of the options DNS HTTP mtls
and wireguard are all options for
protocols I stuck with DNS for this one
because that's where I'm most
comfortable at
and then from an operating system
perspective it's literally just a dash
OS and you can specify for whatever you
want and it'll dynamically generated for
any of those systems
the important thing to note here and
probably the most important flag is your
implant type and so this made some this
may be something that's not immediately
evident to people that haven't used this
before there's two different types
there's session and there's Beacon
and maybe you can see I don't need you
to read anything on this slide but maybe
you can see that the Wireshark on the
left hand side for session is going nuts
and basically it's sending out a ton of
DNS requests their text records going
out and they're hitting the attacker
infrastructure and so that's super noisy
and should be really really evident to
anyone that's even keeping a remote eye
on that
on the right hand side there's a beacon
implant and that's more of the the
method you use to stay kind of low and
silent and so it's setting it out I
think it's got some Jitter in there so
that means it's very there's a variation
for how often it reaches out but you're
seeing that once a minute or once every
two minutes and so of course looking at
this you're like well I want a beacon
implant I don't I don't want to be
making all this noise but from the
attacker's perspective there's an
advantage to how often the session
implant talks to that server
so when we start to run commands you'll
notice the one on the left comes back
immediately I'm running PWD I'm running
who am I I think I run one more maybe
yeah if config and it's coming back
immediately
on the right hand side I run PWD and it
says great I I just asked that Beacon
and so it has to wait for that Beacon to
reach out to respond that has some
implications for how you leverage it it
also limits you a session implant can be
used to actually stand up a true shell
inside that host whereas a beacon
implant doesn't allow you to actually
stand up a shell at all so
once you establish that session there's
a ton of different commands here and the
takeaway for for everyone in the room
here you see some commands you probably
recognize there's cat there's ifconfig
there's kill there's LS right and it may
be one of those things where you
immediately assume oh great I'm just
going to run LS on this host and that's
not exactly what's happening what's
happening is you're sending that to your
implant your implant is using system
calls to return that information
and so it's not going to show up in your
command history it's not going to show
up through any of those traditional
mechanisms the other advantage of this
is thank God I can finally run LS
against a Windows host right like
holy hell it makes it so much easier as
a single command and so if you were to
open a shell then you're interacting
directly with with that that endpoint
but here it's kind of abstract and it's
all running from the the audio running
implant
so here it is in action you'll see the
once we we actually execute that implant
on the host we get a callback and it
says Hey modern Army just checked in
and we can use the use command to go
select that that implant and we start
running those commands one thing that I
particularly liked about sliver is that
it goes through and it assigns a code
name for every implant and that's really
handy because I've used some in the past
that just give it a one through six or
whatever a number that's hard to keep
track of so what sliver does is it
assigns that an adjective and a noun and
so in this case it's modern Army I think
another one a while back was
cultural Coast
um boiling comment right and that makes
it much more identifiable those names
are changeable
um
but moving on
the final piece I'm going to talk about
is opening a shell and so you can run
the shell command that says hey this is
bad obstacle are you sure you want to do
this like are you an adult which I I
love the snark
and so you can run that
and the thing that I noticed is it opens
up a new process right
from a Defender perspective this is
really easy to spot because now you see
Powershell being executed from the
parent process of in this case it's
culturalcoast.exe super super visible
it's going to get you caught
so let's talk about that for a second
what happens when you get caught uh
sliver has an amazing functionality that
allows you to generate a DNS a DNS
Canary and so how this works is when
you're generating your implant up top
you can use the tag Canary and specify
another domain
so when these are generated there are
very few strings that are visible that
can tie tie that implant back to your
infrastructure it's all obfuscated but
when you use Canary it says cool I'm
just going to drop this domain
as a raw string the thought there is
that once a Defender finds out they're
going to say why I need to I need to
dive into this they're going to run
strings it's going to print out a bunch
of nonsense and they're going to find a
domain I say got them
they're going to go resolve that domain
and as soon as that resolution comes
through
our canaries go from yeah it's never
been triggered to oh by the way this
particular this particular implant
queried this or I'm sorry this
particular implant may have been found
this this DNS domain was uh
was queried and we see it triggered and
we even see when it triggered we don't
see the host or the IP address with DNS
queries depending on how it's configured
that wouldn't necessarily always take
you back to the in the end host that
actually triggered it but we know an
implant
um was discovered and there's some
investigation done so I thought that was
a really cool functionality
so keep in mind this recommendation is
for the specific path I used I'm sure
that that there's there's people who
know slivered that are squirmy in their
chairs waiting to ask me questions after
this but what about this how could I
hide this
um from the perspective of how I used it
there was a tremendous amount of text
records being used
and so those typically we don't see a
lot of especially if you're using a
session implant you're going to see an
absolute ton so it should Spike up
pretty quickly
so last but not least Afghan it didn't
have an icon I figured that's as good as
anything else
um
yeah right that's how that's how
official icons are born
um this one is just a network scanner
and I say that I don't mean to be
dismissive of it but it doesn't bring
anything that new to this ecosystem
there you could use nmap you could use
Advanced ip scanner Port Authority all
these are great Alternatives it is
pretty quick it's written in go and it
was released in the last couple of years
it's just on somebody's GitHub right put
a nice little Panda icon up there we see
a lot of Chinese actors using this and
so I was I was really excited I started
looking at the documentation right and
and man there's all kinds of stuff that
this this tool can do and I was like
great let's see how the users the advers
are using it this is the first tool
um in in a lot of cases that we get to
see what the adversary is doing because
it's you download it to the victim host
and you run commands so I was like
awesome they're probably like doing some
really advanced stuff
and they're really not I was kind of let
down actually they're just using F scan
to scan the environment they're not even
using the vulnerability scanners
um they're just looking for their next
hops they're looking for open ports and
so I almost excluded this from my talk
altogether but I I think there's an
important thing to note here and this is
something we see across all of our
intrusions
adversaries still have to do Discovery
once they gain access to an environment
nation state as well I know we put them
up on a you know this this Ivory Tower
that they're mystical creatures that are
able to do things through the wires um
but this next level of Discovery is
needed and we're seeing Chinese actors
use this tool just to say hey what ports
are open what hosts are there and so
whether that is as host Discovery or
network discovery or domain Discovery
it's a crucial part of that um I think I
have to pay money if I say kill chain
but it's part of the process right
so how do we how do we find this luckily
Network scans are incredibly noisy
you're going to see one host reaching
out to a bunch of other hosts over a
bunch of ports and so not too difficult
to spot
so to close it out we looked at four
tools any desk was a remote access tool
my favorite way to kind of block that
from your environment is to to block any
domain any DNS request going out to
net.nas.com keep in mind there are tons
of competitors out there against any
desk and so you block this one you
probably need to go look up the other
domains as well and garlic is reverse
proxy slash tunneling tool once again we
can black hole that at the edge of our
Network and we can stop a lot of those
engrock agents being able to actually
reach back out to the service
for sliver at least in the way that I
used it with the DNS tunnel blocking
text records stops a lot of that
activity or at least monitoring for it
maybe not blocking a bit monitoring for
it and then fscan of course you're just
monitoring Network traffic so with that
said
um does anybody have any questions
all right go ahead
you can actually use
it
forced them what what what's kind of
like the least one you've seen or the
best way to kind of put that oh thank
you oh that's awesome you have a
question box
does that have a mic in it yeah do you
want to repeat the question because I
was about to but I'll let you do it so
you can get it right yeah of course so
um I know a lot of clients use any desks
themselves for remote access into their
systems um is there either
any good
um uh either alternatives for any desks
that adversaries don't use as often but
it doesn't cost as much as you know a
lot of clients don't have that money for
remote accessories they're kind of like
a specific method to you know blog
adversaries with any desk but not the
current clients I'd assume like doing
that you know an IP
specific but obviously a lot of clients
that use any desks don't have technical
knowledge to do that well and the
problem of blocking it at the IP level
is the the host isn't reaching out to
adversary controlled space right they're
reaching out to the any desk service and
so my recommendation works great if
you're not using any desk but it works
terribly if you do now the issue with
saying well they use any desk I'm going
to use something else
odds are from an adversary I'm going to
log on I'm going to see if there's any
remote access tooling and I'm probably
going to leverage that because I know
it's not blocked it's really tough tough
if if a company uses that I would have
to look further into like maybe there's
there's opportunities to authenticate
differently maybe like a two-factor
authentication within any desk or
something like that maybe you can push
that out to a third party like OCTA
would probably be a better approach than
trying to like shift services to dodge
what adversaries are using because
they'll just follow you there especially
if it's easy to use
so that's not a great answer it's not
satisfactory but I think it's an honest
one so
all right so yeah we got some some uh
some possible opportunities in the crowd
all right we've got another question
here
the flavor client is running on
the victim books right so uh sorry could
you uh this is really weird for anyone
on the stream there's this weird box
could you hold the Box closer to your
face
like this yeah that's perfect there we
go okay so the sliver uh client is
running on the victim
so it should be visible on that one that
perspective and network communications
yeah so so it is running on the victim
box and depending on how tight you have
your processes tuned down
um maybe you're looking at certain API
calls being ran maybe you could detect
that but most of the time most AVS at
least are trying to block it at md5
level to stop it from even getting on
the box but you're correct it is it is
running on the victim host
um and in theory you could go to your
processes and actually find it I did
some procmon and absolutely found them
it's just it's a different name it's a
different md5 and so it's harder to look
for a specific implant if you don't know
what you're looking for is the issue and
so that's why I tend to lean on there's
going to be network communications
coming out of that host that's probably
how you find it and then you work
backwards
good thank you yeah absolutely
that's the throwable Box this is great
uh you mentioned as a possible
mitigation for ngrok to Black Hole the
domain
and figure and grog with your domain of
your choice that just sort of set its
own
that's a great question
um a Darwin answer for you I don't want
to say yes or no but uh engrock's got a
lot of capabilities
um let me look into it and we can talk
offline
yeah because that would absolutely
shatter that right it does require a
bigger investment from an adversary to
go by the domain to stand everything up
um and then they you have to register an
account with ngrok to do any of those
more advanced features so there is a
more inherent cost but a dedicated
adversary is going to do all that stuff
so it's a really good call
and just to give you some feedback from
how we see it in our environments or I
guess our clients environments it's
normally just ran with ngrok without
specifying a different type of domain
and so capability wise possibly but we
don't see at least from our narrow
window of the world we don't see it
happening like that yeah good good
question though
got a question behind you there
hi
um I was curious uh what signals that
Falcon picks up that indicates it's
sliver or is that just figured out
afterward after like sort of finding the
Badness yeah it's usually found after
the fact because it is new md5 keep in
mind we have the Falcon side of the
house that's the sensor doing its
detections that's a totally different
world than the thread hunting side and
so we're not necessarily looking for
those signatures we're looking for
surrounding behaviors so maybe they
installed a service maybe they created
into account maybe they ran a certain
command from a weird parent process
right we hone in on that and then kind
of build out and that's usually where we
come across sliver
so yeah it's a great question though
all right any other questions
all right I'm going to go ahead and jump
off stage here if you have any questions
feel free to come up and talk to me over
here
um thank you all so much for attending
my talk
[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
foreign foreign
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
foreign foreign
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you foreign
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign foreign
[Music]
foreign
thank you
[Music]
foreign
thank you
[Music]
foreign
thank you
[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
I'll just speak really loud oh it's
working now hi
uh good afternoon everyone
um we are still waiting for the speaker
uh for this talk but just to make sure
track two
shoden Olson automation to mass
exploitation of vulnerabilities
um we'll keep you guys posted where your
speaker is we're still hunting them down
I don't know where he went
does anyone have
any
the community
changes
is
yeah
foreign
of course
hello I am not the speaker you're
looking for
they're not here uh so we're working on
getting another talk over here right now
you can stand by if you want to for that
or you can head to one of the other
awesome things going on at cactuscon
sorry about that The Showdown talk will
not be going on
foreign
anyway
s
foreign
experience
inside
showed him
thank you
foreign
so terrific
this is
thank you
foreign
[Music]
importantly yes
foreign
deliver s
I think there was something on
about technical yeah
foreign
here
excuse me
no
probably
have a
chance
it's driven
but there's things that I do
firmware
yeah
it's usually
high in terms
yeah
so I'm like great
[Music]
he wanted
it's like BGA right yeah
oh yeah
well no it is
but taking
the process yeah
come here
what do you mean you don't care yeah
later
stickers and
um
no
we don't get the camera
really well
it takes one person
foreign
go buy another
one
we
have a good time
foreign
it's like
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign foreign
[Music]
foreign
okay
interesting
look at
the right traveling in a hurdle yeah
yeah that's right
so yeah
um
elevated
I thought that's a huge
thing
thank you
please
oh
speakers
so anything
right yeah yeah and so that was the only
way
because
foreign
I thought
all right up next we have Casey Beaumont
talking about documenting incident
response thanks for coming
[Applause]
alrighty hey guys like was mentioned
just make sure you're in the right talk
we're talking about the single source of
Truth and documenting and leading
incident response so it's a topic we
don't often really think about too much
we think about IR is how are we going to
solve the mystery but there's more that
goes into it than that right we need to
have deliverables at the end we need to
have someone kind of leading the way
so we're going to go over a lot of
things in this presentation starting
with pre-planning around roles and
responsibilities and having an incident
response plan in place so that all of
this isn't just knowledge in the head of
someone on your IR team but formally
documented because if you think about
your own companies and everything
everyone knows on your teams how much of
that is written down so if they left
tomorrow with no notice how many people
could pick up the slack
then we will assume you're in the midst
of an incident and discuss what needs to
be documented and how and the best ways
to keep these deliverables neat and
helpful will tackle both created
documents for using the investigation
incident artifacts themselves and after
action
so a little bit about me and why I'm
talking about this I've been coming to
cactuscon off and on since it was hosted
out of Dave and Buster's which had
definitely a certain charm to it
my background originally was in computer
systems engineering so I very briefly
was a developer I took one class in
Security in college because you know in
2010 there wasn't much to go from and
luckily fell into security and I've been
happy ever since I'm currently an
incident response manager at Marsh
McLennan a Global Financial Services
firm
but I started out in defense I started
out as a defense contractor and that was
kind of a great way to learn IR because
they typically have the budget the
policy which is extremely important the
seriousness around security uh and the
training to really get you started from
nothing
I've been doing direct incident response
for over 10 years and I'm a sucker for
process and documentation so I very
naturally started scribing these things
I very naturally started being the one
to be taking notes on what was going on
and kind of fell into being an incident
response lead and manager for the team
so first we're going to talk roles
responsibilities and realities
and let me give the context too that I
work at a Fortune 500 we have Staffing
we have documentation we're not perfect
but our level of sophistication is
generally higher if this is not you
customized to your needs if I'm going to
go over something and you're like
there's no way we can't do like we're
nowhere near this level of documentation
that's cool
if you Google incident response plans
for instance you'll see a lot of
examples are a single document I'm going
to describe something more than that but
start where you can
so why do you need an incident response
to lead or a scribe and I want to
preface this by I gave a similar talk to
this purely on incident response plans
at a conference back in October and it
was a conference for Rural Broadband
Telecom an industry I wasn't intimately
familiar with
before my talk there was a tabletop
exercise that everyone kind of did
together it was a smaller conference
like 150 people
and I participated and as I sat with
those folks it was revealed to me that
most of the companies represented were
across the board understaffed wearing
multiple hats and not at the level of
sophistication that you kind of get used
to in a larger company or if you've only
worked at large firms so when faced with
a question like how does your
vulnerability management handle new
major threats like solarwinds a couple
of them said we don't we don't have time
for that we're just that goes right past
us because we can't do that
so if your I.T team is your security
team and that's two people in your whole
organization you got to start small but
you have to think and Define who steps
into these roles ahead of time because
if you only have a limited security team
and nobody is taking notes and nobody is
keeping track in an incident and this is
something major
you're going to have a bad time
so know in advance even if you don't
have the luxury of a dedicated role
who's going to be doing these things
so why is this important and what do
these roles give us and let's talk big
picture here and this could be a little
unique to a larger organization but you
might have a cyber incident response
team as well as a general incident
response team at your organization so
the Cyber incident response team is kind
of what we're talking about here which
is like the separate call where it's all
the technical folks working the
investigation and the IR lead is on that
call
kind of facilitating leading but then
feeding updates through their leadership
and translating the technical updates
into digestible content for the business
then your leadership or you however your
organization does it maybe your CSO
takes that to the general incident
response team and I'll talk a little bit
about that later which handles the
business level handling of legal privacy
continuity client relationships briefing
the sea level things like that making
decisions with the data you're giving
them
so first be prepared with an incident
response plan everything is so much
easier if you have a plan before
this is not a good incident response
plan if your incident response plan is
update your resume you're doing it wrong
don't rely on winging it we all have to
start from somewhere right you know
we've all been at companies or incidents
where you're kind of largely winging it
and each one gets a little bit better
but incidents can be emotional things
and having a plan provides a guide rail
to hold on to when things get rough
and you might say well can't our third
party IR firm that we're going to engage
our retainer in do this for us and yes
they can you know they can kind of
perform that IR lead role for you
they're going to be documenting it for
you but wouldn't you like to be able to
focus them where you want them to be
focused and use them to both confirm
your own work and instantly increase
your 24x7 Staffing in a perfect world
you want to engage that IR firm and say
we just need bodies you know we've got
talented people but we've only got three
of them or five of them or something
like that we just want more folks that
we can direct at the knowledge and get
the right answer faster
so what is an incident response plan an
instant response plan is your place to
detail your approach to incident
response so that your organization is
prepared in advance right so you're
going to talk about the big picture
activities that are required and what
you hold yourself to as a company you're
going to talk about the step-by-step
flow of processing an incident not the
step-by-step of exactly how you do every
little thing to solve the mystery but
how does an event turn into an incident
how does it get to certain teams
who is involved in incident response and
who are the decision makers and then
contact information to engage teams
communication requirements and
deliverables so this is really important
because you don't want to be arguing
over whose role and responsibility is
what during the incident you don't want
to have a power struggle between teams
and I.T during an incident
now coming back to the general incident
response plans you know we're talking
about cyber incidents specifically but
your org may also you know have a
general incident response plan to cover
things that are outside of security
right so you might have an outage in an
application but it's not a security
issue it just it went down it's
affecting people the general incident
response plan is engaged to solve that
however these incident response plans
are linked developed together and major
incident response often involves both
particularly when it comes to data so
defining an I.T security incident is
purely let's say a server has malware
running on it but that's it you contain
it it's fine
end of story that's purely an I.T
security incident a purely data incident
is a colleague emailed the wrong
client's data to another client whoops
they're going to contact privacy they're
going to handle that as a general
incident
the second you have a server was
compromised and data was exfiltrated and
now it's online that's a hybrid incident
and all hands are on Deck because you
need those other teams to help you out
early triage in all of these you know if
something comes in through the service
desk they might have a triage that kind
of figures out what kind of incident is
this who are we sending it to
it might be part of your plans too to
say like okay if it's an I.T security
incident at what point are you engaging
the other team and vice versa to make
sure they're engaged at the right time
so talking about how we can break an
incident response plan into digestible
pieces this is one way of doing it so
that you can have pieces of it that are
shareable pieces of it that are not if
we break it into you know policy process
playbooks and procedures it makes it a
little bit easier
and so depending on the size of when and
what you already have you could have an
incident response plan that all is one
document but doing it this way really
helps out
policy addresses purpose scope roles
responsibility management commitment
coordination among organizational
entities and compliance but don't
reinvent the wheel you don't have to
write a policy from scratch pick a
guideline like nist and base your policy
around it say we can we can
realistically hold ourselves to the
standard and you copy and paste out of
nist
a process will facilitate the
implementation of the policy and
Associated controls so it's more like
the flow of events and all steps taken
in a typical response what teams are
doing what and that flow maybe with like
a flow chart is not saying like in the
weeds first we're going to look at this
log then we're going to look at this log
it's here's how our events come in
here's how the sock gets them here's how
they triage it it might break off and be
handled by other predefined procedures
but then here's how it gets into
incident response and what teams are
involved
then playbooks this is where it starts
getting into more of a luxury so
playbooks are something that your IR
team might generate from scenarios that
haven't happened yet but you want to be
prepared for so whatever's keeping you
up at night if you're thinking we've
never had an incident in a cloud and I
don't really know how we'd handle it if
an oracle Cloud instance has a problem
so you're going to write a playbook for
that you're going to investigate it
you're going to find the teams that
would be involved and you write it out
as a Playbook
an early one that's an easy win because
it kind of covers a lot of incident
response is ransomware so our first
Playbook was ransomware because you know
most things can lead to ransomware you
know and so you'd write the whole
Playbook of you know what what do you do
and what's different about ransomware
that you might want to pre-define in
advance like what's your policy on
things
that's shareable to the different teams
that might be involved so if you're
calling out a team in the Playbook
saying this team's going to do this for
us make sure they've seen your playbook
and have agreed to do these things
and then your playbook might link to
procedures so in ransomware
you might be like well if it came in
through email let me link to procedures
on how to do something very specific so
I want a procedure on here's all the
methods we use to analyze URLs in email
here's all the methods we use to analyze
an attachment anytime that you've got a
repeatable process that someone knows
how to do technically make it a
procedure put it somewhere because you
know that when major incidents happen
that's when your best guy on the team is
on vacation for two weeks or on medical
leave because you just had a baby or is
super sick or whatever maybe they've
just left the company and taken all
their knowledge with them
if you have a new hire you want to be
able to point them to oh yeah you don't
know how to pull that log here's how
it's written down here's what access you
need and here's how to do it in a
consistent way
it's also important to think about where
the stuff gets stored before it happens
you know for audit purposes for metrics
purposes you hopefully have some sort of
ticketing system either homegrown you've
bought a solution but you need to
consider what's the access control to
that ticketing system can anyone in your
company go in there and search their own
name and see if they've ever been
involved in an incident or an internal
investigation that's not great so for
most stuff it's going to be in your
ticketing system but what about major
incidents that are a little bit scarier
you're going to want some restricted
access and you can do this in any way
you want if you have a ticketing system
that has like a special module for only
security where it's private awesome if
you don't you could have a general
ticket with a link in it to a restricted
you access SharePoint and say okay well
all the documentation's over here what I
can control who can see it
if it's really bad or if it's a very
sensitive incident where you're like
even new hires in security I don't know
if they should be able to see it it's
need to know only only the people who
were there should be able to see it
encrypt it further
and then it's important to talk to your
legal team about retention periods
planning for legal holds and
standardized naming conventions so you
can keep track of all of this
so I could Deep dive very heavily into
incident response plans the components
of each so if that interests you reach
out to me later and I've got a whole
presentation on that with kind of more
in depth into each section
however for this we're focused on what
we want to accomplish specifically as an
IR lead and or scribe in documenting a
major cyber incident so what are our
goals
so first and foremost we want to get
through the incident life cycle right we
want to survive this incident your job
is to help the teams quickly and
efficiently move through analysis
containment eradication without having
to manage on their own the documentation
side of things in IR is directly
involved in a lot of these things you
know the preparation is kind of what
we've covered before detection is
something along with your sock you know
finding out some things happening in the
first place and then you're going to be
going through the rest of the steps a
lot but it's important to consider where
does your job end as an incident
responder you know you can't hand hold
the whole way there's going to be a
point where you have to release this to
the business and say okay we've
completed the investigation the problem
is gone persistence is gone we want you
to rebuild these systems we have these
recommendations you can't directly do
that yourself but you have to identify
where your role ends in being on daily
calls and you know you need to be able
to trust the business to recover back to
a typical state
and a big part of incident response as a
leader is getting the right parties
notified immediately your process may
help Define who notifies who so maybe
you'll say you know you don't want
anyone just randomly going and notifying
the sea level there should be the proper
flow of information but it's important
to be timely both for regulatory reasons
and so that a business CSO isn't the
last one to hear about an incident
affecting their organization
so I put a bunch of teams on here it
really depends on the situation but as
an IR lead part of your role is getting
the right person on the phone if there's
something that needs to be done that you
can't do directly so often the hardest
part is figuring out who from the
business side owns a thing so you've got
an application it's been defaced it's
down something's clearly wrong but
you're like I don't know in this major
company what business unit owns this I
don't know what team owns this I don't
need to you know I need to find out how
and you might be lucky you might have a
group that through that General incident
response plan is dedicated to figuring
that out they might be able to get the
phone you know on the phone whoever you
need
but if you don't have that resource you
need to have a plan for figuring out
okay do I have contacts for messaging do
I have contacts for the business uh who
do I talk to when inevitably it's three
in the morning and you need to get
someone up and it's your job to call
those people in the night and say you
know you're in charge of this team
you're going to be helping otherwise
you're gonna have a problem
so what do we want to accomplish with
our records of the incident so we want
to be able to tell the story and answer
questions later I don't know about you
but I'm kind of a goldfish and if
someone asks me about an incident that
happened last week I'm like which one I
don't know you know there's it's hard to
keep in your head the facts straight of
something that happened and you'll find
that people come to you asking questions
nine months later two years later you
want to be able to have all of it
written down
you want a detailed searchable artifact
and host list so you can cross-reference
future incidents or confirm actions
taken so someone might say hey this you
know this is a year later hey this
username is kind of familiar in this
ticket were they involved in that
previous incident you can go check
someone might come to you and say hey
just sanity checking did that host get
re-imaged what did we do with that you
better have the answer you can't just
leave these things unfinished
and then legal retention considerations
this could come back as a court case you
don't know until you've been through the
whole thing how bad it's going to get
so accurate objective documentation is
essential for your legal team so that
you can just hand them all this and be
like that's we've got it all we've got
all the data that feeds into it here's
the story and they can speak from that
so legal considerations are especially
important the second this becomes a data
incident right because now you have to
consider regulatory issues it really
depends on your industry and this is not
your area of expertise this is legal's
area so let them make the decisions
about what's going to happen and who's
going to be notified
because you might not know you might not
be thinking about everything so Loop
them in the second it's appropriate to
there's also issues sometimes with
country if you've got a global
organization depending on where the
assets are sitting depending on Whose
data is at risk there could be other
reporting requirements or maybe you have
a special customer or client where
you've signed something you've agreed to
some different uh reporting requirements
saying okay well I'll call your sock
within 24 hours if a certain kind of
incident happens
for the parties managing the incident
for your own IR team you might face
legal holds where you're told do not
destroy logs don't destroy information
or Stop Trade orders where if it's bad
enough your legal team might say
you know you're going to be issued a
Stop Trade order so that you can't dump
your stock before this hits the news
right
so now to talk about how things play out
when you get paged for something funky
happening off hours it has to be off
hours or Friday at 4 pm because it has
to that's just the rule of ir
and how does it play out so typically
this clip of the Matrix just shows Neo
dodging bullets but I expanded it a
little bit to include the part where he
gets clipped because after all you might
get lucky sometimes you might be super
prepared as an organization and you skip
a lot of major issues or some of the big
vulnerabilities in the news maybe you
handle it perfectly and not a single
host had a compromise from some big
thing in the news but if some it's going
to happen if it hasn't happened to you
it did you just missed it so does your
incident response plan does all the
pre-work you did give you the Bare Bones
you need to get the right people on the
phone and the ability to investigate
properly
with the right preparation and
experienced team your goal is to feel so
on top of it that you're engaging a
third party IR but you're not just
relying on them to do all the work
you're using them as equal teammates
you're using them to check your own work
you're providing them information just
like they provide you information and
then they're the nice objective third
party
are we good nope
they're the objective third party that
is comforting to your sea level
to say okay our internal team is not the
only one saying that we handled it
appropriately but you know your third
party firm is validating what you've
done
so what does the incident response lead
do and I keep mentioning an incident
response lead and a scribe if you are
super luxurious you might have the
luxury of two dedicated bodies for this
I do both I'm the lead but you know you
end up being the Scribe too but the
primary responsibilities are incident
stand up so creating dedicated resources
so you've planned all this out in
advance how you're going to do this you
know what tools are you going to use are
you going to have like a private teams
Channel where it's access controlled
where are you telling people to dump
logs where are you you know what is your
plan for out-of-band communications
where are you doing through
documentation
initial notifications an IR lead is the
person who needs to be getting the right
teams involved notifying the right
people and sending out that first status
message to maybe your CSO saying here's
what we know here's the background
here's what we've done and here's what
we're going to do
there's also the delegation of tasks and
decision making
so you delegate some tasks if you need
to most of us know with an IR team if
you find something cool if someone says
I found something I found a web shell I
found something to Pivot on the natural
inclination is to squirrel it's too big
I found it I'm going I'm going to look
at this new lead and I'm going to leave
that old system behind you need to make
sure that you're completing an
investigation on a system controlling
who's going off on the new shiny lead
and making sure sure things are moving
appropriately
another important thing to consider is
you need to delegate who has the
authority to make an uncomfortable call
so okay you've got an infection on a
production server that's running an
application that generates revenue for
the business
whose can make the call and whether or
not you contain that system and stop the
business if you've got a VIP with a
compromised account
you know who can make the call on
deactivating his accounts and who's
going to take the political Fallout if
that's a bad decision or someone gets
upset about it
and then reporting status translating
developments into digestible status for
management so this could be hourly if
it's really early an incident it could
be once a day it could be once a week as
things are winding down it's whatever
makes sense for your organization but in
a perfect situation when you've
established this trust with your
management they're not going to be
micromanaging the situation if they
trust you've got it under control
so here's rules of communication and
what is your problem and what is not
your problem
so your problem is the team
communication because everything you say
could be used in court one day so you
want to make sure that anything you say
with your team is recorded you know if
you're using teams or slack or whatever
create a separate place for that
communication and give people ground
rules make sure there's some level of
professionalism try to discourage people
saying we are so screwed we need to
update our resumes because if that's
read out in court it doesn't look great
and then talk about out-of-band
communication
so maybe your typical communication is
there's an outage it's gone whatever the
attacker did you can't get to it or you
don't trust it you think an attacker
might have visibility into it you need
to have planned in advance how you could
talk to your team in a worst case
situation and talk to Legal about this
because they are going to have opinions
and they're not going to be a fan of
this but you need to pick the least of
the evils right so if you're using
signal with your group no disappearing
messages
because as a lawyer told me if there's
like nine hours of Disappearing messages
an opposing lawyer can infer anything
they want about what was in that content
what is it not your problem is public
statements client communication or
internal notifications that's why you
engage the business that's why you
engage Communications they are the ones
who control that you want to keep this
held close you don't let people go
talking to the public or whoever
Staffing this is a tough one it usually
kind of comes up when you're already
deep into the night on the first day of
an incident is understand your team size
and how you'd staff a major extended
incident like I'm going to be doing this
for a whole couple weeks you know we got
to talk about how we're going to staff
it and what your expectations are can
you do 24x7 work on your own are you
going to engage a third party and hand
it off completely
or if you have let's say like my team we
have four dedicated incident responders
but we have a lot of talent in all of
our teams we have managers who used to
be ir and who want to help if
something's really happening people
aren't going to say well no I'm on a
different team I don't you know it's not
my problem a lot of people in your sock
might say I want to be fully involved a
lot of people in all your teams you know
your CTI folks are going to be like well
we're helping directly anyone who can
you can start fitting into the Staffing
rotation
so we consider plan shifts and downtime
and agree with your team what makes
sense because the hard part is kicking
people off you know when something's
happening adrenaline's up your IR team
does not want to go to bed they want to
stay and keep working but it's been 14
hours and somebody needs to take a nap
so plan shifts and pair people up and
say okay we're all going to work in the
business day we're all going to work
till like six or seven but then two
people are going to stay on the bridge
and two people are going to go to sleep
and we're being strict about that and
then we'll pick it up we'll switch it 2
A.M or something
and figure it out so that you've got
bodies doing something but then people
are getting rest as well
and figure out who's managing the
business as usual right because stuff is
still happening but someone's got to be
working tickets someone's got to be
answering emails and kind of figure out
how that balance works
a nice thing you can do is reward or
make easier these long hours if you're
fortunate maybe you can get a slush fund
where you can help doordash for these
people or do it out of your own money if
you're you know you've got a close-knit
team you don't have that luxury can you
reward at the end can you give people
additional time off can you do a
challenge coin at the end and say hey we
all survived this horrible incident
let's you know have this coin to attach
all our PTSD to
so now we've reached deliverables and
what are we generating right
right so the Scribe or the IR lead
whoever is doing this gets to work and
this is what's being generated from the
moment you realize something major is
happening
so you've got an overview document and
that's the catch-all that is like a one
long word document where you're putting
everything all your notes from calls in
chronological order statuses copies of
Correspondence a list of Who's involved
because that could be more relevant if
it gets more serious and anytime anyone
says you know what this wouldn't have
happened if we had done this in the
organization if this architecture was
changed if we fixed this or hey I
noticed this host doesn't have GPO
enforced properly so the logs are all
messed up note that down because you can
Circle back to it in your after action
a tracking spreadsheet is where you list
the specifics of what you're finding and
what about it is important so that you
don't lose track so that can be systems
accounts iocs requests uh you know
evidence tracking things like that
you want to make sure you're capturing
timestamps for a timeline generating the
actual timeline might come at the end
but you want those time stamps in UTC uh
you know as you go along and it's
extremely important to be translating
the time zones because I work at a
global company it never happens you know
your whole team is working in different
places the way they view tools might
display the data in different time zones
and the systems where this is happening
are in different parts of the world
potentially you need to standardize that
when you put it in a timeline it makes
sense
and then you need to consider file
storage you need to make sure that if
you come back to this log file it's not
log.csv and you're like oh shoot I don't
know what Host this is I don't know what
time frame this is you need to make sure
they're named appropriately
I'm breaking everything okay
so the overview document can be huge if
the incident is Major I speak of doing
this all in a Word document maybe you're
lucky and you have like a ticketing
system where you can like put all this
in there magically but you know going
more into the weeds of what you can put
in there you want to talk about the
background so what was the original
source of this incident what did you
know and at the end when you've kind of
figured it all out right like an
overview right the story of the
beginning the middle the end and
everything so that when you come back to
it to learn from to show this to
somebody else you've got the full story
and then copies of all the
correspondence anything notes from calls
it's all important
any ticket numbers that are related if
you Outsource work to other groups or
you have tickets tracking this incident
jot those down and then anything the
timestamp developments because you're
going to be feeding those into a
timeline
you also want to keep track of who's
doing what and what the due dates on
that kind of stuff is and then one nice
thing to have in there is URLs for
Relevant references or articles if it
hits the media you want to keep track of
that and then if you're a cyber threat
intelligence team is finding cool
information saying what we're seeing or
what's happening in our environment is
lining up with this vulnerability it's
lining up with this thread actor or this
method of doing things capture those
links as references
appendices can include output from IR
firms so if they generate a timeline
stick it in there to compare to yours a
list of red and individuals copies of
attacker correspondence God forbid and
contact information
for the spreadsheet so typically I've
rolled my own you know in the moment you
just create a spreadsheet but you might
miss something in terms of what types of
data you're tracking that going back
later you're like oh shoot and I have to
go figure out what domain all these
hosts are in I found in some Googling
crowdstrike has an awesome example one
that's free you don't have to put your
information into their website to get it
I've got a copy on my GitHub I'll
provide to you but they've got tabs for
all these different kinds of things and
importantly they've got columns with all
the different types of information you
might want to track
so this can get pretty specific but it's
useful because you're going to get
questions later about all of this I
guarantee it you want to really keep
track of okay we have all these hosts
identified we haven't proved that all of
them are directly involved yet because
maybe sometimes you have a lead but it
doesn't really pan out but what did you
do with it which ones have you contained
which ones had web shells on them or
which ones had evidence that something
actually happened or where a lateral
movement happened you've got a time
stamp put all that in there so you can
piece it all together later and then
during recovery you can break it down
into okay well we know these ones were
actually involved these ones were
decommissioning these ones were
rebuilding and you can kind of keep
track
same with accounts keep track of what
accounts were involved and what you did
with those accounts were they service
accounts you got rid of at the end were
they you know were changes made to them
were they deactivated make sure you keep
track
indicators of compromise uh you might
want to share them someday if you have
permission to so having a lot of
information not only led to your own
teams sweep your environment for these
indicators compromise but you might want
to share them later and you know you
want to have the information to give out
and then task tracking you can choose to
do this in a spreadsheet or however you
want but if you've got some action item
for a team you can track it here
for timeline creation this could be
something you Circle back to later when
you have the luxury of time you can use
any tool you like to do this this little
screenshot is from a tool called
timeline maker Pro that we impulse bot
in the middle of an incident because it
is cheap I think it's under 200 for a
lifetime license and it was just
something you can plug stuff into and
break it into categories and get a bunch
of different visual ways of showing it
so here we've got things on artifact
information like when did a certain
artifacts show up threat information so
if you figure out okay well this the
root cause here was a cve you can put
something on there and say this
vulnerability was reported on this date
we didn't patch it in time but here's
how much lead time was between it being
released publicly and when something
happened
things the attacker did things that your
team did and then actions taken on the
host so keeping track of what your
actions were in the timeline of the
actual attack
and then you need to be organized
because this stuff piles up right so
like I mentioned you know you need to
put a date on there you need to make
sure that there's the data type where it
came from and a Time range so if you're
pulling email records from someone put
the date you're pulling it that it's
email what the user account is and how
big of a range it is because it could
end up being hundreds of log files and
you want to make sure they're organized
so that if you need to pull them you
know if legal needs them later you're
not searching through your email saying
okay well when did someone send me this
and what is it and can I figure out the
context from email
so after action so we did it we kept our
jobs uh you know no one's fired but you
know you want to move on but you need to
go through an after Action Report you
need to learn something from this right
and all the documentation you've been
doing really helps put all that together
you can write in like maybe a PowerPoint
or a Word document however you want to
do this a background actions taken
importantly what was successful and then
what did you drop the ball on both on
your own team and then within the whole
business you know we're teams giving you
trouble did your own process fail you
and what can be improved and that's
where you create draft recommendations
to the business that you can float up to
other teams one way of doing this is
doing an after action kind of small
doing it with your own incident Response
Team anyone who is involved in security
and doing it there but you could also do
an after action involving other teams in
the business and what their view was of
how it was successful or not successful
then you need to document those changes
and you can't just make a list of
recommendations and just shove them off
to someone and say it'll be done it's
not our problem anymore because if those
go off and die in someone's inbox and if
something happens with a breach and you
had recommended something that could
have prevented the next one and someone
in legal finds out that you had
recommended these things and nobody
followed through it can be kind of a
problem so make sure if you're
recommending action that you get
agreement from the party who's going to
do it and a timeline in which they can
do it and who has accountability for
that change
the easy stuff to do though is process
improvements you've got control over
that so figure out where did your own
incident response plan let you down is
it inaccurate like do you have this nice
little flow chart of how IR works and
none of that happens in real life fix it
right if you have contact information
that's super out of date or it
references tools that don't exist take
the time and fix it
and then emergency and versus proactive
changes in an incident you're going to
be doing stuff in real time you're going
to be like screw the process I'm not
doing a 10-day lead time on this change
make it happen but you need to make sure
those things you know
you close that Gap
then we archive and move on so having an
incident response plan in place and to
find leadership and documentation should
have gotten you some wins and kept more
people happy about your response so
faster time to inform better analysis
and response people just feeling like
there's better relationships between the
different teams in I.T and the
businesses and that nobody was panicking
and upset because we talked about the
life cycle of an incident there's also
the life cycle of grief and we all know
that when something is going real
sideways at your company there's going
to be a lot of emotions flying between
denial you know denial anger you know
being upset finally accepting you know
that kind of defeatist attitude you got
to make sure that having these guide
rails in place and having leadership
guiding can keep people in a healthier
mind space
but you got to move on right because the
worst fear is you're in the middle of
major IR you think what if we bump into
a separate problem what if something
else gets reported at the same time you
know you want to make sure you're always
ready that when it rains it pours you
could have one right after or at the
same time but then at the end you can
archive all this you've done it it's not
going to be like an action item where
you're like oh shoot I have to go back
and finalize all this stuff or try to
remember what happened two weeks after
it did you've been able to be successful
so I know this was a lot of content I
have a GitHub lifted list here where
I've stripped down some example policy
process and Playbook documents policy is
easier if a lot of it's pulled from nist
there's a lot more to look at there
playbooks might just kind of have more
like headers of sections because I can't
talk about what we do specific to our
organization but I did put a copy of
that crowdstrike tracking spreadsheet so
you don't even have to Google it you can
just go grab it
and if anyone wants these slides I'll go
post them there too as well so if your
organization does this differently or
better come find me after I'd love to
talk I'd love to improve a lot of this
kind of was homegrown but if anyone has
any questions comments you know we can
talk
and that's it
[Applause]
anybody got anything
otherwise just find me after
yes
not quite I mean typically where it
leaves me in particular is I explain to
our CSO you know this is what's going on
this is what's handled and not handled
and maybe he'll determine who needs to
be told at that point how nervous are we
about this at this point so but I
wouldn't say that's pre-scripted at all
because every situation is different
anything else
all right thank you Casey Beaumont
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign
thank you
[Music]
foreign
thank you
[Music]
foreign
thank you
[Music]
foreign
thank you
[Music]
foreign
thank you
[Music]
foreign
thank you
[Music]
foreign
hey everybody Welcome to the talk uh if
you're here for decompiler Tom Fuller
you're in the right room if you're in
here for another talk you're still in
the right room it's a great talk stick
around
so I I thought I'd start this off by uh
talking about some alternative titles I
had for this talk uh a song of dragons
and elves anybody
uh debugger Wars episode three Revenge
of the dwarf
hmm
so I I've recently been told by my
professors that I really need to take
down the text in my slides so I've had
this revolutionary revolutionary new
idea to talk to other gen zeers like
myself this is the title
yeah
I can't even I can't even read that
title so I've also shortened the title
That's How we'll refer to the talk from
now on fish bridge Dragon that's it
so I I'm Zion
um my hacker name is mahalos I'm a
native Hawaiian hacker I'm from Hawaii
that also means no pineapple pizza
uh don't bring in near me I'm the
co-captain of shellfish we're a hacking
team we compete at Defcon finals every
year since 2003 we're really into the
hacking scene I love helping with ctfs
and stuff like that if you know poem
college is I'm one of the authors of
phone college so I'm all over the place
I'm a PhD student here at ASU I study
decompilers how we can make them better
how we can improve structuring so that's
kind of what I do I'm all around in that
stuff and I've also been the ASU hacking
Club president they're a great Club here
so all these symbols kind of represent
things I'm associated with so if you see
these symbols and you happen to have a
pineapple pizza go the other way
so an outline of this talk we have five
major components of the talk we're going
to be talking about reversing embedded
devices then reversing the things on the
embedded devices that make them tick
which is the binaries then we're talking
about previous approaches of course by
the old sages
solving previous problems problems with
those previous approaches and then the
big headliner decomp debug which tries
to solve all of these previous problems
we represent decompilation with this
little dragon guy debugging with the
fish and the Gap with a scrunched face
of pain
so let's talk about reversing embedded
devices a lot of the talks here at uh
Cactus con have been about embedded
devices and how we integrate them in our
lives how we pen test them things like
that so one major component of reversing
embedded devices is the actual Services
which run those by you know the the
embedded device which is usually
binaries uh binaries compiled programs
that you know are not interpreted so
we're not talking about python or
JavaScript we're talking about rust C go
things you compile
so that means you have no source code
and what I have here is a nice embedded
device a Netgear router it's of the
Nighthawk variant they don't want you to
have the source code
for obvious reasons it would be good if
we could have it because then we could
validate the claims they make but we
don't
um these binaries you have no Source you
likely have no symbols either they take
away the symbols because it makes it
smaller they also don't want you to have
an easier time and local execution is
actually rather frustrating if you've
ever tried to reverse an embedded device
before you realize often these binaries
are connected to the physical stuff on
the hardware so like imagine you have a
binary which does hurts manipulation for
these specific uh antennas if you run
that binary on your own you know VM even
if you have the right architecture it
likely won't run at all because it
doesn't have the right connections it
doesn't have the right Services talking
to it it doesn't even know what Hardware
to touch so it's not really an option A
lot of the time and it's a huge space of
work
so in this talk we focus on one of these
major categories which is that binaries
have zero symbols essentially they're
really hard to understand and these
other two are assisted by this first one
so let's talk about reversing binaries
reversing binaries is a rather hard
thing for a lot of people including
myself I'm a Noob that's why I work on
decompilation because I can't read
assembly it's terrible I only can read
decompilation and emojis those are the
only two things I understand
so you have this binary right you can
take two approaches dynamically which
means you run through it concretely with
one state in your mind as you Traverse
the binary this is you creating a model
of the binary as you walk through it one
at a time with like GDB or something
the other way is statically and this is
usually with a decompiler and this gives
you a general abstract model this allows
you to understand all paths for the
program it's like reading source code
when you read the source code you are
creating a model of every path that goes
through it so you iterate this process
until you have some fundamental
understanding you go between debugging
go between decompiler you get this great
understanding of what the binary does
awesome
so what does this actually look like in
practice so this is this is ghidra a big
old panel full of a lot of things I'm
not going to explain the things it's a
lot we don't even want to look at it
really but there is one some one thing
really important in here and it's the
decompilation the decompilation is our
approximation of the source given only
the binary
take a closer look so this is what it
looks like it's rather ugly right now
fun zero zero four seven whatever right
that's
that's uh very descriptive we don't
really know what it means what does this
function do what do any of the variables
mean what are the types everything's
undefined nothing makes any sense this
looks nothing like my C code
right luckily guidra allows us to
redefine it we can work on it ourselves
and we can Define the symbols and the
types and you know whatever else we want
this is called generating reverse
engineering artifacts or we call them
Reas
so what has changed exactly the name of
the function is changed we have symbols
so has the variables and so have the
types so what we have done in our mental
model of this program is we've raised it
to a new symbolic level this is main
this is the entry point is authenticated
is a state we also have types like car
or Char you know the argument so these
are the things we have right
so let's move over to the dynamic side
now that was the static side this is the
dynamic side this is GDB this is what
GDB looks like without any other
extensions on top of it so looking at
this you know there's some assembly
we're breaking at four zero zero seven
One D that's the same address as main so
we're breaking at some address and we're
getting some assembly
all right a little hard to comprehend
after just seeing this great source but
we see it now there's ways to extend
this you can actually extend it with a
plugin called Jeff which is just about
extending what you can see now you know
from a distance this kind of just looks
like an eyesore but I promise you it's
actually useful in practice this gives
us more information it kind of prints
out everything that we would see in the
current state of the debugger but one
fundamental problem we still don't have
any of the information from our
decompiler nothing has made it here we
still are just seeing assembly we're
seeing addresses none of our symbolic
information
and here lies the Gap right the first
thing that's problematic we've created
symbolic locations in our mental model
of this program
40071d is mapped to main we think of
this as main when we try to break here
we're trying to break at a symbolic
location
that's the same for these types and
their variables right we are thinking
about a higher level standard already we
have converted this assembly into C in
our minds but yet we still have to deal
with assembly in our debugger which
sucks again decompilation or emojis
so where is my source that is the main
question here and that is the
fundamental motivation of this talk how
can we get source and how can we get our
debugger to be more like our decompiler
where can we merge the two and close
this Gap
so some previous approaches have tried
to make this a little bit easier
I think of two major previous approaches
there are some other ones the first one
is retsync here's their GitHub rhet sync
is about synchronizing your actual view
from the decompiler to your debugger so
you know say I'm at 40071d and I'm at
Main it will just make sure that
whatever you're looking at in either or
are synced up so you know if you change
your address it changes it in the
decompiler
so that's nice because at least you have
synchronized views but you still don't
have any of the symbolic information
inside of your debugger you can't break
it main you can break it the address
representative of Maine
the second one is probably the closest
approach that has to try to get here
which is called dwarf export dwarf is a
debugging format for GDB or sorry for
for elves that GDB can understand so
what this project tried to do was take
all the information inside of Ida
another decompiler export it to a dwarf
once and then import it into the
debugger so this is actually really
really close because you have Source
lines you have types you also have
variable names now the big problem with
this is when you update anything in any
of your decompilers this dwarf is now
not correct you have a model mismatch
right you've changed something in this
the compiler doesn't update in the
debugger it's a mismatch second this
only works for Ida and this only works
for Linux you can't use it on anything
else because it is specific to dwarfs
and third this can take a long time
sometimes because the dwarfs are kind of
complicated
so these are the kind of problems we've
faced
now there's some generic solutions to
these problems that we've had there's
three main ones that you need to cover
to be a valid solution to this problem
which is first you need to update your
symbols dynamically they need to be
updated as we go you know you need to
continue to have changes when you make
them in your static engine your
decompiler whatever it is second you
need to display your context we want a
debug Source where's my source show me
the source so we should have Source in
our debugger and third this should be
somewhat extensible to you know some
degree shouldn't be really Linux
specific it could be anywhere so we try
to cover all three of these spaces and
surprise surprise we we do cover them in
this project that is associated with
this talk which is called dcom to debug
which tries to lift this information
into a standard format and then you know
fit them into the the debugger in
whatever way we can if you're using GDB
you can get actual uh Native symbols
symbols that are real to GDB now that's
this is fun stuff in here you can see
this kind of pain and if you're
interested in using it it works for Ida
guidra binary ninja anger management and
you know GDB and all its variants
including Jeff and stuff like that you
can go check it out if you're interested
and I think the best way for you to see
what the power is is for me to do some
some demo so we're going to do some demo
in the shellfish tradition things may
Sig fault break or blow up during the
presentation so that's just part of the
tradition of shellfish this hacking team
that you guys are now about to get in on
so let's uh let's see it in action
so this first uh binary I'm going to
show you I have two I have two different
demos for you guys the first is a local
debugging session and the second is a
remote debugging session the second one
actually features a zero day we found on
this router over here
latest version or that's the latest
Netgear router it's one firmware update
behind so it is now patched and latest
but this was the zero day as of the last
update so I guess now it's an end day or
a one or 0.5 day because it's not
publicly known you guys are actually the
first ones to see it so we'll see it in
the second demo so the first demo will
be local the second demo will be remote
the second demo is where things get
dicey so we'll hope it goes well yeah so
let's check out this first one so
running your dcom to debug session is
pretty easy we started up everything is
talking over a local port on an XML RPC
server so we start this we enter the
binary and now we do decompiler connect
ghidra
and we've connected to the decompiler so
earlier we actually had no symbols right
this binary doesn't have any symbols we
can't break it anything it's completely
stripped
now we can break a main we hit continue
we next instruction a little to get into
past the prologue and you can see on
this left hand side we actually have
decompilation inside of our debugger now
these are actually mapped addresses that
go between decompilation lines and we
have real symbols so if I print main
right this is actually a real symbol
inside the debugger now it's not fake
it's not an artificial symbol so it's
pretty awesome
so what we can do is we can actually
keep stepping right we can keep moving
through stuff we hit a call for a read
we say cactus
right and now we can actually print our
variables over here as well password
it's typed which is awesome we also have
username
so these variables which are local
variables are mapped as GDB helper
variables so these ones are not actually
native and it is kind of fun because you
can now Port that to wind debug and much
other ones so if we print this it's
typed so we can actually see the whole
normal thing we didn't have to assume
types we didn't have to do any of that
we get it all here in addition to that
if we change stuff we can do new
username right new username very cool we
do a next instruction everything has
changed in our decompilation
print new username
we see the same thing same address we
can dereference it it's Cactus it works
it's awesome it works for Global
variables which we can see inside over
here
four zero zero two five four
these are all Global variables found
within the binary and it even works as
we change the symbols so for instance if
we change this to uh not Main
that's fine
next instruction
a little crash on not main I guess
that's fine
so generally speaking we are able to
update these things on the Fly you can
update symbols you can update types you
can update these little helper variables
and the decompilation modifies as we go
through it so this is kind of the basics
of dcom to debug and after the demo I'll
you know reveal a little bit of the
magic of how we did it so that's kind of
the cool part of this so now we move on
to the risky demo let's get to the risky
demo so here's the risky demo let me
plug this in
so what I'm doing right now is plugging
us into the Netgear router so we're on
the same network interface so what we're
going to do is we're going to exploit
the router so that we can have a shell
on the router and then once we have a
shell on the router we're going to start
a GDB server so that we can connect
remotely what this all goes to say is
this is running arm32 and it's running
very specific binaries but we connect
from here with GDB remote and then we
can get our symbols from our decompiler
so let's try it out
all right wait for the exploit to
trigger
should be uh some nice little suspense
brilliant we're on the box awesome so
right now we are on this router's shell
and what we're going to do is start this
GDB server
now I know this is a little pedantic
because we're going this huge roundabout
just to run a remote server but I I
promise it is worth it
so we also go here let's start this dcom
to debug server over here on a different
port 633 good awesome start this in
multi-arc
we do Jeff remote
192.
we connect remotely
connect our decompiler
print packet callback
see if we have symbols we do to make
sure things are safe this is a remapped
address we break there
now the cool thing about this binary is
that this binary is for parsing packets
you can't step through this binary
unless you're able to trigger packets
and listen to it remotely without
interfering with those packet parsings
so what we do is we send a single curl
I've sent a curl to this router now you
can see that it's a Netgear router and
everything in here
and now we've actually broken inside of
the function
so this is awesome because we are live
on this router looking at this
information here which we can now parse
so I can do something like print packet
data
print packet data
and you can see that the data is
actually there which is very fun
so the kind of point of this is that
this debugging standard Works regardless
of architecture it works regardless of
decompiler and debugger we can do it
remotely and these symbols can kind of
go back and forth and this is cool
because this is normally not possible
for embedded device reversing so you
know anything you do in here it holds
the same standards that your normal
local debugging environment has
essentially getting you Source over a
remote connection
uh so yeah if you're interested more
about how I actually did this because
this does kind of look like black magic
I kind of just got a shell went on the
router and now we have debugging
um we have a blog post coming later this
week where we'll be explaining what this
bug actually is it is a zero or it's a
one click into your router over one side
but it's a fun little thing for all
Netgear Nighthawk routers so we fully
you know discovered this exploitability
through using this decomp to debug
interface because we have this faster
reversing system
so let's move back now to the rest of
this I will unplug this guy so I have
normal internet again
and let's go back to the talk
I guess we'll have to reconnect to the
Wi-Fi that's what I get for uh
trying to do a demo disconnect the Wi-Fi
and then reconnect
awesome
right so you guys have kind of seen some
of the magic that you can do right we
can actually make these two things more
like the same you can get your
decompiler in your debugger you can have
these symbols you can map things on the
Fly how are we actually doing this so in
the steps that go right you got your
little reversing sent to the fish here
you're trying to debug something you're
trying to debug a binary when you try to
debug it you trigger events called
rebase stop events or break points
anytime you have a break point access we
take that address we eliminate whatever
the Base address was in the debugger we
send it off to the decompiler the
decompiler sees that what it does is it
weights on a trigger every time you
change something we update the cache of
symbols that we have stored these
symbols get updated on every change so
we have hooks in every decompiler that's
supported so the big four and then we
send these symbols back in a rebased
format so those addresses get rebased
back to the original addresses of the
debugger we do this with the symbols we
send you the context of your
decompilation so we map your address to
the real source and decompilation and we
send it back as an XML so you can parse
this in whatever debugger you want and
we're kind of doing this through another
project I write called binsync
and lastly all those are now made into a
fake symbol file this symbol file we use
inside the debugger
so to give you the quick overview of how
we do that last part because it's kind
of nuts we make a small elf on hand
rapidly on every debug we inject into
the dot symbol table because this is a
section of your symbols that can
actually be modified in runtime we bite
patch that section to have the max size
which are these many F sizes so that we
override the GDB code which checks if a
section is big enough for new symbols
and then we add a fake symbol file in on
every iteration that's kind of a fast
overview but if you want to see more you
can read the code online it's open
source accessible to everybody and you
know if you like it I'd love for you to
check it out Port it to windybug you
know Port it or whatever I accept PRS
from anybody so it's out there it's open
you know ready for for you to work with
it
and on that note I think we've covered
all the cool stuff
um does anybody have any questions about
any part of this even binary analysis
since I love binary analysis love
questions
yes
oh oh wait there's a sorry about that
like this box
that's a microphone wow yeah
um so I assume that there was an
intermediary step when you got root on
the router in which you had to copy off
all the binaries to load them into your
decomposer is that right yes yes it is
um however the firmware for all these
routers are usually available online so
you can just download all the firmware
but in this case yeah we would have had
to copy it off normally yeah
yes uh and then
you mentioned briefly about how you had
to rebase these addresses I assume this
is because in the static firmware they
have some assumed load address and then
that load address is different at
runtime is that right precisely not only
that but the decompiler will decide
whatever Base address it wants in Anger
We Do ox 40 000 in ghidra they do 50 000
sometimes and in Ida they do sixty
thousand so everyone gets to just choose
whatever they want so we always have to
make it an offset regardless regardless
of if it's Pi or not pi yeah okay yeah
yeah it's a mess and then lastly you
made a point of explaining how it wasn't
like a virtual symbol in GDB it was like
a real GDP it's a real g2b Center I
don't know what that
is right right so the difference between
a virtual and a real symbol virtual um a
virtual symbol was when I did that
dollar sign that's essentially like an
environment variable right you
environment variable and GDB and those
environment variables you can even set
types to so it almost looks real to a
viewer it would look like the same thing
you'd be like those are the same it'd be
that this is the same meme but um in
reality that symbol that was not with
the dollar sign those are symbols that
GDB has parsed that are located inside
the elf and that it recognizes as a real
function now the reason that's kind of
like whoa is because other tools down
the pipeline they depend on that
information and it's not a dwarf it's in
the dot symbol table which was invented
in like early 2000 or something and you
know way before my time
and they uh they they made it in such a
way that it's parcelable by everybody so
the difference between these real and
not real symbols is kind of that they're
not supposed to exist in GDB you're not
allowed to to create a new symbol like
hey I reverse this function let me name
it something GDB says no go get a new
binary why don't you write Source
compile that and bring it back right so
you can't do that in GDB but with our
tool you can you can hack it in it's
you're not allowed to do it we hack it
in and the reason why during the remote
demo that I couldn't show Breaking at
that specific symbol like without taking
the address is because up until I think
three versions ago GDB if it's 32-bit it
just sank false GDB it's just save fault
so this is a rather recent update that
you can with our stuff hack in real
symbols and that's kind of what a real
symbol is very cool
yes oh yeah
all right
um so you found zero days or I guess now
like end days for the router yeah uh
get any feedback from Netgear on that so
for these ones for Netgear they patched
these I think five days before the pone
to own but nobody has acknowledged that
they exist publicly so right now we have
something going through miter to try and
get you know CV so we can release it
more but uh either way it's patched in
the latest but nobody actually knows
that this one exists it was categorized
as a lan exploit which means that you
can only pone it when you're on the
Wi-Fi router but we've found that this
is actually much more devastating you
can um if I have a website I can point
you yeah
ponone is a zero day competition
more questions I got I got five minutes
left of questions any questions you want
binary analysis trivia go
what's your favorite decompiler
my favorite decompiler is the decompiler
called anger management at ASU we write
our own decompiler we have our own cell
front decompiler so I guess I'm biased
but I think that is the coolest
decompiler however I Ida is uh is Miles
Ahead of of most decompilers yeah
any other questions
there
why that's that's a real question
actually I actually feel a little bit
insulted like like I actually did make a
mistake and it was uh a t or it was the
yeah it was at T syntax when I had it up
there
I that was a mistake that was just a
mistake I'll I'll admit my uh fault
there my bad
if my uh Professor were here he would
definitely be like he's a faker he
doesn't know how to reverse
any other questions
from you Rob
no
okay
all right awesome thank you so much
oh
I have a light a nice last statement for
you guys uh goodbye question so in in
this kind of envisionment of what the
future of binary analysis looks like
right because this this was rather
complicated anything could have gone
wrong during this talk what does the
future of binary analysis look like to
you guys we have more AI we have more
emojis you know I couldn't find a single
decompiler that would let me name my
function in emoji so you know what does
the future of binary analysis look like
to you guys
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]