thank you yes all right welcome
everybody and thanks to us for inviting
me here
well dr. church's your engineer in ing
and co-founder of a project called
IOT sect that you publish bigger for
different conferences such as yeah oh
what's up Zack blackhat their second and
yeah my focus is mobile applications a
curio to measure like will see during
the talk
IOT security and yeah like everybody
ting in this room I'm a builder but also
breaker so why does mobile security
matter today I think you all know this
new setting is from August 26 and yeah
it says that the four night Android app
lets hackers install malware on their
device so you can imagine I work for ing
right a bank and you can imagine if that
title says critical flow in the ing up a
law allows malware on your device then
everybody will delete it up and I will
be fired directly my manager is there so
so but what was the problem in this case
problem or feature let's say the problem
was this line of code in the manifest
file Android manifest file so right SMS
storage and it's a permission that Allah
allows you to write and read from the
external storage in the Android device
so every app can read and write in that
storage so you can imagine if you have a
malware on your application can
overwrite in that case the fortnight up
and installed malware on your device so
if we consider the agile as DLC when
should we that when is the best where is
the best place to detect vulnerability
of course we want to detect
vulnerabilities as soon as possible
right so during the requirements and
design phase through security
requirements
secure design review and of course
threat model and in this case is pretty
cheap the earlier one bag of money there
if we run the second phase so code and
build it's already more expensive right
and if we take in consideration the
vulnerability of the problem with the
four-night app forest principle maybe
wouldn't detect that problem right
because it's not in the security
requirements is not in a threat model so
it's fine right but maybe if we have
coding guidelines yeah that will be
easily detected because google says is
not safe at all to use that if we go in
the turf face maybe secure code scan
wouldn't detect maybe we'll raise a
warning but definitely a penetration
test will detect that that is a problem
but of course is very very expensive
right and at the end of course if we
detect in production then yeah it's too
expensive right
so why do ya mistakes happen mistakes
happen because yeah we need a feature we
need a new product as soon as possible
right so developers have pressure and
maybe security requirements are not
followed or not in place nor enforced or
there is no trap modeling session done
before deployment and we still rely on
SAS tools so with a lot of false
positive and also but mainly DevOps do
not write security tests right is there
at the box of bright security test here
that's not true it's my colleague
anyways so in mobile we have let's say
two groups if you consider the security
challenges we have technical challenges
for security engineers because we have
different operating system clients our
testing is very important is the biggest
part of the test I would say different
apps native hybrid web everything new
frameworks different languages so sus2
do not support right away new languages
if we think about Kathleen example and
different security controls right so if
we speak about process challenges as
security engineer what we want to do is
actually provide security at the vault
speed right we don't want to be there
two weeks testing a feature that the
developer developed in half day right we
want to have developers understand
security and the tech mooner ability in
early stage at least the basic security
should be covered right away and of
course I'm also a pen tester so I would
like to focus on fun and serious stuff
when I do a pen test instead of coding
everything right so how can we improve
this so in this talk we're going to see
how to build security integration tests
and embed this test of course in the CI
CD so we have different kind of tests
right we have the testing you let's say
test-driven development where the tests
are written before coding and passing
the test is crucial right or accepted
test-driven development where team
members collaborate also with other
parts to write tests on a functionality
and at the end we have BDD behavior
driven development we are going to talk
about this where the tests are written
in a non-technical language that
everyone can understand so we're going
to feel few gaps here in communication
between developers security business and
it uses language called gherkin yeah
because what's the biggest problem with
testing the biggest problem is
misunderstanding right so if a writer a
developer right at writes a test maybe
it's a security test but the security
engineer doesn't understand it doesn't
know it's already there so we want to
fill this gap and the solution is yeah
BDD BDD allows us to describe
the behavior of our software in a very
understandable language so an example
this is just an example of BDD test
ability is dividing into let's college
yeah file a feature file so the business
facing on my test as you can see the
test is written in English Puri English
in this case I want to test coffee
machine so if there is one coughing the
in the Machine and I deposit one dollar
then I press the coffee button and I
should be served with a coffee it's very
easy very understandable right the
technology facing is what translates the
business facing in code right in this
case we're using Ruby and as we can see
the second function let's say the given
just initialize our machine with one
element in it right so ya YB didn't
security because if you consider yes
security engineers developers and
business what we have right now is
something like this right so secure
engineer speaks one language developers
another language maybe they can
understand each other somewhere their
business can understand anything they
say right so with BDD we fix
communication right business will still
speak money but we'll understand that
because we're going to use a
construction given when then so and the
developers will write the tests in the
same language as the security engineer
and we fix speed of course because if
developers write security tests right
and this tests are validated by the
security team then they can go to
production much faster so how do we
write this test the framework we're
going to use to write this test is
cucumber we are the king of BDD because
it allows you to write features like we
set so the business facing and steps use
in different type of languages so
be adopted by different companies but
what we're on of right is mobile BDD
security tests so in order to do that
first of all we need to translate the
always mobile security testing guide in
BDD we have spend the one of the founder
there so we want to do the mobile
security testing guide it's a set of
tests and yes security checks to test
the security of your app right and what
we want to do we want to translate these
tests in BDD tests so we're going to
create the features and these steps to
be integrated in the CI CD and be
executed on every build let's say of
your mobile app right but in order to do
that we need to automate DUI so one part
of the mobile Siri test is the
client-side testing right if we don't
have to me do I we cannot access all the
code right so we're going to use in the
example we're going to use calabash
that's just a UI automation framework
but this test can be written using other
you automation frameworks such as a
human example right we can we're going
to integrate a course because we want to
write security that's not UI security
test we need to integrate some tools in
example for Android you can integrate
the Android a bug bridge over stop to
test network issues or use browser
famous fantastic mobile time testing
tools that can be automated in your in
your scripts and of course what we want
it's our feedback from from the test
right we want this test to be all green
so we know that we cover the security
the basic security in our app so the
full process in the sdlc will look more
or less like this so we have the mobile
application security verification
standard checklist and our security
requirements and of course our threat
model we want to translate this in code
right one to translate our threat model
our security requirements in code
right and of course the mobile Siri
testing guide so we wanna implement
standard BDD tests they can be applied
on every app because interact with the
operating system but we want to
implement also BDD application specific
security tests like an example tests in
the business logic or authentication
bypass vulnerabilities and so on we're
gonna secure this test against
acceptance environment but of course we
cannot automate everything right we
cannot we're not gonna cover everything
so we still have the manual pen test
phase done by security engineers or pen
testers but what we can do is that if
our pen tester identifies and issues
that can be automated we go back in the
cycle we introduce new security
requirements we update our threat model
and we implement new BDD security tests
right and then the next time that issue
will be covered in our CI CD all right
let's go a little bit more technical not
too much
so the old setup looks like this so we
have our test script our apk we have a
docker container with our UI automation
framework right and the tests can be
executed on emulators or devices real
devices so in example if you have a farm
we will execute your tests on every
device just in one shot
we're gonna use as a target the Ava's
mobis your MS CG hacking playground
still from span and it's an application
that as like yeah different buttons a
manual with different vulnerabilities
and just testing up to practice mobile
security let's say in example if we want
to test locks for sensitive data right
our security requirements will be that
locks must not contain username locks
man's not contain password information
too
that related to user and PII and
security requirements could be the
loggia should be disabled if we think
about a banking app in example so the
flaw that we want automate is something
like this we click on the button we
insert username we insert a password and
we click on login
the app will write message in the log
files that contains our username a
password of course don't do it but this
just to test our scripts right so our
BDD will look like this we will have a
feature a feature just what we are gonna
do right so we're gonna test against
sensitive data in law files a scenario
so in this case our scenario is we open
the app we press the button relate
relate to log files and we check then no
sensitive data are written in the log
files so the BDD test will look like
this given I clean all the application
logs so the key word given is just a
precondition like I said we're gonna
delete all the logs from our phone from
our emulator we don't want noise right
we want to test in a clean environment
then we automate the UI and the last
step is the step that we'll check then
no sensitive information will be stored
in the log files so the first the given
statement will look like this in the
step step file so the implementation is
just we call the Android debug bridge to
clean all the logs as we can see here
the keyboard all is passed to the
function right and the second the last
statement is the statement is gonna
check that no sense of information are
between the log files so in this case
the function just gets in input the the
but level right that we wanna use of the
logs
and in the second part is gonna use the
again the Android debug bridge so adb
logcat - to check that sensitive
information are not in the law files in
this case we're gonna use also grep
count how many instances of the sensor
information is locked and if there is
more than one then the test fails so you
can imagine in this case what we want to
achieve here is that the developers will
write something like this so on every
critical function every new feature that
shouldn't log information in the log
files they need to they will have to
write tests like this as part of their
their integration tests right so if
everything is green the pen testers one
check that sends information are logged
while using that feature right another
example is the testing local storage for
sensitive data so our security
requirement will be that databases
should not contain sensor information as
we know they're insecure data bases must
be encrypted in example and we should
use the keychain to store the
credentials so in this case what we are
gonna do is of course go through the UI
press the button relate to database and
then as we can see from the last step
we're gonna check that the tables that
are created and information that are
stored in the table Donna do not contain
sense information this case it's admin
password in clear-text so if you go in
the steps the the test will look like
this in this case we're still using the
Android debug bridge and sequel I to
read from the database with them the old
content of the database and we grab for
information that shouldn't be in that in
that database right and of course if we
find that information we fail
we fill the test so after we execute all
the tests of course we want developers
to execute those tests in the CI CD and
when all the tests are completed we will
s something like this so we can give a
report like this to business to the
security guys to the managers in order
to prove and that our application is
secure and it's understandable by
everybody because it's normal English of
course in this case the report will
contain that the test failed and will
tell you where it failed if we want to
integrate it in the CI CD we will do
something like this so in this case we
use Jenkins and as you can see from the
red line it's just a shell command that
will call our feature files and will
activate will go through the test and
automate it on our on our mobile or on
our emulators right so let them just to
show you how this looks like
[Music]
all right let's move it there
not easy and this
all right this is this more difficult
yeah all right
have you ever tried this - right here
and so we have our mobile device and on
in the console it's our docker container
right so the in the docker container the
all contain is attached to our tests and
our folder containing the apk and what
we're gonna do is actually spin up the
test from the docker container and then
use the emulator to yeah
emulate the the app so the comment that
we're gonna use in this case is calabash
Android because we're going to use
calabash to automate UI right but of
course you can use other you have frame
or such a command the comment will be
more or less the same but the concept
will be exactly the same so if we run it
our first test is that database should
not contain sensitive information and in
this case calabash will spin up the the
application and click in the interface
and then as we can see in this case the
test fails because the app stores
information in the database and the
second test is the sensor information in
the log files and in this case it fails
again because there are information in
files as we can see if we go ready be
like that's secret yeah we have multiple
instances of cigarettes being logged
logged in the application and here we
have a username and password so our test
will will fail
so coming back to presentation I hope
it's doing that yes what are the
benefits yeah we're ready discuss few
benefits but what we want to do with
this kind of tests we want to increase
the security maturity on mobile teams
right it applies also for other web and
desktop application but we wanna
increase the security because we want
developers to understand what are the
security issues right we want them to
write tests for us of course we are
gonna write first this kind of tests but
then with the time there will be so good
that they will write their own tests
because they know better every single
line of code in the mobile app right we
wanna have security baseline always
covered right
we don't want surprise and we can do
this we can detect mooner abilities in a
very early stage so on every built
before the app arrives to pen testers or
is in production and of course we can
decrease the time to release because if
the tests are green and we know that the
team brought the right tests they could
go to production without even going
through the security team right and yeah
like I said we want to translate threats
in code in tests because it's the only
way to keep track and have developers
writing and understand threats in their
model and of course we can never ready
to go security to use security
documentation from the gur context that
can be used to prove that the app covers
the security features so this is an open
source project on the ING Bank get up
rapper and you can fork it you can clone
it you can modify to do what you like if
you want to contribute you're very
welcome
so yeah the last video test is for you
guys and questions yes
no it's also for iOS yes in this case we
used calabash Android like we saw but
there is also calabash iOS app you miss
for both Android iOS so it is related to
the UI framework that you're gonna use
okay other questions
so you're working with developers so I
assume these are you mentioned threat
modeling earlier how difficult is it to
train developers to write these kinds of
tasks up tests right yeah yes yeah first
of all what we do we do modeling
exercises together with developers and
other like product owners or a business
so once they understand their threats
and for them is not difficult to write
this kind of test right what we need to
teach them is how to use security tools
right and how to automate them but I
mean I can say as was i working ing and
the mobile app should be secure right
the mobile teams are pretty mature in
security but of course it takes time to
let them understand the benefits of this
approach but of course if they see that
they can go to production very fast they
would spend some time learning this
thank you any more questions
excellent thank you thank you
[Applause]