well thank you everyone for coming this
is a topic that is always in the news as
we are all know vulnerabilities and
components whether we use them or not is
a subject of many breaches so in this
talk we're going to be talking about the
ability to continuously analyze our
components for various types of things
regardless of whether or not that
software is being built or not
so dependency track is a open source
continuous component analysis platform
Gartner and Forrester make all that
software composition analysis I think
that's a terrible term it doesn't take
in environmental things run time and
it's specific to software and as we all
know Hardware also has vulnerabilities
and dependency tracking monitor those
components as well
dependency track works on the concept of
software Bill of Materials where
basically we tell dependency track
factually what components we have from
then it it monitors all of the
components that it's tracking for known
vulnerabilities as well as out-of-date
components out-of-date components is
really really important because only a
small portion of all publicly disclosed
vulnerabilities of all vulnerabilities
excuse me are actually published of
things like the NVD it's always a good
practice to stay up-to-date it does
track open source license this is not a
strategic part of the project the
evidence is there we will use it but
being an OS project I really I'm focused
more on the security aspects not
necessarily the license and compliance
aspects although I do accept pull
requests
it has a auditing workflow
much like static analysis tools four to
five check marks etc you have a bunch of
findings and those findings may or may
not be relevant to your particularly
product that you're working on so you
can mark things as false positives maybe
you can mark them as not applicable to
your application you can produce a comet
trail you have a complete audit history
as well as making marking things as
being suppressed so that your metrics
and whatnot are um are nicely affected
by that and finally it's built really
for DevOps and I it's designed with an
API first design but I think some of the
features in here you'll see that we we
don't also we don't just embrace DevOps
from the automation standpoint we we do
kind of embrace the the cultural aspect
in dependency track as well I think we
do a pretty good job of that so what is
the software Bill of material it's a
list right it's just a list of things
that we have it is a list of ingredients
that our software are in an IOT device
our pacemaker whatever it is that we are
working on it is a list of all the
ingredients that goes into that thing so
conceptually dependency track is this
you have an asset piece of software a
micro service pacemaker you create a
bill of material for that that describes
all the ingredients and you throw it
into dependency track where it will
constantly monitor it whether you're
building that software or not now the
generation of the Bill of material is
really simple to do it can be automated
and this is ideal to be put into a CI CD
pipeline so you're constantly generating
the bill of materials and you're putting
it to dependency track on a continuous
basis and you basically end up with a
loop within a loop right so you're
continuously analyzing things whether or
not you are building them or not so and
this is really important when
organizations create software they
typically create multiple versions
support multiple versions of the same
thing and you might be at version 3.0
but you still have some 1.0 in the field
and you still support it but you don't
build it every day but you still want to
check your components right well you
might have a bunch of microservices say
for example you've got hundreds or
thousands of micro-services these
development teams they go from one
service to the next to the next outside
of a few core services that are really
important to your business you're not
working on all thousand services all the
time right but you still need to monitor
those without necessarily having to
build everything all the time so the
types of analysis that we do
vulnerabilities out data components so
for vulnerabilities we check the NBD we
integrate natively with NPM public
repositories using NPM out of API
big thanks to Sonu type for supporting
OSS index and rolling that out and we've
got partial support volunteer B we're
kind of working on that a little bit as
we as we go forward for outdated
components we currently support ruby
gems there's like nine or ten maven
public maven repositories that we
support NPM and nougat is in development
so Billo material support we support two
different types of bill materials
Cyclone DX and SP DX
cyclone DX was written specifically for
dependency track it is a very
lightweight specification it is designed
to be essentially the the minimal Viable
Product of what a bill of material
should be with an application security
focus so it is the recommended way to do
this SPT X is also supported SPD X is a
much older Bela material specification
it's used by a black duck and a few
others but it has historically focused
mostly on license copyright compliance
that type of thing there is a new
version of SPD X coming up version 2.2
which I at that point I'll also be able
to say that that's also recommended
although not a bill of material we also
can depend in jest dependency check
reports as well so generating a bomb is
really simple you basically start with
something that's native to your eco
system maven NPM there's a dotnet core
module there's other things in
development the specification is really
super simple to understand
you could probably create something for
Ruby or Python in a few hours actually
have something of production quality
within a day maybe two if you're slow
but it's really really simple to get
started this is what a bill of material
actually looks like for this sake of
screen real estate I only have one bill
of material listed here but as you can
see this is a type of library
it's rest easy from the JBoss project
it's got a bunch of file hashes it has
the SPT X license ID and then it has
this thing called called Perl or package
URL this thing is very very important it
is a standardized based way to represent
your components irregardless of what
ecosystem that component is a part of so
instead of having maven gods or you know
the Ruby version of that or the NPM
you've got one representation regardless
of ecosystem I can describe maven or NPM
or Red Hat package managers pretty much
everything but it's really important I
know
cyclone DX supports a dependency track
supports it so no typo SS the next
supports at Red Hat is in the process of
supporting it few other folks but
basically it is a decentralized URI it
actually conforms to the URS
specification there are a bunch of
parsers out there I wrote the official
Java version of that and I marks also a
part of the
the group that our that's helping define
the specification but there's
implementations for for JavaScript for
Ruby I think there's a Python there's a
dotnet one out there so definitely go
check it out
so dependency track once you actually
ingest your bill a material that's top
left we work with the multiple sources
of vulnerability intelligence and we
also do the outdated version detection
so once you actually have the build
material in dependency track we're going
to constantly analyze that now every
time you upload a bill material we're
going to analyze it but if you don't
upload a bill material we're still gonna
analyze it every 24 hours but it doesn't
do anybody any good if the information
just sits there right so we've got
notifications support so you can
actually get slack or Microsoft teens
notification the really interesting
thing though is to be able to automate
your response so we have web hooks and
the data that we actually provide in web
hooks allow you to do some really
interesting things so for example if you
have a library and you discover that
it's vulnerable well you can automate
that response so you can send the web
hook out and maybe it's a library and
maybe it's a minor version so you might
in that particular case you want to
automatically do a pull request to
update it to the latest version or maybe
it's a framework or it's a major version
update so in that case you might want up
to the business response is going to be
just to automatically create a JIRA
ticket to go into the team's backlog to
fix so it's really up to you how you
kind of use that functionality but we
provide a ton of data that you can
really use via web hooks we do have our
own Jenkins plugin now and for thread
fix customers you actually get a thread
fixed remote importer from denim group
supported by denim group we're working
on other vulnerability aggregation
things as well
Kenna security support is coming up and
I will be writing a fortify SSE
plug in as well so you'll be able to get
your aesthetic analysis results and your
component analysis results in a single
pane of glass questions before the demo
and please pray to the demo gods for
right
right so the question is how can you use
package URL or Perl to query for
vulnerabilities just using that string
right so dependency track actually and
cyclin D acts really puts a big focus on
package URL just because it's a
standardized representation of any
component we treat package URL as kind
of a router right so if I have a
component that I know is of the NPM
variety I'm gonna automatically use NPM
audit API you don't have to know that
the system just does that for you
whereas if I have something that has
like maven I might choose to do OSS
index if I don't have a package URL I'm
gonna use dependency check internally
and do my fuzzy matching voodoo stuff
against the nvd to try to try to pull
some some of that stuff back so package
URL is really really important OSS index
the service provided by sono type
actually uses package URL natively you
have to use it in order to use a service
and that's how we integrate with them
it's really simple actually it doesn't
have to be unlike a URL it doesn't have
to be resolvable so essentially what you
do is in the case of maven for example
the it's going to be PKG : you know :
maven and then slash the group slash the
component name at sign the version
that's it the group is optional in a lot
of ecosystems for example in an NPM the
organization or the group is an optional
thing in things like nougat it doesn't
exist right so you just don't MIT that
yeah it's really simple yeah
yep
so that's a great question so the
recommendation regardless of whether or
not you have vulnerabilities in your
components is always going to be keep it
components up-to-date it's a best
practice from just a hygiene perspective
because you get performance and bug
fixes and all that but when you have
something like struts or a spring that
gets popped especially struts all the
time you need to be able to respond
within hours sometimes or less because
those things are typically weaponized
within a few hours right
so it's really important for you to keep
those things up-to-date on a very
consistent basis because if I'm a few
versions buff behind
I now may have to deal with API changes
to do that upgrade whereas if I'm
continuously upgrading you know I can
just you know update the thing and I can
probably not even test right I can just
go forth and deploy but the question was
really about the unknown vulnerabilities
that that are not in a thing like the
env D which is about 90% of all
vulnerabilities that's a really hard
problem to solve there's a lot of really
good commercial sources of vulnerability
intelligence so a type Nexus IQ for
example has some really good stuff snake
who I'm actually in the process of
trying to integrate with they actually
have some really good stuff as well
for example package URL with snipe
they actually have REST API s for each
ecosystem so like the REST API for
nougat is different than the REST API
from maven it'sit's crazy but if they
were to standardize on package URL you
wouldn't have to worry about you know
what ecosystem that package is actually
and you have one API that you can then
then query I'm trying to get them to
support that but I think the package URL
really has a really really big potential
impact for things like commercial
sources of vulnerability intelligence so
vulnerability intelligence that we
integrate with they had Moses 6000
varner abilities in their database that
weren't in the NBD and 20 or 17 we
support that so yeah
it's only gonna get better
right right
right are you on those working groups
dude yeah right yeah so there's actually
a couple working groups going on right
now at the in the federal government I'm
actually part of two of those working
groups that are discussed discussing
software transparency at the government
level yeah and yeah it's a really hard
problem to solve because there's a lot
of use cases Cyclone DX doesn't handle
every single use case it's not designed
to it's really designed for that minimal
Viable Product for you to be able to
generate the Bill of material from your
build system in a very easy automated
way to get results
SPD X you know it's again it's an older
standard it's supported by things like
black duck it's supported an
independancy track it was designed not
for software security so there's the the
package URL and some of these other
fields isn't aren't in the specification
yeah it's but version 2.2 they're
actually adding some of these things so
we'll see where it goes software ID are
Swit I don't support because the
specification is behind the paywall so
if they ever change that I'll support
the specification
vulnerability to Ribbit's you can't yes
yeah so if you want to as an
organization if you want to create your
own internal private vulnerability
database you can do that today yes
third party JavaScript to the Europe
like to package URL yes a little just be
package PKG where's that uh let's see so
it literally be package npm the optional
organization so the if you had one slash
whatever the name of the component is at
version that's really it and there's
actually a cyclone DX npm module that
will automatically create your bill of
material from package jason so if you
have a a node project you can actually
create all of that with one command
what's that
well if it's a if you're building with
NPM if you if you're using a JavaScript
package manager right it'll it'll do
everything for you if you're using
unmanaged dependencies that's that's an
entirely different problem right all
right yeah that's that's a different
problem well dependency check it's not a
bill of material it does provide a
report that does have the some of that
information in there it's not a true
bill of material it's limited and it's
inconsistent so for example if I were to
scan a package Jason with dependency
check the dependencies and the
transitive dependencies are actually
represented differently and some of my
other components so I don't necessarily
get all the information that that I
really need nor does it support package
URL which is really important there is a
backlog item for the dependency track
our dependency check to support package
URL and if they ever do support it you
know I'll be able to support that a much
for for accurate results yeah if you
want there's really two interesting use
cases for this so like if you want very
specific actionable results without a
lot of noise if you want a very clear
signal to noise ratio use cyclone DX and
use you know the Maven NPM whatever to
generate it and use NPM audit and OSS
ENDEX and disable dependency check now
if you want to cast a wider net and be
able to get environmental things or
maybe you are working on a legacy
project that doesn't have maven or
not then in that case her on depends you
check and it'll find those types of
things but at the expense of false
positives
sorry quick question how does the tool
handle the notification and the tracking
of issues if I like let's say I
submitted my bomb a month ago and there
is a vulnerability today
does it notify me does it allow me yeah
you know to customize who else would be
notified and so on
yeah so the the notification support it
actually keeps track of the all the
history of the components and the
vulnerabilities it also keeps track of
all the analysis decisions that you've
made so for example if you have a bill
of material that you ingested like a
month ago and there was no
vulnerabilities and a month later there
is if you have a notification configured
and it's like a two minute process to
configure them but if you have a
notification configured you can get a
slack notification Microsoft teams web
hooks we also support email
notifications if you want email it's
really up to you
no no no eventually there will be there
will be like JIRA integration with
bi-directional thing I accept pull
requests yeah so last question so how
can we found out was inside a pure
material what I mean here that for
example you mentioned trust you right
pay attention to scratch to a lot of
people to know like text and data path
that's three inside straws too so what I
ever try to date about how somewhat of
ADT coming up how can we you know
notifies trust you and you know get it
fixed so what's what's the question
specifically it's like what's the second
level dependency what's the yeast at a
pyramid here right so do you have any
tools to do that or do you have news
right so when you generate the Bill of
material it is basically a flat
representation because that's what a
bill of material is so it's bill of
material is not a dependency tree first
and foremost it is just a flat
representation of first level what do
you yeah but it but it does include all
your transitive dependencies so when you
do create the like maven or NPM if when
you do create your cyclone DX pillow
material you will get all of your
transitive dependencies under stress
it's under stress - yeah transitive fear
yes yes they will you do have the
relationship between these two yes yes
okay yes yes it's in there
all right let's how much we've got five
minutes seven minutes okay okay so here
is the main dashboard for dependency
track I am going to go ahead and create
a project
let's do web code and this is version
8.0 of web code I think okay so I've got
an empty project in dependency track
I've got a Jenkins installation over
here and I've got a job let me just show
you the configuration of the job here so
this is OS webgoat looks like I'm
pulling it from I might not want to do
that because I don't want to rely on the
internet right now and I would normally
end up building the right building
webgoat but in this particular case I
just want to generate the Bill of
material with all of my transitive
dependencies so this is what this does
so it just calls out to the to the maven
plug-in directly ideally this would be
in your maven profile or part of your
build step the next thing I want to do
is I want to publish my results then to
dependency track it's automatically
going to populate my full list of
projects I only have one to find there
and I know that the Bill of material
will be in my maven target directory and
it will be called BOM that XML so let's
save that and run it and pray to the
demo guys that it works
okay so right now it's making an
aggregate of of all the components that
are in there
see how long this takes I'll come back
to that one thing that you can do with
dependency check or track is it actually
maintains a full list of all the
vulnerabilities so if you want to do
analysis on things in the nvd right so
for example CVE 2018 something or other
right so this one is high severity you
get all the metadata about what it is
all right you get the base impact
exploitability scores links out to nest
for that but you also get if I if I had
any projects in my portfolio in my
enterprise right you'd actually get a
list of all your affected projects so if
you already use this to monitor like for
example all of your commercial software
right a lot of organizations have
hundreds if not thousands of
applications that they use that they
didn't develop
well now you can instead of when the
next heartbleed comes out right you
don't have to call every vendor because
that's not scalable
you can now look at dependency track and
see which applications across your
enterprise are actually affected okay so
this is done it looks like it created my
billow material and it published the
artifact to dependency track so let's
let's go back to that project that I
created
there you go so I've got a bunch of
vulnerabilities now if I go in here so
these are all my dependencies some of
these things may not be able to resolve
these things will tell you whether or
not it's out of date or not the little
green ones tell you that it's it's
actually the the latest version and then
you can go over to audit and these are
all the findings that it found so I can
go over to looks like I'm version using
anniver toner illusion of Tomcat so you
can go into the each vulnerability here
and make your analysis decisions again
just like a static analysis tool you can
mark things as being exploitable
suspicious if it's in their
investigation not affected right
yeah correct so it really depends on the
source of vulnerability intelligence
like OSS index provides a lot of that
the NVD obviously does note security
platform used to NPM no longer does
so within p.m. for example you don't get
some of the cbss scores nor do you get
the vectors so those pretty little
graphs and stuff you no longer get with
NPM what's that
well you're always going to if it's a if
it's you publicly disclose vulnerability
you're always going to have a CVE or
some kind of unique identifier so to
type for example has they actually use
you you you IDs NPM is just you know one
through whatever the nvd uses CBE -
something or other
so depending on your source of
vulnerability intelligence you're always
gonna have a unique identifier Devon the
vulnerable versions we don't track
that's this that's almost impossible to
track without human intervention because
yeah because CPEs are completely
unreliable and the the nist is trying to
get rid of them right right exactly
yeah CPEs are long outlived their
usefulness they were good for a time but
it really depends on the source of only
really intelligence like if you if you
use NPM right if you've got a node
project it'll actually tell you in the
in the vulnerability information what
things you should actually update to if
you're using sono type OSS index they
don't provide that information to non
paying customers right
right yeah so you can actually go to
like if you go to the CVE
right you know actually tell you what
cwe it it has yeah so we have that well
they're always going to be a unique
identifier regardless of the source of
vulnerability intelligence always
yeah it works similar to static analysis
so the question was what happens when
you constantly upload bombs to the
pendency tract right it works very much
like static analysis where you're
analyzing a bunch of code and you upload
you know your code for analysis when you
do that it's basically a it's basically
the equivalent of stating these are
everything that I am up have is as
components it is not an additive process
when you update your your bill of
material right if if you're no longer
using something it'll drop off if you
are using something new it will be added
and for the things that remain the same
it will maintain that history across you
know forever as well as your your full
audit trail it's language agnostic yeah
so we don't care what language that
you're using it doesn't really matter
what matters more in that regard is
really the source of vulnerability
intelligence what can they do
one last question before we gotta go
correct
that's a great question right now that
it lists them separately in the future
it will try to correlate them thank you
everyone
[Applause]