or name so today I'm going to talk to
you about some open-source security
tools that you can use for kubernetes
and the applications running on top of
kubernetes as well as the gentleman said
I'm Michael Ducey I work for a company
called cystic we have several open
source projects that are focused on not
only security but also its performance
and troubleshooting and my role is
pretty much well a lot of things with
those open source projects ask me what
my job is and I'll tell you so for the
agenda we're going to talk about kind of
the layers of container security and how
a lot of people in the kubernetes world
is starting to kind of categorize things
we're going to talk about some of the
challenges of container security and
kind of interspersed as we go through
each layer I'm going to talk about open
source tools for each layer the two
things that I'm going to concentrate on
the most and spend the most time on is
the build layer and then also the
runtime layer as well so when you think
of the layers you can kind of think of
them like this so we have the underlying
infrastructure and then we have the
applications that reside on that
infrastructure and somehow we need to
package up those applications in a
reproducible format that you can use to
deploy to the infrastructure and so when
we think of the infrastructure layers we
tend to start to think about things like
host security networking cluster
security the container runtime security
as well and how do we lock that down in
some ways there's a lot of what we do in
the host security and the networking
world are very and cluster security
world are very basic and we are just
adapting things that we've been doing
for years in the security world to the
infrastructure layer so on the build
process we tend to think of things as
things the problems or challenges that
you're trying to solve is understanding
where the software comes from that
you're going to be deploying to your
infrastructure
so there's who's heard of the term shift
left or shifting left right it's the big
buzzword these days I think that we tend
to think of it that we're shifting
responsibility to the left I think what
you really want to focus on is that
we're shifting choice to the left and so
we're empowering the teams at the
beginning of
process with a lot more choices in what
they can choose to actually package up
and put into those containers and then
these containers start to become a black
box and so if we start to think of it as
that way that the choice is shifting
left we have to understand how do we
make help them make good choices as my
wife would tell my kids or as I would
tell my kids make good choices and so
developers much like children I guess we
need to help them make good choices no
offense to any developers in the room on
the runtime level we want to think of
things sorry I just so we look at these
things than in this way I was too caught
up in my joke and that it landed really
well that I forgot to cover these so we
tend to make good choices around where
our software comes from and the
artifacts that we're putting in and
verifying that we're getting the thing
that we expect and then also
vulnerability management not only from
the upstream operating system
perspective but also application
vulnerabilities and then at the runtime
level there's a the runtime level is
where things really start to begin to
change from our the way that we've done
things traditionally the build system is
very very similar to what we've worked
with before that we're just creating an
artifact and by the way I think that all
of distributed computing problems are
just about how you ship an artifact
around and how you make that secure and
so when we have that artifact and we're
going to have that artifact running we
need to think about how do we get
secrets into that artifact how do we do
things like service or container
admittance and there's a lot of open
source projects right now that are
starting to focus on that spiffy inspire
is one and as well as this technology
that's been coming out called service
meshes do a lot around that layer and
then anomaly detection and forensics is
also something really important so
containers don't last long they spin up
spin down very quickly and so that
container might go away within a matter
of minutes after it's spun up so if it
got compromised in that time one how do
you know and then how do you look into
that container to actually
what was going on and this object that
no longer exists then you can't get back
some challenges is that as I already
mentioned decisions are pushed to the
edge or pushed to the left
containers are very ephemeral there are
some benefits though because your attack
service has been reduced if you're
building a container properly you don't
necessarily have all of the traditional
tools inside of that container that an
attacker might need to then go and
bounce someone somewhere else once
they've got into the got into the
operating system and then resource
isolation resource isolation in the
containerized world has its benefits but
it also has its drawbacks
if resource isolation gets broken in a
containerized world then they have
access to the entire host or if a
privileged pod somebody gains access to
a privileged pod they have an access to
the entire host and so it's much easier
to break well I wouldn't say that it's
easier to break isolation from
hypervisor in a hypervisor world I would
say that the way the resource isolation
works is that if resource isolation gets
broken in a containerized world I think
it you you have many more problems than
you would in a hypervisor world so you
kind of can think of infrastructure
security in these different layers and
I'm just gonna focus on a couple tools
here real quick and things that you can
do so at the cluster layer you have
things like our back row base axis
access control security policies and
affinity most of the schedulers in the
container cloud native world and
kubernetes has this thing called
affinity so you can actually have
workloads that are scheduled and you put
them you can basically say I never want
this workload to be scheduled next to
this workload so if you have a workload
that's processing sensitive data and you
would you can isolate that over on to
its own host to process that sensitive
data and then you don't have things like
your web front-end running right
alongside of it right
on the host and container runtime side
and by the way most of these are all
configurable in the yamo or JSON that
you
up into kubernetes so these are all
well-documented things in the kubernetes
world there's host container runtime
security focused around suck comp
SELinux and app armour tools that we've
been using for a long time on the host
layer but then also an important one
that we need to start to focus on and
make sure that your developers are
putting in air our resource constraints
and what resource constraints can do so
you have to understand that when a
container runs on a host all the
resources of that host are shared with
every single container and so it's very
easy for someone if you don't put
resource constraints in place it's very
easy for one bad container to then take
over overwhelm or almost DDoS the
operating system of the underlying host
so resource constraints are very
important to put in I've kind of talked
about service mesh a little bit but
there's also Network policy and network
filtering I should have wrote this tool
on the board but there's a tool called
cilium that does layer 7 network
filtering and it allows you to control
what applications can talk to other
applications and then the network policy
is also something very powerful that
could kubernetes allow you allows you to
abstract away and then some tools that
kind of help check whether if you put
all of these layers in place there's one
by a company called aqua called coop
hunter and coop hunter will actually go
and pen test your kubernetes cluster to
look for common misconfigurations that
allow people to have access so things
like dashboards being exposed or the
what's called the couplet API endpoint
being exposed so every single node has a
little daemon that runs called the
couplet which allows that to talk back
into the kubernetes master and that's
how workloads get scheduled that API if
you leave it open it can be compromised
and it has been compromised so the coop
hunter will look for kind of those
common things that you do might be doing
wrong kuu bench is another tool by aqua
as well and this allows you to kind of
benchmark your kubernetes infrastructure
against the CIS benchmarks and then
another tool that I think is pretty
powerful but still pretty early as coupe
sec what coupe sec will do is now
we've shifted the power and control to
the left and into the developers hands
which you can do with coupe SEC is when
that yeah mo that they give you to
deploy their application to put into
kubernetes coupe SEC will actually check
that yeah Mille to say is this following
best practices are they running as a
user are there are they trying to launch
a privileged pod are they mounting up
file systems we don't want them mounting
up and other things like that as well so
coupe SEC goes to the left and it allows
the developers to actually sanity check
and you can stop a build if their
deployment doesn't have some of the
things that you want to have on in that
deployment so resource constraints
network policy pod security policies and
so forth and there are security policies
as well so the security policies allow
you to fine-tune what can be accessed
from a hosts perspective the user group
of the container read-only file system
and you can restrict to make sure that
when that deployment runs that these
things are in place and if they're not
in place this pod security policy allows
you to actually automatically have those
applied and defined the only thing the
developer would need to do is specify
what pod security policy they're wanting
to use so in the build security side so
I'm going to talk about a tool called
encore here so when you think about
everything that needs to happen from a
security perspective to get the
container out and running in the
application there's lots of things
around static code analysis and so
source code dependency checks and other
things like that when we get into the
build level what we want to start
looking at are things like build
artifacts scanning doing the dependency
checks again configuration checks as
well as other best practice checks as
well and this is really what all ends up
getting packaged up and put into the
container image that we're going to ship
out so container image scanning you
should think of it in this way so tools
and services that a high-level should
take input minimally as the built
container image they need to analyze and
inspect inside of that container image
itself
it should also perform various types of
security and best practice and
compliance checks so actually checking
the configuration of the application
that's getting packaged up so that
they're not doing silly things exposing
ports we don't want them to expose in
their application and other things like
that as well storing secrets and
environment variables all of those sorts
of things so it should result in a
report or notification or a control
decision based upon analysis Chuck's and
I think the really interesting thing
that you can start to do is control
decisions and so that you can have this
automated system that's automatically
checking the images and then kubernetes
has an interesting feature called
admission controllers and the admission
controller can actually go and check
your source of data around this scan to
say if this container image has been
violated policy and we don't want it
running in our environment the admission
controller can actually deny that thing
from being ran the other cool thing that
you can do with this in the world of
kubernetes is that you can have what's
called a Moot mutating admission
controller to where if they ask for a
particular container image you can say
no you need to run this container image
instead so you can make them and force
them get on to an image automatically
that's been scanned and you has been
checked
so the encore engine is container native
so it has idea of what a container is
and one of the problems is is that when
you try and take some of these tools
that have existed for a while and run
them in this environment they don't have
the construct or an abstraction of what
a container is so it becomes much harder
to use them you run it as a service and
it has a broad API that you can interact
with and it has policy checks that you
can customize for security best
practices and other things as well so
there are different types of checks that
you can do so you can do oh s package
checks you can also do third-party
checks as well for things like NPM Jim
and Java dependencies as well you can
look at the file names and the contents
of their file of the files as well you
can also look at the build metadata
itself so the docker file as well and
making sure that inside the docker file
that best practices are being followed
and we're not pulling things from
locations that we don't want them to
it'll check for software vulnerabilities
not only in the operating system
packages but also in third-party
packages and it can also check to make
sure to see if secrets are being
packaged into the container image
somehow as well so the way that you end
up using it is that you put it in your
delivery pipeline so developers would
ship their code to Jenkins like they
always do and then you have a cheque
that actually goes through the Encore
analyzer it does an evaluation as well
and then it uses a database to store all
the information so it'll pull the
vulnerability information for you from
various locations stored in the database
and do the evaluation if the image fails
then you can go back to the developer
and have that feedback loop and tell
them that their build failed but you can
also choose to what you depending upon
what your risk level is for the
application you can decide to let the
application go forward so encore is very
flexible with what you can do in the
policies and you can say well at least I
want to know that I'm running this piece
of code with this medium vulnerability
in it it's not a high or severe so while
you don't feel like we need to patch it
right away we can go ahead and ship it
out so I'll skip this architecture slide
because I'm going a little slow I feel
so there's different ways to install
encore you can use it be a docker
compose file you can run it directly
from the command line as well so it's
pretty easy to actually stand up and use
you can also run it as a Helmut art so
helm is definitely beginning starting to
become kind of the standard for
deploying kubernetes applications so you
can deploy it via a helm chart as well I
wouldn't recommend taking a picture of
this and trying to run those commands so
from a build perspective there is a
plugin as well that you can use to use
Jenkins for CI and CD and basically what
you need to do is the image list
configure a few settings whether if you
want to build the fail or not and then
also how many retries you want and plus
some user information
and this is what it will look like when
the evaluation comes through you can see
that there is one stop action one
warning action and zero go actions and
so it stopped because it had one of the
stops actions triggered and then it will
also give you the actually the report as
well right in the Jenkins UI they also
talked about you also can do as I said
the admission controllers as well and
there's a mission controller that they
actually that odd the on corn team ships
you can also use it with cystic and
Falco so what you can do and I'm going
to talk about Falco here in a minute so
if this doesn't necessarily make sense
to you but you can basically what we
wrote a little integration that what
will happen is is it will automatically
generate Falco rules based upon images
that are kind of I don't want to use the
term on a list that you don't want
blacklisted but I would I don't know
another term besides blacklisted but
that's a term we should probably stop
using so we should basically what will
happen is is then when we see one of
these container images try to get ran
will send a notification and let someone
know and so I'll cover a Falco here in
just a second alright so in the runtime
security side let's talk about service
admit so service admittance I'm not
going to cover it but basically what it
is is what's allowed to run a service so
what's what's allowed to be part of that
service about micro service and does the
application actually fit somebody who I
want joining that particular service no
it's this secure secrets are all about
how applications authenticate
authenticate so basically how do we get
secrets into the container so using
tools like hash II corpse vault and
other things like that as well
there's anomaly detection so how do I
know if my runtime environment is being
tampered with you can also think of this
as kind of traditional
intrusion detection system as well and
then forensics what happened if
something was compromised as well so I'm
gonna focus on the anomaly detection
side here so it gets interesting when we
think about the changes that containers
have brought us so because what's in a
container is much more well scoped as to
just what you need to actually run the
application you have a much smaller
footprint and because you have as much
smaller footprint when you kind of have
this abstraction of a container you you
know what's - what what you expect so
you know that the container is going to
maybe write to these particular
directories you know that these
processes are going to be running and
you know that with high degree of
certainty that it should only ever be
listening on these ports and if you
start to violate those things and maybe
further in the bill earlier in the build
process you detect that all of a sudden
we're listening on a new port you can
stop that build and say okay like we're
listening on a new port now when were
you gonna tell me that we're needed to
add this said to our rules and you can
use these types of anomaly detection to
say that this container should never get
shipped forward so let me introduce
falco to you falco is a cnc a sandbox
project focused on runtime security for
cloud native platforms it allows you to
detect abnormal behaviors in your
applications in your containers and in
your hosts we're also adding in a lot of
integrations around how do we pull data
from other sources as well so one thing
that we're going to be doing very very
shortly is adding in kubernetes audit
events and allow you to write rules
around those kubernetes audit events so
anytime somebody hits the kerbin Eddy's
API and performs an action will get that
event over to us and then you can apply
rules to it to decide what action you
want to take or whether if you just want
to log it it detects suspicious activity
defined by a set of rules and I'll show
you that here in a second it uses our
sister open source project sistex
filtering an expression language so you
kind of saw the expression language
earlier on the screen but I'll go
through that here in just a second
what's different about Cystic is that it
uses I'm sorry what's different about
Falco is that it also leverages sistex
container
Orchestrator supports so we can see on
the host operating system depending upon
what container runtime you're running
what si grips have been created what
namespaces have been created the
abstraction around what a container
actually is on the host operating system
will detect that and will be able to
give you information around the
container ID the image name and all of
that information that you expect from an
Orchestrator perspective will also pull
that information in from the
orchestrator so will tell you what pot
it's running in what services namespace
all that information as well now when a
rule is violated what will happen is is
that you can alert to various locations
to file standard out syslog or arbitrary
programs as well and that's another area
that we're going to be improving as well
as giving you more destinations and
places to go and push the information to
what a lot of companies do with Falco is
they just use it as another mechanism
where they log a lot of information and
so there might be rules violations that
are going off that are more notices or
informational and they use this to
actually establish what they can
consider normal for their environment
and then they can use this information
as well if there isn't incident and they
can aggregate it with other information
as well to find out what actually
happened in the environment at that time
and as I said it's open source so anyone
can contribute rules or improvements so
it's some quick examples for you
so the first one somebody's spawned a
shell inside of a container so maybe
they're doing troubleshooting maybe
they're not doing troubleshooting but
generally speaking running a shell
inside of a container if you're not
doing troubleshooting is bad you can
then go and update the container and
change it from the immutable image that
it's based on and then that never gets
back into the environment into the
actual container build environment and
now you've made a change that nobody
knows about when that container dies the
courts that change is gone and so if you
need to make that change again then you
have to run a shell again but it's also
a kind of a common point where
somebody's going interactive in an
environment that's not supposed to be
interactive overriding system binaries
so FD directory in that list and they're
trying to do a right so we don't
necessarily care if someone's reading
from that director
but if somebody's trying to write to the
bin directory that's a problem
containers tried to change its namespace
so it's trying to escalate its
privileges so that it could go and
communicate with other containers and
that another namespace and then we don't
care if docker assisted tries to change
the namespace we only care if other
things change the namespace and then you
know trying to hide yourself so
somebody's trying to create something
under /dev that's not a block device and
that's essentially what that does yes
then it is not Devon all so you're not
trying to write to Devon all and of
course the one that happens on all of
your micro services environments
especially your cloud environments that
somebody's trying to access the webcam
it's a joke because hopefully you don't
run so the way Falco works from an
architecture perspective there is a
kernel module that kernel module
basically takes back a stream of system
calls so these are the low-level calls
that users and applications use to
access things like disk memory network
run commands other things like that as
well that stream of system calls goes
through some processing libraries that
we borrow from the Cystic open source
project and then we create a stream of
events that goes through the Falco rules
engine and if there's an alert then we
go and send that alert out to the
various notification channels we're
actually making some changes here to
where we're going to be much more
generic at the bottom so not only will
we have a tap into the kernel but we'll
have a generic HTTP endpoint where you
can then pull data from other sources as
well and then we've also made some code
changes to make it much easier to add in
other endpoints where you can pull data
from directly as well that'll still go
through the processing libraries and the
rules engine but it gives you a lot more
flexibility and a lot more that you can
monitor with Falco
there's excuse me
there's 25 rules available out of the
box and they're really kind of focused
on common container best practices so is
somebody writing a file in banner at C
directories reading of sensitive files
binaries being executed other than your
command or entry point so here's an
example of a rule so we have a couple
different things that make up a rule
file the first one our macros the macros
are essentially shortcuts so if you need
to use an expression over and over and
over again then you should go once
you've used it in more than one rule you
should probably create a macro and so
this is basically going to define what
our binary directories are so we have
this list bin espen user bin user s bin
and then basically what will happen is
when we call the macro which we do down
here a little bit further that
expression will get put in the place of
of the macro now we also have lists as
well so this list right here of shell
binaries we could have made a list here
and included the list for been
directories instead of calling out the
list directly but the list allows you to
list out things and then you can use it
later so here you can see we'd actually
don't use this list but here you can see
that we have a bin directory and the
event Direction is exit so this
basically means that the system call has
exited and we're getting a return value
back from the system call and somebody
opens something for writing and it's not
a package management process well you
know in theory you probably wouldn't
want this because you shouldn't run
package managers and containers either
but so this would actually detect this
and then it would send an alert out that
a file below a known binary directory
was open for writing you can use these
same variables that you're using these
fields in the output as well so we'll
get the actual user name we'll get the
command line and we'll get the file that
was open for writing as well so let's
talk a little bit about how you can use
Falco and then I'll wrap up with a quick
demo so a couple different things one
thing that we did was create what's
called a response engine with some
secure
playbooks for falco so with detect
abnormal events with falco will publish
the events to a pub sub service such as
nats and then you can have subscribers
that subscribe to various topics so
every Falco alert is has a
classification and notice informational
critical so forth and you can subscribe
to specific topics as so if for instance
you just want to take notice events or
critical events then you just subscribe
to that particular topic on the pub sub
server and then those subscribers can
then take action so for instance this
Falco's star could be subscribed to buy
a service that's going back and login
everything in something like elastic
search for you and then the subscribers
can take actions they can do things like
kill an offending pod you can taint a
worker node to prevent scheduling so you
can leave that node around but it will
no longer get any more workloads because
maybe you're not sure about how far
container isolation was broken or if it
was broken at all it can isolate a pod
with networking policy as well so this
keeps the pod around as well so then you
can go back and do forensics inside of
those containers running the pod or you
could do things like sending a
notification via slack and we've
published all of these on our github
repository which I'll have a link
towards the end so basically the way it
works is that Falco will pull the data
and events from the kubernetes
environment we have a little sidecar
that Falco is using to push the events
into Nats and then what we did was Kubb
list functions so Kubla says it
functions as a service or service
framework and we use cout bliss to go
and subscribe to the messaging server
and then also to take action in our
environment there's a link for you to a
good blog post around open source
container runtime security it covers
Falco and encore a lot more as well
alright so I think this is something
that we should look at more as an
industry so functions for operations so
it's really really easy to write simple
functions to
not only to security events but also
operational events as well in your
environment a great example of this is
that if you're using AWS you can have
lambda functions in your cloud formation
templates and those lambda functions can
then go and do things and query
information in your environment and you
can pull that back into the cloud
formation template to make it more
dynamic you can also have functions
though that can see behaviors in your
environment to then go and take action
so in this case we wrote these functions
to the Lita pod to notify teams to log
events as well and the nice thing is is
you can have multiple subscribers to the
same event and each subscriber could
take a different action based upon how
you want to slice and dice it the other
thing is is that you get small reusable
components and if you need to make a
change to one piece of your automation
you're just changing one function you're
not having to change your entire
automation platform that you're using so
I think this is something that is
security people we should probably look
at a little bit more about how you can
write these functions to take action on
security events you can use also use
file code to kind of build a assim this
is an area that I want to work more on I
was having a good conversation with a
friend last night around how some of the
logging providers are really really
focusing in on this area and making tons
of money on it and so I feel like it's a
right place for people in the Falco
community to contribute in Kabana
dashboards and other things like that as
well to build this but with a
combination of elasticsearch fluent D in
Cabana you can collect all of the
security events from Falco then you can
easily do aggregation and reporting of
these events across various other pieces
of information as well and this is a
horrible graphic of what it looks like
but the cool thing is is that if you've
never used Cabana which you can then do
so you can see all of the rules and
which rules are firing we see rules by
priority as well and so you can click on
any one of these and then down at the
bottom when you build this you can have
all of the events that actually
correspond to that so it allows you to
use the graphical interface to present
information and then you can easily
drill down into that interface to get
more information about
what the actual events are that are
causing these problems I think there's a
lot more that we could do in this in the
community and it's probably something
I'm going to add on my roadmap to prove
in the community so I'll do a quick demo
here if everyone's happy with me all
right so let me show you some rules real
quick for this particular demo so how
many people have ever find found a
Bitcoin miner running on their
production systems you don't need to
raise your hand this is becoming more
and more of a common kind of thing that
people are doing so they don't really
care about getting data out of your
environment they just want to use and
steal your CPU power and so this will
actually detect that somebody is running
in a node no tap front-end so here we're
using metadata from kubernetes and so
we're if we're in this namespace and we
have this pod of this particular label
then this rule is going to apply so you
can see here that I'm using that macro
and somebody spawned a process and the
container ID does not equal host let me
scroll over there we go
and then you can also see that the
processes command line contains stratum
TCP write which is a common a common
protocol that you use to connect back to
miner pools so if anyone ever runs a
command with that in the processes
command line then an alert would be
fired and then the other thing that we
have here is that you can list out kind
of common ports that miners are using
the more popular pools and then you can
basically define a macro here that says
if the port is in minor ports and then
if any outbound connection to one of
those ports gets fired then we'll throw
a critical alert as well now what we're
going to do and what we're going to run
to actually take action to kind of give
you an example of how simple these
functions can be that you can write so I
wrote a really really simple Python
script that basically allows you to
delete the pod so it's going to get the
priority it's going to get some other
put fields that falco has since over and
if the priority is critical then we're
going to log a message and then we're
going to find what namespace this pod
lives in and then we're going to go and
delete the particular pod that's okay
because if it's a stateless application
it's not storing data then we could do
that and then kubernetes will just
reschedule that pod and spin it back up
so let me make sure my environment see
if I can do this
yeah it hasn't been too bad all right so
you can see I've got a Falco deployed to
my environment and then I'm gonna run
down here coupe CTO get pods for the
particular namespace I care about and
I'm just going to have that in a loop
and then while that runs I'm gonna do a
coop CTL get pods and I need to see
where it's actually running all right
all right so come back to the window I
want so here I have Falco running
Falco's Bend so we have a daemon set we
have a helmet art that you can use as
well to deploy Falco if I just run a
coop CTL get pods and I need to see what
hosts
so you can see that there's some
activity that falco is already detected
so it'll see a lot of stuff it'll see as
kubernetes
is bringing up a pod and other
information like that as well you can
see that a file was open for writing
namespaces are being changed and other
information like that as well so either
you may want that information you can
turn it off in your log file if you
don't want it by just changing the log
level that you care about so in this
environment what I'm gonna do is this
command never ran all right well you'll
have to imagine with me so I'm going to
do a coop CTL exec and I'm going to get
into this particular front-end
and so I got a shell on the container
and you can see right away that the
message was sent across that a shell was
spawned on the container and then I'm
just gonna do a curl stratum and this is
gonna fail because the protocol is not
there oh I didn't work there's a bug in
this a demo environment so I should have
been killed if I go and do other things
though if I touch a file so if I do
touch something under then you can see
that a file below a known binary
directory was open for writing and so
forth so then you should have action
taken so the container should have been
killed it worked this morning when I
tested it but this is this is falco and
how you can kind of use Falco's so let
me just jump back to the slides
so in closing we're an open source
project iron core is also an open source
project as well we have public slack
teams that you can participate in as
well the Falco website and then the
github repositories for both of the
projects as well which you can find all
of our code there as well as some other
repos as well that kind of give you
additional rules and other things like
that as well so thank you very much I'll
be around a little bit for questions
you