all right we're gonna go ahead and get
started here so welcome everybody we're
here on behalf of all state to present
you guys sedated quick introductions I'm
Simeon Cody air I'm the project lead on
the sedated project I'm also a lead
application security engineer at
all-state joined by my colleague Dennis
Kennedy he's the lead developer on the
sedated project and he's also an
application security engineer at
all-state quick agenda for what we're
gonna talk about today first we'll go
through the promise aim and we'll talk a
little bit about the whys you know why
are we talking about this what is the
problem statement we'll go into the
solution we'll do some demos we'll show
you some source code go through some of
the processes that we coupled the source
code with then we're gonna get a little
bit into performance and future goals
and then talk about open sourcing okay
so I want to start with a wasa top ten
hopefully everybody's heard of that
number three in particular sensitive
data exposure so this is when your
application deals with sensitive data
like PII pH I PCI data or anything that
you consider within your company to be
sensitive data restricted confidential
data anything like that so it's on the
list because you should be protecting it
properly whether it be in transit when
you're transmitting it across the line
you should be doing it securely or when
you're storing it you should be storing
it securely you should have proper
access control mechanisms in place for
that data so know it's number three and
lists it's important and we're gonna tie
this together why are we talking about
this and our solution to address some of
the promising so I want to talk real
quick about a company to exploits that
they had so May 2014 this company had an
exploit where they had 50,000 drivers
license data leaked and then in October
2016 unfortunately they had 57 million
users data leaked and 600,000 drivers
since data does anybody know what
company this is by chance anybody
besides Joe in the back who is it Joe
it's it's it's super so this is uber so
we're not here to pick on uber or
wellness together we're trying to secure
our data right but we wanted to talk
about the particulars of what actually
happened in in both of these exploits
and this leads right into the problem
statement that we wanted to talk about
today so how how exactly did this happen
so in May 2014 their database key
unfortunately was on a publicly
accessible github page the hacker got
hold of it found it and in they go so
they asked that's how they access the
data and then in 2016 again it was a
database key they had the database key
but this time it was inside of a private
private repository but the hacker was
able to gain access to that repo and
once they gained access that repo there
was the key sitting in their repo so we
want to talk about this in particular
this was a you know this is a database
cases like the master you know key to
your kingdom right or your data it's
sensitive data and you want to have you
know defense-in-depth you want to have
multiple layers that an attacker has to
jump through to gain access so with with
sensitive data like this we definitely
would recommend keep it out of your repo
things like database Keys private keys
passwords user and anything like that
store it some results in this instance
you know maybe on the server that the
apps running on maybe you have an
environment variable where this key is
sitting or somewhere else but not in the
source code so this leads into our
problem statement then we wanted to talk
to you about today how do we prevent
sense sensitive data from being stored
and get so data like this or passwords
or digital certificates things like that
how do we prevent that from being stored
and get so the solution that we're here
today to present sedated so sedated
stands for sensitive enterprise data
analyzer to eliminate disclosure I want
to talk about the flow of sedated how
sedated work what exactly does it do so
in this diagram here on the left hand
side you have a developer on the right
hand side you have your your git server
in this example this is github
enterprise this could be get lab or this
could just be a get server that's
running so the developers coding their
code right there constantly coding and
pushing things to the repository so in
this example the developer codes
something it follows the yellow arrow
pushes new code instead of it going
straight into the repository it's going
to hit sedate at the black box now if
you're already familiar with this it's a
pre receive hook running on the get
instance so technically that's what
sedate it is it's a pre receive hook so
what it's going to do is this gonna fire
before it goes to the repository and
it's going to scan all the deltas so
whatever code the developer is pushing
it's gonna scan that and it's gonna see
if there's sensitive data in there if
there is no sensitive data it'll follow
the green arrow and it'll get pushed
into the repository that's happy path
right but if it does identify sensitive
data in this push it will forcibly
reject it that's gonna follow the red
arrow and that code with that sensitive
data will not end up in the repository
and again that's the problem statement
that we're after today with the solution
with that okay so that's sweet thank you
Mew
yeah
the
this
nothing I'm or it's a it's a previous
evoke so it sits in the server
all right and let's take a look at our
demo here ok so what we're gonna do this
is a pretty empty repo our demo repo we
just got to read me in it we've got a
clean working tree no we're gonna do is
we're just gonna create a simple file
just hello world Python file and you can
see it over in the text editor of there
jump over there and we'll just throw
some code in we'll do a just a print
simple print statement hello world so
this is going to be a cleans as a happy
path so this is no sensitive data if
you've had gots sedated turn out on your
repo and this is what's gonna happen so
you're gonna do your git add and then
you're gonna do your git commit an
important note is the sedated won't fire
on this get commit so it's not going to
fire here this is just creating the
commit ID unless we do that now we've
got the commit idea now is when sedate
it's gonna fire when we do they get push
so we're gonna do the push right there
and then once we try to push this is
where sedate it's gonna scan that for
delta's for anything any sensitive data
and if there's no sensitive data you get
this happy credential panda right there
so they pretty clear and you can see on
the bottom push was accepted so this is
was a happy path so everything's good
good to go so on this one here we've got
the sad path yeah this one is the sad
path ok so on this one we're going to
actually add a hard-coded credential in
it and we'll see what happens
so the creds dot config file create it
will jump back there we will add just a
hard-coded password a password is my
password
one two three yep Murr save jump back
into the terminal and we're gonna do the
same as before
go do your git add git commit creating
the commit ID and again
sedate it's not going to fire on the
commit on this commit it's only gonna
fire when you try to push it up to the
server add commit there we go and now
when we do our git push you're gonna see
sedated fire again
but this time when it fires see a much
different error message and you've
killed the credential Panda and now he's
no he's dead
so you can see the in the error message
we're actually showing the developer the
commit ID that has because you can push
multiple commit IDs in it so the commit
ID the file and then the actual
violation itself were outputting
straight to the developer right away and
the to the console we show them how many
violations and then clearly a push
rejected and then another handy thing is
at the bottom here you can add in your
organization's URL for instructions on
exactly how you want the developer to
remediate when violations are found you
can see in the bottom it took 17
milliseconds for this to run to run
through will pass it back over to you
you see me so one thing we wanted to
talk about as we're open sourcing this
and going through that is how we combine
this code that we're showing you with
processes this code on its own will do
things right and it's gonna look for
things but we married this up with some
processes that we're gonna walk you
through that
really create an overall robust solution
to this problem you'll see here in a
second why this is necessary so we
wanted to talk about those processes
with you and explain those one in
particular the whitelist process so this
is false positives if you go and you
turn this thing on in your organization
it is inevitable that you're gonna have
false positives
no matter how extensive the Reg X's are
you're probably going to have instances
where it you know Flags one and it's a
false positive so we need to create a
way to deal with that
so this is our whitelist flow that we've
developed within it so we want to walk
through that so on the left hand side
here you have a developer he's pushing a
commit number one commit one two three
and let's say that that has a false
positive in it something that's sedated
thinks it's a password but it's not it's
gonna get rejected so number two sedated
will not allow it to go into the
repository but this is a false positive
so the developer sees this CC error
message and he says this is not actually
a password this was flagged incorrectly
so the next step is the developer can go
number three they can raise a pull
request into the whitelist file so we
actually have a whitelist file it's just
a text file you put the commit ID in
there and you raise this pull request
now on the repository and and this is
kind of part of the process that were
you know coupling this with we have the
permissions set up on that repository
such that at least for us that all state
the developers themselves do not have
write access to this so they can't
whitelist themselves and that's
intentional on our part so we have a
permission set up they can raise a pull
request they can request this but only
the application security team can
actually approve that so that's number
four so the developer raises this pull
request and he says for this commit ID
this is a false positive number for the
security team reviews it and looks at it
and checks if they agree that it's a
false positive if we agree that it's a
false positive
we go ahead and approve it and merge it
and then immediately after doing that
the developer can go to number five and
just repo again so they go ahead
and they pushed one two three and
immediately sedated we'll see this is a
whitelisted commit ID and it'll go ahead
and accept it
we yeah now we're gonna go through a
kind of a step by step of what this
looks like in action so we're going to
pick up where we left off before we're
gonna create another file and this time
we're gonna add something that could be
a false positive in here you say
password equals password no quotes and
then we'll save that we'll jump back
into the terminal and then we will go
ahead and do the same thing we did
before we'll door get add and commit run
that get our commit ID and now when we
run the actual get push it's going to be
rejected the same as before but this
time the developers is gonna see the
exact same message as before this time
the developers can make well wait a
minute this this isn't a this isn't a
fault this isn't a real hard-coded
credential this is just false positives
I think if password as a variable they
see was rejected so now what they need
to do to do the pull request they need
to make some some sort of documentation
that the security team can review which
is what we put into one command which is
kind of a chain of a couple commands but
we do a get format patch which is going
to create a patch txt file which will
give some context to the lead or
whoever's reviewing this pull request
and it's going to also do a push and
then it's going to create its take all
that output from the push and put it
into a hook out txt file so this one
command is going to create two files for
them to include in their pull request so
that they can use as documentation so
when you go ahead and run this you'll
see the exact same output as before but
this time there were two files that were
created that they can submit for their
documentation so we'll go ahead and jump
into finder now you can see there's the
hook out file
it's in the desktop directory so we've
created that file with that command and
then we've also created the patch txt
file and you can point these wherever
you want you can customize the command
to do whatever you would like but it's
basically those two files that we use
for the documentation and then we copy
the commit ID up there that says in this
commit and we'll jump into in this case
github and to our github repo under the
commit whitelist file then we're gonna
go ahead and add that commit ID that
shows us the head of Violation you can
include in there whatever commit message
you want to go with it saying it's
reason why it's not a heart go tarantula
and then in here you don't want to
commit don't allow them to commit
directly to master so you create a
branch they submit that and then now in
this portion of it we'll go ahead and
submit our documentation and wait for it
and boom black box of reaction and then
go ahead and add the hook out about txt
file as well throw that in there and
drop it in so now they've got the
documentation to go along with their
pull request they go ahead and create it
and this is where the developers job
stops and now you would be the app sec
engineer or whoever you want reviewing
these pull requests it's gonna go in and
look at these files this is what was
included in the patch dot txt file this
will have a lot more context and do
exactly what was included in their
commits will have the commit ID the file
the violations and things of that nature
and then the hook out dot txt file is
helpful because it will show the app sec
engineer exactly what the developer was
seeing in their error message so there's
no miscommunication or developer trying
to explain something to the app psych
engineer that is maybe hard for them to
verbalize so if the app psych engineer
reviews it says it's all good they can
go ahead and merge it I mean if not they
can put some comments in there reject it
what-have-you but if it's all good
they'll go ahead and click merge and
then they
add that it's verified but whatever
comments you want the them to put in
there I'll merge it and then as soon as
you see the pull request successfully
merged and closed d developer will be
able to push their code again they don't
have to do anything additional they
don't have to rewrite anything they can
go ahead and just run their get push
command again and then as soon as they
run that you'll see that their message
will be a little bit different but their
push will be accepted you'll see that it
has been whitelisted you'll see that it
shows the community that was whitelisted
and then of course that the push was
accepted so it's it's that simple it's
pretty straightforward it's just a
standard pull request that an app stick
engineer reviews to get around that and
then assume you wanted to add something
to that just a quick comment on this we
wanted to mention you know there's
always room for improvement so here in
our instructions we're very clear for us
in our instructions link to the
developer you know make sure that this
pull request that you're raising is
truly a false positive we don't want
them actually taking and generating
documentation like this that actually
has a password and then creating a pull
request and attaching a file to that
poet dress that has a password in it
that's what we're trying to prevent in
the first place right now there's room
for growth here we're working on things
like maybe instead of having them attach
that file to the pull request we haven't
put it on a secure server with very
limited access you know what the only
the application security team sees just
in case they don't follow the
instructions and there is a password in
it um so we that's a caveat room for
growth right room for improving there we
just want to mention that exactly I mean
you would hope common sense would kick
in and if they wouldn't submit a pull
request or something that was a
hard-coded credential but can't always
rely on that so here's the look at the
source code just kind of a brief snippet
a snippet of it the kind of the meat and
potatoes of how it's working you can see
line 89 but the
top there it's just looping through all
the commit ID so you can have 1 10 20
100 however many commit IDs are included
in the push it's going to go through
each one of those then line 90 is where
it's going to go through all the deltas
so everything that was added in that
push it's gonna grep against the the
regex list which we mentioned earlier
and it's if it flags anything it'll
check it in lines 99 and 100 to see if
it's in the whitelist file if it is in
the whitelist file then it'll add it add
the whitelisted commit change the
variable break out of the loop and then
jump to the next commit ID and then from
there if it's not if it's not
whitelisted will jump down to 107 and
below where it's going to add it to the
violation list it's going to have a
different output print out the file name
and then add the file violation and
total violation variables and then back
up the line 90 where we mentioned the
Reg X's this is kind of a brief snippet
of some of the Reg X's we've got for it
right now we're at 75 or so reg X's
we're always looking to add make them
better these are just kind of some some
general ones that we've got and we're
always trying to like I mentioned add
and improve modifying them but that's
kind of that can be a tricky thing to do
when you're messing with so many reg X's
so you don't mess up something else
which is why we've we've created you the
unit testing suite and with this we can
run this whenever we need to anytime we
make a change to a reg X we can then run
our reg X unit test cases run those
against it right now we've got over 400
test cases that include pushes that
should be accepted and pushes that
should be rejected so we're checking to
make sure we're catching what we're
supposed to and not catching what we
don't want to catch so any so we can
make changes and modifications to our
reg X's with confidence that we're not
breaking something else that we have not
intended and in addition to that we also
have the integration tests for the
sedated itself the script so anytime we
make changes to that we can run our
integration test makes
nothing was broken make sure all the
whitelist functionality is there make
sure that the the regex is work as
supposed they're supposed to make sure
it's rejecting and accepting and so
forth and what we're doing at all-state
is we got a we have a Jenkins job that
kicks off anytime we make changes to our
production repo that's gonna run all the
tests all these tests via web hooks so
if we get anything negative back we'll
know to what we need to do to fix it and
to not have an in production so
implementation of sedated there's three
levels you can start enterprise level
which is gonna turn it on just force
turn it on on every single repo and your
entire organization you can also turn it
on at the org level like if you have a
specific org within your enterprise that
maybe deals more with sensitive
sensitive data API keys things of that
nature
then then others you could just turn it
on to that specific org or you can go as
granular as the repo just turned on
individual repos themselves and as Samia
mentioned already it is a get pre
receive hook so anywhere that you can
enable a get previous evoke you can use
sedated so it doesn't have to be github
it can be get lab get whatever else if
you can use a git previously poke you
can you can leverage this and in
addition to that since it is a preview
see folk they've got a five second
timeout so you've got a five second
window for this whole thing to run
through before it hits a timeout so
that's why in performance it's very high
priority for us so we scripted a lot of
it with performance in mind yes so we
have some numbers here we'd like to
share with you this is just based on
what you know our server our github
enterprise server and how it performed
so there's two in particular here I kind
of wanted to show you the first one in
green so this is an example of one file
and that one file has nearly six hundred
forty thousand lines of code and it
deltas change changes in that one file
to put that in a little bit of context I
don't know if I'd
code that much code in five years total
that's a ton of code six hundred forty
thousand lines of code for me to just
knock out but let's pretend you did send
that through sedated it's gonna take two
point two seconds based on our numbers
that we've been running well within the
five-second window so it's it's pretty
fast the way it's performing right now
another number I want to throw out is in
orange so this is two hundred and fifty
files and each file has two hundred
lines of code change again I'd say this
is a fairly obnoxious use case you know
when was the last time you waited to
commit you know after 250 files that he
modified why didn't he commit sooner I
would say that's you know well let's say
you did that's 50,000 lines of code
total and it takes it can it can bump
through our 75 reg X's scan all this
code for sensitive data and it did all
that in point eight seconds so it's
performing it's performing pretty good
for us it meets all our needs any
average use case I would say it's well
within the limit now we did want to
mention if it's not within the limit
let's say we hit that five-second window
you're gonna have to put a little bit of
effort in to hit that five-second window
but let's say you did maybe an example
of it is you take a you take a
repository and you clone it and then you
take that code and you copy it over to
another repository and you you push it
well now sedated is scanning all the
deltas and we're talking about a brand
new fresh repository and that you just
copy and pasted you know from one to
another there might be a lot of code in
there we did set up along with commit ID
whitelisting we set up a repo
whitelisting so there is the ability for
this other repository for you to put it
into a repo whitelist file and sedated
will see it inside of there and it will
not scan the deltas now use this
sparingly at higher
recommend that if you do this you know
do some sort of offline checks and
balances to make sure that the
repository doesn't have sensitive data
in it before you push it there's other
solutions to this
there's truffle hog for instance you
know that can scan it you could you know
scan it with truffle hog so you have
some level of confidence if there's a
sense of data in it but the point is you
can get you know past this five-second
window this issue by white listing the
repository and with that we're gonna
kind of go back to where we started so
we're open sourcing sedated how we're
excited to be able to do that and have
this opportunity part of the reason
we're excited about that
so we're coupling up with OWASP turn it
into a project that's in the works right
now and open sourcing it not only to get
it out there for people to use but also
there's room for growth right and
there's room for us to improve this
thing and so we want to get it out there
and hopefully have others contribute to
this and make it better and use it so
we're excited about that yeah we've got
some future goals for this as well but
before I jump into those just so I'm
just wanted to mention that this is a
preventative control not a detective
control so it's not going to go through
your entire get history on every push
it's just going through those Delta's
just so just to be clear just about it's
preventing new credentials or hard-coded
things from getting added into your
repos and with that we've got some good
future goals in mind we'd really love
the community support with we're really
excited to get this out get you guys
involved one of the things we're always
looking to make it more performant right
as we mentioned the five-second timeout
five-second window there's ways we know
it could be better it could be faster it
could work better and for any ideas for
any improvements on that we're really
hoping to get some some community
support with and feedback working on
improving the the regex is maybe even
enhancing them with some sort of
intelligence engine that would be pretty
awesome
even customizing the regex is for if
it's a Java file then we'd use the Java
rec regex as if it's a JavaScript file
uses JavaScript projects
what have you yeah no files config files
so you can really minimize your false
positives in your workload there and
we're also you looking to add test cases
that's a pretty simple thing just
there's a string of something you don't
want it to catch something you do want
it to catch making sure it catches those
things things of that nature
well thanks for joining us please be
sure to keep an eye out for the new
sedated a wasp project enjoy the rest of
epic I am curious about the ability to
customize this yeah where I work we have
lots of different authentication tokens
and mechanisms yeah we that may only be
specific to our org so how friendly is
it to adding more records that literally
just look like an array of Reg X's is
that that's all there is right now I
have to modify that code for Iza config
to get a custom search pattern you could
you could modify other reg exes however
you want like if you only want it to
catch certain things certain strings you
can you can wipe out all the Reg X's we
have in there now and just have it for
yours but it's very specific very
customized you can tailor it to your
needs and it's just going to catch those
and it's gonna have that exact same
behavior okay you can modify the Reg X's
to even one if you want to just want to
catch this one thing yeah but that reg X
list look like it's embedded in the code
of the the project itself versus like an
additional config file somewhere we look
at that in addition to whatever like a
general config
okay good yeah I don't want to break the
top itself from messing up the Reg acts
okay thank you yeah and there's there's
error messages as well if the regex is
do break it'll flash something up on the
console that'll show you that they hate
the Reg X's are broke so you have
immediate feedback with that as well
okay thanks again thank you