I'm gonna get started here I'm gonna
today gonna be talking about 200 oz
tools that helps with penetration
testing coverage so good afternoon
everyone
so my name is Ken parole
I am I wear two hats I'm the CTO for a
code DX
Cody X is a system that allows you to
bring together all of your application
security testing activities so static
analysis dynamic analysis code reviews
all into a central console we have a
booth outside and we can provide some
more information on that I'm also a
principal investigator for the secure
decisions secure decisions does research
and development in the area of
application security we have some
contracts with the Department of
Homeland Security and the tools I'm
going to talk about today we're funded
through DHS code DX itself was also
funded initially through DHS and then we
transmit transitioned that into a
commercial product securitizations is a
division of apply visions that's the
parent company it's been around for over
30 years they do custom software
development I'm based in New York I am
the project lead for the two projects we
talk about today code pulse and attack
surface detector I've been in software
development for for over 20 years I
started out doing C++ development and
most recently being helping people
develop more secure software so a quick
agenda I'm gonna talk a little bit about
the tools from high-level talk about the
white high penetration tester but the
typical workflow is like and we're gonna
talk a little bit about the attack
surface and what that means and how
these tools can help with that
so the two tools we're gonna go into
depth on to that os code pulse we talked
about the challenges it addresses how it
works provided a short demo and then the
attack surface detector is going through
you know what's the blotches purpose and
give you some highlights of the features
and finally wrap up where to learn more
information and do some Q&A I hope that
you know after this talk you'll able to
see how these tools can help make black
bus penetration testing less
Oh bake all right so an overview the two
projects are code pulse and attack
surface detector I've been to several
talks where you know a lot of projects
are kind of really early on these are
pretty mature projects the both OS
projects open source fully freely
available code pulse has been around for
about four years we just recently made
some a lot of improvements to it it's
basically a way to instrument an
application while it's being tested and
get a sense for how much code coverage
you're getting the attack surface
detector is also a No Mas project we
actually collaborated with denimm group
initially on this effort through the DHS
contract extending on some of the work
that they've done and that helps you
figure out the attack surface that's
exposed in the application we're gonna
go into more depth about that the output
of that can be used to precede tools
like zap and burr so that it can have a
better understanding of the application
and do a more thorough testing and we
actually use the attack surface now
within code pulse and I'll demonstrate
that as well so these two are working
together
alright so whitehat penetration testing
that's the core users that we're
addressing also known as ethical factor
hackers or you know ah speak they're the
breakers the ones that go in and try and
attack an application anyone here
consider themselves a white hat pen
tester awesome cool so you know you have
a little some disadvantages right you
your job is to find all of the
vulnerabilities where you know a hacker
just has to find one and you have
limited time compared to what the
hackers have out there and if you're
working closely with the development
team they started to keep keep up with
them right they're developing code
really rapidly and that's a challenge so
there's a few advantages that you can
have if you have access to the bytecode
or the source code these tools can help
out with that and I'll also talk about
some ways around that if you don't have
direct access to the source code anyone
here familiar with zap ok burp suite I
just use it really popular penetration
testing tools
can be used manually or automated a lot
of these solutions we'll talk about
today can also work with tools like web
inspect or a kinetics or nets Parker or
even dooms strict manual reviews or if
you have an outside penetration testing
organization that is doing testing for
you you want to get an idea of how much
coverage you're getting these tools can
help out with that let's talk a little
bit about the the typical workflow for a
penetration tester we have a web
application that's probably accessing
some database where you have your
sensitive information as a pen tester
typically the first step is to try and
figure out how to authenticate you know
you have to know different users and
different user roles that are associated
with the application if you don't have
the right credentials you're not gonna
really get too far with being able to
test the application and then do
endpoint and numeration so a lot of
times you'll manually map out the
application go to every single link on
the page go through the forms go through
multiple step forms like you know check
out processes have multiple steps so
that you can build up that site map in
order for the tools to perform their
testing for you to do more thorough
manual testing then typically go through
the automated spidering and crawling
process so tools like sap and burp you
can just point them out at the website
it'll automatically figure out all of
the different end points and the better
you do that manual mapping the the
better the tool will be able to do to to
crawl out further then you can do brute
forcing or forced browsing so this is a
way of the tools trying to find unlinked
end points in the application basically
there's a dictionary of different
keywords that a little try on put on the
URLs that you know other apps might use
but a lot of times this is hit earnest
if you're gonna be able to find one of
these when these hidden end points from
this end point enumeration process out
pops the attack surface so the attack
surface is how an attacker can get into
the application to get to the sensitive
data that you're trying to protect and
once the attack surface is is out there
then you can go through the
vulnerability discovery process doing
passive
active or fussing let's talk a little
bit about the attack surface a little
bit more I'm gonna use a house as an
analogy so if you look at a house you
know how can someone get into your house
you know maybe they'll try the front
door the side door they'll look for open
windows so these are ways of getting and
getting to sensitive information with a
web application that's typically the
URLs that the application is exposing
like a login form and depending on you
know how that login form is used the
attacker can get in too in the
application in different ways but the
open window is just kind of the starting
point for getting at the sensitive
information there's different paths that
one can take through a house or an
application to get to that particular
area of interest for web applications
though this is much more complex right
there's not a single floor much more
complex you have many floors and being
able to you know for if you look at this
as an application how can you know how
much coverage you're getting and where
it going within the application when
it's this complex so this is why we
developed OS code pulse if you look at
Wikipedia under web applications
security scanner you'll find this it
wasn't written by me the penetration
tester should look at the coverage at
the web application or its attack
service to know if the tool was
configured correctly or was able to
understand the web application and this
is really what code pulse is is aiming
to address being able to measure how
much coverage you're getting during your
penetration testing activities a lot of
times if you're just looking at what you
can see you don't know what you can't
see so code pulse helps with several
different things it'll tell you if
you've reached all of the application as
you're doing actions within the
application you can see which parts of
the source code were executed so similar
to the house analogy where you're you
know performing different ways of trying
to get in how you can get different
different parts the same thing you can
do in real time to be able to see
much coverage you're getting and where
you're going within the app based on the
actions that you're performing you'll be
able to compare different tools to see
which ones are getting better coverage
if you have multiple testers that are
doing testing you can compare how well
they're doing or which parts of the app
they're they're testing more most
important it helps you tune your test
coverage your testing tools so a lot of
the tools need to be tuned for the
application or just tuned for themselves
to get better coverage you can use that
for this and then communicate the
testing coverage to others so you know
helps with coverage gaps tuning the
applications and tools and then
communicating the results to others so a
code pulse is primarily a code coverage
tool now there's other solutions out
there that will be able to check code
coverage but this was really developed
specifically for penetration testing
activities the other tools are primarily
static where you do all your testing and
then you come back and you look at kind
of a flat list of what was covered but
code pulse is a real time and very
visual presentation of the application
under testing and you know the old adage
that a picture's worth a thousand words'
is is what was something true for what
we're dealing with with code pulse and
it allows you to really see a whole
application in a single view so in a
nutshell code pulse is a real-time code
coverage visualization tool for
penetration testing activities
so how code pulse works and you have
your penetration tester looking at an
application in this case it's it's
webgoat and that's a black box
perspective you can't really see what's
going on inside with a code pulse agent
you install this within the application
we have support for Java and.net and
what this will help you provide is real
time code coverage information so
turning that black box into glass box
that you can actually see what's going
on inside so that provides transparency
it provides feedback into your testing
and helps with tuning your testing to
get better coverage so this is a picture
of code pulse each
each box here represents a method within
the application and it's grouped by the
classes and the namespaces that are
involved and as you test the application
the boxes will highlight and just like
in the house scenario you'll be able to
see where within the application you're
going during your testing activity so
this is kind of like a blueprint for
your software so let's look at a
coverage scenario I took webgoat and
Waze app and I was monitoring it during
my testing activities with code balls I
launched zap I pointed at webgoat URL
and let it do its spidering let it do an
active scan and this was the coverage I
got
well yeah I just wasn't a boxer yeah
there's uh yeah there's one box here one
box here home box here if you look at
the tooltips on this you can see that
it's the index.jsp login JSP and the
login controller so because I didn't I
didn't log in to web go zap you know did
all this testing ran for you know a few
minutes you know you might think that
you tested the whole application but
really you didn't you know you just you
just tested the login page and you
weren't able to break that so the
nighttime said well then I I went in a I
logged in through his app so now I was
app knows how to log in and I ran the
spider and ran the active scan and this
was the math that was generated so I got
you know I did a better job got some
more coverage then I did manual browsing
I went through web code went through a
bunch of different forums and then now
you can see that the picture is getting
better hey so I'm getting a lot more
coverage and I could still look for
areas that I may have missed like in
here there's a in this admin class
there's a refreshed database screen I
never never went through that particular
action so zap wasn't able to to get into
that part of the thing so looking at the
you know overall results of these you
know this is the first scan second scan
and third scans and now visually you can
see that I'm getting better coverage
just with this tool you could also use
it to compare manual and automated
scanning so in within code pulse you can
have different recordings and in here
basically everything that's black is
saying that you know is found both by
manual and automated testing the things
that are in green we're just found
during my manual scan and then the
things that were in blue or just found
by automated scan so it allows you to
compare different testing approaches and
kind of get an idea where this overlap
you can compare tools so maybe you know
running to tools or evaluating tools you
can see how well they're they're they're
performing so in this case the same kind
of thing where the black is found by
both
and the colors represent what was found
by individual tools compare testers if
you're hiring outside firm you have an
internal testing team and you want to
see how much coverage they're getting
you can instrument the application and
so now I'm gonna go to a live
demonstration here I'm gonna use contoso
University which is a sample application
for Microsoft it's built on asp.net
framework and so this is code pulse
I've given code pulse the binaries and
the source code for the contoso u
application you don't need the source
code but if you provide the source code
you'll have some additional information
that I'll show you here on the left is
the application inventory this is all
how the application is broken up into
different namespaces we also integrate
dependency check and so you can drill on
that you can seeing any dependencies
that this application makes use of that
can be used full for penetration testers
to then try and exploit those
vulnerabilities like the Apache struts
or some other vulnerability that is
known as a pen tester you can go in
there and try and exploit that
so here I've highlighted the main
package for contoso University and you
can see you know again all these boxes
are all the methods and they're grouped
by the where they are on the application
you see this whole box here is all
migration classes so that's probably not
of interest since it's not something
that can probably be touched from the
outside some stuff getting cut off again
but and then you see here that these
little icons this indicates what we've
identified as the attack surface so this
is utilizing the other two loaves
talking about the attack surface
detector and so you can highlight what
are the entry points we're open windows
for this application that attacker can
get into all right so I'm going to now
instrument the application and code
false is saying you know do you want to
associate it with this particular
project I've gone and
did that and just gonna bring up browser
here all right
let me get rid of let's focus on just
the controller package which primarily
is the attack surface for this
application
so IAS is gonna wake up here and as the
application is loaded you'll see some
things highlight in real time so you
know we just we just hit some methods
here and this is the the home controller
index method so this particular
application you can create the
departments and instructors and students
you can add and delete and stuff like
that so as I interact with the
application in real time you'll see
things start to highlight I'm actually
going to start a recording we'll call
this manual
so I'm gonna look at the the courses and
you'll see here this this kind of
represents all of the courses methods
and as I start interacting with this
application I can you'll see the
coverage start improving so we're gonna
add a new course to this College called
app sec it's a three credit course under
the computer science department and boom
so now I've hit some of those methods
we're gonna go in and let's change the
Edit it we'll make it a four credit
class instead of three and let's get rid
of calculus that wasn't fun all right so
now we're getting some more coverage I
could look at the details so pretty good
here so now we we've covered just about
all of the methods although we missed
one and that's the update course credits
method and this is this I didn't put it
in here this is from the Microsoft
application this is an unlinked endpoint
that you won't be able to find just by
navigating the application so I could
actually go in here and then because I
know it's called update course credits
so you see some index there this
basically allows you to change the
number of credits you can multiply it by
two now I've gotten full code coverage
although that's just saying at the
method level we now have the ability to
go into the line level information so
let me
look at the
the Edit method so this is to edit a
particular course
you see we hit some lines here but we
got five out of seven statements so
let's try and prove on that so we see
courses and edit so you can see up here
it takes in parameter which is the the
ID which is what it's looking for here
now if it doesn't find the ID it's gonna
go through different code path so if I
put in one thousand which I know isn't
an ID that's gonna come up as null so
now we're entering different parts of
the application and it's this is an own
it's going to throw an error saying they
couldn't find that if I put in null
you're gonna see that it's gonna try and
find that ID and it's not gonna find it
and then in real time you'll see that
that information gets highlighted in the
source code
so let's stop this recording and start
another one where this time I'm going to
run the app against the application
so I haves a party set up to connect to
this particular Apple and we're gonna
spider it so you see that you know zap
is going through its spidering process a
whole bunch of boxes are lighting up and
you know again you can see in real time
how much coverage you're getting and
once that's done just about done now I
can stop that recording and now compare
that to my manual scan that was done and
you see is that you knows that found a
lot of things but it wasn't able to find
that unlinked end point the update
course credit that was found during the
the manual review using the tool all
right so that's that was code pulse now
gonna switch over to the attack surface
detector which you start a little bit in
code pulse where you're able to
highlight the attack surface part of the
application so the problem that we're
looking to identify is to improve the
attack surface you know particularly the
endpoints that are undiscoverable by
dynamic tools unless you're using brute
forcing or if you're going through and
looking at the source code so we have an
open source solution that will help
identify the attack surface and that can
be used to proceed tools like zap and
burp so it helps to abbreviate the
testing process again you don't have to
do brute forcing you don't have to go
through a manual code review it'll help
discover unlinked endpoints so just like
we saw in that sample application for
Microsoft it has an unlined end point
that it would be extremely difficult to
find with other means and also optional
parameters like if you have a debug
parameter that's being added to the
application you'd be able to see that as
well as the data types associated with
it so just by running the attack surface
detector you get all that information
about the attack surface that can then
be used to proceed tools like zap and
burp with the attack surface there's
plugins available for both of those
tools and they can also take a look
compare different applications different
versions of applications to see how that
application has changed between
different parts so how it works
it analyzes the source code the source
code is required and from that is able
to figure out all of the endpoints and
the parsing routes for the application
and the parameters that are available
these are supported frameworks languages
and frameworks so net Java Python Ruby
and in his framework dependent so these
are the frameworks that are currently
supported it is available today in the
iOS app and verb suite marketplace so
right from within those tools you can go
in and and add this plug-in and improve
your attack surface detection once it's
installed this is looking at burp you'll
have a new tab within burp and zap that
called the attack surface detector and
then there you can you know tell it give
it a zip file of your source code if you
want to compare it to another version
you can give that here what you get from
that is a list of the endpoints this is
again using the same content University
application the number of parameters
that were detected and whether was it
get her post method and whether it was
changed between the last version of it
and then on the bottom you can get
details about the particular endpoint I
know this one was a new one we have
another example where the integer ID
datatype change from integer to string
another one where a debug parameter was
added to the endpoint and then all that
information can get fed into zapper Bert
so it can improve your site map and you
can also see we have color coordinated
way of seeing you know whether it was
detected by source code whether it was
modified or whether it is new since the
last scan so now this allows Birkins app
to have a more intelligent way of doing
its analysis since it's being told a lot
more information than it would be able
to discover otherwise so running this
against contoso University there you
know there's more after going through
the attack surface detector there's more
points that were detected there's the
update course credits again that was the
unlinked end point that was found during
the attack surface detector there's a
delete and edit end points that weren't
detected and that was because when I ran
this there was no data that was already
part of the application so those
endpoints weren't able to be discovered
by zapper so looking at a comparison
this is a report generator and byte verb
sweet you can see you know we before the
preceding visa the number of URLs that
were detected in parameters and then
after just by doing the proceeding we
were able to improve that and find a lot
more for a lot more endpoints and
parameters that now can be tested and
then bringing this back into code pulse
we were able to take a look you know
with and without the attack surface
detector so again the overlap is shown
in black and then the things that were
discovered after using the attack
surface detector are all shown in blue
here so we're able to visually show that
you're able to improve your code
coverage by using this and also in code
pulse you can see a bar graph of the the
code coverage and again looking at the
controllers which is the attack surface
before the attack surface detector
preceding got 46% and then after we were
off to 75% this is a report that was
done for a more complex application so
contoso university is pretty
straightforward this was a proprietary
application that we ran burp against so
this was just just using burp this is
just using the attack surface detector
to discover the attack surface and you
know we have found a lot more and then
this last one here is first using the
attack surface detector and then going
through the the burps
discovery process and what I was able to
find so do you know the best way of
doing it is to first have the attack
surface detector integrated and
through the crawling and automated
scanning from from the dynamic tools
lastly you know one of the problems with
the tool is a lot of times pen testers
don't have direct access to the source
code what we provided is a command-line
interface that can be used so that you
can give this to the person that owns
the application they can run this CLI
tool against the application and a JSON
file will get generated that just lists
out the endpoints and parameters that
can then get fed into Berbers app and so
they don't have to give you the
proprietary source code they can just
give you this attack surface discovery
file that they can then be used into
into the Berkins am I'm just gonna wrap
up and they'll take some questions yeah
yeah this is couple more slides where to
learn more about these projects code
plus tax service detector both ojas
projects from there you can find out all
kinds of information about them there
the github repos the user guide and
documentation they're all linkable from
there you know we've talked about OS app
and web goat and dependency check those
are all really good Alost tools that
were demonstrated today or integrated
with the technology the contoso
university application that i use for
the demonstration is shown here and
finally link to burp suite which was was
highlighted during the demo and now I'll
take questions I'm really interested in
any feedback you guys have please reach
out to me directly we can walk through a
demo Matt took the Kodiaks booth we can
we can talk more really really
interested in getting getting feedback
from community
ah Donnie's Mike
so you mentioned when you need to sort
culture to the surface detection
comedians for Java just use a jar if the
jar file has a source embedded in it
then that would work yeah no that's a
good idea
yeah yeah no that's a good answer good
feedback yeah not now not currently but
that's a that's a good idea I'll make a
note of that thank you very nice you
have a question what is the benefit of
the a dark surface detector if in the
end of the using of code pools you will
find out all the entry points the
applications and you see on the code
pools at those parts which you are like
triggering so you know that these are
entry points so in the end of using you
will get all this information why do we
need the surface yeah I mean they're
complementary the detectors detect a
nice part about that is you can just
feed that into zap and burp directly so
it's a little bit more automated in that
way where code pulse it's more
interactive and you're exploring around
and trying to improve your coverage that
way and code pulse does require that you
instrument the application in order to
do that card that got testing coverage
which isn't so the first question is if
you notice like burp and SAP they are
moving towards continuous integration
continuous testing do you have any plans
to move these two projects for a
continuous integration sure that's a
good question yes that's probably the
highest thing
the roadmap is to fit better within the
automated process in CI process the
attack surface detector is a little bit
easier in that way you know you can you
use that CLI tool you know it's part of
your CI process to show the endpoints
and the differences in the end points
between them and feed em into Burton's
app but we're looking to make that a
little bit more seamless and then
certainly with code pulse as well right
now it's more hands-on interactive and
we're looking to make it work in you
mention about there is a Department of
Homeland Security funding for so it's
that for both projects and Lister Amy if
you don't mind can you let us know the
scope is there any license restriction
for any companies to use or any kind of
mess behind funded through the partner
home security there our Science and
Technology Directorate under the Cyber
Security Division we all are working on
other projects as well so if you check
out the secure decisions website you'll
see some other other projects that we
have in the area of application security
both of these projects are open source
code pulses Akashi license and the
attack services sector is them is a
public license I was really interesting
set of tools and I wanted to ask what
kind of support would there be for
single page applications since there's
not so much crawling that has to be done
yeah that's a good question I you know
for code pulse you'd be able to see it
down to the the method level so you'd be
able to you know look at more depth yeah
I'm not sure how the attack surface
detector would work on single page apps
but I know they're like for any web
api's and all that stuff is all is all
supported by by the attack service
detector so okay thank you
Thanks all right thank you everyone
[Applause]