[Music]
what I want to do is spend some time
talking about a wasp glue which is a
project that I work on and started
somewhere around 2013 I want to take
just a brief second and introduce myself
you need a picture a picture of my bio
sorry
so I'm actually on the a wasp global
board right now but I'm here really more
representing the project because Omer
has been running it lately and so I want
to first acknowledge him he's kind of
primary and he's been writing the most
code and so forth but he's in Israel so
he was not able to present so normally I
would not feel real comfortable getting
up at an app second talking as a board
member because it feels like the wrong
dynamic but I wanted to talk about the
project and I wanted to just put it in
context of hey like I was a software
developer for a really long time and
then I basically had my stuff broken
turned in you know like a lot of us
started working on security and glue
emerged essentially because we wanted to
solve automation problems actually let
me just also acknowledge Brian this is
sort of roughly in order of current
activity but we've had a bunch of people
work on it
we used it at a couple clients so we've
sort of built it purpose-built pieces of
it to solve problems at clients and they
let us open source that as part of the
tool I could talk more about that
I'm term-limited so I'm done on the
board in December so hopefully I'll be
able to spend more time on this again I
really like the project so obviously at
a wasp flew on github and what we're
trying to do is make automation easier
and so it's not in a lot of ways it's
not a security tool it's more of like a
meta tool to make automation easier and
so what I want to do is explain that and
these are OMERS slides so I want to give
him full credit here the idea here is
we're taking a task like one of these
things like snack or zap or check marks
or so forth we want to run it and then
we want to figure out what we're gonna
run it against and then we want to
collect findings which are like the
candy and then we want to take the
findings and we want to filter them out
because most tools don't have false
positives we don't have to worry about
that and then we want to report those
we're like juror or teamcity so the idea
here is basically to get a pipeline
together here we go back right so we're
running tools we want to be able to
target and this is representing source
code this is representing like a live
running application this is representing
like a hard like just a file on a file
system and so what we're trying to do is
abstract all of these things so that
it's easier we also produce a docker
image so you can run glue very easily
and hopefully as you'll see that
actually opens up some fun possibilities
right so if you want it to right now you
could go say docker run and I do the - -
RM so it removes the docker image when
you're done because unlike many docker
images we don't send it like an engine X
service where you want to leave it
running you want to run it once and let
it go away and so the RM removes the
docker thing when you're done so the - H
is you might expect shows help here I'm
running it I'm running a tool so this -
T tells me I want to run a tool and I'm
running break man
which is an open source through rails
static analyzer and I'm running it
against this vulnerable application
which is intentionally vulnerable if you
ran this right now glue would produce a
bunch of findings and you don't need to
do any other work to set it up which is
kind of the whole point right
to change the tool I just change what
I'm running this or the - T this is a
sensitive file look up so if you have
certs on your in your file system or you
have passwords or private keys those
kinds of things this will find right we
also support the idea of labels so you
can run all of the tools that are
related to code and I'll explain a
little bit more about how we know what
the labels apply to but instead of
running tool by tool you can run all the
code related things here I want to show
a deeper obviously we people wanted to
run the tool but they wanted it to run
and produce the results where they
wanted them so what we do is we take all
the results from break man or whatever
standardize that into a common finding
format and then report those wherever
you wanted them to go and jurors one of
the places people want them to go so we
can say we want the format to be JIRA
we have to give it the URL so like this
works if you're like we have a gem
Rideout Atlassian at URL but whatever
yours is you can run if it's hosted
we're it's doing sort of basic off in
this scenario so if you were using this
in an enterprise you'd probably have to
solve this off problem that's not like
out-of-the-box easy for you necessarily
but you tell it did your project and now
when it runs SFL or retire j/s against
your project it's going to report those
issues into jura and basically post them
into that project which is handy because
now you've got a list of those on a
sidenote
my experience is you want to have you
want to start by having like a security
project or a knapsack project in JIRA
you don't want to dump these directly
into the developers JIRA projects right
away until you figure out what's gonna
be there right because otherwise you're
gonna make a lot of noise we like to get
to the point where we can have it be
part of their CI CD it's running in
Jenkins which I'll show you in a minute
and it just pushes to JIRA that's like
what we want but initially I would
suggest running it to a place where you
can manage it and figure out which
things apply this is just more detail
about JIRA but the thing that I want to
point out here is there's a filter so we
won't create the same issue more than
once in JIRA so now we have sort of a
way of managing duplicates right or
change over time so if I've seen a
certain problem and reported the issue
to JIRA before and I can search your and
find it I'm not gonna report it again so
that's kind of one of the strategies for
managing noise over time if that makes
sense so I wanted to talk a little bit
about the architecture of glue like how
we built it like what the stages are as
you'll see and happy to answer questions
but we'll look at code in a little bit
about what each of these are by far the
most common thing that we've done is use
git repos so we'll point at a I usually
just point at public it of repos for
demos but you you basically have to be
able to connect to somewhere to pull
source code so usually a lot of the
tools that we've used the most are the
source analysis so we're pulling source
code from get and then we're gonna do
something but we sort of want to
abstract how we got that because we want
to be able to run it against a file
system if you got the code some other
way we want to be able to look at I
shows when we first did this we thought
we might look at like a.m. eyes and like
dig in and do deeper interesting things
I named eyes that stuff is not as robust
as some of the other stuff and we don't
really do a lot with docker images
either will on tar them and do certain
things like check for obvious will run
clean clamavi against that but that's
not all that I don't know that that's
all that useful
the main thing we're doing that I think
is useful is this like we're mounting
getting the thing we want to analyze and
then we have what we think of as like a
file stage and what this what what
happens behind the scenes is glue saying
okay we want to run tasks that apply to
files so I have a file system mounted
whether I got it from github or I got it
from the docker image or I got it from
the ami or I got it from git or did I
say git already
I can run things that are just looking
at files right so theoretically I can
use hash deep to do basically FEM so
foul and Tegrity monitoring so or I can
use clamavi to look for viruses there
are other cool things we could do here
the whole intent is that it's extensible
so we would want to build those out as
needed this is where we kind of make our
biggest impact is in this code stage
where we've pulled down the code now
we're gonna analyze it right so we'll
run a bunch of tools I have a summary of
the tools that we'll run but it's
essentially you can think of it as like
we pull the code we run the tool against
the code we parse the output which is
gonna be there a little later but the
code runs the code analysis runs we
parse the output we put the results into
sort of a common format so that we can
handle them in a the same way because we
don't really care which tool generated
the finding right we've written
something that will work with zap but
it's sort of like we can use the API
drivers apps can get the results out of
zap create findings for them that all
works it's not like I don't think it's
robust to the point where I'd say like
use this tool to go do that yet
and zap has an old hole independent
project to do similar things so I would
look at them first but the point is this
this stage is intended to be like a live
stage where we're we're testing against
an app that's running or a network
that's live so we might do em map and
map in fact I have something in progress
to do
to run nmap and then check you know
which ports you intended to open because
this is something that people see a lot
with security groups in the cloud for
example that they didn't mean to open
stop or put the instance in the security
group and they end up with ports open
they didn't want so we want to be able
to make that easy
gauntlet isn't it turns out it's harder
to like interact with than I would like
but that's a that's a whole other thing
so then there's this filter stage and
you'll see there's code for each one of
these like these basically if you write
a lot of code these each have an
interface and I'll describe the
interface in a minute but you just have
to implement that interface to create a
new filter or a new app an analyzer or
whatever but the filter is basically
like we don't want to see false
positives in JIRA so for example with
zap you will get a different result for
iframe options for every different page
you hit right well you only want to see
one in most cases because you're gonna
fix it one time in the web server you're
gonna add that header to make sense so
because you fix it in one place we want
to show one finding if you had a
cross-site scripting on two different
pages that would be two different
finding still you want those both
differently but for one something that
you're gonna fix in one way we want to
make it as clean and easy to get as
possible now these also there's lots of
opportunity to make those better so I
don't want it I don't want to oversell
this like we have magic that will
prevent you from having findings I would
love to have something that does like
advanced native stuff here so that you
can actually filter in a smarter way but
you know again there's extension points
for all of these and then we have the
concept of a reporter and this is where
we go to gerra teamcity I wrote in a
reporter for pivotal tracker so if you
want to take the issue somewhere you can
get them out you can get them as JSON
you can get them as CSV we're automating
around this so we clearly want it to be
easy to do stuff with the data once you
have it we're not opinionated about
where you should put it does that make
sense and I'm gonna I'm gonna dive into
actual code but this is a screenshot and
the reason I show it is because I want
you to see like this organization of the
source code is mapping directly to those
things I just showed you so here we have
filters that was the second last thing
we looked at here we have mounters this
is like how we get to get how we get to
an ISO right we're basically how do we
to that stage if you want to mount
something new you go look at this base
mount er and maybe you implement the
methods we'll talk about in a second for
the reporters you have reporters so you
can go look at the one that's there and
copy it and make one for whatever you
want the tasks are really where we were
doing more of the analysis this is a
really old snapshot actually now that I
think about it cuz there's like 20 of
them now and then a lot of this is just
the kind of code around the code that
makes it all work so let's spend a
minute and go how much do people want to
know like the meta and how much do you
want to know like like in the code do
you want to want to write a new task
right now she do laugh do laugh all
right can you see that kind of kind of
not
I'm sorry it's hard to get the mouse and
the exact thing I want so let's look at
a task for bandit for example this is a
good way to kind of see
so remember tasks are the things that
are doing the code analysis so I have a
base task that knows how to report
findings so its implements some base
behaviors that I want so I don't have to
re-implement them and so this bandit
task will inherit from that here I have
to add it to sort of the base class so
that I know all the tasks this is how
the thing that's running it knows that
you have a new task this is just as a
bunch of utilities when I initialize the
task if I say I want to give it a name
and description so you know what's going
on when I assign the stage that's how it
knows when to run it so if it were a
live stage it would run it as a live
tool the labels are like okay this is a
code related tool this is a Python
related tool so I could actually pass a
label for python and any task that's
labeled for python will run so it makes
sense so you can kind of figure out ways
of categorizing your stuff to make it
work and then with the with an actual
task you just have to implement this run
method and analyze method and a
supported method to have it be sort of a
valid task because that you imagine the
task is like a thing the thing that's
running a task doesn't know what it is
all it does is say hey I need each task
I want to see if it's supported on the
environment I'm in I want to run it and
then I want to analyze the results
sometimes running it takes a little
while particularly with like SAP
so here
run analyze and this supported method I
think I have a slide that'll show you
for each two in a second if we go back
to slides I don't know so when I'm
running the tools typically and and in
particular when we build the docker
image we build a bunch of the tools in
so for anything that's open source we
can build the tools in right so we built
the docker image that's a really it's
not as lightweight as it should be so
it's one of the pieces of feedback we
have but we don't know whether to build
like a big docker image that has Java
and fine bugs or whether to just build a
small one that just has Python right so
we can tweak that but what we're ending
up doing in the case of bandit is we're
just running a local bandit program
bandit is a static analyzer for python
right and we're asking for JSON output
and we're running it against a path that
we're in so we've tracked where we are
in this root path variable right so and
I'm and we're taking that JSON result
and putting in this class variable
result for this instance variable result
when I'm analyzing it now we're parsing
that into JSON and we're for each item
that comes back as a result we're
essentially mapping that into how we're
gonna report the finding so here this
detail we're pulling out essentially
what the text is out of the tool we want
into defining detail that we're gonna
end up packaging up so when we see this
if you see this report method this is a
method that's on the base class and so
when we call this we're passing in the
detail which we got here so we're
basically parsing the XML JSON in this
case from bitch from bandit and dropping
it into our finding so that when we
report it we have all that in the same
format no matter which tool we're
looking at it might be useful to look at
a different a different tool here like
so
well dependency checks not a good
example because it's XML which makes it
hard to read but like I don't know
so here we've implemented a helper
method report finding and we're
essentially grabbing things out of a
string and then reporting it based on
the detail that we get here so we're in
this case we're grabbing a description
field off of output you can't see it so
sorry that's probably not super helpful
the reason we came here was partly to
see the tools that we run so I should
mention that we've sort of had to bend
the rules for up a couple of cases so we
will see burp contrast I can remember if
there's others those are things where
we'll take the report in some kind of
format that they produce and ingest it
so this is almost like thread fix and
we're not intending to compete with
thread fix but it's almost more like
that where you're taking input from
another tool and pushing it where you
want it right we're not running burper
or contrast in that case right we did
write an adapter for check marks so you
could run check marks as part of your
analysis and get the detail and put it
in in JIRA that was a pain and it's
against the old API which is soap based
so you might not want to use that part
we probably need to rewrite that so if
you're at a company where you want to
use this and you're using commercial
tools you may end up having to write
your own tasks which is part of why we
could talk about that so let's just sort
of so I showed you the docker command to
run this if I want to run it if I want
to run it locally like while I'm working
I can just run this bin glue so if you
don't know if you can see this down here
but this just that's like what ends up
being your command line and you just
basically say glue tasks and I had made
a sort of messing around and made a new
task and so I can run a new task against
defect dojo by doing this and it's
pretty fast but in the meantime let's
talk about what it looks like to
implement a new task because that'll be
fun so let's say I want to just do
there's a tool in Python called safety
does anybody work in Python a lot and
know that tool right so there's tools
safety safety check it's like dependency
check but for Python libraries so let's
let's write that real quick so if I go
maybe I'm gonna go safety check yeah and
so you get an empty ruby file which is
not all that helpful but might as well
start with the Bandit code because copy
and paste is great right let's call it
safety check and can leave it as source
code we can leave all that that's why I
copied that one so then I have to figure
out how I'm gonna run safety check well
I spent just a little bit of time to
figure making sure I knew how that works
so that it would work and it looks
something like this where I say safety
check and I passed this JSON thing and I
passed this our - our - the requirements
that text and safety runs and shows me
the vulnerabilities that that app has
right so now I can say let's just
I'm gonna go over here
so here I've got sorry I actually tested
this in advance which should make you
happy so I so here's how I would set up
that command to run and I'm assigning
the results of the output into this
result thing now this let's just
actually delete this for a minute
so analyze is empty but let's just do
puts result and then let's just do this
this is kind of done but I don't know if
it's gonna work actually just it's been
smart enough to tell me that it's not
there so if I run if I run this now this
is case insensitive it basically pulls
the defect dojo code larger and it works
the same time same way when you run it
in the docker image the docker image is
pulling the source code from wherever it
is grabbing it running the analysis and
here we've just pulled so we've run the
safety check and got it into that result
object right so to finish writing this
check we would implement this supported
method where we would basically I looked
at this too and the way to do this it
seemed like was to say and every tool is
different right so safety doesn't have a
version usually I like to do it with
like oh how do I know the tools here I
can say run it with version and get it
resolved like oh yeah we're version 1.2
right so in this case it looks more like
ended up looking more like this where
you can run it and if you don't if you
run the help essentially on safety you
can know if it's there or not right and
if it's not available you'll just
obviously not run the analyse gets a
little trickier so I got I was kind of
preparing for this and I wasn't really
planning on doing anything live but we
would start to basically parse out the
JSON we get back and map it into the
finding that we have and the finding
that we have is pretty simple let me
show you that real quick
it's basically God the task the app name
when it was found some sort of severity
the source which is like what tool found
the finding description detail which I
think are self-explanatory and then the
concept of a fingerprint and this is
really important if you implement a new
task you need to make sure you think
think about how the fingerprint is going
to work because if you can make
something that's unique for that finding
we can be sure we're not producing the
same thing again that makes sense
without that you can't we can't know so
fingerprints some tools like break man
for example produces its own fingerprint
so we just use that in other cases we
use a combination of the file the line
which of course is flawed right because
if we just use a file in line the same
code could be flawed and move and we'll
report it again
but we decided like we don't wanna be
too smart for most cases we'd rather
report something again if it moves
around because we're not a static
analyzer we're not we don't understand
what's happening in the code right we're
just tracking where that thing was found
so make sense but the fingerprint
essentially gets reported in the detail
of the finding and let's say we're
reporting it to JIRA you can imagine
that we say push it to JIRA and then oh
don't push it if this fingerprint exists
in JIRA already so if the fingerprint
exists already we won't report it again
great but that's why the fingerprint is
really important it's usually like the
type of finding where it is if it's like
live it might be the page the field that
makes sense
so let me go back to the meta for a
second and we can dive back in here so
you can see that we have bandit I was
working on gauntlet but I haven't
finished it yet brake man bundler audit
is basically similar to brake man it's
gonna do dependency type of checking for
for for Ruby burp I mentioned we ingest
the findings checkmarks we run a scan
over the soap api clamavi just runs
clamavi contrast injustice a report
dawn scanner is similar to Ruby to break
man we did a lot of work with companies
that we're using Ruby that's why the
such a focus there this dynamic one is
something that Homer is working on where
it's gonna be more flexible about what
tools even being run and how the input
gets parsed so that you can write like a
almost like a DSL so you can write
something around how you run the tool
and get the results back out I haven't
actually used it yet will run es LAN
which is like a JavaScript tool so you
can use yes lint with security checks
and it'll find sometimes things in
JavaScript will run fine security bugs
we don't have a great rule set for
spying security bugs because the
security rule set for fine screw bugs is
yeah but it will find certain things NPM
I don't know if NPM is still this
probably needs to get updated now that
there's an NPM audit function it's
probably those I think that's probably
old but we will also run dependency
check so we'll run Java dependency check
against projects and take the findings
out of the XML that we get back and push
them into JIRA we had some PMD security
rules which this is primarily like a
Java static analysis tool right retire
shows you JavaScript old old JavaScript
libraries we just did a safety check one
I was working on a scout 2 integration
so that I don't say anyways heard of
Scout two but you if you supply AWS
credentials you could run Scout to have
it pull out the stuff push them into
JIRA it's kind of hot if I could get it
done just at the time this SFL looks at
sensitive files
snick I don't know if you're familiar
but it's also dependencies truffle hog
is looking for a like hmm creds yeah
like strings that are have high entropy
and then zap connects this app over the
API runs a scan and gets the results
back so I like to think that it's pretty
simple but let me go back to the
presentation so you can see like what
the actual extension points are because
that's
useful right so if you're gonna write a
mounter you're gonna write something
that says support so how do you know
that you can mount that kind of thing
and then the actual mount function and
the mount function has to actually
result in that filesystem being
available for us to do the further
analysis right tasks I mentioned this
you have to write the run analyze and
supported methods for filters there's
just one method called filter and it
essentially takes the array of findings
and you can do whatever you want to
remove them so I wrote a dumb filter
that just zeros out the array so you'll
never get any findings right but you
could filter on anything you can inspect
the findings and say I don't care about
these because whatever right the JIRA
filter is one that doesn't just sit
there in place and look at those
findings for each one of those that
connects the juror and asks do we know
about this one already that's how that's
implemented and then the run report is
the thing that actually takes the
findings array that you run you end up
with after the filter runs and pushes
them out to wherever you want it to go
so I think of these as being tasks these
files code and app things so this is
where all the analysis actually happens
here we're just getting the stuff after
this we're filtering it and reporting it
that make sense I think I just said that
so you can also just run like against
the file system so if you're building
something locally you can do that some
checks are really good I just went
through them all others are still noisy
the whole goal here is to run this like
make it easy to run these tools every
day right so how can you do that one way
you can do it is you can run Jenkins
right so if you're running Jenkins
already you can run our stuff this glue
tool right in Jenkins and the idea is
you can set up a what I doing here
I'm setting up the manage scripts
plug-in in particular because you need
that and then I build a project in this
case I built a whole separate project
for this just because that seemed like
the best way to kind of isolate it and
then you go to this on the left if you
go to config you go to this config file
manager you can add a manage script and
here's this pipeline build script and
then you can basically run the same
docker thing you'd run locally and
Jenkins will just run that as part of
your build and so then you can fail the
build because your thing didn't run so
make sense that's step one right and of
course because we're all about DevOps we
want to see it in slack that that's not
anything we do that's just Jenkins slack
stuff but it's kind of cool to be able
to know that that's easy right like
Jenkins has a slight I mean that setting
that up is literally following a
five-minute slack back right then you
get builds that work and don't work etc
I don't think you need to see the
details here we just talked about all
those so I'm gonna skip that so this
starts to get interesting because so we
packaged as a docker image initially for
portability because we're like oh
wouldn't it be cool if you could just
run it over there without having to set
up PMD like who knows how to setup maven
so you can run find bugs right it's just
like all these different things seem
like a pain so how can we do that well
that's why we chose to build a docker
image but once you have the docker image
now you can do some really interesting
things and I wouldn't actually do this
through the GUI I'll show you the
scripts that you can use that are in the
glue repo now but you can run glue
and obviously in a in a job in community
so let me show you what that might look
like and again this is this is really
more like the it's more it's more the
integrations and understanding how
kubernetes and docker work than anything
we did in the glue project right so this
is just like a demo script we package so
that you could set up a glue pod to run
triage run glue on triage treasures that
intentionally vulnerable project I keep
referring to right so if I do this this
will create a container and run glue and
just this one just runs at one time so I
can just go if I have this if I have
this yellow file which describes sort of
a pod which is a Cooper Nettie's thing
if you don't know
and then this wass glue is the image so
this is published to docker hub so you
can just go docker pol i wasa glue
that's why this works and then i run the
command and you hopefully are starting
to get familiar with what the syntax of
the command is cuz i've been showing it
so much right like there's the tool
break man against the triage thing well
if i want us so this is just a yellow
file that describes a pod if i want to
set that up I can say coop control
create based on this and I'm may or may
not do that based on time but it's not
it's not a big deal I'm running mini
cube here and you could just basically
go create the command and it'll run it
one time and then you can look at the
logs and see what happens and delete it
right now I'm sure that what you'd
actually want to do is use secrets so
that you know how to connect to junk to
JIRA and you'd want to have this set up
on a cron so you can also set up like an
integration where you have a cron in
kubernetes so this is kind of cool
because kubernetes just runs the job for
you you don't have to know what it is so
here I've got a cron this is every 30
minutes it's the same concept of the
container this is the same as the last
one but now I can run so this will if I
if I set up this cron every 30 minutes
it's gonna run break man
against my project and if I set it up
properly it's not in this command line
but I can make it report the issues to
JIRA right so now with almost no not no
work but you can copy this script out of
your thing change the command to run the
tools you want integrate it to JIRA now
you've got if you can set up a little
kubernetes cluster to work with now
you've got whatever security tools glue
supports pushing stuff to JIRA with like
no work that make sense not no work
that's total simplification but that's
the idea
so I also in a past life bill
vulnerability scanners and we used to
have literally like a rack machine for
each scanner so we had and it wasn't
that big a company but we had thousands
of them not tens of thousands but like
we don't a lot of them right and then
what we built was all the like smartness
to figure out how to manage those and
like distribute jobs across different
scanners and so forth if you do this
because it's all sort of shared
resources a lot of this kubernetes takes
care of you for you so like to build a
cluster of scanners in kubernetes is
like kind of a cool easy thing to do
right and again I wouldn't tell you to
use this for zap because I think sap has
a whole roadmap for doing this that's
cool but for a lot of this stuff I think
it makes it easy if you want to set up
glue in Jenkins this is an example of a
script you so these are pushed to the
repo right so in github you can go look
at the glue repo and we have these
sample integrations sorry because of
where I am you can't see this very well
but there's this integrations folder
right so one thing you could do let me
step back one thing you could do is run
it as a pre-commit hook right so you
could have git commit and run something
and have that either succeed or fail
based on what runs so because you only
want to run things that are really fast
in that kind of spot you don't want to
run zap every commit and you don't want
to run anything that's like gonna take
more than a couple seconds at the very
most right you you want it to be careful
about what you do I would recommend
running like the secrets manager or
something like that like the SFL tool
but if you know how get commit hooks
work it basically means that when I do
might get commit as a developer it has
to meet some criteria before it'll let
me commit people often use these to do
things like make sure that your issue is
in the name of the commit message right
but we can use it to do other things too
if you want to go beyond that now you
can go say I want to set up a managed
script where Jenkins is gonna run in
this case Jenkins is gonna run glue it's
gonna run well this is the active one
but Jenkins well if you're if you're
using Jenkins to do deployments it may
also know what's running so you might be
able to integrate this into your into
your deployment where you're running
Jenkins you push the thing you can run
Zab down but more what I would expect
more more likely would be that you'd
want to run it against source code on
every commit or something like that on
every push to master and then you can
build like a pipeline so if you're
working in Jenkins do you have this fun
thing called pipelines right so you can
then write groovy code to set up each
one to do what you want and this is what
it would look like if you wanted to run
the docker image in Jenkins as a stage
in your pipeline I think I'm almost out
of time so I'm gonna just finish and
then take whatever questions I mentioned
that Omar is working on dynamic tasks I
would need to defer to him to explain
what he wants to do there to be honest
we've written a bunch of tests but we
need to write more tests so I think if
that's one of the things we'll end up
spending time on it's a little tricky
because as you can imagine right we're
shelling out running a tool getting the
results to write really good tests you
need to see a lot of different scenarios
and so most of the time once by the time
we've done the tool integration we've
got the environment working and it's
hard to come up with why it would fail
so it's like many things just an
exercise and writing better tests we
also need to improve documentation so
like this kubernetes thing has always
been possible but nobody knows how to do
it so we can't say hey anybody wants to
just run us to gain cluster you can
start up and go
right like nobody knows how to do that
so we need to we need to improve that I
think there's easy opportunities to run
more tools like safety check like we
should actually I should probably polish
that up make it work and come in it it's
nice to have i think the like from a big
picture
I feel like beyond this the tool needs
to get kind of kind of consolidated but
what I usually tell people is use it as
like your first stage of thinking about
how you're gonna do automation it's not
like the whole end game right so a lot
of the people we talk to and my firm
works mostly with very small like
smaller companies so they're usually
like figuring out what to do from a
knapsack perspective and they're like
let me buy a tool right like well that's
cool tools are really good like the
tools are better than what's in here
probably like bluntly right if you use a
commercial tool for any one of these
scanning pieces it's probably gonna give
you better results than what we can run
from open source probably not definitely
but probably but if you don't know how
that tool is gonna fit into your process
or anything like that then it's hard to
know that you're gonna use it
successfully but if you have some
engineering resources and you can do
this now you've got something and you
can build the tools into that that make
sense so you can sort of build the
automation and flow such that you could
take a tool plug it in and get the
better results you want it anyway so
make sense so that's basically it we
already did the live right at task as we
go did the run mount supported and
analyze make sense
cool anybody else have questions
thanks for coming I really appreciate it
it's been really a fun project for me
because I spent a lot of time on it and
I haven't been able to spend as much
time but OMERS picked it up and like
really run with it and so it's kind of
like I don't know if you work in open
source it's kind of like a great thing
when somebody else picks up and runs
with something you start like that's not
a common experience so I really
appreciate that
yep that would be great
I'm I'm of two minds about that because
I think a lot of people in open-source
always say you can start with tests and
Docs and then people aren't as
interested in that part so then they
don't engage right so I would almost say
find the thing you want and build that
you know what I mean
like if there's a tool you want I mean
we I think we would be happy to talk to
you about how to do the integration or
like bounce ideas or whatever but my
thinking would be do that and we
collectively need to just do a better
job with testing and documentation
because again it's not that it's wrong
it is an easier way to contribute but
it's not the fun way to contribute for a
lot of people so I would say don't feel
constrained to that I would I this is
off the topic I did a whole talk about
writing security unit tests I would love
to build some kind of like bootstrapping
thing where this can give you a whole
bunch of frameworks for that and we
could like pull tests from get and then
run those and then push the finding
cetera but like that's outside the scope
of what I have time for thanks for
coming
have a great day
[Applause]