engineers and some security people and
some application people at Aptech I am
both and also run a security program for
a start-up in San Francisco today I'm
going to talk about how to do basically
how to protect data or do you encryption
the right way hopefully a lot better
than I can get a new MacBook to project
on slides so this is a typical setup for
a web application on the Internet
the internet connects to a web server
web server connects to a database you
have a lot of secrets in that database
that you want to protect the problem
that we keep seeing is this is a crazy
model this is like we take our most
expensive valuables maybe a diamond ring
we stick it in a safe we put it in the
trunk of our car we drive a car out to
the worst neighborhood you can find the
internet and we leave it there and we
hope it's safe any compromise in that
web server that web server has
credentials in that database can pull
the data out we've seen this happen over
and over again so what's the situation
as we look at across the spectrum
knowing that we have application
security people here these are all
probably pretty well-known attacks I'm
going to go through quickly so in 2014
Anthem Blue Cross discovered that they
had lost thirty seven point five million
health records because a database admin
logged into the database and saw that he
had logged in the night before when he
wasn't anywhere near his computer it
took a year for them to discover that
they were breached in the first place
and the the the findings a report that
the government issued on this company
afterwards said that they had
best-in-class security they exceeded the
security of other people in their space
like they couldn't find anything wrong
with a security program it wasn't a
problem with the security program that
made them lose their data the equifax
breached I mean we're really familiar
with this one this is exactly what I was
talking about a single exploit on the
web server can literally happen to
anyone yes they could have patched
earlier but
I think a lot of companies miss patches
on some servers and they don't discover
until months later and then they fix it
and that's how the world works but one
vulnerability on a web server exposed
300 something million records through
Equifax so it's a low barrier it's hard
to protect that rise and a debate the
Verizon data breach investigation
breaches aren't discovered for months
and 96% of the cases most of the time
they're actually discovered by somebody
from the outside who noticed that some
data was leaked I mean it's the brian
curbs this is the hey the credit card
company is calling you and saying that
you're the source of compromise for a
lot of credit cards so we don't monitor
data very well best companies keep
getting breached our architecture is not
security to begin with and we don't
monitor data very well I think though
the real issue there's web boils down to
is we don't even know if we're safe I
mean as a head of security
I have people asking me like what is are
we safe today like what's the chances of
us being breached or are we already
breached and I have to tell you I think
everyone in this room shares the same
fear that you don't actually know if
you're breach you could have a bad guy
in your network right now and not know
about it and that not knowing can keep
you up at night but there there may be
some solutions of this does anyone
paying attention it's blockchain right
that's a solution it's not the solution
the solution is encryption done right so
my theory the premise is that if you do
good if you do have cryptography around
your data that helps you defend it and
identify who's accessing it then you
have a really great signal whether or
not you've been breached or whether or
not your company's safe so quick outline
where I'm going to go through talk about
the goal to keeping data safe the
problem we don't know if we are safe
some of the challenges in protecting the
data
the solutions I'm gonna go through most
cryptic cryptographic solutions or
techniques that we use not like AES
versus RSA but more of the crypto system
and how you how you as a non cryptograph
for can it analyze it and the last one
which is what is this crypto anchor I've
been talking about so challenge this
this is our challenge at first it
doesn't look that hard to protect but
then you start adding all the people and
all the different roles that have to
access this environment you've got on
the bottom system admin database admin
you have your developers you've got a
building deploy stack the pushes new
code out you have users that access it
from the internet some sales for some
admins out there all those people they
also have laptops and you have to
incorporate all the vulnerabilities and
their laptops as well
have they been exposed to phishing have
a installed malware on their laptops
what else is going on with those laptops
that now has the access to this data
then you have to realize that those
laptops are managed by IT so the IT
people also have access those laptops
they can compromise those laptops ik and
remotely control those laptops and so
while you may trust you it's just admin
you may forget your IT guy that you're
about to you terminate also has access
to this environment and could have left
backdoors in place hackers got access to
all of these people and all these
devices he also run it on Amazon Web
Services so you have your credentials
for that environment right so your
management console or your yeah or your
access keys you're also backing up your
database somewhere so there's a copy of
all that sensitive information that you
want to keep safe and then you have the
policy police right they the people that
come in and say hey are you rotating
your passwords are you meeting all the
compliance and policy things so these
are all the concerns that you have in
addition to just keeping that simple
data safe we're gonna go through these
six challenges the ones that have the
star on them so compliance
you've got AWS management console
and these are these gonna be threats
like these are the threats to the system
the most obvious threats compliance is
only on there because it fills out a row
it's a checkbox for me as well the AWS
management compromise that's a big one I
mean with a device credentials you can
do so much work there's so much damage
that I'm not a big fan of one single
point of failure and I believe that if
you don't architect your systems well
AWS is a single point of failure in
terms of the management console so we'll
go through these a little bit more you
have a server admin database backup
database admin compromised an
application compromised okay great so
those are the challenges the next step
is we're gonna look for the solutions
for how we're going to defend our
networks against those challenges so
let's talk about encryption encryption
done right so encryptions essentially
you get cipher text by encrypting
plaintext with a key you get plain text
by decrypting cipher text with that key
so you always need so what we're really
focused on is how do you recover that
plaintext you need both the ciphertext
and the key now if we could keep the
data or the plaintext secure in the
first place we wouldn't need to encrypt
it so what makes us think we're going to
be able to keep the ciphertext safe
probably not but we do need to be able
to keep the key safe so if you have to
you have to pick one either key or the
cipher text and the way crypto works is
you want to keep that key safe and let
that ciphertext go wherever so when
you're analyzing a crypto system you're
really looking at where that key is who
has access to that key and how you can
protect that and monitor those keys ok
so I'm going to look at these five
techniques for doing cryptography the
first one is Amazon Web Services has a
checkbox where you can turn on
encryption on the hard drive the second
one
is where you have your operating system
perform the cryptography and this can be
BitLocker on Windows or the lux file
system on Ubuntu you our Linux the third
one is database implemented encryption
so this is where your sequel server or
your my sequel is actually doing the
encryption operation at some field level
or during your sequel statements the
fourth one is application encryption so
on that previous diagram this would be
the web application so the encryption
happens before the data goes to the
database and the fifth one is is the
crypto anchor which we'll get to you for
the rest of that talk okay so looking at
the first one which is hard drive
encryption through Amazon Web Services
basically start off with the physical
servers you have a virtual server on the
left the data when the virtual server
goes to write data to the disk it's in
plain text it sends it to the virtual
hard drive
Amazon intercepts it it encrypts it
using a KMS key and then that it takes
out ciphertext and it writes that actual
cipher text to the physical disk and so
what this buys you so this chart here on
on the column we have the six different
types of encryption we're gonna go
through right now and then I'm sorry on
the column we have the the six different
threats or the the challenges that we
talked about a minute ago and then on
the top we're looking at the five
different types of encryption so the
first one's AWS hard drive encryption
and you can see that the one threat or
the one challenge it meets is that it
meets your compliance requirements you
know honestly I think the the other
challenge inmates is there are actually
other two other challenges which is when
you're on AWS when you write data to a
disk and then you shut down that server
you don't want the next customer to come
and see that data right so you want that
data to be scrambled so the next
customer can't see the share data the
truth is AWS already wipes their disks
they they solve this problem a long time
ago they they thought about it already
because they didn't want customers to
see their data and the other one is this
also protects when somebody goes into a
data center removes a physical disk but
again AWS handles this by destroying
their disk before they leave the data
center so impractical
practically this meets a compliance
checkbox today ok let's look at
operating system disk encryption so in
this case you boot up a server you give
it a key that key doesn't you don't
store the key on the disk because that
would be crazy if you saw it on our disk
then somebody could take a back of the
disk and recover the key and decrypt the
data you have to keep that key in memory
you can't write it to disk so you boot
up the server you type in the key and
now every time that server writes data
to its disk it runs it through a
software encryption so that only
ciphertext written it is written out to
the hard drive the key doesn't leave
memory and so what this buys you is you
now can protect yourself against
somebody that steals Amazon Web Services
credentials for your environment so
before when you're doing this first one
with the AWS hard drive encryption if I
was an admin on your AWS management
console I could take a snapshot of your
I can take a snapshot of your disk and I
could see all that data because I have
access to the key the keys stored with
kms as an admin I can use all those keys
to decrypt data so that's why I didn't
protect you from an M in this on
management console compromised however
with an operating system encryption
because the AWS service doesn't have
that key you're protected from this this
threat and that is really important for
me because again I don't like Amazon
admins being my single point of failure
for my entire security posture
okay let's do the next one database
encryption I'm not gonna go into too
many details about this because there's
a lot of databases out there and they
all do it a little bit differently but
fundamentally most of them have a key
internally that they have to persist
somehow and when they persist that key
it's gonna get written to disk so when
you take a copy of that disk you have
both the encrypted data and a key to
decrypt that data fundamentally that
doesn't bias very much it it protects
the data from a few use cases maybe and
again it depends on how it's implemented
and how its configured so we're just
going to say maybe for these next two
threats which it's a database admin
compromised and the database backup
compromised again it depends on how you
backw of the database where the key
store and all those things but let's
move on to the next one this one's
application encryption and the idea here
is that you never send the plaintext to
the database in the first place you only
send ciphertext of the sensitive data to
the database now I'm not saying that you
encrypt every single thing you saw in
the database you'll take something like
a social security number or a credit
card number the sensitive information or
even password hash like a decrypted
password hash you wouldn't cook that
before you store it in the database
because that way if you know somebody
steals a backup of the database unless
they also have the key that's stored on
the application they can't recover the
data and that's the goal we're going for
so there's some definite advantages to
moving that key away from the database
entirely now you can protect that key
separately from the data the ciphertext
they're completely different threat
models at this point you can protect a
database who has access to the database
entirely differently than you have to
protect that web server and who has
access that web server so that gets us
down this chart now we have data and
server admin compromised would be a
database server admin
or somebody who has access to you like
the backups of that database
I wouldn't necessarily protect us from
the person that has a web server admin
credentials because they have the key
and maybe they can get a copy of the
database but it still doesn't protect us
from an application compromised right
and that's what that's what we're here
for
how do we do that it's application
compromised it's gonna be the next one
this is where we're going to talk about
the crypto anchor in this scenario we
take the key and the encryption
operation and we move it to a micro
service so now neither database or the
application server have the key and
neither one of them are doing the actual
encryption and decryption and the reason
this is important is because again if
you can get that key then you're pretty
and it's going to be easy for you to get
a copy of the data and if you get that
key as well you can take the data you
can decrypt it at your house you can
decrypt it anywhere you want but we need
to try to do is force people I mean as
it sorry as a developer and there's a
common practice you might even download
a copy of the database decrypt it
locally and start playing with the data
because it sometimes you just need to do
that but in this model you can't do that
you there's no way for you to extract
the key so let's talk about yeah so
basically crypto anchor is the only one
that protects against all these tech all
these threats
and Christian done right to summarize we
need to use a crypto anchor to meet the
only way to actually have to know that
you have a good encryption technique is
if it meets all the threats in your
threat model and what we found out is
that the crypto anchor needs to do these
three things can't decrypt offline you
have to limit access to the keys and you
have to log what's being decrypted okay
so the crypto anchor so the way it works
is the web server has something it needs
to store in the database may have a
social security number it sends out
plain text to the crypto anchor it says
encrypt this the encryption service logs
out to the log system that says that the
web application is encrypted this social
security number at this time and then it
sends back the secretary to the web
server and the web server sends a cipher
text to the database server now the
database server only has a encrypted
copy of that data and we have a log the
reverse of this is decryption the web
server goes and gets the socially
encrypted social out of the web out of
the database sends ciphertext to the
crypto anchor we get a log that says
that this social security number is
decrypted at this time by this service
and then the plain sex to return the web
server
the real trick in this crypto anchoring
the reason is this protects your web
application is the logging so we the
cipher that we're using for encryption
is an authenticated cipher it's actually
a es GSM and I don't know how to say
what that stands for but the what's
important with it is you send actually
three pieces of information to the
crypto algorithm you send the plaintext
you send the key actually I'm sorry the
web server doesn't send the key the key
is managed by the crypto anchor the web
server will send the plaintext and a
description of what's being encrypted
and that description should be verbose
should be verbose and it's
gonna be logged and the whole point is
the description is logged so you could
say John's social security number and
that then you know what is actually
being decrypted so in the first first
example this is a normal encryption you
a timestamp you get who decrypted it you
get the size of what was the crypt in
you see what the key was it's not very
informative it could be anything it
doesn't tell you what was being
decrypted or encrypted versus
authenticated ciphers you get the person
get the size you get the same
information but you also get that
context you see the record ID you see
the record type was a credit card number
the second one you see the record ID you
see it was an email address so we can
start to make theories about whether or
not Tom should be encrypting email
addresses we can make theories about
whether or not Bob should be decrypting
credit card numbers you couldn't do that
before from your database you couldn't
do that anywhere else in your
environment but now you can actually
start to profile who's doing what with
your data how many records is Bob
decrypting if you're Equifax how many
records per hour do you normally decrypt
do you normally decrypt 300 million
records in an hour and in a day or in a
week or is that outrageous or something
you need to investigate maybe after a
million records in an hour you shut down
the service so that's that's basically
the key to low logging pieces how you
can defend against application
compromises
the other piece the other reason this
isn't the way that this works is you
have to force people to come back to
your data center the reason it's called
an inker is because it incurs the
decryption process to your data center
you can't extract the keys from a from a
good micro service you you can't take
those keys and use them offline you have
to come back to the data center which
means they're going to get the logs
every time that a record is decrypted
and with those logs again you can
profile whether or not they should be
doing this and you set off alerts as to
your whatever the threshold is for that
service you also use this for other
encryption things like maybe all of a
sudden John starts decrypting all the
API keys and that might be a problem
right maybe I went rogue or I got hacked
and now I'm decrypting a bunch of stuff
I shouldn't be decrypting but we
actually have records of the information
I've access now so I have a couple of
minutes I'm probably gonna go five over
it's just we got started late I'm gonna
talk about the three ways so we can
implement a crypto anchor first one is a
hardware security module what that means
is if the keys are actually stored in
silicon on some piece of hardware it's
not possible to extract those keys off
of that hardware so this meets that
property where you can't pull the key
out of the out of the service you have
to come back to the HSM to decrypt your
data that's a strongest guarantee you
have the next one is a common crypto
system is Amazon AWS now using kms from
AWS as your crypto service you get
everything we just talked about with the
one drawback that your Amazon admin also
has access to these crypto primitives
and so again if our threat model
includes an Amazon admin being
compromised kms is probably not your
first choice the third one is hashed
record vault
hashtag or vault is my favorite it's a
micro service the way you defend it is
you only give like one or two people in
your environment access to it the keys
could be theoretically extracted if
people if you can log onto the machine
pull them out of memory which would kind
of defeat the entire crypto anchoring
solution at the same time if you only
have a couple of people with access to
this machine
you also can monitor who's accessing and
when they're accessing it and have a
heightened alerts on that kind of
situation so the way vault was
architected is you don't get the keys
out of it unless well yeah you have to
get memory access to get the keys out of
it nobody else has the key so by default
you don't pull the keys out by default
you send all your data to it it encrypts
it and sends it back to you so I think
the the takeaway from this talk is to go
out and get vault play with it you can
download it and you run it you can look
at the log so you can see the benefit of
logging out context with all of your
encryption decryption operations and
yeah there's some quick instructions you
can reach out to me and I can give you
more detailed instructions so we've set
up through this
so to summarize what a crypto anchor is
logging is the key to protecting the
data you have to bring the data back to
the data center so it's a choke point
all of your encryption and decryption
have to happen on this service that
gives you the event that gives you the
benefit that you can log and you always
know when your data's been accessed
which is really hard to do on that other
you know and in the world we live in
otherwise with all the different people
who can access your database it's the
only way you can actually tell who's
access to your data and the last item
here is a you can profile normal
behavior and you set thresholds for
abnormal behavior and you can take
actions against that all right so that's
it thank you for coming to the talk
[Applause]